<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-30T18:39:42-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-30T18:39:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-30T18:39:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>Lil Nas X, Bella Poarch, Grimes, and more are releasing TikTok NFTs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Celebrities Visit The SiriusXM Studios In New York City" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XbWRBB61EUoHBcpfCP6QGxYa_tw=/0x0:2760x1840/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69934187/1340301664.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Cindy Ord/Getty Images for SiriusXM&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9arAGY"&gt;Because no peace can be found in the age of man, TikTok has decided to partner with select creators, celebrities, and online entities like Lil Nas X, Bella Poarch, and Grimes &lt;a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-us/tiktok-launches-first-creator-led-nft-collection-powered-by-immutable-x"&gt;to release a collection of non-fungible tokens&lt;/a&gt;. These TikTok Top Moments, as the company is calling them, are inspired by six “culturally significant” TikTok videos in the form of one-of-one NFTs. TikTok plans to auction them alongside a selection of limited edition NFTs it’ll sell weekly throughout October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fFdwrI"&gt;The partnerships, creators, and new material being tokenized and put up for auction vary. Musician Lil Nas X is up first on October 6th with a collaboration with artist Rudy Willingham, while Grimes is collaborating with Brittany Broski (“Kombucha Girl”), and separately with Bella Poarch. TikTok’s full list of collaborations goes into more detail about these selections and more, but is oddly missing details on how creators will actually get paid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="bVW4QX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"NFTs, explained ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22310188/nft-explainer-what-is-blockchain-crypto-art-faq"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="uuB5td"&gt;“Proceeds will largely go directly to the creators and NFT artists involved,” TikTok writes, but the company declined to break down specific percentages when asked by &lt;em&gt;The Verge. &lt;/em&gt;TikTok says a majority of the earnings will go to the creators of the NFTs. The rest will go to Immutable X, which handles NFT trading for the set, and the Museum of the Moving Image, which will be hosting a TikTok exhibit displaying the six main pieces in the TikTok collection. TikTok will not take any proceeds from sales, and says that the weekly drops of limited edition NFTs will “be sold at accessible price points to ensure each creator’s audience can own a piece of their history.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ivFK8C"&gt;While “owning” a viral TikTok might be an exciting idea, it’s worth acknowledging the environmental impact it could pose. NFTs and other blockchain-based projects &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22328203/nft-cryptoart-ethereum-blockchain-climate-change"&gt;have the potential to use massive amounts of energy&lt;/a&gt;, by design. Immutable X says the NFTs it helps TikTok mint will be carbon neutral, but not all NFTs or NFT marketplaces are created equal. Similarly, whether you actually “own” the video NFT you purchase is — outside of the philosophical implications — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331818/nifty-gateway-hack-steal-nfts-credit-card"&gt;dependent on the security&lt;/a&gt; of wherever they’re stored. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IilBVf"&gt;For more information on TikTok Top Moments, &lt;a href="https://tiktok.immutable.com/"&gt;visit Immutable X and TikTok’s site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22702871/lil-nas-x-tiktok-top-moments-nfts-auction"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22702871/lil-nas-x-tiktok-top-moments-nfts-auction</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-30T18:13:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-30T18:13:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>Pixel phones can automatically record and upload video in an emergency</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ll17K8onLEikeQeERYoLNcP_L2E=/0x0:1325x883/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69934104/pixel_4a_blue.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bFfyTE"&gt;One of the features Google offers exclusively through its Pixel Android phones is the Personal Safety app. Over the years, it’s added features like a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/1/21276908/google-pixel-feature-drop-june-2020-safety-check-bedtime"&gt;safety check-in&lt;/a&gt; that automatically notifies your emergency contacts if you don’t respond as scheduled and the ability to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/1/20892875/google-pixel-personal-safety-app-car-crash-detection"&gt;automatically dial 911 if it detects you’ve been in a car accident&lt;/a&gt;. Now &lt;a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/personal-safety-emergency-sos-feature/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;XDA-Developers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/google-pixels-personal-safety-app-can-now-automatically-record-video-during-an-emergency/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;point out a new feature that can automatically record video if you activate the built-in Emergency SOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PhyMgt"&gt;We installed the update &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.safetyhub"&gt;from Google Play&lt;/a&gt; on a Pixel device. It informs users that it can record continuously for up to 45 minutes once it’s activated, assuming your phone has enough storage. If there’s an internet connection, the video will get automatically backed up to your Google Account, where it will be stored for seven days. If you tell the app to Share Automatically, it will send a link for that video file to any Emergency Contacts you’ve selected.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Pixel Emergency SOS settings screens" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4amWXmqiGkbZkS4EXoJhTcCKKko=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22891927/pixel_emergency_sos_settings.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Cameron Faulkner&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Pixel Emergency SOS settings screens&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CQoRwE"&gt;If you have a Pixel phone, you can find the feature in the Personal Safety app’s settings. To activate the Emergency SOS, users press the phone’s power button five times. While it’s active, the phone is still available for you to use with a minimized viewfinder and notification icon to indicate that a recording is happening. The SOS can do other things depending on your settings, including calling 911, choosing to play (or not play) an alarm sound when activated, or share information with your emergency contacts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BEneYV"&gt;For other phones, Google &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/05/19/android-12s-new-emergency-sos-feature-is-back-in-beta-1/"&gt;tested a version of Emergency SOS in early betas for Android 12&lt;/a&gt;, but right now, this app and feature set is only for the Pixel line.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22702213/pixel-personal-safety-app-automatic-video-backup-emergency-sos"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22702213/pixel-personal-safety-app-automatic-video-backup-emergency-sos</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-30T18:06:15-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-30T18:06:15-04:00</updated>
    <title>PSA: Neiman Marcus still exists and it was hacked</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A Neiman Marcus storefront" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CoLg9O50PTnTx74Jdpg5hwVL5a0=/0x62:5685x3852/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69934061/1228428799.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Luxury retailer Neiman Marcus has notified 4.6 million customers about a data breach | Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6E9nLs"&gt;Luxury retailer Neiman Marcus &lt;a href="https://www.neimanmarcusgroup.com/2021-09-30-Neiman-Marcus-Confirms-Unauthorized-Access-to-Customer-Online-Accounts"&gt;said Thursday&lt;/a&gt; it had notified 4.6 million customers that their personal information, including credit card numbers. may have been part of a May 2020 data breach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pkYh2l"&gt;The Dallas-based company said in a news release that an “unauthorized third party obtained personal information associated with certain Neiman Marcus customers’ online accounts.” Neiman Marcus notified law enforcement, and is “working quickly to determine the nature and scope of the matter.” The company did not say who was responsible for the breach or how they were able to access its systems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h5XNxb"&gt;The data access may have included names and contact information, credit card numbers, and expiration dates— but not the CVV numbers on the back of the cards— Neiman Marcus gift cards, usernames, passwords, and security questions and answers “associated with Neiman Marcus online accounts.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zn0srX"&gt;According to the company, more than 85 percent of the 3.1 million payment and virtual gift cards affected “were expired or invalid,” and no active store brand credit cards were affected. Parent company Neiman Marcus Group (NMG)  said its other retailers Bergdorf Goodman and Horchow did not appear to have been part of the breach. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3fW59f"&gt;After it learned of the breach, NMG says it required customers who had not changed their online account passwords since May 2020 to reset them. CEO Geoffroy van Raemdonck said NMG would “continue to take actions to enhance our system security and safeguard information.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="baAWFo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.neimanmarcus.com%2Feditorial%2Fsecurity%2Fonline-accounts&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F30%2F22703171%2Fneiman-marcus-hacked-security-credit-cards" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The company has set up a website&lt;/a&gt; for customers to get more information about the breach, as well as a phone number: 866-571-9725.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22703171/neiman-marcus-hacked-security-credit-cards"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22703171/neiman-marcus-hacked-security-credit-cards</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-30T17:32:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-30T17:32:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>How the Surface Laptop Studio and Surface Pro 8 stack up against other creator laptops</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Surface Laptop Studio" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KG1pPCiMFMJcaHhRsaVgZ3en4r0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69933878/bfarsace_210921_4770_0019.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5FWQMS"&gt;Microsoft announced a new version of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22685923/microsoft-surface-pro-8-specs-price-release-date"&gt;Surface Pro&lt;/a&gt; last week, along with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22686010/microsoft-surface-laptop-studio-price-specs-release-date"&gt;Surface Laptop Studio&lt;/a&gt;. The Surface Pro 8 feels very much like a logical evolution of Microsoft’s tablet / laptop. Some of the more notable improvements include a 120Hz display with slimmer bezels, Thunderbolt 4 support, as well as a reworked surface keyboard that includes a dedicated space to store and charge the new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22686095/microsoft-surface-slim-pen-2-haptics-features-price-release-date"&gt;Surface Slim Pen 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vCXxU1"&gt;Meanwhile, the Surface Laptop Studio features a uniquely hinged screen and more powerful hardware. This is effectively a replacement for the Surface Book 3, with a three-point adjustable display that can lay flat for drawing or snap upright to deliver a more traditional laptop experience. This laptop comes equipped with an Nvidia RTX 3050 Ti GPU and a four-core, 4.8GHz, 11th Gen Intel processor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CY3oWn"&gt;Perhaps the coolest thing to come out of the event was the Surface Slim Pen 2, which aesthetically appears like any other stylus, but includes haptic feedback to simulate the subtle tactile response you get from putting a pen to paper. While the inclusion of a stylus is hardly revolutionary, improvements to the overall user experience are nice to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mpq31I"&gt;But how do the new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22686705/microsoft-surface-pro-8-keyboard-screen-photos-video-hands-on"&gt;Surface Pro 8&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22686706/microsoft-surface-studio-laptop-design-specs-photos-hands-on"&gt;Surface Laptop Studio&lt;/a&gt; stack up against other laptops that occupy the creator and power user space? We’ve collected a few of our favorites below for comparison based on our early impressions and spec sheets, with full reviews to follow in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="tYNcsP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to preorder all of the new Surface hardware","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22683783/microsoft-surface-pro-x-8-3-go-laptop-studio-preorder-price-date"},{"title":"Here’s how much buying into Microsoft’s pro Surface vision actually costs","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22688403/surface-pro-8-duo-studio-x-go-true-price-keyboard-pen-stylus-bundle"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="ot9Igy"&gt;Versus the Surface Laptop Studio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Ma4ruS"&gt;We chose the 14-inch models of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22264792/hp-spectre-x360-14-laptop-stylus-oled-review-price-specs-features"&gt;HP Spectre X360&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22430445/acer-conceptd-7-ezel-2021-review"&gt;Acer ConceptD Ezel&lt;/a&gt; because of their competitive pricing, which includes a stylus, and also for their ability to reorient themselves in some creative ways. (The new Microsoft devices don’t include the Surface Slim Pen 2, which costs $130 separately.) &lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=7168&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=VergeCreatorLaptops093021&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hp.com%2Fus-en%2Fshop%2Fpdp%2Fhp-spectre-x360-laptop-14t-ea000-touch-1q881av-1" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The Spectre&lt;/a&gt; is technically a 2-in-1 and can operate effectively as a tablet if you flip the screen over, though it doesn’t hold it up at an angle quite like the Surface Laptop Studio. The &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Facer-conceptd-7-ezel-cc715-71-7196-laptop%2F8v916pqmq44c%3Focid%3DAID2200057_aff_7593_1243925%26tduid%3D%28ir__0thgbaanw9kfqhhygvquhus6yn2xrv21qkgxj29e00%29%287593%29%281243925%29%28nOD_rLJHOac-8dpOdXgdIleApxHzJMABfw%29%28%29%26activetab%3Dpivot%3Aoverviewtab%26ranMID%3D24542%26ranEAID%3DnOD%252frLJHOac%26ranSiteID%3DnOD_rLJHOac-8dpOdXgdIleApxHzJMABfw%26epi%3DnOD_rLJHOac-8dpOdXgdIleApxHzJMABfw%26irgwc%3D1%26irclickid%3D_0thgbaanw9kfqhhygvquhus6yn2xrv21qkgxj29e00" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ConceptD Ezel&lt;/a&gt;, meanwhile, can flip out its screen and prop itself up like an easel or lay flat like a tablet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="7CWKEi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10777072"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qmwVig"&gt;We also threw in the Laptop Studio’s predecessor, the 13.5-inch &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21271796/microsoft-surface-book-3-review-price-specs-features-13-5-screen"&gt;Surface Book 3&lt;/a&gt;. The screen may not fold or flip, but it can still operate as a tablet when detached from its keyboard. We considered adding the 15-inch version of the Surface Book 3, but its &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fstore%2Fconfigure%2FSurface-Book-3%2F8XBW9G3Z71F1%3F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;starting price of $2,300&lt;/a&gt; made it just a little too expensive when stacked against its competition.    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lS2sz3"&gt;Still, the Surface Laptop Studio sets itself apart by offering a greater battery life and likely a superior dedicated GPU option to any of these other machines. It also has the distinction of being the only laptop in our lineup with a 120Hz refresh rate display, a feature typically reserved for gaming laptops. You’d generally need to look at a gaming-class laptop if you need a higher-end GPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="30BNMX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10768014"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="HKxepF"&gt;Versus the Surface Pro 8&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="3PomAq"&gt;The unique form factor of Surface devices makes them tough to compare, but the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22569871/lenovo-yoga-9i-14-inch-laptop-review"&gt;Lenovo Yoga 9i&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"&gt;Apple MacBook M1 Air&lt;/a&gt; make a strong case as ultraportables outside the Surface ecosystem that cater to creatives, and we’re also including the previous-gen &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fsurface-pro-7%2F8n17j0m5zzqs%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%3Aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Surface Pro 7&lt;/a&gt; for comparison. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="04Pq9K"&gt;Like previous generations of Surface, the new Surface Pro 8 doesn’t come with a pen or keyboard to start. The &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fsurface-slim-pen-2%2F8tb9xw8rwc14%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%253aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;new Slim Pen 2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fsurface-pro-signature-keyboard%2F90fj6zkw1rzb%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%253aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Surface Pro Signature Keyboard&lt;/a&gt; will cost you $130 and $180, respectively, but can also be &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fsurface-pro-signature-keyboard-with-slim-pen-2%2F8vdb5vrkc5tq%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%253aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;bundled for $280&lt;/a&gt;. Obviously, the other laptops we’re discussing come with built-in keyboards, and the Yoga i9 includes the pen as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zk9g3e"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10771697"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="95GkMo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfFKTLj8MM4#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The Lenovo&lt;/a&gt; also shares many of the same hardware specifications as the Surface Pro 8, with options for an 11th Gen Core i5 or i7 CPU. It does make a couple of compromises, most notably in the resolution and refresh rate of its display. These caveats could be overlooked by anyone who needs to save a little more money, though. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gpMQIw"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5LNQCX?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MacBook M1 Air&lt;/a&gt; is really the outlier of this lineup, not just because of its OS, but because it’s also the only laptop we picked that doesn’t have a touchscreen or can operate as a 2-in-1. It does, however, strike a solid balance in terms of features, performance, and price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nL0Tae"&gt;The biggest draw for the Surface Pro 8 — besides its unique form factor — is the display, which boasts the highest resolution and refresh rate out of the contenders below. It’s also the only model that features a 4K rear camera.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="u8udLq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10771732"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22687992/microsoft-surface-laptop-studio-pro-8-hp-spectre-macbook-air-creator-laptops-compare-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22687992/microsoft-surface-laptop-studio-pro-8-hp-spectre-macbook-air-creator-laptops-compare-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-30T17:31:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-30T17:31:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Before Astro, these were the robots people invited home</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="aibo" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NhDRUkbCvCtAV8Q9KwyUyvE1nBk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69933876/DSC00076.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 2017 version of Aibo, Sony’s robot dog.&lt;/em&gt; | Sam Byford / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LITrUb"&gt;Amazon announced its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22697244/amazon-astro-home-robot-hands-on-features-price"&gt;Astro home robot on Monday&lt;/a&gt;, which is designed to be an Alexa on wheels that can also bring you stuff (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22699251/amazon-astro-robot-cannot-fetch-your-beer"&gt;if other people load it into the cargo bay&lt;/a&gt;) and act as a sort of guard dog. With a touchscreen for a face and the ability to move itself around a single story of your house, it’s a bit like the personal robots from decades of science fiction. Given that Amazon seemingly wants to continue making home robots, though, we figured we’d go through a little history to look at some previous attempts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S13wHu"&gt;Of course, there’s plenty of discussion to be had about what does or does not count as a robot — to anyone with a smart home setup, Siri, Alexa, and Google Assistant could be considered robots, as they can do any number of tasks if you buy the necessary hardware. But for this list, we’re going to look at things that are either billed &lt;em&gt;specifically&lt;/em&gt; as household robots or are robots that we’d really love to invite into our homes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="XxSHRC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The five types of robots you meet at CES","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/9/18175168/ces-2019-robots-best-worst-delivery-butler-tablet"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gI9MI1Kp5jOSBlBrkyAQtYpd4m8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22888567/Screen_Shot_2021_09_29_at_2.16.53_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;em&gt;Byte Magazine&lt;/em&gt; / The Internet Archive&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The HERO didn’t look very friendly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="YC2q1a"&gt;HERO&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ZbDMJg"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release year:&lt;/strong&gt; 1982&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YS8mXV"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it could do:&lt;/strong&gt; Teach you what it’s like to build a robot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TZizuy"&gt;The HERO, which stands for Heath Educational Robot, was a massive tank of a machine that was designed to be, as the name suggests, an educational tool. It came as a kit (though you could also get it pre-built), and most of its utility came from what you learned putting it together. I’m not going to do an &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uHQ4WCU1WQc"&gt;Ahoy-style research journey&lt;/a&gt; to prove that it was absolutely the first home robot that ever went on sale, but being from the 1980s, it definitely came in on the ground floor. The decade would later see &lt;a href="https://tedium.co/2018/05/24/80s-home-robot-history/"&gt;a variety of other home educational robots&lt;/a&gt; similar to the HERO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="aCpzCU"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 75%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oibgyqdXfJM?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nDPQ1M"&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://archive.org/details/byte-magazine-1983-01/page/n88/mode/2up?view=theater"&gt;a &lt;em&gt;Byte&lt;/em&gt; magazine article from the time&lt;/a&gt;, it could talk, be controlled with a remote, and could even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22699251/amazon-astro-robot-cannot-fetch-your-beer"&gt;pick up a beverage&lt;/a&gt; — that is, after you assembled the add-on mechanical arm, which the author says took 10 hours. Does that make it more useful than what Amazon just announced in 2021? I guess that’s up for you to decide. You can watch a demo of the Hero Jr., a successor to HERO, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oibgyqdXfJM"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Nintendo museum GDC ROB test unit" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0fw0ZIt5i-k-pIZYp63AnMFE_Xc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/assets/4168313/ROB_test_unit.JPG"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="zHfBIK"&gt;Nintendo R.O.B.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ZzsibH"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release year:&lt;/strong&gt; 1985&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y3STtR"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it could do:&lt;/strong&gt; Sell NESs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uU83MA"&gt;When Nintendo went to sell its Family Computer in the US, it had a problem: video games were about as attractive to most consumers as toxic waste, as the industry had &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ikIeaCE3Ljc"&gt;more or less just imploded&lt;/a&gt;. Its solution was to instead market the console as a toy, calling it the Nintendo Entertainment System and including a robotic pal named Robotic Operating Buddy. R.O.B was a big part of much of Nintendo’s early marketing for the NES, making potential customers look and say, “Wow, what can that do?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hbNunK"&gt;The answer was that it could move gyroscopes and plastic tokens around to &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/w2FuHErzhVE?t=815"&gt;let you play all of two games&lt;/a&gt;. R.O.B. turned out to be better at making kids want an NES than helping them play it — some commenters have said that playing games designed for it is more fun if you have another human press the controller’s buttons on the controller instead of the bot. The fact that it wirelessly received signals from the TV was pretty neat, though, and the NES did pretty well for itself. So despite not having the robot servant capabilities that its looks implied, maybe R.O.B. did everything it needed to.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2nw3EH"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Sony Aibo dog robot|35266" data-volume-uuid="71f58ba70" data-volume-id="35266" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-744" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3WFNFK"&gt;Aibo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="jRREKc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release year: &lt;/strong&gt;1999&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NzhJwh"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it could do:&lt;/strong&gt; Fill my heart with warmth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1eUixg"&gt;Sony’s Aibo was a late-90s robotic pet dog, which was designed to be more of a companion than a servant. And it is, at least in my opinion, probably the cutest home robot. According to the &lt;a href="https://www.sony-aibo.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/aibo_ers110_handbook.pdf"&gt;user manual uploaded to an Aibo fansite&lt;/a&gt; (PDF), Aibo’s personality would change as it got older, and how it behaved as an adult would differ depending on how you treated it. Sony also claimed that Aibo would play and run around your house if you raised it right — otherwise, it’d be like my non-robotic cat and just nap all day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g3bT8K"&gt;Some people and families formed an actual emotional connection with Aibo, like they would with a biological pet. There are genuinely sad stories of &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2015/06/18/technology/robotica-sony-aibo-robotic-dog-mortality.html?_r=0"&gt;people who held funerals for their robot dogs&lt;/a&gt;, which broke down after Sony stopped fixing them. Yes, it does seem like something out of &lt;em&gt;Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep&lt;/em&gt;, but &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/features/loving-a-robot-dog-is-about-so-much-more-than-not-cleaning-up-poop/"&gt;you try living with something that looks and acts like a dog&lt;/a&gt; for years without falling in love with it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A66JL3"&gt;Okay, no, Sega’s iDog doesn’t count, because all it really did was &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7bmx3aiWqtg"&gt;kinda&lt;/a&gt; dance to music and &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/AbJrslGZx2g?t=66"&gt;get moody&lt;/a&gt; (shoutout to my childhood friend who had &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IDog#iFish"&gt;the iFish&lt;/a&gt;, by the way).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f1bpBh"&gt;There have been several iterations of Aibo over the years, along with attempts at robotic pets by other companies. Sony announced a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kJoAcEI2PXQ"&gt;new version of Aibo&lt;/a&gt; in 2017 and appears to still be selling it — though the website said there was only one left in stock when I looked.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Roomba 880 vacuum cleaning robot hands-on pictures" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hNJf-AdH1bQhXUiHArAXoqE7xoE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/2797238/roomba-880-hands-on3_2040.1384228987.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="S36Zqu"&gt;Robot vacuums&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="GSrE5r"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release year: &lt;/strong&gt;2001, first Roomba introduced in 2002&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6sCo5L"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it can do:&lt;/strong&gt; Clean your floors and freak out bio-Aibos (dogs)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q4riuL"&gt;Companies have been &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/Vui2CSEwOxQ?t=711"&gt;envisioning self-controlled vacuums for decades&lt;/a&gt;, but one of the first ones you could actually buy was &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V9u0f6jVxw0"&gt;the Electrolux Trilobite&lt;/a&gt;, which was released in 2001. It was made by a huge name in high-end vacuums but was upstaged the next year with the introduction of the iRobot Roomba. The robotic floor-cleaners were basically primitive versions of the ones we have today — they’d bump around your room until the floors were clean. We’ve also seen plenty of variations on that same concept, with companies introducing robots that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/8/4/12370840/braava-jet-irobot-mop-robot-roomba-vacuum"&gt;mop hardwood floors&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/5/22658457/segway-navimow-robot-will-mow-your-lawn-using-gps"&gt;even mow your lawn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xaixKr"&gt;Arguably, robot vacuums (and other single-purpose automated machines) are the most successful home robots we’ve seen so far. While they &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/9/22/22687449/roomba-rug-dark-pattern-cliff-edge-why-problem"&gt;can still struggle in hilarious ways&lt;/a&gt;, they’ve come a long way since the Trilobite, and some models are even able to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/20/18104679/irobot-roomba-i7-plus-robot-smart-vacuum-review-price-specs-features"&gt;empty themselves&lt;/a&gt;. That’s not even mentioning the various ways people &lt;a href="https://hackaday.com/2017/11/23/bringing-matlab-to-a-vacuum-near-you/"&gt;hack into&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/gopro/comments/7600cn/strapped_my_gph6_to_our_roomba_im_sure_this_has/"&gt;strap things onto&lt;/a&gt; their robot vacuums to make them more useful.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aiYvsAwUgB_pb7NB2_rhl6dFCM8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22889165/homepage_section5.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Sense Medical&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="GTGieO"&gt;Paro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="1gixQ8"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release year:&lt;/strong&gt; 2004&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ri4kJm"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it can do:&lt;/strong&gt; Provide emotional support&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qveebz"&gt;Paro is a robotic baby seal that was designed to act as a sort of therapy for people in elderly care or for people who otherwise need emotional support. It makes seal sounds, can move, and even charges with a cable shaped like a pacifier. In other words, it’s &lt;em&gt;exceedingly cute&lt;/em&gt; and has been used in nursing homes as an alternative to real-life animals for pet therapy, &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/SB10001424052748704463504575301051844937276"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Paro isn’t going to bite anyone or cause an allergic reaction, and it doesn’t need to be fed anything except electricity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yk0xZr"&gt;There have been debates about whether robots should have such a role in elder care, and whether they may take the place of human relationships. But as someone who is frequently distressed, I would love to have one of these to hug (though, given Paro’s multi-thousand dollar price tag, I may have to settle for &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/i-snuggled-with-this-robot-cat-and-it-didnt-scratch-me-1822402186"&gt;the Qoobo&lt;/a&gt;, a robot pillow with a tail).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="pepper-softbank-robot" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ha6UrW2xCECA0WchIToV5iwFRSY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6930569/DSC01589__1_.0.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="8pUv7P"&gt;Pepper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="mEuPT5"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release year: &lt;/strong&gt;2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tCb0rV"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it was supposed to do:&lt;/strong&gt; Understand your emotions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JFRdwR"&gt;Pepper ended up being mainly used as a billboard and a way to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/28/22554566/softbank-pepper-robot-production-layoffs-robotics"&gt;greet people in shops&lt;/a&gt; and airports (or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2018/4/24/17277350/softbank-pepper-the-robot-smithsonian-museum"&gt;the Smithsonian&lt;/a&gt;), but when it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/6/5/5781628/softbank-announces-pepper-robot"&gt;was announced by Softbank&lt;/a&gt;, it was pitched as a robot able to understand human emotions and take care of babies. Physically, it had actual arms and wheels to move around with, as well as a screen that it could use to display things like its name or info about Softbank’s latest phone plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V5b9V4"&gt;It wasn’t particularly successful at &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/6/19/5820080/meeting-softbank-pepper-robot"&gt;connecting with people on an emotional level&lt;/a&gt; and certainly didn’t live up to some of the ads that &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-A3ZLLGuvQY"&gt;depicted it comforting someone who’s crying&lt;/a&gt; — perhaps it was just too ambitious too early, or maybe it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578346/pepper-robot-failures-wall-street-journal"&gt;was just too dystopian&lt;/a&gt; to keep around. Softbank &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/28/22554566/softbank-pepper-robot-production-layoffs-robotics"&gt;stopped making Pepper&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cZ8EM8KjeoxGMRIFAaRPL5jpO-c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16214083/akrales_190423_3384_0344.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="f9mXXy"&gt;Jibo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="zci0oT"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release year:&lt;/strong&gt; Sold on IndieGoGo in 2014, arrived in 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xyq9Ct"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it could do:&lt;/strong&gt; Dance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xlRX8p"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/7/16/5909625/robot-assistant-jibo"&gt;crowdfunded Jibo robot&lt;/a&gt; may be one of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/19/18682780/jibo-death-server-update-social-robot-mourning"&gt;most loved&lt;/a&gt; home robots, despite the fact that it didn’t actually do a lot. It was meant to be a “social” robot that would greet you by name and that you could have conversations with. What it actually did best was dance with its little robot body (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/3/4/18250104/jibo-social-robot-server-shutdown-offline-dead"&gt;including when it was announcing its own death&lt;/a&gt;) and hem and haw about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2017/12/12/16764376/jibo-robot-ai-climate-change-siri-alexa-google-assistant"&gt;whether climate change is real&lt;/a&gt;. Despite that, there are still those &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/23/21325644/jibo-social-robot-ntt-disruptionfunding"&gt;trying to keep Jibo alive&lt;/a&gt; after its original makers sold it in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="asus zenbo" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dzuGe8z_Vzg35Ughv1ZIJSy-VB4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6564667/ASUS_Zenbo_3.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Asus&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1lQNoJ"&gt;Asus Zenbo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="GQq0OQ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release year:&lt;/strong&gt; Didn’t make it to the US, announced in 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dyQ1Wg"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it could do:&lt;/strong&gt; Control your smart home and basically act like a tablet that can follow you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zrF6nC"&gt;Zenbo &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/5/30/11810102/asus-zenbo-home-helper-robot"&gt;was announced as a $600 robot&lt;/a&gt; with many of the same features that Astro is promising today — Asus said it could act as a security guard, contact people for help in case of a fall, and display recipes and videos on its face. It proves difficult to actually find evidence of it existing though — there are no eBay listings for it, and Asus’s support site doesn’t seem to remember the Zenbo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J4YxmX"&gt;I did find evidence that Asus actually released this product in the form of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=45tnlGZm9tM"&gt;an unboxing video from Malaysia&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s not easy to get your hands on — &lt;a href="https://zenbo.asus.com/developer/faq/ZenboJunior/Product?cid=122"&gt;Asus’s Zenbo website&lt;/a&gt; directs you to contact the company’s sales team if you want to purchase the robot’s education and health-focused successors, the Zenbo Juniors I and II.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xn1MILWrUMsjh1T2w1lYZF5d_00=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13376877/vpavic_181101_3065_0087.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="lZHc0h"&gt;Anki Vector&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="QbwpOw"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release year:&lt;/strong&gt; 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="otA1QM"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it could do:&lt;/strong&gt; Make faces at you as it explored your desk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F9GXOs"&gt;The Anki Vector was a follow-up to another toy robot, the Cozmo. You could get it to play games with you, dance along to your music, and express various emotions with its eyes. Like Jibo, it also had a built-in voice assistant, and also like Jibo, that voice assistant was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/5/18056514/anki-vector-review-toy-robot-news-features-skills-ai"&gt;just OK&lt;/a&gt;. But dang, was Vector cute, as it drove around your desk, moving its little forklift arm. The company that created it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/29/18523124/anki-drive-robot-toy-company-out-of-business-shutting-down"&gt;went out of business&lt;/a&gt;, but you can buy a home server to keep it running from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/5/21050378/anki-vector-saved-shutdown-servers-assets-bought"&gt;another company that took over Anki’s assets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0GYyngY362FTzfbUlyzxtByaB-Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13672985/FoldiMate_with_folded_items.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: FoldiMate&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="MTrMVv"&gt;Foldimate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="80pwGG"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Announced year:&lt;/strong&gt; 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SSFCdN"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it can do:&lt;/strong&gt; fold your clothes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WDowwv"&gt;There were two robots that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/1/7/16854206/foldimate-laundry-folding-machine-ces-2018"&gt;promised to fold your clothes&lt;/a&gt; at CES 2018, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/10/16865506/laundroid-laundry-folding-machine-foldimate-ces-2018"&gt;neither of them really worked&lt;/a&gt;. In 2019, though, Foldimate returned with a working prototype that could actually fold a shirt in about five seconds. Is that worth the &lt;a href="https://foldimate.happyfox.com/kb/article/2-how-much-will-foldimate-cost/"&gt;estimated $1,500 to $2,000 pre-order price&lt;/a&gt; that Foldimate lists on its website? I guess it depends on how many clothes you fold. Either way, the machine isn’t out yet (and even its design doesn’t seem particularly nailed down), so you may be stuck &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IjkmqbJTLBM"&gt;folding your laundry by hand&lt;/a&gt; for a while longer. Bummer!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AVoeZR9a3l9UmIjjAjwKtEMWhCo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22889020/top_img_03.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Lovot&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lovot, mind-controlling someone to hug it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="zuLAXW"&gt;Lovot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="0HTp3N"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release year:&lt;/strong&gt; 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YE8V07"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it can do:&lt;/strong&gt; accept your love&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ae5ejJ"&gt;Lovot may be the most human robot of all because it’s mainly designed to feel needed — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/20/18149817/lovot-groove-x-home-robot-japan-designed-to-be-loved"&gt;according to its creators&lt;/a&gt;, it “won’t do any of your work” and “begs for attention and gets in the way of those it lives with.” To help it achieve its purpose of obtaining all your affection, it has wheels, cameras, and microphones that it can use to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/10/18176002/lovot-groovex-robot-emotional-attachment-ces-2019"&gt;recognize people and steer itself towards them&lt;/a&gt;. In that way, it’s a little like Astro, where it’ll follow people around — but instead of sticking a camera in their face, it’s just asking for them to pick it up and hug its soft body. You can also tickle it to make it fall asleep, and sorry I can’t write any more about it because I’m trying to figure out how to buy one in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/X0eoWzJFwHxalU9c1fXVhsC7TDk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16223219/mira_robotics_ugo_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Mira Robotics&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="QD7icT"&gt;Ugo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="BXAbzZ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release year:&lt;/strong&gt; 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BY4B0S"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it can do: &lt;/strong&gt;act as a remote set of arms&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4GRfcP"&gt;The Ugo is a home robot, but not in the traditional sense that we may think of one. Instead of having an advanced AI robobrain, it just has a human controlling it, like a more functional version of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/3/26/8294855/telepresence-robots-double-robotics-remote-skype-office"&gt;iPad-on-wheels telepresence robots&lt;/a&gt;. The human is able to move the robot, as well as operate its arms by using a pair of VR-style controllers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vfRMHl"&gt;The Ugo was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/9/18538020/home-robot-butler-telepresence-ugo-mira-robotics"&gt;originally pitched as a butler&lt;/a&gt;, either for the elderly or for families who don’t have time for housework. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DYXj0m6jDrk"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The World is One News &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; that companies have also rented the Ugo to help sanitize buildings during the pandemic. It remains to be seen if it’ll actually be particularly helpful — in the past, a hotel that had robots do various tasks like carry luggage and check in customers found that the system &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/15/18184198/japans-robot-hotel-lay-off-work-for-humans"&gt;actually created more work for human employees&lt;/a&gt;, instead of making their lives easier.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SDXUj1pEiJl0m9Mhw1_Cldja8gY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19550608/MarsCat___10_min.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Elephant Robotics&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="DkcUCT"&gt;MarsCat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="n8djFe"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release year:&lt;/strong&gt; 2021(?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7BEIKq"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it can do:&lt;/strong&gt; Be a cat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xLJfiq"&gt;The MarsCat is like a cat version of the Aibo, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/26/21035263/robot-cat-kickstarter-marscat-elephant-robotics"&gt;its Kickstarter launched in late 2019&lt;/a&gt;. Its makers, a company called Elephant Robotics, say that the robokitty will play with cat toys, accept scratches, and respond to commands like “come here.” You should also be able to program MarsCat yourself if you want, as its brain is a Raspberry Pi. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YcDhOQ"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1655380003/marscat-a-bionic-cat-a-home-robot/posts/3291808"&gt;latest update on the MarsCat’s Kickstarter page&lt;/a&gt; is from earlier this month and says that the cats have shipped, though there are only two commenters who claim to have gotten one (and one says theirs is broken). &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h0TghnK371BcPZ18gBqmzm34zkg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22227359/samsung_bot_handy_kitchen_full.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Video: Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This bot would indeed be handy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Pd6QTh"&gt;Bot Handy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="7VLWQG"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Announced in:&lt;/strong&gt; 2021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zmcJOe"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it’s supposed to do:&lt;/strong&gt; Decorate my home with flowers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mNmamn"&gt;At CES this year, Samsung showed off its Bot Handy robot, which looks a bit like an oscillating fan with a robotic arm. The bot brought the presenter a drink of water, something that the Astro can’t do by itself. Samsung also showed it using that arm to put dirty dishes in a dishwasher, and a towel in a laundry basket. Samsung said that the Bot Handy was “in development,” but it’s an extraordinarily ambitious concept — for it to work like Samsung’s demo, it would need lots of abilities that don’t really exist yet, so it’s not likely this particular bot will make it into our homes. Speaking of...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lhT6i4Q76JxRWGxMiwKuzGTMwzs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22794095/robotics_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Tesla&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="FpDERJ"&gt;Tesla Bot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="XJciKv"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Announced in:&lt;/strong&gt; 2021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vGkaXA"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it’s supposed to do:&lt;/strong&gt; Usher in luxury space communism by replacing labor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i67PSs"&gt;Earlier this year, Elon Musk got up on stage and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22633514/tesla-robot-prototype-elon-musk-humanoid-ai-day"&gt;said that Tesla was working on a humanoid robot&lt;/a&gt; that it would build at some point in 2022. He showed it off by having someone dressed as the robot come out and dance and, after the awkwardness, announced “obviously that was not real” (I’m not sure anyone was fooled). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MsVQst"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Lmao this is how he made his announcement? &lt;a href="https://t.co/6Ktybjyeav"&gt;pic.twitter.com/6Ktybjyeav&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ryan Mac   (@RMac18) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RMac18/status/1428708172856918018?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 20, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JZMINb"&gt;Musk did promise that the bot &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; be real at some point, and Tesla says that it’ll be a “general purpose” robot, which will be able to carry out “unsafe, repetitive, or boring” tasks. Is that a realistic vision for next year? &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22633958/tesla-bot-elon-musk-ai-day"&gt;I’m laughing too hard to answer&lt;/a&gt;. If only I had a robot to bring me a glass of water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="cq8xdm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Amazon’s Astro cannot fetch your beer","url":"https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22699251/amazon-astro-robot-cannot-fetch-your-beer"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22701141/home-robot-brief-history-amazon-astro-toys-vacuums-pets"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22701141/home-robot-brief-history-amazon-astro-toys-vacuums-pets</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-30T16:35:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-30T16:35:52-04:00</updated>
    <title>Cruise gets the green light to give driverless rides to passengers in San Francisco</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Cruise Self Driving Car" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7r17Shwb1Q8sKx_4pia4Jbk8zG4=/0x209:5000x3542/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69933533/1091888728.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Smith Collection/Gado/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="AfKPg7"&gt;Waymo and Cruise, two of the leading autonomous vehicle companies in the US, received permits from the California Department of Motor Vehicles to offer rides to passengers in their robotaxis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2ft4C2"&gt;But while Cruise was approved to give rides in its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/5/22520227/cruise-permit-california-driverless-autonomous-vehicles"&gt;fully driverless vehicles&lt;/a&gt; without safety drivers, Waymo only is allowed to deploy its autonomous vehicles with a human monitor behind the wheel. In order to give rides to paying passengers in its fully driverless vehicles, as it does in Arizona, the Google spinoff would need to apply for an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/23/21591045/california-robotaxi-paid-rides-cpuc-permits"&gt;additional permit from the California Public Utilities Commission&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CkwwkB"&gt;Waymo was the first company to receive a driverless testing permit in 2018. And while the idea of a fully autonomous ride-hailing service is still Waymo’s “north star and ultimate service model,” according to a spokesperson, the company will only remove safety drivers from its vehicles when it’s ready to do so. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Ehp8HH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Waymo’s incremental approach&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eWE3jq"&gt;“As part of Waymo’s incremental approach to rolling out the fully driverless experience to our users in a new geographic area, we first deploy AVs equipped with our automated driving system (“ADS”) and a trained driver behind the wheel,” the spokesperson said in an email. “We begin offering trips to passengers, before we remove the driver to offer trips in rider only mode.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aFsdzD"&gt;Cruise, for its part, is hailing the permit to give rides to passengers in fully driverless vehicles as a milestone. Rob Grant, senior vice president of government affairs and social impact, said the permit “brings [Cruise] one step closer to achieving our mission to make transportation safer, better, and more affordable in cities with our fleet of all-electric, self-driving and shared vehicles.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5yv970"&gt;The company had planned to launch a commercial robotaxi service in San Francisco in 2019 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/24/20707242/cruise-gm-self-driving-taxi-launch-delay-2019"&gt;but failed to do so&lt;/a&gt;, and it has yet to publicly commit to a new date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="KMWRox"&gt;&lt;q&gt;California is ground zero for AV testing in the US&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="imOASL"&gt;California is ground zero for AV testing in the US, with over 50 companies licensed to operate autonomous vehicles for testing purposes in the state. A handful of companies hold permits to test fully driverless vehicles, without safety drivers behind the steering wheel. And an even smaller number have been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/5/22520227/cruise-permit-california-driverless-autonomous-vehicles"&gt;approved to pick up and drop off passengers&lt;/a&gt; as part of a commercial pilot service. Today’s permits represent the next step in that process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BJcGUL"&gt;AVs registered in California traveled approximately 1.99 million miles in autonomous mode on public roads in 2020. The total miles driven by Waymo and Cruise, 1.39 million, is 70 percent of the total autonomous miles driven in California in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yvCGFB"&gt;Cruise vehicles are approved to operate between 10PM and 6AM at a maximum speed of 30mph and can even drive in “light rain and fog.” Waymo vehicles can operate on public roads in parts of San Francisco and San Mateo counties at a maximum speed of 65mph. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tokOtG"&gt;“We can only offer paid rides in driverless AVs to members of the public during those hours (pending the final CPUC deployment permit),” a Cruise spokesperson said. “We can continue to test with or without passengers in both driverless and with drivers 24/7. We will coordinate with our regulators as we expand hours of operations and geographic corridors.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YtiVW0"&gt;Last week, California Governor Gavin Newsom &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22691410/california-autonomous-vehicles-zero-emission-2030-newsom"&gt;signed a bill&lt;/a&gt; that would require AV companies to only use electric vehicles starting in 2030. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22702962/cruise-waymo-california-dmv-autonomous-vehicle-permit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22702962/cruise-waymo-california-dmv-autonomous-vehicle-permit</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-30T16:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-30T16:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Anybody want to see Lindsay Lohan’s NFT fursona?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Celebrities Attend 2019 Melbourne Cup Day" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0UZkP7J-IZPwVkUzZcy6PfKDQok=/58x0:3712x2436/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69933494/1185550832.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by James Gourley/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="q3kU9j"&gt;I am a woman who believes in taking accountability for her actions and this is mine. Because I unleashed this tweet upon my colleagues, I must now share it with the masses. This is my punishment. Now it’s yours too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9z77Lf"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;It's official, I'm a Friend of The Cartel!!   It’s the first NFT the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CanineCartelNFT?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@CanineCartelNFT&lt;/a&gt; is minting for the collection and you've got a chance to own it! &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Auction runs for 72 hours!  &lt;a href="https://t.co/k85RHYToRc"&gt;https://t.co/k85RHYToRc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Best of luck!   &lt;a href="https://t.co/6UNsFWsQxB"&gt;pic.twitter.com/6UNsFWsQxB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Lindsay Lohan (@lindsaylohan) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lindsaylohan/status/1443247758199205893?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 29, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AU5JgO"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22702478/anybody-want-to-see-lindsay-lohans-nft-fursona"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22702478/anybody-want-to-see-lindsay-lohans-nft-fursona</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-30T16:18:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-30T16:18:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Slack is down for some people, and of course, the problem is DNS</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/l02Kn6ZFJYCb7xP8bdvHkDoRZgE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69933251/acastro_190412_1777_slack_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / Th&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="U6lo71"&gt;Slack appears to be having issues for some people, with reports coming in of users who can’t connect to the service, receive errors when trying to send messages, and can’t &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SlackStatus/status/1443644374311649288?s=20"&gt;even access Slack’s website&lt;/a&gt;. The issue doesn’t appear to affect everyone, and Slack hasn’t gone as far as calling it an outage on &lt;a href="https://status.slack.com"&gt;its status page&lt;/a&gt;. The differences in experiences pointed to a possible routing issue or the even more likely culprit, &lt;a href="https://imgur.com/WmRbmf5"&gt;DNS&lt;/a&gt; (it’s always DNS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VStAF1"&gt;At 3:50PM ET, &lt;a href="https://lists.dns-oarc.net/pipermail/dns-operations/2021-September/021340.html"&gt;Slack confirmed&lt;/a&gt; what we suspected and what &lt;a href="https://lists.dns-oarc.net/pipermail/dns-operations/2021-September/021340.html"&gt;others had already figured out&lt;/a&gt; — it was DNS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Be4eVb"&gt;Some of my co-workers have had issues today, while it’s working fine for others (including, unfortunately, me). It’s unclear how widespread the issues are — DownDetector &lt;a href="https://downdetector.com/status/slack/"&gt;only shows a thousand or so reports&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kRdq33"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We're doing our best!&lt;/p&gt;— Slack (@SlackHQ) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SlackHQ/status/1443654557763051528?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 30, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3kFuY7"&gt;The company says it’s working on a fix for the issue, but &lt;a href="https://status.slack.com/2021-09/06c1e17de93e7dc2"&gt;the incident report page&lt;/a&gt; says it’s been ongoing since around 12:30PM ET, or 9:30AM PT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pFqf7E"&gt;If you’re still having trouble connecting, then either &lt;a href="https://www.wikihow.com/Flush-DNS"&gt;you&lt;/a&gt; or your ISP may need to flush your cached DNS information. One way to get connected if your ISP’s information hasn’t been updated is to use alternate DNS servers, like Google’s ( 8.8.8.8 and 8.8.4.4) or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/3/17191538/how-to-change-dns-routers-windows-mac-ios"&gt;Cloudflare&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="QHOfMl"&gt;We are aware of connectivity issues related to DNS that are impacting a small subset of users. This issue was caused by our own change and not related to any third-party DNS software and services. In order to resolve this faster, your ISP (Internet Service Provider) will need to flush their DNS record for slack.com. Please reach out to your networking team to provide them with this information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="64rc5y"&gt;We expect all customers’ connectivity issues to be resolved within the next 24 hours. We know how important it is for people to stay connected and we apologize for this disruption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="jlZu83"&gt;If all that fails, maybe it’s the universe telling you to take a walk or cook yourself something nice. When the chat app eventually comes back, it’ll probably do so in a bit of a wave — you can just tell your boss that it came back a little later for you and that you were really trying to message them about that draft, honest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iS9LEl"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Our investigation of this connection issue is still ongoing at this time. We’ll be back with another update and apologize for this disruption. Thank you for your continued patience. &lt;a href="https://t.co/tZUb1TWDEc"&gt;https://t.co/tZUb1TWDEc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Slack Status (@SlackStatus) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SlackStatus/status/1443656781230575635?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 30, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Jn3hYx"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 30th, 4:18PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added DNS outage information and possible fixes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22702876/slack-is-down-outage-morning-disruption-work-chat"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22702876/slack-is-down-outage-morning-disruption-work-chat</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-30T15:04:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-30T15:04:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to use Focus assist in Windows 11</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TGPcB-hag5ziG8bREU7-h7I7cOY=/0x0:3240x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69932976/Screenshot__52_.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CYNzSf"&gt;It’s all too easy to allow distractions such as social media or videos to seduce us from the things we’re supposed to be doing — such as, say, writing articles about Windows 11. Features such as Focus assist are now being included with operating systems to try to help us keep our eyes on the road, so to speak. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XeWhvf"&gt;Microsoft’s Focus assist was first introduced in a 2018 update of Windows 10, where it replaced a feature known as Quiet Hours, and while Windows 11 doesn’t offer any radical updates, it has made the feature easier to use. Focus assist stops notifications from popping up on your screen and can be activated automatically when you put on your display on presentation mode, are playing a game, or are using an app in full-screen mode. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pkz6CD"&gt;I’ll show you how to edit the automatic sessions in a moment. First, here’s how to manually begin a Focus assist session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="LTnVfe"&gt;Start a session&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="SXQKyl"&gt;In Windows 11, Focus assist has been made a part of the Clock app. To start a session manually, type “Clock” into your taskbar’s Search icon. You’ll be guided to a page that helps you set up the length of time you want the session to last; you can also set a daily goal if you wish. And there are tiles that let you link your Spotify account (should you have one) to your focus sessions or use Microsoft To Do to pick a task for that session. Don’t need either of these? Keep reading.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Now part of the Clock app, Focus assist lets you set goals for keeping on track." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8yT8TO3-9CeinWol_0hKqVStWCs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22890585/Screenshot__54_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now part of the Clock app, Focus assist lets you set goals for keeping on track.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="boy9gO"&gt;If you click on the settings icon at the bottom left of the Clock app, you can adjust the length of your focus time (including breaks) and select a sound to play when your focus period (or your break) ends. And you can get rid of the Spotify and / or To Do tiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MCq2ZS"&gt;The Clock settings page also lets you pick a theme for the app and tweak your notification settings, including which notifications should not be filtered out during a Focus assist session.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Clock settings page lets you edit your notifications settings." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9bC_nl4YSLad-ohtZZ5LlqU7WL0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22890631/Screenshot__56_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Clock settings page lets you edit your notifications settings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="filDrf"&gt;To personalize this feature a bit more and to edit the automatic settings, you need to go to “Focus assist settings.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="C9SiKZ"&gt;Focus assist settings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="lQIBkH"&gt;You can get to Focus assist settings in several ways: by clicking on “Settings” &amp;gt; “System” &amp;gt; “Focus assist,” by using the taskbar search icon to find “Focus assist,” or by clicking on the system clock at the right edge of the taskbar and then on “Focus assist settings.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Within system settings, you can decide when you want Focus assist to activate, and for which notifications." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-vQP46U1hZ-IlfsO0PT-ZzJpzuY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22890745/Screenshot__49_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Within system settings, you can decide when you want Focus assist to activate, and for which notifications.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="RKJfQ5"&gt;Once you’re there, there are two main sections. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="znnux1"&gt;The first section lets you turn Focus assist on and off and set certain parameters when it is active:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="ZsSKqd"&gt;“Priority only” limits active notifications to those specified in a priority list. You can set that list up by selecting the “Customize priority list” link right below the “Priority only” subhead. You can have it always notify you of incoming calls, always notify you of reminders, or allow notifications from specific apps. New to Windows 11 is the ability to prioritize notifications from contacts who are either pinned to your taskbar or whom you specify via an “Add contacts” button.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can prioritize calls, reminders, apps, and specific contacts." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Vsj_NDeomzR9Tn_8ITRU3I2gQ8I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22890748/Screenshot__47_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can prioritize calls, reminders, apps, and specific contacts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="prjKxx"&gt;“Alarms only” lets you hide all your notifications, except for any alarms you may have set up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="VjrrSb"&gt;Concerned that you may miss something? If you check “Show a summary of what I missed when focus assist was on,” then you will be automatically notified of all your filtered notifications as soon as Focus assist is no longer active.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="trWFAb"&gt;The second section, headed “Automatic rules,” lets you adjust several pre-set rules. You can toggle each on and off from this page, but if you want to change their settings, click on the name of the feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="UoU9Za"&gt;“During these hours” lets you set specific times and days when Focus assist will kick in. To edit the settings, select “During these times” and then, on the next page, toggle it on. You’ll be able to choose the start and end times for each session; whether it applies to every day, to just weekdays or just weekends; and whether it will allow priority only or alarms only.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can prioritize calls, reminders, apps, and specific contacts." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PoaXowXi7UtfmMMmWs7OdqXiCUU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22890749/Screenshot__57_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Decide when you want Focus assist to kick in automatically.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="wj0XAJ"&gt;The other features under “Automatic rules” operate in much the same way. On the Focus assist page, click the toggle to turn them on or off, and click on their name to adjust them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="5FUd7k"&gt;“When I’m duplicating my display” kicks in when you’re got two displays going; toggle it on so you can edit it to allow either priority only or alarms only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="MwMQSi"&gt;“When I’m playing a game” is pretty obvious; again, toggle it on to change it to priority only or alarms only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="4IltbK"&gt;Finally, “When I’m using an app in full-screen mode only” can also be tweaked to be priority only or alarms only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="7Ym1bI"&gt;One last thing: when Focus assist is active, you will see a small moon icon at the far right of your taskbar. Click on it, and you should be able to see any missed notifications.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22696232/focus-assist-windows-11-microsoft-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22696232/focus-assist-windows-11-microsoft-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
