<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-13T05:00:35-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-13T05:00:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-13T05:00:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Realme’s extremely green GT Neo 2 flagship has a Snapdragon 870 for $425</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8aMZvd8TZfj44M3gEcbFmurSixk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69987706/IMG_0172.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9TPtp3"&gt;Realme has launched its latest flagship phone for India, the GT Neo 2. It’s similar to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/15/22534618/realme-gt-hands-on-europe-launch-price-specs"&gt;the impressive Realme GT&lt;/a&gt; that came to Europe a few months ago — this one is better in some ways but worse in others. Depending on your taste, you’ll probably feel quite strongly about which bucket the neon green version pictured above falls into. (It also comes in black and blue.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YeSjvR"&gt;While the GT has a Snapdragon 888 processor, the GT Neo 2 is built around an 870. This is basically Qualcomm’s speed-bumped version of the 865 Plus, which was itself a faster version of last year’s flagship chip — the main core now runs at 3.2GHz. Realme says the GT Neo 2’s new vapor cooling system is 30 percent larger and 20 percent more efficient, making use of stainless steel as well as copper. The phone does include 5G connectivity, though 5G networks haven’t yet been switched on in India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZpIDHT"&gt;The display is a little bigger than the GT’s, measuring in at 6.62 inches. It’s a 1080p OLED panel with a 120Hz refresh rate. The battery is also bigger than the GT’s at 5,000mAh, up from 4,500mAh, and the GT Neo 2 still has Realme’s 65W SuperDart fast charging. Realme says it should take 36 minutes to fill from 0 to 100 percent. There’s still no wireless charging, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22633722/realme-flash-magdart-magnetic-wireless-charging-time-test"&gt;the new magnetic MagDart system&lt;/a&gt; that is so far yet to be included on any commercial device.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/S-3WNa8ZoP38yeyR9-QOKV_Bvo0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22923288/IMG_0171.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="n7DWcE"&gt;Like the GT, the triple camera system includes a 64-megapixel main sensor, an 8-megapixel ultrawide camera, and a 2-megapixel macro lens. Realme is pushing the GT Neo 2’s Street Photography mode, which is supposed to boost shutter response and focus performance, as well as including some film simulation filters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QB7Ezh"&gt;The Realme GT Neo 2 will be available later this week in India. It costs Rs. 31,999 (~$425) for a model with 8GB of RAM and 128GB of storage, or you can get a 12GB/256GB version for Rs. 35,999 (~$475).&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22723967/realme-gt-neo2-india-announced-specs-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22723967/realme-gt-neo2-india-announced-specs-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-13T04:38:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-13T04:38:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>Quake remaster is now 4K 120fps on PS5 and Xbox Series X / S</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mlH_uJ9jls3jS0etabTX27qkpW0=/308x0:1613x870/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69987692/Quake__Minor_Update_HERO_v3_1920x870.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Bethesda&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ilOfvm"&gt;The “next-gen upgrade” for this year’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632110/quake-xbox-playstation-switch-4k-visuals-version-download"&gt;Quake remaster&lt;/a&gt;, which adds support for up to 4K / 120fps gameplay, is now available for the PS5, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S. The upgrade is available for free, &lt;a href="https://bethesda.net/en/article/6dXzcvcwZCrzKLsv7yJZSC/quake-next-gen-update"&gt;according to Bethesda&lt;/a&gt;, and there’s no time limit to redeem it. The PC version of the game isn’t getting the upgrade, since it already supports 4K / 120fps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WyM6z4"&gt;As well as the framerate improvements, the upgrade also adds support for the PS5 Dualsense controller’s adaptive triggers and integrated speaker. Meanwhile, Xbox players get &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/7/4/12092820/xbox-play-anywhere-launches-on-september-13th"&gt;Play Anywhere support&lt;/a&gt;, a Microsoft technology that means ownership of the game and progress automatically carries over to its PC version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nAHuof"&gt;The upgrade process is a little different for the PlayStation and Xbox. Xbox owners should see the upgrade installed automatically thanks to Microsoft’s Smart Delivery system, and any existing saves should carry over. Meanwhile, on PS5, players will need to download the upgraded game via the game’s hub or PlayStation Store, and Bethesda provides instructions for how to do so &lt;a href="https://bethesda.net/en/article/6dXzcvcwZCrzKLsv7yJZSC/quake-next-gen-update"&gt;over on its blog&lt;/a&gt;. PS4 saves cannot transfer to the PS5 version of the game, Bethesda says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mAkxcM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lkRyf6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22723961/quake-ps5-xbox-series-x-s-remaster-120fps-4k-upgrade-play-anywhere-dualsense-support"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22723961/quake-ps5-xbox-series-x-s-remaster-120fps-4k-upgrade-play-anywhere-dualsense-support</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-13T03:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-13T03:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Bowers &amp; Wilkins updates iconic Zeppelin speaker with Alexa and AirPlay 2  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GjLnGM7aHEIUDQOGPpRmkFy1Lik=/0x0:1080x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69987638/1x1_Zeppelin_Midnight_Grey_Lifestyle_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;New streaming tech, old Zeppelin shape.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Bowers &amp;amp; Wilkins&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6rTqck"&gt;Bowers &amp;amp; Wilkins has announced a new Zeppelin speaker that updates the eye-catching design with modern connectivity and smarts. The new speaker supports wireless standards like Qualcomm’s AptX Adaptive and Apple’s AirPlay 2 and also has Alexa built-in for voice control of your music. The new Zeppelin is available to order in light or dark grey starting today and is priced at $799 / £699 / €799. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MvcX5f"&gt;The original Zeppelin was one of the most iconic iPod docks available when it launched in 2007, and it’s been updated several times over the years as the way we listen to music has changed. 2011’s Zeppelin Air added support for Apple’s AirPlay standard alongside its existing 30-pin dock, while the 2015 Zeppelin Wireless dropped the dock entirely to focus on wireless connectivity using standards like AptX Bluetooth or Spotify Connect (although it kept a 3.5mm input around as a wired option).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5Pb9gxIgNVyY9sltr50gASk6wKg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22920583/High__Zeppelin_Midnight_Grey_Connector_Panel_Detail_2.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Bowers &amp;amp; Wilkins&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are no wired inputs for music sources.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="qqo6Gv"&gt;With the new 2021 Zeppelin, however, B&amp;amp;W has gone fully wireless. Around its back, there’s a socket for power and a USB-C port, but the latter is only there for servicing rather than connecting a music source. Instead, the Zeppelin supports a full suite of wireless standards, including AAC, SBC, and AptX Adaptive Bluetooth codecs (but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22652655/qualcomm-aptx-lossless-announced-snapdragon-sound"&gt;no AptX Lossless&lt;/a&gt;), AirPlay 2, Spotify Connect, and B&amp;amp;W’s own Music app, which offers support for streaming services like Deezer, Qobuz, and Tidal. There’s no Chromecast support built-in, nor is Google Assistant available alongside Alexa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="86DpVQ"&gt;If you’d like to use the Zeppelin as part of a multi-room setup, then B&amp;amp;W says it plans to add support early next year. When it’s released, the feature will let users pair multiple Zeppelins together with B&amp;amp;W’s existing line of connected Formation speakers together. Alternatively, if you’re on iOS, you should be able to achieve a similar setup thanks to Zeppelin’s support for AirPlay 2. Just don’t expect to be able to pair two Zeppelins together as a stereo pair; B&amp;amp;W says the multi-room functionality is designed for each Zeppelin to offer stereo sound by itself.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mfn10sKpX_uAiUF6nGTqP6W5yXc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22920591/High__Zeppelin_Midnight_Grey_Drive_Units_White_Background.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Bowers &amp;amp; Wilkins&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Two tweeters, two mid-range drivers, and a subwoofer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6KtUUE"&gt;Internally, the new Zeppelin has a pair of one-inch tweeters, two 3.5-inch mid-range drivers, and a single six-inch subwoofer powered by a total of 240W of amplification. Although there’s no remote like with previous Zeppelins, there’s a set of physical playback controls on the rear of the speaker (but there’s no physical off switch for Alexa).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iNcX1B"&gt;In the era of iPod docks, the Zeppelin was one of the most desirable all-in-one speakers on the market. But in the years since, it feels like Bowers &amp;amp; Wilkins has lost ground to the likes of Sonos and Amazon as multi-room audio and smart speakers have taken over, respectively. With the new Zeppelin, I’m sure the company is hoping to reverse that trend.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22722494/bowers-and-wilkins-zeppelin-alexa-airplay-2-speaker-update"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22722494/bowers-and-wilkins-zeppelin-alexa-airplay-2-speaker-update</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-13T02:26:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-13T02:26:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>Fujifilm launches wide-format version of its Instax Link mobile printer</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LXIiqJx510J9TuIq3nNcLNa3s2A=/0x0:1200x800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69987616/large_210520_instax_LINK_WIDE_AshWhite_Sketch_Edit_Print_291_Stack_retouch.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="buD3Fs"&gt;Fujifilm has announced a new mobile printer that uses its larger Instax Wide format film. The  Instax Link Wide Smartphone Printer is a similar idea to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22397156/fujifilm-nintendo-instax-mini-link-app-collaboration"&gt;the existing Instax Mini Link&lt;/a&gt;: hook up your phone over Bluetooth and use an app to edit and print your own Polaroid-style snapshots from your camera roll. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PjwxcZ"&gt;Instax Wide film is much bigger than Instax Mini — it’s about the size of two credit cards side by side. That means your Link Wide printouts might not be as easy to carry in a wallet as Instax Mini photos, but they should be a lot more viewable and usable for other purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sLGrj5"&gt;The Link Wide printer is also compatible with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21517015/fujifilm-x-s10-camera-vlogging-price-specs-features"&gt;Fujifilm’s X-S10 mirrorless camera&lt;/a&gt; from last year, allowing you to print directly without a phone. Of course, you can print photos taken with other cameras by uploading them to your phone and then to the Instax Link app.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MDCYzR6ovu3ZcTyLllVelfqs2Bs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22923253/linkwide.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The Instax Link Wide’s Rich and Natural color modes.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="JT07t2"&gt;Fujifilm says the Link Wide printer should be good for about 100 Instax prints on a battery charge. There are two printing modes, Rich and Natural, that let you choose between “bright and immersive or saturated and classic” color output, as well as the ability to edit images in the app by cropping or adding text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dW8mZC"&gt;Fujifilm will release the Instax Link Wide Smartphone Printer late this month for $149.95. The company is also introducing a new black-bordered variant of Instax Wide film, which will sell for $21.99 for a pack of 10.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22723925/fujifilm-instax-wide-link-smartphone-printer-announced-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22723925/fujifilm-instax-wide-link-smartphone-printer-announced-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T21:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T21:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Some of Verizon’s Visible cell network customers say they’ve been hacked</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JYy2soK3rXiuStajsstFeIuJ5qg=/331x0:1081x500/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69987158/1500x500.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Visible&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8JPEpQ"&gt;Some customers of Verizon’s Visible service are using social media to say that hackers have accessed their accounts, &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Visible/comments/q6y73u/im_seriously_disappointed_with_visible_today/"&gt;changed their information&lt;/a&gt; to lock them out, and in some cases &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Visible/comments/q6o4q4/yes_i_was_hacked_as_well_im_making_this_as_public/"&gt;even ordered phones&lt;/a&gt; using their payment info (&lt;a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/verizon-owned-visible-network-suffers-suspected-data-breach/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;XDA&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). If you’re not familiar, Visible is a cell service &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.verizon.com/about/news/what-visible" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;owned and operated by Verizon&lt;/a&gt; that pitches itself as a less expensive, “all-digital” network, meaning there aren’t any physical stores like you’d get with a traditional carrier. Starting on Monday, customers on both Twitter and Reddit reported en masse that they’d been getting emails from the company about changed passwords and addresses, and that they’ve &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dao0815/status/1448026781332623360?s=20"&gt;had difficulties contacting the company’s chat support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KYw5nt"&gt;Visible’s customer service account on Twitter seemingly hasn’t addressed the issue, besides &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/visiblecare/status/1448040220318961665?s=20"&gt;directing upset customers to its DMs&lt;/a&gt;. A user marked as a Visible employee on the subreddit &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Visible/comments/q65cdl/security_update/"&gt;posted a statement on Monday&lt;/a&gt; afternoon, saying that a “small number” of accounts were affected, but that the company didn’t believe its systems had been breached. The statement did recommend that users change their passwords, but as many commenters pointed out (and as I can confirm), the password reset system currently isn’t working. Verizon didn’t immediately respond to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="yX8ZQb"&gt;
    &lt;blockquote class="reddit-card" data-card-created='"2021-10-13T01:13:44.362093+00:00"'&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Visible/comments/q65cdl/security_update/?ref_source=embed&amp;amp;ref=share"&gt;Security Update&lt;/a&gt; from
      &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Visible/"&gt;Visible&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    &lt;script async="" src="https://embed.redditmedia.com/widgets/platform.js" charset="UTF-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="D0Ho6e"&gt;&lt;q&gt;I haven’t received any emails or texts from the company about the situation&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9aXBLc"&gt;I’m a Visible customer myself (I switched from T-Mobile for reasons unrelated to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22633853/tmobile-data-breach-imei-sim-fcc"&gt;its recent massive data breach&lt;/a&gt;, but am &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; thrilled to possibly have been double-owned) and so far my account doesn’t seem to be compromised. I’m able to log in online and make sure my order history doesn’t have anything untoward, and opening the app is working like normal (though I received a few errors earlier in the day). I haven’t received any emails, texts, or other communications from the company regarding this situation. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sj6f0YP8i1FoTvugJ7E9tmVjifQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22922737/IMG_2881.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The error message I received earlier trying to log into the app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ofVyAc"&gt;Without much official word from the company, it’s hard to say exactly how the reported breaches happened, and what any potential hackers have access to — though we’ll keep you updated if we hear back. With many security breaches, the advice is to change your password and make sure you have two-factor authentication turned on, but Visible &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Visible/comments/q53nk9/lack_of_2fa_on_visisble/"&gt;currently doesn’t support 2FA&lt;/a&gt;. Hopefully, incidents like this where some customers are seeing &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Buttered_Pecans/status/1447413221057462275?s=20"&gt;$1,000-plus charges&lt;/a&gt; on their credit cards from Visible may make that feature a higher priority.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723587/verizon-visible-cell-network-potential-hack-data-breach-phone-sales"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723587/verizon-visible-cell-network-potential-hack-data-breach-phone-sales</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T21:02:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T21:02:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>Trans employees at Netflix plan walkout even as one activist is reinstated following suspension</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ifQDrf5naa_aQggrLd67fPdSGdU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69987110/acastro_181101_1777_netflix_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kjhFcp"&gt;The trans employee resource group at Netflix is planning a company-wide walkout on October 20th to protest statements made by co-CEO Ted Sarandos regarding Dave Chappelle’s latest comedy special &lt;em&gt;The Closer&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pZgGSc"&gt;“Trans Lives Matter. Trans Rights Matter. And as an organization, Netflix has continually failed to show deep care in our mission to Entertain the World by repeatedly releasing content that harms the Trans community and continually failing to create content that represents and uplifts Trans content. We can and must do better!” wrote a leader of the trans ERG in an internal organizing message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B9XJPe"&gt;The event comes even as Netflix has reinstated Terra Field and two other employees who were &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/11/22720724/netflix-suspends-trans-employee-tweeted-dave-chappelle-the-closer"&gt;suspended after attending a director-level meeting they were not invited to&lt;/a&gt;. Field had recently posted a viral tweet thread about the Dave Chappelle special, saying it “attacks the trans community, and the very validity of transness.” Field was not aware that she was not supposed to attend the meeting, according to people familiar with the situation. Netflix now plans to issue guidance to employees regarding its meeting attendance policy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="leqh9K"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Netflix has reinstated me after finding that there was no ill-intent in my attending the QBR meeting. I've included the statement I requested below.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I'm going to take a few days off to decompress and try to figure out where I'm at. At the very least, I feel vindicated. &lt;a href="https://t.co/lYxemYgRkJ"&gt;pic.twitter.com/lYxemYgRkJ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Terra Field (@RainofTerra) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RainofTerra/status/1448097310026747908?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 13, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="EtmH3e"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Netflix suspends trans employee who tweeted about Dave Chappelle special ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/11/22720724/netflix-suspends-trans-employee-tweeted-dave-chappelle-the-closer"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="pTrgTL"&gt;Netflix employees say that comments made by co-CEO Ted Sarandos have only inflamed the situation. On October 8th, the executive sent an internal email saying the company would not be taking down the special. He added that he didn’t believe Chappelle’s stand-up crossed a line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="id__9gqde7xl32s"&gt;Sarandos later wrote a second memo saying: “Our hope is that you can be hugely inspired by entertaining the world, while also living with titles you strongly believe have no place on Netflix. This will not be the last title that causes some of you to wonder if you can still love Netflix. I sincerely hope that you can.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YP8ItO"&gt;In the special, Chappelle addressed critiques he’s gotten from the LGBTQ community — then doubled down on his jokes about trans people. The stand-up set has been widely slammed by trans activists and groups like GLAAD and the National Black Justice Coalition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OrZdr3"&gt;Internally, organizers wrote: “As we’ve discussed through Slack, email, text, and everything in between our leadership has shown us they do not uphold the values to which we are held. Between the numerous emails and non-answers that have been given, we have been told explicitly that we somehow cannot understand the nuance of certain content.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723592/netflix-trans-employees-walkout-statements-ceo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723592/netflix-trans-employees-walkout-statements-ceo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung announces Unpacked 2 event for Wednesday Oct 20th, right after Apple and Google</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KVR4JRpTmrHFcTSVE6s5D6S9qBk=/0x0:1013x675/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69986975/Samsung_Galaxy_Unpacked_Part2_Static_Samsung.com.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GKa0mn"&gt;Samsung has just sent out invitations for an event it is holding online on Wednesday, October 20th at 7AM PT / 10AM ET. It’s called “Galaxy Unpacked Part 2,” which is possibly an indication that rather than all new Galaxy phones, we may be seeing iterations on existing ones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jLUUSo"&gt;With Samsung’s announcement, we’ll now have an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722112/apple-october-2021-event-rumors-macbook-mac-mini-airpods-m1x"&gt;Apple event on Monday&lt;/a&gt; (where we are expecting new MacBook Pros), &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22691850/google-pixel-6-event-2021-fall-announcement"&gt;Google’s Pixel 6 launch on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;, and now Samsung’s apparently smaller event on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HqhR10"&gt;In addition to the invite’s image, Samsung’s newsroom post announcing the event hints at some kind of personalization for Galaxy devices: “Our users are multifaceted and live life in so many colorful, interesting, and unique ways. As such, the technology they use every day should reflect their individuality. Join Galaxy Unpacked Part 2 on October 20 to see how Samsung is opening up new experiences for self-expression through technology.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="85GIiz"&gt;That could mean anything, but it does seem to hint at new colors of the Galaxy phones or maybe even a full-on customization option. I could imagine building a Z Flip 3 with my choice of colors on each side of the fold, for example, and the teaser image may hint at just that. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/1/21407750/samsungs-galaxy-z-fold-2-price-release-date-hinge-screen-durability"&gt;With the Z Fold 2,&lt;/a&gt; Samsung offered customers the option to choose their own accent color for the hinge, though that option went away on the Z Fold 3 (thus far, anyway). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="H85ZA6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s going to be a very busy week&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FWsqIi"&gt;Of course, no customization program has come &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/8/5/4588922/moto-x-review"&gt;close to the original Moto X&lt;/a&gt;, which let people chose any number of different color options and even materials for their phone — including bamboo. It seems unlikely that Samsung will be willing to go that far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T0UJLu"&gt;What seems even more unlikely is the Galaxy S21 FE, a lower-cost “fan edition” of the Galaxy S21 that’s been kicking around the rumor mill for a while now. It’s less likely mainly because the S21 FE is currently in a kind of limbo where it’s either been delayed or cancelled because of the chip shortage. &lt;a href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/galaxy-s22-delayed-galaxy-s21-fe-quiet-launch-january/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sammobile&lt;/em&gt; reports that Samsung is still considering a January launch for the S21 FE&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="veyIZQ"&gt;Regardless of what Samsung announces on Wednesday the 20th, it will have a hard time getting attention after all the Sturm (Apple) and Drang (Google) the previous two days. Though perhaps picking Wednesday is Samsung’s strategic attempt to wrest some interest away from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/9/22718007/google-pixel-6-leak-teases-magic-eraser-camera-five-years-android-security-updates"&gt;the Pixel 6&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LnDwLD"&gt;Speaking of it being a busy week, we also have &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s 10 year event called &lt;a href="https://www.voxmediaevents.com/ontheverge/Podcast"&gt;On The Verge&lt;/a&gt; on Friday and Saturday. If you’re in New York City, tickets are available at a &lt;a href="https://www.voxmediaevents.com/ontheverge/Podcast"&gt;discount with code $99NOW right here&lt;/a&gt;. This leaves Thursday the 21st open for another tech company to announce something. Has anybody heard from OnePlus lately?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zLbaaV"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723435/samsung-announces-unpacked-2-event-galaxy-colors"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723435/samsung-announces-unpacked-2-event-galaxy-colors</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T19:48:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T19:48:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>G4 TV returns November 16th with Attack of the Show, Xplay and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Se2pPUXQYumH6bXHBAPSMGdiEQo=/0x0:1023x682/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69986952/g4_teaser.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: G4 TV&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HzvaLy"&gt;After more than a year of teasing and occasional streams, G4 &lt;a href="https://g4tv.com/g4-launch-nov16"&gt;will make its return as a linear TV channel on November 16th&lt;/a&gt;. So far, the channel is confirmed to appear on Comcast/Xfinity, Verizon Fios, Cox, and Philo. Since announcing its return last year, G4 has put out some reunion content plus &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/29/22254953/g4b4-revival-twitch-youtube-attack-of-the-show-x-play"&gt;occasional streams on Twitch&lt;/a&gt;, where the network will maintain a “multi-year promotional and commercial partnership.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eCZHBq"&gt;Though the original G4 faded out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/12/8/3744200/g4-rebrand-esquire-channel"&gt;when it got rebranded as the Esquire Channel&lt;/a&gt; about eight years ago, the network’s new mantra is that “we never stopped playing.” Network president Russell Arons writes in a statement that G4 “can’t wait to have our fans join us in our hilarious and fairly preposterous sandbox.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6pefG0"&gt;When G4 comes back next month, some of the programming and hosts should be very familiar. &lt;em&gt;Attack of the Show&lt;/em&gt; is back with host Kevin Pereira, while &lt;em&gt;Xplay &lt;/em&gt;(no longer X-Play) is again in the review business under the auspices of Adam Sessler. Along with some esports-focused series, G4 has also obtained US streaming rights to &lt;em&gt;Sasuke&lt;/em&gt;, aka &lt;em&gt;Ninja Warrior&lt;/em&gt;, for old-school fans who watched the original Japanese version on its cable channel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UwWbyM"&gt;A new highlight is G4’s &lt;em&gt;Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons Limited Series&lt;/em&gt;, a follow-up to D&amp;amp;D Live 2021 created in a partnership with Wizards of the Coast. Expect the show to feature “a mix of G4 talent, veteran D&amp;amp;D players, and celebrities” as they proceed through four campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ns6Vte"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The rise of D&amp;amp;amp;D liveplay is changing how fans approach roleplaying","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/16/16666344/dungeons-and-dragons-twitch-roleplay-rpgs-critical-role-streaming-gaming"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="htFrsj"&gt;If your particular carrier or service isn’t listed here, Adam Sessler notes in a tweet that there will be more announcements as the network gets closer to launch. G4’s new programming will air from a dedicated studio in Burbank, CA, designed by the same architecture firm behind Red Bull HQ and Esports Stadium Arlington.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2QLDCU"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;bear in mind the content is also live on &lt;br&gt;Twitch as well. We're intending to make &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/G4TV?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@G4TV&lt;/a&gt; as readily available to as many people possible worldwide. Plus there are even more distribution channels to be announced in the coming weeks. &lt;a href="https://t.co/FZmy8EKq3n"&gt;https://t.co/FZmy8EKq3n&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Adam “Halloween Reference" Sessler (@AdamSessler) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AdamSessler/status/1447920041312194561?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 12, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22722479/g4-tv-launch-november-16-gaming-tv"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22722479/g4-tv-launch-november-16-gaming-tv</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T19:26:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T19:26:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix is adding the original Cowboy Bebop so you can watch it all before the live action adaptation</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8_tyR55YNTZj4p2dNrHVzrlso6U=/28x0:1051x682/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69986898/Screen_Shot_2021_10_12_at_4.20.28_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An image from &lt;/em&gt;Cowboy Bebop&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/NetflixGeeked/status/1448060919595126787" target="_blank"&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nEggb0"&gt;Netflix is adding the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NetflixGeeked/status/1448060919595126787"&gt;original &lt;em&gt;Cowboy Bebop&lt;/em&gt; anime series&lt;/a&gt; to its catalog on October 21st, giving you about a month to watch it all ahead of the live-action series’ debut on November 19th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wHihKP"&gt;This is great news for me personally. I’ve been extremely intrigued by what Netflix has shown from the live-action series — which so far has included a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22634321/netflix-cowboy-bebop-release-date-john-cho-photos"&gt;series of images&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yq2N-9EmedA"&gt;opening title sequence&lt;/a&gt;, which is inspired heavily &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9Go4J1RaeuM"&gt;by the one from the anime&lt;/a&gt; —  but I haven’t seen the original show for myself. Now that the whole show will be on Netflix, I can see it all with a subscription to just one streaming service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="frpIUS"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Bang… COWBOY BEBOP, the original anime series, is coming to Netflix worldwide on October 21 &lt;a href="https://t.co/BN3LF2XVSl"&gt;pic.twitter.com/BN3LF2XVSl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Netflix Geeked (@NetflixGeeked) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NetflixGeeked/status/1448060919595126787?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 12, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TONzqb"&gt;It’s unclear if the move to Netflix means that &lt;em&gt;Cowboy Bebop&lt;/em&gt; will be removed from Hulu, Funimation, or any of the other streaming platforms &lt;a href="https://www.justwatch.com/us/tv-show/cowboy-bebop-2001"&gt;where it’s currently available&lt;/a&gt;. It’s also unclear based only on Netflix’s tweet if the show will be updated or remastered in any way.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723502/netflix-original-cowboy-bebop-anime-watch-before-live-action-adaptation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723502/netflix-original-cowboy-bebop-anime-watch-before-live-action-adaptation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T18:52:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T18:52:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix calls Squid Game its ‘biggest ever series at launch’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/G6RxfL3Ai631T6YxSzglRKURO8c=/382x206:2463x1593/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69986799/Screen_Shot_2021_10_12_at_3.32.44_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9tbPJY"&gt;Netflix’s hugely popular series &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/6/22713623/netflix-edit-squid-game-phone-number-prank-calls"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Squid Game&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has become its biggest title ever at launch, the company said Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QVXbpl"&gt;The company’s Netflix Geeked account &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/netflixgeeked/status/1448045572200534022?s=21"&gt;tweeted Monday&lt;/a&gt; that Hwang Dong-Hyuk’s survival thriller reached 111 million global accounts in its first 17 days on the service. Additionally, &lt;em&gt;Squid Game&lt;/em&gt; is the first Netflix series to surpass 100 million in its first 28 days on the service, a spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. Netflix typically uses &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22697364/netflix-viewing-data-code-2021"&gt;28-day windows&lt;/a&gt; to measure the performance of a title on its platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lUF326"&gt;The spokesperson confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the figures it shared are based on the number of accounts that watched the series for at least two minutes, its standard metric for ranking titles (though it has used &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/21/20924954/netflix-viewers-numbers-metrics-data-stranger-things-tuca-bertie-oa-renew-cancel"&gt;additional measurements&lt;/a&gt; to track the success of titles in the past).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uXyywR"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;It took more than 10 years for Hwang Dong-hyuk to get Squid Game made.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It only took 17 days and 111M global fans to become our biggest ever series at launch (and the first to surpass 100M when it premiered). &lt;a href="https://t.co/zVF8GjHIkQ"&gt;pic.twitter.com/zVF8GjHIkQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Netflix Geeked (@NetflixGeeked) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NetflixGeeked/status/1448045572200534022?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 12, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="u3h58G"&gt;Since debuting on Netflix on September 17th, &lt;em&gt;Squid Game&lt;/em&gt; has reached the no. 1 position on the streaming service in 94 countries — every country in the world where the service features a top 10 list, the company spokesperson said. Additionally, the show has held the no. 1 position for 21 days in the US, shattering the record for a non-English language title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ukWTCy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Squid Game&lt;/em&gt; was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/6/22713623/netflix-edit-squid-game-phone-number-prank-calls"&gt;previously announced&lt;/a&gt; as the first Korean title to reach the top spot in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723452/netflix-squid-game-biggest-ever-show-at-launch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723452/netflix-squid-game-biggest-ever-show-at-launch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
