<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-06-08T12:22:54-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-08T12:22:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-08T12:22:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>Aqara M2 ecosystem review: a smart home for less</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Why spend more?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="nhD158"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AqaraSmarthouse/status/1402247808489508864"&gt;Aqara M2 smart home hub officially launches in the US today&lt;/a&gt;, making it the ideal time to take a deeper look at the company’s inventory of inexpensive smart home devices that work with Amazon Alexa, Google Assistant, and Apple HomeKit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JtqviP"&gt;While Aqara might not have the brand cachet of Philips Hue or Samsung SmartThings, it’s been around since 2016 — an eternity for smart home companies. The Aqara brand is owned by Lumi United Technology, a Xiaomi ecosystem company based in Shenzhen, China. Aqara entered the US market in 2019 and now claims to serve over 2 million customers across 192 countries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HWqIAh"&gt;Aqara bills the M2 as the company’s “&lt;a href="https://www.aqara.com/us/product/hub-m2"&gt;most advanced and future-proof smart home hub&lt;/a&gt;.” It connects to your home network via ethernet or 2.4GHz Wi-Fi and the Zigbee 3.0 radio controls up to 128 related devices like smart bulbs, switches, and sensors. It’ll even control infrared devices like air conditioners, fans, TVs, or humidifiers thanks to a 360-degree IR blaster that circles the hub. One day “soon,” Aqara says the M2 will also control Bluetooth LE sensors and bulbs, for example, but this wasn’t ready for me to test. The M2 is fitted with a small speaker than can be used for security alerts, a doorbell, or alarm clock. The whole thing is powered from a 5V 1A Micro-USB port, meaning the M2 hub can run for up to 30 hours when plugged into a typical 10,000mAh portable charger in the event of power failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="db1qpl"&gt;I’ve been intrigued by Aqara for some time, so I decided to test the new M2 hub alongside the older M1S hub and 12 Aqara devices here in Europe where the M2 has been shipping for a while (it was announced in 2019). I also ran everything through HomeKit since the M2 takes advantage of both adaptive lighting and HomeKit secure video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="85adXU"&gt;&lt;q&gt;More capable than expected&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wHa50T"&gt;All in all, setup was quite easy and intuitive, and several of Aqara’s devices proved more capable than I expected. There were quirks, but they’re easy to overlook for the price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lAW3WL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10596437"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eMYFv2"&gt;My Aqara test network consisted of 16 Aqara devices spread across three floors of a narrow but tall Amsterdam home. I placed the new &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Aqara-Control-Automation-Supports-Assistant/dp/B08Y1PJZZH?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$57.99&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.de/-/en/Control-Gateway-HomeKit-Compatibility-Ethernet/dp/B08X23Z55L?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;€56.99&lt;/a&gt; M2 hub in my office on the top floor (third) and the older M1S hub in the living room on the ground floor (first) mainly because it has a very useful nightlight built in. The M1S is also totally self contained in a unit that plugs into any wall outlet without any cabling mess. Although my router is on the ground floor I have ethernet runs to my office, making the distance to the M2 a non-issue. With this setup, I was able to ensure top-to-bottom Zigbee 3.0 network coverage for all the Aqara child devices: six bridged to the M2 and six bridged to the M1S. The Aqara Home app makes it easy to view signal strength for each child device on a scale that ranges from poor to acceptable to good, with graphs showing how the strength changes over time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="znG2Xn"&gt;Unfortunately, you can’t move child devices between hubs. This could be useful in cases where you move a sensor originally assigned to, say, the M1S to a room that receives a stronger signal from the M2. Instead, you have to remove the sensor from the original hub and add it back to the new hub. Fortunately, the process isn’t destructive as it maintains any automations already created in the Aqara app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HJbDPD"&gt;Here’s a list of all the Aqara devices I tested alongside Aqara’s recommended retail prices in USD and Euros where available: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="ALVFeb"&gt;One Camera Hub G2H (&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Aqara-Security-Family-Friendly-Wireless-Surveillance/dp/B08F2DBP3Y?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$64.99&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.de/-/en/Aqara-Camera-Hub-G2H-HomeKit/dp/B08X1PSG8K?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;€75.99&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="VXuz4d"&gt;One Wireless Remote Switch EU (double rocker) (&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.de/-/en/WRS-R02-Wireless-Remote-Switch-Version/dp/B094QL17GY?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;€29.99&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0KrNOT"&gt;One Smart Wall Switch H1 EU (no neutral) (&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.de/-/en/WRS-R02-Wireless-Remote-Switch-Version/dp/B094QL17GY?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;€39.99&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uC0s82"&gt;One Smart Plug (&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Aqara-12LM-ZNCZ-Smart-White/dp/B07CJ2MM6Z?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$29.99 &lt;/a&gt;/ &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.de/-/en/Aqara-Smart-Plug-EU-HomeKit/dp/B087M8LF63?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;€32.99&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="E9hG8S"&gt;Four Door and Window sensors (&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Aqara-MCCGQ11LM-Window-Sensor-White/dp/B07D37VDM3?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$17.99&lt;/a&gt; /&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.de/-/en/WSDCGQ11LM-Aqara-Door-and-Window/dp/B07D37FKGY?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt; €16.99&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7UDpoq"&gt;One Water Leak Sensor (&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Aqara-11LM-SJCGQ-Water-Sensor/dp/B07D39MSZS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$18.99&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.de/-/en/SJCGQ11LM-Aqara-Door-and-Window/dp/B07D39MSZS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;€21.99&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AXiqPc"&gt;One Vibration Sensor ($19.49 / &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.de/-/en/Aqara-DJT11LM-vibration-sensor-detector/dp/B07PJT939B?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;€18.99&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="IWvQ5e"&gt;One Motion Sensor (&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Aqara-RTCGQ11LM-Motion-Sensor-White/dp/B07D1CRRVF?ref_=ast_sto_dp&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$20.49&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.de/-/en/RTCGQ11LM-Aqara-B07D1CRRVF-Motion-Sensor/dp/B07D1CRRVF?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;€23.99&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0D4GBF"&gt;One Temperature and Humidity Sensor (&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Aqara-WSDCGQ11LM-Temperature-Humidity-Sensor/dp/B07D37FKGY?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$19.99 &lt;/a&gt;/ &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.de/-/en/Homekit-Temperature-Humidity-Compatible-WSDCGQ11LM/dp/B087LWH5L1?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;€18.99&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="4mPlBM"&gt;My test network is fairly representative of the Aqara ecosystem, which varies in availability by region. Generally speaking, the &lt;a href="https://www.aqara.com/us/products.html"&gt;US has the least amount of choice&lt;/a&gt; compared to &lt;a href="https://www.aqara.com/eu/products.html"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt; where Aqara also ships lightbulbs, a greater variety of wired and wireless dimmers and switches, a smart door lock, and even a controller for window shades. &lt;a href="https://www.aqara.com/cn/productIndex"&gt;China has far greater choice&lt;/a&gt; still, much of which will likely eventually trickle out to the other Aqara regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TFN9xw"&gt;So, let’s briefly dig into each of these Aqara child devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kkc30dZUP7ZFphgASHlyUi7rsNU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22644693/verge_DSC_4403_2040pxl.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Aqara M2 Hub (left), G2H camera hub (center), and M1S hub (right).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="J8gfei"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Camera hub G2H&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="SbAEE9"&gt;As the name implies, the G2H camera has the unique ability to also act as a hub for Aqara child devices. This can be useful for smart home newbies who aren’t ready to fully commit to Aqara but would still like an indoor camera that’s compatible with Apple’s excellent HomeKit Secure Video service. For example, you could drop the G2H into your home network and pair an Aqara Vibration Sensor to it that would tell the camera to start recording if a window was broken or forced open, without ever having to install an Aqara M1S or M2 hub. The G2H can connect up to 64 Aqara child devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JPGcB2"&gt;The G2H camera also features two-way audio, ultra-wide 140-degree coverage, 1080p resolution, infrared night vision, definable activity zones, and a magnetic mount for easy placement on tables, walls, or the ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OtCnA7"&gt;The G2H can record video in three ways: to the Aqara cloud, to a local microSD card (up to 32GB), or to your iCloud drive with HomeKit Secure Video enabled. I disabled the Aqara cloud recording features in favor of both microSD and HomeKit Secure Video (requires a compatible iCloud subscription of 200GB or more). Recordings to microSD benefit from an event timeline. In my home for example, I can scroll the timeline quickly by looking at the colored bars that signal the front and back doors opening, or the booze cabinet opening (I have teens). HomeKit Secure Video allows me to confidently flip on AI face recognition linked to my iCloud library so that I receive notifications when family members come home. HomeKit Secure Video also stores videos for up to 10 days without affecting my storage quota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CxTqgp"&gt;Aqara homes can be configured in one of six predefined regions: China Mainland, Europe, United States, South Korea, Russia, and Other. When selecting Europe, like I did, I’m protected by European GDPR law as explained in &lt;a href="http://cdn.aqara.com/cdn/app/mainland/h5/index.html#/privacyPolicy_GDPR?language=en"&gt;Aqara’s EU privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;. Aqara has its own &lt;a href="http://cdn.aqara.com/cdn/app/mainland/h5/index.html#/privacy/general/en?language=en"&gt;privacy policy for the United States&lt;/a&gt;, which you should read if you’re concerned how this Chinese company might handle your data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tKj2DI"&gt;Overall, I really like the G2H as a do-it-all camera for the home, especially for the price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/53IhWN-TacMmDGLPlCN2I7eYaUw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22644688/verge_DSC_4457_2040pxl.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Smart Wall Switch H1 installed in my kitchen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tQMKxp"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wired and wireless switches and smart outlet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="YaPKYW"&gt;I tested two Aqara switches: the &lt;a href="https://www.aqara.com/eu/product/smart-wall-switch-h1-no-neutral"&gt;Smart Wall Switch H1 EU (single rocker, no neutral)&lt;/a&gt; and the double rocker Wireless Remote Switch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Yi5sIsrZ7RpeJfyVNH1F5A_rxFQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22644685/verge_IMG_7921_2040pxl.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Installing the H1 Switch in the original socket.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1suScRBNx04zDG-EvAWCcYevS1A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22644686/verge_IMG_7923_2040pxl.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wiring the H1 into household electricity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PuO9Vf"&gt;The H1 wall switch is powered from the household wiring like any other light switch but results in making standard lightbulbs smart. I installed mine in the kitchen to control four existing LED spotlights that illuminate the countertop during food preparation. In addition to enabling Google Assistant, Siri, and Alexa voice control, I was able to define an automation in the Aqara app so that the lights will automatically turn off after 30 minutes whenever anyone is making a late-night snack and forgets to turn off the spots (teens!). I like the finish of the H1 and the reassuring heavy-mechanical &lt;em&gt;click&lt;/em&gt; it makes when pressed. Aqara also makes &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Aqara-REQUIRES-Automation-Compatible-Assistant/dp/B081ZQWX1F?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;US versions&lt;/a&gt; of these switches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QSC0n5"&gt;Although the Wireless Remote Switch shares the same form factor and tactility of the H1, it’s an entirely different product. First, it’s battery powered and meant to control other Aqara devices like smart lightbulbs or smart plugs. By default, it’s added in what Aqara calls a “high-speed click mode” which I immediately changed to “multi-function mode” to expose the single-click, double-click, and long-press actions to HomeKit for both the left and right buttons of the double-rocker switch.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hybaulH5KQCfy3YAf4-onAMKc-E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22644687/verge_DSC_4463_2040pxl.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Aqara Wireless Remote Switch next to an old Hue remote.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5T0MTP"&gt;In the Apple Home app, I assigned a single press of the left button to turn on the Aqara Smart Plug behind my TV (with a Govee Immersion LED light strip plugged in), my Apple TV box, and LG OLED TV; and defined a double press to turn it all back off. While the Aqara app can show the energy usage of the Smart Plug over time, it can’t expose this information to HomeKit, nor can it use the information as a trigger even in the Aqara app. Ideally, I’d just plug my TV into the Aqara Smart Plug and kick off a bunch of automations when the plug detected that the TV had just turned on or off. Alas, no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JZ8r0o"&gt;I couldn’t test the in-wall Single Switch Module T1 from Aqara as I was sent the version that requires a neutral wire. Nevertheless, I’m happy to see Aqara making these for people who &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447008/hue-wall-module-make-any-switch-smart"&gt;prefer to make their existing switches smart instead of their lightbulbs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RgGKZ1IyuXKJiGcKkDyBTUANZe0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22644689/verge_DSC_4440_2040pxl.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Aqara Motion Sensor also contains a light sensor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="167PIW"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Door, window, motion, vibration, temperature &amp;amp; humidity, and water sensors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Sdk44k"&gt;Aqara sensors offer great value and functionality that the company claims will last for two or more years on a single coin battery. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L0ttdF"&gt;The nondescript white Door and Window sensors are particularly notable. For just $17.99 / €16.99  each, you can attach the little sensors on all your doors and windows with double-sided tape to enable any number of smart home scenarios. I have a HomeKit automation that sends me an alert when my roof hatch is open and rain is expected in the next 15 minutes (or has already arrived). I also have them configured to send alerts when the front door or freezer door have been left open too long. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="icxRPS"&gt;The Door and Window sensors are also useful when tied to any of the four native HomeKit alarm modes (Home, Away, Night, and Off) supported by the M2 Hub (the M1S only supports on and off). In that way, the Aqara M2 can be used to create a basic home security and self-monitoring solution without having to pay any subscription fees. However, the M2’s speaker is anemic at best, so triggered alarms won’t be heard by any neighbors and are barely audible on other floors when music is playing. Anyone needing a dependable home security solution should look elsewhere for a professionally monitored service.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Sq8VnND7b4DG1jRg0O4wzP3mPcU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22644690/verge_DSC_4428_2040pxl.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The two halves of a Door and Window Sensor shown far apart and reporting “open” in the app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fXggUf"&gt;The $20.49 / €23.99 Aqara Motion sensors are also incredibly useful. I configured the sensor to automatically trigger a Hue bulb whenever anyone enters the laundry room. It then shuts off the light automatically after five minutes. I love the tilting mount than can be placed just about anywhere, as long as you don’t mind the double-sided tape. The tape is convenient until you have to move the sensor and potentially strip paint or paper from the wall. The motion sensor has a reasonably fast reset time of one minute and includes a light sensor in the device. While the light sensor can’t be used as a trigger in HomeKit, it can in the Aqara app. Overall, the Aqara sensor is reasonably priced compared to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22310841/ikea-shortcut-button-motion-sensor-homekit-smart-home-review-test"&gt;Ikea’s Tradfri motion sensor&lt;/a&gt; with slower three-minute reset, no light sensor, and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com/?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https://www.ikea.com/us/en/p/tradfri-wireless-motion-sensor-white-60377655/&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https://www.theverge.com/22310841/ikea-shortcut-button-motion-sensor-homekit-smart-home-review-test&amp;amp;xcust=___vg__p_22074882__t_w__r_google.com__d_D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$14.99&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com/?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https://www.ikea.com/nl/nl/p/tradfri-draadloze-bewegingssensor-wit-70429913/&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https://www.theverge.com/22310841/ikea-shortcut-button-motion-sensor-homekit-smart-home-review-test&amp;amp;xcust=___vg__p_22074882__t_w__r_google.com__d_D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;€12.95&lt;/a&gt; price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b1egbn"&gt;I was dubious of the Aqara Vibration Sensor before testing it out but eventually figured out a way for it to be useful. It detects vibration, tilts, and drops in addition to being configurable for three sensitivity settings (low, medium, high). Tilt is useful on a mailbox opening, for example, assuming your Zigbee signal will reach the end of a driveway, while vibration can be useful for detecting broken windows and identifying when the washer and dryer are running. I put mine on a tilting cabinet door to alert me when someone is accessing my prized collection of brown booze (teens!!).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/muRf_OlLrqMc4P-coJySRmDG_Qc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22644691/verge_DSC_4426_2040pxl.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aqara Water Leak Sensor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="kYXklu"&gt;The Aqara Temperature Sensor and Humidity and Water Leak Sensor also work as advertised. The Temp sensor, like many similar cheap sensors, is inaccurate when exposed to direct sunlight, measuring almost twice the actual air temperature at times. Otherwise, it’s useful for triggering a Smart Plug to turn on a fan, humidifier, or smart blinds. Aqara envisions its Water Leak Sensor being used to send a signal to the Aqara Smart Plug to shut off a smart water valve in the case of a water leak. I currently have my review sensor sitting in a saucer just inside my roof hatch to alert me when rain comes inside. I’m tempted to try &lt;a href="https://home-assistant-guide.com/2021/02/03/turn-an-aqara-water-leak-sensor-into-an-instant-rain-meter/"&gt;this hack&lt;/a&gt; to turn it into a real-time rain sensor so I can prevent the water from accumulating in the first place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zc0LCz"&gt;The M2 seems to offer a slight advantage over the M1S in terms of Zigbee coverage. For example, the M2 on my third floor was able to maintain a “poor” connection to the Water Sensor when moved to the first floor, but the M1S on the first floor lost connection to the same Water Sensor when moved to the third. But if coverage is your issue, then it’s better to plop another powered Aqara device into your network (like a Wall Switch or Smart Plug) which also double as range extenders for the Zigbee mesh network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="iqz9Wo"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;360-degree infrared control &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="uZ17pr"&gt;Although I don’t have much use for a 360-degree IR blaster, it’s neat that the M2 includes it, I guess. There are plenty of IR controllable home devices like TVs, window shades, air conditioners, and fans in the world that would benefit from being included in the smart home. Just keep in mind that it’ll require line of sight visibility to the black plastic M2 hub, which looks better in a utility closet than out on a shelf. Nevertheless, I did test the IR capabilities on a handful of devices. I was able to train the M2 to control a cheap strand of LED lightbulbs and my LG OLED TV, yet it failed with another strand of LED lights and my old remote-controlled Hunter Douglas blinds. When successful, added devices can be controlled in the Aqara app and Aqara automations but aren’t exposed to HomeKit at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="bFCEEA"&gt;Overall, I’ve been pleasantly surprised by the M2 hub and the Aqara ecosystem of products. They’re inexpensive like Ikea’s Zigbee-based Home Smart lineup, which also works with HomeKit, Google Assistant, and Alexa. But Aqara devices are much easier to set up and frequently offer more features and better build quality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HyOKZ3"&gt;The M2 is mostly an improvement over previous Aqara hubs with support for Zigbee 3.0 (and more child devices), reliable ethernet, HomeKit’s nuanced security modes, and IR control for those who really need it. But it also lacks the clever nightlight, louder speaker, and minimalistic design I enjoyed with the old M1S hub. Aqara also wouldn’t commit to updating the M2 with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/11/22430666/matter-project-chip-smart-home-partnership-apple-amazon-google-zigbee"&gt;Matter / CHIP support&lt;/a&gt; when asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="0kKsO6"&gt;So while I can’t say it’s the “most advanced and future-proof smart home hub” ever, as Aqara claims, I can confirm that building a DIY smart home around the Aqara ecosystem of feature-rich devices is relatively easy, won’t break the bank, and maintains compatibility with Apple, Google, and Amazon smart homes. And really, what more can you ask for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dQdNBy"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Thomas Ricker / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22523877/aqara-smart-home-review-m2-hub-homekit-alexa-google-assistant"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22523877/aqara-smart-home-review-m2-hub-homekit-alexa-google-assistant</id>
    <author>
      <name>Thomas Ricker</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-08T12:20:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-08T12:20:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Playdate preorders begin next month, and here are the first games</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w6CVApkJ5iiy8GHBok-Z8qSwyiE=/0x1:2000x1334/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69423056/June_hello.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PRAsaD"&gt;Panic has announced that the Playdate, its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/4/22466184/panic-playdate-handheld-price-double-season-one-games-update-preorder"&gt;$179 handheld console&lt;/a&gt; with a crank and a black-and-white screen, will be available to preorder in July with shipping starting later in the year. The company doesn’t have a specific date lined up just yet, but says it’ll provide at least a week’s notice before orders open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IAcSPO"&gt;Panic is doing its best to avoid a PS5/RTX 3080-type stock situation by implementing its own ordering system. “The sooner you order, the sooner you’ll get one, but we’re not going to close the door on you,” says co-founder Cabel Sasser in a video update.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XU9JwDeCEbM3I7qIEJS37ZLb2so=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22644670/Playdate_photo_1.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="lkHHDN"&gt;The company is also announcing an adorable stereo dock accessory for the Playdate, which makes it look like an old TV and works as both a Bluetooth speaker and a pen holder. Panic hasn’t given pricing or release information for the dock yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CdjhiQ"&gt;Finally, Panic has announced 21 out of the 24 titles that will feature in the Playdate’s first “season.” Details are intentionally being kept secret until each game is automatically downloaded onto the device; owners will get two games a week over 12 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XRnkny"&gt;Here are title screens for all 21 games:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UTfEOQNyA3t1w2DKDRdDc0BgZvo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22644673/Playdate_Season_One_games.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MRx7wb"&gt;And here’s the list of games and their developers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="VDnTep"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Crankin’s Time Travel Adventure&lt;/em&gt; by uvula (Keita Takahashi, Ryan Mohler), Matthew Grimm, and Shaun Inman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vlPEZX"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Battleship Godios&lt;/em&gt; by TPM.Co Soft Works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="HC3EII"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Casual Birder&lt;/em&gt; by Diego Garcia with music by Max Coburn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="MJjEeT"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;DemonQuest 85&lt;/em&gt; by Alex Ashby, Lawrence Bishop, Duncan Fyfe, Belinda Leung, and Jared Emerson-Johnson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Hnk3ts"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Echoic Memory&lt;/em&gt; by Samantha Kalman, Everest Pipkin, Carol Mertz, and Rachelle Viola&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Tifk6H"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Executive Golf DX&lt;/em&gt; by davemakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uLm7V3"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Flipper Lifter&lt;/em&gt; by Serenity Forge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3wyTxd"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Forrest Byrnes: Up in Smoke&lt;/em&gt; by Nels Anderson and Christina “castpixel” Neofotistou&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8H3b2s"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Hyper Meteor&lt;/em&gt; by Vertex Pop (Mobeen Fikree, Robby Duguay, and h heron)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="zf1dVF"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Lost Your Marbles&lt;/em&gt; by Sweet Baby Inc. &amp;amp; Friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="UKrNbe"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Omaze&lt;/em&gt; by Gregory Kogos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JYKfxa"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Pick Pack Pup&lt;/em&gt; by Nic Magnier and Arthur Hamer (he/him) with music by Logan Gabriel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="y8ljUT"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Questy Chess&lt;/em&gt; by Dadako&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="1OMVF8"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Ratcheteer&lt;/em&gt; by Shaun Inman, Matthew Grimm, and Charlie Davis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AjQuDI"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Sasquatchers&lt;/em&gt; by Chuck Jordan with music and sound by Jared Emerson-Johnson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2OEwub"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Snak&lt;/em&gt; by Zach Gage with art by Neven Mrgan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="oPnv2p"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Spellcorked!&lt;/em&gt; by Jada Gibbs, Nick Splendorr, Ryan Splendorr, and Tony Ghostbrite with music by A Shell in the Pit (Em Halberstadt)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="GTCZ0P"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Zipper&lt;/em&gt; by Bennett Foddy &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kKbB0o"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Saturday Edition&lt;/em&gt; by Chris Makris with music by A Shell in the Pit (Gord McGladdery, Alfonso Salinas)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="XXXG5Z"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Whitewater Wipeout&lt;/em&gt; by Chuhai Labs (Giles Goddard, Mark Lentz, Peter Traylor, Hero Liao, Remy Thor, Charlie March, Kensaku Nakata, Zach Aikman, Mihoko Terao, and Kinsey Burke)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="JZxyFI"&gt;The Playdate has had a long road to market. It was first announced in May 2019, and we got our first look at the console itself &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/1/18648304/playdate-hands-on-panic-keita-takahashi-bitsummit"&gt;the following month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22523929/playdate-preorder-game-lineup-dock-announced"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22523929/playdate-preorder-game-lineup-dock-announced</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-08T12:18:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-08T12:18:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>macOS and tvOS are getting spatial audio support with the AirPods Pro and Max</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cldvICuW5DevDXGBeqxPhGZAFA8=/90x0:2790x1800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69423054/Screen_Shot_2021_06_08_at_10.48.24_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QbWXbF"&gt;Apple is extending support for spatial audio to macOS and tvOS. The feature will work with the company’s high-end AirPods Pro and AirPods Max, using the devices’ built-in accelerometers and gyroscopes to create a 3D audio effect that tracks the listener’s head movements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KziSGB"&gt;Apple initially announced spatial audio for the AirPods Pro last year and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/2/21498931/apple-spatial-audio-airpods-pro-surround-sound-quick-auto-switching"&gt;impressed us with the feature’s immersive quality&lt;/a&gt;. At this year’s WWDC, the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523228/apple-music-lossless-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-features"&gt;extended support for spatial audio to Apple Music&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522889/apple-facetime-android-windows-web-ios-15-wwdc"&gt;FaceTime calls&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YjAYV5"&gt;According to a &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fnewsroom%2F2021%2F06%2Fmacos-monterey-introduces-powerful-features-to-get-more-done%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F8%2F22523914%2Fmacos-tvos-spatial-audio-support-airpods-pro-max" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; from Apple, spatial audio for macOS will only work with the AirPods Pro and Max on Macs with the company’s latest M1 chip and the macOS Monterey operating system. During this week’s WWDC &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/0TD96VTf0Xs?t=2357"&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt;, Apple said spatial audio would arrive on tvOS sometime “this fall,” offering a “full-surround experience” and “dynamic head tracking.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5IrFYs"&gt;Some &lt;a href="https://www.techradar.com/uk/news/tvos-and-macos-will-get-spatial-audio-support-for-airpods-pro-and-max"&gt;outlets&lt;/a&gt; are reporting that spatial audio on tvOS will only work with the Apple TV 4K, and it’s not clear what apps on the Apple TV will support the feature. Or when support for spatial audio through other headphones on either platform will be available. We’ve reached out to Apple to find out more and will update this story if we hear back.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22523914/macos-tvos-spatial-audio-support-airpods-pro-max"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22523914/macos-tvos-spatial-audio-support-airpods-pro-max</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-08T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-08T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sony announces WF-1000XM4 noise-canceling earbuds with LDAC and IPX4 water resistance</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0vMMuuTsWDKK31U5J1jXHs_XDmk=/0x50:1200x850/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69422893/WF_1000XM4_B_wearing_Mid.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Sony&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RXiwLY"&gt;After a few weeks of leaks, Sony has today formally announced its latest flagship true wireless earbuds. The new WF-1000XM4 earbuds cost $279.99, and the previous WF-1000XM3s, released in 2019, will remain in the company’s lineup at $229.99. The new headphones will be available in either black or light gray — both with gold accenting. They’re available starting today from retailers including &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WF-1000XM4-Industry-Canceling-Headphones/dp/B094C4VDJZ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and Best Buy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cypifD"&gt;Featuring a completely revamped design that’s 10 percent smaller than their predecessors, the 1000XM4 buds also have a new processing chip that results in improved noise cancellation “at all frequencies,” according to Sony. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5JRcEKrq1k0xtdu-mVpC4wLq48A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22644966/1000xm4.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Sony&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="0o2YVN"&gt;Battery life has been upped to eight hours of continuous playback when NC is enabled, which soundly beats competitors like the Apple AirPods Pro, Bose QuietComfort Earbuds, and Samsung Galaxy Buds Pro. The charging case has been significantly downsized and is 40 percent smaller than before. Aside from plugging in over USB-C, it also supports Qi wireless charging. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f3B2R1"&gt;Sony has also addressed a disappointing omission from the 1000XM3s: these new earbuds are rated IPX4 for water and sweat resistance. The 1000XM4s also have an updated voice call system that uses both beamforming mics and bone conduction sensors to improve performance. But here’s the one standout disappointment: there’s still no support for multipoint Bluetooth connections. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jAr07R"&gt;If you’re wondering how all of this shakes out, I’ve been using Sony’s new premium buds for several days. You can &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22287625"&gt;read my full review&lt;/a&gt; of them right now. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22524088/sony-wf-1000xm4-noise-canceling-earbuds-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22524088/sony-wf-1000xm4-noise-canceling-earbuds-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-08T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-08T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Loki’s first two episodes are a blast</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p-Pi8q7JATdzDCR631OFJVU10Uw=/642x0:3198x1704/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69422897/TPL2300_101_comp_v810.1037.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Marvel Studios&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;A promising start for the trickster’s debut on Disney Plus&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="WuWpFc"&gt;When &lt;a href="https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/c/482924/1084177/9358?subId1=VergeLoki&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.disneyplus.com%2Fseries%2Floki%2F6pARMvILBGzF" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Loki&lt;/a&gt; is first captured by an organization devoted to maintaining the purity of the timestream, it’s a bit like a trip to the DMV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AslUsU"&gt;His time at the TVA — otherwise known as the Time Variance Authority — includes taking a number to wait in line, walking through a metal detector-like security device, and verifying some paperwork. But there are some differences compared to getting your license renewed. Failing to queue up properly at the TVA can result in death. And that paperwork? It’s a massive stack consisting of literally everything Loki has ever said (including the two confused words he utters while standing in the office). It’s extremely funny to watch an all-powerful deity be forced through a confusing bureaucracy — and it’s the perfect way to start off the new &lt;em&gt;Loki&lt;/em&gt; series on Disney Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yHXydg"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This review contains light spoilers for the first two episodes of Loki.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OAg077"&gt;While Loki has been part of the MCU for a decade, his role has been somewhat scattershot: a handful of memorable appearances spread across six films. &lt;em&gt;Loki&lt;/em&gt;, a six-episode series on Disney Plus, is his first chance at a starring role. The show follows the character, once again played by Tom Hiddleston, after he stole a magical doodad called a Tesseract in 2019’s &lt;em&gt;Avengers: Endgame&lt;/em&gt;. Almost immediately, he’s captured by the TVA and accused of being a “variant” that has disrupted the timeline. He’s given a choice: be destroyed or partner with TVA agent Mobius (Owen Wilson) to help track down another fugitive variant who has been killing agents across various time periods. Naturally, Loki chooses the option where he doesn’t die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y0g4dvWd6PbTpZEYwEalQTUBaOQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22643549/ARC_101_03265_R.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Marvel Studios&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vDC1o6"&gt;Like other bureaucratic entities from movies like &lt;em&gt;Men in Black&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Hellboy, &lt;/em&gt;the TVA is the kind of organization that exists in the margins, unknown to almost everyone. Its objective is an important one: to maintain a timeline created by three beings known as the Time Keepers in order to prevent anomalies that will create new potentially dangerous timestreams. But they also operate like a straight-laced government department. There are rules and procedures to follow. Men and women sit behind desks oblivious to the outside world, as they appear to exist outside of time and space. (At one point, Loki threatens to gut an office worker like a fish; unfortunately, the desk jockey has no idea what a fish is.) Even magic doesn’t work within the confines of the TVA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lX0szZ"&gt;The result is a wonderfully absurd contrast between the mundane and the fantastical. Loki is completely out of place in this world, where his powers are useless and he has no idea what’s going on, making it impossible to truly plot ahead. At first, he’s his old arrogant self. When a judge asks whether he pleads innocent or guilty to being a variant, Loki says simply that gods don’t plead. But eventually, he comes to realize that he can’t fight the TVA, at least until he learns enough about them to come up with a scheme. There are some great slapstick moments, like when Loki is outfitted with a collar that lets a TVA guard send him back in time; every time Loki hops out of a chair for a sneak attack, he’s zapped back into his seat. Later, he fails to get a librarian’s attention until he rings a bell &lt;em&gt;just &lt;/em&gt;right. These moments drive home just how out of place Loki is — and how in many ways he’s really just&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;another cog in a big cosmic machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5csiS2"&gt;The relationship between Loki and Mobius is one of the most important parts of the show. It almost has a buddy comedy dynamic. The two clearly don’t trust each other, but they form a sort of uneasy alliance. At one point, when Loki tries to convince Mobius to follow one of his hunches, the TVA agent seems to think he’s being led into a trap. To assuage his fears, Loki tells him: “Trust one thing — I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; to be right.” The chemistry between Wilson and Hiddleston is great, with the pair able to seamlessly transition from throwing barbs to contemplating serious revelations. Mobius has spent a long time studying Loki, and he’s both unfazed &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; impressed by him. Early on, he shows Loki pivotal scenes from his life, asking questions like “Do you like to hurt people?” Eventually, Loki breaks down and starts to worry that he’s a villain. “That’s not how I see it,” Mobius tells him. It’s a touching moment that further complicates an already complicated character, as you can never really tell what side Loki’s on (aside from his own).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4Bf6GnKo9QrMOQ_u9YKYsmxgGEk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22643550/ROX1400_102_comp_v005.1091.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Marvel Studios&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hbXYIo"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loki&lt;/em&gt; also has a vibe that — at least early on — feels unlike anything else in the MCU. The TVA has a retro-futuristic quality, with computers and interior designs that look ripped from the 1970s. The agency even has a cute little watch mascot, which also appears to be sentient, sort of like a holographic Siri mashed with the Kool-Aid Man. It’s both surreal and grounded, like something Douglas Adams would dream up. And as opposed to the more typical action-oriented Marvel stories, &lt;em&gt;Loki &lt;/em&gt;plays out a bit like a police procedural, as Loki and Mobius attempt to figure out just who the fugitive variant is. Without his superpowers, Loki is forced to spend hours at a desk, flipping through files in hopes of finding a clue, before venturing out into the field to investigate. He quickly goes from god to amateur detective. The time travel premise also means that the show is able to jump around a lot, with visits to everywhere from Pompeii to a futuristic big box store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="3QXk20"&gt;Much like &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Loki&lt;/em&gt; is evidence that there’s a lot of room to experiment within the tight confines of the MCU. It blends elements of buddy comedies and police procedurals with a hefty dose of classic sci-fi, helped along by an incredibly charming cast. It’s also a story that seems ideally suited for episodic storytelling, with the space to dig deeper into a character that’s often stuck on the periphery of larger moments. In its first two episodes, &lt;em&gt;Loki&lt;/em&gt; nails the formula — now we just have to see if that momentum keeps up for the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="MNtitg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Disney Plus","description":"&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Loki&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; debuts on Disney Plus on June 9th, with new episodes out every Wednesday.","label":"Subscribe Now","url":"https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/c/482924/1084177/9358?subId1=VergeLoki&amp;amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.disneyplus.com%2Fseries%2Floki%2F6pARMvILBGzF"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22523186/loki-review-episode-1-2-disney-plus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22523186/loki-review-episode-1-2-disney-plus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-08T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-08T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sony WF-1000XM4 review: a sonic triumph</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Sony’s new earbuds deliver on sound, battery life, and beat all comers at noise cancellation&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p-large-text" id="nDUe44"&gt;Sony first released its WF-1000XM3 earbuds nearly two years ago, and though they offered some of the best noise cancellation and sound quality you could find at that time, a lot has changed since. Facing newer competitors like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"&gt;Apple’s AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21507552/bose-quietcomfort-earbuds-review-best-noise-cancellation"&gt;Bose’s QuietComfort Earbuds&lt;/a&gt; at the high end, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22432633/amazon-echo-buds-2021-review-features-specs-price"&gt;countless&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22323748/anker-liberty-air-2-pro-review-wireless-headphone-price"&gt;plenty-good&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22231848/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-review"&gt;alternatives&lt;/a&gt; below, Sony has returned with the new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22523584/sony-wf-1000xm4-wireless-earbuds-headphones-review"&gt;$279.99 WF-1000XM4&lt;/a&gt; earbuds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NVjNBg"&gt;They provide even more powerful noise canceling; so good that it now rivals over-ear headphones. The audio quality has been further refined, and Sony added key features it frustratingly omitted last time — like IPX4 water and sweat resistance. The 1000XM4s also raise the bar for wireless audio and battery life in noise-canceling earbuds. Does that mean they’re worth almost $300?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="EuXdH3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10596539"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nvhq8K"&gt;If you want the absolute best active noise cancellation in truly wireless earbuds, the answer is an emphatic yes. Sony has built a new chip it calls the V1 into the 1000XM4s that brings their noise cancellation capabilities to impressive new heights. These earbuds do a better job than the AirPods Pro and even slightly outperform Bose’s QuietComfort Earbuds at hushing nearby noise. It’s now reached a point where the NC on these feels about as effective as Sony’s premium &lt;em&gt;headphones&lt;/em&gt;. Impressive stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="UKrxZA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple AirPods Pro review: perfect fit","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"},{"title":"Bose QuietComfort Earbuds review: noise-canceling champion","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21507552/bose-quietcomfort-earbuds-review-best-noise-cancellation"},{"title":"Amazon Echo Buds review: very hard to beat for the price","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22432633/amazon-echo-buds-2021-review-features-specs-price"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="tO4bHB"&gt;They practically make the ambient sounds in my local coffee shop go poof, and while visiting family upstate over Memorial Day, I tested them in a crowded bar and found that I could listen to my music at around 60 percent volume without hearing any of the lively chatter surrounding me. Becca took them on a plane and they passed with flying colors, and they were able to cut down the cacophony of subway cars better than all earbud competitors. I credit these results partially to new memory foam tips that I’ll cover later, but it’s very evident that the V1 is cutting out more noise at all frequencies — just like Sony claims. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UIp0RShf4Nn0geW2MkBq65EspI4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22644190/DSCF4082_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Both the earbuds and case are smaller than Sony’s previous WF-1000XM3s.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3i3MQ4"&gt;And when it comes to sound quality, the 1000XM4s are even more of a slam dunk than their predecessors. Sony told me that when it tunes earbuds, it closely looks at current music trends. So if you compare these directly to the 1000XM3s, you might notice slightly richer bass to handle your Dua Lipa fix. There’s no better of-the-moment album than Olivia Rodrigo’s &lt;em&gt;Sour&lt;/em&gt;, and Sony’s earbuds simply do better at handling deep bass and low-mid frequencies than the AirPods Pro. But Sony’s audio prowess extends through all frequencies. Her voice, the acoustic guitars, and background vocals on “traitor” all come through with excellent distinctness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="9A872x"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best wireless earbuds to buy right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="q3n4pX"&gt;It’s easy to close your eyes and get completely lost in the groove of Billie Eilish’s “Lost Cause,” where even whispered vocals come through with total clarity in the mix. John Mayer’s new Toto-influenced single “Last Train Home” and its airy vibe are right at home on the 1000XM4s, as well. Jump through genres and it’s hard to find anything that these earbuds can’t make shine. Electric guitars have just the right grit on ‘70s rock. Switch over to Motown and Sam Cooke’s voice has the warmth you’d expect. That extra bass lends added kick to hip-hop and dance tracks, though the low-end never gets bloated or overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a8eIFmT_o2dPf61X100z20WH8EI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22644189/DSCF4081_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The earbuds now have an all-matte design with more subtle Sony branding.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="k6wT2h"&gt;The 1000XM4s look nothing like their predecessors. Sony has moved away from the pill shape to a more subtle, all-matte style. And the earbuds are noticeably smaller. Sony told me it’s just a 10 percent downsizing, but it feels like more due to the sleeker overall design. There’s a big round area for touch controls, and the flashiest thing about these earbuds is the small, accented circular microphone inlet. Sony’s logo is now on the side of the buds, where few would ever spot it when you’re wearing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wanOxH"&gt;Sony has shrunk down the carrying case even more; it’s 40 percent smaller than the bulky case that came with the 1000XM3s. Now it’s on par with cases from Jabra and other competitors. It’s shorter than the AirPods Pro case, but a tad wider and noticeably thicker. The case has a USB-C port and supports wireless charging, and the earbuds magnetically latch into the case strongly and should stay seated unless you fumble the whole thing to the ground. If I’m being fussy, the lid has a little more play than I’d like for $280 earbuds, but it stays shut fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9xm30z"&gt;But I’d argue the best thing about this redesign isn’t the actual earbud hardware: it’s the new ear tips Sony is including in the box. Last time around, Sony shipped six pairs of tips with the 1000XM3 buds — three silicone sizes and three foam-like tips. But with the 1000XM4s, Sony is going all-in on the memory foam approach with new “noise isolation ear tips.” They’re quite different from Sony’s past foam tips, now with a thicker design that’s less rounded and with a tackier feel that helps them stay planted in your ears. I’d describe it as almost a hybrid between silicone and memory foam.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NAdLUex0md0o7BDe6afOLeUJYc8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22644191/DSCF4083_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new noise isolation ear tips are actually one of the best things about the WF-1000XM4s.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LNroOp"&gt;You don’t get any plain silicone sets at all, and Sony only includes the standard small, medium, and large sizes; XS and XL would’ve been nice at this price point, but the large tips were a perfect match in my case. The seal is so strong that you’ll sometimes notice them twist in with a squeaking sound. Unlike the 1000XM3s, the 1000XM4s have a proper IPX4 rating for water and sweat resistance, so you can confidently use them for workouts or in the rain without weighing their odds of survival. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oSryMa"&gt;Once you power them on, the 1000XM4 earbuds will outlast all of their main noise-canceling competitors on a single charge. They’ll run for eight hours of continuous playback with NC enabled, an impressive jump from the five hours that the AirPods Pro, Galaxy Buds Pro, QuietComfort Earbuds, and Jabra Elite 85t all hover around. Turn noise canceling off, and the new earbuds can keep running for up to 12 hours. The charging case can juice the buds two times, so you’re looking at a total playing time of around 24 hours (NC on) or 36 hours if you can do without it wherever you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NEZlZbFZFomwJDgRFokEoGWCTAE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22644192/DSCF4084_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The case supports Qi wireless charging.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lSw46_F71FYZ50eLPQxU31hsJGw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22644193/DSCF4085_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The earbuds have beamforming mics and bone conduction sensors for improved voice calls.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uWH7Yx"&gt;Sony is also beating Apple at bringing higher bit rate wireless audio to earbuds. The 1000XM4 buds fully support Sony’s own proprietary LDAC codec, which can transmit music tracks at up to 990kbps. This is currently the gold standard for Bluetooth audio, and though I’m sure it’ll prompt the usual “no one can tell the difference” debates, I’m glad to see LDAC show up in more portable form. 2021 is becoming the year of lossless music streaming, with Apple and Spotify both joining Amazon Music HD and Tidal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H7axWO"&gt;But LDAC has its own challenges. Playback can get a little unreliable and choppy if you set it to max quality in an Android device’s developer settings, so generally I stick with the middle “performance” option where the top bit rate falls to 660kbps. At that quality, can you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; perceive any improvement compared to AAC? Maybe I’m buying into snake oil, but to me it does sound like certain tracks do have that ever-so-slight extra bit of depth and clarity when streaming with LDAC. But keep in mind this is a feature that only applies to Android devices, and the 1000XM4s sound quite stellar when paired with an iPhone, where LDAC isn’t even a thing. It’s a reminder that everything in the chain — from how music was mastered and encoded to the earbud hardware itself — matters just as much as sheer bit rate. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PJpnI2AVD1mnt8FGjxyQ2xtdjV8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22644863/Screenshot_20210607_204605_Headphones.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MW80ti"&gt;LDAC has a detrimental impact on that otherwise exceptional battery life, too. If you’ve got noise cancellation active and are streaming LDAC, it drops to the typical five hours of continuous playback. That’s not bad when you consider how hard the buds are working under those conditions, but it’s a decrease all the same and removes one of the advantages the Sony buds have over the competition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OAVAht"&gt;So far, this review has been largely praise, but the WF-1000XM4 earbuds do come with one crushing disappointment: they don’t support two simultaneous Bluetooth connections, a feature known as multipoint. It’s become a status quo feature for many high-end &lt;em&gt;headphones &lt;/em&gt;(including from Sony) and allows you to have your headphones connected to both your phone and your computer and seamlessly switch between them. But for whatever reason, Jabra continues to be the only company that’s offering the convenience of multipoint in earbuds. This situation is getting frustrating — especially for products in this price bracket — and I hope the whole product category of true wireless earbuds can make progress on multipoint very soon. After recent leaks, I saw comments from people who said they wouldn’t purchase these earbuds if they lacked multipoint. And unfortunately, that’s where we’re at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="1BHalb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10596606"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZS4yNV"&gt;Microphone performance is better than it was on the 1000XM3s, but it’s still not as good as Apple’s AirPods Pro or Samsung’s Galaxy Buds Pro. The new earbuds utilize both beamforming mics and bone conduction sensors to know when you’re speaking and when you’re not. This does a respectable job of cutting out background noise for people on the other side of your calls, but it has the negative side effect of making your voice sound clipped or overly gated. In a home environment, they’re adequate for chatting with others, but things get a little more inconsistent outside or in loud environments. On a related note, Sony has brought over the speak-to-chat feature from the 1000XM4 headphones; with this setting on, the earbuds will automatically pause music and enable ambient sound mode whenever speech is detected. Once you’ve stopped talking for a few seconds, audio will automatically resume. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lEH4Ej"&gt;Sony’s ambient mode sounds more natural this time around, but since the buds aren’t vented and you can feel them in your ears, the effect is less convincing than on the AirPods Pro. Still, I like that Sony’s app lets you go deep on customizing the various sound modes; you can manually select how much outside sound to let through like other buds, but you can also adjust the mix of noise cancellation and ambient sound based on location — home, work, the gym, etc. — or have it change automatically if the app detects different activities. Lastly, Sony preserves its trick of holding a finger on the left earbud to temporarily activate transparency mode and lower the volume of your music until you lift it back off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TEhGD3"&gt;Not that I expected them to, but the 1000XM4s can’t keep up with Apple’s ecosystem advantages that exist between the AirPods Pro and iPhone, iPad, or Mac. While they support Sony’s 360 Reality Audio and Dolby Atmos music tracks on Tidal, the setup process is a little ridiculous: you’ve got to take a photo of each ear in Sony’s app, images the company says are deleted after 30 days, to “optimize” the sound. But what’s more important beyond that hassle is that Sony’s solution doesn’t yet work for movies or TV shows, where Apple’s spatial audio does a tremendous job immersing you in content. Since Sony only makes the earbuds and almost certainly not the tablet or phone in your hand, it lacks the necessary tie-ins for head tracking and other tricks that help Apple pull off spatial audio so well. Sony doesn’t even really advertise the 360 audio chops of the 1000XM4 buds; they’re clearly intended more for music and stereo listening. (Many Dolby Atmos music tracks have an artificial wideness to their soundstage, so I don’t miss that part.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VuNexC"&gt;My first review pair of 1000XM4s experienced what I’d consider severe bugs: several times, they would completely crash and produce a buzzing sound — the sort of noise you hear when a video game freezes — and then power on again. I’d also have cases where only one earbud would connect to the paired device until I plopped them both into the case and tried again. Sony provided me with a second set that didn’t suffer the same problems. Becca didn’t have any such issues with her set either, so I’m relatively sure I got a bad unit the first time around. But I still think it’s worth mentioning for transparency’s sake. Sony generally does a respectable job of patching up early quirks with firmware updates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="cPxJ1Y"&gt;Putting the one lemon pair aside, the other drawbacks aren’t enough to derail the end result: the WF-1000XM4s are a triumph for Sony. They’re an ambitious flex of decades’ worth of personal audio expertise, and they’re a reminder of just how well the company can execute when it’s focused on the right things. These earbuds can’t match all the bells and whistles of Apple’s AirPods Pro, and the lack of multipoint continues to sting. But they’re in a class of their own where it counts most: noise cancellation and sound quality. You’ll be paying quite a premium to get the best of that criteria, but if you’re the sort of person who will appreciate the top-notch performance, the 1000XM4s are a worthwhile investment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gywVT9"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22523584/sony-wf-1000xm4-wireless-earbuds-headphones-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22523584/sony-wf-1000xm4-wireless-earbuds-headphones-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-08T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-08T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Azio Izo wireless mechanical keyboard review: form over function</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Azio’s latest keyboard looks the part but struggles with the basics&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="nI6Njl"&gt;I cannot overstate the strength of the reactions the Azio Izo keyboard got when people saw it sitting on my desk. Not many mechanical keyboards out there have big volume wheels attached to their frame, and fewer still style them in a gaudy reflective gold to pair them with a gold spacebar and escape key. Get beyond the gold, and you’ll spot that the rest of its keycaps have a kind of rounded shape that almost makes them look like little pieces of candy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AuYh7v"&gt;Azio is no stranger to bold keyboard designs like these. Before now, its most notable keyboards have been from its &lt;a href="https://aziocorp.com/products/retro-classic-bt"&gt;Retro Classic line&lt;/a&gt;. These literally attempt to emulate the look of old-fashioned typewriters with flat circular keycaps and metal frames. The result, as one of my colleagues pointed out, is a keyboard that looks like it could sink a U-boat and only supports coding in COBOL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GiFlNH"&gt;I’m all for a piece of consumer tech that’s willing to embrace an eye-catching design like this, but when you’re spending $129.99 on a keyboard, it has to do more than just generate big reactions from everyone that sees it. After spending a week using the Izo as my main work keyboard, my impression is its functionality doesn’t match up to its design. It’s launching on &lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/azio/1946518804"&gt;Kickstarter today&lt;/a&gt; alongside a matching mouse and calculator, and the plan is to deliver to backers in August. The keyboard’s MSRP is $129.99, but Azio is also offering early bird discounts with its Kickstarter campaign that bring the price down to $79.99 and $69.99. For this review, I evaluated it at its full retail price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="yA78R0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10596364"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pvmaMU"&gt;From the photos at the top of this article and throughout the page, you likely already know whether you like the look of the Izo. As well as blue, the keyboard is also available in pink and white. But whichever look you choose, you get rounded white keycaps and a blingy gold escape key, space bar, and volume wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JDTsvz"&gt;I’m a big fan of volume wheels like this, and the Izo’s is no exception. It’s got a nice tactile feel, and it worked flawlessly regardless of whether I was using the keyboard in its wired or wireless modes. Pressing the dial down also works to mute and unmute your computer, while holding down the Fn key as you turn it will adjust the backlighting brightness. The volume wheel’s functionality cannot be remapped, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rBUFQe"&gt;The only problem with a volume wheel like this is that it takes up space, and space is a rare commodity on compact 75 percent-style boards like this, which omit the numpad of larger keyboards but still include a function row. The more compact selection of keys means you have to be smarter about which you include, and Azio has made a couple of bizarre decisions when it comes to the Izo. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4gdrvyT7XH08k8mZlwtYSfclPdM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22643617/akrales_20210607_4620_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Izo includes an Insert key, but no dedicated print screen button.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZG7_b74EehdRRNOd3gvYuvsITMY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22643620/akrales_20210607_4620_0007.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s keycaps have a rounded design that’s a bit of an acquired taste.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Nnf4fm"&gt;The most egregious of these is that there’s no dedicated print screen key. Instead you get, of all things, an Insert key, which is a key that in my nearly 30 years on this planet I have only ever pressed accidentally. Its print screen button, meanwhile, is hidden behind a function key. For me, this one small omission ruled out using the Izo keyboard for important work events where I have to take frequent screenshots. With no built-in support for key remapping, it’s not something that can be easily fixed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ADdING"&gt;The keycaps themselves are a bit of an acquired taste. Construction-wise they’re fine: a double-shot combination of hard-wearing PBT plastic and transparent lettering to let the keyboard’s white LEDs shine through (there’s no RGB support here). But their rounded design takes a little bit of getting used to. I found my fingers slipping off the rounded edges of the keycaps a little as I typed, as I missed the sharper raised edges you get on more traditional keycaps. I didn’t have any issues installing third-party keycaps, but good luck finding some that match the unique look of this keyboard. There’s no angle adjustment on the Izo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s3NLHG"&gt;While most keyboards are designed with Windows in mind and Mac as an afterthought, the Izo is first and foremost a Mac keyboard. Its bottom row features Option and Command keys, and while it does have Windows and Alt legends printed alongside them, they’re smaller and don’t let the backlighting shine through. It would have been nice to see Azio include replacement dedicated Windows keycaps like Keychron does. You can switch between Mac and PC layouts by hitting Fn + Home. Azio is only producing this keyboard with a US (aka ANSI) layout for now, but it says it hopes to release additional layouts in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k4mpASVi9uHF2YQucfeYcgFHNzw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22643618/akrales_20210607_4620_0005.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A gold switch lets you swap between wired and wireless modes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BKLz-55jfNKvS7hHQtdyztykwIc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22643616/akrales_20210607_4620_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The wheel controls volume and backlighting brightness.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Okpw8W"&gt;The Izo works as both a wired and wireless keyboard, via USB-C and Bluetooth respectively, and a gold switch around the top of the board toggles between them. If you’re using it in wireless mode, there’s the option to pair it with up to three devices (much like Keychron’s keyboards), and switch between them with a key shortcut. The initial pairing process is a bit fiddly and involves you selecting one of the three profiles first before putting the keyboard into pairing mode. Keychron’s process is more seamless. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n3FooI"&gt;Azio claims the keyboard’s 5,000mAh battery should go for a full year on a single charge if you’re using it with its backlight turned off, dropping to two weeks of eight hours of daily use with it turned on (which, trust me, you will). It’s hard to directly compare, but Azio’s two-week battery life claim translates to around 112 hours of use, which is a little higher than the 68 and 72 hours the Keychron K2 claims with its lights on, understandable given the bigger battery in Azio’s board. I wasn’t able to run the Izo keyboard’s battery down to zero during my review period, but after two days of wireless use, the built-in battery indicator reported I had 60 percent of charge left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="vQVabO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10594845"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Uf4nKn"&gt;Quibbles aside, the feeling of actually typing on the Azio Izo is fine so long as you like your switches clicky. The keyboard is only available with Gateron Blue switches, which means fans of tactile or linear switches are going to be out of luck. That’s great for fans of clicky switches like me, but if you aren’t, or if you can’t afford for your keyboard to be a little cacophonous, then Azio isn’t interested in taking your money. The Izo isn’t hot-swappable&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;either, which means changing its switches will only be possible with a soldering iron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/alCT6PkL785M-IMXAmFYmgI0UqM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22643622/akrales_20210607_4620_0009.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The keyboard can be paired with up to three devices wirelessly.&lt;span class="ql-cursor"&gt;﻿&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SyH8Di"&gt;I’ll just come out and say it: I think Azio’s Izo keyboard looks great. It’s got the kind of loud, eye-catching design that I wish more consumer tech would embrace. It won’t be for everyone, but if you’re into it, you’re into it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="du9RVT"&gt;But you’re going to have to put up with a little hassle if you want to enjoy this keyboard’s looks. The key selection is odd, it’s available with a limited range of switches, and the keycaps are an acquired taste. The Izo might look the part, but it struggles to act it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="DlTCek"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:1523637"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WlaKxI"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Jon Porter / The Verge &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22522473/azio-izo-collection-wireless-mechanical-keyboard-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22522473/azio-izo-collection-wireless-mechanical-keyboard-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-08T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-08T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Lock it down</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An illustration of a laptop with three locks, a key, an at sign, a key and colorful pixels all randomly placed around the image." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x2kc4wcC4UJDmYLmwkxVDf9qf70=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69402125/VRG_4614_0_Overview.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Maria Chimishkyan&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IgMp00"&gt;There are a lot of ways things can go wrong online. Password databases get breached, personal data gets leaked, and trackers pop up where we least expect them. We don’t like to dwell on the bad side of the internet because we want technology to be fun — but there’s a lot of hard, careful work happening to get you there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CYmfzC"&gt;So this week, we’re putting together a guide to protecting yourself online. Some of it is basic hygiene — how to set up two-factor authentication, how to block tracking pixels in your email, and so on — but there are also a few more exotic problems in the mix, like Dogecoin scammers or the quantum security apocalypse. Taken together, it’s a full-spectrum reminder of all the things that can go wrong on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CVsNnt"&gt;Stay safe out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mo9Z5Z"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="eYYdgY"&gt;
&lt;script src="https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/jquery/3.5.1/jquery.min.js" type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
$( ".c-package-cover__title"  ).append( $( ".c-entry-content &gt; div" ) );
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22465512/cybersecurity-online-security-privacy-breaches"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22465512/cybersecurity-online-security-privacy-breaches</id>
    <author>
      <name>The Verge Staff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-08T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-08T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft Outlook for iOS now lets you use your voice to write emails and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vg9QLBpKlpbXTrzFjBs9tRLfnvo=/0x0:1620x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69422525/voiceoutlookmobile.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="InS8os"&gt;Microsoft is adding voice capabilities to its Outlook mobile app that will let people write emails, schedule meetings, and search using their voice. The new Cortana-powered voice capabilities will be available first in Outlook for iOS, with Android support coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6GYCwG"&gt;A new plus sign icon in Outlook mobile will appear soon that lets you activate the voice mode. You’ll be able to ask things like “When’s my next team meeting?” or search for co-workers, files, and calendar entries. You can even use voice to attach files quickly, as Outlook is using the Microsoft Graph to surface relevant documents. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B2bTft"&gt;Dictation has been a big part of Word and Outlook on the desktop for years, and it’s now appearing in the mobile version of Outlook. You can respond to messages with your voice on iOS, or write new emails using the speech-to-text functionality. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_51qgRT3rUSQsU1n6j4XWnM9uTY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22644769/outlookvoice.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Outlook voice integration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="S6kvwo"&gt;This isn’t the first time that Cortana voice functionality has appeared in Outlook. Microsoft has been gradually building to this point with a dedicated &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/4/20942026/microsoft-cortana-male-voice-outlook-ios-android-integration-launch-features"&gt;Play My Emails feature inside Outlook mobile&lt;/a&gt;. This new update brings voice to nearly every part of Outlook mobile, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YwkYvD"&gt;Alongside the voice addition, Microsoft is also launching a separate Scheduler Microsoft 365 service today. It’s designed for Microsoft 365 administrators to enable as a backend service that helps schedule meetings. It plugs into Cortana to allow users to set up meetings using just email replies. You can reply to a colleague confirming a meeting and simply write “Cortana, please find a time to meet next week,” and Scheduler should find the most appropriate time and arrange the meeting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RGZFdz"&gt;Scheduler is part of a bigger push by Microsoft to reposition Cortana as a productivity assistant. Microsoft &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/12/9/9877908/microsoft-cortana-android-ios-features"&gt;first launched Cortana&lt;/a&gt; for iOS and Android in December 2015, and the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/1/22361687/microsoft-cortana-shut-down-ios-android-mobile-app"&gt;shut down the app earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;. The closure came after Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella previously recognized the company’s difficulties competing with other digital assistants, revealing in 2019 that Microsoft &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/18/18187992/microsoft-cortana-satya-nadella-alexa-google-assistant-competitor"&gt;no longer saw Cortana as a competitor&lt;/a&gt; to Alexa and Google Assistant.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22524014/microsoft-outlook-mobile-voice-dictation-emails-calendar"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22524014/microsoft-outlook-mobile-voice-dictation-emails-calendar</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-08T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-08T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung has given its smart home app SmartThings a fresh interface</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_kgtlqZ0IEmxfnnklm8aMtkfHjg=/227x0:2095x1245/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69422524/ST_2021_0527_ux_2.5_graphics_b2.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1pa0fY"&gt;Samsung has updated the user interface for its smart home app SmartThings, replacing the slightly muted color scheme of the old app — full of grays and earth tones — with a new UI and overall fresher look. The new interface launches on Android today with the iOS version “to follow” at some unknown time in the future, says Samsung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yvWLno"&gt;While the interface of the old app was oriented around the different rooms users had assigned for their smart home gadget, the new layout now focuses on five spaces:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="O8TlR3"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Favorites &lt;/strong&gt;- a new homescreen, with quick access to users’ most-used devices and scenes (scheduled routines, like for the morning or leaving the house). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="YcPPxL"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Devices - &lt;/strong&gt;for a full list of all connected smart devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="MgSqrD"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Life &lt;/strong&gt;- for access to Samsung’s add-on services, like &lt;a href="https://news.samsung.com/us/samsung-introduces-one-stop-shop-your-cooking-journey/"&gt;SmartThings Cooking&lt;/a&gt; (which is supposed to help you sort shopping lists and recipes into a cohesive life plan).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="q8EtX2"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Automations &lt;/strong&gt;- for creating and organizing Samsung’s &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.samsung.com/sg/support/mobile-devices/setting-up-an-automation-in-samsung-smartthings-with-certain-time-and-device-condition/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;if-this-then-that automations&lt;/a&gt;, like triggering lights based on motion sensors and so on. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="CLUw23"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Menu &lt;/strong&gt;- for everything else, including notifications, settings, and device history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="KRZtQ3"&gt;That’s all the information and images we have for now of the new SmartThings app, but it seems like a sensible enough update. We’ll have to see how it works in person to get a better idea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yqR2GD"&gt;It’s nice to see Samsung paying a little attention to SmartThings for once, but updating the app is about the bare minimum the company can do. It’s &lt;a href="https://staceyoniot.com/smartthings-starts-saying-goodbye-to-its-hardware/"&gt;stopped making original hardware&lt;/a&gt; for its smart home platform, and is outsourcing the work to third parties to make “SmartThings compatible” devices. The company says it’s &lt;a href="https://blog.smartthings.com/roundups/matter-joins-smartthings-ecosystem-paves-way-for-expanded-connected-home-possibilities/"&gt;onboard with Matter&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/11/22430666/matter-project-chip-smart-home-partnership-apple-amazon-google-zigbee"&gt;new smart home alliance&lt;/a&gt; which includes Google, Amazon, and Apple among its members, but we haven’t yet seen specific details for how that will impact current SmartThings owners..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E9Yu5i"&gt;The SmartThings app is also &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-gb%2Fp%2Fapp%2F9n3zbh5v7hx6%3FSilentAuth%3D1%26wa%3Dwsignin1.0%26ranMID%3D24542%26ranEAID%3DkXQk6*ivFEQ%26ranSiteID%3DkXQk6.ivFEQ-WBYlPA9WjOvU_1IAP.4ibg%26epi%3DkXQk6.ivFEQ-WBYlPA9WjOvU_1IAP.4ibg%26irgwc%3D1%26OCID%3DAID2000142_aff_7593_1243925%26tduid%3D%2528ir__w9prhavkgckfqgznkk0sohz3wu2xupggwf9fwhv600%2529%25287593%2529%25281243925%2529%2528kXQk6.ivFEQ-WBYlPA9WjOvU_1IAP.4ibg%2529%2528%2529%26irclickid%3D_w9prhavkgckfqgznkk0sohz3wu2xupggwf9fwhv600%26activetab%3Dpivot%253Aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available to download for Windows PCs&lt;/a&gt;, though it doesn’t seem like that app is getting an update along with the Android and iOS versions.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22524228/samsung-smart-home-smartthings-app-new-interface"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22524228/samsung-smart-home-smartthings-app-new-interface</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
