<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-11T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Steve Aoki teamed up with Capcom on a Street Fighter arcade cabinet and clothing line</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JieIeH4miq7hLf6GNc5DVqK-zVM=/0x334:2000x1667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68804078/SFAoki__Countercade_2Player_1.21.21_3_.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8viko3"&gt;DJ Steve Aoki and his Dim Mak record label and fashion brand have teamed up with Capcom on some cool &lt;em&gt;Street Fighter&lt;/em&gt;-themed items: a limited edition countertop arcade cabinet, a clothing line, and even a remix of the theme song for &lt;em&gt;Street Fighter &lt;/em&gt;icon&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Ryu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W8JKXQ"&gt;The countertop arcade cabinet, which you can see at the top of this post, will allow up to two players to play four different Capcom games together: &lt;em&gt;Street Fighter II: World Warrior&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Street Fighter II: Champion Edition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Super Street Fighter II Turbo&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Final Fight&lt;/em&gt;. The cabinet is made in partnership with &lt;a href="https://arcade1up.com/"&gt;Arcade1Up&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s the first two-player countertop cabinet the company has made. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rErZbi"&gt;In addition to the slick art on the cabinet, each one is signed by Aoki. But if you want to get your hands on it, you’ll need to act fast as there are only 30 units available. The cabinet &lt;a href="https://dimmakcollection.com/collections/dim-mak-x-street-fighter/products/dim-mak-x-arcade1up-street-fighter-ii-countercade"&gt;costs $199&lt;/a&gt; and will ship in May. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jSKNti"&gt;There’s also a line of &lt;em&gt;Street Fighter&lt;/em&gt;-inspired apparel. You can see the &lt;a href="https://dimmakcollection.com/collections/dim-mak-x-street-fighter"&gt;whole collection on the Dim Mak website&lt;/a&gt;, and we’ve included a few pictures in this gallery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="y5OXYj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10337933"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lKfvBX"&gt;The remix of Ryu’s theme song, titled “Ryu’s Theme (The Moe’s Pizzeria Steve Aoki Remix),” isn’t out just yet. It will be available on February 19th, but you can pre-save it to your streaming service of choice &lt;a href="https://ffm.to/ryustheme"&gt;right now&lt;/a&gt;. I haven’t heard the remix yet, but I’m looking forward to checking out Aoki’s take on the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hO7JEqIPQv0"&gt;iconic song&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7yQh45"&gt;According to a press release announcing the collaboration, Aoki was a huge &lt;em&gt;Street Fighter&lt;/em&gt; fan growing up, heading to a local pizzeria every day after school to play the game. That love for the series definitely shows on the cabinet and in the apparel collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XdRRnC"&gt;And Aoki’s main? “Ryu,” he said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. (I can’t say that’s surprising, given Ryu’s prominence on much of the gear.) “I always picked him when I was a kid when I obsessively played &lt;em&gt;Street Fighter II.&lt;/em&gt; He represents the strong, iconic, Japanese warrior hero that I always aspired to become,” Aoki said.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278140/steve-aoki-capcom-street-fighter-arcade-cabinet-clothing-line-remix-dim-mak"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278140/steve-aoki-capcom-street-fighter-arcade-cabinet-clothing-line-remix-dim-mak</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google Photos gets new paywalled editing features for Google One subscribers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/q4Bci5rVuLg_C6ZytQpGabrpDG4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68804071/1BEB77B1_EB2C_4E1F_A9C1_1B863908E956.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KMG5RX"&gt;Google is adding some of its fancy, Pixel-exclusive editing features to Google Photos today for all Android users to enjoy, but there’s a catch — if you don’t have a Pixel, you’ll have to be a paying Google One subscriber to use them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vs0xBz"&gt;The paywalled editing features have been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/6/21553303/google-photos-editing-features-color-pop-one-subscription"&gt;rumored for some time&lt;/a&gt;, but today marks the official announcement of the new program. Specifically, Google is offering some of its more recent machine-learning powered editing tools, like its enhanced &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/pixel/more-helpful-pixel-features/"&gt;Portrait Blur&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/photos/new-helpful-editor/"&gt;Portrait Light&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/photos/take-action-sharing-editing/"&gt;Color Pop&lt;/a&gt; features that it started offering alongside the Pixel 5 last fall to a broader audience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7309P0"&gt;As Google clarified to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; when the paywall was first discovered, the company isn’t taking away existing versions of features like Portrait Blur or Color Pop from free Google Photo users. The current iteration of those features — which work with newer photos that offer depth data, such as a portrait mode shot — will still work for everyone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3FsTlb"&gt;But the new Pixel- and subscription-only version promises to take things a step further and allows users to apply those effects (through the power of machine learning) to older photos that don’t have that existing depth data. Pixel users will still get access to the features for free, whether or not they subscribe to Google One.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZPBjbM"&gt;Along with the new editing features, Google is also offering new AI-powered filters: a new “dynamic” option that automatically enhances brightness and contrast, and “sky suggestions” that can tweak skylines for more dramatic effects. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/58yg0E1sai2rY1bqjbzU1WiqRTk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22297256/blog_sky_palette_v3.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new “sky suggestions” filters.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="vYm1Rh"&gt;&lt;a href="https://one.google.com/about?utm_source=blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=web&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Photos_editing"&gt;Google One&lt;/a&gt; subscriptions start at $1.99 per month and primarily focus on expanding storage for Google services (the base plan, for example, offers 100GB of space over the 15GB of included free storage). Google also offers additional perks to subscribers to help sweeten the deal, like Google Store rewards — the new Google Photos editing features are likely part of that plan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lOyHfC"&gt;It’s also worth noting that Google is expanding the photo-focused offerings with Google One just months before it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/11/21560810/google-photos-unlimited-cap-free-uploads-15gb-ending"&gt;ends its free unlimited storage program for Google Photos&lt;/a&gt; — meaning that the company will likely be pushing Google One as a solution for users who’ll need more storage space for their pictures, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zqR8gr"&gt;Lastly, Google announced that it’ll be introducing some feature parity between its iOS and Android versions of the app. The Android version is set to get the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/31/21409339/google-photos-ios-update-crop-trim-add-filters-video-editor"&gt;improved video editor&lt;/a&gt; that Google already offers for iOS in the coming weeks, and the iOS version will be updated to receive the new photo editor that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/30/21495793/google-photos-editing-tools-app-update-machine-learning-suggestions-android"&gt;Google introduced last fall&lt;/a&gt; in the coming months. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278149/google-photos-pixel-paywall-editing-features-one-subscribers"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278149/google-photos-pixel-paywall-editing-features-one-subscribers</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T11:59:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T11:59:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>Post Malone will hold a virtual concert to celebrate Pokémon’s 25th anniversary </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VXq4QArvuK8hccByEP5WHHrazrE=/529x0:2536x1338/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68804066/Screen_Shot_2021_02_11_at_11.16.25_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WynNnV"&gt;Post Malone is joining &lt;em&gt;Pokémon&lt;/em&gt;’s 25th anniversary celebration with a virtual concert. The rapper will perform on February 27th in a digital event kicking off at 7PM ET. On YouTube, the company released a teaser video alongside the news, which includes a look at a very Pixar-ish, animated version of the artist ahead of the performance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5QctYS"&gt;The Pokémon Company International announced P25, a series of musical events, last month with news that pop star &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228760/pokemon-25th-anniversary-katy-perry"&gt;Katy Perry will headline&lt;/a&gt;. Post Malone’s concert will be a free event fans can tune into over on the event’s &lt;a href="https://25.pokemon.com/en-us/"&gt;official website&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/pokemon/featured"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/Pokemon"&gt;Twitch&lt;/a&gt;. The event is also expected to include more news on upcoming musical acts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PA9ctX"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wtQx4R2M2iw?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1ortZG"&gt;In the absence of live events, more games are turning to virtual concerts these days, with artists like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/10/21557275/lil-nas-x-roblox-virtual-performance-announced-holiday-old-town-road"&gt;Lil Nas X&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/5/21502149/roblox-virtual-music-events-concerts-ava-max-interview"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roblox&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; and last year, Travis Scott’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/23/21233637/travis-scott-fortnite-concert-astronomical-live-report"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; performance turned the entire game into one big stage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OVTvmX"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2ilgAJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="je1SNy"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fWgjqk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278179/post-malone-pokemon-concert-25th-anniversary"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278179/post-malone-pokemon-concert-25th-anniversary</id>
    <author>
      <name>Megan Farokhmanesh</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T11:49:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T11:49:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>HBO Max will launch internationally in June</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ho1sJ-uf0FEBoQx4ghY7bNz9JRo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68803995/acastro_200602_1777_HBOMax_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6X2aQx"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21272223/hbo-max-app-how-to-watch-download-price-subscription-stream-shows"&gt;HBO Max&lt;/a&gt; will finally make its international debut in June, with the streaming service set to launch in Latin America and the Caribbean. Currently, HBO Max is only available in the United States. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ah8gvi"&gt;The Latin America rollout is just the first phase of HBO Max’s international debut. The company promises it will also transition HBO-branded services in Europe (specifically, “the Nordics, Spain, Central Europe, and Portugal”) to HBO Max later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="yBrDpF"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CG7VvdRZ1xo?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nAch4y"&gt;The June launch will see HBO Max expand to 39 countries and territories across Latin America and the Caribbean, including Anguilla, Antigua, Argentina, Aruba, B.V.I., Bahamas, Barbados, Belize, Bolivia, Brazil, Cayman Islands, Chile, Colombia, Costa Rica, Curacao, Dominica, Dominican Republic, Ecuador, El Salvador, Grenada, Guatemala, Guyana, Haiti, Honduras, Jamaica, Mexico, Montserrat, Nicaragua, Panama, Paraguay, Peru, St. Kitts and Nevis, St. Lucia, St. Vincent, Suriname, Trinidad &amp;amp; Tobago, Turks and Caicos, Uruguay, and Venezuela.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mvT7Pf"&gt;As with the (somewhat messy) launch in the US, WarnerMedia will phase out the HBO Go app and service entirely and replace it with a new HBO Max app that should look virtually identical to the US app. Customers who pay for HBO Go directly through WarnerMedia (or through “eligible partners”) will automatically be converted to HBO Max — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/26/21268490/hbo-max-launch-price-warnermedia-att-dc-harry-potter-friends-disney-netflix-peacock"&gt;hopefully with less confusion than the US rollout&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="gi3a8M"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"HBO Max is full of potential, but its biggest hurdle remains AT&amp;amp;T’s messy execution","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/26/21268490/hbo-max-launch-price-warnermedia-att-dc-harry-potter-friends-disney-netflix-peacock"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="061pU8"&gt;The company promises it’ll have more details for the Latin America rollout — including what content will be available, promotional offers, and more — closer to launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="29qYIE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278287/hbo-max-international-launch-june-2021-latin-america-europe-warnermedia-streaming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278287/hbo-max-international-launch-june-2021-latin-america-europe-warnermedia-streaming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T11:45:09-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T11:45:09-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here’s every game coming to the PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X in 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ctg6U9v5jr9RrXkzgL82pqnQOXQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67735830/vpavic_4261_20201023_0084.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;For the early adopters of next-gen hardware&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="cyuvuR"&gt;Just over two months after their release, the PS5 and Xbox Series X / S continue to be some of the most desirable gadgets in the world. While it’s still &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21451144/sony-ps5-preorder-microsoft-xbox-series-x-nvidia-rtx-3080-mess"&gt;very difficult&lt;/a&gt; to get your hands on a new console, those lucky enough to own one can enjoy something unprecedented in modern gaming history. For the first time, next-gen console owners can take their existing library — whether it’s physical, digital, or a mix of the two — and bring it to a next-gen platform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pNh3ro"&gt;That gives consumers unprecedented freedom in deciding where they want to play and what performance benefits are worthwhile enough to upgrade. And technologies like cross-platform play and now even cross-generation support will allow people to still play with their friends, even if they don’t upgrade to the latest gaming hardware. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="5uXjX1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Giving consumers unprecedented freedom in deciding where they want to play&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CveWHl"&gt;Yes, both consoles arrived within seven years of the last generation of console hardware. And while it’s likely within the first year of both consoles’ lifespan that many of the hottest titles may launch on last- and current-gen simultaneously, there’s still a good chunk of games that will be exclusive titles playable only a PS5 or Xbox Series X / S. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u79IWA"&gt;Besides 4K, the solid-state drives, and other spec changes, Microsoft and Sony have pledged to support close to every title in the existing console platforms’ libraries. Every Xbox, Xbox 360, and Xbox One game currently playable on existing Xbox One hardware (minus Kinect games) &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/16/21326805/xbox-series-x-xbox-one-game-support-backward-compatible-feature-kinect"&gt;will be playable on the Series X / S&lt;/a&gt;, while Sony is supporting a “vast majority” of PS4 games, totaling &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/16/21440748/ps5-playstation-5-99-percent-backward-compatible-ps4-games-jim-ryan"&gt;more than 4,000 titles&lt;/a&gt;. With both consoles early into their lifespan, it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22163921/ps5-playstation-5-xbox-series-x-old-games-next-gen-consoles"&gt;easy for many to return to older games&lt;/a&gt; to help fill the gap in between long wait periods for more titles to be added to each console’s library. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="dwgnjo"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The new consoles let you take a majority of your existing libraries with you&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nUlnZM"&gt;This changes the calculus a bit with regard to buying a new console. No longer do you have to abandon what you were playing on your old device and start anew. And thanks to some genuinely consumer-friendly initiatives like Xbox Smart Delivery and similar upgrade programs, plenty of the games we own now or are planning to buy in the next couple of months will not only work on the new platforms, but in most cases, they’ll also come with free upgrades from the standard PS4 and Xbox One versions. Sony also introduced the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/28/21538383/sony-playstation-plus-collection-available-games-november-free-bugsnax"&gt;PlayStation Plus Collection&lt;/a&gt;, a library of PS4 games available for free with its online subscription service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lmWX6y"&gt;That leaves us with one big issue: how do you know what new games are coming out for which platforms and when? There’s also the painstaking process of parsing whether a game company is giving out a free next-gen upgrade of a cross-gen title, charging a little extra, or releasing a next-gen-only game. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EsrpjD"&gt;2021 is packed full of new releases and full optimizations of cross-gen games that should further pad out what’s available to play on your new system of choice. We’ve compiled the list below to help you understand every game coming out during the first year of the PS5 and Xbox Series X / S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GM3UJT"&gt;This excludes games without release dates that may have been previously announced — like &lt;em&gt;Elder Scrolls VI &lt;/em&gt;and the &lt;em&gt;Fable &lt;/em&gt;reboot, for example — and any games that were released for either console in 2020, including launch titles. We’ve also chosen only to list release dates for games where the publisher has chosen a concrete date with both day and month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="hTe555"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:9552771"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4tQEqz"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update November 4th, 2020, 12:35PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added that &lt;/em&gt;ARK: Survival Evolved&lt;em&gt; recently released an Xbox Series X enhancement update that will be available to new console owners on launch day.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rC6OMy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; An earlier version of this post incorrectly stated &lt;/em&gt;Haven &lt;em&gt;would be a PS5-only release and that &lt;/em&gt;War Thunder &lt;em&gt;would be Xbox Series-only at launch. Those are incorrect; Haven is also coming to Xbox Series X and Xbox One and as part of Game Pass at launch, and &lt;/em&gt;War Thunder&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;is slated for PS5 mid-November. We regret the errors. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qPYdhq"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 15th, 2021, 5PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to add additional titles releasing in 2021 and update any games that may have been delayed into this year. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yywDTp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n76LJk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21538464/ps5-xbox-series-x-launch-games-list-new-release-holiday-2020-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21538464/ps5-xbox-series-x-launch-games-list-new-release-holiday-2020-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T11:45:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T11:45:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>PS5 exclusive Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart will launch on June 11th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hu2repbHRJetLiZ_hyZOBEJq2ac=/100x0:1180x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68803970/Et9SHNVXAAIM7oq.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: PlayStation&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eusm4j"&gt;We already knew Insomniac Games was working on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/ai3o0XtrnM8"&gt;a sequel&lt;/a&gt; to the 2016 reboot of &lt;em&gt;Ratchet &amp;amp; Clank&lt;/em&gt;. And today, Sony announced that &lt;em&gt;Ratchet &amp;amp; Clank: Rift Apart &lt;/em&gt;will launch on June 11th &lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/02/11/ratchet-clank-rift-apart-arrives-on-ps5-june-11/"&gt;exclusively for the PS5&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Cjowl"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ratchet &amp;amp; Clank: Rift Apart&lt;/em&gt; will have the titular characters traveling across multiple realities as they try to stop a dastardly emperor who is attempting to exterminate organic life from all the universes. Like other titles on Sony’s next-gen console, the game will take advantage of the &lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2020/08/27/an-extended-look-at-ratchet-clank-rift-apart-gameplay/"&gt;PS5’s hardware&lt;/a&gt;, including support for ray tracing, and it will take advantage of the DualSense game controller’s haptic feedback and adaptive triggers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5jDSPF"&gt;The game was originally announced last June during Sony’s next-gen showcase. A few months later, Sony &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/27/21401754/ratchet-clank-rift-apart-trailer-gameplay-sony-playstation-5-ps5-gamescom-2020"&gt;released seven minutes of new gameplay footage&lt;/a&gt; at Gamescom Opening Night Live 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZCBMBR"&gt;This is the third big PS5 console exclusive releasing this year, following &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22261214/destruction-allstars-playstation-5-ps5-sony-interview-cars-demolition-derby"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Destruction AllStars&lt;/em&gt;' release earlier this month&lt;/a&gt; (which is currently free), and Arkane Studios’ &lt;em&gt;Deathloop&lt;/em&gt;, which is set to &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2020/11/12/21562692/deathloop-arkane-lyon-release-date-ps5-pc"&gt;launch on May 21st&lt;/a&gt; and will remain a PS5 console exclusive for one year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="EuS6Vc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Watch seven minutes of Ratchet &amp;amp; Clank: Rift Apart, releasing in PS5’s ‘launch window’","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/27/21401754/ratchet-clank-rift-apart-trailer-gameplay-sony-playstation-5-ps5-gamescom-2020"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="J91oqW"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278233/ratchet-and-clank-rift-apart-ps5-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278233/ratchet-and-clank-rift-apart-ps5-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T11:33:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T11:33:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>Cyberpunk 2077 studio’s hacked data has reportedly been sold</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Keanu Reeves as Johnny Silverhand in Cyberpunk 2077" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jTm6PYisxrW3on6bqVi8jU64-wc=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68803887/Cyberpunk2077_No_Future_RGB.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: CD Projekt Red&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8dOVzM"&gt;Hackers have reportedly sold the game source code and other information stolen from &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077 &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;The Witcher 3 &lt;/em&gt;studio CD Projekt Red (CDPR). Cybersecurity firm &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Intel_by_KELA/status/1359856145205239812"&gt;Kela released screenshots&lt;/a&gt; of a post on the hacking forum Exploit allegedly posted by the attackers, saying that they’ve received an offer for the data from outside the forum. They added that they ended the auction at the request of the buyer. Cybersecurity Twitter account vx-underground &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/vxunderground/status/1359890201686990863"&gt;subsequently confirmed&lt;/a&gt; that the auction had closed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jV9mwO"&gt;On Tuesday, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274035/cd-projekt-hack-source-code-cyberpunk-2077-witcher-3-encrypt-data-ransom"&gt;CDPR disclosed&lt;/a&gt; it had been the victim of a ransomware attack in which hackers had collected “certain data” from the company. It posted a ransom note from the hackers, in which they claimed to have access to source code from the studio’s most popular games, as well as internal legal, HR, and financial documents. CDPR said it would not give in to the demands or negotiate with the hackers, even if that meant the stolen data would begin circulating online. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="hc9zV6"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Just in: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/CDProjektRed?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#CDProjektRed&lt;/a&gt; AUCTION IS CLOSED. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Hackers?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Hackers&lt;/a&gt; auctioned off stolen source code for the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/RedEngine?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#RedEngine&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/CDPR?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#CDPR&lt;/a&gt; game releases, and have just announced that a satisfying offer from outside the forum was received, with the condition of no further distribution or selling. &lt;a href="https://t.co/4Z2zoZlkV6"&gt;pic.twitter.com/4Z2zoZlkV6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— KELA (@Intel_by_KELA) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Intel_by_KELA/status/1359856145205239812?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="p8ZcX2"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Update: we have confirmed the auction has closed. Someone has indeed purchased the material.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Image courtesy of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DrFurfagMD?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@DrFurfagMD&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/TnQVqTiM5w"&gt;pic.twitter.com/TnQVqTiM5w&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— vx-underground (@vxunderground) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/vxunderground/status/1359890201686990863?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ChDiBd"&gt;It is not known who purchased the data or how much it was sold for. However, the auction was thought to have included source code for &lt;em&gt;Thronebreaker: The Witcher Tales &lt;/em&gt;spinoff&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Witcher 3&lt;/em&gt;, a ray-traced version of &lt;em&gt;The Witcher 3&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;, and copies of the company’s internal documents. That’s according to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/vxunderground/status/1359568916339646466"&gt;screenshots posted by vx-underground&lt;/a&gt;. The auction followed a leak of the source code for CD Projekt Red’s&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;virtual card game &lt;em&gt;Gwent&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;which was &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/qjpapp/hackers-release-cdpr-data-gwent"&gt;verified by &lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LaxntL"&gt;Kela previously reported that the starting price for the auction was $1 million, with a buy-it-now price of $7 million. These terms were subsequently verified by vx-underground, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7aiaiB"&gt;Although the hackers have not been officially named, one security researcher &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/cd-projekt-red-ransomware-hack-cyberpunk-2077-source-code/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Wired&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; he believed it involved the use of the HelloKitty ransomware, which had also been used to hack a Brazilian power company called CEMIG. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Xv8Xr"&gt;A spokesperson from CD Projekt Red did not immediately return &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s request for comment. However, earlier this week the company &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/qjpapp/hackers-release-cdpr-data-gwent"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;it is still “actively investigating” the incident.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278121/cd-projekt-red-ransomware-hack-cyberpunk-2077-the-witcher-3-auction-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278121/cd-projekt-red-ransomware-hack-cyberpunk-2077-the-witcher-3-auction-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T11:14:51-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T11:14:51-05:00</updated>
    <title>More people are going back to theaters to game, not to watch movies</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="CGV" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xNpSXjwVRWb_CFuZZX7-TfTyeYM=/0x33:750x533/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68803745/0000006645024004451024264.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;CGV’s branding for the new AzitX service that lets gamers rent out screens&lt;/em&gt; | CGV&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BI1IpU"&gt;It’s no secret the pandemic has taken a huge toll on the theater industry, but some chains are getting clever to offset some of these losses. &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/business-55994767"&gt;&lt;em&gt;BBC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reports that CGV, the largest cinema company in South Korea, has been allowing gamers to rent its screens for two-hour chunks, costing $90 before 6PM, then going up to $135 later in the evening. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iZej9n"&gt;That’s a lot of money, especially since gamers need to come bearing their own consoles, controllers, and games. But hey, where else can you play games on a screen that’s at least 20 feet long with bombastic sound quality?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jnTYO2"&gt;Given the opportunity, I’d bring my PS5 so I could play through the last few layers in &lt;em&gt;Bloodborne&lt;/em&gt;’s Chalice Dungeons standing in my way of a platinum trophy (it’s a PS4 game, I know!). &lt;em&gt;Destruction AllStars&lt;/em&gt; would probably look and sound fantastic, too. Though, before I get too excited, I’m a little skeptical that a DualSense, or really any wireless controller could fare being too far from the console to which it’s paired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OPPis2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The company calls this service “AzitX,” a play on the Korean word “azit,” meaning hideout.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8I38gq"&gt;Even with bookings from gamers, CGV told &lt;em&gt;BBC&lt;/em&gt; they make nothing close to what a usual, pre-pandemic night could bring in. A 100-seat auditorium filled to half capacity would bring in $600 alone, not including the cost of food. But the company says its screens have been booked more than 130 times &lt;a href="https://english.cj.net/cj_now/view.asp?bs_seq=14639&amp;amp;schBsTp=2"&gt;since launching the service&lt;/a&gt; in late January 2021, so it’s popular — mostly among men in their 30s and 40s. Couples and families are renting screens, too, according CGV. The company calls this service “AzitX,” a play on the Korean word “azit,” meaning hideout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Agwpwl"&gt;The report also points out that US theater company Malco Theaters, which owns 36 cinemas in southern states, has been allowing people to rent screens for gaming or private viewing. It has a name for this service, called &lt;a href="https://malco.com/movie_vista.php?selected_movie_vista=HO00007125"&gt;Malco Select Gaming&lt;/a&gt;, and pricing is set at $100 for two hours or $150 for three hours. You can bring up to 20 guests. Malco specifies &lt;a href="https://www.malco.com/subpage.php?page_id=309"&gt;on its FAQ&lt;/a&gt; that any console that connects with an HDMI port can be used, and you can connect via Ethernet to play online, which is cool. However, you can’t host a stream there, so leave your ring light setup at home.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278096/cgv-theater-screens-rental-gaming-azitx-south-korea-pandemic"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278096/cgv-theater-screens-rental-gaming-azitx-south-korea-pandemic</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T11:03:32-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T11:03:32-05:00</updated>
    <title>DJI Mini 2 review: tiny dancer</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;It looks the same, but it flies and shoots much better&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="BzHVcC"&gt;When the first Mavic Mini was introduced, it was clearly created with one purpose: make a drone with an adequate camera that weighs under 250 grams. That number is the key spec because anything under it still doesn’t require FAA registration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uGiDYF"&gt;The new DJI Mini 2 hits that same sub-250g target but with fewer compromises than the first Mini. Where the original was mostly targeting people who were thinking about making that first step into the drone world, the DJI Mini 2 aims to satisfy not only beginners but also experienced drone pilots, photographers, and videographers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0LUzkG"&gt;As someone who spends a lot of his free time traversing the city with a camera, taking photos, I usually end up carrying more gear than I really need. It can become a tough call deciding if it’s worth bringing my drone with me. When it is, I usually grab my DJI Mavic 2 Pro. It is still a very portable drone, but paired with two extra batteries and a controller, it becomes a little hard to carry for hours on end. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tromZy"&gt;This is where the $450 DJI Mini 2 comes in. It’s light — in fact, it’s tiny. And though it obviously has a worse camera than DJI’s bigger drones, it’s still a very good camera. I underestimated the Mini 2 at first, but I soon discovered a ton of little improvements that make this new $449 drone a perfect package for a content creator on the go. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="k0hMVT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10336942"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MKDfTeCYFX7bh8p7nDfIYszzAfU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22296016/vpavic_201214_4405_0361.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Ryan Loughlin&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="19aDoz"&gt;Flying the DJI Mini 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="opeIoA"&gt;The DJI Mini 2 is the exact same size and weight as its predecessor so it won’t require registration with the FAA. And according to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203398/faa-remote-id-rules-location-night-over-people"&gt;newly updated drone laws&lt;/a&gt;, sub-250g drones won’t be subjected to broadcasting the pilot’s and drone’s location. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G5RRw0"&gt;The Mini 2 also comes with a new larger controller. The same controller that was introduced with the Mavic Air 2. The phone now sits on top of the controller and it’s way easier to use. Unlike before, you don’t have to be worried if you have a case on your phone, either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FYrdx9"&gt;Besides the improved camera, the most notable new addition on the DJI Mini 2 is Ocusync. It provides a solid and reliable link compared to the old Wi-Fi connection on the original Mini. Ocusync operates on radio frequencies and already proved its worth in other DJI drones — it’s low latency, can transmit 1080p or 720p video previews to your phone, and in ideal conditions can provide ridiculous range. It is single-handedly the biggest upgrade between the original Mavic Mini and the Mini 2, and it makes flying this drone so much easier and enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;div id="0X8y7e"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10336946"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="57aLoD"&gt;Another thing that makes it more enjoyable to fly are the stronger motors. It makes the drone able to sustain high winds on par with some of the more powerful DJI drones, like the Mavic 2 Pro and Zoom. At no point during my testing was I ever worried about losing control. Also, smaller drones are just way more fun to fly, and this one actually doesn’t sound too loud. Smaller drones tend to have a very high-pitched noise, but you don’t get that with the Mini 2 until you fly it in speedy sport mode. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6aVaVg"&gt;What you won’t find on this drone are obstacle avoidance sensors, so you do need to be very careful about how you fly it. But despite not having any sensors, I actually felt more adventurous with the Mini — it is so small you can easily squeeze it through tighter spaces. I found myself trying things that I normally wouldn’t try with a heavier and more expensive drone. The downside of not having any sensors is that it also means you won’t find a lot of the automated, preprogrammed flight modes. The autonomous Active track mode isn’t here, nor can you create hyperlapses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wW9VjX"&gt;In order to fly the Mini 2, you’ll have to use DJI’s Fly app; it’s basically a stripped-down version of the DJI Fly 4 app intended for more advanced drones. It has all the essential features that you need — including gimbal calibration, which I’m only pointing out because I had to use it more than once. Without calibrating every few flights, the horizon would look slanted, which I found annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="01U7nD"&gt;Also, this is minor, but it’s something I really appreciated: the app doesn’t auto-pause your music or podcasts, so you can keep listening to your jams while flying. I don’t know why that isn’t the case on other apps, but it’s been bothering me for so long now and I’m glad DJI addressed it here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jYDZqpFZzR8J87XDeBfhZ3x_-ak=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22296014/vpavic_201118_4405_0353.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5KIpIDhw6WiZMvdgAtPDiZ24kW8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22296003/vpavic_201118_4405_0295.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TOSEop"&gt;I’m also a big fan of the charging hub, which you can buy separately for an additional $39. It fits up to three batteries and charges them one by one, starting with the least-drained battery. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H6XluL"&gt;Usually when I bring my Mavic 2 Pro hiking or traveling, I rely on about three batteries per day of filming. And I try really hard to maximize all of those batteries by carefully planning my flights because chances are I won’t find a wall outlet to top them off, nor do I have the optional $80 car charger. The charging hub, which was available for the original Mavic Mini, also has a USB-C port. That means you can easily power it with an external battery pack in your backpack and have it charge your drone’s batteries as you move from one location to another. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qenXHviXS2l0zWP08eMLL2aSv34=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22296006/vpavic_201118_4405_0307.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="wvLeDq"&gt;Photos on the DJI Mini 2 &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="Aend4W"&gt;The camera still has the same, small 1/2.3-inch 12MP sensor as the original Mini, but it produces much nicer photos than before. JPGs that you get right off the drone are fantastic, and you can “enhance” them within the DJI app. It applies some subtle adjustments to the overall contrast of the image, lifts shadows, and adds a bit of life to overall colors. I appreciate how subtle and effective these adjustments are. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2r1daB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10337191"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rIfPBh"&gt;Photos look sharp and they hold a good level of detail and contrast up to 1600 ISO. Above that, things starts breaking down a bit. Images start looking muddy and lose definition and color. You’ll rarely shoot past that number anyway, and I think that everything up to 800 ISO actually looks very good. The noise handling has been getting better on all DJI drones and the Mini 2 is no exception. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hT35Xk"&gt;Most drone pilots are looking to capture stunning landscapes or cityscapes with a clean, punchy, and vibrant look. And the downside of smaller sensors is that they make noise more pronounced. One extra benefit from more powerful motors is that the drone is more stable in the air, so you could allow yourself to slow down your shutter speed and lower the ISO for even better results. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eUJ6Q_AePnTI7X5HBBsdolFGlJM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22296500/vpavic_Mini_2_20210211_0001.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7Ucjh9"&gt;One thing you should keep in mind is where you want to show your photos and in which format and size. Personally, I probably wouldn’t make large prints out of most of these photos, but I’d post almost all of them on my Instagram grid. And if you’re still not satisfied with the JPGs, you can always edit the RAW files separately and see how far you can push it in post. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1NdDkk"&gt;But in my past few weeks with the Mini 2, I rarely even bothered with doing a lot of post-processing of my RAWs. I am usually very happy with what I get directly from the drone and can apply minor edits myself if needed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7WBhsM"&gt;It’s also part of the reason why this is a perfect drone for almost everyone. Usually when I take out the Mavic 2 Pro, I worry about ND filters, polarizers, and I try to keep the aperture at that sharpest f/5,6 – f/8 range. But with the Mini 2, my approach changes entirely. It’s almost like going from a fully manual SLR to a point-and-shoot camera. I basically just leave everything on auto without being too precious about the technical side of things, trusting that everything I get will actually be quite good. It’s a nice change of pace to my overall approach that I wasn’t expecting when I started my review. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GCeXxo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10337197"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="FUrJ0Z"&gt;Video on the DJI Mini 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="6rqLxW"&gt;Even though the sensor is unchanged, it is now capable of shooting 4K video at 100 Mbps bitrate up to 30fps compared to 2.7K at 60 Mbps that was on the original Mavic Mini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ckTLQ1"&gt;The footage looks surprisingly good for a sensor of this size. Daylight footage looks crisp throughout and the color doesn’t look overly processed. There’s enough information there for you to do minor color edits in post production if you really want to, but most people will be happy with videos straight out of the camera. Unfortunately, you won’t find a dedicated cinelike color profile, which would have provided a little bit more control over the coloring process and extended the dynamic range. For someone like me who likes to manipulate color in the edit, this is a big downside. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;
&lt;aside id="b2Ot7s"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There are no color profiles, but footage straight from the camera is solid&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6c8UMYE_xtrHiudAjwLh9ZxGKCQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22296011/vpavic_201118_4405_0348.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bij_Wwh2kdJB3okOiraNxtJkI8s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22296012/vpavic_201118_4405_0349.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LLMhqS"&gt;DJI does have a decent track record of bringing useful software updates to its products. The first Mavic Mini received a massive upgrade last year which enabled things like the cinelike profile and added the ability to take RAW photos in addition to JPG. I hope DJI keeps adding more features to this drone, too, but as always you shouldn’t buy hardware today based on the hope of a software update in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GxInVJ"&gt;Similarly to what I said about photos, the smaller sensor really shows its limitations at higher ISO numbers, but I wouldn’t let that discourage you. The footage still looks good even at low light. The blacks and shadows hold up very well and the overall image still looks rich. There is visible noise in the shadows, but my advice is to lean into those shadows, make them darker and a lot of that noise will get removed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aeDKnU"&gt;There is one more downside to this camera and that is the lack of support for ND filters. I’ve seen some third-party options online, but the camera isn’t designed for them. On rare occasions some video clips did look choppy due to very fast shutter speeds, but for the most part it has been surprisingly tolerable. The lack of ND filters speaks more to who DJI had in mind as a potential consumer. Most people don’t go through the hassle of learning about and using ND filters, but I wish it was an option for the few of us who do invest more time in the filming process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HjbIgh"&gt;Lastly, this drone also has a 2x zoom. DJI calls it lossless, but that’s a bit generous. It looks fine on smaller screens, but once you start editing your footage, you’ll immediately notice its drawbacks. Pixels become larger and footage loses its sharpness. It doesn’t look any different than cropping the original footage. It’s a nice little bonus feature which could work in a pinch, but I wouldn’t rely on it too much. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JCYgwppJO16OvlZWfbGQ5dK55gA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22296009/vpavic_201118_4405_0339.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="eKfcJP"&gt;The Mini 2 isn’t DJI’s flashiest drone. In fact, it is almost the opposite. It proved to me how many flagship drone features I actually don’t miss when they’re gone. The Mini 2 is a culmination of some of the best things DJI can offer inside a minuscule package, starting with an always reliable and steady connection, more than adequate camera, and a great software experience. This drone strikes a near perfect balance between price, mobility, and image quality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cCUEZg"&gt;But as a creator, image quality is really important to me. And as much as I praised the improvements here, you still have to be aware of the limitations of smaller sensors when it comes to noise-to-pixel density ratio, low light performance, and dynamic range. Ninety percent of the time this drone was great for what I needed it to do, but there were times I wished I had a slightly better camera on me with higher megapixel count, a bigger sensor, or wider dynamic range. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aFitV0"&gt;All those image quality specs really do matter — but so does the DJI Mini 2’s size. It’s a drone that I never hesitate to toss in my camera bag. The old saying that the best camera is the one you have with you is just as true when that camera is attached to a drone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="h0orip"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="YTXjkC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10337439"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22277238/dji-mini-2-drone-review-price-specs-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22277238/dji-mini-2-drone-review-price-specs-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Vjeran Pavic</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T10:52:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T10:52:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>Waymo and Cruise dominated autonomous testing in California in the first year of the pandemic</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fa2I_i208ZTscMz6Nmbg6azs-es=/0x168:4032x2856/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68803589/Image_from_iOS__9_.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="H4ERkN"&gt;Unsurprisingly, there was much less autonomous vehicle testing in California in 2020 compared to years prior. The COVID-19 pandemic and ensuing lockdowns &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/18/21183421/self-driving-cars-coronavirus-covid19-human-drivers-waymo-cruise-zoox"&gt;forced many AVs off the road&lt;/a&gt; in the early part of the year. But companies licensed to operate AVs on public roads in California still logged nearly 2 million miles of testing, with two of the top operators, Waymo and Cruise, comprising the bulk of those miles thanks to what some safety drivers allege was a lax attitude toward safety. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tMlncs"&gt;Autonomous vehicles registered in California traveled approximately 1.99 million miles in autonomous mode on public roads in 2020, a decrease of about 800,000 miles from the previous year, according to the state’s Department of Motor Vehicles. These mileage figures were reported as part of &lt;a href="https://www.dmv.ca.gov/portal/vehicle-industry-services/autonomous-vehicles/disengagement-reports/"&gt;the state’s annual “disengagement reports,”&lt;/a&gt; which all licensed operators are required to submit. In addition to the miles driven, the reports list the frequency at which human safety drivers were forced to take control of their autonomous vehicles (also known as a “disengagement”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="HJdSIS"&gt;&lt;q&gt;a decrease of about 800,000 miles from the previous year&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fARZc7"&gt;The disengagement reports are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/26/21142685/california-dmv-self-driving-car-disengagement-report-data"&gt;widely disparaged&lt;/a&gt; as being, at best, meaningless and, at worse, misleading. Companies have a lot of discretion about when to disengage, the testing environments aren’t uniform, and it’s difficult to make an apples-to-apples comparison between companies. Media outlets tend to overhype the numbers in service of a false “race” narrative in which certain companies are outpacing others in miles driven and disengagements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Qm2Vyp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Everyone hates California’s self-driving car reports","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/26/21142685/california-dmv-self-driving-car-disengagement-report-data"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="zpdHsF"&gt;But this year, the reports can still serve as a time capsule of a year upended by the coronavirus pandemic. Waymo, for example, generally considered to be the leading autonomous vehicle operator in the world, only drove 628,838 miles, a 56-percent decrease compared to the 1.45 million miles it drove in 2019. That decrease is notable considering Waymo was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/3/20680938/waymo-self-driving-cars-passengers-permit-california-pick-up"&gt;recently approved to begin accepting passengers&lt;/a&gt; in its vehicles in preparation for the inevitable launch of a robotaxi service in California. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9o2Qwv"&gt;Waymo only reported 21 disengagements over the course of the year, or a rate of 0.033 disengagements per 1,000 miles. That’s an improvement over the company’s rate of 0.076 per 1,000 self-driven miles in 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a0BiVo"&gt;Cruise, a wholly owned subsidiary of General Motors and Waymo’s main rival, is also prepping to launch a similar service in the state. And interestingly enough, its mileage number remained more or less the same last year as compared to 2019. The company reported driving 770,049 miles, a 7-percent decrease over 2019. It logged 26 disengagements during the year for a rate of 0.033 per 1,000 miles, improving on its 2019 rate of 0.082. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="G38k7p"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The total miles driven by Waymo and Cruise, 1.39 million, is 70 percent of the total autonomous miles&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="H0YOQI"&gt;The total miles driven by Waymo and Cruise, 1.39 million, is 70 percent of the total autonomous miles driven in California in 2020. Both companies briefly grounded their vehicles in the early months of the pandemic, but Cruise was back on the road by late April, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/10/21286301/cruise-self-driving-car-testing-san-francisco-stay-home-order"&gt;using deliveries to local food banks as a pretext&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/30/21275441/waymo-self-driving-car-delivery-bay-area-resume-covid"&gt;Waymo followed suit&lt;/a&gt;, resuming limited operations in June delivering packages for two Bay Area nonprofits. Over the summer, as COVID-19 cases in California were peaking, both companies resumed regular operations. Only when the air quality became very poor during the summer’s historic wildfires did Waymo and Cruise pull their vehicles from the road — and only briefly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ju5I9w"&gt;This was a worrisome decision for many of the companies’ backup drivers. Waymo and Cruise &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/5/21123049/waymo-self-driving-cars-workers-vendor-contracts-benefits-needles"&gt;contract the labor of thousands of operational staff&lt;/a&gt; in the Bay Area, including backup drivers, mechanics, cleaners, and fleet managers. Backup drivers, in particular, play a crucial role: they monitor the driving operations of the self-driving car and occasionally take control when something goes wrong. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="D04xOf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Waymo and Cruise safety drivers face a bleak choice: pandemic or pollution?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/5/21473719/waymo-cruise-self-driving-car-backup-safety-driver-pandemic-wildfires-california"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="vKweI5"&gt;Some backup drivers were glad to be back at work. But others raised concerns about being stuck in a vehicle for hours a day with another person without the ability to socially distance. They chafed at being asked to come back to work while the salaried employees in the engineering and software divisions of these companies got to continue to work from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eJXN1u"&gt;Waymo and Cruise both insist that safety, including the safety of their contract workers, is a top concern. But several drivers have accused the companies of exploiting loopholes to get cars back on the road in defiance of local public health orders. Cruise, in particular, was criticized for deploying non-delivery vehicles despite public health orders banning regular autonomous vehicle testing. Cruise said the extra vehicles were needed for R&amp;amp;D support for the delivery operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i2mzST"&gt;Waymo and Cruise weren’t alone in racking up big mileage numbers during the pandemic. Pony.ai, a self-driving startup based in Silicon Valley and Guangzhou, China, reported driving 225,496 miles in autonomous mode. And Zoox, an autonomous vehicle company recently acquired by Amazon, drove 102,521 miles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OXKGWv"&gt;Apple, which has been working on its own secretive car project for years, reported driving 18,805 miles, more than doubling its mileage in 2019. The tech giant also reported 130 disengagements, up from 64 the previous year. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22276851/california-self-driving-autonomous-cars-miles-waymo-cruise-2020"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22276851/california-self-driving-autonomous-cars-miles-waymo-cruise-2020</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
