<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-07-02T09:26:48-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-02T09:26:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-02T09:26:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla delivered over 200,000 cars in the second quarter of 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QxDCyMnqZ4PxNqSIJannNZCjq9I=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69533799/jbareham_180213_2301_0168.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qkU2uy"&gt;&lt;a href="https://ir.tesla.com/press-release/tesla-q2-2021-vehicle-production-deliveries"&gt;Tesla delivered 201,250 vehicles&lt;/a&gt; in the second quarter of 2021, a record for the company but still falling slightly short of Wall Street expectations. Elon Musk’s company also produced 206,421 vehicles during the same period. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Np3aK"&gt;Of all the cars that Tesla produced during the quarter, the vast majority — 204,081 — were Model 3 and Model Y vehicles. On top of that, Tesla also produced 2,340 Model S and Model X vehicles — though the company did not break out how many Model S sedans were &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22528963/tesla-model-s-plaid-ev-price-specs-range-speed"&gt;the high-end Plaid variant&lt;/a&gt; that just started reaching customers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wDW7g4"&gt;Earlier last month, Tesla held a delivery event for the redesigned Model S, featuring a new powertrain, more horsepower, a new landscape touchscreen and steering wheel, and more range. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hIebET"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing... &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LG16dh"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c8bz1o"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22560608/tesla-q2-2021-deliveries-elon-musk"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22560608/tesla-q2-2021-deliveries-elon-musk</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-02T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-02T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Electric vehicles are the future for everyone — except disabled people</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Rz2cT0Szh1PhsITx0l0OBrfveg4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69533659/acastro_210625_4643_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;By locating the battery in the floor of the vehicle, auto companies are making it difficult to convert EVs for wheelchair users&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="jU2oxZ"&gt;In a Super Bowl commercial that aired earlier this year, GM declared that its electric vehicles were designed for everyone. The ad closed with the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nJf5Woythmk"&gt;image of a one-armed surfer&lt;/a&gt; to emphasize its point. But sometime later, that &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KgdQfbaGPsE"&gt;surfer was replaced by an able-bodied counterpart&lt;/a&gt;, with no explanation for the switch. As a wheelchair user, I was left wondering whether people like me are being left out of the EV revolution?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G1lT9H"&gt;There’s no doubt that EVs are going to be one of the pillars of our future, yet there are currently none on the market for the disabled. Retrofitting these vehicles with ramps seems close to impossible due to the architecture. And the only &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/26/22352748/volkswagen-id-buzz-electric-microbus-us-release-date"&gt;EV on the horizon&lt;/a&gt; that could be made accessible isn’t coming until 2023 — and even then, it’s unclear that it will be marketed toward disabled drivers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZcXT9V"&gt;I don’t drive because treatment for a brain tumor caused swelling that impacted my cranial nerves, corrupting my balance, motor skills, and causing my eyes to bounce. I did own a Dodge minivan with a converted ramp so that others could transport me in my electric wheelchair when I had to travel long distances or on tough terrain. For someone with an active life, these vans are a necessity. I was fortunate in that I had the financial support to purchase one, but for many disabled people who live off Social Security income or low-wage jobs, this option is prohibitive. And the price tag will only go up with new technology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JV1eCv"&gt;But price is not the problem at this juncture. Most electric vehicles use a so-called “skateboard architecture,” which includes the battery pack, the electric drivetrain, and the electrical architecture that rests under the floor of the vehicle. This makes an EV harder to get into for those with physical disabilities — if only by a minimal amount — because the floor is placed above the battery pack. For disabled drivers, an untapped consumer base of 61 million with nearly $500 million of disposable income, that extra inch or two could be the reason for not getting a license or owning a car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="b04H6k"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I do feel that I might have a harder time getting into the driver’s seat if the battery raises the height of the floor.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="afVBzn"&gt;Kelly Dawson, a disability advocate and writer based in Los Angeles, has limited mobility due to cerebral palsy that mostly affects her legs. She can’t bend down to fill her tires with air because she can’t crouch and balance at the same time. But even as an ambulatory driver, she is worried about the challenges EVs might present her. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OK0wLg"&gt;“I do feel that I might have a harder time getting into the driver’s seat if the battery raises the height of the floor,” she said. “With my current fuel-powered car, I can step or slide in, but an EV might be a tighter (potentially unsafe) squeeze.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PVHZTa"&gt;Dawson points out that “when cars were first introduced to the public at the beginning of the 20th century, disabled people were in no way a part of public life — they were actively excluded from it. The main difference with this chapter of automotive innovation is that it’s coming 30 years after the passage of the ADA [Americans with Disabilities Act].”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SqRAVz"&gt;Where this barrier for the disabled comes into focus is in the potential conversion of the vehicle. Dropping the floor of a gas-powered vehicle 10–14 inches would typically cost $25,000–35,000 and can be partially paid for with help from the state government or Department of Veterans Affairs. Roughly 20,000 of these conversions are done every year, according to Sam Abuelsamid, principal analyst for e-mobility at Guidehouse. However, vehicle conversion companies like &lt;a href="https://www.mobilityworks.com/"&gt;MobilityWorks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.braunability.com/us/en.html"&gt;Braunability&lt;/a&gt;, while being able to add handbrake equipment, can’t convert electric vehicles to have a ramp due to the battery’s position. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZCUVEjikxuiuXRUiH-ekl9yfRc8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22693492/Screen_Shot_2021_07_01_at_10.59.41_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Screenshot via &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.mobilityworks.com/vehicles/chrysler/" target="_blank"&gt;Braunability&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7oJtvl"&gt;Abuelsamid said that Braunability does offer a conversion for the Chrysler Pacifica plug-in hybrid, which has drop-down ramp access through the rear, but there are no fully electric minivans like that on the market today. Some larger electric vans will appear later this year in the Ford &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21559954/ford-e-transit-electric-delivery-cargo-van-price-specs-range"&gt;E-Transit&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/roadshow/news/gm-brightdrop-ev600-electric-van-ev-ces-fedex/"&gt;Brightdrop EV600&lt;/a&gt; from GM, but those are prioritized for commercial fleets. The first real electric minivan expected to arrive is the VW ID Buzz in 2023. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lkBmyJ"&gt;Kevin Frayne worked for 34 years at GM before joining Braunability as its quasi-futurist. He recently spoke on behalf of the US Access Board at the Department of Transportation’s forum on equity. And he works closely with companies to consult on designs. He said this task will be a difficult one. “It’s not insurmountable, but companies have to start working with us now,” Frayne said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="qg3Vg6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“In this case, everything has to do with geometry and triangles.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bHHCTf"&gt;“In this case, everything has to do with geometry and triangles,” he said. Frayne has to think about things like roof height because the ADA requires door openings to be 56 inches tall, which makes it a problematic crunch when the floor is raised. If he has two inches to fit an ultra-thin ramp between the floor and the battery, he has to devise a blueprint for the ADA-mandated slope ratio of one inch of rise for every four inches of ramp — though Frayne and others think it should be 1:6. And that doesn’t even take into account automated tie-down systems to secure a wheelchair once inside a vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XilhHL"&gt;But conversions are not the only potential barriers for the disabled community. &lt;a href="https://www.zap-map.com/electric-vehicle-charge-points-lack-accessibility/"&gt;A four-year study by Zap-Map and Motability in the UK&lt;/a&gt; found that one-third of drivers with disabilities had difficulty finding a charge station they could use. The survey only included 2,200 people, and 176 of those considered themselves disabled, but that might have something to do with EV ownership among the disabled being so low due to income and access. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nnN6e6"&gt;According to that survey, one reason for inaccessibility at charging stations is the heavy weight of charging cables. Like cellphone and laptop batteries, high-power charging generates a lot of heat in the cable, which is why they are typically insulated and liquid-cooled. This makes them heavier and harder to maneuver. Adding to the difficulty, the charging connectors need to be precisely aligned in order to slide in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gl67KN"&gt;Other issues include the force required to connect the cables to the EV, the lack of curb-cuts to access the charging station, and parking spaces bunched too closely together. Hopefully, as electric vehicles become cheaper and more popular, charging station operators will abandon the current side-by-side setup to support disabled drivers as well as trucks, buses, and vehicles pulling trailers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="tM1xLL"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It seems that disabled drivers and passengers are, at the moment, something of an afterthought”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kEU9Jv"&gt;In 2014, the Department of Energy released a &lt;a href="https://afdc.energy.gov/files/u/publication/WPCC_complyingwithADArequirements_1114.pdf"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; with measurements and images depicting a layout for charging stations. While it would be easy to install charging stations in old or unused parking spaces, by law, every lot must have four accessible spaces, and 1 in 6 must be van accessible. As EV expert Dan Caesar from &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/fullychargedshow"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fully Charged&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; says, “It seems that disabled drivers and passengers are, at the moment, something of an afterthought for the nascent electric vehicle/charging sector.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QHxHtM"&gt;I asked Henry Claypool, technology policy consultant for the American Association of People with Disabilities, about the obstacle of EV batteries in the floor of the vehicle. He was optimistic, recalling how in 2019, Volkswagen convened a meeting with a range of stakeholder groups to discuss building a purpose-built wheelchair-accessible vehicle as part of the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.inclusivemobility.com/"&gt;Inclusive Mobility&lt;/a&gt; initiative. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0ajoMt"&gt;“At the end of this meeting, a few VW engineers came down to the parking garage to look at my aftermarket modified van,” Claypool told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “They observed the kneeling and ramp system and didn’t seem troubled by creating something like an electric vehicle with a battery in the floor. They seemed really committed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0XJvtO"&gt;Claypool said Toyota is another company that is really advanced in accessibility. “It will be exciting to see them unveil an accessible AV at the Paralympics in Tokyo, Japan,” he said. “And the thing is, when one OEM successfully does this, everyone’s going to follow.”                                               &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zLjIhi"&gt;What remains frustrating, though, is how disabled people are being used to sell products while being left out of the engineering decisions. The disabled community doesn’t want to drive gas-burning cars while everyone else zips around in zero-emission vehicles. Automakers shouldn’t put off the disabled community’s concerns because if we’re not included on a foundational level, it’s going to be more complex and expensive for everyone going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="6syBEw"&gt;“Disabled people are arguably the most innovative cohort of Americans,” says Dawson. “We shouldn’t just be behind the wheel of electric cars, we should also be calling the shots on how to build them.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22550853/electric-vehicles-disabled-wheelchair-conversion-battery"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22550853/electric-vehicles-disabled-wheelchair-conversion-battery</id>
    <author>
      <name>Christopher Reardon</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-02T08:40:40-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-02T08:40:40-04:00</updated>
    <title>Dell’s G15 Ryzen Edition with an RTX 3060 is $1,078 for a limited time</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Dell G15 Ryzen Edition" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SAM8rUcZPfPqmvLElwMlEpvf5mc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69533629/g15lineup.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Kvemwm"&gt;Right now, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22368010/dell-g15-amd-ryzen-edition-15-inch-gaming-laptop-release-date-price-specs"&gt;Dell’s G15 Ryzen Edition&lt;/a&gt; is perhaps the most affordable gaming laptop that has a powerful Ryzen 7 5800H processor and an Nvidia RTX 3060 graphics chip inside (via &lt;a href="https://slickdeals.net/f/15136345-dell-g15-r5-15-6-fhd-165hz-ips-ryzen-7-5800h-16gb-ddr4-512gb-pcie-ssd-rtx-3060-win10h-1077-99?src=jfy%7Crecombee%7C6318339ea0bbb63ee26e92b252a7a4de"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slickdeals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Those two components alone &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-8836598-14367655?sid=verge&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdeals.dell.com%2Fen-us%2Fmpp%2Fproductdetail%2F9dch" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;make today’s price of $1,078 an amazing deal&lt;/a&gt; (originally $1,459). Additionally, this laptop features a 15.6-inch 1080p screen with a 165Hz refresh rate, 16GB of DDR4 RAM, and a 512GB NVMe SSD (both the RAM and storage are user-upgradeable). I can’t hide that I’m pretty excited about this deal, partially because I don’t know how much longer it will last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L3o0Go"&gt;If you’re interested in buying a gaming laptop that doesn’t cost too much but want one that has a respectable graphics card, consider this one. Its RTX 3060 supports up to 115W of total graphics power — the same power you’ll find in the much more expensive &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22518545/alienware-m15-r5-ryzen-edition-review-7-5800h-nvidia-rtx-3060-features-specs-performance"&gt;Alienware M15 R5 Ryzen Edition&lt;/a&gt; that currently sells for $1,372. With it, games like &lt;em&gt;Red Redemption 2&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Horizon Zero Dawn&lt;/em&gt; ran faster than 60 frames per second on ultra graphics settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wWHO07"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10634452"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="XPpvpa"&gt;
&lt;p id="P8MU9y"&gt;Sony’s last-gen WH-1000XM3 over-ear, wireless headphones are discounted at Best Buy. Originally $349, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1743780474724360893#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;they’re $200&lt;/a&gt;. We featured a similar deal recently that saw them at $10 cheaper, but this isn’t a bad deal if you have an eye out for headphones with great sound quality and a very effective noise cancellation effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="HH32Qa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10326538"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="8BifuY"&gt;
&lt;p id="dlZ4yY"&gt;The Master &amp;amp; Dynamic MW07 were a tough sell for their original $299 price back in late 2018, but &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-8836598-13142092?sid=verge&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Felectronics.woot.com%2Foffers%2Fmaster-dynamic-mw07-true-wireless-earphones-15%3Fref%3Dw_cnt_wp_2_46" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Woot has them new for just $115&lt;/a&gt;. These aren’t the most capable truly wireless earphones you can buy in terms of features, but they have a unique look, a cozy fit, decent noise isolation, and sound quality that likely outpaces most competition at the $115 price range. They come in a shiny case that’s reminiscent of the backside of old iPods.  Similarly, it’s prone to scratching and collecting fingerprints, but it looks distinguished, at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="P3Rrgn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10307496"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="K4GKgt"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/7/2/22560530/dell-g15-ryzen-edition-rtx-3060-sony-wh1000xm3-headphones-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/7/2/22560530/dell-g15-ryzen-edition-rtx-3060-sony-wh1000xm3-headphones-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-02T08:30:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-02T08:30:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>Full approval could make the difference for the US COVID-19 vaccine campaign   </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Covid-19 Vaccinations in USA" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M5s4yRv0Li2UagRr6bSuZlTuJ_Q=/134x0:4967x3222/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69533609/1301632521.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by: Jose More/VWPics/Universal Images Group via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qbVrdI"&gt;Right now, anyone rolling up their sleeve for a COVID-19 vaccine in the United States is supposed to get a &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/media/144414/download"&gt;long information sheet&lt;/a&gt;. The document informs them that, even though the vaccine can prevent COVID-19, it’s technically not yet approved in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NrIrZx"&gt;Instead, people are getting the shot under an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22189236/fda-approval-authorization-difference-clearance-vaccines"&gt;emergency use authorization&lt;/a&gt; (EUA) — a designation that let the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) sign off on the lifesaving immunizations without going through the long, onerous licensing process. The shots still went through a rigorous safety review, and there’s ample evidence that they’re highly effective. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iSUHaN"&gt;But for some people, the “emergency” tag and the fact that the shots are still unapproved is a reason to avoid getting vaccinated. &lt;a href="https://www.kff.org/coronavirus-covid-19/poll-finding/kff-covid-19-vaccine-monitor-june-2021/"&gt;New polling&lt;/a&gt; from the Kaiser Family Foundation released Wednesday shows that around a third of unvaccinated adults in the United States would be more likely to get vaccinated when the FDA gives a full approval to the shots. About 35 percent of adults in the United States are currently unvaccinated — a third of that group would be around 10 percent of US adults. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="6y4wPM"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9360449"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="m58tHt"&gt;A 10 percent bump in the number of US adults who are vaccinated would be significant, especially as the Delta variant of the coronavirus takes hold across the country. The variant is highly contagious, and it is &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/michael-brown-europe-coronavirus-pandemic-coronavirus-vaccine-science-e1379d34d3cdff0f522e0915b0f246fe"&gt;easily burning through&lt;/a&gt; communities where most people aren’t vaccinated. In Missouri, for example, counties with low vaccination rates are seeing spikes in COVID-19 hospital admissions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zu8yGX"&gt;Experts cautioned &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/26/21266591/covid-19-coronavirus-vaccine-fda-authorize-emergency-experimental"&gt;last summer&lt;/a&gt; that the emergency use of a COVID-19 vaccine, even if it was the best way to beat back the pandemic, could lead to some vaccine hesitancy. The limited data they had back then looked bad — only &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/26/21266591/covid-19-coronavirus-vaccine-fda-authorize-emergency-experimental"&gt;around 8 percent&lt;/a&gt; of people said in 2009 they’d take a hypothetical emergency H1N1 vaccine. People proved far less reluctant to take an emergency COVID-19 vaccine, but some clearly still have reservations. And each person who avoids the COVID-19 vaccine is a weakness in the US protection against the virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a4sMWm"&gt;The FDA is currently reviewing applications for full approval of both the Moderna and Pfizer / BioNTech COVID-19 vaccines, but it’s not clear when the final license for either might be released. While we wait, public health officials are still using every tool at their disposal to encourage more people to get vaccinated, like lotteries and convenient mobile clinics. Full approval will likely be a big boost for vaccination numbers, but Delta is here already — and there’s no time to waste. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ATIaVh"&gt;Here’s what else happened this week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gHfsse"&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="KNga9l"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/28/health/coronavirus-vaccines-immunity.html?smid=tw-nytimes&amp;amp;smtyp=cur"&gt;Pfizer and Moderna Vaccines Are Likely to Produce Long-Lasting Immunity, Study Suggests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Researchers checked the lymph nodes of people who had been vaccinated with mRNA vaccines to see how immunity developed. The findings suggest that people could be protected from COVID-19 for years. (Apoorva Mandavilli / &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dhBkYa"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2021/06/coronavirus-evolution-virulence/619301/?utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_campaign=share"&gt;Why No One Is Sure If Delta Is Deadlier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Delta variant of the coronavirus clearly spreads faster and is more contagious, but it’s hard to pin down any changes in how sick it can make people. (Katherine Wu / &lt;em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p9cFIQ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/28/health/coronavirus-vaccine-immunity.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=Top%20Stories&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage"&gt;Three Studies, One Result: Vaccines Point the Way Out of the Pandemic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;A set of new studies on the COVID-19 vaccines underscore their efficacy, and indicate that people may not need boosters — if the virus doesn’t continue to change. (Apoorva Mandavilli, Carl Zimmer, and Rebecca Robbins / &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="odMcn4"&gt;Development &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="S27mJK"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-moderna/modernas-covid-19-vaccine-shows-promise-against-delta-variant-in-lab-study-idUSKCN2E51J5"&gt;Moderna’s COVID-19 vaccine shows promise against Delta variant in lab study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Antibodies produced by the Moderna COVID-19 vaccine could still neutralize the Delta coronavirus variant in blood samples, a good sign that the shots can still handle that form of the virus. (&lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dH81ia"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-021-01805-2?utm_source=twt_nat&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_campaign=nature"&gt;Mix-and-match COVID vaccines: the case is growing, but questions remain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Combining one shot of the AstraZeneca COVID-19 vaccine with a second Pfizer / BioNTech jab might give better protection than a two-dose series of the same brand, research indicates. There needs to be more research on potential side effects of mixing shots. (Dyani Lewis / &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="grbPRu"&gt;Perspectives &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="NgfJTi"&gt;As the national government doled out limited amounts of oxygen, officials in Delhi grew increasingly worried. Its hospitals had built only one small oxygen-generating plant because there had previously been little need, said Manish Sisodia, Delhi’s deputy chief minister. And Delhi could store only about one day’s worth of its pandemic needs at its hospitals and in a city-owned tank.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="8adCCj"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;— &lt;/strong&gt;a &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/28/world/asia/india-coronavirus-oxygen.html?smtyp=cur&amp;amp;smid=tw-nytimes"&gt;&lt;em&gt;New York Times &lt;/em&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; traced the cascade of failures that lead to oxygen supplies running out at hospitals in India&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="IOqaIp"&gt;More than numbers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Vw2L5J"&gt;To the people who have received the &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/covid-vaccine-tracker-global-distribution/?sref=ExbtjcSG&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Antivirus%3A%20This%20week%20in%20COVID-19%20research&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=Revue%20newsletter"&gt;3.1 billion vaccine doses&lt;/a&gt; distributed so far — thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cbalD2"&gt;To the more than 182,420,108 people worldwide who have tested positive, may your road to recovery be smooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sp0gru"&gt;To the families and friends of the 3,950,309 people who have died worldwide — 604,935 of those in the US — your loved ones are not forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TiEK5k"&gt;Stay safe, everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2E0iMD"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22559712/covid-vaccine-approval-delta"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22559712/covid-vaccine-approval-delta</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-02T08:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-02T08:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix bets on bingeable horror with Fear Street trilogy  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="fear street" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/efL815r-DhXgrOARdmvI7aIuRHA=/714x0:3126x1608/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69533601/1_008_070_c_v007._1000_1215__1.156.1_CR.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vSsQFo"&gt;Something special happens when you marathon horror movies. On their own, slasher flicks like &lt;em&gt;Friday the 13th&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Halloween&lt;/em&gt; can seem like nothing more than bloody fun. But when you watch a bunch in a row, the connections and mythologies become much more apparent; Jason Voorhees shifts from a murderous demon into something more sympathetic. Some of them even feature “previously on” segments to make these links more obvious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xc4Z2F"&gt;These movies may not have been created with binge-watching in mind, but in many ways they benefit from it, which is part of what makes the &lt;em&gt;Fear Street&lt;/em&gt; trilogy on Netflix so interesting: it was designed to be binged. All three entries, starting with part one on July 2nd, will be released over the course of three weeks. It’s a unique experiment with changing viewing habits, and one that feels uniquely suited to horror as a genre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ABra2V"&gt;The films are based loosely on the R.L. Stine books of the same name, following a town called Shadyside that’s been haunted for centuries, cursed by periodic — and grisly — killings that have earned it a reputation as the murder capital of the US. The movies track this history across three time periods. Part one is set in 1994, followed by 1978 and 1666. Though they tell individual stories, they’re all tightly connected to the Shadyside mythos. You’ll definitely want to watch them in order.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Fear Street" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Zf5uXpZW79fuuQ2_p-d4tYVNWFY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22694120/Fear_Street_Part_1__1994_00_49_16_17_R.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="YTJ61D"&gt;The 1994 movie starts, as many horror movies do, with a young woman being killed. From there, you learn that the town of Shadyside has long been haunted by a dead witch named Sarah Fier (pronounced “Fear,” naturally) and that, every so often, someone goes on a murderous rampage, apparently due to her influence. The vibe is sort of like &lt;em&gt;Scream&lt;/em&gt; crossed with the &lt;em&gt;Chilling Adventures of Sabrina&lt;/em&gt;, as a group of misfit high school students work together to learn about Fier and end the killings once and for all. (You can get a sense of the first movie &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/30/22558138/netflix-fear-street-movie-1994-first-five-minutes"&gt;by watching the first five minutes here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="70bAaT"&gt;It has all of the hallmarks of a slasher movie — inventively grisly deaths, single-minded killers that never give up, gratuitous sex scenes — but it’s buoyed by the hint of a deeper mystery. I won’t spoil anything, but the way the first movie connects to the sequels makes them ideal for close viewing. When I finished part one, I immediately had to know what happened next. And even though each one has a very different vibe — part two takes place at a summer retreat reminiscent of &lt;em&gt;Friday the 13th&lt;/em&gt;’s Camp Crystal Lake, while the third goes back a few centuries to the early days of Shadyside — they all feel part of the same whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pLNYJM"&gt;According to Netflix, the three movies were filmed over a 108-day period in Atlanta, which was preceded by a month-long writers’ room to nail down the story and the way it would connect each film. “Everyone involved in production knew this was crazy,” Leigh Janiak, who directed all three movies, explained in a statement. “I didn’t realize how crazy and weird it was until I got into post-production and was like, these are three completely different movies.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="fear street" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CbHOnG62VVmfYS3T0_pXOOQkYKQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22694128/Fear_Street_Part_1_1994_A226C002_190503_R2QE_1.368.1_r_rgb.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="BJj1hm"&gt;Ever since Netflix started to dabble in original programming, there have been countless debates about how and when episodic stories should be released on streaming services. Netflix typically drops new seasons of its big shows, like &lt;em&gt;The Witcher&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/em&gt;, all at once, so viewers can watch at their leisure. Disney, meanwhile, tends to go the weekly route, so you have to wait to see what happens next on &lt;em&gt;Loki&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt;. (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/17/22538210/disney-plus-wednesday-friday-release-schedule-loki"&gt;Disney even recently shifted to experimenting with Wednesday releases instead of Friday&lt;/a&gt;.) There are benefits to both; binging gives fans what they want immediately, while weekly releases help a show stay in the spotlight for longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eYCdCK"&gt;Up until now, though, that conversation has never really involved movies. &lt;em&gt;Fear Street&lt;/em&gt; represents something new in that regard, and it’s the kind of experiment that could only really work in the world of streaming. What might otherwise be a gone-and-forgotten horror flick is now more of a summer movie event. After part one debuts on July 2nd, two and three will follow on the 9th and 16th. The releases are close enough that you won’t forget what happens in between, but also spread out so that the trilogy has its own prolonged moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CmYGta"&gt;As with all experiments, it’s unclear if this is a one-off event or the beginnings of a trend. It’s unlikely that Marvel will do something similar for its next superhero epic; blockbuster movies are challenging and expensive enough to make already, without having to worry about doing several at once. But for lower-stakes genre films, such as horror, it makes a lot more sense. And, at least in the case of &lt;em&gt;Fear Street&lt;/em&gt;, the release strategy actually improves the viewing experience — a new technique to breathe life into an old genre.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22559554/fear-street-trilogy-netflix-horror-movie-binge"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22559554/fear-street-trilogy-netflix-horror-movie-binge</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-02T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-02T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>General Motors strikes a deal to source lithium in the US for its electric car batteries </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Salton Sea In California Faces Ecological Collapse" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CmOufuVIBPzoM5U64xMxG9he81M=/2x0:5407x3603/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69533503/1231148258.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by David McNew/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JSPWok"&gt;General Motors has struck a deal with a mining company to source lithium, a key ingredient in electric-car batteries, from geothermal deposits in the US. The automaker is making a “multi-million dollar” investment in Australia’s &lt;a href="https://www.cthermal.com/"&gt;Controlled Thermal Resources&lt;/a&gt; (CTR) to bolster the mining firm’s efforts to extract lithium from California’s Salton Sea Geothermal Field. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yuQtC9"&gt;It’s a risky bet by GM, given that there is no full-scale lithium production in the US from geothermal wells. Most of the world’s lithium comes from two places: lithium brine deposits in South America’s “lithium triangle” of Argentina, Chile, and Bolivia; and hard-rock deposits in Australia. But its a sign that GM is trying to think holistically about the challenge of becoming an EV-only company by 2035. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="IwmWVO"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s a risky bet by GM&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="k8XSml"&gt;CTR’s “direct extraction” process will have a “very small physical footprint” that produces very few carbon emissions, said Tim Grewe, general director electrification strategy and cell engineering at GM. Electric vehicle batteries can use lithium carbonate or lithium hydroxide, but the industry typically talks of lithium carbonate equivalent, which contains both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sn7y8Q"&gt;“Lithium is a crucial metal to make these affordable high mileage electric vehicles in our future,” Grewe said. “We’re gonna have the first rights for the lithium produced out of this project.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0xf5bU"&gt;GM said a “significant amount” of the lithium it needs for its EV batteries will come from CTR’s “Hell’s Kitchen” development site in the Salton Sea Geothermal Field, located in Imperial, California. The California Energy Commission &lt;a href="https://ww2.energy.ca.gov/2020publications/CEC-500-2020-020/CEC-500-2020-020.pdf"&gt;estimates the area could produce 600,000 tons of lithium carbonate&lt;/a&gt; annually, worth $7.2 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mrKRbm"&gt;“It’s the single largest lithium brine resource in the United States, if not on the planet… It will be a critical hub,” Rod Colwell, CEO of CTR, &lt;a href="https://fortune.com/2021/06/11/lithium-electric-cars-extraction-green-brine-geothermal/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Fortune&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;earlier this month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2O5nSb"&gt;There won’t be an immediate payoff for GM’s investment, the size of which the company declined to disclose. The first stage of CTR’s project is not expected to yield lithium until 2024. But Grewe said GM will try to synthesize the lithium for its batteries as “quickly as it can, trying to beat [2024]” if possible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="dsEZqO"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The race to find new and environmentally friendly sources of lithium in California has been called a “white go&lt;s&gt;&lt;span class="ql-cursor"&gt;﻿&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/s&gt;ld rush”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kgTcmU"&gt;The race to find new and environmentally friendly sources of lithium in California has been called a &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/04/28/990867075/californias-white-gold-rush-lithium-in-demand-amid-surge-in-electric-vehicles"&gt;“white gold rush,”&lt;/a&gt; with companies intent on producing millions of electric vehicle batteries looking to secure a piece of the process. This rising demand has also triggered &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/shortages-flagged-ev-materials-lithium-cobalt-2021-07-01/"&gt;concerns about shortages&lt;/a&gt;, with analysts forecasting deficits in the tens of thousands of tons by 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7JPner"&gt;CTR isn’t the first company to try to find a cost-effective way to pull the mineral from the naturally heated waters deep beneath the Salton Sea. One recent example was Simbol Materials, a much-hyped start-up that collapsed in 2015 shortly after Tesla &lt;a href="https://www.desertsun.com/story/tech/science/energy/2016/06/08/tesla-offered-325-million-salton-sea-startup/84913572/"&gt;offered to buy the firm&lt;/a&gt; for $325 million. (Tesla has since said it would &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/1/21452436/tesla-battery-day-reaction-elon-musk-questions-lithium-mining"&gt;mine its own lithium&lt;/a&gt; from clay deposits in Nevada.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hb0m6G"&gt;“I’d say the main concerns around lithium extraction from geothermal brines are mostly economic,” said Chris Berry, president of House Mountain Partners and an analyst who focuses on energy metals supply chains. “Investors want to see proven economics before writing big checks to develop projects and battery manufacturers want to see proof of scalable production of battery grade lithium before entering into binding off-take agreements.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XIIzJP"&gt;But GM sees the risk worth taking. “It is very difficult,” Grewe said. “It has to cover all of our built in quality metrics that we have at General Motors.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uKurd5"&gt;The automaker recently announced that it would spend &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22536601/gm-ev-investment-increase-amount-electric-autonomous-vehicles"&gt;$35 billion through 2025&lt;/a&gt; on the development of electric and autonomous vehicles. That includes the construction of two new battery facilities in the US. GM is positioning itself to be the largest manufacturer of EVs in North America, much like it already is for gas-powered vehicles. The automaker has previously said that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/28/22254116/general-motors-carbon-neutral-vow-2040-tailpipe-emissions-ev"&gt;it hopes to only make zero-emission light-duty vehicles by 2035&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22559718/gm-lithium-ctr-ev-battery-investment-salton-sea"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22559718/gm-lithium-ctr-ev-battery-investment-salton-sea</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-02T05:54:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-02T05:54:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft warns of Windows ‘PrintNightmare’ vulnerability that’s being actively exploited</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CO7Zc7_W1iKZZqRh9BPeVcriFg4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69533180/acastro_170629_1777_0008_v2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2lvTar"&gt;Microsoft is warning Windows users about an unpatched critical flaw in the Windows Print Spooler service. The vulnerability, dubbed PrintNightmare, was uncovered earlier this week after security researchers accidentally published a proof-of-concept (PoC) exploit. While Microsoft hasn’t rated the vulnerability, it allows attackers to remotely execute code with system-level privileges, which is as critical and problematic as you can get in Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K3OKmz"&gt;Researchers at Sangfor &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/edwardzpeng/status/1409810304091889669"&gt;published the PoC&lt;/a&gt;, in what appears to have been a mistake, or a miscommunication between the researchers and Microsoft. The test code was quickly deleted, but not before it had already been forked on GitHub. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dRz3ob"&gt;Sangfor researchers had been &lt;a href="https://www.sangfor.com/en/info-center/blog-center/cyber-security/two-sangfor-security-research-results-selected-at-black-hat-usa-2021"&gt;planning to detail&lt;/a&gt; multiple 0-day vulnerabilities in the Windows Print Spooler service at the annual Black Hat security conference later this month. It appears the researchers thought Microsoft had patched this particular vulnerability, after the company published patches for a separate Windows Print Spooler flaw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="SpSiMx"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The vulnerability is being actively exploited&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HvPmGH"&gt;It has taken Microsoft a couple of days to finally issue an alert about the 0-day, and &lt;a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/microsoft-shares-mitigations-for-windows-printnightmare-zero-day-bug/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bleepingcomputer &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; that the company is even warning customers that it’s being actively exploited. The vulnerability allows attackers to use remote code execution, so bad actors could potentially install programs, modify data, and create new accounts with full admin rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nw7yI0"&gt;&lt;a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2021-34527"&gt;Microsoft admits&lt;/a&gt; “the code that contains the vulnerability is in all versions of Windows,” but it’s not clear if it’s exploitable beyond server versions of Windows. The Print Spooler service runs by default on Windows, including on client versions of the OS, Domain Controllers, and many Windows Server instances, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ysbLaN"&gt;Microsoft is working on a patch, but until it’s available the company recommends disabling the Windows Print Spooler service (if that’s an option for businesses), or disabling inbound remote printing through Group Policy. The Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/current-activity/2021/06/30/printnightmare-critical-windows-print-spooler-vulnerability"&gt;has recommended&lt;/a&gt; that admins “disable the Windows Print Spooler service in Domain Controllers and systems that do not print.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VBW5py"&gt;Vulnerabilities in the Windows Print Spooler service have been a headache for system administrators for years. The most infamous example was the Stuxnet virus. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/4/12/2944329/stuxnet-computer-virus-planted-israeli-agent-iran"&gt;Stuxnet used&lt;/a&gt; multiple 0-day exploits, including a Windows Print Spooler flaw, to destroy several Iranian nuclear centrifuges more than a decade ago.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22560435/microsoft-printnightmare-windows-print-spooler-service-vulnerability-exploit-0-day"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22560435/microsoft-printnightmare-windows-print-spooler-service-vulnerability-exploit-0-day</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-02T05:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-02T05:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Don’t back down from Facebook fight, lawmakers tell FTC</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7P9HUakoPHYz7EXpSVfRMA7vYbo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69533142/acastro_180406_1777_facebook_Congress_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gQ2NRG"&gt;A bipartisan group of lawmakers have asked that the FTC continue its antitrust lawsuit against Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/28/22554476/ftc-facebook-instagram-antitrust-case-whatsapp-federal-court"&gt;after setbacks in court&lt;/a&gt;. Senators Amy Klobuchar (D-MN) and Mike Lee (R-UT), together with House representatives David Cicilline (D-RI) and Ken Buck (R-CO), &lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22694505/FTC_letter_7_1_21.pdf"&gt;signed a letter&lt;/a&gt; addressed to FTC Chair Lina Khan detailing why the regulatory action is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3vUVbH"&gt;“It is essential that the Commission take action to deter anticompetitive conduct by digital monopolists by ensuring that they are held liable for antitrust violations to the full extent of the law,” the lawmakers wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Rw19qf"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It is essential that the Commission take action”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iMFlXl"&gt;This letter comes just four days after Judge James E. Boasberg &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/28/22554476/ftc-facebook-instagram-antitrust-case-whatsapp-federal-court"&gt;dismissed&lt;/a&gt; the federal government’s key antitrust complaint against Facebook on Monday, as well as a complaint from 48 state attorneys general. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3DApAc"&gt;The FTC has until July 29th to refile its complaint, although it will have to offer more comprehensive evidence that Facebook does indeed wield monopoly power in social networking. In the Monday dismissal, Boasberg wrote he was unimpressed with the FTC’s attempt to classify Facebook as a monopoly, as the initial complaint only provided “the naked allegation” that the social media giant had a 60 percent market share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rib9Sm"&gt;The dismissal does offer some metrics that might be persuasive to the court, like how much users spend on Facebook apps, or an explanation of Facebook’s competition in the sector. However, each of those suggestions are caveated with how examples of how difficult these metrics can be to prove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BBnafi"&gt;In the dismissal, Boasberg also noted how difficult it was to fit Facebook’s service into the existing antitrust regulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="org1gh"&gt;“This case involves no ordinary or intuitive market,” he wrote. “Rather, PSN [Personal Social Networking] services are free to use, and the exact metes and bounds of what even constitutes a PSN service — i.e., which features of a company’s mobile app or website are included in that definition and which are excluded — are hardly crystal clear.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qqi3vk"&gt;This point hasn’t been lost on lawmakers, who have rallied around changing antitrust law to better address modern tech giants. Buck, one of the letter’s signatories, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RepKenBuck/status/1409594342860283904"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; Monday that the dismissal showed antitrust reform is urgently needed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l5PTzm"&gt;“Congress needs to provide additional tools and resources to our antitrust enforcers to go after Big Tech companies engaging in anticompetitive conduct,” he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22559549/lawmakers-tell-ftc-to-continue-facebook-antitrust-lawsuit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22559549/lawmakers-tell-ftc-to-continue-facebook-antitrust-lawsuit</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dave Gershgorn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-02T02:49:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-02T02:49:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook confirms tests of a new anti-extremism warning prompt</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="facebook stock art" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6A_w0wpZvZky7K0Hzdg-GuCDkrI=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69533067/acastro_180928_1777_facebook_hack_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TmCli8"&gt;Facebook is testing prompts that will link users to anti-extremism support and resources if the company believes the user knows someone who could be on the path to extremism, or if the user has been exposed to extremist content themselves, &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/07/01/tech/facebook-extremist-notification/index.html"&gt;according to a report by &lt;em&gt;CNN Business&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jvwrfw"&gt;In a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, a Facebook spokesperson said that the test is part of the company’s “larger work to assess ways to provide resources and support to people on Facebook who may have engaged with or were exposed to extremist content, or may know someone who is at risk.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KrKbGE"&gt;Facebook says that it’ll continue to remove extremist content that &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/communitystandards/dangerous_individuals_organizations"&gt;violates its rules&lt;/a&gt;, though the company has had issues tracking down and removing similar content, even from groups that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/12/21365278/facebook-boogaloo-tech-transparency-right-wing-extremist-platform"&gt;it’s actively tried to kick off the platform.&lt;/a&gt; Facebook has long been the subject of scrutiny from the public and lawmakers, as many say that its algorithms divide people and push them towards extreme ideologies, something &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/26/21270659/facebook-division-news-feed-algorithms"&gt;the company has itself recognized&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="fHDl5L"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A history of failing to track and remove extremist content&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zFzxlO"&gt;Facebook says that the tests go along with &lt;a href="https://counterspeech.fb.com/en/initiatives/redirect/"&gt;its Redirect Initiative&lt;/a&gt;, which “helps combat violent extremism and dangerous organizations” in several countries. According to its webpage, the program (as the name implies) redirects users to educational resources instead of further hateful content. It also says the test is part of &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2020/05/combating-hate-and-dangerous-organizations/"&gt;its response to the Christchurch Call for Action campaign&lt;/a&gt;, and the test identifies both users who may have seen extremist content, and those who have had enforcement actions taken against them by Facebook in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wEjpBf"&gt;The test links to resources intended to help someone intervene if they’re concerned about a loved one joining a violent extremist group or movement. On &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/help/139388761595380/"&gt;a Facebook support page&lt;/a&gt; titled “What can I do to prevent radicalization,” Facebook links to Life After Hate’s ExitUSA program, which Facebook says helps people find “a way out of hate and violence.” The support page also gives tips on engaging with someone who’s trying to leave a hate group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iIsyNk"&gt;Facebook, like other platforms, has had issues with extremism for a long time, and though it’s good that it’s trying to combat it, some of its efforts feel like they should’ve been implemented long ago. This is the case with many forms of bad behavior online, as many platforms are still struggling to get a hold on users &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559115/twitter-tiktok-google-facebook-protect-women-abuse"&gt;who harass women&lt;/a&gt;, or display &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22558731/twitter-trusted-friends-facets-features-pre-announce"&gt;other general toxic behavior&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22560108/facebook-anti-extremism-prompt-user-resources-content-moderation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22560108/facebook-anti-extremism-prompt-user-resources-content-moderation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T20:26:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T20:26:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nike brings hands-free entry shoes to the Olympics with the Glide FlyEase</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Nike Glide FlyEase" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AbwshNTf8ouVdJi7lHR6n7m6CtE=/0x0:2066x1377/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69532396/Nike_Medal_Stand_FlyEase_Glide_original.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Nike&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="E0Ardb"&gt;The Olympics are back on this summer in Japan — despite &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/health-coronavirus-pandemic-2020-tokyo-olympics-olympic-games-sports-dd8098040f1f965ae90d289ca35c7423"&gt;local opposition&lt;/a&gt; — and athletes will of course find themselves outfitted in the lightest, slickest gear to assist in record-breaking performances. Ahead of the games, Nike has unveiled some of the apparel the US team will wear (including &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fnews.nike.com%2Ffootwear%2Fnike-rawdacious-colorway-tokyo-official-images-release-date&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fdesign%2F2021%2F7%2F1%2F22560002%2Fnike-glide-flyease-olympics-sneakers" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;“Rawdacious” themed&lt;/a&gt; track spikes with carbon fiber plates), but you may want to keep an eye on outfits reserved for medal winners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TdY9hK"&gt;Nike is highlighting sustainability themes with pants and jackets that are made from 100 percent recycled material, and while the accompanying footwear is made partially from recycled materials, that’s not the only thing special about it. This year’s medal stand features Nike’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/7/20/9002197/nike-flyease-zipper-disabilities"&gt;FlyEase tech&lt;/a&gt;, which is made for easy entry that brings comfortable athletic shoes to people who might not be able to put on other shoes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Nike Go FlyEase" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uWPYDWASMJIx4c7RihAYwbS3OQQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22694879/c748bc50_64f5_11eb_bfed_408b02ac5810.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Nike&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Go FlyEase&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="mT7MRx"&gt;The Glide FlyEase is similar to the &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/tldr/2021/2/1/22260179/nike-go-flyease-shoes-hands-free-pricing-release-day"&gt;Go FlyEase model Nike introduced earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;. However, instead of that shoe’s “bistable hinge,” Nike said the Glide FlyEase has a flexible heel. We haven’t seen it in action, but apparently you simply step into the shoe and it snaps back into place while an elastic cord goes over the foot for a snug fit.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Nike Glide FlyEase" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sEw67iH6OWhKVAM6bAtXpcNuDO8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22694865/Nike_Medal_Stand_FlyEase_Glide_3_original.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Nike&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Glide FlyEase&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="X2YGJK"&gt;Despite &lt;a href="https://www.wired.co.uk/article/nike-go-flyease-review"&gt;glowing reviews&lt;/a&gt;, Nike has been &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/03/28/981197687/nike-accused-of-using-disability-to-hype-new-hands-free-sneaker"&gt;criticized over the Go FlyEase launch&lt;/a&gt; as limited quantity releases make it hard for the people who need the shoes to get them. Putting the Glide FlyEase on the medal stand will provide another highlight of accessible sportswear that lets people know they exist, but it can only have a larger impact if you can actually get them. Nike has said there will be more opportunities to get the $120 FlyEase Go, and tells The Verge that these Glide FlyEase shoes will be released at a later date.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/design/2021/7/1/22560002/nike-glide-flyease-olympics-sneakers"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/design/2021/7/1/22560002/nike-glide-flyease-olympics-sneakers</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
