<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-27T15:49:22-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-27T15:49:22-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-27T15:49:22-04:00</updated>
    <title>A major Hollywood union could vote soon on a deal for better streaming pay</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="IATSE members were planning to strike over working conditions" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-R81Hbkbf_VnauFckRu1_CwoSzM=/0x0:6265x4177/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70053723/1235538501.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Myung J. Chun / Los Angeles Times via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TI8YYA"&gt;A Hollywood union representing tens of thousands of production workers will soon decide whether to ratify agreements that will, among other labor protections, enforce better pay from streaming services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f13TRF"&gt;The International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees (IATSE) announced Tuesday that it reached a tentative three-year “area standards” agreement with the Alliance of Motion Picture and Television Producers (AMPTP) that “delivers our members a fairer deal on streaming,” according to the union’s international president Matthew Loeb. AMPTP represents major Hollywood studios that include, among others, Netflix, Apple, Amazon, Disney, Paramount, and Warner Bros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tnJaZ0"&gt;A spokesperson for the union told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that lawyers are still working out details of the agreement, which could “take a few days.” After that, members will need time to review the terms. A vote should then be scheduled in the next few weeks, the spokesperson said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="v6sjec"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;If you don't have the budget to prioritize safety, then you don't have the budget to make movies. Full stop.&lt;/p&gt;— IATSE // #IASolidarity (@IATSE) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/IATSE/status/1453036345899814917?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 26, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7V5shp"&gt;The tentative deal reached this week will cover some 20,000 workers on productions in TV and film — including crew, artists, editors, and other behind-the-scenes roles — from 23 local unions across the US. Earlier this month, a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/17/22731087/hollywood-union-reaches-contract-agreement-iatse-avoids-strike"&gt;tentative deal&lt;/a&gt; was reached for separate “basic” and “videotape” contracts that cover another 40,000 workers represented by 13 West Coast-based local unions that are part of IATSE. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dprLne"&gt;That earlier agreement narrowly avoided a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/6/22711567/iatse-strike-authorization-negotiations-resume-streaming-pay"&gt;major Hollywood strike&lt;/a&gt;, which was supported nearly unanimously by the union’s members and would have had an industry-wide impact. The union’s members supported the strike authorization after negotiations stalled with AMPTP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bcNGzb"&gt;The proposed “area standards” agreement will improve pay “significantly” by up to 60 percent for its lowest-paid workers, according to the union. All members who operate under the new contracts will see their pay increase by a minimum of 9 percent over the three-year term. The proposed agreement also covers rest periods, breaks, wage terms, and payouts from streaming services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1xBJPD"&gt;“We were able to achieve gains in all of our core areas,” Loeb said in a statement. “Quality of life issues were at the top of our priority list. The protective terms we negotiated in this agreement and the agreement reached earlier establish a defined weekend with the studios for the first time. The two agreements incorporate stiff penalties for failing to provide meals and breaks. Taken together, the improvements we made at the bargaining table are very significant and directly due to the solidarity of our members.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22749253/hollywood-union-itsea-amptp-vote-streaming-pay"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22749253/hollywood-union-itsea-amptp-vote-streaming-pay</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-27T14:04:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-27T14:04:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>GameStop memes even harder with ‘Web3 Gaming’ and NFT job listings</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tAFH8vML4EbXDWP2-8R50MYkLb4=/0x0:2200x1467/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70053091/20170822_Sean_Hollister_Verge_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ezNrqI"&gt;After a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22253363/wall-street-bets-verge-stories-gamestock-reddit-discord"&gt;rollercoaster of a year on the stock market&lt;/a&gt; fueled by WallStreetBets retail trading, GameStop is going full meme and looking to build a “Web3” platform, according to a flurry of job listings posted to its careers site on Monday. One of those ads, &lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/business/2021/10/26/gamestop-enters-the-metaverse-with-web3-gaming-job-post/"&gt;discovered by &lt;em&gt;CoinDesk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, is a &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/2767078769/"&gt;LinkedIn listing&lt;/a&gt; for a “Head of Web3 Gaming” in which the company says it's looking for someone to “accelerate the future of gaming and commerce” based on blockchains. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jrLykR"&gt;If you’re lucky enough to have never heard the phrase “Web3,” it’s often used to describe a decentralized, crypto-based internet. That tracks with the other job listings, which indicate that GameStop is developing some sort of NFT platform, likely based on Ethereum. While sometimes job listings are just job listings, in this case, it may be a play by GameStop to get back on WallStreetBets’ radar or to work its way into the crypto community’s good graces. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-Ssuo3l0ZKXHkr6IdnftIVsznXw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22958377/Screen_Shot_2021_10_26_at_17.56.08.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;GameStop’s many job listings for NFT and Web3 Gaming-related positions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Rbb9MG"&gt;GameStop hasn’t mentioned its ardent retail trading fans much &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.fool.com%2Fearnings%2Fcall-transcripts%2F2021%2F06%2F10%2Fgamestop-gme-q1-2021-earnings-call-transcript%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F27%2F22747748%2Fgamestop-web3-gaming-nft-job-listing-nfts-ethereum" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;in its earnings calls&lt;/a&gt;, but the company’s stock has clearly benefited from their enthusiasm — at the beginning of 2021, it was hovering around $20 per share, and it closed on Tuesday at $177.84, according to Yahoo Finance. High stock prices don’t necessarily indicate &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.fool.com%2Finvesting%2F2021%2F09%2F11%2Fgamestop-earnings-another-stinker%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F27%2F22747748%2Fgamestop-web3-gaming-nft-job-listing-nfts-ethereum" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;that the company as a whole is doing well&lt;/a&gt;, but they can at least help keep people liking the stock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hTW4T7"&gt;When you’re dealing with an Internet mob, though, attention eventually fades. AMC has tried to court back traders’ interest (it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22251964/amc-stock-price-reddit-wallstreetbets-trading-gamestop"&gt;caught up in the same trading fiasco&lt;/a&gt; as GameStop) with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465198/amc-meme-stock-popcorn-wsb"&gt;things like free popcorn&lt;/a&gt; and news that they’re &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22617594/amc-bitcoin-memestock-apple-google-pay"&gt;looking into accepting Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; and other crypto at theaters. For GameStop, it’s possible that an NFT platform promising a future of games where “play is driven by the things you bring” and incorporating buzzy phrases like “Web3” and “blockchain-based gaming” is a similar tactic to reignite the passion investors once felt for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Bkc7lM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;If you’re trying to get Reddit traders’ attention, building an NFT platform could be a pro strat&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tR5zEE"&gt;With all the talk about GameStop as a wild stock market bet, you’d be forgiven for forgetting that its main business is &lt;em&gt;being a video game store. &lt;/em&gt;Whether or not video game vendors allow for games that include NFTs is a bit of an open question at this point — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728425/valve-steam-blockchain-nft-crypto-ban-games-age-of-rust"&gt;Valve declared&lt;/a&gt; that developers can’t sell blockchain-enabled games on its Steam store, while &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22729050/epic-game-store-open-to-blockchain-cryptocurrency-nft-games"&gt;Epic has said&lt;/a&gt; that it’s okay with them. Apple has yet to publicly make a decision about the App Store, possibly because developers are rightfully scared to be the first ones to try submitting an NFT-powered app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vTtceC"&gt;Meanwhile, GameStop seems very interested in becoming a place for those kinds of projects — one of the listed responsibilities in the job description is “build a team to help creators launch their projects on the GameStop platform.” While the company seemingly &lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/business/2021/05/26/gamestop-is-hiring-for-new-nft-platform-on-ethereum/"&gt;teased plans for something NFT-related&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year, an obscure webpage is more cryptic than a call for applicants who want to build a blockchain empire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zaYFqn"&gt;To whoever’s going to try and do this for GameStop, I wish you luck — because you’re going to need it. Dropping the ball on this project could upset the crypto people, retail traders, and blockchain game developers, and that’s a Venn diagram I’d want to be well outside of. Though if things do end up going disastrously wrong, please email me because that could be an incredible story.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22747748/gamestop-web3-gaming-nft-job-listing-nfts-ethereum"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22747748/gamestop-web3-gaming-nft-job-listing-nfts-ethereum</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-27T14:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-27T14:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The new Onewheel GT can travel 32 miles on a single charge</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_JCLHv3lBveX1cTfVL0GH-PmFzY=/0x0:3999x2666/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70053023/Shot_2_Dust.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Images: Future Motion&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pm3t3M"&gt;California startup Future Motion has revealed two new versions of its funky self-balancing electric rideable it calls Onewheel, with more range, power, and better ergonomics. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OT5BSM"&gt;The most capable of the two is the new $2,200 Onewheel GT, which Future Motion says was “completely redesigned from the ground up.” It employs a higher-voltage control system that pushes more power to the motor — Future Motion says the GT is the “first 3 horsepower Onewheel.” The GT is pulling that power from a battery pack made up of 21700 lithium-ion batteries (the same size cell that powers many of Tesla’s current vehicles), which give it a whopping 32 miles of range on a full charge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oV98me"&gt;Performance aside, Future Motion says the Onewheel GT now has concave footpads for better board feel, brighter headlights, a sturdier carrying handle, and an optional treaded tire for people who want to take their Onewheel off-road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9Hv7UE"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10830862"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="niz8tx"&gt;The other new vehicle announced Wednesday is an update to the smaller Onewheel that Future Motion announced in 2019, the Pint. The new $1,400 Pint X gets more than twice the original Pint’s range (18 miles compared to six to eight miles previously) and a slight boost to top speed (18 miles per hour compared to 16mph previously). It also gets some small fit and finish upgrades, adjustable riding modes via the companion smartphone app, and will even be available in a neon colorway. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ExnJ3r"&gt;Electric bikes, scooters, and skateboards have become increasingly popular over the last decade, and the pandemic has only increased the focus on alternative modes of transportation. Onewheel has been able to survive by carving out an extremely specific niche and making really good products, even while companies like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22575594/boosted-electric-skateboard-khosla-lime-lawsuit"&gt;Boosted&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20943500/inboard-technology-electric-skateboard-scooters-layoffs-sale-liquidation"&gt;Inboard&lt;/a&gt; (which ostensibly sold more “approachable” electric skateboards) went out of business. That focus appears evident in the new models, which are significant refinements — but still not reinventions — of the Onewheel we &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/1/11/5296628/the-dream-of-the-perfect-electric-skateboard-continues-at-ces-with"&gt;first met seven years ago&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22749004/onewheel-gt-pint-x-price-specs-future-motion"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22749004/onewheel-gt-pint-x-price-specs-future-motion</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-27T13:37:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-27T13:37:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>TCL’s new wireless soundbar gives Roku TVs better audio for $179.99</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Wall mounted TV with Soundbar on a blue entertainment center in a clean apartment with a laundry hamper to the right" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b83Eghw0xLHsaoy89hTWYPbf43Q=/129x0:1071x628/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70052916/smallblog_R1_Lifestyle_Front_V1_5000x3333.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;One less cable to run makes this look more achievable | Image: TCL&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EoHdx8"&gt;If you need to elevate the audio experience for your second guest bedroom’s Roku TV, TCL’s new soundbar may be the one for you. The &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.roku.com/products/audio/tcl-roku-tv-wireless-soundbar" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Roku TV Wireless Soundbar&lt;/a&gt; (announced at CES 2021 as the Alto R1) is TCL’s vision of a simple and easy audio drop-in solution for $179.99 that only works with Roku TVs but not any other Roku streaming box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FkJwEa"&gt;As far as soundbars go, the unit is bare bones with no HDMI or audio ports. TCL is saying this is by design for a clutter-free entertainment center where the only cable you need to route is the power cable — all other functions are wireless using Wi-Fi 802.11ac. A part of the “Roku TV Ready” lineup of products the company is putting out, this soundbar uses the existing Roku TV remote and lets you pair the soundbar wirelessly through the Roku TV setup menus.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Rear of the TCL Roku TV wireless soundbar with one power port, a reset button, and no other ports" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OPJlpUPOicvQ2ehaiOp04yjL0vY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22959729/http___image.roku.com_w_rapid_images_pdp_carousel_items_99cb46b6_0a47_40c0_a8de_5d36920d9486.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: TCL&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;No ports means less cables, but also less options.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ehYngq"&gt;In terms of features, the Roku TV Wireless Soundbar is 2.0 channel pumping out what the company calls “studio quality” audio with a max output of 120W. Multiple EQ settings are available in the TV sound settings menu, and the soundbar is capable of software updates. Expandability includes adding the Roku Wireless Subwoofer for 2.1 audio, but unfortunately, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/29/18116610/roku-tv-wireless-speakers-review"&gt;Roku’s own&lt;/a&gt; wireless speakers can’t come to play. The soundbar also has Bluetooth 5.0 to stream from smartphones and includes wall mount hardware for some DIY frills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ctOj8P"&gt;TCL does sell other “Roku TV Ready” soundbars with subwoofers and HDMI, such as the Alto 6+ for $129.99, and those can even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/29/21113141/roku-surround-sound-smart-soundbar-wireless-speakers-home-theater"&gt;use the wireless speaker set for full surround sound&lt;/a&gt;. If you can figure out how to plug in one HDMI cable, then this probably isn’t made for you. But if your TV setup is unusually complicated, or you just want to meet the bare minimum requirements for upgraded audio without taking extra steps, this is a budget-friendly match for your Roku TV set. Available now for $179.99 from &lt;a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Ftcl-alto-r1-roku-tv-wireless-2-0-channel-sound-bar-for-roku-tvs-bluetooth-tsr1-31-5-inch-black-black%2F6475655.p%3FskuId%3D6475655&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/TCL-Wireless-Channel-Sound-Bluetooth/dp/B099Z7K3N7/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22748527/tcl-roku-tv-ready-wireless-soundbar"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22748527/tcl-roku-tv-ready-wireless-soundbar</id>
    <author>
      <name>Umar Shakir</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-27T13:24:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-27T13:24:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>EU opens formal investigation into Nvidia’s Arm acquisition</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8-B5Yc59BH0zckla_kFp_XSFdok=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70052855/acastro_180529_1777_nvidia_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6v6NPI"&gt;The European Commission has &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/setback-nvidias-54-bln-arm-bid-eu-regulators-open-probe-2021-10-27/"&gt;opened a formal competition investigation&lt;/a&gt; into Nvidia’s acquisition of chip designer Arm. The deal, which would see Nvidia purchase the UK-based company from SoftBank for $40 billion, was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/13/21435507/nvidia-acquiring-arm-40-billion-chips-ai-deal"&gt;announced in September 2020&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yD8SP6"&gt;&lt;a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/ip_21_5624"&gt;In a press release&lt;/a&gt;, the EU’s Executive Vice President Margrethe Vestager said that Nvidia buying Arm could make it harder for other manufacturers to access Arm’s technology, hurting much of the semiconductor industry (which is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/21/22739192/intel-chip-shortage-q3-2021-earning-laptop-revenue"&gt;already facing supply problems&lt;/a&gt;). At the heart of concerns is Arm’s neutrality. Arm licenses its chip designs to a broad range of companies including Apple, Samsung, and Qualcomm, many of which compete with one another and Nvidia. There are fears that having Nvidia control Arm may result in Nvidia’s competitors being put at a disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="fZnXmt"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Regulators aren’t taking Nvidia’s word that it’ll keep Arm open&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Yqucrq"&gt;Nvidia’s CEO Jensen Huang says this won’t happen and has committed to maintaining Arm’s open licensing model. But critics of the deal fear that regulators won’t be able to force Nvidia to remain neutral indefinitely, the &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/a3adccc9-678e-44ef-bdb5-e847ecb7de8c"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; in February. According to the EU’s press release, Nvidia submitted commitments to try to address some of these concerns, but the commission decided they were “insufficient to clearly dismiss its serious doubts as to the effect of the transaction.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iMMZOW"&gt;The EU also plans on investigating how the deal could affect how competitors share information with Arm, and whether Nvidia could change Arm’s research and development funding to make its products more profitable, to the detriment of those that use Arm’s other tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sAm9rH"&gt;Both Nvidia and Arm have been expecting regulatory investigations like this and anticipate that the deal could take 18 months to complete. The EU’s investigation is unlikely to be the only regulatory scrutiny the deal faces either. The UK’s Competition and Markets Authority &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22634379/nvidia-arm-aquisition-delay-uk-phase-2-investigation"&gt;recommended its own in-depth investigation&lt;/a&gt; in August, &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/nvidias-acquisition-of-arm-to-face-u-k-antitrust-probe-11609959700#:~:text=LONDON%E2%80%94U.K.%20officials%20said%20they,Arm%20from%20SoftBank%20Group%20Corp.&amp;amp;text=That%20philosophy%20led%20to%20its,95%25%20of%20the%20world%27s%20smartphones."&gt;after asking third parties to comment on the merger&lt;/a&gt;. According to the&lt;em&gt; Financial Times&lt;/em&gt;, regulators in the US and China could also take a formal look at the deal. Separately, the UK is also investigating its potential national security implications.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22266504/nvidia-arm-deal-eu-formal-investigation-merger"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22266504/nvidia-arm-deal-eu-formal-investigation-merger</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-27T13:01:59-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-27T13:01:59-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google makes it easier for Android developers to build apps with its Material You design</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Android 12 running on Pixel 6" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/v7Absq0oih71wNwMdc5Bxqivsho=/0x0:1620x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70052735/pixelandroid12.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iFzKyy"&gt;Android 12 has launched along with Google’s new Pixel 6 lineup and brings with it a new look that Android VP of product management Sameer Samat &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22439777/android-12-design-features-widgets-first-look-google"&gt;called “the biggest design change in Android’s history.”&lt;/a&gt; That’s in reference to Material You, which applies a new set of principles for creating interfaces, in addition to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22746599/android-12l-feature-drop-big-screens"&gt;changes that will help Android adjust to bigger screens&lt;/a&gt;. We’ve already gotten a hint of how the look affects usability across the updated OS &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22666355/google-material-you-design-gmail-calendar-docs-android"&gt;and Google’s own apps&lt;/a&gt;, but now the focus is expanding to reach more of the apps made by others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wXympB"&gt;Today at Google’s Android Developer Summit, the company announced that &lt;a href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2021/10/12L-preview-large-screens.html"&gt;Material You is available&lt;/a&gt; in Jetpack Compose, so app designers can more easily adopt the look in their own products.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Material You design in Android 12" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cEsv2_RbAjSBbTZPaItiO3htqqg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22960054/material_you_android_12.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Material You design in Android 12&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Fr89Ub"&gt;New elements include dynamic guidelines that will help apps respond and adjust algorithmically to a user’s wallpaper choice, as well as tips on how to maintain a third-party app’s individual brand expression while adapting. Another element developers will need to learn about are the design tokens that “represent design system styles as data” so they can change as the system changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="TCqfRS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Android 12 review: it’s mostly about the looks","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22708720/android-12-review-features-pixel-update-software"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="8prLCV"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.5%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=PLWz5rJ2EKKc9-BJh8Os6W6iQIp1gtOh2T" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fOwimm"&gt;Developers can see how their apps will look in different circumstances using the Material Theme Builder, which is available as a Figma plugin and on the web starting today. Beyond just how apps look, Google says that new features for its Jetpack libraries will help developers manage Android 12’s background restrictions, measure performance, and handle backward compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tAawJJ"&gt;For future updates, Google says it’s planning on accessibility updates that tie into the dynamic color and adaptive layouts. Other guidance and system adjustments will help apps work with new form factors like foldables, even though Google doesn’t make a foldable phone... yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="hRFyDS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Where is Google’s foldable phone? Everything we know so far ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22735454/google-foldable-phone-pixel-fold-pixel-6-samsung"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22748821/android-12-developers-material-you-summit-jetpack"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22748821/android-12-developers-material-you-summit-jetpack</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-27T13:01:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-27T13:01:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>Android’s 12L feature drop aims to be a big improvement for folding phones</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Inside The Samsung Unpacked Product Launch Event" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/n_S0h9XJAJY01XmsC3BiexrIoJ0=/4x0:3996x2661/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70052386/1234620007.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eeNwoH"&gt;At this year’s &lt;a href="https://developer.android.com/events/dev-summit"&gt;Android Dev Summit&lt;/a&gt;, Google announced an upcoming update for devices with larger screens, which includes tablets, foldables, and devices that run ChromeOS. Google is calling the update 12L, and it’s supposed to make Android 12 run smoother on big screens. We first heard &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22697950/android-12-1-foldable-features-report-split-screen-multi-tasking-taskbar"&gt;the possibility of a “12.1” update&lt;/a&gt; in late September, and it looks like many of the rumored features are true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oomQxQ"&gt;12L optimizes the layout of a device’s UI, adjusting the placement of the home screen, lock screen, notifications, Quick Settings, and more. Google notes that any screen 600 density-independent pixels (dp) and above will display a two-column layout that makes use of the entire screen. In the example Google shows, the Quick Settings menu is pushed towards the left side of the screen, while the notifications panel is locked to the right, giving you the ability to access both simultaneously — all without opening one app and closing another.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Android 12L two columns" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QG9OeO7osVio_2T6SgK03a8niss=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22956414/android_12l_messaging.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Google&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="WJpFiJ"&gt;12L also introduces a new taskbar that makes it easier for users to quickly switch between different apps. Dragging and dropping an app from the taskbar opens it up in split-screen mode, which Google notes it has enabled for all apps, whether they’re resizable or not.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="12L multitasking" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FD3D0_mO4f485sllpdRAZ3BUjzY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22959161/12L_multitasking.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Google&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="K0CuPy"&gt;Another change coming with 12L is improved letterboxing that should make apps look more appealing. Google is letting device manufacturers change the size, shape, and color of letterboxing, as well as add rounded corners and tweak the position of the inset window. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MfpAQC"&gt;12L is set to release early next year, but you can try out the new features in advance on its &lt;a href="https://developer.android.com/12L"&gt;12L developer preview page&lt;/a&gt;. From there, you can &lt;a href="https://login.corp.google.com/request?s=android.devsite.corp.google.com:443/uberproxy/&amp;amp;d=https://android.devsite.corp.google.com/about/versions/12/12L/get%3Fupxsrf%3DAO9zFu1-Js9Q5Dunv6xiViFB4D0DCSRvLdYrVLT04EszQ_zKyg:1635280184986&amp;amp;maxAge=1200&amp;amp;authLevel=2000000&amp;amp;keyIds=xSS,Caq,p2T,ul2&amp;amp;3pd=1"&gt;download the 12L emulator&lt;/a&gt; to get started. Google also says that it's working with OEM partners to roll out the 12L update, and that a developer preview of 12L for the Lenovo P12 Pro tablet is in the works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V4oOQZ"&gt;With so many new foldable phones coming to market, it’s not much of a surprise that Google decided to roll out an update specifically for them (and tablets, too, of course). While &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22683566/google-jumbojack-foldable-passport-android-12-1-code-discovery"&gt;Google reportedly has two foldable phones&lt;/a&gt; in the works, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22440623/samsung-display-foldable-screen"&gt;Samsung is experimenting with a monitor that can fold into a tablet&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a year for foldable devices, and the trend shows no sign of stopping — they’re becoming so mainstream that even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744407/best-buy-authorized-samsung-foldable-repairs"&gt;Best Buy is offering in-store repairs for Samsung’s foldables&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22746599/android-12l-feature-drop-big-screens"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22746599/android-12l-feature-drop-big-screens</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-27T12:06:58-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-27T12:06:58-04:00</updated>
    <title>Adobe has built a deepfake tool, but it doesn’t know what to do with it</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pTXwQje8slFqVVzh2pzQ5HU2htU=/92x0:1913x1214/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70052462/Screen_Shot_2021_10_27_at_4.32.40_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vBTvnd"&gt;Deepfakes have made a huge impact on the world of image, audio, and video editing, so why isn’t Adobe, corporate behemoth of the content world, getting more involved? Well, the short answer is that it is — but slowly and carefully. At the company’s annual Max conference today, it unveiled a prototype tool named Project Morpheus that demonstrates both the potential and problems of integrating deepfake techniques into its products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KmcvWE"&gt;Project Morpheus is basically a video version of the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/20/21517616/adobe-photoshop-ai-neural-filters-beta-launch-machine-learning"&gt;Neural Filters&lt;/a&gt;, introduced in Photoshop last year. These filters use machine learning to adjust a subject’s appearance, tweaking things like their age, hair color, and facial expression (to change a look of surprise into one of anger, for example). Morpheus brings all those same adjustments to video content while adding a few new filters, like the ability to change facial hair and glasses. Think of it as a character creation screen for humans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="cz72Z1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Project Morpheus is a deepfake tool, though Adobe won’t call it that&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="n1vp9z"&gt;The results are definitely not flawless and are very limited in scope in relation to the wider world of deepfakes. You can only make small, pre-ordained tweaks to the appearance of people facing the camera, and can’t do things like face swaps, for example. But the quality will improve fast, and while the feature is just a prototype for now with no guarantee it will appear in Adobe software, it’s clearly something the company is investigating seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1lZwRU"&gt;What Project Morpheus also is, though, is a deepfake tool — which is potentially a problem. A big one. Because deepfakes and all that’s associated with them — from nonconsensual pornography to political propaganda — aren’t exactly good for business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Bjmx2A"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bpABm6XcRMw?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MZ0Unj"&gt;Now, given the looseness with which we &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/22/17380306/deepfake-definition-ai-manipulation-fake-news"&gt;define deepfakes&lt;/a&gt; these days, Adobe has arguably been making such tools for years. These include the aforementioned Neural Filters, as well as more functional tools like AI-assisted masking and segmentation. But Project Morpheus is obviously much more &lt;em&gt;deepfakey&lt;/em&gt; than the company’s earlier efforts. It’s all about editing video footage of humans — in ways that many will likely find uncanny or manipulative. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kDWZtg"&gt;Changing someone’s facial expression in a video, for example, might be used by a director to punch up a bad take, but it could also be used to create political propaganda — e.g. making a jailed dissident appear relaxed in court footage when they’re really being starved to death. It’s what policy wonks refer to as a “dual-use technology,” which is a snappy way of saying that the tech is “sometimes maybe good, sometimes maybe shit.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UqPmQu"&gt;This, no doubt, is why Adobe didn’t once use the word “deepfake” to describe the technology in any of the briefing materials it sent to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. And when we asked why this was, the company didn’t answer directly but instead gave a long answer about how seriously it takes the threats posed by deepfakes and what it’s doing about them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VZLYR6"&gt;Adobe’s efforts in these areas seem involved and sincere (they’re mostly focused on &lt;a href="https://www.slashgear.com/adobe-expands-content-authenticity-initiative-tools-to-fight-misinformation-26696717/"&gt;content authentication schemes&lt;/a&gt;), but they don’t mitigate a commercial problem facing the company: that the same deepfake tools that would be most useful to its customer base are those that are also potentially most destructive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="ItBMMF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Deepfakes present a tricky problem for Adobe’s business strategy&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mdPYlm"&gt;Take, for example, the ability to paste someone’s face onto someone else’s body — arguably the ur-deepfake application that started all this bother. You might want such a face swap for legitimate reasons, like licensing Bruce Willis’ likeness for a &lt;a href="https://www.inputmag.com/culture/bruce-willis-licensed-his-deepfake-for-a-series-of-russian-mobile-carrier-ads"&gt;series of mobile ads in Russia&lt;/a&gt;). But you might also be creating nonconsensual pornography to harass, intimidate, or blackmail someone (by far the most common malicious application of this technology). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a4ByKp"&gt;Regardless of your intent, if you want to create this sort of deepfake, you have plenty of options, none of which come from Adobe. You can hire a boutique deepfake content studio, wrangle with some open-source software, or, if you don’t mind your face swaps being limited to preapproved memes and gifs, you can download an app. What you &lt;em&gt;can’t&lt;/em&gt; do is fire up Adobe Premiere or After Effects. So will that change in the future? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wvcGTt"&gt;It’s impossible to say for sure, but I think it’s definitely a possibility. After all, Adobe survived the advent of “Photoshopped” becoming shorthand for digitally edited images in general, and often with negative connotations. And for better or worse, deepfakes are slowly losing their own negative associations as they’re adopted in more mainstream projects. Project Morpheus is a deepfake tool with some serious guardrails (you can only make prescribed changes and there’s no face-swapping, for example), but it shows that Adobe is determined to explore this territory, presumably while gauging reactions from the industry and public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6RKFkt"&gt;It’s fitting that as “deepfake” has replaced “Photoshopped” as the go-to accusation of fakery  in the public sphere, Adobe is perhaps feeling left out. Project Morpheus suggests it may well catch up soon.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22748508/adobe-deepfake-tool-max-project-morpheus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22748508/adobe-deepfake-tool-max-project-morpheus</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-27T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-27T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Intel’s 12th Gen Alder Lake chips usher in a new generation of x86 processors</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W2HJTvONFOxRjwzprQSNLSKuMUY=/0x1:1925x1284/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70052373/i9_Gaming_Desktop___Box_Shot.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VphOEM"&gt;Intel’s 12th Gen Alder Lake chips have finally arrived, ushering in a new era of the company’s chips, lead by the flagship Core i9-12900K CPU, which Intel promises is the “world’s best gaming processor.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UfKO7Q"&gt;The company has been teasing Alder Lake &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225514/intel-12th-gen-hybrid-alder-lake-chips-2h-ces-2021"&gt;since CES 2021 in January&lt;/a&gt;, and it revealed a lot more details on the specifics of its hybrid architecture approach &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22631059/intel-alder-lake-chip-hybrid-architecture-day-2021-desktop-laptop-preview-cores"&gt;at its 2021 Architecture Day in July&lt;/a&gt;. But today’s announcement marks the culmination of those efforts in the form of actual hardware that you can buy and use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rt8twX"&gt;Intel is kicking things off with three new chips, led by the Core i9-12900K model, which offers a total of 16 cores (split between eight performance forced “P-cores” and eight efficient “E-cores”) and 24 threads and is capable of reaching clock speeds of up to 5.2GHz using Intel’s Turbo Boost Max 3.0 technology. All told, Intel promises a 19 percent performance improvement thanks to the new P-core architecture compared to its 11th Gen chips. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fU2jjRw8qi7ax84cOW3a1-fcytk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22957885/tomwarren_corei9_12900K_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Tom Warren / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MgXt4g"&gt;There’s also the Core i7-12700K (12 total cores and 20 threads, with eight P-cores and four E-cores) and the Core i5-12700K (10 total cores and 16 threads, with six P-cores and four E-cores) for those who don’t need as much firepower. Each of the three new chips are also available in a KF variant that ditches the integrated Intel UHD Graphics 770 to shave a few bucks off the price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5MuOM6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10830140"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jm3QRu"&gt;Intel is also using the new chips to introduce a lot of future-facing support for more advanced standards. All three new chips offer up to 20 PCIe lanes (split between 16 PCIe 5.0 and 4 PCIe 4.0 lanes), support for DDR5 memory at up to 4800MT/s (along with older DDR4 support at 3200MT/s), and larger L3 and L2 cache sizes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="z2BHG7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Intel’s new chips look to the future&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Zppz6T"&gt;Unfortunately, with new chips comes the need for a new motherboard: Alder Lake will need a motherboard built on Intel’s newly announced Z690 chipset, which adds more modern conveniences like Wi-Fi 6E support and faster USB 3.2 Gen 2x2 data transfer. Intel is using a new LGA 1700 socket here, so you may even need a new cooler or slightly updated standoffs from the manufacturer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VXM052"&gt;Intel is also heavily pushing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22708762/microsoft-windows-11-review"&gt;Windows 11&lt;/a&gt; as a key part of its Alder Lake lineup, noting that it’s worked with Microsoft to optimize its Intel Thread Director software to better manage tasks across threads when using the new OS. We’ll have to do some testing ourselves to see whether Windows 11 offers a notable boost in performance, however, along with how well the new chips stack up against competition from AMD and Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/B_xCcCodcpDa8ZoE6uWXm3qUfEg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22957888/tomwarren_corei9_12900K_4.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Tom Warren / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="biaAmg"&gt;And while Intel often brands each year’s chips as a new generation, the 12th Gen lineup (starting with today’s desktop release) truly deserves the title. It represents not just the biggest leap for Intel’s desktop chips in years but the debut of a new approach for Intel as to how it designs its best chips. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VmN5bq"&gt;The new lineup of Alder Lake chips are the first of Intel’s desktop chips to move beyond the 14nm process that the company has been using since it was first introduced in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/8/5/9094209/intel-skylake-processor-launch-release-date-price"&gt;2015’s 6th Gen Skylake chips&lt;/a&gt;. Instead, the new 12th Gen chips will be released on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/26/22594074/intel-acclerated-new-architecture-roadmap-naming-7nm-2025"&gt;freshly rebranded Intel 7 process&lt;/a&gt; (previously known as Intel’s third-generation 10nm process, or Enhanced Superfin).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AmWUyQ"&gt;As Intel has already explained, the new Alder Lake chips are a new approach to x86 chips for the company, one that strongly resembles the approach that Arm has been taking for years (and which has seen such success on Apple’s M1 line of chips). Instead of simply relying on cramming as many power-hungry cores as it can into a single chip, the Alder Lake hardware combines “performance” cores (broadly similar to Intel’s Core-class processors) with “efficiency” cores (closer to its Atom-class cores) for a mix of power and efficiency. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="LXpb4h"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The biggest change in Intel’s desktop chips since 2015&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1HXxbe"&gt;Intel has dabbled with this idea before, in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/21285821/intel-3d-stacked-lakefield-chips-hybrid-core-atom-arm-processor"&gt;2020’s Lakefield chips&lt;/a&gt;, but those were a far more limited set of chips designed for low-powered hardware. Alder Lake, on the other hand, aims to power full-scale desktops as Intel’s flagship CPU, in addition to laptops and ultra-portable devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tvDggq"&gt;The 12th Gen chips also represent a chance for Intel to redeem itself after its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22325460/intel-11th-gen-desktop-chips-rocket-lake-s-faster-speeds-cores-gaming"&gt;lackluster 11th Gen desktop lineup&lt;/a&gt;, which tried to compensate for Intel’s aging 14nm process and its struggles with 10nm manufacturing delays by using the 10nm designs back-ported to the 14nm process. But due to differences in the two architectures, Intel was forced to reduce the number of cores it could offer on the 11th Gen chips &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/4/30/21242512/intel-10th-gen-desktop-lineup-offers-gaming-processor-speed"&gt;compared to the 10th Gen hardware&lt;/a&gt; that preceded it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mmMBoq"&gt;As a result, last year’s models offered poor multithreaded performance compared to their processors: &lt;a href="https://www.anandtech.com/show/16535/intel-core-i7-11700k-review-blasting-off-with-rocket-lake/19"&gt;as &lt;em&gt;Anandtech&lt;/em&gt;’s thorough review&lt;/a&gt; points out, the 11th Gen chips offered little to no gain (and even, in some cases, worse performance) for gaming, while also running far hotter and more power-hungry. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="50DDTX"&gt;The new desktop chips are also only the beginning: Intel has big plans for the hybrid Alder Lake architecture, which includes mobile chips (an example shown featured six P-cores and eight E-cores) and ultra-mobile chips (like a model with two P-cores and eight E-cores) for laptops and other portable devices in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yw1kIh"&gt;Preorders for the new Intel 12th Gen chips start today, with the chips available on November 4th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22747271/intel-12th-gen-alder-lake-chips-hybrid-architecture-price-release-date-i9-12900k"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22747271/intel-12th-gen-alder-lake-chips-hybrid-architecture-price-release-date-i9-12900k</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-27T11:50:47-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-27T11:50:47-04:00</updated>
    <title>Chinese students sue Apple for not including a charger with the iPhone 12</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OHfvlwkzpoAbgcEOjTGzpSEO4Pk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70052302/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0002.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="poI4Sh"&gt;Five Chinese students are suing Apple for not providing a charger with the iPhone 12, first reported by &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/m7vqmb/apple-sued-china-iphone-chargers"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21514480/apple-iphone-charging-brick-charger-earbuds-box-environmental-impact-carbon-emissions"&gt;stopped including EarPods and wall chargers with iPhones&lt;/a&gt; in 2020, opting only to include a USB-C to Lightning cable in its packaging. &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2020/10/apple-introduces-iphone-12-pro-and-iphone-12-pro-max-with-5g/"&gt;According to Apple&lt;/a&gt;, ditching the charger and EarPods is supposed to reduce carbon emissions and preserve raw materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qf2nzM"&gt;There’s some skepticism as to whether Apple really did this to cut costs, rather than save the environment, as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/16/21519466/apple-iphone-12-chargers-airpods-greenhouse-gas-emissions-e-waste"&gt;the transition to 5G could make iPhones more expensive to make&lt;/a&gt;. Skipping out on chargers and EarPods could be a way for Apple to save a buck, and forcing customers to purchase accessories separately may help increase profits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aXtIhD"&gt;The students’ argument in court, which is a part of the Xiaocheng Cup Public Welfare Litigation Competition, cruxes on this premise. A report by the &lt;a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/z4w89z7vhGdeTY2algqlYw"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shanghai Law Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; describes the case in detail, noting that one of the students, named Xiaofang, was frustrated that her purchase of the iPhone 12 Pro Max didn’t come with a charger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="66GsW9"&gt;Xiaofang points out that since the cable included with the device is a USB-C to Lightning, it’s not compatible with the wall chargers that were previously included with Apple devices (via &lt;em&gt;Shanghai Law Journal&lt;/em&gt;). This means that customers will have to purchase a USB-C-compatible charger or a MagSafe charger if they don’t have one already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kxHSQY"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt;, Xiaofang claims that Apple is leaving out wall chargers to promote its MagSafe chargers, a line of magnetic chargers that powers your phone wirelessly. She alleges that Apple’s decision not to include a charger is motivated by profit, and that Apple is merely operating under the guise of saving the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="6aYMwb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"A year later, Apple’s MagSafe continues to underwhelm ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728967/apple-magsafe-duo-wallet-cases-charging"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="j5Bc3i"&gt;Xiaofang and her colleagues took Apple to the Beijing Internet Court, asking for Apple to provide a wall charger, as well as pay 100 yuan ($16) for breach of contract and for litigation fees (via &lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt;). As mentioned in the report by the &lt;em&gt;Shanghai Law Journal&lt;/em&gt;, a representative for Apple argued that it’s common for companies to sell phones without a charger and noted that the iPhone 12’s packaging makes it clear that no charger is included. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mFFHw1"&gt;The case is reportedly still in progress and has since gone viral on Chinese social media site Weibo, where the students have seen an outpouring of support (via &lt;a href="https://www.globaltimes.cn/page/202110/1237420.shtml"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Global Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Suing Apple for such a small sum may seem odd, but it’s the statement that matters. According to the report by &lt;em&gt;Global Times&lt;/em&gt;, a Chinese student sued the Shanghai Disney Resort in 2019 for just 50 yuan ($7) for not letting customers bring food into the park — Disney later conceded and agreed to pay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uc0fCf"&gt;This isn’t the first time Apple has faced legal issues for not providing chargers. Earlier this year, a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/20/22342051/brazil-regulator-fines-apple-2-million-chargers-iphone-12"&gt;Brazilian regulator fined Apple $2 million&lt;/a&gt; for failing to include chargers with the iPhone 12, alleging that Apple is misleading the customer by selling it without one.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22748474/chinese-students-sue-apple-including-charger-iphone-12"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22748474/chinese-students-sue-apple-including-charger-iphone-12</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
