<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-22T09:55:57-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-22T09:55:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T09:55:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nintendo delays its Advance Wars remaster to spring 2022</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vfaJByBHZe6-i2iZXqks_VHrh9o=/54x0:1134x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70030926/screenshot03.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A screenshot from &lt;/em&gt;Advance Wars 1+2: Re-Boot Camp&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jX2wMK"&gt;Nintendo has delayed its upcoming remaster of the first two &lt;em&gt;Advance Wars&lt;/em&gt; games. &lt;em&gt;Advance Wars 1+2: Re-Boot Camp&lt;/em&gt; had been set to release on December 3rd, but it will now be coming out sometime in spring 2022. “The game just needs a little more time for fine tuning,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1451533822022066179"&gt;Nintendo said in a tweet&lt;/a&gt; on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cZRz1y"&gt;The company announced the remasters of &lt;em&gt;Advance Wars&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Advance Wars 2: Black Hole Rising&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fftL_XeK2qU"&gt;at E3 2021&lt;/a&gt;, and Nintendo says they’re “reimagined and rebuilt from the ground up.” You can check out the board game-inspired aesthetic in &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fftL_XeK2qU"&gt;the game’s debut trailer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wuAZa4tjWpg"&gt;in an E3 gameplay demo&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="KBNiTw"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fftL_XeK2qU?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6wUYEp"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Advance Wars&lt;/em&gt; is one of many recent game delays. In September, EA’s &lt;em&gt;Battlefield 2042&lt;/em&gt; was bumped nearly a month &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/15/22676330/battlefield-2042-release-date-delay"&gt;from October 22nd to November 19th&lt;/a&gt;. Last week, FromSoftware’s &lt;em&gt;Elden Ring&lt;/em&gt; was pushed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732651/from-software-elden-ring-release-date-delayed"&gt;from January 22nd to February 25th&lt;/a&gt;. And on Wednesday, CD Projekt Red said that the next-gen versions of &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22736560/cd-projekt-red-delay-cyberpunk-2077-witcher-3-2022"&gt;would miss&lt;/a&gt; their targeted late 2021 release windows.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/22/22740195/nintendo-advance-wars-1-2-re-boot-camp-switch-switch-remaster-delay"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/22/22740195/nintendo-advance-wars-1-2-re-boot-camp-switch-switch-remaster-delay</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-22T09:36:09-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T09:36:09-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung’s unique Frame TV is $500 off</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Samsung Frame TV 2018" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LwCiwE71z4_xN5WXZ4ZuB0vZclw=/0x699:4194x3495/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70030818/2018_2_The_Frame_Lifestyle_Image_Assets_20.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 65-inch LCD version is $1,500 today.&lt;/em&gt; | Samsung&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rEPUfc"&gt;Samsung’s The Frame doubles as both wall art and an HDR-compatible QLED TV. The television offers a decor-friendly design while also displaying customizable images when somebody’s in the room. When turned on, however, it transforms into a smart 4K TV with Alexa built in that boasts a 120Hz refresh rate to display content smoothly. Right now, you can pick it up for its lowest price yet. For a limited time, you can buy the 65-inch 2021 model for $1,500 instead of $2,000 from &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08VW898FS/?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0QwA2D"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10819823"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vkvczZ"&gt;Samsung lovers, you’re in luck: we’ve got another great deal for you, this time on phones. Right now, Amazon is taking $280 off of Samsung’s recently released &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09HGBG94S?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Galaxy Z Fold 3&lt;/a&gt; – which supports Samsung’s stylus, the S Pen – when you buy the 256GB version bundled with an S Pen Folio Case. Normally, you’d pay $1,880 for the package, but right now, you can get it for $1,600 in the green, silver, and black colors — its best price on the site yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RLRrYQ"&gt;In our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22638257/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3-review"&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;, we called the Galaxy Z Fold 3 as good as a foldable gets, making this a great deal. We also loved that it’s water-resistant and praised how Samsung improved the 120Hz screen, its multitasking capabilities on Android, and its durability. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22638257/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="igpN4c"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10820291"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zbVkbs"&gt;If the Galaxy Z Fold 3 deal is a little too expensive, you may be interested in this tempting deal, which can save up to $1,000 on your carrier plan. Right now, T-Mobile is &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fnews%2Foffers%2Ft-mobile-pays-off-your-phone&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F22%2F22738411%2Fsamsung-the-frame-google-pixelbook-go-galaxy-z-fold-3-t-mobile-legend-of-zelda-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;offering&lt;/a&gt; to pay off up to $1,000 of whatever you owe AT&amp;amp;T or Verizon starting today, October 22nd, if you switch carriers. Families can also benefit from this deal. T-Mobile will additionally pay up to $1,000 for up to five of your devices, which means a family of five can get a maximum of $5,000 to pay off their phones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t515wi"&gt;To qualify for this deal, you’ll have to bring your smartphone to a T-Mobile store, as well as a photo of your last bill. If you qualify, T-Mobile will then give you a virtual prepaid MasterCard with up to $1,000 you can use to “free” yourself from your old carrier. Note, however, you need to also stick with T-Mobile for over 90 days to get the deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="oh23EM"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10820342"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="ulRnqA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best phone plans in 2021 (and how to pick one)","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22606623/best-cell-phone-plans-verizon-att-t-mobile"},{"title":"Cellphone plan fine print, explained","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/31/22360228/unlimited-plan-verizon-att-t-mobile-premium-data-tethering-limits"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Xgbmmi"&gt;Google’s least expensive Pixelbook Go is even cheaper today. Right now, you can purchase the Intel i7 processor-powered model with &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07YMM3R39?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;256GB of storage and 16GB of RAM for $1,302 instead of $1,400.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WD9Isv"&gt;If you’re a fan of Chromebooks made by Google, the latest Google Pixelbook Go &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/25/20931476/google-pixelbook-go-review-the-price-of-simplicity"&gt;offers&lt;/a&gt; good value for its price, making this an even better deal. It has a great backlit keyboard, a simple, elegant design, and weighs relatively little — at 2.3 pounds, you can carry it around easily. The Chromebook also sports a 13-inch touchscreen display, as well as an excellent 12-hour battery life, with two USB-C ports and a 3.5mm port as well. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/25/20931476/google-pixelbook-go-review-the-price-of-simplicity"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nXSTW3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10820334"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="uUUdlv"&gt;Come hang out with us at our 10-year anniversary party this weekend&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ASpOMQ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;is turning 10, and you’re invited to the party. Taking place in New York City on the 22nd (tonight!) and 23rd of October, On The Verge is going to be a celebration of everything we’ve accomplished over the past decade, and we want you to be a part of it. Right now, you can &lt;a href="https://voxmediaevents.com/ontheverge/evite"&gt;snag tickets for just $99 with the promo code $99NOW&lt;/a&gt;, which gets you admission for both days and four complimentary drink tickets. The event will include speakers from &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;talent and from the wider world of tech, as well as musical performances and interactive experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="9xFaU8"&gt;Wait! There’s more! Here are some other great deals going on:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="1lD11l"&gt;Walmart’s offering a digital download of &lt;a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FThe-Legend-of-Zelda-Breath-of-the-Wild-and-Expansion-Pass-Bundle-Nintendo-Switch-Digital-Download%2F938165002" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;for the Nintendo Switch&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;with an expansion pass to boot for $47 instead of $80.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="zBh3Zk"&gt;Pair up your new iPhone 13 Pro with today’s discounted &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09G8WTNVR?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MagSafe leather case&lt;/a&gt;, which also supports Apple’s MagSafe charging features. Typically $59, the case is selling for $50 in select colors on Amazon — an all-time low. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="UkyWF0"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08NRNSVRK?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy Smart Tag+&lt;/a&gt;, which is a Bluetooth device tracker similar to Apple’s AirTag, is also selling at its best price yet. Normally $40, you can buy one for $30 instead — a 25-percent discount.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="5BMFg1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="923W0Y"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/22/22738411/samsung-the-frame-google-pixelbook-go-galaxy-z-fold-3-t-mobile-legend-of-zelda-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/22/22738411/samsung-the-frame-google-pixelbook-go-galaxy-z-fold-3-t-mobile-legend-of-zelda-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-22T09:15:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T09:15:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nest Cam (indoor) review: Google’s pretty little camera takes one step forward and three steps back </title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;It might look good, but it doesn’t perform well&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="CUFCsf"&gt;Indoor cameras are an awkward category. It’s hard to find a way to fit one into your home without feeling like Big Brother is watching you. My family hates having them in the house and only grudgingly lets me set them up to test as long as I take them down as soon as possible. Despite my assurances that the devices are set to not record when we’re home — they just don’t quite believe me. And they’re not alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="79yVHk"&gt;Making a camera prettier so it blends in better with your home — as is the case with Google’s newest $100 Nest Cam (indoor) — may feel like a step in the right direction, but it really isn’t. In the end, it’s still a big black eye staring at you — no matter how attractive its exterior casing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="hYtKi4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10820719"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fswtfV"&gt;If you’re going to have an indoor camera, you need a really good reason. Security — while a valid reason for some — can be just as easily achieved with a well-placed outdoor camera (and be much less likely to catch you in your knickers by accident). Safety — checking to see if you left the stove on or looking in on the living room when your smart smoke alarm goes off is fine in theory — but, in reality, requires a camera in every nook and cranny where something could conceivably go wrong (which is the theory behind Ring’s new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22692048/ring-always-home-cam-drone-amazon-price-release-date-specs"&gt;Always Home Cam&lt;/a&gt;). Ultimately, the most popular reason to use indoor cameras is to check in on pets and kids. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nxO82c"&gt;As a pet / child cam, the Nest Cam — which is part of &lt;a href="https://www.googlenestcommunity.com/t5/Blog/Message-from-our-GM-Updates-for-our-Nest-customers/ba-p/17122"&gt;Google’s new lineup of security cameras that includes&lt;/a&gt; a doorbell, an indoor / outdoor camera, and a floodlight cameras —  does a nice job. Its best feature is its on-device processing that delivers snappy (and free) smart alerts to tell you whether it’s a cat or your child that just snuck into the kitchen before dinner. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="obbTRG"&gt;With three hours of free event playback, you can see what went on without having to pay a monthly subscription fee (as long as you catch the alert within that three-hour window), and thanks to some local storage, the camera can record an hour’s worth of events if the internet goes down. If you spring for Google’s Nest Aware plan (starting at $6 a month), you can add the excellent Familiar Faces feature (which will tell you &lt;em&gt;which&lt;/em&gt; child snuck into the kitchen — but sadly not which cat) and enable 24/7 recording (a handy feature if you want to see what your dog did all day or “film” a party or event at your home).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OtFgeY"&gt;Unfortunately, the Nest Cam is not as good at either of these things as Nest’s previous camera — the $299 Nest Cam IQ Indoor. It had the option of sound alerts to detect a dog barking and people talking and could record a timelapse — which was a fun use of 24/7 recording. Granted, it was $200 more expensive and quite large and bulky in comparison to the diminutive newer model, but I’m not usually a fan of making smart home devices dumber or less capable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZfsjzO"&gt;Perhaps Google thinks the fancy 4K sensor-powered Nest Cam IQ with a built-in Google Assistant was overkill for the average person, and maybe it was. But that doesn’t explain why the newer Nest Cam with its 1080p, 2-megapixel camera has significantly worse video quality than the older version, beyond just lower resolution. Google said it ditched the 4K sensors to help preserve bandwidth (its wired cameras are notorious data hogs), but based on my testing, competitors’ cameras that cost under $50 have better video quality than this camera. They don’t look as pretty, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KcRegQmi82OGdWQTPWAeNGIUVsY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22946134/1D84FD79_B8C7_4664_B453_9C26AA1DD7D1.JPG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nest Cam struggled with contrast and definition in indoor lighting situations.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3H0uatox2yLSuQvlnHHcKEtCl9k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22946137/B8D02405_CCDE_44D5_A864_9D54EF84C214.JPG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The $36 Wyze cam with similar specs as the Nest Cam captured much clearer footage, as you can see in this screenshot taken at the same time in the same location as the Nest Cam.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="T3JwK1"&gt;In my testing, I compared the Nest Cam side-by-side with a $36 Wyze Cam V3, and the Wyze Cam produced much better quality images. The images from the Nest Cam were over-saturated, dark, and regularly had a lot of artefacting. They also looked like I was viewing my home through rose-tinted glasses. I tested two units because Google said it has identified an issue with some cameras where the auto-white balance is out of whack, causing the rosy tint. But both cameras I tested had the same issue. Google says it’s rolling out a fix next month, and I’ll re-test and update this review if I see any changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vYDaUd"&gt;I also did a comparison with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22710545/nest-doorbell-battery-cam-battery-test-review-price-specs-features"&gt;the Nest Cam battery&lt;/a&gt;, which is Google’s new indoor / outdoor camera that has the option of being wired. It didn’t struggle as much with the contrast as the wired version, but its indoor images were not as crisp and clear as those it captured outdoors.  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/t7j4YXRd6wV_wI_mSEcfQo0ZMMI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22946144/3405C8C4_A7AC_4902_BAAE_89C8549CB06F.JPG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nest Cam cast a very rosy glow over my house (which is not pink in real life). &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0ibudBKMJQq17AH-jlLpsAhmPVY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22946160/6719EAD3_08AB_4F13_8DDC_A5AB1FB4DBDF.JPG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This image taken at the same time but from a wall-mounted Nest Cam IQ, provides a more accurate representation of my kitchen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="1O5RAt"&gt;Night vision on the Nest Cam was more successful — and definitely not rose-tinted. The standard black and white video captures up to 15 feet at night, which is more than you’d need in most home environments. The 6x digital zoom (a step down from the Nest Cam IQ’s 12x) gave me enough pixels to zoom in on faces and make them out clearly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X6Gol6"&gt;Of course, video quality isn’t &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; when it comes to a smart home security camera. It’s no good having top-quality video if you can’t access it quickly on a useable app. Design and build are also factors, as are privacy features, audio quality, and smart home integrations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e6cfGtMGGC_DwtidEhsFbAE3IBY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22928575/jtuohy_211012_4809_vrt.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nest Cam can be mounted to a ceiling or wall using screws.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DxMNfz"&gt;The Nest Cam has a nice design and the unique option of four color choices — white, grey, blue, and pink. It’s also surprisingly small — the base is almost as big as the camera, and the two together top out at just under four inches. A maple wood base on the pink camera is a nice decor touch, but I didn’t like the limited amount of flexibility the camera had on the mount (which it’s fixed, too). While you can mount it on the wall, as well as sit flat on a table or shelf, it only tilts up and down a few degrees, making it tricky to position perfectly in some situations. You can move it side to side almost a complete 360 degrees, but the fixed cord will stop you from going all the way around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5OxNIa"&gt;When the camera is recording, a small LED on the camera glows green, and this can’t be disabled. If someone is viewing the live stream, the LED flashes. This is a good privacy feature — although not enough to assuage the fears of my family. Ultimately, a physical hardware shutter is the only thing that will make most people feel comfortable, and I’m surprised Google didn’t offer this option.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DHHr9KwJv_bHOMHgs3cTYsXdXmE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22928574/jtuohy_211012_4809_6.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nest Cam is only slightly taller than a travel sized bottle of hand sanitizer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="IYXR4t"&gt;The Nest Cam has full-duplex two-way audio, which worked well in my testing. I could carry on a conversation as if it were a telephone call — even talking over each other and still being able to hear. That experience is much better than a lot of indoor security cameras where the interaction is more like a walkie-talkie, and lag time can be really frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JEa9BK"&gt;The Nest Cam is also fast at sending alerts. Notifications for motion, animals, people, and vehicles (there’s not a lot of traffic in my living room, to be fair) arrived on my iPhone 13 just 1 to 3 seconds after the action. This would give me plenty of time to react — however, the Google Home app takes up to 10 seconds to pull up the footage. For just quickly viewing footage, the Nest Hub smart displays are faster than the app, pulling up a feed within a couple seconds, but you can’t interact with the feed or talk to someone through the Hub. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MFswPp"&gt;This brings me to my other issue with the Nest Cam: the Google Home app. You have to use it with this camera; it won’t work with the Nest app. I have used and loved the Nest app for years, and its ability to quickly scroll through footage and recorded events all on one page is something I really miss here. With the Home app, you have to tap into two or three different screens to see clips, live footage, or a timeline, and the timeline scroll is very slow (&lt;a href="https://www.googlenestcommunity.com/t5/Blog/Message-from-our-GM-Updates-for-our-Nest-customers/ba-p/17122"&gt;Google has said it’s fixing this&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dGG8ST"&gt;While the accuracy of alerts in the newer Nest Cams is far superior to the older ones — which would routinely ping me 35 times in the middle of the night because a spider was building its web on the camera — digging in the Settings section of the Google Home app to figure out how to set up an activity zone is almost as tiresome. But Google has clearly indicated that it plans to migrate everything from the Nest app, so we’ll all have to struggle on in the Home app. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/23Z0R5glzw8QCf2o8XAeauKTFvc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22928553/jtuohy_211012_4809_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nest Cam uses an attached 10 foot USB-A power cable, which can plug into the included power brick.  &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MTyDQe"&gt;There is simply too much going on in the Home app to make using it as a security camera hub a pleasant experience. And while the camera interface has some nice touches (like seeing a live feed of all your cameras when you open it), it’s too fiddly and requires too many taps and clicks and scrolls to get to the footage you want. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OElNUE"&gt;It’s also missing some features from the Nest app, including scheduling your cameras to come on and off at certain times. Instead, there’s a Routine that will control them based on your location, but that’s not helpful if you want them on at night while you are sleeping. There is an option to only get notified when the camera is on and no one is home, which helps a bit, but scheduling doesn’t feel like a big ask. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="WCT15R"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10820840"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5x1dCH"&gt;You also can’t use Google’s Nest cameras in any ecosystem other than Google Home. The old Nest cameras worked with Amazon Alexa and, more recently, SmartThings, but these are Google only. If you are running a Google smart home, that won’t be an issue — these cameras integrate nicely with any other Google-compatible device. Except for in one odd way — you can’t view your camera feed on a Chromecast-enabled TV. Google says it’s working on adding the feature, as well as a web interface, which was a feature of Nest cameras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RvWnMy"&gt;While I do appreciate Google’s efforts to make smart home devices more suited to our home, and the local processing is an excellent step forward, I don’t like seeing devices lose functionality. Google still has a lot of work to do with the Nest Cam, and that’s a shame because Nest’s indoor cameras were the industry gold standard. Now, in far too many respects, they’re playing catch up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h68coQ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Jennifer Pattison Tuohy / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b1nk7L"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dhQcMI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22739349/google-nest-indoor-cam-wired-review-smart-security-camera"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22739349/google-nest-indoor-cam-wired-review-smart-security-camera</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-22T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>It’s party time, smash the EXTRA BASS button</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VwooU4nfKbDtpiBDo9qXUxzT59g=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70030660/akrales_210916_4737_0043.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LpIFK6"&gt;The button is simple, almost plain. A flat black circle, simple dye-sublimated letters, and a small LED pinprick to let you know that it’s on. “EXTRA BASS,” it declares in tall, bold capitals. For indeed, the EXTRA BASS button only does one blindingly obvious thing: it adds &lt;em&gt;extra bass.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1OROMT"&gt;The speaker in question here is a &lt;a href="https://www.sony.com/electronics/hi-fi-systems/gtk-xb90/buy/gtkxb90"&gt;Sony XB90 Extra Bass High Power Audio System&lt;/a&gt;. It is a product without pretension, without guile or duplicity. It has Extra Bass in the name, and the eponymous button is a microcosm of the device, a thing that encapsulates the form and function in a neat, tidy shorthand.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JkUvY9AAvPpawwFnSQvZEN6xl_k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22869930/akrales_210916_4737_0037.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MPGRqM"&gt;This is not a speaker for listening to soft sonatas of Mozart or enjoying the sonic subtleties of a rare acoustic studio recording. It is a party speaker, with emphasis on the “party,” and if you don’t happen to have a party handy, it will happily create one in seconds with thudding, ear-rattling sound. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="3xRSlb"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It is a party speaker, with emphasis on the “party”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NCMMcB"&gt;The Sony XB90 Extra Bass High Power Audio System is the size of a beer cooler and is destined to sit alongside one — its intended resting place a dingy basement of a college apartment, a backyard pool party, or a raucous tailgate. (Sony, in fact, sells a different model &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/1/8/18173383/sony-gtk-pg10-beer-holding-karaoke-party-speaker-hands-on-ces-2019"&gt;with cupholders built in&lt;/a&gt;.) It is liberally festooned with LED lights and offers a variety of useful input methods (including Bluetooth, an aux cable, and a USB-A port for charging and playing music from a newer phone that might not have a headphone jack). You can daisy chain more of the 26-pound speakers together, too, should you own more than one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L5qGZ6"&gt;The EXTRA BASS button is the natural culmination of the XB7. “Parties are good,” the XB7 practically says merely by existing. “Loud, thumping bass makes parties better. But what if the bass was… EXTRA BASS?”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uS8wuzPpD3LmDhuMCw8q3RU9NWk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22869929/akrales_210916_4737_0030.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="9mtVts"&gt;Pressing the EXTRA BASS button doesn’t, at first, translate the impact of what you’re doing. The button itself is ordinary looking, the mechanical click is the same as any other button on the XB7. But its impact can be felt (literally, depending on the track and how high you’ve cranked the volume) almost immediately. The EXTRA does exactly what it promises: it boosts up the bass to almost comically distorted levels, ensuring that whatever you’re listening to will be given the deep, body-rattling sound it deserves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="CTJVZK"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“What if the bass was… EXTRA BASS?” &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AG5LRn"&gt;The almost pedestrian nature of the EXTRA BASS button is its biggest flaw. Other party speakers, like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2016/8/2/12353122/philips-nitro-speakers-headphones-synesthesia-LED-light"&gt;regrettably discontinued Philips Nitro Speaker&lt;/a&gt;, gives the bass-boosting button the visual splendor it deserves: a glowing red, caution-tape-ringed “NX BASS” button that gives the impression that pressing may also inadvertently launch a missile in addition to making sure that partygoers feel the bass line of Daft Punk’s “Around the World” vibrating in their bones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V402iJ"&gt;The EXTRA BASS button dreams to imagine a world that can be more. What if the party never had to end? What if the night &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; go on forever? What if the bass was just a little bit more &lt;em&gt;extra?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gEBjD7"&gt;On any other product, an EXTRA BASS button would be a ridiculous thing to exist. But in the Natty-Light soaked world of the XB90, the EXTRA BASS button turns not just logical but almost necessary — and when faced with a tool designed and implemented with such bespoke perfection for the task it’s meant for, it’s hard not to appreciate the beauty of it. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/22/22732447/sony-extra-bass-party-speaker-button-loud-design"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/22/22732447/sony-extra-bass-party-speaker-button-loud-design</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-22T08:48:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T08:48:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>Micro Center leaks specs and pricing for Intel’s new Alder Lake Core i9 CPU</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FP9uzpelyKTSPR22EKUeFbVZJqo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70030545/acastro_210120_1777_intel_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jFFOdK"&gt;Even though someone managed to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/22/22740060/intel-core-i9-12900k-sold-early"&gt;secure early purchases of a couple of Core i9-12900K CPUs&lt;/a&gt;, we still didn’t have detailed information about Intel’s upcoming line of Alder Lake chips. Now, a sale page &lt;a href="https://www.microcenter.com/product/641915/intel-core-i9-12900k-alder-lake-32ghz-sixteen-core-lga-1700-boxed-processor-heatsink-not-included#tab-specs"&gt;has popped up on Micro Center&lt;/a&gt;, suggesting the chips will be available for $669.99 when they launch on November 4th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LQMLKq"&gt;The spec sheet reveals this chip will have a 3.2GHz operating frequency, capable of 5.2GHz in Turbo Mode, with 16 cores and 30MB of L3 cache. As expected, the specs reveal it also supports DDR5 memory, PCIe Gen 5, and the Intel Z690 chipset motherboards that should go on sale at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pYu9uArfC7ccOQ1Ik2Az1GUAgck=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22792156/Screen_Shot_2021_08_19_at_8.16.23_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="qMzMGu"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22631059/intel-alder-lake-chip-hybrid-architecture-day-2021-desktop-laptop-preview-cores"&gt;During its Architecture Day 2021 event in August&lt;/a&gt;, Intel promised Alder Lake chips with 16 cores using eight performance cores and eight efficient ones. This leak lines up with the top-end promises, right down to listed support for 24 concurrent threads (two each on performance cores, one thread at a time on the efficient cores) and 125W thermal power.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/22/22740133/intel-core-i9-12900k-spec-release-date-price-alder-lake"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/22/22740133/intel-core-i9-12900k-spec-release-date-price-alder-lake</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-22T08:45:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T08:45:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Verge Merch Store is back!</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tlDnrN4h2FiF-FJeBrsX_91hIPg=/134x212:2609x1862/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70030537/poster_1.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ce7j3l"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; is celebrating its 10th birthday on November 1st, so we thought this would be the perfect occasion to relaunch our online merch store! Check out the store &lt;a href="http://store.theverge.com"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. We partnered with DFTBA on some new products we’re really excited about — including a special edition &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; 10-year design by artist Richard Parry — as well as some classic favorites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fqJAEN"&gt;This is just the start for &lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;merch, and we’re excited to work on even more all-new designs in the future. If there’s anything you think we should make, let us know in the comments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7gryX7"&gt;Now, what are you waiting for? There’s an EMAILS shirt with your name on it. (Well, not literally. But let us know if embroidery is something you’re interested in.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="LQej7n"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10807023"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="2WZIfB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10807034"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="lojEyT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10807040"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="1QwM1w"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10807054"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="64m309"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Visit The Verge Merch Store","description":"Check out our brand-new merch — including T-shirts, sweatshirts, stickers, and posters — just in time for &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;The Verge&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;’s 10th anniversary!","label":"Go to store","url":"http://store.theverge.com"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="zE48gw"&gt;Special thanks: &lt;br&gt;Richard Parry, Will Joel, TC Sottek, Kaitlin Hatton, Lukas Phelan, Rachel Navarro, Sue Bohlen, Sarah Smithers, and Helen Havlak    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="MTtMqb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KkN3xA"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22726201/verge-merch-store"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22726201/verge-merch-store</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kara Verlaney</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-22T08:30:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T08:30:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>Watch the first trailer for the GTA remastered trilogy, launching November 11th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-AypPasNJWNegujXC9Ex-1iDofM=/0x0:3240x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70030392/gtaIIIremastered2.6.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new Claude in GTA III remastered.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Dt6LsH"&gt;Rockstar Games finally &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D71cBUeAL58"&gt;showed off a trailer&lt;/a&gt; for the remastered &lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto&lt;/em&gt; trilogy, including &lt;em&gt;GTA III&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Vice City&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;San Andreas&lt;/em&gt;, showcasing many graphical and quality-of-life improvements made to each game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PYJudj"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy — The Definitive Edition&lt;/em&gt; collection will launch digitally on November 11th for $59.99 (£54.99). You’ll be able to play them on the Nintendo Switch, PlayStation 4 and 5, Xbox One, the newer Series X/S consoles, and PC via the Rockstar Games Launcher. It’ll get a physical release on December 7th, followed by versions for iOS and Android in the first half of 2022. &lt;a href="https://www.rockstargames.com/GTATrilogy"&gt;Rockstar Games launched a site where you can look through more details&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5yjGeI"&gt;Xbox Game Pass subscribers will get instant access to &lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas — The Definitive Edition&lt;/em&gt; on launch day. &lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto III  — The Definitive Edition&lt;/em&gt; will come to PlayStation Now on December 7th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="0Oa8KE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;San Andreas — The Definitive Edition is coming to Game Pass on launch day&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aYx245"&gt;Each of these games was remastered by &lt;a href="https://grovestreetgames.com/"&gt;Grove Street Games&lt;/a&gt;, which appears to have done extensive work to make them far prettier and more playable than their PS2 counterparts. Rockstar says it used Unreal Engine and a “completely rebuilt” lighting system, and the graphical improvements seem to touch practically every part of the games. The list provided in Rockstar’s press release includes improved shadows, weather, and reflections, and upgraded character and vehicle models. There are increased draw distances, smoother surfaces, and “higher resolution textures across buildings, weapons, roads, interiors, and more.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NMI5zoNI16mcjRucmgWziXUY268=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22947220/tommyvremastered.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="A6jSmM"&gt;Rockstar Games confirmed that each game has &lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto V&lt;/em&gt;-inspired controls. That alone should do a lot of heavy lifting in making these games feel more modern. Targeting and lock-on aiming has been overhauled in each game. In terms of their interfaces, each game offers updated weapon and radio station wheels, along with new mini-maps that let players set waypoints and destinations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2g80G4"&gt;There are some platform-specific additions, too. On Nintendo Switch, Rockstar added gyroscopic aiming, and you can utilize its touchscreen to zoom or pan with the camera and make selections within menus. The PC version (a 45GB download) supports Nvidia’s DLSS tech that can help games run a little better on a wider array of graphics cards without a noticeable drop in visual quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H5tkE0"&gt;This latest trickle of news comes on the 20th anniversary of &lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto III&lt;/em&gt; for PS2. The $59.99 price might surprise some people, but the improvements make it seem worth it for fans. Nevertheless, if you’re a Game Pass or PlayStation Now subscriber, at least you already know you’ll get to experience some of the games in the collection at no additional cost to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jAtEAv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/22/22739195/remastered-grand-theft-auto-trilogy-release-date-november-11th-gta3-vice-city-san-andreas"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/22/22739195/remastered-grand-theft-auto-trilogy-release-date-november-11th-gta3-vice-city-san-andreas</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-22T06:33:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T06:33:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>Intel’s unreleased Core i9-12900K processor goes on sale early</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/m005alGBgku-EY_bBAnUFTpL-bs=/0x0:2400x1600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70030065/intelcorei912900k.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Intel’s Core i9-12900K hasn’t even been officially announced yet.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Seby9123/" target="_blank"&gt;Seby9123&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RBfAtv"&gt;Intel hasn’t even officially announced its new Core i9-12900K processor, but it’s already been sold by a retailer. The unreleased CPU is expected to be the flagship for Intel’s new line of Alder Lake processors, offering a chance to reclaim the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21552336/amd-zen-3-ryzen-review-roundup-5950x-intel-comparison"&gt;performance crown from AMD&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BrWEGx"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/intel/comments/qcszo9/so_i_somehow_got_one_of_these/"&gt;Reddit poster&lt;/a&gt;, spotted by &lt;a href="https://www.techspot.com/news/91523-photos-intel-alder-lake-packaging-leak.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Techspot&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, managed to purchase two Core i9-12900K processors in retail packaging from an unnamed retailer for $610 per CPU. A similar mix-up happened earlier this year, when retailers started selling Intel’s Rocket Lake CPUs nearly a month before their launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="CH1GIN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;This unreleased CPU is useless without a new motherboard&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nfstp0"&gt;The Reddit poster has published a number of photos of the unreleased Core i9-12900K processor in its retail packaging, which matches leaks from &lt;a href="https://videocardz.com/newz/intel-core-i9-12900k-and-core-i7-i5-alder-lake-series-packaging-has-been-leaked"&gt;earlier this month&lt;/a&gt;. The box includes a wafer ornament, but it doesn’t detail the processor frequency or even its core count. As Z690 motherboards aren’t yet available, the processor is useless without them, so the Reddit poster can’t post benchmarks or any information about the Core i9-12900K.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E0xDK6"&gt;We’re still waiting on Intel to officially detail its flagship processor, and the motherboards that will support it. A number of Asus Z690 motherboards &lt;a href="https://videocardz.com/newz/asus-z690-rog-strix-motherboards-for-intel-alder-lake-cpus-leaked"&gt;leaked earlier today&lt;/a&gt;, but without specs or feature lists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fu4ClJ"&gt;Intel is rumored to be launching its Alder Lake desktop CPUs, with the flagship Core i9-12900K, later this month. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22631059/intel-alder-lake-chip-hybrid-architecture-day-2021-desktop-laptop-preview-cores"&gt;Alder Lake will feature&lt;/a&gt; Intel’s latest hybrid architecture: a mix of both performance and efficiency x86 cores. Alder Lake will also include support for DDR5, PCIe Gen 5, Thunderbolt 4, and Wi-Fi 6E.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/22/22740060/intel-core-i9-12900k-sold-early"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/22/22740060/intel-core-i9-12900k-sold-early</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-22T06:14:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T06:14:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>Elgato’s app that turns iPhones into webcams gets AR Snap Lens support</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4NlcnDrltm4N3iycmRoLeNvogIU=/0x0:2553x1702/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70030034/msedge_AUo0F80iib.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Elgato&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="I5TAav"&gt;EpocCam, the app from streaming brand Elgato that lets you repurpose your iPhone as a webcam for your PC or Mac, has been updated with native support for Snap Lenses augmented reality filters, &lt;a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2021/10/21/2318449/0/en/Elgato-Partners-with-Snap-to-Bring-Snap-Lenses-to-Mobile-Webcam-App-EpocCam.html"&gt;Elgato’s parent company Corsair has announced&lt;/a&gt;. The functionality comes thanks to a partnership with Snap, who already offers similar filters natively in the Snapchat app, as well as with its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22276091/zoom-snap-camera-filter-how-to-youtube-cat"&gt;Snap Camera software&lt;/a&gt;. Now the functionality is included natively in the EpocCam app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nR9DQl"&gt;There are a total of 15 Snap Lenses for EpocCam, which include virtual backgrounds, virtual masks, and customizable filters. “Become your digital avatar, colorize your hair, interact with animated characters, and much more,” &lt;a href="https://www.elgato.com/en/epoccam"&gt;promises Elgato’s website&lt;/a&gt;, which also notes that the Snap Lenses work with the &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/epoccam-webcam-for-mac-and-pc/id449133483"&gt;free version of EpocCam&lt;/a&gt; as well as its &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/epoccam-webcamera-for-computer/id435355256"&gt;$7.99 Pro version&lt;/a&gt;. The company says it plans to add more filters over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="R4zi4H"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Become your digital avatar, colorize your hair, interact with animated characters, and much more”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cMwBCn"&gt;Elgato advertises that EpocCam lets you use your iPhone as a webcam across a range of services including Zoom, Teams, and OBS Studio, which means these filters should be able to transform your appearance regardless of whether you’re streaming, or participating in an important work call. In theory, this could have previously been possible by using a combination of the EpocCam and Snap Camera apps, but now it’s all neatly integrated and officially supported in a single piece of software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MWvqeV"&gt;If you’d like to give the feature a try, EpocCam is available as a &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/epoccam-webcam-for-mac-and-pc/id449133483"&gt;free download on iOS&lt;/a&gt;, though its &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/epoccam-webcamera-for-computer/id435355256"&gt;$7.99 version&lt;/a&gt; includes extra features like being able to use your iPhone’s microphone, and also removes the software’s watermark from your feed. Unfortunately there’s no sign of an Android version.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/22/22740048/elgato-epoccam-snap-lenses-support-iphone-as-computer-webcam"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/22/22740048/elgato-epoccam-snap-lenses-support-iphone-as-computer-webcam</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-22T04:51:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T04:51:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>PUBG: New State arrives on iOS and Android on November 11th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EPNtL00A7dQnLYcHRPZOGQPQgZA=/0x0:1894x1263/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70029953/msedge_dX2AbABxCv.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Krafton&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SOEq8q"&gt;&lt;em&gt;PUBG: New State&lt;/em&gt;, the upcoming free-to-play mobile game, will release on iOS and Android on November 11th, its &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.co.uk/news-releases/krafton-to-globally-launch-pubg-new-state-on-nov-11-857106352.html"&gt;publisher Krafton announced today&lt;/a&gt;. The game is set in the year 2051, and will offer a futuristic take on the multiplayer-focused PUBG formula with new features like weapon customization and in-game drones. &lt;em&gt;New State&lt;/em&gt; will be available in over 200 countries and 17 languages at launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h0nwwi"&gt;&lt;em&gt;New State&lt;/em&gt; is a significant launch for the PUBG series, which popularized the battle royale genre after the launch of its first title in 2017. Although &lt;em&gt;New State &lt;/em&gt;isn’t its first mobile entry, following the launch of PUBG Mobile in 2018, it’s the first to have been made by the game’s original developer, PUBG Studios. Development of the original PUBG Mobile was handled primarily by Chinese tech giant Tencent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZgTyPn"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Strong anti-cheat” measures have been promised&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aySGaS"&gt;PUBG Studios emphasizes that New State will come with “strong anti-cheat” measures at launch, and that the company will be actively monitoring the community to catch problems before they grow too widespread. The PUBG games have had big problems with cheaters in the past, with &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/93ywj3/inside-the-worlds-largest-video-game-cheating-empire"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Motherboard &lt;/em&gt;reporting&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year that one cheat-making group allegedly made over $70 million selling cheats for PUBG Mobile. PUBG is far from the only game to have had these problems, however. Other companies like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22724037/call-of-duty-ricochet-anti-cheat-system-kernel-level-driver"&gt;Activision&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22690670/epic-eac-anti-cheat-linux-valve-steam-deck-support-games"&gt;Valve &lt;/a&gt;have made news recently with their efforts to prevent cheating in their games and hardware, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uBZJMh"&gt;Like previous PUBG games, &lt;em&gt;New State &lt;/em&gt;is centered around multiplayer matches. Up to 100 players enter a map, and one player or squad emerges victorious. There’ll be four maps available at launch in &lt;em&gt;New State&lt;/em&gt;, including franchise staple Erangel, and PUBG Studios is promising to regularly update it with new content over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zjlDMD"&gt;Away from mobile, Krafton plans to release another PUBG-related game for PC and consoles by next year, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-01-18/coding-prodigy-behind-hit-game-pubg-eyes-ipo-worth-billions?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;reported in January&lt;/a&gt;. There are also plans for a new survival horror game set in the PUBG universe three centuries in the future, which will release in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HwakPS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s95wND"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/22/22740022/pubg-new-state-release-date-november-11-ios-android-mobile-game"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/22/22740022/pubg-new-state-release-date-november-11-ios-android-mobile-game</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
