<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-01-13T10:05:04-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T10:05:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T10:05:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s first major racial equity investments include a Detroit developer center and HBCU tech hub</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bqB2hEUoyV4fu7JPXwzaF6MrS50=/225x0:2655x1620/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68660972/apple_racial_equity_justice_initiative_propel_center_render_01132021_Full_Bleed_Image.jpg.large_2x.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A render of the Propel Center. | Image: Propel Center&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Trabhq"&gt;Apple is announcing &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fnewsroom%2F2021%2F01%2Fapple-launches-major-new-racial-equity-and-justice-initiative-projects-to-challenge-systemic-racism-advance-racial-equity-nationwide%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F1%2F13%2F22228580%2Fapple-detroit-developer-academy-equity-center-hbcu-tech-hub#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the next big investments&lt;/a&gt; to come out of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/11/21287999/apple-racial-equity-justice-initiative-amount-cook-lisa-jackson"&gt;$100 million commitment to racial equity and justice today&lt;/a&gt;: the launch of an Apple Developer Academy in Detroit; founding support for an Atlanta tech hub for historically Black colleges and universities; and new grants, scholarships, and investments for Black and brown students and entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YxDIzQ"&gt;The Apple Developer Academy in Detroit will be the “first of its kind in the US,” Apple wrote in a press release, after previously partnering on &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2019/05/16/apple-developer-academy/"&gt;a similar program&lt;/a&gt; in Italy. The academy is focused on “young Black entrepreneurs, creators, and coders” and will offer training in iOS app development. The plan is to offer a shorter 30-day program that introduces students to “what it means to be a developer” and then to offer an “intensive” 10- to 12- month program meant to help aspiring developers gain relevant skills to get tech jobs or start their own businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="g6ARRI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Propel Center will offer in-person and online courses&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WgMimC"&gt;Apple expects the academy to teach around 1,000 students each year. It’s supposed to open later in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1QmSuM"&gt;In Atlanta, Apple is partnering to help launch the Propel Center, a tech-focused hub for HBCUs. The center will offer in-person and online courses focused on technology, entertainment, and business. It’ll be located in the Atlanta University Center that links four HBCUs — Clark Atlanta University, Spelman College, Morehouse College, and the Morehouse School of Medicine. Apple and Southern Company, an Atlanta-based energy giant, will each contribute $25 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P64QZI"&gt;Other tech companies and major donors have made similar contributions to HBCUs over the past year. In September, &lt;a href="https://newsroom.ibm.com/2020-09-17-IBM-Establishes-First-Quantum-Education-and-Research-Initiative-for-Historically-Black-Colleges-and-Universities"&gt;IBM announced&lt;/a&gt; it was putting $100 million into technology, skill development, and other resources for HBCUs alongside the launch of an “IBM Quantum education and research initiative.” The same month, Michael Bloomberg &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/09/03/business/dealbook/bloomberg-black-medical-schools-donation.html"&gt;announced plans&lt;/a&gt; to give $100 million to four historically Black medical schools, focused on easing student debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6ew5eF"&gt;Apple also announced a number of new grants and investments today. It’s investing $10 million with Harlem Capital, a VC firm with the goal of “investing in 1,000 diverse founders over the next 20 years,” and $25 million in Siebert Williams Shank’s Clear Vision Impact Fund, which is focused on minority-owned businesses. Apple is launching grants for HBCU engineering programs and is expanding its scholarship program with a focus on underrepresented communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DZlE5d"&gt;Today’s announcements are part of a $100 million commitment Apple made in June 2020, as companies across the US began reflecting on how they could better combat racism following the death of George Floyd and protests against police brutality. Apple VP Lisa Jackson was put in charge of the initiative, which was meant to “challenge the systemic barriers to opportunity and dignity that exists for communities of color and particular for the black community,” Apple CEO Tim Cook said at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bn6s6v"&gt;Facebook, Microsoft, Google, and other tech giants &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21362540/racial-justice-tech-companies-donations-apple-amazon-facebook-google-microsoft"&gt;have made similar pledges&lt;/a&gt;, putting millions of dollars toward racial equity initiatives. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228580/apple-detroit-developer-academy-equity-center-hbcu-tech-hub"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228580/apple-detroit-developer-academy-equity-center-hbcu-tech-hub</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Chill imbibes: inside the booming business of relaxation drinks</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_hKt2bjm9511YYINaQn0KGw2Z0U=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68660919/VRG_ILLO_4363_RelaxationDrink_Lede.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Taking a dip in the new business of relaxation&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="Spnciz"&gt;After a long day, we all want to slow our heart rate and breathing, loosen our muscles, and lower our blood pressure. We want to calm the mind and body, decreasing tension. We want to interrupt our stress hormonal cascade, ultimately reducing our own hostility. We want to kick back and activate our parasympathetic nervous system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Q53Yx"&gt;You know, relax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="EPt3nj"&gt;&lt;q&gt;These drinks exist for your subclinical anxiety needs&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Pjng7n"&gt;That might mean yoga or a massage. Maybe we turn on gentle classical music or looping rainfall through our speakers. Maybe we take slow breaths or turn our fingers to prunes in the bath. But if some entrepreneurs have their way, it’ll mean cracking open a can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vT5Nej"&gt;These relaxation drinks aren’t uniform in form or taste, but they all make promises. Some offer sleep, others promote better focus and creativity. They are healthy and calming, at least according to their marketing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FO2aGQ"&gt;The idea seems to be that there’s plenty of stress that doesn’t quite hit the psychiatric level — and so these drinks exist for your subclinical anxiety needs. It seems like big business, given the rather crowded marketplace, which includes such brands as Tranquini, Just Chill, Drank, and Marley’s Mellow Mood. Pepsi will be getting into the market shortly, with its &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/09/14/pepsico-to-launch-drink-to-aid-sleep-as-consumers-struggle-with-stress.html"&gt;Driftwell beverage&lt;/a&gt;, which became &lt;a href="https://www.drinkdriftwell.com/"&gt;available online&lt;/a&gt; in December. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8Z9Ahh"&gt;So I decided to make a journey to the heart of relaxation. I wanted to see if I could overdose on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="ZWzfpr"&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="hVKCl0"&gt;I’m not going to tell you these drinks &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt; because there’s no evidence they do. I’m also not going to tell you they’re bullshit because there’s no evidence there either. Most of these products incorporate multiple ingredients that have more evidence when studied alone — but like, not &lt;em&gt;enough&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jSHaC0"&gt;Pepsi, like most major corporations, doesn’t take big risks, so I figured the components of its Driftwell beverage would be a good place to start. Pepsi chose to use l-theanine, a workhorse ingredient in relaxation drinks. &lt;a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28056735/"&gt;Some small&lt;/a&gt; studies &lt;a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26797633/"&gt;found that&lt;/a&gt; l-theanine may &lt;a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16930802/"&gt;reduce stress&lt;/a&gt;, induce relaxation, and make it easier for people to get &lt;a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25759004/"&gt;to sleep&lt;/a&gt;. Chanaka Kahathuduwa, an assistant professor at Texas Tech University, is responsible for several studies on the amino acid, both alone and combined with caffeine. Kahathuduwa found that l-theanine had an effect, though it appeared to be subtle. “I don’t think it’s equivalent to the current medications in use,” he tells me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/siecyfhZ2zrM8qWVMvqwPphMbHY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22231433/VRG_ILLO_4363_RelaxationDrink_DriftWell.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oYfzSn"&gt;Another common ingredient, also found in Driftwell, is magnesium. While some studies suggest that magnesium may help people with anxiety, the quality of evidence is poor, &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5452159/"&gt;according to a recent review article&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bnf7fv"&gt;For the companies that are more adventurous than Pepsi, there are other ingredients, like melatonin and CBD. Melatonin, which you’ve probably heard of, is a version of a hormone we all naturally make. It’s &lt;a href="https://www.consumerreports.org/vitamins-supplements/does-melatonin-really-help-you-sleep/"&gt;a widely used sleep aid&lt;/a&gt;, even though its uses are limited, and the American Academy of Sleep Medicine doesn’t recommend it as a treatment for insomnia. It shows up in Som Sleep, Dream Water, and Kin Dream Light. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wjHb3K"&gt;And then there’s CBD, arguably the bad-boy ingredient. There are &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4604171/"&gt;a few&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6326553/"&gt;early studies&lt;/a&gt; that show it may be useful for anxiety. However, it’s not, strictly speaking, legal to &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/public-health-focus/fda-regulation-cannabis-and-cannabis-derived-products-including-cannabidiol-cbd#dietarysupplements"&gt;sell CBD as a dietary supplement&lt;/a&gt;, per the Food and Drug Administration. It’s also &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/public-health-focus/fda-regulation-cannabis-and-cannabis-derived-products-including-cannabidiol-cbd#dietarysupplements"&gt;not legal to sell foods or drinks&lt;/a&gt; to which CBD has been added. Given the number of these beverages on the market, though, I suspect this prohibition is not being heavily enforced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZFuhr6"&gt;There’s one other thing that isn’t really listed on any of these labels. All of these concoctions are meant to make you relaxed or sleepy, which are subjective responses. That means we have the good ol’ placebo effect in play; on some level, these drinks don’t actually &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to do anything because if you anticipate them making you relax, you might just relax anyway. And the stronger your anticipation is, the stronger the placebo effect will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zcMHvZ"&gt;So in some sense, a key ingredient for all of these drinks is marketing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kyRaeM5pvUOLTUpSS4CmhCPuoXs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22229645/VRG_ILLO_4363_RelaxationDrink_Spot_01.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="3BhFsU"&gt;Faced with relatively scant scientific literature, I decide to self-experiment. Like pretty much everyone else who will show up in this story, I can charitably be described as “tightly wound.” Part of the reason relaxation drinks appeal to me is because, at the best of times, I’m wired and tense, &lt;em&gt;and these are not the best of times.&lt;/em&gt; Plus, I already self-medicate with beverages — what else would coffee be for? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="xkN6c9"&gt;&lt;q&gt;If I drink two in a row, I begin to feel like my brain has been wrapped in fleece&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ba1Ium"&gt;So I drop about $100 on drinks that promise to unwind me. Most of them have a distinct GNC vibe. For instance, Neuro Bliss’ packaging kind of looks &lt;em&gt;enough&lt;/em&gt; like a bottle of water to fool people; it contains 200mg of l-theanine. I get it in the white raspberry flavor, which immediately takes me back to blue-flavored ICEEs at my hometown Kum and Go. It is, by far, my favorite flavor of all the drinks I sample.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7blvNE"&gt;In fact, I like the flavor so much that I wind up drinking them a couple times a day. This is definitely more than the dosage I’ve seen in any controlled study, but whatever. If I drink two in a row, I begin to feel like my brain has been wrapped in fleece. It’s not quite the same as feeling &lt;em&gt;relaxed&lt;/em&gt;, but I do notice I’m less likely to lose my temper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D1jEht"&gt;I also seem to accomplish less. In fact, one of the things I come to muzzily realize while my brain is wearing its LL Bean Wicked Good slippers is that my capacity for work is directly tied to my ability to be focused but &lt;em&gt;not &lt;/em&gt;relaxed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q25qEy"&gt;This doesn’t stop me from moving on to Zenify — which contains 350 mg of l-theanine and GABA as well as 350mg of glycine, another amino acid. The drink kind of looks like bizarro Red Bull. I am trying to think of how to describe its taste, but besides “sweetened chemicals,” I’m drawing a blank. Because I don’t much care for the flavor, I wind up gulping down Zenify pretty quickly, which results in some genuinely monstrous burps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wj6opC"&gt;As part of my self-experiment, I decide to watch one of the 2020 presidential debates. I wind up knocking back three Zenifies, two Neuro Blisses, and a Som Sleep. This does not make the debate any less excruciating, unfortunately; so when moderator Kristen Welker brings up the question of “the talk” Black families give their kids about police officers, I find I am wringing my hands — unsure what President Donald Trump will specifically respond, but after his response to Charlottesville, pretty clear on the generalities. I pound the Zenify and crack another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ssoZ3z"&gt;By the end of the debate, I have only a dim impression of what happened and a stomachache. The stomachache lasts into the next day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="ZPdR91"&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="IWP0VV"&gt;Relaxation isn’t really about the ingredients in the drink, says Benjamin Witte, the founder and CEO of Recess. I had called to ask about the science behind his product, but he brushes my questions aside. Have I seen Recess’ Instagram page, he wants to know. “Recess’s Instagram is Recess you consume with your mind,” he tells me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lGVS6f"&gt;The Recess you consume with your mouth contains CBD, American ginseng, l-theanine, and lemon balm. But that’s not really important. See, the ingredients I just listed are commoditized functional ingredients, Witte explains. For instance, no one markets the “caffeine category” — they’re marketing how it makes you feel. &lt;em&gt;Energy drinks&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NcvXFT5lGKCsEVEzYEA0ncTzzjA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22231432/VRG_ILLO_4363_RelaxationDrink_Recess.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FwInWl"&gt;Recess’ marketing campaign, accordingly, is about feelings. Literally. “We canned a feeling,” the marketing copy reads. “Not tired, not wired. Just calm, and focused.” The cans are packaged in what appear to be jewel tones run through a pastel filter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1nIMV7"&gt;Witte, whose previous experience was at an early stage startup, AdRoll, has always been a stressed-out, anxious millennial, he tells me. And so he’d experimented with CBD and so-called adaptogens, which are typically plant-based and promise to help people deal with stress. (Whether they &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; do that is &lt;a href="https://www.self.com/story/read-this-before-spending-money-on-adaptogens-for-stress-relief-or-anything-else"&gt;something of an open question&lt;/a&gt;.) Eventually, Witte came across a combination that helped him feel more productive, more creative, less stressed out, and less anxious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IpfN50"&gt;Witte knew he wasn’t the only stressed-out millennial in search of the promised calm; he also knew that the CBD he used — a grassy oil placed under the tongue — is not the best user experience. And so he came up with Recess, a line that contains millennial-approved flavors such as black cherry, pomegranate hibiscus, blood orange, and blackberry chai. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fMyf9x"&gt;“New categories and platforms are correlated to things happening in society,” Witte says. He points to social media, in particular, as something that’s left people unsettled; Trump arguably exacerbated that unease, he says. In Witte’s view, the previous era was exemplified by Monster Energy Drink — a growth-at-all-costs mentality that was the hallmark of the go-go era of the first and second tech booms. By contrast, Recess is “a reflection of wellness, carbonated, but without sugar and calories,” Witte says. “This category is about creating products that help you deal with the world around you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sxzJvrx4fsF1VGrvJ93t27VwQVY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22229644/VRG_ILLO_4363_RelaxationDrink_Spot_02.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="xv5ke7"&gt;The stress Witte talks about also has an effect on sleep, which is why the relaxation drink category also includes beverages with melatonin. Som Sleep — which contains a 357mg “proprietary blend” of l-theanine, GABA, and melatonin — isn’t really for me. None of the sleep drinks are; I don’t have problems dropping off. So I chug one in the middle of the afternoon. It &lt;em&gt;does &lt;/em&gt;make me drowsy, but not so tired that I have to beg off work for a nap. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F0dw3f"&gt;“I live off energy drinks,” says Abdul Khan, the co-founder and president of Som Sleep. “So my lightbulb was, why isn’t there a Red Bull for sleep?”’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="a0ozEr"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Clearly, sleep is big business&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nzs3j4"&gt;Khan is capitalizing on the wellness movement also, I realize, though he’s doing it somewhat differently than Witte. A full night of sleep is actually a growth hack, a shortcut to the best version of yourself, Arianna Huffington &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2018/03/11/arianna-huffington-became-successful-after-she-started-sleeping-well.html"&gt;insists&lt;/a&gt;. Gwyneth Paltrow’s Goop has a &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fgoop.com%2Fwellness%2Fhealth%2Fhow-to-get-better-sleep%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22217197%2Frelaxation-drinks-recess-som-sleep-pepsi-branding#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;whole sleep section&lt;/a&gt;; it also sells books on sleeping, special pillows and sheets, and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fgoop.com%2Fgoop-wellness-knock-me-out%2F30-chews%2Fp%2F%3Fvariant_id%3D68899&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22217197%2Frelaxation-drinks-recess-som-sleep-pepsi-branding#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;“Knock Me Out” chews&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/followthenap/?hl=en"&gt;On Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, a man named Alex Shannon is a “&lt;a href="https://www.insider.com/instagram-influencer-travels-world-to-sleep-in-luxury-hotels-2019-9#he-still-has-plenty-of-places-that-hes-itching-to-explore-number-one-on-my-list-has-always-been-tokyo-and-ive-never-managed-to-make-it-there-shannon-said-ive-never-visited-asia-so-im-hoping-to-do-an-asia-trip-theres-so-many-others-ive-never-been-to-greece-iceland-brazil-australia-or-new-zealand-15"&gt;sleep influencer&lt;/a&gt;,” who uploads gorgeous photos of himself semiconscious in very luxurious beds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rQBQWo"&gt;Clearly, sleep is big business. Pepsi’s Driftwell, for instance, slots into this market — part of the reason it comes in a dinky 7.5-ounce size is so you won’t have to wake up in the middle of the night to pee. (I am &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/09/14/pepsico-to-launch-drink-to-aid-sleep-as-consumers-struggle-with-stress.html"&gt;not making this up&lt;/a&gt;: “According to [Emily] Silver [vice president at Pepsi’s North American beverages unit], it’s the perfect size for hydrating before bedtime without requiring another trip to the bathroom,” CNBC reports.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RmjM4E"&gt;I ask about the proprietary blend — after all, dosing matters, particularly with melatonin. Som Sleep contains 3mg of melatonin, Khan tells me, but he refuses to give the rest of the breakdown. Like Recess’ Witte, Khan also comes from the tech industry; he was a VC at Crosslink Capital where he led investments in Pandora, Ancestry.com, and Omn. Som is his first physical product. After brewing it in Mason jars and sharing it with some athlete friends, he realized he was onto something when the athletes kept coming back for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="15Zjrg"&gt;Unlike all the other drinks I try, there’s an &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2016/7/19/12165860/dietary-supplements-safety-efficacy-quality"&gt;NSF certification&lt;/a&gt; on the back of the can. NSF audits supplements to determine whether they contain what they say they contain — and it also looks for substances that have been banned by athletic organizations. That makes sense since Som Sleep sells to more than 60 pro teams, including those in the NBA, MLB, NFL, and NHL, according to Khan. Apparently, athletes really are just like us: dying to get a couple more hours of shut-eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="7ka29C"&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="XDmsje"&gt;Witte is right to point out that these beverages are products of our era; they may also be a response to a trend among &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2019/3/26/18267092/sober-curious-nonalcoholic-drinks-spirits"&gt;younger people to drink less alcohol&lt;/a&gt;. After all, the original relaxation drink is booze, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l2m5z9"&gt;These drinks are part of the “functional beverage” category, a way of grouping together non-boozy beverages with ingredients such as probiotics, vitamins, and so on. It’s a pretty broad category, one that includes sports drinks, energy drinks, and, of course, relaxation drinks. &lt;a href="https://www.thebusinessresearchcompany.com/report/functional-beverages-market-global-report-2020-30-covid-19-growth-and-change"&gt;One marketing report&lt;/a&gt; pegs the functional beverage category as growing to $158 billion by 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ieUTTKRIKGQXp2dqG5t5hHZPLOs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22231431/VRG_ILLO_4363_RelaxationDrink_SomSleep.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BZNHCH"&gt;And both Khan and Witte tell me sales are up in the pandemic. According to Witte, Recess’ direct-to-consumer sales have increased fourfold since the beginning of the pandemic, mostly through subscriptions. Som Sleep sales have jumped 15 to 20 percent each month in both retail and online, Khan says. COVID-19 has increased stress and uncertainty for basically everyone. I’m not the only one who’s trying out new ways to unwind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pgpwjE"&gt;Six Recesses, 12 Som Sleeps, 12 Zenifies, and 12 Neuro Blisses later, I find that the relaxation drinks omit what may be their greatest appeal: they let the consumer bypass the inconvenient parts of relaxing. You can’t meditate and work simultaneously. And establishing &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/sleep/about_sleep/sleep_hygiene.html"&gt;proper sleep hygiene&lt;/a&gt; — the best cure for most insomnia — can take weeks of devoted work. Deleting Facebook (or Twitter or Instagram or TikTok) is probably the simplest way to remove the stressors of social media, but most of us can’t bring ourselves to do it. We can’t or won’t give up the things that stress us out, so we’ve settled for just wanting to be less stressed out by them. And if the stress keeps us up at night, well, there’s a drink for that, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="bYmd0a"&gt;In this sense, the relaxation drinks aren’t that different from the energy drinks that inspired them. They take the edge off so that you can keep grinding or let you sleep well so you hustle harder. You could say that’s counterproductive, but to me, it sounds like a recipe for repeat customers.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22217197/relaxation-drinks-recess-som-sleep-pepsi-branding"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22217197/relaxation-drinks-recess-som-sleep-pepsi-branding</id>
    <author>
      <name>Elizabeth Lopatto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T09:50:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T09:50:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>Intel is replacing its CEO next month</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Z-uN9-qvJ80kh7EB1Zaj90l-5fk=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68660821/msedge_C71M2hMcRX.5.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Intel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1UcN5N"&gt;Intel CEO Bob Swan is stepping down from the position on February 15th, &lt;a href="https://newsroom.intel.com/news-releases/intel-appoints-tech-industry-leader-pat-gelsinger-as-new-ceo/#gs.qic5yl"&gt;the company has announced&lt;/a&gt;. He will be replaced by VMware CEO Pat Gelsinger. Swan was named Intel’s permanent CEO two years ago &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/31/18205142/intel-ceo-bob-swan-permanent-interim"&gt;in January 2019&lt;/a&gt;. He initially took on the role on an interim basis in June 2018 following the resignation of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/21/17488070/intel-ceo-brian-krzanich-resigns-employee-relationship"&gt;Intel’s previous CEO Brian Krzanich&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lZ0dn3"&gt;Gelsinger, who previously worked at Intel for 30 years, will step into the CEO role at a crucial time for the chipmaker. Intel is facing renewed competition across its portfolio. It sustained a serious blow last year when Apple announced it would be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/22/21295475/apple-mac-processors-arm-silicon-chips-wwdc-2020"&gt;transitioning its Mac lineup&lt;/a&gt; away from Intel’s processors and toward Apple’s own Arm-based designs. The first Macs based on Apple’s processors released late last year to a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/19/21574057/apple-m1-chips-laptop-performance-intel-qualcomm-competition"&gt;hugely positive response&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="56FFuC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Gelsinger previously served as Intel’s first CTO&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="q0nCOG"&gt;Meanwhile, Intel is also facing competition from a newly resurgent AMD, with Zen processors that offer competitive performance for gamers and professionals in both desktop and laptop computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4VsR7Y"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/01/13/intel-ceo-bob-swan-to-step-down-in-february.html"&gt;CNBC&lt;/a&gt;, which reported the news prior to its official announcement, notes that Swan had faced criticism for having a largely financial background, rather than a technical one. Prior to working at Intel, Swan served as eBay’s chief financial officer and has worked at the venture capital firm General Atlantic. In contrast, Gelsinger began his career at Intel and served as the company’s first chief technology officer. CNBC reports that Intel’s stock was up 10 percent on news of Gelsinger’s appointment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rutCdz"&gt;“The board is confident that Pat, together with the rest of the leadership team, will ensure strong execution of Intel’s strategy to build on its product leadership and take advantage of the significant opportunities ahead as it continues to transform from a CPU to a multi-architecture XPU company,” Intel’s independent board chair, Omar Ishrak, said in a statement, adding that the board appreciates Swan’s contributions to the company.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228702/intel-ceo-bob-swan-pat-gelsinger-technical-financial"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228702/intel-ceo-bob-swan-pat-gelsinger-technical-financial</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T09:18:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T09:18:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>What social networks can learn from public spaces</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="In this photo illustration, an ‘Account suspended’ message..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RVyqh0QdotfWzPIwxFhN1c2U2bE=/212x0:4499x2858/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68660639/1230540343.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Pavlo Gonchar/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="e5OFi8"&gt;In the aftermath of &lt;a href="https://www.platformer.news/p/three-questions-about-tech-after"&gt;the Great Deplatforming&lt;/a&gt; of the past week, we’ve seen a thoughtful debate over the power and limits of taking away a person’s ability to post online. It’s a blunt but powerful tool for punishing people who would use your platform to incite violence or commit other crimes. But building healthy, happy communities requires much more than removing their worst users. You don’t have a healthy media ecosystem just because Donald Trump no longer dominates it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wNWFY6"&gt;With that in mind — and in an effort to turn our attention to some constructive ideas after a terrifying week — today I want to talk about an effort to design better digital spaces. For those of you who work on platforms, or hope to someday, I hope it will spark a sense of what else could be possible in your work. And for those of us who live and work on these platforms, I hope the ideas shared here give us a better sense of what we could and should demand from the digital world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3M8fg2"&gt;The ideas come from &lt;a href="https://newpublic.org/"&gt;Civic Signals&lt;/a&gt;, a new nonprofit organization dedicated to building “flourishing, public-friendly digital spaces.” It’s led by Eli Pariser, author of the 2011 bestseller &lt;em&gt;The Filter Bubble&lt;/em&gt; and the co-founder of Upworthy; and Talia Stroud, director of the Center for Media Engagement at the University of Texas at Austin. For the past two years, they led an inquiry into what makes for good digital spaces. And on Tuesday, the first day of their inaugural &lt;a href="https://newpublic.org/festival"&gt;New Public Festival&lt;/a&gt;, they released the results of their research. (&lt;a href="https://newpublic.org/signals"&gt;You can find it all here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="J9zpZE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Imagine if a Facebook, or a Reddit, or a YouTube offered actual programming to these communities&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="din8e8"&gt;The research began with the observation that in the offline world, healthy communities have traditionally been served by thriving public spaces: town squares, libraries, parks, and so on. Like digital social networks, these spaces are open to all. But unlike those networks, they are owned by the community rather than a corporation. As you would expect, that difference results in a very different experience for the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fDdEWg"&gt;Public spaces display a number of features that build healthier communities, according to researchers. “Humans have designed spaces for public life for millennia,” they write, “and there are lessons here that can be helpful for digital life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IidvOf"&gt;Here’s a list (emphasis theirs). These spaces:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="mZpMMW"&gt;Develop &lt;strong&gt;programming&lt;/strong&gt; — social activities — that draw different groups in, without over-optimizing for any one group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jjUKv8"&gt;Offer visual &lt;strong&gt;cues as to what kinds of behavior are invited&lt;/strong&gt; in the space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="quv0Ou"&gt;Are designed to be physically accessible and &lt;strong&gt;attractive to many different populations&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="1nRWnM"&gt;Engage &lt;strong&gt;stewards, leaders, and maintainers&lt;/strong&gt; who can do the labor of community-building &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0KHwQm"&gt;Are designed in &lt;strong&gt;partnership with the communities that use them&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="dDYAMZ"&gt;Save for the third bullet point on that list, these are not features that I would associate with any of our largest social platforms. And that begins to explain, I think, the rot we find throughout them. Giant, rudderless communities left to imagine for themselves what they ought to do on a platform, or how they ought to behave, often turn on one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GPuLFl"&gt;Imagine if a Facebook, or a Reddit, or a YouTube offered actual programming to these communities — constructive, creative tasks that go beyond individual fundraisers or the creation of content. Would they not wind up with services that they were more proud of?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GYLbu5"&gt;It’s relatively easy to imagine what this might look like. Over the past couple of months, I’ve been captivated by the story of &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/legit/news/ratatouille-musical-actors-fund-1234881445/"&gt;the TikTok users who took it upon themselves to write a musical inspired by the Pixar film &lt;em&gt;Ratatouille&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It happened spontaneously — and raised $1.9 million for The Actors Fund — but there’s no reason other platforms couldn’t similarly goad their users into creativity, philanthropy, or other ends more compelling than the traditional like, comment, and share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wyBO2W"&gt;On Monday, I attended a virtual briefing with Pariser and Stroud to learn about their findings. While they began with drawing analogies to the physical world, their research ultimately explored the possibilities contained within digital-only spaces as well. Ultimately, the team identified 14 design principles for building better digital spaces. The principles are grouped into four categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="1WPIuu"&gt;Welcoming new users to the space and to conversations within it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="W6SlKC"&gt;Helping people to understand the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AEm5XB"&gt;Connecting people across hierarchies and divides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vbL4UP"&gt;Enabling people to act together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="r1vrWj"&gt;What I love about these principles is that they take a point of view on human behavior. Facebook’s mission “to give people the power to build community and bring the world closer together” reads somewhat similar to the bullet points above but is ultimately much less prescriptive about how the network ought to be used. The same could be said of Twitter’s mission to “serve the public conversation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="T63X6E"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We need private actors and more public platforms if we want all these needs to be met”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4pvglT"&gt;The centerpiece of the Civic Signals research is a survey of more than 10,000 platform “super users” around the world about how well they believe existing social networks live up to the design principles identified in the research. The results are a mixed bag, as you would expect — Facebook ranked high for cultivating a sense of belonging and inviting everyone to participate, but low for showing people reliable information or ensuring people’s safety. Twitter ranked high on building bridges between groups, but low for showing reliable information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fx8cBz"&gt;For Pariser and Stroud, the lesson is that better digital spaces are both necessary and possible. The question is whether the principles they’ve identified can be incorporated into existing platforms, or if they will need to be baked into a new project from scratch. And should that new project be a traditional venture-backed startup or a digital public space managed by a government or nonprofit community?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mNYHPd"&gt;When I asked them, they told me that they welcome experimentation. “We need private actors &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; more public platforms if we want all these needs to be met,” Pariser told me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gw0pCh"&gt;But perhaps because none has yet succeeded on a grand scale, it’s the prospect of a public digital space that intrigues me the most. It intrigues Pariser, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="On146H"&gt;“If you look at physical communities, there’s a reason that libraries are libraries and not venture-backed bookstores,” Pariser said. “They do different things. And those functions are really important as well.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hlti6c"&gt;Stroud noted that no existing platform had performed well across the board in its survey, suggesting that there could be significant demand for the sort of spaces envisioned by Civic Signals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WMXs32"&gt;“And some of these are really base-level things that you would want in a space,” Stroud said — things like protecting users’ safety, or their data, or simply making them feel welcome when they join. “I think there’s a lot of opportunity for innovation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DsNtIg"&gt;The New Public Festival continues online today and Thursday. You can attend virtually, and for free, &lt;a href="https://newpublic.org/festival"&gt;at this link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="EMBE4I"&gt;
&lt;p id="qN76Nj"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This column was co-published with &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.platformer.news/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Platformer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, a daily newsletter about Big Tech and democracy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tm2SWr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228208/social-networks-public-spaces-civil-signals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228208/social-networks-public-spaces-civil-signals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Casey Newton</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T09:04:09-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T09:04:09-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to watch the impeachment proceedings against President Donald Trump</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="capitoldome-congress" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UuMY_m55g-wQxjf4gF86AxkoqMI=/0x45:1024x728/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68660578/capitoldome-congress.1419979569.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;capitoldome-congress&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="63Yrpu"&gt;On January 13th, Congress will begin proceedings for the impeachment of President Donald Trump, based on his incitement of the January 6th mob attack on the US Capitol. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S72z93"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://assets.documentcloud.org/documents/20449065/house-impeachment-resolution-final.pdf"&gt;official articles of impeachment&lt;/a&gt;, filed Tuesday night, charge the president with “incitement of insurrection,” based on his comments to the crowd, as well as &lt;a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/georgia-election-brad-raffensperger-60-minutes-2021-01-10/"&gt;previous calls made to election officials in Georgia&lt;/a&gt; that sought to alter the state’s election results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jsdNeG"&gt;“He threatened the integrity of the democratic system, interfered with the peaceful transition of power, and imperiled a coequal branch of Government,” the articles allege. “He thereby betrayed his trust as President, to the manifest injury of the people of the United States.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NAKw3m"&gt;National guard troops have been &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/scottwongDC/status/1349356950157463554"&gt;deployed within the Capitol building&lt;/a&gt; to guard against any attacks that might disrupt the proceedings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="WWW9lr"&gt;When does impeachment begin?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="bLbncT"&gt;The House of Representatives began proceedings at 9AM ET, which will include debate over the articles followed by a vote. If the articles are approved by the House, they will be sent to the Senate to vote on removal; that vote has yet to be scheduled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="iYxjwA"&gt;How do I watch the impeachment proceedings?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="231RWP"&gt;C-Span has a live stream of the proceedings available &lt;a href="https://www.c-span.org/video/?507879-1/house-session"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. CNN has also &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bristei/status/1349150769421963265"&gt;pledged to lift its paywall&lt;/a&gt; for coverage of the debate and vote, which will be available at &lt;a href="http://CNN.com"&gt;CNN.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="lRjROX"&gt;Who is in charge of the impeachment proceedings?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ltFILM"&gt;House Speaker Nancy Pelosi &lt;a href="https://www.speaker.gov/newsroom/11221-0"&gt;has named nine Democratic House members&lt;/a&gt; as impeachment managers. The lead manager will be Rep. Jamie Raskin (D-MD), supported by Rep. Diana DeGette (D-CO), Rep. David Cicilline (D-RI), Rep. Joaquin Castro (D-TX), Rep. Eric Swalwell (D-CA), Rep. Ted Lieu (D-CA), Rep. Stacey Plaskett (D-USVI), Rep. Madeleine Dean (D-PA), and Rep. Joe Neguse (D-CO).&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228595/trump-impeachment-how-to-watch-congress-house-nancy-pelosi"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228595/trump-impeachment-how-to-watch-congress-house-nancy-pelosi</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T08:50:54-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T08:50:54-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google urgently investigating Android coronavirus tracking app issues</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CbM1vlpQu56y_n4WVClH9U3uLCc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68660442/acastro_180427_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XXhsVI"&gt;Google says it’s working quickly to investigate issues with Android apps that use the Android Exposure Notifications System to track the spread of COVID-19. An unknown issue is causing apps to take longer to load or conduct regular exposure checks. The NHS COVID-19 app that’s used across England and Wales is &lt;a href="https://github.com/nhsx/covid-19-app-android-ag-public/issues/39"&gt;affected by this Android issue&lt;/a&gt;, with a loading notification stuck in the notifications area for many users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ShOlj5"&gt;“We are aware of an issue affecting Android apps developed using the Android Exposure Notifications System,” says a Google spokesperson in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Our engineers are investigating the issue.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CANl41hv0gjAEgvFoXtqeg-yS-k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22232458/104391472_d3359b00_5537_11eb_96a2_002ba81410c6.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The NHS COVID-19 notification issue.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="W9M3fA"&gt;We understand that Google is working urgently to identify the source of these issues and correct them as soon as possible. These issues are affecting all apps worldwide that use the Android Exposure Notifications System.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bwDBQD"&gt;More than 10 million people in England and Wales downloaded the NHS COVID-19 app &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/nhs-covid-19-app-has-been-downloaded-over-10-million-times"&gt;in September&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s not clear how many total downloads have been made to date or the split between iOS and Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xXKmiC"&gt;Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/10/21216484/google-apple-coronavirus-contract-tracing-bluetooth-location-tracking-data-app"&gt;first introduced its coronavirus tracking system&lt;/a&gt; for Android in April 2020. The app uses Bluetooth to anonymously broadcast data and help enable track and trace programs worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228594/google-coronavirus-tracking-app-exposure-notifications-issues-problems"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228594/google-coronavirus-tracking-app-exposure-notifications-issues-problems</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T08:47:44-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T08:47:44-05:00</updated>
    <title>Ubisoft is making an open-world Star Wars game</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Visitors are seen at Disney’s Star Wars booth during the Ani..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZOWCR4aOehqjH9j7ALntjvXvV0A=/0x3:5000x3336/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68660438/1158661067.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Budrul Chukrut/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VOskeV"&gt;The studio behind &lt;em&gt;The Division&lt;/em&gt; is making a game set in a galaxy far, far away, according to &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/lucasfilm-games-star-wars-ubisoft-indiana-jones-bethesda/"&gt;a report from &lt;em&gt;Wired&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Today, Ubisoft announced that its Swedish studio Massive Entertainment is making an open-world video game that’s set in the &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dEdaR6"&gt;There are no details on when the game will launch, on what platforms, or what slice of the &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; universe it will explore. The game will be built using Ubisoft’s own Snowdrop engine, which is best known as the tech behind &lt;em&gt;The Division&lt;/em&gt; series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ozp2Vh"&gt;Earlier this week, Disney rebranded its game division to &lt;a href="https://www.starwars.com/news/lucasfilm-games"&gt;Lucasfilm Games&lt;/a&gt; for what it described as “a new era.” Since then, the company announced not only Ubisoft’s &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; game, but also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226966/bethesda-indiana-jones-game-machinegames"&gt;an Indiana Jones title from Bethesda studio MachineGames&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EId5vW"&gt;Previously, EA was the main developer behind blockbuster &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; titles, which resulted in games like the &lt;em&gt;Battlefront&lt;/em&gt; reboots, open-world adventure &lt;em&gt;Jedi: Fallen Order&lt;/em&gt;, and last year’s space combat game &lt;em&gt;Squadrons&lt;/em&gt;. Disney says that relationship will continue even as other developers work on Star Wars games as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ebKkmh"&gt;“We’re really proud of the games we have created with EA,” &lt;a href="https://www.starwars.com/news/lucasfilm-games-interview"&gt;Lucasfilm Games VP Douglas Reilly says&lt;/a&gt;. “We will continue working with them and our relationship has never been stronger. While we may not have a lot of details to share at the moment, we’ve got a number of projects underway with the talented teams at EA.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22227235/ubisoft-star-wars-game-massive-entertainment-lucasfilm"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22227235/ubisoft-star-wars-game-massive-entertainment-lucasfilm</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T08:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T08:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Headset maker Turtle Beach acquires Neat Microphones to expand beyond gaming</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nxJKHaZotNj-vCe3hP-kB7MarwM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68660366/akrales_190313_3227_0050.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Neat Microphones Beecaster and Bumblebee (not all of its mics are bee-themed)&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JOJtCP"&gt;Gaming peripheral company Turtle Beach is acquiring Neat Microphones, makers of eclectic-looking desktop USB microphones that stray from the industry standard. Neat’s leadership has plenty of experience in the market. They were the original founders of popular brand Blue Microphones, now owned by Logitech. Turtle Beach declined to share financial terms of the acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oEx2g0"&gt;In a press release shared with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, Turtle Beach CEO Juergen Stark says Neat’s technology will “further enhance our future industry-leading Turtle Beach and Roccat products.” Though the deal also represents Turtle Beach’s expansion beyond gaming with “[Neat’s] broader assortment of consumer and prosumer audio products.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FlMMlc"&gt;You may disagree, but I hope Neat gets to keep their unique design ID under Turtle Beach ownership. Neat’s microphones have an almost Teenage Engineering-esque aesthetic, yet they’re usually fairly affordable. My colleague and &lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;podcast producer Andrew Marino tested a few models in the quest to find &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/5/18295732/podcast-microphone-best-top-price-specs-features-rode-blue-shure"&gt;the best microphones for beginner podcasting&lt;/a&gt; and found quite a lot to like about them.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22226680/turtle-beach-acquiring-neat-microphones-podcast-roccat"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22226680/turtle-beach-acquiring-neat-microphones-podcast-roccat</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T07:38:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T07:38:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>T-Mobile’s network will stop working with over a dozen older phones this month</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f7eqJrWXt0x20yYDyDbJNuNArt4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68660149/acastro_191108_1777_t-mobile_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zQTF5X"&gt;Over a dozen devices including the original OnePlus 1 and Sony Xperia Z3 won’t be able to connect to T-Mobile’s network from January 29th, the carrier has announced in &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fsupport%2Fcoverage%2Fnetwork-upgrade-device-compatibility&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F1%2F13%2F22228540%2Ftmobile-network-shutdown-devices-january#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a support document&lt;/a&gt;. T-Mobile says this is the result of a network update, and that the affected devices are not able to receive a software update to allow them to stay connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K9kJIB"&gt;“As a result of a network update going into place on 1/29/2021, we identified a small number of older devices that are not able to receive a manufacturer software update and as a result, these devices will be unable to establish a network connection,” the document reads. “T-Mobile and Metro customers utilizing these older devices will lose all network connectivity if they do not replace their device.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="cCILWN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“These devices will be unable to establish a network connection”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="K1Sqr6"&gt;It’s not clear exactly what it is about this network update that means these older devices can no longer function. &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/01/08/these-are-all-the-devices-t-mobile-says-will-stop-working-on-its-network-next-month/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which reported the news based on internal documents, initially said it related to a requirement for devices to support voice over LTE (VoLTE). However, T-Mobile says this is not the case, and says the change is not related to the shutting down of any legacy network. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zh9QHn"&gt;Here’s the full list of devices T-Mobile says will no longer work from January 29th. Note that they’re all older devices, with the most recent being 2016’s Huawei P9 according to &lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="hsCjKB"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T or Verizon Galaxy Note 4  (T-Mobile branded version will still work, but needs a software update)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="36zReg"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T Galaxy Note Edge &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qg0Q5d"&gt;HTC Desire 10 Lifestyle &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZZmrHQ"&gt;HTC Desire 650 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="61hUVp"&gt;Google Nexus 9 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lYawxw"&gt;Huawei Mate 8 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jg1UOZ"&gt;Huawei P9 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="91f4re"&gt;Mikrotikls SIA R11e-LTE6 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="52MrtR"&gt;OnePlus 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="5g6GsQ"&gt;Quanta Computer Inc Quanta DragonIR7 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Lij8Lz"&gt;Samsung Galaxy S5 Duos &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WLBMuY"&gt;Sony Xperia Z3 Compact &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="5U046p"&gt;Sony Xperia Z3 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nqCiCe"&gt;Sony Xperia Z3 Orion &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qCSJMO"&gt;Sony D6616 Xperia Z3 Orion &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Bwn4Xy"&gt;Soyea Mobile Communication Equipment Co Ltd SOYEA M02 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="tco9I2"&gt;ZTE ZMAX &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="ddkZBR"&gt;T-Mobile’s site also provisionally includes the Arlo Security Camera System on its list, but adds that it’s in talks with Arlo about a possible solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5IAJAs"&gt;T-Mobile reportedly started informing affected customers of the changes by post on December 18th, followed by sending SMS messages on December 28th. Additionally, &lt;em&gt;Android Police &lt;/em&gt;reports that the move will also affect Sprint customers with affected devices, who’ll lose the ability to roam on T-Mobile’s network. However, T-Mobile or Metro by T-Mobile subscribers are thought to be the only ones losing &lt;em&gt;all &lt;/em&gt;network connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="87t9LS"&gt;T-Mobile says affected customers should contact it to arrange an upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AXHTpv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QMTl0t"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228540/tmobile-network-shutdown-devices-january"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228540/tmobile-network-shutdown-devices-january</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T07:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T07:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>CES 2021 Day 2: here come the gaming laptops</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Razer Blade 15 Advanced" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1NxhXOk8TF8grWncToTww4BD8mc=/1x0:3652x2434/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68660086/blade15hero.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Razer Blade 15 Advanced | Razer&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qCBjay"&gt;Yesterday, AMD and Nvidia took to the CES virtual stage to announce their respective updates. AMD headlined with a new series of CPUs, the 7nm Ryzen 5000 series, that is going to be a really compelling gaming laptop option. Nvidia headlined with new graphics for laptops, bringing some performance that was previously exclusive to desktop machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pWa3fM"&gt;With all the parts from AMD, Nvidia, and Intel out, the laptops made up of those parts were free to be announced. And so we had a very, very large pile of gaming laptops to sift through from Asus, Razer, Acer, Lenovo, Gigabyte, Dell, and Origin. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BrATYj"&gt;They’re all linked below and taken in sum I am optimistic that it is going to be a very good year for gaming laptops. I wouldn’t go so far as to say that you won’t still notice some graphical compromises — of course desktops will be better — but the ones that sting the most could be smoothed over. Getting legitimately high frame rates at 1440p with respectable graphics settings is more than I honestly expected out of 2021. (Assuming, of course, that any of these computers live up to those claims in actual use.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="eaX7P3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9028921"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ryq24r"&gt;Those laptops and the components that power them were the biggest &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; news yesterday, but CES is just as much about &lt;em&gt;concepts. &lt;/em&gt;Specifically concept gadgets that are almost guaranteed to never land on store shelves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wi7Vry"&gt;Are they attention-seeking vaporware? Quite often. 2021 may be TCL’s year to flex, but it’s also a year for it to engage in a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22225446/tcl-rollable-phone-extendable-display-concepts-ces2021"&gt;weird flex — by showing off two more of its rollable, extendable display concepts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ow8o3c"&gt;Are concepts worth a look if only to get a sense of what might actually be released someday? Actually, maybe yes! &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226532/lgs-rollable-phone-launch-release-date-ces-2021"&gt;LG, for example, claims that its Rollable phone is real and launching in 2021&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Razer Project Hazel" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Jnx4UmRFWu7CkemWUzDgnv5oDn4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228437/hazelnight.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Razer&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="J0b2HI"&gt;Razer’s concept mask: Project Hazel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="LxXVYo"&gt;Then there’s the concept that by all indications (including reader attention on our website) has won the show: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22221344/razer-project-hazel-n95-respirator-mask-coronavirus-chroma-rgb-concept"&gt;Razer’s concept N95 mask with RGB and voice projection&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TNVuwz"&gt;I will admit, when I first saw that Razer had a concept mask with gamer-themed color lights I was not happy. My fear for this entire CES has been that a major company would try to take advantage of the pandemic to gather attention to itself with a gadget that isn’t scientifically sound. CES is always awash in dubious health tech, but the risk of people believing in bad health tech seems even higher this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b0guIU"&gt;But then, well, it seems like Razer has thoughtfully considered a lot of the very real problems masks cause and tried to account for them. It looks like one of those actually-unsafe vented masks, but those vents have filters the company wants to make N95-grade. It’s clear, so people can read your lips. It will have some sort of audio system (with help from THX) that will solve for the muffled voices masks can cause. It should seal tightly against your nose to help with fogging glasses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3oPnKT"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FvWiCclESL8?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JrqCBd"&gt;All that sounds neat — neater than RGB lights anyway. But neat does not equal real, and this is very much like a concept car to my mind. In the &lt;a href="https://press.razer.com/product-news/razer-unveils-smart-mask-and-gaming-chair-concept-designs-at-ces-2021/"&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;, Razer’s language not only skirts the issue of a price and release date, it also skirts the issue of releasing a mask with this exact design at all:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="ZIfxKZ"&gt;The smart mask concept will continue to be optimized through rigorous testing and user feedback to ensure safety compliance and maximum comfort and usability. Design improvements will also be ongoing to support the evolving user needs and to deliver value without compromising functionality and performance. Project Hazel will be foundational to Razer’s ongoing support and commitment to public health and safety within the community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="pvTPMI"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22221344/razer-project-hazel-n95-respirator-mask-coronavirus-chroma-rgb-concept"&gt;company told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that it is “working with a team of medical experts and scientists,” but if Razer decides to actually produce and sell this mask, I expect — and you should demand — that it seek the “necessary approvals and certifications from the Food and Drug Administration, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, or Occupational Safety and Health Administration.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fmWJTt"&gt;As a rule, I am more generous than most when I see a CES concept because I know what they really are: fantasies with a purpose. Some of that purpose is absolutely marketing, but some of it is to show us ideas for products that are more imaginative or better than what’s available today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D1A55e"&gt;Motives — especially when it comes to corporate beneficence— don’t need to be and rarely are pure. Just because Razer grabbed our attention with RGB lights doesn’t undo the good of converting a production line to making masks and then donating a million of them to healthcare workers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="99wlu8"&gt;Of course, no amount of engineering can solve the biggest mask problem in the US: too many people are refusing to wear them. Please: wear a mask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="LdSfsN"&gt;AMD&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="1256011616"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22225474/amd-ryzen-5000-series-mobile-processors-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMD’s 7nm Ryzen 5000 mobile processors promise 2021’s best gaming notebooks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; AMD is building on the gains it made last year and appears to be pushing to establish itself as a CPU fixture in the laptop market instead of a somewhat rare alternative. Though as my colleague Monica Chin points out to me, that rarity was due in part to the fact that models with AMD chips seemed to be in short supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TKza3b"&gt;I think the company has a very good chance of doing just that. I will leave a full-on “AMD vs. Intel” analysis for somebody else (or at least wait for real-world results once laptops start shipping), but it doesn’t take a genius to see that AMD is not to be dismissed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Job5pQ"&gt;In other words: 2021 could be the year we stop thinking about Ryzen as an alternative to Intel, but instead just a straight up competitor again. Intel could be at risk of no longer being the “default” to a lot of potential customers. That’s not to dismiss Intel entirely, as Chin notes we still need to see what laptops with Tiger Lake H chips are like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="nIFXQt"&gt;AMD has announced its new Ryzen 5000 mobile CPUs. Most (but not all) of them are based on the company’s 7nm “Zen 3” architecture. AMD CEO Lisa Su called the series “the most powerful PC processors ever built.” ... The big question will be how these processors compare to Intel’s new Tiger Lake H systems — the company announced those chips yesterday at its CES 2021 keynote. All three of those chips (including two Core i7s and one Core i5) max out at 35W and have just four cores and eight threads — half the count of Ryzen’s top offerings. However, Intel says there’s an eight-core processor with speeds up to 5GHz coming “later this quarter.” That’s likely what AMD has to watch out for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="1255994951"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227144/amd-rdna-2-gpu-gaming-laptops-release-date-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMD says RDNA 2 GPU-powered laptops will arrive in the first half of 2021&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="QHPd6x"&gt;RDNA 2 is AMD’s new graphics chip architecture and the foundation of the custom chipsets in Sony’s PlayStation 5 and Microsoft’s Xbox Series S / X, and now it’s coming to laptops. ... The Radeon RX 6000 series of GPUs were the first to feature AMD’s new RDNA 2 architecture when they were unveiled in October of last year, but those were top-of-the-line desktop graphics cards designed to go head-to-head with Nvidia’s 3000 series line. ... Today at CES, AMD CEO Lisa Su said the company is “on track to launch the first notebooks with RDNA 2 in the first half of the year with our partners,”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="tweet-text"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227638/amd-threadripper-pro-available-directly-to-consumers"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMD will be letting consumers buy the Threadripper Pro directly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;. &lt;/strong&gt;This is definitely for professional use. As &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/1349132593619460098"&gt;Tom Warren notes&lt;/a&gt;, “64 cores, 128 threads, and 2TB of memory all sounds amazing until you realize the processor alone is $3,990.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1256020013"&gt;Nvidia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="1256007449"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226544/nvidia-rtx-3080-laptops-gpus-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nvidia is bringing its RTX 3080 to laptops on January 26th&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Nvidia showed a demo of a Razer Blade 15 running a full three-screen rig with &lt;em&gt;Microsoft Flight Simulator&lt;/em&gt;, which is a very good sign that many of the planned 70+ laptops with these GPUs will have the goods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="8gSxY4"&gt;Less than six months after introducing its RTX 3000 series GPUs for desktop PCs, Nvidia is bringing the RTX 3060, RTX 3070, and RTX 3080 to gaming laptops. Nvidia is promising big energy efficiency gains here, thanks to its new Ampere architecture, alongside the obvious performance improvements over the previous RTX 2000 series laptops.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="nQWnM7"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226546/nvidia-geforce-rtx-3060-specs-price-release-date"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nvidia announces $329 GeForce RTX 3060, available in February&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1256007905"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226560/nvidia-resizable-bar-support-intel-amd-smart-access-memory-feature"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nvidia answers AMD’s Smart Access Memory with its own boost to frame rates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="kla7gk"&gt;Laptops&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="jqqW1u"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/1/12/22227043/swedish-metal-band-lenovo-legion-5i-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We gave this laptop a 7, then a Swedish metal band turned it up to 11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; This has nothing to do with CES and is related to a laptop that’s half a year old. But just... just watch this. Trust me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CZpSBR"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22215119/razer-blade-15-17-laptops-screens-graphics-gaming-price-release-date"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Razer’s 2021 Blade laptops are getting QHD screens and Nvidia’s RTX 3000-series graphics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="PUSF5o"&gt;Until recently, 1080p and 4K were the only options for displays on gaming laptops, despite 1440p being an increasingly popular choice among PC gamers looking for a new standalone monitor. ... The higher-end Blade laptops will be equipped with Nvidia’s new RTX 3000-series graphics chips, and so should have an easy time running most games on a 1440p high refresh rate display. The Blade 15 Advanced (Razer’s name for the more powerful variant) with the RTX 3070 and a QHD screen with G-Sync will cost $2,499.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="RFBPeU"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227383/asus-zephyrus-g14-g15-gaming-laptops-ryzen-price-specs-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asus updates Zephyrus G14 and G15 with latest AMD and Nvidia chips&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; I bought a G14 last year myself and agree with Monica Chin, it was one of the best. These updates look solid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1256007188"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227013/lenovo-legion-7-slim-5-pro-gaming-laptops-amd-ryzen-5000-cpu-nvidia-rtx-gpu-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lenovo’s new Legion gaming laptops go all in on AMD’s latest Ryzen chips&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aQUezT"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22218681/acer-nitro-5-gaming-laptop-intel-11th-tiger-lake-h35-amd-ryzen-rtx-3080-qhd-release-date-price"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acer’s latest Nitro 5 gaming laptop seems more powerful than ever&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1256006774"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22225902/acer-aspire-5-7-laptops-amd-ryzen-5000-series-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acer announces AMD Ryzen-powered Aspire 5 and Aspire 7 laptops&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1256006546"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227004/acer-predator-triton-300-se-ultralight-gaming-laptop-intel-nvidia-rtx-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acer’s new Predator Triton 300 SE is an ultrapowerful, ultralight gaming laptop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Chaim Gartenberg:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="wKZ1jR"&gt;Acer is ditching the garish, colorful lights and logos on the Predator Triton 300 for a more restrained — dare I say, professional — all-metal design that wouldn’t be out of place in an office or a classroom, while still offering top-notch gaming hardware on the inside.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="1255997411"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227273/dell-alienware-m15-m17-gaming-laptops-nvidia-rtx-3000-gpu-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dell updates its Alienware m15 and m17 laptops with Nvidia’s new RTX 3000 GPUs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5ooTwd"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22224929/gigabyte-gaming-laptops-a5-a7-g5-announced-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gigabyte announces new midrange gaming line powered by AMD’s Ryzen processors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1255997267"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226043/gigabyte-aero-aorus-nvidia-rtx-3000-laptops-gaming-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gigabyte’s latest Aero and Aorus laptops include RTX 3080 and OLED options&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oQd7iS"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227598/origin-evo15s-evo17s-gaming-laptops-nvidia-rtx-3000-gpus-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Origin updates EVO15-S and EVO17-S with new RTX 3000 series GPUs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="A83SCb"&gt;Weird laptops&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="1256018597"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226031/lenovo-thinkbook-plus-gen-2-e-ink-lid-display-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lenovo’s ThinkBook Plus Gen 2 has an even bigger and better E Ink display on the lid&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="7G43OJ"&gt;The ThinkBook Plus debuted at last year’s CES, standing out as a laptop with an E Ink display built into the lid that allowed users to take notes, read ebooks, and display things like calendar information. ... The new model improves on that, though, with a 12-inch, 2560 x 1600 E Ink panel that supports multitouch and works with the pop-out stylus, creating what should be a more enjoyable E Ink experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="NVmeeK"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226223/asus-rog-flow-x13-zephyrus-duo-15-se-gaming-laptop"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asus ROG’s 2021 lineup includes its first convertible gaming laptop (ish)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; This is a weird one. Gaming laptops are usually neither convertible not 13 inches. Then there’s the GPU situation, which also involves some ...let’s call them &lt;em&gt;choices&lt;/em&gt;. However, if you want a gaming laptop that can do double or triple duty for other laptop things, it may be worth understanding those choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1256019830"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="NApQw1"&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id="HiIb5d"&gt;GM&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="tTN44O"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226098/gm-chevy-bolt-electric-car-tease-super-cruise-release-date"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GM teases new Chevy Bolt with Super Cruise, sets release date for February&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="C0aQIS"&gt;The refreshed Bolt will feature a sportier look, new seats, adaptive cruise control, and a few other minor changes. GM bumped up the range in this past year’s version of the Bolt, from 238 miles to 259 miles, but no further increase is expected in the refresh. ... The new Bolts can’t come quick enough, given the controversy surrounding the current versions of the EV. GM was recently slapped with a class action lawsuit alleging that the Chevy Bolt’s battery is “prone to burst into flames.” The lawsuit comes on the heels of GM announcing that it was recalling 68,000 Bolts over a malfunctioning battery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="1256018834"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226778/gm-flying-car-cadillac-halo-av-evtol-concept-autonomous-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GM surprises with autonomous Cadillac and flying car concepts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; It wouldn’t be CES without some weirdo car concepts, and thankfully Cadillac has delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="q3LwjN"&gt;The automaker showed off a luxury egg-shaped autonomous vehicle and a single-seater electric vertical takeoff and landing (eVTOL) aircraft during its keynote address on Tuesday. Both vehicles are part of Cadillac’s Halo Portfolio and probably won’t be going into production anytime soon — or at all. ... Still, the concepts are meant to show off Cadillac’s (and, by extension, GM’s) design intentions for future products, as well as serving as an extravagant symbol of the brand’s manufacturing skills.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="1256018714"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226760/gm-cadillac-celestiq-electric-luxury-tease-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GM teases Cadillac Celestiq EV with adjustable glass roof and full-width touchscreen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; This is definitely a tease, not a reveal. But the adjustable glass roof looks cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1256018843"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22227810/ces-2021-day-2-amd-nvidia-razer-mask-gaming-laptops"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22227810/ces-2021-day-2-amd-nvidia-razer-mask-gaming-laptops</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
