<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-09T10:31:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T10:31:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T10:31:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sony is reportedly remaking The Last of Us for PS5 as it chases big hits</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Last of Us" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jSEmvqxAZ33gWRcjWMbLzm4FdWk=/75x0:885x540/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69101182/2013_06_13_LaunchDayPost_960p.0.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jmzqvn"&gt;Sony is reportedly working on another remake of Naughty Dog’s &lt;em&gt;The Last of Us&lt;/em&gt; — first released in 2013 for the PlayStation 3, followed by a PlayStation 4 remaster in 2014. The latest version of the game is intended for the PlayStation 5 and would reportedly feature the gameplay and graphical improvements introduced in 2020’s &lt;em&gt;The Last of Us Part II&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-04-09/sony-s-obsession-with-blockbusters-is-stirring-unrest-within-playstation-empire?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gKWoJT"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reports the remake’s status is part of a broader reorganization at Sony’s first-party development studios, which are struggling with the conflicting goals of the company’s desire for larger, blockbuster-scale projects from its major studios and the smaller, less lucrative passion projects from its smaller teams. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wrqlRc"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Last of Us&lt;/em&gt; remake is one such project. The remake was originally started by Sony’s Visual Arts Service Group, an internal team that largely provided support work for art, animation, and development to Sony’s other studios on bigger projects like &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man &lt;/em&gt;or the &lt;em&gt;Uncharted&lt;/em&gt; games. But the Visual Arts Service Group aspired to work on its own games, and it figured that lower-cost remakes of popular Sony franchises would be a good place to start — &lt;a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/sonys-secret-san-diego-team-what-are-they-working-on.342760/"&gt;leading to rumors last year&lt;/a&gt; of a “secret” new Sony studio in San Diego. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zB6rL2"&gt;But Sony reportedly largely ignored those efforts. It tentatively approved the Visual Arts Service Group’s remake project but refused to give the team an expanded budget for the remake. The project was then moved back to series creator Naughty Dog, where it’s apparently still in development — with the Visual Arts Service Group assisting, as usual. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BpKaWg"&gt;It’s worth noting that all these projects are still apparently fairly early on, so there’s plenty of time for Sony’s plans here to change regarding if, when, or how these games actually are released. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FsG16y"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;’s report notes similar issues with Sony’s Bend Studio, the developer of &lt;em&gt;Days Gone. &lt;/em&gt;The Bend team reportedly tried to pitch a sequel to the open-world zombie game but was rejected — instead being tasked with helping Naughty Dog on a multiplayer project and a new &lt;em&gt;Uncharted&lt;/em&gt; game. Bend’s leadership was apparently so concerned about being fully absorbed into Naughty Dog’s team that it asked to be removed from those projects; it’s now reportedly working on a new game of its own. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wb49d1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375262/sony-remake-the-last-of-us-ps5-studio-reorganization-report"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375262/sony-remake-the-last-of-us-ps5-studio-reorganization-report</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T10:20:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T10:20:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>Grab a full year of PlayStation Plus for only $27</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TmbFu6W9uMU8K9gbMzbPjRfdkd0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69101117/vpavic_4261_20201023_0104.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;PlayStation Plus is available for both PS4 and PS5 owners&lt;/em&gt;.  | Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hiK2Qq"&gt;If you managed to get your hands on a PS5 — or you own a PS4 — and you want to renew your PlayStation Plus membership, Eneba is offering a great deal, with an added discount to readers of &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. Now until Sunday, April 11th, if you’re in the United States you can grab a &lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=20387&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=VergeDeals04062021&amp;amp;clickref2=verge&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.eneba.com%2Fus%2Fpsn-playstation-network-card-psn-365-days-usa-psn-key-united-states" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;one-year subscription to PlayStation Plus for $27.30&lt;/a&gt;. And &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; readers in the US can get an extra discount of $2.37 by entering the code &lt;strong&gt;APRILVERGE &lt;/strong&gt;at checkout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5u5tDo"&gt;PlayStation Plus is a great subscription for PS4 and PS5 owners. Aside from the ability to play non-free-to-play titles online with friends, a subscription to the service also includes regular discounts to the PlayStation Store, a list of free games each month, and if you own a PS5, you get access to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/16/21440388/playstation-plus-collection-ps5-ps4-games-titles"&gt;PlayStation Plus Collection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dz6tZD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9734577"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8ytVxE"&gt;Even though the first-generation Oculus Quest is nearly two years old, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21437674/oculus-quest-2-review-features-photos"&gt;with a successor already available&lt;/a&gt;, it is still a good VR headset that does not require a console or gaming PC. You can get the &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=43993&amp;amp;u1=vergedeals&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oculus.com%2Fquest%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;original Quest headset for $199&lt;/a&gt; at Oculus’ direct website. This price nets you a refurbished model in “as good as new” condition, 64GB of storage, and a one-year warranty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="KFoaqk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10375901"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="B7VGkv"&gt;As part of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22372126/halo-mouse-keyboard-xbox-master-chief-collection-mcc"&gt;a new April patch&lt;/a&gt;, you can now fire up your Xbox One or Series X / S and have the option to play &lt;em&gt;Halo: The Master Chief Collection&lt;/em&gt; with a mouse and keyboard. If you need a copy of the game, you can grab a digital copy of &lt;em&gt;The Master Chief Collection&lt;/em&gt; for $20 at &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fp%2Fhalo-the-master-chief-collection%2F9MT8PTGVHX2P%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%3Aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FHalo-Master-Chief-Collection-Microsoft-Studios-Xbox-Digital-Download%2F239267489%3Fwmlspartner%3Dwlpa%26selectedSellerId%3D0&amp;amp;subid1=VergeDeals04082021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zOX49t"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10248487"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uutgx3"&gt;Speaking of exclusive discounts for &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; readers, 1Password is offering a big discount on a family subscription to its service until Thursday, April 15th. Normally $5 per month, &lt;strong&gt;new users&lt;/strong&gt; can get &lt;a href="https://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8836598-14464697?sid=VergeExclusive1PDeal040121&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2F1password.com%2Ffamilies%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a one-year subscription for half the price&lt;/a&gt;, bringing the monthly price down to $2.50. You’ll find the discount when you create your account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OX1NFX"&gt;1Password’s family subscription grants up to five people (not restricted in your household) individual access to 1Password’s services, such as password management and 1GB of storage, which you can use to store sensitive documents and information securely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jeUJEz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10437502"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="tooYsA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/4/9/22374100/playstation-plus-one-year-subscription-ps4-ps5-oculus-quest-1password-deal"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/4/9/22374100/playstation-plus-one-year-subscription-ps4-ps5-oculus-quest-1password-deal</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T10:03:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T10:03:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>One side effect of the COVID-19 vaccine could be a heavier period  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Feminine hygiene articles" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZqG6AOc1EM_9HV6Lu2h4_f6RopA=/0x4:4674x3120/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69101014/1229921264.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Annette Riedl/picture alliance via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GyvRpd"&gt;Katharine Lee got her COVID-19 vaccination early on in the United States’ rollout. So did a friend of hers — they got their shots on the same day. They compared notes, curious to see what the side effects would be. Lee, a research fellow in the Division of Public Health Sciences at Washington University in St. Louis, says that they both had one surprising symptom: they both started their period soon after they took the vaccine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vkBXJb"&gt;“It wasn’t a symptom that was on the list,” she says. “I expected that my arm would be sore, or that I might have a fever or a headache, but this just wasn’t on the list.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RdGACl"&gt;Lee reached out to Kate Clancy, who studies the menstrual cycle at the University of Illinois, to share the observation. When Clancy got her vaccination, she also had an unusual period. So she posted on Twitter asking if other people did, too — and watched dozens of responses roll in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="cIi9YN"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;A colleague told me she has heard from others that their periods were heavy post-vax. I'm curious whether other menstruators have noticed changes too? I'm a week and a half out from dose 1 of Moderna, got my period maybe a day or so early, and am gushing like I'm in my 20s again.&lt;/p&gt;— Dr. Kate Clancy  ️‍  (@KateClancy) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/KateClancy/status/1364671490772320259?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 24, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="79Rk7t"&gt;“It made us want to capture those experiences,” Lee says. So this week, the pair launched a &lt;a href="https://redcap.healthinstitute.illinois.edu/surveys/index.php?s=LL8TKKC8DP"&gt;formal study&lt;/a&gt; to collect data about the relationship between the COVID-19 vaccines and the menstrual cycle. It’s not a side effect that clinical trials checked for, and it’s not included on the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention’s vaccine health check-in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RN8dhK"&gt;There isn’t much research on how vaccination affects menstruation. But vaccines do stress the immune system, and the menstrual cycle sometimes responds to those types of changes. “The menstrual cycle is really dynamic, and it responds to tons of things,” Lee says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jr2Vas"&gt;There’s also a potential relationship between the nanoparticles used in the COVID-19 vaccines and changes in bleeding patterns. In some people, the nanoparticles end up creating a temporary immune reaction that kills off platelets, a type of blood cell involved in clotting, Clancy says. They regenerate quickly, but if someone has a bleeding event like a period just after they get a shot, it could make it heavier. She’ll be collaborating with Anirban Sen Gupta, a platelet researcher at Case Western Reserve University, to try to understand that potential mechanism. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NNHdSf"&gt;If it turns out that there is a relationship between the vaccines and the timing of a person’s menstrual cycle, that doesn’t mean there’s something wrong or dangerous about the vaccines themselves. It would most likely be a temporary side effect, and probably wouldn’t have effects on fertility, Lee stressed. It wouldn’t be that different from other side effects that crop up with the vaccines, like a fever or headache. But it’s important to have a full understanding of what kinds of reactions the vaccinations can cause so that people are as informed as possible about what they might experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e88Czo"&gt;“It really sucks to be surprised by your period,” Lee says. “It’s nice to know that it could happen, in the same way that it is knowing that you might have a fever and headache.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="H0pHJM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It really sucks to be surprised by your period”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tFe2eN"&gt;Similarly, unusually heavy periods are generally something people should be concerned about — they can be a sign that something is wrong, Clancy says. Knowing that it’s a possible effect of the vaccine could make the experience less concerning. On the other hand, if the research shows that there isn’t a strong link to vaccination, it may mean that people who do have this experience need to go to the doctor to make sure there isn’t something else wrong. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x3lfVA"&gt;People are eager to share their stories on this survey, Clancy says. Within a day of launching the survey, there were already over 700 responses. They’re hoping to better understand how people’s periods are changing and the characteristics of people having those experiences — their age, gender, underlying health conditions, or other factors. They’re also tracking the timing. Clancy says she suspects that people who get the shot just before their period is supposed to start might be more likely to see heavy bleeding. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i7PGb7"&gt;Right now, Lee says they’re hoping the survey fills a knowledge gap around menstruation and the vaccines. People have discussed their experiences on social media, but it hasn’t appeared in any scientific literature. Lee says she isn’t surprised. It took until the ‘90s for women to be regularly included in clinical trials of any kind, and some of those lingering biases remain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NLqG2h"&gt;“These are just not things some people think about. It’s not part of their daily lived experience. I think a lot of it is related to that history, and the bias around who gets to decide what’s important to consider as a side effect,” she says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HGwgrq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22374523/covid-vaccine-period-heavy-survey"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22374523/covid-vaccine-period-heavy-survey</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T09:49:26-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T09:49:26-04:00</updated>
    <title>How an offshore wind boom in the US could boost ocean research </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Block Island Wind Farm" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ych5GHmlvw4vy2pCrDu9oPh_Tbo=/0x97:4596x3161/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69100880/695950446.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;LOCK ISLAND, RI - JUNE 13: The Block Island Wind Farm off the coast of Block Island, RI is pictured on Jun. 13, 2017. | Photo by David L. Ryan/The Boston Globe via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aQDagO"&gt;The US wants to use offshore wind farms to collect valuable data on climate change and ocean health. Renewable energy giant Ørsted recently signed a memorandum of agreement with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), agreeing to help the agency gather data in US waters leased to the company&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; NOAA &lt;a href="https://www.noaa.gov/media-release/noaa-signs-data-share-agreement-with-offshore-wind-energy-company"&gt;says the agreement&lt;/a&gt; “paves the way for similar data-sharing agreements with other developers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wJsezC"&gt;The Biden administration plans to dramatically &lt;a href="https://www.commerce.gov/news/press-releases/2021/03/us-secretary-commerce-gina-m-raimondo-announces-efforts-advance"&gt;expand&lt;/a&gt; the country’s offshore wind capacity. The US currently only has 42 megawatts of capacity from two relatively small projects on the East Coast. If the Biden administration makes good on its commitment to offshore wind development, that’ll grow this decade to 30,000 megawatts coming from wind farms across both East and West coasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="odkD0p"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Each new wind farm could also boost the agency’s ability to track the effects of climate change&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eR6fnu"&gt;That growth should help the US slash its greenhouse gas emissions and avert a deeper climate crisis. The new agreement puts forward a smaller but still significant benefit for research; each new wind farm could also boost the agency’s ability to track the effects of climate change that are already here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="isoduX"&gt;“Having more data sharing and more sampling from the wind developers is going to help us, wherever there are wind development projects, to understand that bigger picture,” says Carl Gouldman, director of the NOAA Integrated Ocean Observing System program office. Conducting research at sea gets costly, so partnerships like the one with Ørsted can help fill in gaps in NOAA’s ocean observations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jrSfUR"&gt;The memorandum outlines broad areas of research with which Ørsted will help NOAA. Ørsted agreed to share data on air and water quality, marine life, meteorology, as well as coastal and ocean currents and waves. It will also collect data to better map the sea and study its physical properties. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yKmlBs"&gt;They haven’t hashed out many specifics yet, but one area Gouldman is excited about is weather data. Weather forecasting could get better, for example, thanks to LIDAR data Ørsted collects. LIDAR, or Light Detecting and Ranging, can map an environment by shooting out laser pulses. The technology &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/7/21055011/lidar-sensor-self-driving-mainstream-mass-market-velodyne-ces-2020"&gt;helps self-driving cars “see,”&lt;/a&gt; but in this case LIDAR is used to take a profile of wind speed in the atmosphere. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xVUpKj"&gt;“We’re thrilled to hear that they’re going to be willing to share that data,” Gouldman says. “A couple of years back we heard things like, ‘well, the companies won’t want to share that because it’s proprietary data that they’re going to want to hold for themselves.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I8FVK2"&gt;Ørsted collects additional data using buoys and vessels that conduct surveys for future wind farm projects, a spokesperson for the company said in an email. It also has a glider that gathers oceanographic data used for storm forecasting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RCeigc"&gt;The first wind farm in the US at &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/future-energy-is-blowing-in-wind/"&gt;Block Island&lt;/a&gt;, operated by Ørsted, is ideally located for studying the effects of climate change at sea and even onshore. It’s just 13 miles off the coast of Rhode Island, which is &lt;a href="https://www.usgs.gov/center-news/northeast-warming-faster-rest-us#:~:text=Rhode%20Island%20is%20heating%20up,for%20regional%2Dscale%20climate%20modeling."&gt;heating up more rapidly&lt;/a&gt; than much of the rest of the United States. Scientists are still trying to understand why the &lt;a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0168697#sec001"&gt;Northeast is the fastest warming region&lt;/a&gt; in the continental US. One culprit could be &lt;a href="https://www.usgs.gov/center-news/northeast-warming-faster-rest-us#:~:text=Rhode%20Island%20is%20heating%20up,for%20regional%2Dscale%20climate%20modeling."&gt;warmer water in the Atlantic ocean&lt;/a&gt;, which can raise temperatures inland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="bBSfDB"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Scientists are still trying to understand why the Northeast is the fastest warming region&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4hZzhd"&gt;After announcing plans last month to expand offshore wind development and data collection, Secretary of Commerce and former Rhode Island Governor Gina Raimondo said in a &lt;a href="https://www.commerce.gov/news/press-releases/2021/03/us-secretary-commerce-gina-m-raimondo-announces-efforts-advance"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt;, “These actions illustrate the Department’s commitment to innovative partnerships to advance the best science and data that will ensure the development of offshore wind is transparent and inclusive of all stakeholders.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dh1sdQ"&gt;Separately from its agreement with Ørsted, NOAA is also &lt;a href="https://www.fisheries.noaa.gov/feature-story/new-tool-available-explore-effects-offshore-wind-fisheries"&gt;studying the potential impact&lt;/a&gt; that offshore wind development could have on marine life. It’s using an &lt;a href="https://www.fisheries.noaa.gov/feature-story/scientists-collecting-data-commercial-fish-species-wind-energy-lease-areas-0"&gt;autonomous underwater glider&lt;/a&gt; to study Atlantic cod and other species found off the Southern New England coast, for example. The agency provides data and analyses to the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management, which issues leases to companies for offshore wind development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c0hH97"&gt;NOAA also agreed to share some of its own data with Ørsted. It has 10 to 15 years of data on current velocities on the East Coast, which it says would help developers understand how ocean conditions might affect wind farm construction. Ironically, new wind farms might interfere with the high-frequency radar stations used to gather that data. So NOAA is looking into whether it can add sensors to wind turbine stations to bolster that effort, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iQ1ZcA"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2gq7vG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375290/offshore-wind-energy-us-ocean-research-noaa-orsted"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375290/offshore-wind-energy-us-ocean-research-noaa-orsted</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T09:25:26-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T09:25:26-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung tries to woo iPhone users with a browser-based Galaxy test drive</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w-tL5rT3tnAniP5hRb7OXfcVVG8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69100721/DSCF0384_result.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung’s iTest site on an iPhone 12 Pro.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Jon Porter / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Y70C9m"&gt;Samsung has released &lt;a href="https://www.itest.nz/"&gt;a new website&lt;/a&gt; to give iPhone users “a little taste of Samsung” from their mobile browser. When visited on an iPhone, the site prompts users to add it to their phone’s home screen, after which it turns into a shortcut to a simulated Samsung Galaxy device. The site appears to be the work of Samsung New Zealand, &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/04/08/samsung-itest-galaxy-device-iphone-experience/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacRumors &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pqyLej"&gt;The experience might be limited, but it’s a neatly designed bit of marketing. Open up the camera “app” and a video will automatically play featuring influencer Logan Dodds, who describes Samsung’s camera app features in the interface around him. Poke around the other “apps” in the home screen and Samsung happily markets its phone’s other features and accessories, while text messages and even a fake phone call outline others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8yqhwHjJNLmEPaYlw_596woOS5E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22431983/IMG_0574.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot: iTest.nz&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A tooltip from the settings app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SoB9n6iGmuve8gHxjCxLgYflnkg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22431982/IMG_0573.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot: iTest.nz&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are fake contacts in the message app to text.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nCrW3d"&gt;There are also a couple of Easter eggs thrown in if you dig a little deeper. I particularly liked finding the “Friends with kids” contact in the text message app, who sends you garbled nonsense whenever you send them a message. Pry too much into the settings app and you’ll be shown a tooltip that reads, “We’ve simplified the settings menu experience, just so our developer could have a lunch break.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7jgXzj"&gt;Samsung is targeting the experience squarely at iPhone users. Try to visit the site with another Android phone and you get a message that says, “You’re on Android already,” while if you try to visit using a desktop browser the site gives you a QR code to scan with your iPhone. Yes, it’s ultimately just a bit of marketing, but it’s more creative than most other smartphone ads out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZRwl3z"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U12vbn"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375287/samsung-itest-galaxy-test-drive-emulator-iphone"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375287/samsung-itest-galaxy-test-drive-emulator-iphone</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T07:53:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T07:53:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>I’m salivating over this new four-volume Philip K. Dick collection by the Folio Society</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IW-TE6zanU9vW-QmRFobZxA0Kuo=/100x0:1180x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69100273/maxresdefault.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eugdg6"&gt;The Folio Society has released a &lt;a href="https://www.foliosociety.com/uk/the-complete-short-stories.html"&gt;limited-edition, four-volume set&lt;/a&gt; of Philip K. Dick’s collected short stories and I am seriously considering selling my plasma to buy a copy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lg2Yux"&gt;Each volume is bound in fluorescent colors, with 2,560 pages of text containing some 118 stories. There are 24 illustrations by 24 different artists, and the set itself has a theme inspired by the symbols found on &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zener_cards"&gt;Zener cards&lt;/a&gt; — famously used throughout the 20th century to test for telepaths (mind-reading being a recurrent theme in Dick’s fiction).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8XPpBC"&gt;The collection is absolutely stunning, like so many special editions by The Folio Society, but has a hefty price-tag of £495 ($679). There are also only 750 copies available to buy and it looks like they’re selling out quick. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="EUBEEz"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YfLlxcY4F6w?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="C0Ggf8"&gt;Philip K. Dick is an undisputed titan of science fiction, and I’ve long been a particular fan of his short stories. Not just because they contain some of the genre’s most iconic tales but because they also offer a capsule history of Dick himself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="EqPMmR"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Philip K. Dick’s short fiction tells the story of his career as a writer&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8tirnG"&gt;He was famously prolific as a writer, and lived at a time when it was possible to earn a decent living pumping out quick fiction hits. He published four stories in 1952 and then accelerated to publish 30 in 1953. (His love of amphetamines also contributed to this prolific output.) A sense of writing as drudgery bleeds into Dick’s stories, which often feature resentful toilers, like the tire regroover in &lt;em&gt;Our Friends from Frolix 8&lt;/em&gt; who takes bald, worn-out tires and carves fresh grooves into them with a red hot iron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LZ02LR"&gt;Despite the grinding nature of the work, Dick’s fiction is endlessly imaginative. His short stories are still being retold today, and are particularly beloved by Hollywood. “We Can Remember it for You Wholesale” became 1990’s &lt;em&gt;Total Recall&lt;/em&gt;; the 1956 short “The Minority Report” was turned into the 2002 Tom Cruise blockbuster of the same name; while the  “Adjustment Team” became 2011’s &lt;em&gt;The Adjustment Bureau, &lt;/em&gt;and so on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="FHZiaT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10437324"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="e9IDBA"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4wD6TeIkBFg?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vp8rrk"&gt;As we progress through Dick’s career into the ‘70s, and ‘80s his output slows. In 1974, Dick famously experienced a series of visions in which an entity that was perhaps God, but which he dubbed the Vast Active Living Intelligence System or VALIS, “fired a beam of pink light directly at him, at his head, his eyes.” His stories from this era, particularly his novels, consequently move away from standard sci-fi tropes into post-modern themes, delving into slipstreams of consciousness, alternate realities, and hidden, unbelievable truths. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gz9obQ"&gt;Reading through Dick’s short fiction chronologically offers its own narrative: the story of this magnificent writer and thinker. The Folio Society’s new set looks like a fabulous accompaniment to this intellectual history. Now excuse me, I have some Googling to do about “infallible get rich quick schemes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XYi3nU"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BbQblv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375173/philip-k-dick-complete-short-stories-folio-society-edition"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375173/philip-k-dick-complete-short-stories-folio-society-edition</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T07:00:47-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T07:00:47-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung reportedly inks deal to buy OLED TV panels from rival LG Display</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5U3314OuYNet2bMCJP9OA29F0z8=/120x0:1302x788/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69100165/LG_OLED_TV_Lineup.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: LG&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fApiIr"&gt;Samsung Electronics is close to ordering millions of OLED TV panels from LG Display, according to &lt;a href="https://m.mtn.co.kr/news/news_view.php?mmn_idx=2021040910490127790"&gt;new reports from &lt;em&gt;MTN&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.etnews.com/20210409000074"&gt;&lt;em&gt;ETNews&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;a href="https://www.sedaily.com/NewsVIew/22L0NM8RQV"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seoul Economic Daily&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Officials reportedly met recently to agree to the deal, which would see 1 million panels supplied to Samsung in the second half of this year, rising to 4 million panels next year. If the deal is finalized, it would be the first time Samsung has bought OLED panels from its South Korean rival and market leader. TVs with LG’s OLED panels consistently rate amongst the best in professional reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TrJYhP"&gt;Samsung exited the OLED TV market &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-samsung-elec-tv/how-samsung-fell-behind-sony-and-lg-in-the-premium-tv-market-idUSKBN1I24K2"&gt;over half a decade ago&lt;/a&gt;. Today, LG Display supplies OLED panels to a variety of TV manufacturers including Sony, Vizio, and Hisense, as well as LG Electronics. Last year &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/24/21336883/lg-display-oled-panel-manufacturing-plant-tv-china-lcd"&gt;LG Display announced an expansion&lt;/a&gt; of its OLED production lines, and market research firm &lt;a href="https://en.yna.co.kr/view/AEN20210409008400320?section=news"&gt;TrendForce says&lt;/a&gt; its production capacity is due to further increase in the second quarter of this year. &lt;em&gt;MTN&lt;/em&gt; reports that LG Display’s total OLED TV panel production capacity is around 8 million units this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZzVJ5P"&gt;Today’s reports are the latest indication of Samsung’s shift away from LCD panels, which it currently uses across its television lineup. Even its QLED TVs still use LCD panels behind that quantum dot layer. Last year &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/31/21200859/samsung-display-ending-lcd-panel-production-quantum-dot-oled-south-korea-china-factories"&gt;Samsung Display announced&lt;/a&gt; it would stop producing LCD panels in the face of stiff price competition from Chinese competitors, however it &lt;a href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/samsung-lcd-production-shut-down-postponed/"&gt;reportedly postponed this shutdown&lt;/a&gt; after the pandemic led to a rise in demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="3U4AX5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Rising LCD prices are reportedly to blame&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Wjw2Pd"&gt;While falling LCD panel prices were believed to be behind last year’s move, &lt;em&gt;MTN&lt;/em&gt; reports that the trend is reversing this year. LCD panels are reportedly growing more expensive, prompting Samsung to explore alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1DGm5p"&gt;While Samsung Electronics plans to buy panels from LG Display, its own display division is believed to be working on Quantum Dot OLED (QD-OLED) TV panels. A report from &lt;a href="http://www.thelec.net/news/articleView.html?idxno=2590"&gt;South Korean publication &lt;em&gt;The Elec&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; this week says Samsung Display is currently working on a prototype TV using the technology, which will be sent to potential customers like Samsung Electronics after it’s produced in June. However, QD-OLED panel samples sent to Samsung Electronics in January was reportedly criticized for their low brightness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K3xetE"&gt;QD-OLED isn’t the only new display technology on Samsung’s horizon. It recently commercialized a new display type called Micro LED, which uses an array of tiny self-emissive LEDs to produce an image. Although Samsung has released the technology in a &lt;a href="https://news.samsung.com/global/samsung-microled-opens-a-new-era-of-breathtaking-picture-quality-and-design"&gt;series of ultra-high end TVs&lt;/a&gt;, it’s believed to be years away from being affordable enough for mass-market sets. There are &lt;a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/samsung-develops-method-for-self-emissive-qled/"&gt;also reports&lt;/a&gt; that the company is working on self-emissive quantum-dot TVs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RLQLBN"&gt;When asked about the potential deal &lt;a href="http://it.chosun.com/site/data/html_dir/2021/04/09/2021040902225.html"&gt;in an interview&lt;/a&gt;, Samsung Electronics Jong-Hee Han, who oversees the company’s display division, dismissed the reports as rumors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xpx1zE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KKeBsb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375179/samsung-electronics-lg-display-oled-tv-panels-quantum-dot-qd"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375179/samsung-electronics-lg-display-oled-tv-panels-quantum-dot-qd</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T05:38:53-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T05:38:53-04:00</updated>
    <title>Airplane takes off a metric ton heavier than expected after computer error weighs adults as children</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Disturbance of air traffic by drones" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MRXa7kDnpmHpMe3GpFA8rq2KZzE=/74x0:3638x2376/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69099955/1231725546.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Boris Roessler/picture alliance via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wh1FQZ"&gt;A flight from the UK to Spain took off with more than a metric ton of unexpected weight after a software error classified female passengers using the title “Miss” as children. This led to the flight’s load sheet estimating the weight of 38 female passengers as 38 kg or 77 pounds each, the standard weight for children, instead of 69 kg or 152 pounds, the standard weight used for female adults. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ePt20H"&gt;The error was classified as a “&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/aaib-reports/aaib-investigation-to-boeing-737-8k5-g-tawg-21-july-2020"&gt;serious incident&lt;/a&gt;” by the UK’s Air Accidents Investigation Branch (AAIB) but did not affect the flight’s safety. Despite a discrepancy of 1,244 kg (2,743 pounds) between the expected and actual mass of the aircraft, the thrust used in takeoff by the pilot was only “marginally less” than what was required. “This meant the safe operation of the aircraft was not compromised,” concluded the AAIB. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="knLFYD"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“This meant the safe operation of the aircraft was not compromised”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5A9bFR"&gt;The error was introduced to the software after the flight operator suspended operations for several months due to COVID-19 restrictions. During this time, it upgraded its IT systems, but in the country where the software was programmed, the honorific “Miss” is used for children while “Ms” is used for female adults. The error affected two more flights from the same operator that same day, July 21, 2020, before it was corrected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b7ZxG3"&gt;According to a report by the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/apr/09/tui-plane-serious-incident-every-miss-on-board-child-weight-birmingham-majorca?CMP=Share_iOSApp_Other"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Press Association&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the flight was operated by Anglo-German company Tui. In statement the company said: “The health and safety of our customers and crew is always our primary concern. Following this isolated incident, we corrected a fault identified in our IT system. As stated in the report, the safe operation of the flight was not compromised.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375136/airplane-flight-takes-off-heavier-than-expected-miss-ms-children"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375136/airplane-flight-takes-off-heavier-than-expected-miss-ms-children</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-09T04:27:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-09T04:27:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple says iMessage on Android ‘will hurt us more than help us’  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CF0be5uHxP1MU1ILYSxxsJAbT9Q=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69099875/akrales_190513_3338_0008_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vBZmZy"&gt;Apple knows that iMessage’s blue bubbles are a big barrier to people switching to Android, which is why the service has never appeared on Google’s mobile operating system. That’s according to depositions and emails from Apple employees, including some high-ranking executives, revealed in &lt;a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.cand.364265/gov.uscourts.cand.364265.407.0.pdf"&gt;a court filing&lt;/a&gt; from Epic Games &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22373826/epic-games-v-apple-fortnite-app-store-antitrust-lawsuit"&gt;as part of its legal dispute&lt;/a&gt; with the iPhone manufacturer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UVNGvI"&gt;Epic argues that Apple consciously tries to lock customers into its ecosystem of devices, and that iMessage is one of the key services helping it to do so. It cites comments made by Apple’s senior vice president of Internet Software and Services Eddie Cue, senior vice president of software engineering Craig Federighi, and Apple Fellow Phil Schiller to support its argument. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="oKuZvO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Three questions that will decide Epic v. Apple","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22373826/epic-games-v-apple-fortnite-app-store-antitrust-lawsuit"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="32yjX7"&gt;“The #1 most difficult [reason] to leave the Apple universe app is iMessage ... iMessage amounts to serious lock-in,” was how one unnamed former Apple employee put it in an email in 2016, prompting Schiller to respond that, “moving iMessage to Android will hurt us more than help us, this email illustrates why.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="tLvPQo"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“iMessage on Android would simply serve to remove [an] obstacle to iPhone families giving their kids Android phones”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AWdybq"&gt;“iMessage on Android would simply serve to remove [an] obstacle to iPhone families giving their kids Android phones,” was Federighi’s concern according to the Epic filing. Although workarounds to using iMessage on Android have emerged over the years, none have been particularly convenient or reliable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pj5gKJ"&gt;According to Epic’s filing, citing Eddie Cue, Apple decided not to develop iMessage for Android as early as 2013, following the launch of the messaging service with iOS 5 in 2011. Cue admits that Apple “could have made a version on Android that worked with iOS” so that “users of both platforms would have been able to exchange messages with one another seamlessly.” Evidently, such a version was never developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SwsUJV"&gt;Along with iMessage, Epic cites a series of other Apple services that it argues contribute to lock-in. Notably, these include its video chat service FaceTime, which Steve Jobs announced &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JOxf9tEXEKQ"&gt;would be an open industry standard&lt;/a&gt; back at WWDC 2010. FaceTime subsequently released across iPhones, iPads, and Macs, but it’s not officially available for any non-Apple devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xS2O37"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q968OH"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BEF7T5"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375128/apple-imessage-android-ecosystem-lock-in-epic-games-filings-app-store-dispute"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22375128/apple-imessage-android-ecosystem-lock-in-epic-games-filings-app-store-dispute</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-08T21:13:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-08T21:13:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>Imposters steal restaurants’ names in delivery app deception</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Proposed Ban On Bluefin Tuna Rejected At World Trade Conference" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/crSKkdQjNjFO_ioyVWIjJ-A910Y=/62x0:2939x1918/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69098988/97868336.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Justin Sullivan/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0PU7a0"&gt;Ordering delivery through an app like DoorDash or GrubHub saves the trouble of cooking and lets you be a little picky — you can order from your favorite restaurant. But imagine receiving your food, sitting down to eat, and it tasting... &lt;em&gt;different&lt;/em&gt;. And then, following your gut, you learn that you’ve been duped by a fake, an imposter restaurant that stole its name. For many people ordering from two Japanese restaurants in San Francisco, that exact thing may have happened, &lt;a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/food/restaurants/article/On-Doordash-these-S-F-sushi-spots-look-like-16078920.php"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The San Francisco Chronicle&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="irTysa"&gt;One restaurant, now styled as an izakaya called Chome, originally opened for delivery and takeout in the former location of Blowfish Sushi. Except it didn’t bother to change the name, awning, or logo at the start. Chome, operating as if it were Blowfish Sushi, served sushi to people ordering through apps like GrubHub, Postmates, DoorDash, and Uber Eats using the identity of a restaurant that closed in December 2020. Before it closed, Blowfish Sushi had been serving its neighborhood for two decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6GE5mv"&gt;Blowfish’s former owner, Jason Teplitsky, was not exactly thrilled. “How does someone decide to do something like this? Did they think we all got COVID and died?” Teplitsky tells the &lt;em&gt;Chronicle&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/G-MTes26QnTrdE7PnbcyWWMjTak=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22430912/Screen_Shot_2021_04_08_at_3.28.42_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Wagyumafia&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Perhaps unsurprisingly, the real Wagyumafia is famous for its use of wagyu beef &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="WyYK82"&gt;Another fake restaurant, SF Wagyumafia, shares the name of &lt;a href="https://www.wagyumafia.com/"&gt;a famous sandwich shop&lt;/a&gt; known for its $180 wagyu sandwich and locations in Tokyo and Hong Kong. This San Francisco restaurant has no connection with the actual chain, according to the real Wagyumafia, but it was advertising the $180 sandwich. The fake was convincing enough to initially fool one food writer, the&lt;em&gt; Chronicle&lt;/em&gt; writes. When you’re ordering through an app without any real way to gauge what you’re getting into, what can you do but take a restaurant at its word?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2dPCu7"&gt;At first glance, both these restaurants might seems like &lt;a href="https://www.eater.com/21540765/ghost-kitchens-virtual-restaurants-covid-19-industry-impact"&gt;ghost kitchen schemes&lt;/a&gt; gone awry. They’re seemingly focused on delivery, readily accessible through the most popular apps, and of an unknown origin. But blatantly copying other well-known restaurants to the point that people mistake one for the other, or think a classic has suddenly reopened, seems more like straightforward fraud. The new “Blowfish Sushi” even registered as Blowfish with the city of San Francisco, which makes it seem like the owner knew what they were doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PvmEC3"&gt;Teplitsky and the original Wagyumafia are considering legal action, according to the &lt;em&gt;Chronicle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KCALkR"&gt;In response to the concerns over both restaurants’ legitimacy, DoorDash and GrubHub have removed Wagyumafia and Blowfish Sushi from their listings,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/food/restaurants/article/DoorDash-and-Grubhub-removed-imposter-S-F-sushi-16081842.php"&gt;the&lt;em&gt; Chronicle&lt;/em&gt; writes&lt;/a&gt;. I wasn’t able to find a listing for either restaurant on Postmates or Uber Eats, either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LyBNPb"&gt;DoorDash, Postmates, GrubHub, and Uber Eats either didn’t respond to our questions about how they verify restaurant listings in the first place, or weren’t able to tell us whether they have any specific protections to keep one restaurant from stealing another restaurant’s name. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N9Xiig"&gt;GrubHub did reply with a generic description of its practices:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="KsmjA0"&gt;We have no tolerance for misconduct or misuse of the Grubhub platform. We have a number of safeguards in place to prevent potentially fraudulent listings on our marketplace and we are constantly improving our processes and testing new features to prevent these situations. In the case of any listings that might be fraudulent, we immediately investigate and remove them from the marketplace if they’re in fact fraudulent. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="DW1LML"&gt;And DoorDash provided something similar:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="31h5RR"&gt;&lt;em&gt;At DoorDash, we work to ensure that we are always offering the highest quality of service to merchants, Dashers and customers. We take these types of allegations seriously and we’ve suspended the Merchants from the platform as we investigate the matter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="0JO8Gg"&gt;In GrubHub’s case, it says fraud like this isn’t widespread, but says it’s unable to explain exactly how it prevents fraudulent listing because doing so would potentially make its methods no longer useful. Typically these companies check banking and tax information to setup payments, so there are some required details that could potentially corroborate a restaurant’s identity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nh67RE"&gt;Fake restaurants aren’t the only surprises potentially awaiting you in food delivery apps: some legitimate brands have also tried to entice diners by changing their name for delivery. Remember, that pizza you purchase from Pasqually’s &lt;a href="https://www.thrillist.com/news/nation/chuck-e-cheese-pasquallys-pizza-wings-new-menu"&gt;actually comes from Chuck E. Cheese&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WG33Q2"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update April 8th, 11:39PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added statement from DoorDash.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TtmKaR"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22374341/imposter-restaurants-doordash-grubhub-ghost-kitchen-wagyumafia-blowfish-sushi"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22374341/imposter-restaurants-doordash-grubhub-ghost-kitchen-wagyumafia-blowfish-sushi</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
