<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-16T17:04:15-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-16T17:04:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T17:04:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Acer’s Nitro XV272U QHD gaming monitor is a steal at $300</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ogPiWHPrsOvfvPn5wkMqW_ZXSco=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68827256/cfaulkner_210201_4392_0014.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The monitor in question is on the left-hand side. Taken for the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.theverge.com/22264684/remote-work-desk-home-set-up-cameron-faulkner-acer-lg-tech-reporter" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;“What’s on your desk?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; series&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9PUFTP"&gt;PC gaming is an expensive hobby, so I wouldn’t blame you if you’re trying to save some money here and there. To that end, if you’re looking for a QHD gaming monitor that’s affordable and loaded with features, Acer’s Nitro XV272U might have your name on it. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07MQBPMJ2?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;It costs $300 at Amazon right now&lt;/a&gt;, which is the cheapest you’ll find it online. This isn’t the first time it has seen this discount, but I always want to tell people about it when it resurfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A7knTv"&gt;I actually purchased this monitor the last time it was on sale because it met all of my requirements at a fraction of the price I expected to pay. It’s a 27-inch IPS panel in 1440p resolution with a 144Hz refresh rate and Nvidia G-Sync compatibility. I’ve seen a lot of other monitors on the market with these specs for around $400–500, but it was a delight to find all of this for $300.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gBKPob"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10346110"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lQFF4C"&gt;After using it for over a month, I can say it was easily worth the money. All monitors are different, though, and I think Acer’s color calibration isn’t stellar out of the box. But after some toggling with settings, it’s looking nice next to my 27-inch LG UltraGear gaming monitor, which I also got on sale. Bargain shopping!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="qcF5kt"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/2/16/22286158/acers-nitro-xv272u-gaming-monitor-g-sync-1440p-qhd-amazon-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/2/16/22286158/acers-nitro-xv272u-gaming-monitor-g-sync-1440p-qhd-amazon-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-16T17:03:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T17:03:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple won’t have to allow App Store alternatives on iOS after North Dakota bill fails</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NbKvVmsB-rnvL4XA1KzSwsgTMA0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68827252/acastro_180130_1777_0005.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mWGwSx"&gt;A North Dakota bill that would have drastically altered the way app store operators like Apple and Google manage their digital marketplaces has failed to garner enough votes, failing in the state senate by an 11-36 vote on Tuesday, according to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/karlarosehanson/status/1361780107619094530"&gt;North Dakota House of Representatives member Karla Rose Hanson&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aBUfLi"&gt;The bill, SB 2333, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276511/north-dakota-senate-bill-2333-apple-google-app-store-antitrust-monopoly"&gt;stirred considerable controversy last week&lt;/a&gt; when a committee hearing drew the attention of corporate lawyers and lobbyists, experts, and Apple critics arguing both in favor and against the proposed legislation’s potentially far-reaching consequences. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ArGIFk"&gt;The bill would have barred any company in the business of software distribution making over $10 million in annual revenue from imposing rules on developers dictating they only use one app store, like the App Store or the Google Play Store, and that they have to use the app store owner’s preferred payment system. Using Apple or Google’s payment system, in turn, lets those companies take 30 percent of most sales, per their long-standing revenue sharing policies around app sales and in-app purchases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="i3nYDh"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple said the bill would ‘destroy the iPhone as you know it’&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QyuXVG"&gt;Requiring developers use the App Store and Apple’s own payment system are pillars of the iPhone maker’s mobile business and largely responsible for the App Store’s continued financial success. The App Store is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22220873/apple-2020-app-store-revenue-60-billion-dollars"&gt;estimated to have generated more than $64 billion&lt;/a&gt; in revenue last year. (Google does allow alternative app stores onto Android, but the company requires users click through security warnings to download and use such software.) Yet, developers have long complained of Apple’s grip on the flow of revenue on iOS, with critics claiming its ever-changing rules are inconsistently applied and that Apple grants exemptions on a case-by-case basis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NtfIBU"&gt;Although the bill would only have dictated how companies like Apple operate within the state of North Dakota, the bill’s broad language may have forced Apple to make systemic changes to its business nationwide. The legislation’s success could have also inspired other states to follow suit with similar attempts to regulate app stores’ relationships with developers, although that appears to be already underway despite SB 2333’s failure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NpBMt6"&gt;In arguing against SB 2333, Apple’s chief privacy engineer, Erik Neuenschwander, testified that the bill “threatens to destroy iPhone as you know it,” arguing that it would “undermine the privacy, security, safety, and performance that’s built into iPhone by design,” &lt;a href="https://bismarcktribune.com/news/local/govt-and-politics/north-dakota-senate-bill-targets-monopolistic-app-stores/article_dc491c88-97e0-54cd-beb2-5a26044cb97c.html"&gt;according to the &lt;em&gt;Bismarck Tribune&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “Simply put, we work hard to keep bad apps out of the App Store; (the bill) could require us to let them in,” Neuenschwander concluded. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="afeGMT"&gt;&lt;q&gt;North Dakota’s app store bill might have had far-reaching consequences for Apple and Google&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0spRQA"&gt;The legislation is just one of a growing number of state bills, which now includes proposed bills in Arizona and Georgia that seek to place limits on the power of Apple and fellow app store owners. a &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/14/technology/north-dakota-tech-apps.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times &lt;/em&gt;report this weekend&lt;/a&gt; linked the bills to a multi-state lobbying effort from Apple’s fiercest critics, with &lt;em&gt;Fortnite &lt;/em&gt;creator Epic Games leading the charge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7ybrKQ"&gt;SB 2333 was proposed by Sen. Kyle Davison (R-Fargo) after the state senator was approached by Lacee Bjork Anderson, a lobbyist with the firm Odney Public Affairs based in Bismarck, North Dakota. Anderson, it turns out, was hired by Epic, &lt;em&gt;The Times &lt;/em&gt;reported. Epic is also suing Apple and Google after both companies removed &lt;em&gt;Fortnite &lt;/em&gt;last August, following Epic’s decision to include its own in-app payment system in the iOS and Android versions of the battle royale hit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n404CS"&gt;Anderson was also paid by the Coalition of App Fairness, an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/24/21453745/spotify-epic-tile-match-coalition-for-app-fairness-apple-app-store-policies-protest"&gt;industry group formed last fall&lt;/a&gt; consisting of Epic and fellow app makers like Tinder parent company Match group and Spotify that have for years railed against the App Store and Apple’s mandate that it take 30 percent of all app sales and in-app purchases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Al1fCl"&gt;In a tweet, Epic CEO Tim Sweeney acknowledged Epic and the Coalition for App Fairness’s participation in he ongoing lobbying efforts.“North Dakota’s effort to combat app store monopolies is awesome for consumers and developers,” Sweeney wrote. “The Coalition for App Fairness organized the outreach, lobbying, and developer participation. Can’t take credit for it, but Epic is proud to be a part of it!” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vEkMG0"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;North Dakota's effort to combat app store monopolies is awesome for consumers and developers. The Coalition for App Fairness organized the outreach, lobbying, and developer participation. Can't take credit for it, but Epic is proud to be a part of it!&lt;a href="https://t.co/Zi0iDMpkaz"&gt;https://t.co/Zi0iDMpkaz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Tim Sweeney (@TimSweeneyEpic) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1361789614722269186?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jvOAtO"&gt;Apple did not immediately respond to a request for comment. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22286234/apple-app-store-north-dakota-bill-sb-2333-failed-vote"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22286234/apple-app-store-north-dakota-bill-sb-2333-failed-vote</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-16T16:45:59-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T16:45:59-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here’s what the upcoming Sonos headphones will probably look like</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fHdBRkTLomYgul7FuG2ovpmptwg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68827129/sonoslede.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: German Patent and Trademark Office&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Lmm3dI"&gt;Sonos has long been rumored to be developing a premium set of noise-canceling headphones to join the company’s ecosystem of speakers and multiroom audio products. A new design patent filing at the German Patent and Trademark Office seems to provide a glimpse at a farther-along, more refined product than what we saw from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/1/21409963/sonos-headphones-patent-wireless-noise-cancellation-bluetooth"&gt;the US Patent and Trademark Office&lt;/a&gt; in September. These latest filings were registered in December and published in late January. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rBwRQJ"&gt;One notable difference is that the Sonos wordmark is visible on this design; it wasn’t present on the previous filing. (That said, it’s in broken lines, which doesn’t count for much in a design patent and signifies that placement could change.) Another evolution is that the rods coming out of the headband now go straight down into the ear cups; there’s no additional part that wraps around the back of each ear cup as we saw before. Again, these are broken lines, but the solid lines also show an evolution from the design we saw before. There are obvious tweaks to the outer ear cup shape. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qCZVzctpzxG9zL56C1OmjFHJ07w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22308211/sonosheadphones.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The latest headphone patent from Sonos (left) shows a more refined design than an earlier USPTO filing (right).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="l8Pql5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10322870"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VtVAo5"&gt;Little is known about the Sonos headphones beyond the fact that they’re expected to cost the same as high-end competitors from Sony and Bose. It’s believed one of the headlining features will be a seamless handoff of music from the headphones to your Sonos audio system (and vice versa). But Sonos will likely need to deliver more than just that to sway consumers away from the market leaders and newer entrants like the Apple AirPods Max.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mj5M3a"&gt;An adapter for earphones is also part of recent Sonos filings at the German Patent and Trademark Office. It’s not unusual for expensive headphones to offer replaceable ear cushions, so that could be what this is for. A USB-C port, various buttons, and a 3.5-millimeter cable input are also sketched out in the headphone drawings. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/j5WayBbQWt2YeX79uhlqrEvaui8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22308305/Screen_Shot_2021_02_16_at_4.22.44_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The German filing also shows drawings of an “adapter” for earphones. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="46nhkw"&gt;Sonos CEO Patrick Spence confirmed during the company’s earnings call last week that the next Sonos product will be announced in March. That device could end up being &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22269050/sonos-fcc-filing-mini-move-portable-bluetooth-speaker"&gt;a smaller portable speaker&lt;/a&gt; to complement the bulky Sonos Move. But during the call, Spence also confirmed that Sonos continues to aim to release “at least” two new products each year. The headphones could wind up being that second new offering for 2021 — assuming they don’t make a surprise appearance next month.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22286147/sonos-headphones-new-design-german-patent-office"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22286147/sonos-headphones-new-design-german-patent-office</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-16T16:37:54-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T16:37:54-05:00</updated>
    <title>Inexpensive Moto G30 offers a 90Hz screen and 5,000mAh battery </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lhoR5THEx3jKOLKT-RXt1UyteEc=/175x0:2056x1254/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68827062/moto_g30.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Motorola Moto G30 is available now in European markets.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Motorola&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rztDlT"&gt;Motorola &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/motorolaUK/status/1361586137844834305"&gt;has announced&lt;/a&gt; two new budget phones coming to European markets: the Moto G30 and the Moto G10, both starting well under €200. The higher-specced G30 includes a fast 90Hz refresh rate screen and a 5,000mAh battery with 15W fast charging, two features not commonly seen at this price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J3j9ur"&gt;The G30’s 6.5-inch display is unfortunately just 720p. Other specs look healthier, though, like IP52 dust and splash resistance, 6GB of RAM, and 128GB of built-in storage that is expandable via microSD. The phone includes a 64-megapixel main camera that produces 16-megapixel images, plus an 8-megapixel ultrawide, 2-megapixel macro camera, and 2-megapixel depth sensor, with a 13-megapixel selfie camera around front. It’s equipped with a Snapdragon 662 chipset, a 3.5mm headphone jack, and will ship with Android 11. It costs €179.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LiQpEwjFLwSyzwnCsngJsxNbB5k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22308100/moto_g10.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Motorola&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Motorola Moto G10 is a little cheaper with a less robust processor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="relS22"&gt;The Moto G10 is a little less interesting, with a less powerful Snapdragon 460 processor, 4GB of RAM, and a 6.5-inch 720p screen with a standard 60Hz refresh rate. It gets a lower-res 48-megapixel main camera and 8-megapixel selfie cam. Like the G30, it contains a 5,000mAh battery, although it charges a little more slowly at 10W. A version sold in India will include a bigger 6,000mAh battery with 15W charging. The European variant is priced at €149.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WyuSia"&gt;Fast refresh rate screens make scrolling and animations appear smoother, and they’re quite common now on flagship phones. It’s not surprising that we’re starting to see the technology pop up in the budget class — the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22214280/oneplus-nord-n10-5g-review"&gt;$300 OnePlus Nord N10 5G&lt;/a&gt; has a 90Hz screen and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278488/samsung-galaxy-a52-a72-leak-90hz-refresh-rate-screen"&gt;upcoming Galaxy A52 and A72&lt;/a&gt; are rumored to include one, too — but the G30 is one of the least expensive phones we’ve seen to offer one. It seems likely that we’re well on our way to seeing 90Hz screens becoming the new normal at every price point. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vHSPVB"&gt;The Moto G30 and G10 are currently listed for sale on Motorola’s UK and German sites and will come to other European markets this spring.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22286048/motorola-moto-g30-moto-g10-90hz-screen-price-launch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22286048/motorola-moto-g30-moto-g10-90hz-screen-price-launch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-16T16:17:59-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T16:17:59-05:00</updated>
    <title>Pokémon’s League of Legends-style spinoff is getting an Android beta in March</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jnQctqVlOYJEddmGzaVxfG5D0Fw=/77x0:907x553/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68826958/pokemon_unite.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="66Avmv"&gt;If you are interested in testing out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/24/21301541/pokemon-unite-team-game-strategy-tencent-nintendo-switch"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pokémon Unite&lt;/em&gt;, a spinoff that has gameplay similar to &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, you may be in luck. Today, the Pokémon Company announced it’ll host a &lt;a href="https://www.pokemon.com/us/pokemon-news/pokemon-unite-development-update-and-regional-beta-test-in-canada-for-android-users/?cid=&amp;amp;utm_source=TW&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_campaign=VG&amp;amp;utm_term=PokemonUniteBeta"&gt;regional beta test&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Unite&lt;/em&gt; in Canada next month. The beta test will be exclusive to Android users, and registration is available on the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=jp.pokemon.pokemonunite"&gt;Google Play Store&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ni16sU"&gt;Initially announced at its Pokémon Presents presentation last June, &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Unite &lt;/em&gt;is a free-to-play MOBA. The game is being developed by TiMi Studios, a subsidiary of Tencent, best known for creating &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Mobile&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Honor of Kings&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZsIY5o"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Pokémon is celebrating its 25th anniversary this year&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tMSSxL"&gt;Similar to other games of the genre, such as &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Unite&lt;/em&gt; pits two teams of five players against each other with the ultimate goal of taking control over multiple points across the map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ux91qp"&gt;This year is huge for &lt;em&gt;Pokémon&lt;/em&gt; as the series celebrates its 25th anniversary. Nintendo has big plans to commemorate the milestone for one of its most popular franchises in creative ways, from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/2/16/22285360/pokemon-25th-anniversary-levis-denim-tuxedo-outfit-merchandise"&gt;obscure&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278179/post-malone-pokemon-concert-25th-anniversary"&gt;partnerships&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22230643/pokemon-snap-nintendo-switch-release-date"&gt;a sequel to &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Snap&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which will arrive on April 30th for the Nintendo Switch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="o4ffpc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Celebrate Pokémon’s 25th anniversary with a matching denim tuxedo&amp;amp;nbsp;from Levi’s","url":"https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/2/16/22285360/pokemon-25th-anniversary-levis-denim-tuxedo-outfit-merchandise"},{"title":"Pokémon&amp;amp;nbsp;is celebrating its 25th anniversary with Katy Perry","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228760/pokemon-25th-anniversary-katy-perry"},{"title":"Post Malone will hold a virtual concert to celebrate Pokémon’s 25th anniversary","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278179/post-malone-pokemon-concert-25th-anniversary"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22286163/pokemon-unite-moba-nintendo-beta-test-canada"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22286163/pokemon-unite-moba-nintendo-beta-test-canada</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-16T16:07:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T16:07:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft Edge won’t show you notification requests other people don’t like</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Microsoft Edge logo hovering above a lake" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vYCKPQhpkOjefjeU-F1tU_T_3l8=/86x0:1571x990/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68826918/Screen_Shot_2021_02_16_at_11.38.26_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wvbffv"&gt;Microsoft is trying a new solution for the persistent “would you like to allow notifications from this website” requests that you see across the internet: crowdsourcing data on which ones people block and which ones they allow. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/ref=nav_logo?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;According to a blog post today&lt;/a&gt;, Microsoft is calling this feature adaptive notification requests, and the company is rolling it out in Edge 88 after it received positive feedback from testers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8cLpsz"&gt;For an example of how this works, say there’s a website that commonly asks for notifications, and nobody wants them. They’ll either ignore the request or click the block button to make sure they never see it again. Microsoft then collects that data and will stop showing new users the notification request in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Glq-ZokCptvBkMpxIko-iPtVEKw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22308123/Screen_Shot_2021_02_16_at_12.22.59_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If enough people click “block,” Edge will stop showing the notification request to users.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CbDuXv"&gt;In previous versions, &lt;a href="https://blogs.windows.com/msedgedev/2020/07/23/reducing-distractions-quiet-notification-requests/"&gt;Edge made the notification requests “quiet” by default&lt;/a&gt;, meaning they would automatically be blocked and show up as a bell icon in the address bar that users could click to opt in. In the blog post, Microsoft says this fixed the complaints from users about getting too many of the requests but introduced new problems: mainly, people stopped enabling notifications altogether, even on sites where many users used to enable them. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E0wXouYRUN9cssgcAFI8Eue_OMk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22308116/fig_1.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edge’s quiet notification was unobtrusive but easy to miss.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="JMfWfE"&gt;The new version is looking to strike a balance between showing users notification requests that they may actually want and hiding the ones they don’t — ones that don’t make the cut will be automatically “quieted.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Da7VBc"&gt;Microsoft isn’t leaving users who never want to receive the requests (like myself) out in the cold, though: you can reenable quiet notification requests by going to Settings, Cookies and Site Permissions, then Notifications to toggle them back on. Microsoft will also turn on Quiet Notifications automatically if you click “block” on three notification requests in a row. Edge will also automatically block notifications from a site if a user dismisses a request with the X button three times in a row or ignores it by clicking elsewhere on the page four times in a row.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hPCiAU"&gt;If you don’t use Edge but &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; on edge from all the notification requests, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/18/18716041/website-notification-prompts-pop-ups-how-to-stop"&gt;we have a guide on how to turn them off in all of the major browsers&lt;/a&gt;. However, it’d be nice to see Chrome and others adopt a feature similar to this, where notification requests that are spammy and annoying are hidden, but genuinely useful ones (like, say, for Gmail) are shown to users.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22286069/microsoft-edge-adaptive-notification-requests"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22286069/microsoft-edge-adaptive-notification-requests</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-16T15:23:43-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T15:23:43-05:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon is opening its first manufacturing line in India to produce Fire TV devices</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Amazon’s Fire TV Stick 4K, the best inexpensive alternative to Roku, pictured attached to a TV’s HDMI port." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/neEZbzaSLmMeFNzxkwIM1vCbuvU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68826661/cwelch_181030_3054_0442.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OPAgJE"&gt;Amazon is opening its first manufacturing line in India in a partnership with Foxconn-owned Cloud Network Technology, an India-based subsidiary of the Taiwanese electronics giant, &lt;a href="https://blog.aboutamazon.in/our-business/amazon-announces-first-device-manufacturing-line-in-india"&gt;Amazon announced on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;. The partnership is part of an effort to work with the Indian government, which has embarked on a campaign to encourage companies to invest in the Indian economy to avoid roadblocks, like high import taxes to entering and competing in the country’s competitive and fast-growing economy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4BHN8N"&gt;The Indian government calls its campaign to encourage local investment and growth in India-based enterprises “&lt;a href="https://aatmanirbharbharat.mygov.in/"&gt;Aatmanirbhar Bharat,&lt;/a&gt;” which translates to “self-reliant India” and has become a cornerstone of Prime Minister Narendra Modi’s economic policy since its official introduction last year. “We welcome Amazon’s decision to set up a manufacturing line in Chennai, as it will enhance domestic production capacities, and create jobs as well,” said Ravi Shankar Prasad, the country’s minister for communications, electronics, and information, in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Djsy6B"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Tamil Nadu has been an essential partner for Amazon India &amp;amp; we are excited to launch our 1st manufacturing line in Chennai. This contributes directly to the local economy &amp;amp; showcases India’s ability to produce world-class products. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CMOTamilNadu?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@CMOTamilNadu&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Guidance_TN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Guidance_TN&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/muruganandamias?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@muruganandamias&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Amazon India News (@AmazonNews_IN) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AmazonNews_IN/status/1361583332513828866?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="12uemG"&gt;According to Amazon, the Chennai line will be capable of producing hundreds of thousands of devices every year, starting with the Fire TV line of streaming devices. The company says it will “continuously evaluate scaling capacity to additional marketplaces/cities depending on the domestic demand.” The announcement comes a year after Amazon said it would begin &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/01/14/amazon-to-invest-1-billion-to-digitize-small-businesses-in-india/"&gt;investing as much as $1 billion&lt;/a&gt; in local Indian businesses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0RlA0l"&gt;“Amazon is committed to partner with the Indian government to advance the vision of an Aatmanirbhar Bharat,” said Amit Agarwal, Amazon’s global senior vice president of Amazon India, in a statement. “We have pledged to invest US $1 billion to digitize 10 million small and medium businesses, help Indian businesses sell worldwide thereby enabling US $10B in cumulative exports, and create an additional 1MM jobs by 2025.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MDqoga"&gt;Amazon’s heavy investment in India is more evidence of the country’s growing significance as both a prime market for Western consumer electronics and as a manufacturing center that can compete with China and other fast-growing production hubs. It’s also a sign that Modi’s aggressive foreign and economic policymaking is translating to successful infusions of outside investment, as Amazon, it seems, would rather create local jobs and work with established production partners than face potential restrictions on reaching Indian customers. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22286059/amazon-fire-tv-india-manufacturing-line-partner-foxconn"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22286059/amazon-fire-tv-india-manufacturing-line-partner-foxconn</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-16T15:03:45-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T15:03:45-05:00</updated>
    <title>The PS5’s actual silicon processor is revealed in these first gorgeous photos</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XBr2_Pqc0BBJpNBbu1m1UamtBTE=/0x0:2200x1467/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68826551/sony_ps5_liquid_metal_fritzchen_fritz_2200.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/130561288@N04/with/50943598756/" target="_blank"&gt;Fritzchens Fritz / Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oBIdSM"&gt;While the world continues to wait for a chance to buy the PlayStation 5, we’re continuing to put Sony’s next-gen console under the microscope — literally, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/2/7/22269634/how-sony-designed-ps5-dualsense-playstation-symbol-microtexture"&gt;when we showed you the 40,000 tiny PlayStation symbols&lt;/a&gt; hidden in each gamepad, and now somewhat figuratively with what we believe are the first up-close pictures of the PS5’s actual silicon &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FritzchensFritz/status/1360994406434807809/photo/1"&gt;from photographer Fritzchens Fritz&lt;/a&gt; (via &lt;a href="https://videocardz.com/newz/sony-playstation-5-soc-die-pictured-up-close"&gt;&lt;em&gt;VideoCardz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3AmFtM"&gt;Above, you can see one of Fritz’s gorgeous close-ups of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/7/21505598/sony-ps5-playstation-5-tear-down-hardware"&gt;the liquid metal interface Sony uses&lt;/a&gt; to keep the PS5’s temperatures in check. Below, find a stunning monochrome portrait of it framed against the motherboard:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nsYi3ZADzJRJ6f-26075uUwNRjA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22307844/sony_ps5_die_shot_fritzchen_fritz_2200.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/130561288@N04/with/50943598756/" target="_blank"&gt;Fritzchens Fritz / Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="kAEEZh"&gt;Let’s turn it upright, shall we? Here’s a high-res version you might be able to blow up more easily (just tap it first):&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nMQnApggHRd4vvrfl3KYS9sTd7g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22307879/sony_ps5_die_shot_fritzchen_fritz_vertical.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/130561288@N04/with/50943598756/" target="_blank"&gt;Fritzchens Fritz / Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="s2iU7Y"&gt;And here’s what you’re actually seeing, according to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Locuza_/status/1361026970893627398"&gt;a tentative die shot analysis&lt;/a&gt; that Fritz retweeted:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vmAkhL"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;My interpretation of the floor plan PS5 floor plan:&lt;br&gt;1. Bomba surprise that Sony likely cut down the 256-Bit FP pipes to just 128-Bit. &lt;br&gt;2. No Infinity Cache/L3$, also not on the Xbox Series. &lt;br&gt;3. Might have the old Render Backend design, need higher res to say for sure. &lt;br&gt;4. ... &lt;a href="https://t.co/gwrXI903U8"&gt;https://t.co/gwrXI903U8&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/Vvmm1hGSM8"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Vvmm1hGSM8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Locuza (@Locuza_) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Locuza_/status/1361026970893627398?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 14, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Vyee8V"&gt;Here’s where you might be tempted to dive into some technical details — perhaps argue &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/ps5-die-shots-reveal-missing-zen-2-rdna-2-features/"&gt;how the PS5’s silicon stacks up&lt;/a&gt; to its Xbox counterpart or AMD’s versions for PC — but I’d suggest you resist for now. For one, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21718936/xbox-series-x-ps5-performance-game-comparison"&gt;results matter more than specs&lt;/a&gt;, but perhaps more importantly, we haven’t finished looking at awesome photos yet! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="bIsgmr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"PlayStation 5: everything you need to know (including comparo specs)","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21450334/playstation-5-ps5-sony-news-price-features-specs-hardware-games"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Y99He5"&gt;Let’s zoom in further. “Enhance!”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CZM7Y7y6iPPEhJ2grnteI8lcQMk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22307915/50943598871_d053b1c8e9_o.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/130561288@N04/with/50943598756/" target="_blank"&gt;Fritzchens Fritz / Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An overview shot of the PS5’s die.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="t9qgng"&gt;And here’s one more, zoomed all the way into the region where AMD’s Zen 2 CPU cores live:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/COu1f6EEUPxbtC-0ptR9fA1-_l0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22307916/50947289326_07f4ba7345_o.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/130561288@N04/with/50943598756/" target="_blank"&gt;Fritzchens Fritz / Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="44qtgB"&gt;That’s as far as Fritz has come with the PS5 so far, but if these kinds of photos excite you, I’d definitely recommend spending some time &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/130561288@N04/with/50943598756/"&gt;on Fritz’s Flickr page&lt;/a&gt; where you’ll find an incredible number of vibrant, up-close-and-personal, public domain&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;photos of silicon that leap right off the page. &lt;em&gt;PCGamesN&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamesn.com/amd-intel-nvidia-naked-silicon-fritzchens-fritz"&gt;called Fritz&lt;/a&gt; a “silicon pornographer,” and it’s not hard to see why. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h8aCwh0xH1U5wwSobuCSiIAuSLk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22307949/50619518626_cc4935a2ef_k.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/130561288@N04/50619518626/" target="_blank"&gt;Fritzchens Fritz / Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hKnT6n"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/2/16/22285947/sony-ps5-playstation-5-die-silicon-processor-photos"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/2/16/22285947/sony-ps5-playstation-5-die-silicon-processor-photos</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-16T14:15:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T14:15:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>Roku job listing suggests big plans for original movies and TV shows</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rbBDltyoezyxEkc77Rp6W7uHA8k=/203x0:4349x2764/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68826225/TRC_UK_Home_Screen.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Dy95Ee"&gt;Roku is looking to create its own original “episodic and feature productions,” according to &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.linkedin.com%2Fjobs%2Fview%2Flead-production-attorney-at-roku-inc-2376352104%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F16%2F22285819%2Froku-original-content-job-listing-plan-original-shows-movies#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a recent (and now closed) job listing&lt;/a&gt; posted by the company (&lt;a href="https://www.protocol.com/roku-original-content-push"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Protocol&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The job listing mentions Roku’s “expanding slate of original content.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SN94VQ"&gt;Roku currently doesn’t have any in-house content of its own. It now owns Quibi’s lineup of shows, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22220426/quibi-roku-channel-acquisition-content"&gt;which it acquired from the defunct streaming company&lt;/a&gt;, and it also offers The Roku Channel, an ad-supported service that lets users watch a wide range of TV shows, movies, live news, and more — but we haven’t yet seen any shows that are made by Roku itself.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kPoToihrjrkzX-msqSaaBDsmgtk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22307574/Screen_Shot_2021_02_16_at_9.29.36_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The job listing that mentions “original episodic and feature length productions.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MpyWdV"&gt;The job listing, however, indicates that Roku is looking to get into the content production business — something its hardware competitors like Amazon and Apple have already done. Providing its own shows could give its users a reason to spend more time on their Roku devices, which in turn could help further boost the company’s ad revenue, even if users aren’t watching its shows specifically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vKKh0H"&gt;The company’s potential shows and movies will be competing with a huge catalog of originals from other streaming services like Netflix, Disney Plus, and Hulu. But unlike those streaming heavyweights, Roku sells devices that bring all the services together, so while Roku will technically be going head to head with the other companies, its users will also be watching &lt;em&gt;WandaVision &lt;/em&gt;on a Roku box. That convenient customer experience remains important — even if Roku occasionally butts heads with streaming providers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fm1krD"&gt;It’s probably worth noting that it may be a while before you’ll get to actually see a Roku show. If the company is just now hiring production attorneys, the process is likely still in pretty early stages. However, it goes to show how much value Roku sees in bringing original content to the table. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22285819/roku-original-content-job-listing-plan-original-shows-movies"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22285819/roku-original-content-job-listing-plan-original-shows-movies</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-16T14:00:48-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T14:00:48-05:00</updated>
    <title>Disaster scammers target Texas blackout victims</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Winter Storm Uri Brings Ice And Snow Across Widespread Parts Of The Nation" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FsM8UtgNUdOfvN8tRBlwdjbVI4s=/0x0:5595x3730/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68826133/1231190479.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Montinique Monroe/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Rbmion"&gt;A freezing winter storm passed through Texas and parts of the Midwest over the weekend, straining parts of the state’s electricity grid to the point of blackouts. But with many Texans struggling to heat their homes, disaster scammers have reportedly been taking advantage of the disaster to try to steal account info.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lrGUOq"&gt;In a tweet on Tuesday, the Electric Reliability Council of Texas, or ERCOT, warned followers that social media scammers were posing as electricity workers and asking people to text them their private account numbers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YIx3Bs"&gt;“Don’t do it!” the company &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ERCOT_ISO/status/1361712314911772683?s=20"&gt;said in a tweet&lt;/a&gt;. “We don’t need any of your info to get your power back on — we are working as fast as we possibly can.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="RQWJ4C"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;There is a scam circulating on social media asking customers to text their private account numbers. Don’t do it! We don’t need any of your info to get your power back on – we are working as fast as we possibly can.&lt;/p&gt;— ERCOT (@ERCOT_ISO) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ERCOT_ISO/status/1361712314911772683?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TScs9t"&gt;Generally, it’s a bad idea to hand over private information — from account numbers to passwords — over the phone or through text message. Scammers oftentimes make big promises for pieces of information like “how much money you make, how much you owe, or your bank account, credit card, or Social Security number,” &lt;a href="https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/articles/how-recognize-and-report-spam-text-messages"&gt;according to The Federal Trade Commission&lt;/a&gt;. These promises could be anything from getting your electricity turned back on to winning an Amazon gift card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xO5HQ9"&gt;Disaster scams like these aren’t unusual. After natural disasters, FEMA has warned survivors not to offer personal or financial information over the phone if the person on the other line does not adequately identify themselves as a government employee. Scammers often pose as FEMA or other government employees during disaster situations like this week’s winter storm in Texas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a66XVh"&gt;In order to protect yourself from text, phone, or email scammers, &lt;a href="https://www.fcc.gov/consumers/guides/after-storms-watch-out-scams"&gt;the Federal Communications Commission asks&lt;/a&gt; that if an insurance, electric, or government employee calls you asking for money, to hang up on them. Then, call the company on your own before handing over any personal or financial information. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eh9Ufe"&gt;The FCC also asks that survivors verify information in social media posts before making a donation to an organization or on a crowdfunding website like GoFundMe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DzNv6B"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22285980/disaster-scammers-target-texas-blackout-victims-winter-storm-ftc-electricity"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22285980/disaster-scammers-target-texas-blackout-victims-winter-storm-ftc-electricity</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
