<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-17T11:07:48-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-17T11:07:48-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-17T11:07:48-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to get more space in your Google storage</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/D3I3JurYKEMLagor1LBvIXUv3ts=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68830586/acastro_190318_1777_google_drive_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="995CJ1"&gt;For many of us, Google storage is the modern-day hard drive. It’s the place where our most important thoughts, documents, and memories reside. But just like with a traditional hard drive, the space isn’t infinite, and running out of room can be a real problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h4NMAK"&gt;By default, Google gives you 15GB of space to use for everything associated with your account. (If you have a paid G Suite account, your limit’s likely higher.) That includes content connected to Gmail, Google Drive, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/11/21560810/google-photos-unlimited-cap-free-uploads-15gb-ending"&gt;all&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Google Photos saved after June 1st&lt;/a&gt;. Needless to say, data adds up fast. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YxF6Db"&gt;You can check your current storage status by visiting &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/settings/storage"&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt;, and if push comes to shove, you can purchase more space there, too, for as little as &lt;a href="https://one.google.com/about"&gt;$2 a month&lt;/a&gt; for an extra 100GB. But shelling out more money might not be necessary. A quick round of old-fashioned housekeeping could be enough to clear away your virtual cobwebs and give yourself ample room to grow. Here’s how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="wffTjP"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delete Drive debris&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="U71Zuv"&gt;Google Drive is a common place for space-sucking files to build up and wear down your quota, but tidying things up doesn’t take long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="FhULDM"&gt;Open &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/u/0/quota"&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;, which will show you a list of all of your Drive files sorted by size with the largest items at the top&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8jiO21"&gt;Look through the heftiest offenders and delete anything you no longer need&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EbNW2h"&gt;Click the gear-shaped icon in Drive’s upper-right corner, and select “Settings,” followed by “Manage Apps”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0JSjeI"&gt;For any apps that have a note about hidden data, click the gray “Options” box to the right, and select “Delete hidden app data”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Google Drive hidden data" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZiCKE3hpTX9bhDcrXlFW0ljAzKM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15969666/google_drive_storage_hidden_app_data.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;For any apps that have a note about hidden data, click the gray “Options” box to the right, and select “Delete hidden app data.” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="f7323i"&gt;Apps associated with your Google Drive storage can sometimes have hidden data, but all it takes is a couple of clicks to remove it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="VuPUfN"&gt;Open &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/u/0/trash"&gt;your Drive Trash folder&lt;/a&gt; and click on the “Empty trash” link at the top of the page&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ckrevF"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Free up Photos storage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="6baCi7"&gt;Unless you &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21562908/google-future-pixel-phone-no-unlimited-photos-storage-confirmed"&gt;currently have a Pixel phone&lt;/a&gt; (in which case, you will, for now, keep the unlimited “high quality” option), as of June 1st, 2021, every photo and video backed up to Google Photos is going to count against your Google storage. If you’ve been saving photos at their original sizes, you can free up tons of space by converting them to Google’s “high-quality” option, which compresses images down to 16MP and videos to 1080p (a change that’s &lt;a href="https://www.phonearena.com/news/Google-Photos-High-quality-vs-Original-Whats-the-difference-and-should-you-care_id93938"&gt;unlikely to be noticeable&lt;/a&gt; for most people and purposes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="II1hIJ"&gt;Go to the &lt;a href="https://photos.google.com/settings"&gt;Photos settings page&lt;/a&gt;, and select “High quality (free unlimited storage)”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="aqoG3F"&gt;When you make that selection, you’ll be asked whether you want to switch to the “high quality” format and compress your existing photos. If there are any photos you don’t want to compress, click on the “Learn how to keep original files” link for instructions on saving those photos to your device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="When you switch to “high quality,” you can also compress the rest of your Google Photos content." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xMuX1eDvb3mXaQ3qGdXGFsCBEys=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22309653/Screen_Shot_2021_02_17_at_9.20.22_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;When you switch to “high quality,” you can also compress the rest of your Google Photos content.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="kIkJIH"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Say goodbye to Gmail junk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="mjcRaE"&gt;Emails don’t take up a ton of space, but you know what does? Attachments. Odds are, you’ve got plenty of old attachments sitting in your Gmail account that you don’t really need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dUTMcd"&gt;Here’s how to address that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="EaQUsC"&gt;Go to the Gmail website and type “has:attachment larger:10M” into the search box at the top&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="78cbK0"&gt;Identify any messages with disposable attachments and delete them. (There’s no great way to get rid of an attachment without also deleting the associated email, unfortunately, but you can always forward a message back to yourself and manually remove the attachment before axing the original.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="viHWJR"&gt;Open your &lt;a href="https://mail.google.com/mail/u/0/#spam"&gt;Spam folder&lt;/a&gt;, and click the link to “Delete all spam messages now” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="v7aCfx"&gt;Open your &lt;a href="https://mail.google.com/mail/u/0/#trash"&gt;Trash folder&lt;/a&gt;, and select “Empty Trash now” to send everything away for good &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="QN1Yay"&gt;Feeling lighter is liberating, isn’t it? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GxCbPk"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 17th, 2021, 10:37AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article was originally published on March 19th, 2019. The information on Google Photos has been updated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22286339/google-drive-storage-more-space-how-to-photos-files"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22286339/google-drive-storage-more-space-how-to-photos-files</id>
    <author>
      <name>JR Raphael</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-17T10:49:44-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-17T10:49:44-05:00</updated>
    <title>Ford says it will go all-electric in Europe by 2030</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3GvSPyN99Jw4nuwQQXnQJeUtaZQ=/0x0:6720x4480/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68830428/All_New_Ford_E_Transit_09.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9vTleR"&gt;Ford will only sell electric vehicles in Europe by 2030, it said Wednesday. The automaker said it will spend $1 billion to convert its factory in Cologne, Germany, into its first EV production line on the continent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5EIGoE"&gt;Ford says it will transition to EV-production gradually over the next decade. By 2024, the company’s entire commercial vehicle lineup will be “zero-emissions capable, all-electric or plug-in hybrid.” By mid-2026, Ford says “100 percent” of its passenger vehicle lineup will be the same. And by 2030, Ford expects two-thirds of its commercial vehicle sales to be all-electric or plug-in hybrid, while all of its passenger vehicles sold will be pure battery-electric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="WK1ujE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Ford said it will increase its investment in electric and autonomous vehicles to $29 billion&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LmlX8k"&gt;The news comes on the heels of Ford announcing that it would increase its investment in electric and autonomous vehicles to $29 billion. The automaker had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/15/16892386/ford-electric-car-11-billion-2022-detroit-auto-show-2018"&gt;previously committed to spend $11.5 billion&lt;/a&gt; on electrifying its vehicle lineup through 2022. Now, it will spend double that amount, while extending the timeline to 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fdcnRW"&gt;Ford will have help in its plans to electrify its vehicle lineup. In 2019, the company struck a deal with Volkswagen to use the German auto giant’s electric-vehicle modular electric vehicle platform. VW’s MEB platform will serve as the basis for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/8/18536668/vw-volkswagen-id-3-preorders-oelectric-car-long-range-ev"&gt;15 million electric cars the automaker aims to sell&lt;/a&gt;. And Ford has said it will use the platform to design and build at least one high-volume fully electric vehicle in Europe starting in 2023. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R7CgmX"&gt;Ford aims to deliver more than 600,000 European vehicles using the MEB architecture over six years, with a second all-new Ford model for European customers under discussion. The move would help Ford comply with European government mandates that push electrified vehicles and strict emissions standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WbpHmG"&gt;Numerous European countries have set out targets for banning traditional gas-powered cars and vans, with Norway aiming for 2025 and France and the UK for 2040 and 2050, respectively. (Granted, the &lt;a href="https://qz.com/1341155/nine-countries-say-they-will-ban-internal-combustion-engines-none-have-a-law-to-do-so/"&gt;legislation for actually mandating the bans&lt;/a&gt; lags far behind.) Several states in the US are also making aggressive targets, with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/23/21452825/california-ban-combustion-gas-vehicles-cars-2035"&gt;California leading the pack&lt;/a&gt;, vowing to ban the sale of gas-powered vehicles by 2035. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nVEw3i"&gt;Ford’s effort to speed up its electrification plans is meant to convince those on Wall Street who have been jittery about the company’s ability to catch up to Tesla, which has been the only automaker to successfully build an EV business over the last few years. Ford is keeping pace with other legacy automakers like GM and Volkswagen, having just begun delivering its hotly anticipated &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22265570/mustang-mach-e-review-electric-ford-ev-photos-video"&gt;Mustang Mach-E&lt;/a&gt; to customers late last year — though a &lt;a href="https://www.freep.com/story/money/cars/ford/2021/01/16/ford-mustang-mach-e-delivery-delay/4189265001/"&gt;quality review issue&lt;/a&gt; delayed hundreds of additional deliveries last month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5vDWTS"&gt;The company also introduced an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/3/21163669/ford-all-electric-transit-cargo-van-2021"&gt;all-electric Transit van&lt;/a&gt; last year and plans on unveiling an electric version of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21288000/ford-electric-f-150-2022-sale-launch-jim-farley"&gt;bestselling F-150 pickup truck&lt;/a&gt; later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E7Hqvo"&gt;Ford isn’t even the only carmaker to greatly increase its bet on electric. Late last year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/19/21575153/gm-electric-ev-investment-deadline-cadillac-chevy-hummer"&gt;GM said it would spend $27 billion&lt;/a&gt; on electric and autonomous vehicles through 2025 — up from the $20 billion it announced before the COVID-19 pandemic. GM has also said it would &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/28/22254116/general-motors-carbon-neutral-vow-2040-tailpipe-emissions-ev"&gt;transition to electric vehicles only by 2040&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287284/ford-electric-vehicles-ev-europe-2030"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287284/ford-electric-vehicles-ev-europe-2030</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-17T10:32:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-17T10:32:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon changed traffic light timing during union drive, county officials say</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BfVvGhkLeHr4JLh34ynR2gDzBFE=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68830297/acastro_180329_1777_amazon_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WmH8Xl"&gt;As part of its ongoing fight over an Alabama warehouse’s efforts to unionize, Amazon reportedly changed the timing of a traffic light outside the warehouse, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MorePerfectUS/status/1361819139866828803"&gt;according to reporting by &lt;em&gt;More Perfect Union&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Union organizers at the site had previously accused the company of altering the timing so that pro-union workers would not be able to canvass workers while stopped at the light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FWIu8Y"&gt;Until recently, the altered timing on the traffic light outside the factory had been dismissed as a rumor. But &lt;em&gt;More Perfect Union&lt;/em&gt; confirmed with Jefferson County officials that last year, Amazon notified the county of traffic delays during shift changes and asked for the light to be changed. On December 15th, the county increased the green light duration in an effort to clear workers off the worksite faster. There’s no indication that the county was aware of the ongoing organizing drive or any effect the traffic light changes might have on the effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="y9xh3e"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;NEWS: A Jefferson County public official has confirmed that Amazon asked for the traffic light patterns to be altered outside its Alabama warehouse.&lt;/p&gt;— More Perfect Union (@MorePerfectUS) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MorePerfectUS/status/1361819139866828803?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9Ccddv"&gt;Workers at the Bessemer warehouse &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/8/22272213/amazon-union-bhm1-alabama-rwdsu-vote-begins"&gt;began their union election on February 8th&lt;/a&gt;, seeking to form a union under the Retail, Warehouse and Department Store Union (RWDSU) after months of organizing. Amazon has vigorously contested the effort, posting anti-unionization flyers throughout the factory, most noticeably in the bathroom. In advance of the official vote, workers also received a flood from Amazon warning of potentially negative consequences from unionization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gGqYmq"&gt;“I have never seen Amazon fight for something like this,” one longtime Amazon employee &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/8/22272213/amazon-union-bhm1-alabama-rwdsu-vote-begins"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; previously&lt;/a&gt;, describing the flood of anti-union messaging. “I have never seen them try to push for something this hard before.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L1esOy"&gt;The traffic light is significant for organizers because of the significant rules about how and where organizers can approach employees under US labor law. Employers like Amazon retain the right to restrict non-work conversations, and non-employees are generally not allowed on the worksite during shift hours. As a result, liminal spaces like the public street outside the worksite are often important venues for organizers seeking to raise awareness about a union drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dxgvuf"&gt;Amazon did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287191/amazon-alabama-warehouse-union-traffic-light-change-bessemer"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287191/amazon-alabama-warehouse-union-traffic-light-change-bessemer</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-17T10:30:29-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-17T10:30:29-05:00</updated>
    <title>Maps show ZIP codes hit hardest by COVID-19 have low vaccination rates</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Chicago’s Roseland Community Hospital Handles Spike In Covid Patients" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TyWGlNZYb_DHIll4UYZwzSI2dxs=/0x2:8192x5463/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68830290/1291860627.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Scott Olson / Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oDmNp7"&gt;From the start of the COVID-19 vaccine rollout, experts &lt;a href="https://www.kff.org/racial-equity-and-health-policy/issue-brief/addressing-racial-equity-vaccine-distribution/"&gt;warned&lt;/a&gt; that it would take careful attention to make sure it was distributed equitably. Making sure non-white and poorer communities had access to life-saving vaccines would be an issue of justice and a public health necessity. Throughout 2020, these groups had &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22252693/covid-19-deaths-us-who-died"&gt;higher rates of death&lt;/a&gt; and disease from the virus than &lt;a href="https://www.ama-assn.org/delivering-care/health-equity/data-10-cities-show-covid-19-impact-based-poverty-race"&gt;white and wealthy&lt;/a&gt; people, so protecting them would be key to the overall goal of using vaccines to save the most lives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8TAIBy"&gt;Despite those warnings, the COVID-10 vaccination campaign got off to a rough and unequal start. By the middle of January, when 17 states were reporting race and ethnicity data, analyses showed that Black and Hispanic people were vaccinated at &lt;a href="https://www.kff.org/policy-watch/early-state-vaccination-data-raise-warning-flags-racial-equity/"&gt;lower rates&lt;/a&gt; than their share of the population. The pattern continued through &lt;a href="https://www.kff.org/coronavirus-covid-19/issue-brief/latest-data-covid-19-vaccinations-cases-deaths-race-ethnicity/"&gt;February&lt;/a&gt;. Across the country, wealthy and white people were &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/02/health/white-people-covid-vaccines-minorities.html"&gt;showing up&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/01/30/us/new-york-vaccine-disparities/index.html"&gt;vaccine clinics&lt;/a&gt; in poorer neighborhoods, crowding out local residents who aren’t as able to navigate the shot sign-up process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C9AmT0"&gt;Many cities, including New York City, Chicago, and Washington, DC, publish maps showing COVID-19 vaccination rates by ZIP code or ward. Looking at them next to maps of areas with the highest rates of COVID-19 deaths are striking: they’re almost the inverse. Officials are trying to course-correct by &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/02/health/white-people-covid-vaccines-minorities.html"&gt;prioritizing residents&lt;/a&gt; of underserved neighborhoods for some vaccination sites, organizing events at community centers like &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Eugenia_South/status/1361068415549657088"&gt;churches&lt;/a&gt;, or going &lt;a href="https://www.nbcboston.com/news/local/baker-launches-covid-vaccine-equity-program-in-20-hard-hit-communities/2304785/"&gt;door to door&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wgYwaF"&gt;But the visuals are a clear sign of how much work still needs to be done. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="HLQsur"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New York City&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="hzcJiS"&gt;Overall, around &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/covid-vaccine-tracker-global-distribution/"&gt;11 percent&lt;/a&gt; of people in New York City have received the first dose of a COVID-19 vaccine. But in some areas of the city with the highest rates of COVID-19 deaths through the pandemic, only around 3 to 5 percent of people have started vaccination. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Kz00D0sPAeEvGa_TT6ad64YcjQE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22309642/nycdeath.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: NYC Health&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;As of February 16th.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YrIi5YySrv-fKTZ2tqrFN6xlyAc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22309652/nycvaccine.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: NYC Health&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;As of February 16th.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3kX6iW"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Washington, DC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="f5hvE9"&gt;Older people eligible for vaccination in Washington, DC’s wealthier wards are &lt;a href="https://dcist.com/story/21/01/27/black-dc-residents-want-coronavirus-vaccine-but-lack-access/"&gt;more likely&lt;/a&gt; to have been vaccinated than people in the poorer, predominantly Black wards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mU-JvzWv4SF1PZk57lORXo1zkVg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22309665/Screen_Shot_2021_02_17_at_9.34.26_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Government of the District of Columbia&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;As of February 15th.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3ruZvxycp6ysJLqmUsziyv7Vkbs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22309656/Vaccine_3_dc.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Government of the District of Columbia&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;As of February 14th.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="zz3ByT"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chicago&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="F3Ma95"&gt;Only 4 percent of residents in one &lt;a href="https://www.usatoday.com/in-depth/news/health/2021/02/12/data-analysis-chicago-vaccine-rollout-reflects-us-racial-disparities/4418978001/"&gt;majority Hispanic Chicago ZIP code&lt;/a&gt; have received the first dose of a COVID-19 vaccine, even though that area had one of the highest death rates in the city. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;div id="rF0lvZ"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://data.cityofchicago.org/dataset/COVID-19-Vaccination-Coverage-by-ZIP-Code-1st-Dose/xk78-iw3x/embed?width=800&amp;amp;height=600" width="800" height="600" style="border:0; padding: 0; margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rjHptCtRQ5pJeqSMqsczxjvTQv4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22309694/Screen_Shot_2021_02_17_at_9.49.52_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: City of Chicago&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;As of February 13th.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287123/covid-vaccination-death-inequity-race-maps"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287123/covid-vaccination-death-inequity-race-maps</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-17T10:16:13-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-17T10:16:13-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Mac mini with the M1 processor is discounted at several retailers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XzOpNVrAWeG_hso6cWtxJwP0mi4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68830234/cwelch_201114_4292_0005.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gyhAdb"&gt;Apple’s new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21570046/apple-mac-mini-2020-m1-review"&gt;Mac mini with the M1 chip&lt;/a&gt; is on sale at select retailers. If you are looking to buy the base configuration, which has 8GB of memory and 256GB of SSD storage, you can grab it for as low as &lt;a href="https://www.costco.com/New+Mac+mini+%EF%BF%BD+Apple+M1+Chip+8-core+CPU,+8-core+GPU+%EF%BF%BD+8GB+Memory+%EF%BF%BD+256GB+SSD+%EF%BF%BD++Silver.product.100694159.html"&gt;$600 at Costco&lt;/a&gt;, but please note membership is required. If you don’t want a Costco membership, you can buy that same configuration for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Mini-Chip-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5PHB83?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$664 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1604799-REG%2Fapple_mgnr3ll_a_mac_mini.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F17%2F22287139%2Fmac-mini-m1-macbook-pro-deal-sale-ps-plus-lg-oled-tv#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$669 at B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rf3NsL"&gt;If you need a bit more storage, B&amp;amp;H Photo also has the model with &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1604800-REG%2Fapple_mgnt3ll_a_mac_mini.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;512GB of SSD (with 8GB of RAM)&lt;/a&gt; for $849. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="T9suKM"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9712859"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Qyj1Al"&gt;If you prefer a laptop, the M1-powered MacBook Pro is one of the best-performing laptops on the market. Both &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-512GB-Storage/dp/B08N5LLDSG?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1604809-REG%2Fapple_myd82ll_a_13_3_macbook_pro_with.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F17%2F22287139%2Fmac-mini-m1-macbook-pro-deal-sale-ps-plus-lg-oled-tv#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt; have marked the late-2020 MacBook Pro base model, which includes 256GB of storage and 8GB of RAM, down to $1,199, which is the best price on this laptop yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="67RRgY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9715950"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jpMcJi"&gt;Sony’s PlayStation Plus online subscription service includes many perks outside of the ability to play games online with friends. An active PS Plus membership also nets you access to exclusive discounts from the PS Store, along with free games that rotate out on a monthly cadence. &lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=20387&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=VergePlayStationDeal020121&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.eneba.com%2Fus%2Fpsn-playstation-network-card-psn-365-days-usa-psn-key-united-states" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Eneba&lt;/a&gt; is offering &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; readers based in the United States the opportunity to stock up on service by purchasing &lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=20387&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=VergePlayStationDeal020121&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.eneba.com%2Fus%2Fpsn-playstation-network-card-psn-365-days-usa-psn-key-united-states" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;two one-year subscriptions for only $54&lt;/a&gt; when you enter code &lt;strong&gt;VERGE27AYEAR&lt;/strong&gt; at checkout, while supplies last. If you want to buy &lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=20387&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=VergePlayStationDeal020121&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.eneba.com%2Fus%2Fpsn-playstation-network-card-psn-365-days-usa-psn-key-united-states" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;one year only, it’s $29&lt;/a&gt;, no promotional code required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xLOmNS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9734577"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jbMPlR"&gt;If you are an early adopter of either the PS5 or the Xbox Series X and you’re looking to find a TV that can take full advantage of the next-gen hardware, LG’s CX OLED TVs are a good option. Right now, you can save $600 on the CX series 55-inch model at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0829RYP8V?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1732559728853775727" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, bringing the price down to $1,350 at both retailers. Please note that if you are interested in buying the TV at Best Buy, you will need to be signed in (or sign up; it's free) to your My Best Buy account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2eN8az"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9733731"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="hiKzrs"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287139/mac-mini-m1-macbook-pro-deal-sale-ps-plus-lg-oled-tv"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287139/mac-mini-m1-macbook-pro-deal-sale-ps-plus-lg-oled-tv</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-17T10:08:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-17T10:08:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>All Your Base Are Belong To Us has turned 20 </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mEBZFcDBnWzf_SWIL8NvjtGreNg=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68830198/all_your_base_are_belong_to_us.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5HPFC5"&gt;As of yesterday, it’s been 20 years since “All Your Base Are Belong To Us” was uploaded to Newgrounds. Let that sink in. And while you’re doing that, &lt;a href="https://www.newgrounds.com/portal/view/11940"&gt;feel free to watch the video in its entirety there&lt;/a&gt;, too. It’s been kept safe in a Flash-emulating container, so even now, it’s safe from the inconvenient fact that Flash has been discontinued. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oF1XyS"&gt;As &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2021/02/get-ready-to-feel-old-the-all-your-base-music-video-turns-20-today/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;, the history of the “All Your Base” video is longer than just a single upload. Much of it is taken from a tiny GIF of the Mega Drive game &lt;em&gt;Zero Wing&lt;/em&gt;, which had been circulating widely online because of its disastrous English translation (and the GIF itself existed because of early emulation culture). “Early Internet communities poked fun at the sequence by creating and sharing gag images that had the silly text inserted in various ways,” writes &lt;em&gt;Ars&lt;/em&gt; author Sam Machkovech. The meme didn’t really take off until the video, uploaded on February 16th, 2001, was posted to Newgrounds. “The video presents the original Sega Genesis graphics, dubbed over with monotone, machine-generated speech reading each phrase,” Machkovech writes. “‘You are on your way to destruction’ in this voice is delightfully silly stuff.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LecFRoM1QdfqweauYsSbyzVfzFo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22309687/AllYourBaseAnimated.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="8jLVhn"&gt;Machkovech’s piece gets into more of the history and the context around the video itself, which is fascinating. He also correctly identifies the video as a bridge between early internet meme culture — which was mostly text-based and how we got things like ROFL — and the multimedia memes we have today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K0cuBD"&gt;Watching it now, 20 years later, the thing that stands out to me most is how culturally dated the video feels. It’s from the era of internet culture when the whole joke was getting the reference; back then, the internet was much harder to access and not the kind of culture-defining trend machine it eventually became. Knowing the reference — and sneaking it in places it didn’t belong — was funny because not everyone could figure out what it meant, unless, of course, you were part of the tribe. That kind of humor felt like the dominant mode of internet discourse up until Dashcon; even now, you can make people’s eyes twitch by typing something like “&lt;a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/the-narwhal-bacons-at-midnight"&gt;the narwhal bacons at midnight&lt;/a&gt;,” or “&lt;a href="https://accessibleposts.tumblr.com/post/161902577685/could-you-explain-the-post-about-shoelaces-and"&gt;I like your shoelaces.&lt;/a&gt;” (Though “superwholock” would probably work, too.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BzP8Qd"&gt;When social media became massively multiplayer, to borrow a phrase, that sense of in-group belonging became cringe. Now, you have to advance the meme to participate. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287208/all-your-base-are-belong-to-us-20th-anniversary-internet-culture"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287208/all-your-base-are-belong-to-us-20th-anniversary-internet-culture</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bijan Stephen</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-17T10:01:54-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-17T10:01:54-05:00</updated>
    <title>New York State is suing Amazon for alleged worker safety failures during COVID-19</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6pbwhYTqMB8BRUk1QKN4lTRq4GI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68830160/acastro_190920_1777_amazon_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JiIBG7"&gt;New York Attorney General Letitia James &lt;a href="https://iapps.courts.state.ny.us/nyscef/ViewDocument?docIndex=muvelgaOEvSt6Yc1gGqzAg=="&gt;filed a lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; against Amazon in the state’s supreme court on Tuesday, claiming the company failed to protect its workers early on in the COVID-19 pandemic and also retaliated against employees who voiced concerns over what they felt were inadequate safety measures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R5kD9o"&gt;The news, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/16/technology/amazon-new-york-lawsuit-covid.html"&gt;reported yesterday by &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, follows Amazon’s decision earlier this month to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22279819/amazon-new-york-ag-state-lawsuit-covid-19-warehouse-conditions-pandemic"&gt;preemptively sue the New York AG’s office&lt;/a&gt; in an effort to prevent James from bringing charges, doing so by trying to have jurisdiction over its workplace safety measures in New York be deemed a federal issue not within the purview of the state AG. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4vdFBr"&gt;“Amazon’s extreme profits and exponential growth rate came at the expense of the lives, health and safety of its frontline workers,” James argued in the 31-page complaint. “Amazon’s flagrant disregard for health and safety requirements has threatened serious illness and grave harm to the thousands of workers in these facilities and poses a continued substantial and specific danger to the public health.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oK0Iub"&gt;The complaint cites a number of alleged offenses stemming from Amazon’s treatment of New York City workers at a warehouse facility on Staten Island and a delivery facility in Queens. Those include Amazon’s alleged failure to notify workers in a timely manner of when they had been in contact with employees who tested positive for the coronavirus, Amazon’s alleged inadequate and “legally deficient” contact tracing measures to contain outbreaks, and Amazon’s alleged failure to close down and sanitize parts of its facilities that housed employees who tested positive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="BvlTtj"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Amazon’s extreme profits and exponential growth rate came at the expense of the lives, health and safety of its frontline workers.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eFmeaS"&gt;The complaint also singles out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/10/21216172/amazon-coronavirus-protests-response-safety-jfk8-fired-covid-19"&gt;Amazon’s alleged retaliation against workers&lt;/a&gt;, including fired Staten Island warehouse worker Christian Smalls, who vocally criticized the company’s working conditions and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/30/21199942/amazon-warehouse-coronavirus-covid-new-york-protest-walkout"&gt;helped organized a major March protest&lt;/a&gt; against its handling of the coronavirus. “Amazon employees reasonably fear that if they make legitimate health and safety complaints about Amazon’s Covid-19 response, Amazon will retaliate against them as well,” James wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yr0M75"&gt;Smalls made national headlines last year when, after helping organize the worker protest, he was fired. Amazon said it was because Smalls violated company policy by attending a protest outside the Staten Island facility he worked after he was told to stay home on paid leave because he had been exposed to a co-worker who tested positive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k55OmM"&gt;However, leaked meeting notes &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/5dm8bx/leaked-amazon-memo-details-plan-to-smear-fired-warehouse-organizer-hes-not-smart-or-articulate"&gt;released last spring by &lt;em&gt;Vice News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;showed high-level company executives &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/2/21206108/amazon-chris-smalls-warehouse-strike-nyc-jay-carney-bernie-sanders-coronavirus-safety"&gt;discussing ways to smear Smalls&lt;/a&gt; and use him to discredit growing labor movements seeking to unionize Amazon’s various warehouse and Whole Foods workforces. Smalls is now &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/13/21563996/amazon-organizer-racial-discrimination-lawsuit-warehouse-fulfillment-center"&gt;suing Amazon for racial discrimination&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SpsoB3"&gt;The New York AG suit is asking that Amazon change its policies to better protect worker safety, create new training and safety monitoring protocols, and pay lost wages and damages to James as well as offering to rehire him. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i9HR3c"&gt;In Amazon’s 64-page lawsuit it filed against the AG’s office earlier this month, the company argued it went above and beyond what it was required to do by state law. Amazon said in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The New York Times &lt;/em&gt;that it cared “deeply about the health and safety” of its warehouse employees and that it intended to fight the lawsuit. “We don’t believe the attorney general’s filing presents an accurate picture of Amazon’s industry-leading response to the pandemic,” an Amazon spokesperson said. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287204/new-york-amazon-lawsuit-worker-safety-failures"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287204/new-york-amazon-lawsuit-worker-safety-failures</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-17T09:39:48-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-17T09:39:48-05:00</updated>
    <title>First trailer for Disney’s live-action Cruella movie feels more Joker than 101 Dalmatians</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lM5qY275OBC-aIHh_O1SOWK0NiM=/97x0:1207x740/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68830012/Screen_Shot_2021_02_17_at_8.59.58_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="o7tWpw"&gt;There’s a moment in the first trailer for Disney’s live-action &lt;em&gt;Cruella &lt;/em&gt;movie when Emma Stone utters in a terrible faux British accent, “I am woman, hear me roar.” It feels less like something Disney fans will remember from the iconic &lt;em&gt;101 Dalmatians &lt;/em&gt;villain, Cruella de Vil, and more like Jared Leto’s Joker &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/14/22278944/zack-snyder-justice-league-official-premiere-trailer-hbo-max"&gt;telling Batman, “We live in a society.”&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C0MSzZ"&gt;All of which is to say that Disney may have found its own Joker-type character in Stone’s Cruella de Vil... but not necessarily in a good way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xNrujM"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cruella &lt;/em&gt;is set in 1970s London. Stone plays the soon-to-be-villain in an origin story of sorts. She’s an aspiring punk designer — and a grifter — who is trying to get society’s wealthiest people to take notice of her and her designs. Throughout the process, she becomes the infamous Cruella de Vil. (If that story sounds somewhat familiar, it may be because it’s seemingly very similar to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/loudmouthjulia/status/1362035570843803654"&gt;Jenny Humphrey’s arc in &lt;em&gt;Gossip Girl&lt;/em&gt;’s second season&lt;/a&gt;.) The way Stone is playing the villain also has hints of Joker and Harley Quinn, leaning into the “madness” of the character and upping the dramatics of it all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lagF2R"&gt;Now, of course, this is just a trailer, and we’re all aware that movies aren’t always best represented by their trailers. &lt;em&gt;Cruella &lt;/em&gt;could turn out to be an amazing film; we’ll just have to wait and see. Disney’s track record with live-action films is relatively hit or miss, though. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/11/20690427/lion-king-2019-remake-review-disney-beyonce-donald-glover-james-earl-jones-jon-favreau"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Lion King&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/23/18637207/aladdin-film-review-disney-live-action-remake-will-smith-guy-ritchie-mena-massoud-naomi-scott"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aladdin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Beauty and the Beast &lt;/em&gt;soared to more than $1 billion at the box office, but &lt;em&gt;Dumbo &lt;/em&gt;lost &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167323/disney-live-action-adaptations-plus-streaming-pinocchio-peter-pan-wendy"&gt;Disney a sizable chunk of change&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Mulan &lt;/em&gt;premiered to lackluster reviews. While &lt;em&gt;Cruella &lt;/em&gt;is inspired by &lt;em&gt;101 Dalmatians, &lt;/em&gt;it’s not a direct adaptation. Disney tried the same formula with &lt;em&gt;Maleficent&lt;/em&gt;: while the first film performed well, the follow-up, &lt;em&gt;Maleficent: Mistress of Evil, &lt;/em&gt;underperformed.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SLOSQO"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cruella&lt;/em&gt; is set to be released on May 28th. Currently, it’s due out in theaters, but as Disney CEO Bob Chapek noted on the company’s recent earnings call, things could change with its theatrical slate depending on where the world is at with the current pandemic. That means there’s a chance &lt;em&gt;Cruella &lt;/em&gt;could wind up on &lt;a href="https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/OJDgN" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Disney Plus&lt;/a&gt; either instead of in theaters or alongside a theatrical release. If that does happen, expect more information in the coming weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="UQQj4n"&gt;
&lt;aside id="VuOMPa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Disney Plus","description":"$6.99 per month or $69.99 if you pay annually","label":"Subscribe","url":"https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/OJDgN"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287149/cruella-trailer-disney-emma-stone-live-action-101-dalmations"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287149/cruella-trailer-disney-emma-stone-live-action-101-dalmations</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-17T09:27:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-17T09:27:01-05:00</updated>
    <title>Ecobee adds baby monitoring features to its SmartCamera</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Ecobee SmartCamera" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/v4qq51bHv7-R8H0K-ll6f5tqO9Y=/360x0:2520x1440/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68829934/ecobee_SmartCamera_1.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ecobee SmartCamera.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Ecobee&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YzE2tQ"&gt;Ecobee has updated its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/15/21221291/ecobee-smartcamera-haven-security-platorm-smart-home-price-specs-features"&gt;SmartCamera home security camera&lt;/a&gt; with a few new features that make it easier to use as a baby monitor. The new Baby Monitor mode, which is enabled during setup of the camera, adjusts the camera’s settings to dim the LED lights on the front, makes it harder to accidentally enable the camera’s Siren alarm, and, perhaps most importantly, adds an audio-only streaming option that lets you continue to listen for disruptions even if you switch to a different app or lock your phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lHzDF9"&gt;Using a home security camera as a baby monitor is hardly a new idea, but this is the first one to my knowledge that actually makes it easier to do so. While traditional video monitors provide an always-on feed to a dedicated screen, home security cameras require the use of your phone and an app, which can be slow to load and cumbersome to use. Ecobee’s audio streaming mode effectively turns the camera and your phone into an always-on audio monitor, from which you can then tap into the app to check the video feed when you hear a disturbance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nbBJc4"&gt;The SmartCamera is also compatible with Apple’s HomeKit platform (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/12/2/22149216/ecobee-smart-camera-apple-homekit-support-firmware-update-subscription"&gt;including HomeKit Secure Video&lt;/a&gt;) and Amazon Alexa, which allows you to view the video feed from an Echo smart display or the Home app on an iOS or macOS device. Ecobee’s dedicated app is the only way to access the audio monitoring and other dedicated features such as pan and zoom on the SmartCamera, however.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/m3aOOMt4j-FfXeH4dtwVlPsdfBI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22309580/ecobee_SmartCameraVC_Lullaby_Day.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Ecobee&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The baby monitoring features for the SmartCamera include dimmed LED lights and an audio streaming mode.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="9arFDH"&gt;One thing the new baby monitor features don’t specifically address is the security concerns inherent with aiming an internet-connected camera at your baby’s crib. There have been numerous accounts of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/18/21028092/amazon-ring-camera-hack-password-security-privacy-access-2fa"&gt;security cameras being accessed by an unauthorized user&lt;/a&gt; and children’s privacy being violated through the camera, speaker, and microphone. Ecobee does have two-factor authentication for its accounts, which helps prevent these kinds of attacks, but that might not be enough comfort for some parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EXAWPm"&gt;Ecobee notes that you can switch between the baby monitoring (which disables some of the home security features of the camera) and the standard security camera modes at any time, so once you no longer have the need for a baby monitor, you can repurpose the camera elsewhere in your home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1d2lkx"&gt;In addition to the new baby monitoring features, Ecobee is also now selling a &lt;a href="https://www.ecobee.com/en-us/solutions-exclusives/sweet-dreams-baby-solution/"&gt;bundle that includes a SmartCamera and a SmartThermostat for $299.99&lt;/a&gt;. The SmartCamera is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/ecobee-SmartCamera-Control-Built-Security/dp/B087D6DRCC?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available separately for $99.99&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287144/ecobee-baby-monitor-smartcamera-features-bundle-news"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287144/ecobee-baby-monitor-smartcamera-features-bundle-news</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-17T09:05:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-17T09:05:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to watch today’s Nintendo Direct live stream</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/j2ydYP5OaY5a9cDH0Cz8VU5XJGc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68829852/acastro_190530_1777_nintendo_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustrations by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8UMJyH"&gt;If you’re into gaming, you’ll want to know that Nintendo is hosting a 50-minute live stream today that it calls Nintendo Direct, and the company will focus on games coming to the Switch in 2021. This is the first time the company has hosted a full-fledged Nintendo Direct live stream &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/4/20850031/nintendo-direct-switch-seven-biggest-announcements-news-super-smash-snes-overwatch"&gt;since September 2019&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NZlig5"&gt;Nintendo already confirmed &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1361676737730519042"&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; that it would be announcing information on &lt;em&gt;Super Smash Bros. Ultimate,&lt;/em&gt; but it did not offer any hints, though there’s a good chance we’ll be hearing about a new character for &lt;a href="https://smashbros.nintendo.com/buy/dlc/"&gt;the game’s second Fighter Pass&lt;/a&gt;. Outside of &lt;em&gt;Super Smash Bros. Ultimate&lt;/em&gt;, the live stream will focus on games coming to Nintendo Switch “in the first half of 2021,” leaving fans to speculate what could be shown during the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="J15ClL"&gt;When does the Nintendo Direct start?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="GEHGpB"&gt;The live stream starts today, February 17th, at 2PM PT / 5PM ET / 10PM GMT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="aFoXcC"&gt;Where can I watch the Nintendo Direct?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="CBFWFs"&gt;We have embedded the live stream at the top of this post, so you can stay here to watch it when it begins. Otherwise, today’s Nintendo Direct will be available on &lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/nintendo-direct/02-17-2021/"&gt;Nintendo’s official website&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/nintendo"&gt;Twitch&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pQ-dE_5el5Q"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tpVDkl"&gt;Of course, if you miss the stream, you can find coverage of all the Nintendo news here on &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22285548/nintendo-direct-february-2021-how-to-watch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22285548/nintendo-direct-february-2021-how-to-watch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
