<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-06-09T21:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-09T21:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T21:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sony announces the $9,000 professional drone it teased at CES</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CZZk2-NCnZzRdGUGHnd8eFg33QY=/93x0:1041x632/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69431382/bandicam_2021_01_11_17_16_20_990.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EpBg0p"&gt;Sony is now &lt;a href="https://electronics.sony.com/airpeak"&gt;fully revealing its Airpeak S1 drone&lt;/a&gt;, which it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225758/sony-airpeak-drone-alpha-photography-cameras-ces-2021-announcement"&gt;teased at CES 2021 in January&lt;/a&gt;. The announcement contains a lot more detail on the &lt;a href="https://electronics.sony.com/airpeak/p/arss1"&gt;drone’s capabilities, features&lt;/a&gt;, and reveals a $9,000 pricetag for the drone sans gimbal or camera, all of which cements the idea that this drone will be aimed squarely at the professional video market.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nhMvLMF8hp3_zdH74RRZUC3Ucpc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22649108/Airpeak_ILCE_7SM3_SEL24F14GM_right_under.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Sony&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Airpeak with an A7S and 24mm lens attached to the sold-separately gimbal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="lC4U3o"&gt;The Airpeak S1 is built to work with Sony’s mirrorless cameras, including the A7S Mark III, FX3, or even the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/26/22250448/sony-alpha-1-camera-announced-specs-price-release-date"&gt;8K-capable Alpha 1&lt;/a&gt;. They’ll be attached to a special version of the Gremsy T3 gimbal that’s been designed specifically for the Airpeak and that you’ll have to buy separately. With a camera, the drone will have around 12 minutes of flight time (though it can achieve 22 minutes without any load). It’s also worth noting that the camera needs its own batteries — it isn’t being provided power by the drone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fwHxRZ"&gt;Sony’s already released a preview of the types of shots you can pull off with the drone, which you can see below. You can also get a shot of the retracting landing gear in motion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="SLQfn3"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MKIK4CIQk3g?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="kRxVWe"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/o_XWbHuwsfw?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Smg8ka"&gt;One of the drone’s biggest selling points is its stability and wind-resistance. According to Sony, it can stay stable in winds of up to 44.7 miles per hour (that’s 20m/s, double what &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dji.com%2Finspire-2%2Finfo%23specs&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22526921%2Fsony-airpeak-s1-drone-cinema-video-acceleration-flight-time" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;DJI quotes for the Inspire 2&lt;/a&gt;), and it has five sets of stereo cameras that let the drone and an infrared rangefinder that should help the drone stop before it hits obstacles and stay steady even without satellite reception. Sony even enlisted JAXA, the Japanese space agency, to help it &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8nRI6iVOeiE"&gt;do some of the tests for the drone&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xH7pQ3"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8nRI6iVOeiE?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FgMIsA"&gt;The Airpeak is also quick — it can do 0-50 (which is close to its top speed of 55.9 miles per hour) in 3.5 seconds. It is worth noting, though, that’s without any sort of attachments — Sony hasn’t said what kind of speed or acceleration can be achieved when the drone is flying a camera. That said, Sony showed me and other journalists a video of the drone doing figure-eights in the air, which it pulled off with impressive speed and agility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M3sKYi"&gt;For comparison, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dji.com%2Fmatrice600-pro%2Finfo%23specs&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F9%2F22526921%2Fsony-airpeak-s1-drone-cinema-video-acceleration-flight-time" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;DJI’s Matrice 600 Pro&lt;/a&gt;, which costs around $7,000 without a gimbal or camera, has a top speed of 40 miles per hour and a quoted battery life of 32 minutes alone or 16 minutes with a 13-pound payload, using its stock batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="hKRq2i"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Sony expects to ship the Airpeak in the fall&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="d5Fuak"&gt;The Airpeak S1 can be operated with just the included controller, but Sony has an app called Airpeak Flight to help make things easier. The app is iOS/iPadOS-only for now, but it will allow for control of the camera and gimbal. The Airpeak can be operated by a single person, but also allows for dual-operator mode, where one person controls flight and the other controls the camera. Sony says the controller’s range is still being tested.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Kxl6GQpCM49Ot66RTiWdQacd5MM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22649043/Airpeak_controller_KV_image.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Sony&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The controller with an iPad running Airpeak Flight.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="c2xhdh"&gt;While you won’t get a camera or gimbal for the Airpeak S1’s $9,000 price, it does come with two pairs of propellers, the controller, two batteries, and a charger. Sony expects to ship it in the fall, and will be offering a service plan to cover damage that could occur from crashes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Kl98e"&gt;In light of all the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22463946/dji-drone-ban-pentagon-department-of-interior"&gt;legislation and controversy around drones from China&lt;/a&gt;, Sony is making it clear that the Airpeak S1 is designed and made in Japan; it came up repeatedly in a press briefing and again in the press release.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526921/sony-airpeak-s1-drone-cinema-video-acceleration-flight-time"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526921/sony-airpeak-s1-drone-cinema-video-acceleration-flight-time</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-09T19:21:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T19:21:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>Bitcoin will soon be an official currency in El Salvador</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MpWI6COaVuAjGZqTwmK-EIESaEc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69431111/acastro_181126_1777_bitcoin_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="W5bAId"&gt;El Salvador has passed a resolution to make Bitcoin a legal currency, which makes it the first country to do so (&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/09/el-salvador-bitcoin-legal-tender-congress"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). According to the law, citizens will be able to use Bitcoin to do everything from paying taxes and paying off debts to buying goods and services. The move was championed by President Nayib Bukele, who says it’s a way to help those who don’t have access to banks, and those who want to send money back to the country from abroad, but critics worry that it’ll be more show than substantive change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s3R6wx"&gt;The proposal was passed by El Salvador’s congress on Tuesday night, after Bukele &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/06/05/el-salvador-becomes-the-first-country-to-adopt-bitcoin-as-legal-tender-.html"&gt;announced it at a Bitcoin conference in Miami&lt;/a&gt; last week. It wasn’t a close call, with 62 out of 84 legislators voting for it, but it’s worth noting that Bukele has large amounts of political power in the country — his party makes up a majority of the congress, which allowed him to &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2021/05/20/el-salvadors-president-launched-self-coup-watch-creeping-corruption-authoritarianism/"&gt;take control over much of the government&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="UlL5sp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Bukele wants citizens to think about Bitcoin, not dollars&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AzXGQV"&gt;While Bitcoin will become an official currency for El Salvador in just under three months, it won’t be the only currency — the US dollar, which was previously the country’s only currency, will be sticking around as an option, though &lt;a href="https://cryptonews.com/news/el-salvador-passes-the-bitcoin-law-10617.htm"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Cryptonews&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Bukele said that he wanted the country’s citizens to think about money in terms of Bitcoin, not dollars. The resolution states that citizens should be able to convert between the two currencies at any time, and that US dollars “will be used as the reference currency” for accounting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EDcmIG"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Guardian&lt;/em&gt;, some human rights groups focused on Central America have doubts about Bitcoin’s adoption leading to meaningful change for many of the country’s citizens. One concern is that the nation’s lower class won’t have access to the tech required to use and store Bitcoin. While the law requires anyone offering goods or services to accept Bitcoin, it does &lt;a href="https://cryptonews.com/news/el-salvador-passes-the-bitcoin-law-10617.htm"&gt;have an exception&lt;/a&gt; for those who don’t have access to the technology. The law does say that the government will “promote the necessary training and mechanisms” to allow the population to use Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TZB08w"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I’ve just sent the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BitcoinLaw?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#BitcoinLaw&lt;/a&gt; to Congress    &lt;a href="https://t.co/DljnxsXlyt"&gt;pic.twitter.com/DljnxsXlyt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Nayib Bukele    (@nayibbukele) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nayibbukele/status/1402446890466217985?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OwW3Ah"&gt;The country currently isn’t a large hub for mining Bitcoin — according to &lt;a href="https://cbeci.org/mining_map"&gt;University of Cambridge estimates&lt;/a&gt;, it’s not in the top 10 mining countries. In fact, according to the university’s map, El Salvador’s contributions make up 0.00 percent of the global computing power that’s put towards Bitcoin. Bukele, though, could be looking to change that — &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nayibbukele/status/1402680890057166858?s=20"&gt;he’s tweeted&lt;/a&gt; that the state-owned electric company has been instructed to provide cheap electricity for mining, powered by volcanoes (no, that’s not a joke).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uoxTYJ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I’ve just instructed the president of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LaGeoSV?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@LaGeoSV&lt;/a&gt; (our state-owned geothermal electric company), to put up a plan to offer facilities for &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Bitcoin?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; mining with very cheap, 100% clean, 100% renewable, 0 emissions energy from our volcanos   &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This is going to evolve fast!    &lt;a href="https://t.co/1316DV4YwT"&gt;pic.twitter.com/1316DV4YwT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Nayib Bukele    (@nayibbukele) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nayibbukele/status/1402680890057166858?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526808/el-salvador-bitcoin-currency-first-country-cryptocurrency"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526808/el-salvador-bitcoin-currency-first-country-cryptocurrency</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-09T18:43:56-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T18:43:56-04:00</updated>
    <title>SpaceX’s Starlink is in talks with ‘several’ airlines for in-flight Wi-Fi</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A satellite tracker image is seen displayed on a smartphone..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xgOlc95mKruSQCSb0Vsik56Yj5U=/0x40:3000x2040/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69430933/1229328429.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Pavlo Gonchar/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mS4vVL"&gt;The team behind SpaceX’s growing satellite internet network Starlink is in talks with “several” airlines to beam internet to their airplanes, the project’s vice president said during a conference panel on Wednesday. Expanding Starlink from rural homes and onto airlines is an expected move for Elon Musk’s space company as it races to open the broadband network commercially later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZsmHBp"&gt;“We’re in talks with several of the airlines,” Jonathan Hofeller, SpaceX’s VP of Starlink and commercial sales, told a panel at the Connected Aviation Intelligence Summit on Wednesday. “We have our own aviation product in development… we’ve already done some demonstrations to date, and looking to get that product finalized to be put on aircraft in the very near future.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="9hPQIz"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Aircraft antennas will be like the consumer ones, “with obvious enhancements for aviation connectivity”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dhajbv"&gt;Since 2018, SpaceX has launched nearly 1,800 Starlink satellites out of the roughly 4,400 it needs to provide global coverage of broadband internet, primarily for rural homes where fiber connections aren’t available. The company is in the midst of a Starlink beta phase that promises up to 100Mbps download and 20Mbps upload speeds, with tens of thousands of users so far. Most are paying $99 per month for internet under that beta, using a $499 bundle of a self-aligning Starlink dish and Wi-Fi router. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qXWFp4"&gt;Last year, SpaceX filed plans to &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/11/18/spacex-asks-to-test-starlink-satellite-internet-with-a-gulfstream-jet.html"&gt;test Starlink on five Gulfstream jets&lt;/a&gt;. And in March, SpaceX sought FCC approval to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319761/spacex-starlink-fcc-internet-cars-boats-aircraft"&gt;use Starlink with so-called Earth Stations in Motion&lt;/a&gt; — industry jargon to refer to basically any vehicle that would receive a signal, including cars, trucks, maritime vessels, and aircraft. Musk clarified on Twitter at the time: “Not connecting Tesla cars to Starlink, as our terminal is much too big. This is for aircraft, ships, large trucks &amp;amp; RVs.” Another FCC filing from last Friday requested approval for testing across five US states of an updated receiver with a square-shaped antenna, a basic design commonly associated with aircraft antennae.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2lrSNz"&gt;Hofeller said the design for SpaceX’s airline antennas will be very similar to the technology inside its consumer terminals, but “with obvious enhancements for aviation connectivity.” Like those consumer antennas, the aviation hardware will be designed and built by SpaceX, he said. The airborne antennas could link with ground stations to communicate with Starlink satellites. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="2EJA2T"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Satellites with lasers to work with flights far over oceans&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hOf5aW"&gt;For Starlink to provide connectivity to airplanes flying over remote parts of the ocean, far from ground stations, will require inter-satellite links — a capability in which satellites talk to each other using laser links without first bouncing signals off ground stations. “The next generation of our constellation, which is in work, will have this inter-satellite connectivity,” Hofeller said.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket lifts off from pad 40 at the Cape..." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kJbNMcaLnb4SdxcbGyIdv3JjJBg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22648855/1233127360.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Paul Hennessy/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;SpaceX launched its 29th batch of Starlink satellites from Florida on May 26th&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="raneDo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22251127/elon-musk-bezos-amazon-billionaires-satellites-space"&gt;Competition is fierce&lt;/a&gt; between Musk’s Starlink network and the growing industry of low-orbit satellite internet providers. New competitors include so-called mega-constellations from Jeff Bezos’ Amazon, which has yet to launch any of its planned 3,000 satellites, and the UK’s OneWeb, which has launched 182 satellites of roughly 640 planned. All of those satellites will be in low-Earth orbit, a domain below the more distant geostationary orbits of larger internet satellites that currently provide internet services to commercial aircraft. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="8cr8V3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Passengers and customers want a great experience that [geostationary] systems simply cannot provide”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4z5BGD"&gt;Established US competitors for in-flight internet are Intelsat and ViaSat, which operate networks of satellites in geostationary orbit. ViaSat &lt;a href="https://www.viasat.com/about/newsroom/press-releases/delta-selects-viasats-flight-connectivity-revolutionize-customer/"&gt;recently announced&lt;/a&gt; plans to use its next-generation satellite network on Delta’s mainline fleet. The California-based company is planning a 300-satellite low-orbit network of its own as well as a new geostationary trio that will start launching early next year. It is already a diehard competitor to SpaceX. ViaSat has threatened to sue the Federal Communications Commission for not doing an environmental review on a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22405779/fcc-approves-spacex-starlink-lower-orbits-against-amazon-rival-objections"&gt;recent Starlink modification&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f2UJe2"&gt;SpaceX appears confident that it can outlast the more established competition. “All in all, passengers and customers want a great experience that [geostationary] systems simply cannot provide,” Hofeller said on the panel. “So it’s going to be up to the individual airline whether they want to be responsive to that, or if they’re okay with having a system that is not as responsive to their customers’ demand.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="FJHnTD"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Timeline TBD&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jwsbWH"&gt;OneWeb, which was pulled out of bankruptcy last year by the UK government and Indian telecom giant Bharti Global, is also targeting in-flight internet services with its constellation and has been &lt;a href="https://www.satellitetoday.com/mobility/2021/03/19/oneweb-selects-satixfy-to-build-leo-geo-in-flight-connectivity-terminal/"&gt;far more public&lt;/a&gt; with its plans than SpaceX. Asked by the panel moderator when customers can expect to use in-flight internet with any of the competing satellite networks currently expanding in low-Earth orbit, OneWeb’s VP of mobility services Ben Griffin estimated “the middle part of next year… maybe sooner.” Airlines want to see developed hardware and services that work first, he added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MUltO9"&gt;“We have been talking to airlines for quite some time, so there’s no lack of interest,” Griffin said during the same panel. SpaceX’s Hofeller was cagey when the question turned to him — “What Ben said is correct. People want to see the hardware, they wanna see the constellation, and so we’re driving that hard as fast as we can. When the announcement will be? To be determined. Don’t know. Hopefully sooner rather than later.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Qw8Yv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526601/elon-musk-spacex-starlink-internet-talks-commercial-airlines-in-flight-wifi"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526601/elon-musk-spacex-starlink-internet-talks-commercial-airlines-in-flight-wifi</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-09T18:09:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T18:09:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>Say goodbye to the Keystone XL pipeline, for real this time </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Biden Blocking Keystone Threatens To End Mega Pipelines Era" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PCPC_DnJyTctBN_5qAo-qAyrE8Q=/0x32:4607x3103/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69430795/1230819697.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Crews work on a right of way for the Keystone XL pipeline near Oyen, Alberta, Canada, on Wednesday, Jan. 27, 2021. U.S. President Joe Biden revoked the permit for TC Energy Corp.’s Keystone XL energy pipeline via executive order hours after his inauguration, the clearest sign yet that constructing a major new pipeline in the U.S. has become an impossible task. | Jason Franson/Bloomberg via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jHNrnw"&gt;It’s official: the Keystone XL is going away for good. The pipeline’s developer &lt;a href="https://www.tcenergy.com/announcements/2021-06-09-tc-energy-confirms-termination-of-keystone-xl-pipeline-project/"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; Wednesday that it’s terminating the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6BYOfC"&gt;For years, the Obama, Trump, and Biden administrations have gone back and forth on allowing the massive transcontinental project to move forward. On his first day in office, Joe Biden &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/20/22240466/joe-biden-keystone-xl-pipeline-canceled-executive-order-climate-change"&gt;canceled&lt;/a&gt; the Presidential Permit that his predecessor had granted. Apparently, that was the nail in Keystone XL’s coffin. Soon after, TC Energy suspended work on the project to &lt;a href="https://www.tcenergy.com/announcements/2021-01-20-tc-energy-disappointed-with-expected-executive-action-revoking-keystone-xl-presidential-permit/"&gt;“consider its options,”&lt;/a&gt; but hadn’t fully given up on the pipeline until now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F6rpxB"&gt;“We took on a multi-billion dollar corporation and we won!” Dallas Goldtooth, an organizer for the nonprofit Indigenous Environmental Network &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dallasgoldtooth/status/1402730374682320898"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt;. “The People made this happen!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="yk4NZU"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The People made this happen!”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="41Vzrr"&gt;Native American tribes and activists fought the project for more than ten years. The Rosebud Sioux Tribe, and the Assiniboine and Gros Ventre tribes of the Fort Belknap Indian Reservation &lt;a href="https://www.narf.org/cases/keystone/"&gt;sued&lt;/a&gt; the Trump administration after it granted the Keystone XL a permit to continue construction. The pipeline threatened their lands and water sources, and the Trump administration didn’t properly consult with the tribes, they said in the suit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P6krWo"&gt;The $8 billion pipeline would have pumped 830,000 barrels of crude oil from Alberta, Canada’s tar sands to Nebraska, where it would connect with other pipelines that reach the Gulf Coast. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KxO8vQ"&gt;Prior to TC Energy’s announcement today, a lot of construction on the pipeline had already taken place in Canada. The company has &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-biden-keystone/tc-energy-cuts-jobs-as-keystone-pipeline-nixed-but-markets-start-to-move-on-idUSKBN29Q1T8"&gt;laid off&lt;/a&gt; hundreds of workers since suspending work on the project this year. But neither President Obama nor Biden worried much about taking away American jobs by killing the pipeline. It only would have resulted in 35 full-time permanent jobs in the US once construction was done, according to a State Department &lt;a href="https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Record-of-Decision-and-National-Interest-Determination.pdf"&gt;analysis&lt;/a&gt;. Climate change, made worse by new oil and gas projects, was a bigger threat to American livelihoods, both administrations argued. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="ek2kas"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Pipeline opponents are far from kicking back and relaxing&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3ugxSo"&gt;Despite the victory against Keystone XL, pipeline opponents are far from kicking back and relaxing. Protests escalated this week against Enbridge’s Line 3 pipeline, which also runs from Alberta to the midwest of the US. Enbridge wants to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21356423/oil-gas-pipelines-abandoned-enbridge-line-3"&gt;abandon the existing pipeline and replace it&lt;/a&gt; with a new one that can carry twice as much crude oil. At least 100 hundred people were arrested during demonstrations this week, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/07/climate/line-3-pipeline-protest-native-americans.html?utm_campaign=Hot%20News&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;_hsmi=132390695&amp;amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz--k05Jk303667-goxaNNuqqLCl3uyzu9enH0Y97YfDZURCOo-bMud78yeHzeQ1PNhtkAI_QTtx4w9F7L0hzZ2jEz8ch1MJkoS4eSitm5LHOekJkutg&amp;amp;utm_content=132390695&amp;amp;utm_source=hs_email"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d5RBa1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526790/keystone-xl-pipeline-tc-energy-terminates"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526790/keystone-xl-pipeline-tc-energy-terminates</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-09T17:38:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T17:38:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Watch the first five minutes of Netflix’s Philippine folklore anime Trese</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cjvl8kd26nujyvkMtZZzsGavBz4=/0x13:1387x938/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69430596/Screen_Shot_2021_06_09_at_2.15.44_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jQO8P8"&gt;Netflix has released the first five minutes of its upcoming anime series &lt;em&gt;Trese&lt;/em&gt;, which is based on the Philippine horror comic of the same name. &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/RKuSsvKjPBQ"&gt;In the clip&lt;/a&gt; (which I’ve embedded at the top of this post), you’ll get a brief look at some of the show’s terrifying-looking monsters and be introduced to detective Alexandra Trese, the show’s protagonist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E35JYO"&gt;Here’s the official synopsis of &lt;em&gt;Trese&lt;/em&gt;, from Netflix:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="Vr5XwX"&gt;Set in Manila where the mythical creatures of Philippine folklore live in hiding amongst humans, Alexandra Trese finds herself going head to head with a criminal underworld composed of malevolent supernatural beings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="VRONHA"&gt;Count me intrigued. The monsters seem quite scary, and I love the supernatural elements hinted at even in these initial minutes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wgR63N"&gt;If you’re interested in another look at &lt;em&gt;Trese&lt;/em&gt; before it premieres, &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/3IhCjxVjM-A"&gt;check out this trailer, from May&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jzZf1L"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3IhCjxVjM-A?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ulMNkL"&gt;And you won’t have to wait long to watch the show itself: &lt;em&gt;Trese&lt;/em&gt; will begin streaming in the US on June 10th at 12PM ET. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526762/netflix-trese-philippine-folklore-anime-horror-comic"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526762/netflix-trese-philippine-folklore-anime-horror-comic</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-09T16:01:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T16:01:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple may have accidentally confirmed the existence of an M1X MacBook Pro</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TQZIHF05TX0m46MhjejfbxYvORg=/0x1:1020x681/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69429868/retina-macbook-pro-15-stock_1020.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Not the new MacBook Pro, but it does have ports that are tipped to return!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GWELYT"&gt;Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference keynote came and went this year without a new MacBook Pro — but it looks like that wasn’t the original intent! Intriguingly, Apple quietly included the phrases “M1X MacBook Pro” and “M1X” as tags &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0TD96VTf0Xs"&gt;on its YouTube video&lt;/a&gt; of the live keynote, as spotted &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/maxbalzer_/status/1402626084265500679"&gt;by Max Balzer&lt;/a&gt; (via &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/06/09/m1x-macbook-pro-referenced-in-metadata-for-apples-wwdc-youtube-video/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cl9C5u"&gt;Not only does that sound like tacit confirmation of at least one new Arm-powered MacBook Pro, it also corroborates the rumors that it’ll include a new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"&gt;M1 chip&lt;/a&gt;, and that Apple will likely market it as an enhanced “X” variant, like it used to do with its high-end iPads, rather than going straight to M2. (Or, as some are pointing out, it could mean that someone on the social media team decided to try for an SEO boost and made it up.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OtQeP6"&gt;Three weeks ago, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-18/apple-readies-macbook-pro-macbook-air-revamps-with-faster-chips?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;’s Mark Gurman reported&lt;/a&gt; that we’d see redesigned 14- and 16-inch MacBook Pros “as early as this summer,” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22441805/apple-macbook-pro-2021-redesign-chip-magsafe-sd-card-slot-hdmi-port"&gt;ones that would&lt;/a&gt; bring back the SD card slot, HDMI port, and some form of the beloved trip-friendly MagSafe charging connector; offer twice as many high-performance CPU and GPU cores; and support up to 64GB of RAM. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22441805/apple-macbook-pro-2021-redesign-chip-magsafe-sd-card-slot-hdmi-port"&gt;I really thought&lt;/a&gt; announcing them at WWDC would be the perfect way to distract from recent developer turmoil — you know, by announcing a MacBook Pro that’s actually for pros? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IqEEJD"&gt;Perhaps that was the original idea, but we got an absolutely jam-packed keynote filled with rapid-fire software announcements instead. Check out our supercut below for the condensed video version, or read &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22461782/apple-wwdc-2021-recap-biggest-announcements-ios-15-macos-monterey-ipados"&gt;our list of the 15 biggest WWDC 2021 announcements&lt;/a&gt; if you only want the highlights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6ptwKW"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="WWDC 2021|102453" data-volume-uuid="7c6d9d097" data-volume-id="102453" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-810" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hcpC2U"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, 6:11PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added the possibility that Apple just wanted to boost this video in search by adding some words that might draw attention.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JEXRxX"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/6/9/22526584/apple-m1x-macbook-pro-wwdc-2021-youtube-tags"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/6/9/22526584/apple-m1x-macbook-pro-wwdc-2021-youtube-tags</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-09T15:50:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T15:50:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to sign up for Amazon Prime</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oO5UJPWxRGnemSkYKJptONRieVI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67558532/acastro_190920_1777_amazon_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8NVy7p"&gt;Amazon has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22459166/amazon-prime-day-dates-2021-june-21-22"&gt;announced that its annual Prime Day sales&lt;/a&gt; are scheduled for Monday, June 21st and Tuesday, June 22nd; and if you feel as if it hasn’t been a year since the last event — you’re right, it hasn’t. Last year, Prime Day happened on October 13th and 14th, three months later than usual, due to the coronavirus pandemic. But this year we’re back on schedule, and as before, Amazon will be dropping prices on a lot of its products for its Prime members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rspoie"&gt;If you’re attracted by the goodies being offered, but you haven’t signed up for Amazon Prime, don’t worry — Amazon makes it very easy. (As you’d expect, it’s the sorry vendor who makes it difficult for people to become new customers.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="zWYyYc"&gt;&lt;q&gt;If you’re attracted by the goodies being offered, but you haven’t signed up for Prime, Amazon makes it very easy&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gDfTNw"&gt;Besides giving access to Prime Day bargains, Amazon has come up with a bunch of features to entice people to sign up to its Prime service. These include: access to &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/video/offers/ref=dvm_us_dl_sl_go_bre_pv3%7Cm_fx5Xv4Gzc_c283448910618?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;gclid=EAIaIQobChMI8vra9fSO7AIVBYzICh2iCwVvEAAYASAAEgKjRfD_BwE"&gt;Prime Video&lt;/a&gt;, its streaming video service; free and faster shipping on purchases (with two-day delivery for many items and even same-day delivery for some); deals on Whole Foods Market purchases; &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/music/prime/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;amp;tag=vergeprimeday2020-20&amp;amp;linkId=46eaa59bb05a9daba4acebf10b46851a&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Music Prime&lt;/a&gt; audio streaming (not to be confused with the more extensive &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/music/unlimited/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;amp;tag=vergeprimeday2020-20&amp;amp;linkId=15f5459988c93e83f0521487ba3ddcb0&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Music Unlimited&lt;/a&gt;, which is an additional $7.99 / month for Prime members); &lt;a href="https://gaming.amazon.com/"&gt;Prime Gaming&lt;/a&gt;, which includes a free Twitch channel subscription; online photo storage; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/kindle-dbs/fd/nonprime-pr/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;amp;tag=vergeprimeday2020-20&amp;amp;linkId=3453c898c7d4320f5a93927ef67342a7&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Prime Reading&lt;/a&gt;, which gives access to a library of comics, books, and magazines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p8rgTa"&gt;You can share your Prime account — and all of its features — with one other adult. And you get a 30-day free trial, so you can try it (and the Prime Day specials) out to see if it suits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wPx9a3"&gt;Here’s how to sign up. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Besides its basic plan, Amazon offers video-only and plans for students and EBT / Medicaid users." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Qf5uq-6iasMm3FSTxILt4KP_5jc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22648311/Screen_Shot_2021_06_09_at_3.05.07_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Besides its basic Prime plan, Amazon offers video-only and plans for students and those who need government assistance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="b1Dj0b"&gt;Choose a plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="QnVQLn"&gt;Go to &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/amazonprime/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;amp;tag=vergeprimeday2020-20&amp;amp;linkId=f5f16070348e679ef06293594236789e&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.amazon.com/amazonprime&lt;/a&gt; and click on the link “See More Plans”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wpBSAT"&gt;Choose which plan you want. The basic plan lets you sign up for the service at $12.99 / month or $119 / year, which comes out to a little under $10 / month. You can also sign up for Prime Video alone at $8.99 / month, but you won’t get to take part in Prime Day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="e0dZ8i"&gt;If you’re a student, then click on the link that asks “Are you a student?” and sign up for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/amazonprime/ref=as_li_ss_tl?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;ms3_c=600582d1095766e4464395cc51032f4d&amp;amp;planOptimizationId=WLPStudentMonthlyEligiblePlans&amp;amp;primeCampaignId=studentWlpPrimeRedir&amp;amp;ref_=st_wlp_pr_redir&amp;amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;amp;tag=vergeprimeday2020-20&amp;amp;linkId=59c82cb7919cb9e3f1c423375b423d16&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Prime Student&lt;/a&gt;. You’ll get a free six-month trial subscription and after that, you’ll only have to pay $6.49 a month. You also get some extra discounts, such as Showtime for 99 cents a month (up to a year), Amazon Music Unlimited for 99 cents a month, and a two-month trial of Kindle Unlimited.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kanQp6"&gt;If you’re on government assistance or use an Electronic Benefits Transfer (EBT) card, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/58f8026f-0658-47d0-9752-f6fa2c69b2e2/qualify/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ref=us_lt35_prime_desktop&amp;amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;amp;tag=vergeprimeday2020-20&amp;amp;linkId=60e0e4a6adcecd8761a4c1fd3e75cb8e&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;you can also join for less&lt;/a&gt;: $5.99 a month. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LIXrkR"&gt;Is it your birthday soon? If you have a generous friend or relative, they can &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/prime/pipeline/prime_gifting_landing/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl&amp;amp;&amp;amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;amp;tag=vergeprimeday2020-20&amp;amp;linkId=ab3b8b77f7aea3069296141b6845a104&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;gift you with a Prime membership&lt;/a&gt; for either three months ($39) or the full year ($119).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="b3jpMU"&gt;Create an account&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="tSvuaZ"&gt;Once you’ve decided what plan you’re going to go with, then you’ll need an Amazon account. If you don’t already have one, you’ll need to sign up. Click on “Try Prime” and then “Create your Amazon account” and set one up with your name, email, and password. We strongly recommend &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22215571/factor-authentication-2fa-apple-microsoft-google-how-to"&gt;setting up two-factor authentication&lt;/a&gt; for your account as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BOLtQ6"&gt;On the next page, Amazon will verify your account by sending what it calls an OTP (one-time password) to your email. Go to your email, copy the OTP, paste it in the Amazon page, and click on “Verify.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="CO2STr"&gt;You’ll then be asked to enter your credit or debit card information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vEsood"&gt;And you’re done!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="8pyhmz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Verge Deals on Twitter","description":"Keep up with our best tech deals daily on Twitter with @vergedeals","label":"Follow us!","url":"http://bit.ly/2JzR5Ud"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="XSTxeG"&gt;We should probably mention the obvious: you can sign up for a Prime membership, take advantage of the free 30-day trial, and then cancel it after the Prime Day sales are over. But you can only do that once — and you may regret that decision next year when Prime Day comes around again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZffU9B"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update June 9th, 2021, 3:30PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article was originally published on July 10th, 2019, and it has been changed to reflect updated information about Amazon Prime.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21493780/amazon-prime-sign-up-day-deals-sale-price-free"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21493780/amazon-prime-sign-up-day-deals-sale-price-free</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-09T15:40:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T15:40:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>The best deals on MacBooks right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The MacBook Air is the most impressive laptop I’ve used in years" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hZX5JfVeNbOPhxgT-vEb8Xev40E=/2x0:2039x1358/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69195507/vpavic_4291_20201113_0337_Edit.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacBook Air (late-2020).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="p1z5Ah"&gt;With multiple configurations and various models to choose from, including some equipped with Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/19/21574057/apple-m1-chips-laptop-performance-intel-qualcomm-competition"&gt;new M1 processor&lt;/a&gt;, finding a deal on a MacBook or Mac Mini is not all that difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i5kEtb"&gt;We’ll run through discounts currently available for the latest MacBook models as well as any deals to be had on the Mac Mini. Of course, there are also frequent discounts available for older Intel-based configurations — all of which will be compatible with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22458628/apple-macos-12-monterey-features-updates-wwdc-2021"&gt;macOS Monterey&lt;/a&gt; upon its release in the fall — and we’ll also highlight those when we find them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7QDx7u"&gt;Alternatively, purchasing refurbished is another way to save money on an Apple computer. &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1022323/7613?sharedid=VergeBestDealsAppleMacbook042721&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Frefurbished%2Fmac" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple’s refurbished store&lt;/a&gt; provides a one-year warranty on all products and generally has discounts of 15- to 20-percent off the price of a new model. Two other retailers to look at for refurbished MacBooks are &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1738963691650209208#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/certified-refurbished-apple-macbook/s?k=certified+refurbished+apple+macbook" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, the latter of which is currently lining up deals ahead of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22459166/amazon-prime-day-dates-2021-june-21-22" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Prime Day&lt;/a&gt;, which takes place on June 21st and 22nd. However, for now, these are the best MacBook and Mac Mini deals you can take advantage of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="EVXzol"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MacBook Air&lt;/a&gt; deals &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="aqfkV0"&gt;The MacBook Air is Apple’s entry-level laptop. It’s best suited for typical productivity work, with a comfortable keyboard, excellent trackpad, and all-day battery life. The most recent model includes the Apple-designed M1 processor and lacks a fan for quiet, efficient performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="FJU3RG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9737407"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LZawtk"&gt;The base configuration of MacBook Air with the M1 chip has 8GB of RAM and 256GB of SSD and typically sells for $999. Right now, you can get it for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5LNQCX?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$949 ($50 off) at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. The retail giant also has the 512GB configuration on sale in &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5M9XBS/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;gold for $1,149&lt;/a&gt; ($100 off), as does &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="RDkNac"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best Apple Watch deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21289209/best-apple-watch-deals"},{"title":"Here are the best iPad deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21280354/best-ipad-deals-apple"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="DTHGG6"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="JByVWG"&gt;The MacBook Pro comes in more sizes and options than the Air, and it’s more geared toward demanding use cases. The base model is the 13-inch &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;M1-powered variant&lt;/a&gt;, which includes a brighter screen and longer battery life compared to the M1 Air. The M1 MacBook Pro 13 normally starts at $1,299, but the base model with 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage is on sale for $100 off at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5N6RSS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1738975458064148072#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="afDps1"&gt;The upgraded, silver version of the M1-touting MacBook Pro with 8GB of RAM and a 512GB SSD is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08N5LH3F7/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$150 off at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. The space gray variant, which typically retails for $1,499 alongside the silver model, is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08N5LM1K3/?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$100 off at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1742946215000206869#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, bringing it to $1,399. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="44XxWs"&gt;Of course, you can also buy some older MacBook Pro models, including the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21256520/apple-13-inch-macbook-pro-2020-review-keyboard-specs-price-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;13-inch mid-2020 model&lt;/a&gt;. The older device features four Thunderbolt ports, Ice Lake processors, a new keyboard, increased RAM, and various storage configurations. Right now, you can save $200 on the 13-inch model at Amazon, which is available in two configurations: a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-Storage-Keyboard/dp/B0881Z844Y?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;10th Gen i7 Intel processor and 512GB of storage&lt;/a&gt; for $1,600 at Amazon, or you can buy one with &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-Storage-Keyboard/dp/B08821TJLG?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;1TB of storage and a 2.0GHz 10th Gen Intel Core i5&lt;/a&gt; processor for $1,800 at Amazon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="J3a3Uu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9733800"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hij1MQ"&gt;If you want a bigger laptop with more horsepower, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/21/20974649/apple-macbook-pro-16-inch-laptop-review-keyboard-test-specs-price-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MacBook Pro 16&lt;/a&gt; is the top-of-the-line model. Compared to its predecessor, it has a better keyboard, newer processors, and improved speakers. B&amp;amp;H Photo currently has an Intel Core i7 CPU and 512GB of storage configuration in both &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1520434-REG%2Fapple_mvvj2ll_a_16_macbook_pro_late.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22399419%2Fapple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;space gray&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1520436-REG%2Fapple_mvvl2ll_a_16_macbook_pro_late.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22399419%2Fapple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;silver&lt;/a&gt; on sale for $2,199 ($200 off). There are other configurations available with more storage and quicker processors, however, not at a discount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zjWXtS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10469149"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="LYpjlZ"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21570046/apple-mac-mini-2020-m1-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Mac Mini&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Un7j7n"&gt;While it is not an Apple laptop, the Mac Mini is an affordable desktop computer with macOS. It does not include a display, keyboard, or mouse (so you’ll have to supply your own), but this compact machine is an excellent performer if you aren’t concerned about portability. It’s fast, efficient, and comes outfitted with Wi-Fi 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O9PC7b"&gt;Like the MacBook Air and MacBook Pro 13, the Mini features Apple’s new M1 processor. It starts at $699, with the price varying based on your RAM and storage configurations. We’ve seen the base model drop to as low as $600, which is its current price at &lt;a href="https://www.costco.com/mac-mini-%e2%80%93-apple-m1-chip-8-core-cpu%2c-8-core-gpu-%e2%80%93-8gb-memory-%e2%80%93-256gb-ssd-%e2%80%93%E2%80%94silver.product.100694159.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Costco&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08N5PHB83?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; right now (coupon applied at checkout).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="RPnQwi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9712859"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="APBdOd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22399419/apple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22399419/apple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
      <name>Brandon Widder</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-09T15:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T15:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The creator economy is running into the Apple Tax — this startup is fighting back</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The name “Fanhouse” on a tie-dye background. The H is shaped like a house." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3b6H9XwVqaUOTS2WG2nxLnA3Sqw=/0x342:2048x1707/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69429382/EvRNO57WYAEsngW.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The logo for Fanhouse, a platform that lets creators charge for access to a private social feed. | Image: Fanhouse&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VxoadZ"&gt;Apple is clashing with the platform &lt;a href="https://fanhouse.app/"&gt;Fanhouse&lt;/a&gt; over whether it gets to take a cut of in-app payments to creators. The incident underscores just how little Apple understands about the creator economy, with the likely outcome being less money in creators’ pockets — and more money for one of the world’s most profitable corporations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rQfXy8"&gt;Founders of Fanhouse — which is basically OnlyFans without the nudity — say the platform will be kicked out of the App Store in August if it doesn’t start forking over 30 percent of the fees people pay creators when purchases are made through the iPhone app. One of Fanhouse’s creators, the streamer &lt;a href="https://fanhouse.app/breadwitchery/fanwall"&gt;Breadwitchery&lt;/a&gt;, says that cut would mean losing two months of rent from her earnings to date. The company doesn’t have a lot of options to push back, but it’s &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jasminericegirl/status/1402691047940100100"&gt;launching a campaign today&lt;/a&gt; to pressure Apple into easing its rules around payments to creators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="D37kCi"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I use this to pay the bills for my family.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aMflPk"&gt;Fanhouse is only the latest company to clash with Apple over App Store terms that are increasingly viewed as steep and domineering. Sure, it’s a small app, and its disappearance won’t necessarily cause problems for Apple, but the situation speaks to the challenges creator-focused apps face in the App Store. As the creator economy continues to grow, the rules mean Apple will be taking more money from not just businesses, but individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oVCxDY"&gt;“People are using this platform to survive, starting with me, our very first creator,” Jasmine Rice, &lt;a href="https://fanhouse.app/jasminericegirl/fanwall"&gt;a Fanhouse creator&lt;/a&gt; and one of the platform’s co-founders, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge.&lt;/em&gt; “I use this to pay the bills for my family. I use this to pay my mom’s medical expenses.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3EtD4I"&gt;Fanhouse, which launched in 2020, initially slipped past the App Store bouncers and offered payments on the web without issue. Now that Apple has spotted the potential for profit, it’s given Fanhouse the same ultimatum it gives (almost) everyone else: Fanhouse either needs to pay up or get booted from the store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="vVpFM6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple often takes a larger cut than the actual platforms&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bc2LQV"&gt;The app only takes a 10 percent cut on its own, so the platform’s creators could soon be earning a whole lot less. Rice says she would be okay with handing Apple a 30 percent cut of Fanhouse’s own profits. But once that 30 percent has to cut into creators’ profits, it starts to hurt &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt;, not just the platform. “This money really means a second job for some people, that they have a place to live, that they can afford tuition,” Rice says. “And we tried to explain this to Apple.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lsCEqe"&gt;Fanhouse allows creators to charge a subscription for access to a private social media feed where they can post updates about their life or publish photos and videos. Creators can also earn money from tips, or they can post “locked” updates that fans need to pay to view. Each account also has a public feed that can be viewed without a subscription, which may be why the app was able to slip through the App Store unnoticed until now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fojC0h"&gt;Apple told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;it’s working with Fanhouse to bring the app into compliance with its rules. The company referred to &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/#in-app-purchase"&gt;its in-app purchase guidelines&lt;/a&gt; and said Fanhouse was rejected previously because of a similar violation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ue8vgJ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/fuckapple?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#fuckapple&lt;/a&gt;, a thread&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I cofounded &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fanhouseapp?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@fanhouseapp&lt;/a&gt; 8 months ago to empower creators to monetize their content. We pay creators 90% of earnings. Now, Apple is threatening to remove Fanhouse from the app store unless we give them 30% of creator earnings. This is theft and exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;— jasmine   (@jasminericegirl) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jasminericegirl/status/1402691047940100100?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ciuIBg"&gt;Apple requires a 30 percent cut from in-app purchases of “digital” goods, such as &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; skins or Netflix subscriptions, though it has a number of exceptions. The figure is reduced to 15 percent for multiyear subscriptions and apps that earn under $1 million. (Fanhouse has more than $1 million in revenue, but it pays nearly all of it out to creators.) And it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/17/21293813/apple-app-store-policies-hey-30-percent-developers-the-trial-by-franz-kafka"&gt;up to Apple to decide&lt;/a&gt; what qualifies as a “digital” good and what doesn’t. For instance, Apple allows Patreon to offer third-party payment solutions for creators rather than use in-app purchases, avoiding the fee. Other apps aren’t afforded that privilege. Apple and Patreon did not respond to a request for comment on the arrangement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="QkpcIF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I think it speaks to a creator illiteracy.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wAnZPt"&gt;Apple’s App Store rules didn’t even acknowledge creators &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523332/apple-app-store-guidelines-change-wwdc-2021-fraud-scam-creators-marijuana-law-roblox"&gt;until this week&lt;/a&gt;. On Monday, they were updated with a new section saying that creator-made content and experiences are allowed in apps — so long as they’re properly moderated and monetized for Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JOP5P3"&gt;The problem is likely to become more acute as platforms offer more ways for creators to get paid. Twitter plans to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447328/twitter-ticketed-spaces-monetization-stripe-approval"&gt;take a 20 percent cut&lt;/a&gt; from ticketed audio rooms later this year, from which Apple will take another 30 percent if fans pay on their iPhones. Facebook is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522706/facebook-creators-apple-google-fees-payment-interface-events"&gt;waiving its cut&lt;/a&gt; for the next year on fan subscriptions and other sources of creator revenue, but Apple will still be taking 30 percent when purchases are made through its store. Twitch already hands Apple a 30 percent cut of subscriptions and tips made through iOS, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/18/20921448/twitch-subscription-ios-app-store-price"&gt;it hikes prices there&lt;/a&gt; so that viewers have to cover the added costs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xZzZqi"&gt;Other creator-focused services simply aren’t offered on iOS because of Apple’s rules: Spotify doesn’t let listeners &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22404273/spotify-podcast-subscriptions-monetize-subscriber-shows"&gt;pay for podcast subscriptions&lt;/a&gt;, despite offering them, and OnlyFans isn’t available on the platform at all because of Apple’s ban on “overtly sexual or pornographic material.” The newsletter &lt;em&gt;Means of Creation&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://every.to/means-of-creation/apple-is-holding-back-the-creator-economy"&gt;criticized these policies last month&lt;/a&gt;, writing that “Apple is now one of the main barriers to independent creators thriving on the internet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uDAm7R"&gt;Apple is currently caught in a legal battle with Epic, the maker of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite,&lt;/em&gt; over its App Store fees. Apple is happy with its cut: it brought in $64 billion in revenue last year, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/01/08/apples-app-store-had-gross-sales-around-64-billion-in-2020.html"&gt;according to a CNBC analysis&lt;/a&gt;. During the trial, Apple CEO Tim Cook said that allowing other payment options “would in essence give up our total return on our IP.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="32RExv"&gt;“I think it speaks to a creator illiteracy,” says Breadwitchery, a narrative games streamer who works part time as a community manager for Fanhouse. “Those corporations like Apple, do you not think that if you invest in creators and treat them well, they’re going to be motivated to make more content and make more money?”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525904/fanhouse-apple-tax-app-store-creator-fees"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525904/fanhouse-apple-tax-app-store-creator-fees</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-09T14:38:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T14:38:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>Former VW, Audi bosses to pay Volkswagen millions over Dieselgate</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Volkswagen AG Headquarters Ahead of 2020 Earnings Announcement" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NLhbQcmAwnJCv_yeUpSv_I4s7oA=/0x0:3854x2569/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69429239/1231393493.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kt3hC1"&gt;Volkswagen will &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/volkswagen-reaches-351-mln-dieselgate-settlement-with-former-execs-2021-06-09/"&gt;receive around $350 million&lt;/a&gt; as part of a settlement with executives who ran the company during the Dieselgate emissions cheating scandal, after claiming they breached their “duty of care.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1IVJrU"&gt;Former CEO Martin Winterkorn has agreed to pay the company 11.2 million euro ($13.6 million), while former Audi boss Rupert Stadler will pay Volkswagen 4.1 million euro ($5 million). Volkswagen will also receive smaller amounts from two other managers who were implicated in the scandal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3w5cZx"&gt;Most of the rest of the money — some 270 million euros (nearly $330 million) — will come from what’s known as “directors’ and officers’ insurance,” or D&amp;amp;O insurance, which normally helps protect executives from individual liability but can also be used to reimburse a company for legal fees and other costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yn8nYW"&gt;The payout is a pittance compared to the $40 billion in fines, court fees, and settlements that Volkswagen has paid to date to resolve the scandal or the $86 billion it has spent on electric vehicles since. But it’s another sign that the company and its executives, current and former, are still dealing with the fallout of Dieselgate — even if that means paying the company, which &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/volkswagen-ag-agrees-plead-guilty-and-pay-43-billion-criminal-and-civil-penalties-six"&gt;itself pled guilty in 2017&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="swjdNo"&gt;News of the settlement comes from &lt;a href="https://www.volkswagenag.com/presence/investorrelation/publications/sonstrechtlangelegentheiten/2021/Preliminary%20report.pdf"&gt;a 62-page preliminary report&lt;/a&gt; examining the executives’ roles in the scandal, which saw Volkswagen and many of its sub-brands install “defeat devices” that made diesel vehicles look less dirty to regulators. The board’s report follows &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/26/22352646/volkswagen-dieselgate-investigation-damages-winterkorn-audi"&gt;a massive third-party investigation that wrapped in March&lt;/a&gt;, which has not been released to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3BHGW2"&gt;Notably, the report reveals that current Volkswagen boss Herbert Diess was in a meeting with Winterkorn in July 2015 where engineers revealed information about the deception. Volkswagen says that Diess, who had just joined the company that month, was “justified in trusting” that the company would resolve the issues raised at that meeting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="76BpFi"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Di2XbT"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526377/volkswagen-audi-dieselgate-settlement-winterkorn-stadler"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526377/volkswagen-audi-dieselgate-settlement-winterkorn-stadler</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
