<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2020-12-24T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-24T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-24T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here’s an HDMI-themed holiday podcast to listen to this season</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6eMiETjdOuCKmDP7vOg4DSH1C2A=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68577101/acastro_HDMI_spectacular_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Alex Castro&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JGSQvR"&gt;Happy holidays! Here is our gift to you: over an hour of audio content exclusively dedicated to HDMI. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h7njAV"&gt;If you’re lucky this holiday season, you may be opening up a new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21550146/sony-playstation-5-ps5-review"&gt;PlayStation 5&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21548987/xbox-series-x-review"&gt;Xbox Series X&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549021/xbox-series-s-review"&gt;Xbox Series S&lt;/a&gt;. And with that, a brand-new HDMI 2.1 cable — ready to game in 4K at 120Hz. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r5JGlG"&gt;&lt;a href="https://hdmi.org/spec/hdmi2_1"&gt;HDMI 2.1&lt;/a&gt; is an updated HDMI standard that expands the bandwidth of HDMI up to 48Gbps, allowing the ability for multiple features like &lt;a href="https://www.hdmi.org/spec21sub/variablerefreshrate"&gt;variable refresh rate&lt;/a&gt; (VRR), &lt;a href="https://www.hdmi.org/spec21sub/autolowlatencymode"&gt;auto low latency mode&lt;/a&gt; (ALLM), and &lt;a href="https://www.hdmi.org/spec21sub/enhancedaudioreturnchannel"&gt;enhanced audio return channel&lt;/a&gt; (eARC). It also supports high resolution and refresh rates like 8K60 and 4K120, and all of these features can upgrade your console gaming significantly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MATiSx"&gt;Both your TV and HDMI cable need to support HDMI 2.1 to unlock these features. This holiday season, it’s still a bit confusing to try to figure out which TVs are the best choice. &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2020/8/3/21348598/ps5-sony-tv-playstation-5-ready-4k-8k"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;Polygon’s &lt;/em&gt;Samit Sarkar points out&lt;/a&gt;, some of Sony’s own “Ready for PS5” branded TVs do not support VRR or ALLM, and in other sets, only one of their multiple ports is HDMI 2.1-ready. From what we’ve seen, &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2020/3/4/21151509/xbox-series-x-ps5-specs-4k-8k-tv-hdmi"&gt;this is not an isolated problem&lt;/a&gt; in the market right now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C5H0XZ"&gt;Hopefully, this podcast can help you sort through it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bGHPU1"&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="200" scrolling="no" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm?e=VMP7588472400" width="100%"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dBVhvn"&gt;For a special &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/the-vergecast"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;holiday episode, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Nilay Patel, Dieter Bohn, and Chris Welch talked to three industry experts about the new HDMI 2.1 standard. They go through what to look for when buying a new TV, how serious the TV manufacturers are on supporting 2.1, and how the new standard is being implemented throughout the industry. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a5xl9u"&gt;First, Dieter and Chris talk with the aforementioned Samit Sarkar, front page editor of &lt;em&gt;Polygon,&lt;/em&gt; about the state of TVs, next-gen gaming, and availability of HDMI 2.1 features in consumer tech at the moment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wpBHUk"&gt;After that, Nilay and Chris chat with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/7/18172397/airplay-2-homekit-vizio-tv-bill-baxter-interview-vergecast-ces-2019"&gt;Vizio CTO Bill Baxter&lt;/a&gt; about implementing HDMI 2.1 in the company’s popular TVs, as well as early bugs that Vizio has encountered between its televisions and the Xbox Series X and PS5. They also talk over where things go from here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j5tJaY"&gt;Last but certainly not least, the crew sits down with the president of the &lt;a href="https://hdmi.org/"&gt;HDMI Forum&lt;/a&gt;, David Glen, to talk about the ins and outs of the organization in charge of HDMI and how the adoption of 2.1 has been going this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X5c0HN"&gt;With this star-studded cast, we hope this episode helps explain why you may or may not be interested in upgrading your TV for HDMI 2.1 this holiday season. You can listen to the full discussion here or in your preferred podcast player. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZbwwkP"&gt;Whether you’re dreaming of a new 4K OLED, PS5, or a new Xbox this Christmas, from all of us at &lt;em&gt;The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;, may your frames be variably refreshed and your latency be extremely low. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="lbisSH"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"The Vergecast","description":"The podcast you need to make sense of the week in tech news","label":"Subscribe","url":"https://pod.link/430333725"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="AjkD1q"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="spahtS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/24/22193437/vergecast-podcast-interview-hdmi"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/24/22193437/vergecast-podcast-interview-hdmi</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sophie Erickson</name>
      <name>Andrew Marino</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-24T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-24T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here’s when you can watch Wonder Woman 1984, Soul, and Bridgerton on Christmas Day</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A promotional picture of Wonder Woman 1984" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/03VZm2gPTafw3z285_0JMMCF8o8=/41x0:740x466/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68577098/wonder_woman.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Warner Bros.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LFItjc"&gt;December 25th is going to be a big deal for streaming, with blockbusters like &lt;em&gt;Wonder Woman 1984 &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Soul&lt;/em&gt; debuting on HBO Max and Disney Plus, respectively, alongside hyped streaming shows like Netflix’s &lt;em&gt;Bridgerton &lt;/em&gt;and&lt;em&gt; We Can Be Heroes.&lt;/em&gt; If you’re planning a big Christmas Day marathon, here’s when each of those pieces of content will debut, so you can plan ahead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U5Hpcj"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wonder Woman 1984&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;will be the last to debut, arriving at 12PM ET on Christmas Day. That means you should have some time to unwrap and set up any new streaming or A/V gear before it debuts on HBO Max. Given the usual 3AM or midnight release times for streaming shows, it’s worth taking note of the noon ET drop here when making your movie marathon plans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PwKcTx"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soul &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;will arrive on Disney Plus at 3AM ET on December 25th. If you’re willing to stay up late, you’ll be able to watch it then. But if you’re not interested in staying up, it’ll be ready to view whenever you wake up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UfDIZm"&gt;Netflix’s &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bridgerton&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; will bring the flair of rockstar producer Shonda Rhimes to Regency London on December 25th at 3AM ET, perfect for anyone looking for a more lengthy show to binge-watch over the holiday weekend. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IwQuAS"&gt;And for younger audiences (or adults who are still fans of &lt;em&gt;The Adventures of Sharkboy and Lavagirl in 3-D), &lt;/em&gt;Robert Rodriguez’s sequel &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We Can Be Heroes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;will continue the story with a new generation of heroes starting at 3AM ET on December 25th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/24/22194171/wonder-woman-1984-soul-bridgerton-christmas-day-release-date-time-streaming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/24/22194171/wonder-woman-1984-soul-bridgerton-christmas-day-release-date-time-streaming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-24T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-24T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tony Robbins claims he saved his employee from COVID — she says that’s a lie</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r5xW9e0ZPhgSnsG_MwWcBL7Fdik=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68577104/VRG_ILLO_4349_Tony_Robbins_Covid.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by William Joel, Photography by Jim Spellman/WireImage &amp;amp;&amp;nbsp;Astrid Stawiar via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Behind Tony Robbins’ dangerous approach to the pandemic&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="N4DvmG"&gt;The story Tony Robbins told on his podcast was harrowing — if also a little convoluted. One of his staff members had come down with a fever of 102 when she started watching the news and freaking out. She went to the hospital, presumably with COVID-19, and began to hyperventilate. The doctors put her on a ventilator — then in a medically induced coma. “The doctor said … ‘If she doesn’t wake up in three weeks, we’ll declare her dead,’” Robbins recounted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l2xl7W"&gt;The self-help guru had been researching coronavirus treatments and decided pressure from ventilators could damage the lungs. “I’m not saying these people are trying to harm. I think they’re all trying to help, but the research is now showing a very different component there,” he said on the &lt;em&gt;Tony Robbins Podcast&lt;/em&gt;. So Robbins asked a physician friend to call the hospital and convince the woman’s doctors to lower the pressure. “As a result, four or five days later, she opened her eyes, which we’re so grateful for, and she’s still in the hospital but she’s healing,” Robbins said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3ix5fI"&gt;The episode fit neatly into Robbins’ self-aggrandizing coronavirus narrative. Since the early days of the pandemic, he’d been suspicious of the hysteria surrounding COVID-19.  He told employees in late March that the flu was worse than coronavirus, adding: “We have lost our minds on this.” He also hosted two events amid the crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ApPNvx"&gt;Robbins’ spokesperson Jennifer Connelly said that, since February: “Two small, private in-person meetings were held, and those were in compliance with federal, state and local regulations and guidance regarding COVID-19.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wodrcq"&gt;As a coach, Robbins always taught people that they had the ability to change their lives — not their wives or their pastors or their priests. The story he told on his podcast highlighted how little doctors knew about the illness they were supposed to be treating and underlined his own heroism in saving her life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2xs0K7"&gt;But according to a new federal lawsuit filed in the Southern District of New York, the tale was largely fabricated. Debbie Kosta, the employee in question, is suing Robbins and his company, Robbins Research International (RRI), saying he lied about his part in her recovery and made it nearly impossible for her to return to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="HYJG1O"&gt;&lt;q&gt;She just wanted to help people change their lives&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GUQI5y"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YWQOjt"&gt;The complaint lays out a starkly different picture of Tony Robbins than the inspirational coach he plays on social media. It says his organization refused to let Kosta return to work part-time while she was recovering from COVID-19 and dealing with a recent cancer diagnosis. Instead, roughly three months after Kosta got off a ventilator, the complaint alleges her managers gave her an ultimatum: return to work full-time or lose her job and her health insurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ujThx5"&gt;In a statement, Robbins’ spokesperson said: “When we were informed Ms. Kosta had contracted COVID-19 and was hospitalized, Mr. Robbins and his organization inquired with compassion and support for her and have treated her fairly and consistent with all applicable laws. RRI answered all of her questions, provided all of her requested accommodations, and did not retaliate against her in any way. Ms. Kosta remains employed by RRI and the organization continues to pay the complete cost of her medical insurance, even though its legal obligation to do so ended in June.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yMzzjJ"&gt;Kosta had been an employee of Robbins’ for 18 years when the pandemic arrived. She’d started working for him in Europe, then moved to New York and joined the sales team in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZqjrQw"&gt;Sales reps at RRI sold tickets to Robbins’ live events — multiday seminars with names like “Unleash the Power Within” and “Date with Destiny.” The world-famous coach taught people to eliminate pain “for good” and urged followers not to “settle for an ordinary life when you can create an extraordinary one.” As such, tickets cost between $600 and $3,000. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0E6yZQ"&gt;Some of Robbins’ clients were dealing with major life issues. They were drug addicts, alcoholics, or philanderers. To them, Robbins’ philosophy of self-empowerment was entirely new. It allowed them to take control of their lives and transformed them into loyal fans along the way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p4CILt"&gt;But Kosta wasn’t like that. She’d always had high self-esteem and a relentlessly positive attitude. Robbins’ curriculum reminded her of Greek philosophy, and while she believed in what he was teaching, she didn’t worship him like others seemed to. She just wanted to help people change their lives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NnjYAV"&gt;What stood out to Kosta was Robbins’ delivery. He’d run onstage to pulsing music, high-fiving and shouting like a maniac. And it worked. “I saw it, it was like, ‘Oh, people listen to this,’” Kosta says. “People actually like high-fiving and hugging.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PErzHz"&gt;Back in New York, Kosta became one of Robbins’ top performing sales reps, according to the complaint. The gig was commission-only, but there were bonuses for people who sold a lot. One anonymous employee who worked on the sales team said they regularly made $80,000 a year in bonuses alone. Kosta liked the hustle and was willing to skip holidays if it meant succeeding at work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yEPQh0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mVScm5UWTmhoKGOJBZLjpUbNUJE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22192469/akrales_201221_4349_0517.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1MD7lh"&gt;Over the next nine years, Kosta made a life for herself and her two young daughters in New York City. She was able to send them to a good prep school in Manhattan and take them to Europe in the summers. But the real money went to Tony Robbins. After a particularly massive event, Kosta says he called her to congratulate her on how much business she was bringing in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cBjxvj"&gt;Then, in early 2020, things started to shift. Robbins’ biggest event was scheduled to take place in San Jose, California, in March. “Unleash the Power Within” was a four-day seminar that taught people to “unlock and unleash the forces inside you to break through your limitations and take control of your life.” Unfortunately, some worried that a 12,000-person event could unleash a bunch of coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TFNZvM"&gt;Less than a week before the event, Robbins was forced to cancel. Attendees started calling to get their money back, sending the sales team into a panic. RRI had a brutal policy that meant each refund came out of employees’ commissions. Some team members went from making well over $100,000 to not being able to make their mortgage payments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="19x5wh"&gt;In late March, Robbins offered employees a stipend of roughly $5,000 a month and urged them to “step the fuck up,” according to audio leaked to &lt;em&gt;The Verge. &lt;/em&gt;They were told they’d need to pay Robbins back by the end of the year. The following month, in April, &lt;a href="https://projects.propublica.org/coronavirus/bailouts/loans/robbins-research-international-inc-c62b8f906ee86f60821af1e98cc0c006"&gt;RRI received a Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) loan&lt;/a&gt; from the federal government. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cmxDR3"&gt;(In a statement emailed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge, &lt;/em&gt;Robbins’ spokesperson wrote: “RRI properly and legally applied and received PPP support and has used those funds in compliance with the program’s rules.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LLtexQ"&gt;The news wasn’t great for Kosta, but she was dealing with bigger problems. She’d developed a high fever and was having a difficult time breathing. Her daughter Stella, a 19-year-old film student at Hunter College, had never seen her mom so sick. On April 12th, when Kosta’s fever had been hovering at 104 for three days, Stella decided to call an ambulance. “She’s very strong and upbeat, so seeing her so weak, barely able to string sentences together, not breathing, it was very mind-boggling to me,” she says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dXSG7H"&gt;Stella had watched the trucks of dead bodies lining the streets in Manhattan. Everyone she knew either had COVID or knew someone who’d died from it. “I was just like, ‘My mom cannot become one of those people,’” she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="drw0Rb"&gt;&lt;q&gt;But Stella says none of that is true&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zIsaFH"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jnhTEW"&gt;At the hospital, doctors put Kosta on a ventilator, then in a medically induced coma. Robbins called Stella to see how her mother was doing. This is where Robbins’ telling of the story really diverges from the truth, according to Kosta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LYOI4J"&gt;Robbins said that Stella did her research and found that the longer her mom was on a ventilator, the more likely she was to die. “The daughter went crazy,” he said on his podcast. “She said, ‘You put her in the coma. She came in with a cough and a fever and shortness of breath…’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nrkz00"&gt;But Stella says none of that is true. “I’m not knowledgeable enough,” she says, bewildered. “Whatever the doctors were telling me, I was believing it.” At one point, she says she asked the doctors how much longer her mother would have to be on a ventilator. “But I was never like, ‘Take her off right now,’” she adds. “Why would I ever do that? I was just asking, ‘How can you make her better?’ But I never went against the ventilator. The ventilator is what saved her.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="80KzfO"&gt;The complaint also says that Robbins told Kosta’s clients he was the one who convinced the doctors to take her off the ventilator. And, it alleges that Sage Robbins, Tony’s wife, called Stella to “pry information from her regarding Ms. Kosta’s condition.” Kosta’s attorney, Chris Albanese, of the employment law firm White, Hilferty and Albanese, says: “Tony and his wife went out of their way to harm her, what kind of person would do that?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eaSLDn"&gt;(Robbins’ spokesperson says the “allegations concerning RRI, Mr. Robbins and his wife, are false.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9KBuuJ"&gt;Robbins took advantage of Kosta’s situation for his own benefit, the complaint adds. He made it seem like she was overreacting about her symptoms because of the news. “I talked to him personally and told him about the 104 fever and how she couldn’t breathe,” Stella notes. “For him to turn around and say, ‘Oh, she had 102 fever and then watched the news and started hyperventilating’ — it was just so shocking. It’s a betrayal. I took lessons from his events at heart and tried to change my life with them. Now I’m just wondering, ‘Well, how much have you been lying then? How many of your stories and how many of your experiences that you used to teach us are lies?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aYt1oF"&gt;Kosta stayed in a coma until early May. Then, miraculously, she started to get better. When she finally got home from the hospital on May 5th, she could barely walk around the block or speak a full sentence without losing her breath. But she was alive. Then her doctors discovered a growth on her chest. They said said she’d likely need six months to fully recover, according to the lawsuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d3dBCf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nfaAO1WIv679OD1QxSSoGWyqO4w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22192464/akrales_201221_4349_0380.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iGrYic"&gt;Kosta was on New York State Paid Family Leave, but it was set to run out at the end of June. She knew she wasn’t well enough to return to work; she still needed surgery to remove the growth. Talking on the phone all day with her voice ravaged from the ventilator seemed impossible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4Rp060"&gt;According to the lawsuit, she emailed HR to see if she could have more time off. They said no. If she didn’t return in July, she’d lose her health insurance. Kosta asked to reduce her hours. She was a commissioned-based employee who worked from home, so the request seemed pretty reasonable. But RRI refused, the complaint says. They offered her $15,000 in severance and encouraged her to go on disability. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ai8uFy"&gt;“Debbie Kosta was at the peak of her sales career when she contracted coronavirus,” said Vincent White, Kosta’s other attorney. “Instead of supporting a woman who had not only supported his organization but enriched him personally, Tony Robbins left her without reasonable accommodation for her disability. She has lost a tremendous amount of earning potential during this time, and frankly it is impossible to put a number on the emotional damages Ms. Kosta has endured at the hands of a company that claims to lift up, not break down, the human spirit.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y5ea9r"&gt;Kosta’s complaint, which was filed with the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission ahead of its filing in federal court in New York City, says that her request to reduce her hours was a reasonable accommodation, and RRI’s refusal to grant it violates the Americans with Disabilities Act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="8WLOU9"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I’m done with this Guru!”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2TbZjw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NSp6P0"&gt;Robbins had been walking a thin line between COVID-19 skepticism and denial. He didn’t doubt that the disease existed, but he hinted that the news coverage surrounding the death rate was exaggerated. Then, in August 2020, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TonyRobbins/posts/the-most-powerful-vaccine-youve-never-heard-ofjoin-peter-diamandis-tony-robbins-/10158871342659060/"&gt;he started promoting a coronavirus vaccine&lt;/a&gt; on Facebook, designed by his friend and longtime collaborator Peter H. Diamandis. Diamandis’ company, Covaxx, is backed by Prime Movers Lab, a venture capital firm where Robbins works as a business strategist and partner. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UsdlQ0"&gt;Jennifer Connelly, Robbins’ spokesperson, said: “Mr. Robbins has invested in one of several companies working on the development of an effective COVID vaccine.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cyb0Wd"&gt;The perceived change disappointed his followers. “I can’t believe what I am actually reading from Tony Robbins who said during 7 day challenge that Covid 19 equivalent of the Flu,” one wrote on Facebook. “What a sell out Tony Robbins turned out to be promoting a ‘safe vaccine’ by one of his Business partners. I’m done with this Guru!” Another wrote: “No thanks Tony how much cash do you have invested in this vaccine?!?!” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t9aZQ2"&gt;The answer, according to Pitchbook, could be close to $2.85 million, which is the amount Covaxx raised in May, in a funding round led by Prime Movers Lab. It might help explain Robbins’ core philosophy — not self-empowerment, or personal growth, but capitalism. America’s number one coach might say his mission is to “help individuals and businesses succeed.” But according to some employees, the individual he’s most interested in helping is himself. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21442382/tony-robbins-podcast-covid-employee-lawsuit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21442382/tony-robbins-podcast-covid-employee-lawsuit</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-24T04:36:52-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-24T04:36:52-05:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung’s Galaxy Buds Pro said to cost $199</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5auPAJWZUOVtJLCCklpHFmWLgdQ=/457x0:2043x1057/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68576643/e31b969143b271229f5243aae0fc864fd5f050c10f701deba1a172fab2d354f7.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The upcoming Galaxy Buds Pro collection.&lt;/em&gt; | &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.voice.com/profile/evan" target="_blank"&gt;Evan Blass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nGqHqU"&gt;More details of Samsung’s unannounced Galaxy Buds Pro wireless earbuds with active noise cancelation have leaked, including the price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oQ70Vh"&gt;According to slides shared on Twitter by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/_h0x0d_/status/1341767829926768643"&gt;WalkingCat&lt;/a&gt;, the Galaxy Buds Pro will cost $199 at launch making them $80 cheaper than the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21507552/bose-quietcomfort-earbuds-review-best-noise-cancellation"&gt;Bose QuietComfort Earbuds&lt;/a&gt;, our noise-canceling champions. Samsung’s pro buds will feature strong IPX7 durability against dust and water, and up to 8 hours of listening time which can be extended to 28 hours with the charging case. WalkingCat provides this handy chart to compare specs across all of Samsung’s wireless buds.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a5eeW0Rv_eAmcUQ5r5MVu2dPZ7M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22195070/Ep7qr_SUYAIMGqR.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/_h0x0d_/status/1341767829926768643" target="_blank"&gt;WalkingCat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung Buds comparison chart.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="o2prhE"&gt;WalkingCat also shared a slide showing an exploded view of the new active noise canceling buds, revealing an 11-mm woofer and 6.5-mm tweeter. The slide also supports rumors of an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/21/22193235/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-3d-spatial-audio-leak"&gt;Apple-like spatial audio feature&lt;/a&gt;. With a price of $199, the Buds Pro would be $50 cheaper than Apple’s AirPods Pro wireless buds. On paper at least, Samsung’s Galaxy Buds Pro are looking very competitive with Apple’s best buds.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8VPVa2MIOkttYBh1p7FGVCKdN0s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22195073/Ep7rDAiVgAIFSMu.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/_h0x0d_/status/1341768211985928192" target="_blank"&gt;WalkingCat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;More Galaxy Buds Pro details.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="FDPrun"&gt;The new slides are similar in look to those leaked by WalkingCat yesterday showing details about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22197354/samsung-galaxy-chromebook-2-leaked-specs-better-battery-life-lower-price"&gt;Samsung’s $699 Galaxy Chromebook 2&lt;/a&gt;. We’ll know soon if they’re legit. The big CES show is coming up and Samsung is hosting its own event in January for the presumed launch of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22196897/s-pen-uwb-comfirm-galaxy-s21-ultra-fcc"&gt;Galaxy S21 series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/24/22198622/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-price-specs-active-noise-cancelation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/24/22198622/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-price-specs-active-noise-cancelation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Thomas Ricker</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-23T18:54:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-23T18:54:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Five easy ways for Elon Musk to combine his companies into a superconglomerate</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ho0CY5bFI60hyNxwPhYYSqP7zZQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68575588/pacalin_190721_3581_0013.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Pauline Acalin for The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GkZ8C9"&gt;Elon Musk thinks it’s a “good idea” to create a holding company above Tesla, SpaceX, Neuralink, and The Boring Company — at least, that’s what the billionaire CEO &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1341801143631028225"&gt;said in response to the idea on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. Such a holding company could be simply known as “X,” longtime Tesla shareholder Dave Lee suggested, in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/7/10/15949862/elon-musk-x-com-paypal-tesla-spacex-domain-name"&gt;a nod to Musk’s ownership of “X.com” from his PayPal days&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aNIIkO"&gt;Musk notoriously entertains changes, big and small, to his companies in &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/wired25-jack-dorsey/"&gt;Twitter’s public square&lt;/a&gt;. In 2018 he even suggested one so large (and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/27/17911428/sec-lawsuit-elon-musk-tesla-funding-tweet"&gt;largely baseless&lt;/a&gt;) — taking Tesla private using “funding secured” from Saudi Arabia — that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/26/18484751/elon-musk-sec-fraud-tesla-tweets-contempt-agreement"&gt;he wound up in court&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="p3aYNQ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It was only five years ago that Google surprise-announced a similar shakeup&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pr8PVr"&gt;But the idea here isn’t &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; far outside the realm of possibility. It was only five years ago that Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/8/11/9129131/alphabet-google-larry-page-sergey-brin-merger-strategy"&gt;surprise-announced a similar shakeup&lt;/a&gt;, creating the Alphabet holding company and splitting some of its bigger and bolder projects out into their own ventures alongside the search giant but still under that new umbrella. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KvI5yt"&gt;If Musk is entertaining something similar after thumbing through Twitter, let’s have a think on what that would even look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vBctC8"&gt;Repeating Alphabet &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="kQCnGE"&gt;The most straightforward way for Musk to create X could be to roughly follow that Alphabet model. The big difference is SpaceX, Neuralink, and The Boring Company are all separate entities that exist outside of Tesla, the only publicly-traded business of the bunch. Let’s start with Tesla, since that’s where most of the action will have to take place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OBBc5v"&gt;Here’s the hilariously paper push-y way Alphabet deal was structured: Google created a wholly-owned subsidiary called Alphabet. It created &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; new wholly-owned subsidiary underneath Alphabet called “&lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001652044/000119312515336577/d82837dex21.htm"&gt;Maple Technologies&lt;/a&gt;.” It then merged Maple and Google to create a new version of Google that was, you got it, wholly owned by Alphabet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G6tFbT"&gt;Easy, right? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cgEeSW"&gt;As for Google stockholders: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="5fzL7R"&gt;Each share of each class of Google stock issued and outstanding immediately prior to the Alphabet Merger will automatically convert into an equivalent corresponding share of Alphabet stock, having the same designations, rights, powers and preferences and the qualifications, limitations and restrictions as the corresponding share of Google stock being converted. Accordingly, upon consummation of the Alphabet Merger, Google’s current stockholders will become stockholders of Alphabet. The stockholders of Google will not recognize gain or loss for U.S. federal income tax purposes upon the conversion of their shares in the Alphabet Merger.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="ZfoWPS"&gt;In other words, Google basically said “sit tight while we change things up, and when we’re done you’ll now own a slice of Alphabet worth the same amount.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G5zqT1"&gt;The same could be done with Tesla. Create a Tesla subsidiary called “X,” create a merger entity underneath &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt;, and then combine the merger entity with Tesla. Tesla shareholders transform into equivalent shareholders of X, deal done. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZiWgnr"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The trouble would more likely be philosophical&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ztZ2iW"&gt;Well, not so fast. X would then have to bring the other three private companies into the fold. Instead of being able to just shuffle them around, like Google did with businesses like Nest, or Calico, X would probably have to acquire SpaceX, Neuralink, and The Boring Company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8CggVX"&gt;That shouldn’t be &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; difficult since Musk is the majority owner of those companies. The trouble would more likely be philosophical. Tesla’s stock price is currently very high because a lot of people believe in the company. But how would people perceive the value of X stock if it includes these other operations?  Would X stock be subject to the fewer dramatic swings since the company’s value would be less dependent on Tesla’s performance? &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/david_j_roth/status/212767135901024256?lang=en"&gt;Things of that nature&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bnUN6p"&gt;Combining the four companies under X could help Musk further sell his futurist vision (making humanity run on sustainable energy, settling other worlds, etc.). More boringly, it could help him consolidate the various companies’ financial or human resources departments, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2016-12-08/google-makes-so-much-money-it-never-had-to-worry-about-financial-discipline?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;which was a benefit Google sought with Alphabet&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DVXMPg"&gt;Okay now let’s get weird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="XVjWcR"&gt;Musk buys Tesla&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ADYypj"&gt;What &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t gel about going the Alphabet route is Musk... &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/8/17664296/elon-musk-tesla-public-private-offering-stocks"&gt;kind of despises that Tesla is a public company&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s what Musk wrote when he tried to take Tesla private back in 2018: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="exDB3a"&gt;As a public company, we are subject to wild swings in our stock price that can be a major distraction for everyone working at Tesla, all of whom are shareholders. Being public also subjects us to the quarterly earnings cycle that puts enormous pressure on Tesla to make decisions that may be right for a given quarter, but not necessarily right for the long-term. Finally, as the most shorted stock in the history of the stock market, being public means that there are large numbers of people who have the incentive to attack the company.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Wqc9FU"&gt;Tesla’s in a much better place financially now, so it doesn’t have to worry so much about the second and third point there. But the overall message still tracks. Musk would rather manage his businesses with fewer prying eyes. Would he really expose SpaceX, Neuralink, and The Boring Company to the same kinds of pressures by folding them into a public holding company? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p2eY5W"&gt;Probably not, so how do you solve that? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PRLbaS"&gt;Tesla is the only public company of the three currently, so... take it private. Yep. Let’s run the whole funding secured experiment all over again, but forget trying to sell it off to Saudi Arabia, or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22195959/elon-musk-tesla-tim-cook-apple-sale-meeting-acquisition-refused"&gt;Apple.&lt;/a&gt; Let’s get &lt;em&gt;weirder&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="vAogd3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Seems like the least Ellison could do&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="h4ODCI"&gt;Musk is now the second-richest man in the world, currently worth around $140 billion. He probably can’t come up with all the money it would take to buy out Tesla at its current valuation north of $600 billion — especially since half his shares in Tesla &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/elon-musk-techs-cash-poor-billionaire-11588967043"&gt;are already pledged as collateral&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;and &lt;/em&gt;the company’s board has limited him to borrowing just 25 percent of the value of any additional shares. It’s also unclear how much of his SpaceX shares are pledged as collateral. But using his ownership in all four companies as the basis for loans, one could see him taking a fair-sized bite out of that $600 billion price tag. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MLKUTj"&gt;He would need still some serious partners to join him in buying out Tesla. Perhaps billionaire and Tesla board member Larry Ellison? Seems like the least Ellison could do after Musk brought him into the fold following the funding secured debacle, and turned what was a &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/01/15/investing/telsa-stock-larry-ellison/index.html"&gt;modest investment&lt;/a&gt; into what is now many billions of dollars. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qPreTm"&gt;Musk does seem to love Tesla’s most loyal shareholders, to the point that he tried to promise that they would still own part of the company during the failed go-private transaction in 2018 — an idea &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/20/18507476/elon-musk-420-funding-secured-sec-lawsuit"&gt;that confused experts&lt;/a&gt; — so maybe he could find a way for them to be involved, too. Whatever consortium Musk draws up could just stand in for X, acquire Tesla, and then bring the other companies into the fold. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="IK71iC"&gt;SPAC X&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="iju2Mm"&gt;Musk creates one of the special purpose acquisition companies, or SPACs, that have been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21502700/spac-explained-meaning-special-purpose-acquisition-company"&gt;oh-so-hot this year&lt;/a&gt; and calls it X. He kicks it off with a lot of his own money (likely from leveraged Tesla and SpaceX shares) and the stock price immediately soars once it starts trading, because a) it’s a SPAC and that’s just how things work now, apparently, b) its existence as a vehicle for brute force capitalism excites the masses, and c) it’s Elon Musk. SPAC X becomes a blank check behemoth, he uses it to buy Tesla and the other companies, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="PWDDjv"&gt;Mars Street&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="EGSreF"&gt;Unsatisfied with merely theorizing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/6/2/11837590/elon-musk-mars-government-direct-democracy-law-code-conference"&gt;what the laws should be on Mars&lt;/a&gt;, Musk establishes the first Mars Stock Exchange. He models it after terrestrial stock exchanges, but with tweaks to reduce some of his least-favorite aspects (like quarterly reporting rules or that pesky Securities and Exchange Commission). Nobody is quite sure if it’s legal, or “real,” but then again the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/1/27/14398492/outer-space-treaty-50-anniversary-exploration-guidelines"&gt;Outer Space Treaty&lt;/a&gt; didn’t exactly go long on financial regulation now, did it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="wCLbGX"&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="AyntSq"&gt;Musk reveals he’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/3/18166096/bitcoin-blockchain-code-currency-money-genesis-block-silk-road-mt-gox"&gt;bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; creator &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/8/30/16222590/satoshi-sec-officials-investors-ucoin-scheme-japanese"&gt;Satoshi Nakamoto&lt;/a&gt;, sells all his coins, and buys Tesla. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="Dp5OgK"&gt;As you can see, Musk has a few options if he really wants to create the kind of world-beating conglomerate that only shows up in the movies. It may be a long shot, but that’s sort of his&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;whole&lt;em&gt; thing&lt;/em&gt;. No wonder he thinks it’s a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c2DeAY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hFf1yO"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22197823/elon-musk-tesla-spacex-x-boring-company-neuralink-holding-speculation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22197823/elon-musk-tesla-spacex-x-boring-company-neuralink-holding-speculation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-23T18:12:53-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-23T18:12:53-05:00</updated>
    <title>Nuro can now charge for robot deliveries in California</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/peRb3_lKsfIJz6eNmSbWnLJDLiM=/856x0:7336x4320/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68575385/Nuro_8.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8Xd1PN"&gt;Nuro is now the first company in California that’s allowed to operate autonomous cars commercially (&lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/12/23/nuro-can-now-operate-and-charge-for-autonomous-delivery-services-in-california/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The company received a permit that allowed it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/7/21212719/nuro-driverless-car-test-california-dmv-delivery"&gt;to test its robots&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year, but this permit will allow the firm to actually charge people for the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kiN4W9"&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://medium.com/nuro/california-dmv-grants-nuro-first-ever-av-deployment-permit-ca424ebd2"&gt;a Medium post by Nuro’s chief legal and policy officer&lt;/a&gt;, the company is planning to “announce [its] first deployment in California with an established partner.” Who that partner is remains to be seen, but it’s likely to be a delivery service that can make use of Nuro’s completely driverless Prius vehicles, though the company plans on (literally) rolling out its own custom R2 bots later on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="12gjks"&gt;The permit, &lt;a href="https://www.dmv.ca.gov/portal/news-and-media/dmv-approves-nuro-to-use-autonomous-vehicles-for-commercial-service/"&gt;issued by the California DMV&lt;/a&gt;, only allows the company to operate its delivery service in parts of Santa Clara and San Mateo counties, which would mean most of the Silicon Valley and its tech workers would be within its domain, but not San Francisco or Oakland. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nkLpbN"&gt;There are some additional restrictions as well — the vehicles will only be allowed on surface streets with a speed limit of 35 miles an hour (and the bots are only allowed to go 25 mph), so don’t expect to see an driverless Prius zipping along the freeway to make a delivery anytime soon. The vehicles are also only allowed to drive in “fair weather conditions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F205ew"&gt;The company was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/30/16936548/nuro-self-driving-delivery-last-mile-google"&gt;founded by two ex-Google engineers&lt;/a&gt;, and was, ironically, the only company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/30/18044670/waymo-fully-driverless-car-permit-california-dmv"&gt;besides Google’s Waymo&lt;/a&gt; to get a California permit allowing it to test driverless cars. Now, it’s beaten the other company to the punch in getting the ability to make a business out of it in the state. It’s a different story in Arizona, though, where &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/8/21507814/waymo-driverless-cars-allow-more-customers-phoenix"&gt;Waymo is running&lt;/a&gt; a paid ride service with its driverless cars.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22197980/nuro-licensed-autonomous-deliveries-california"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22197980/nuro-licensed-autonomous-deliveries-california</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-23T18:03:45-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-23T18:03:45-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Queen’s Gambit Funko Pops immortalize the show in plastic</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iXiKnlKOb_vj8T5c-494uk9yuUc=/0x37:768x549/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68575353/POP_Television_The_Queens_Gambit_Beth_Harmon_with_Trophies.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Funko Inc.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="klN1iG"&gt;In what will hopefully be the last surprise of 2020, Netflix’s &lt;em&gt;The Queen’s Gambit&lt;/em&gt; is getting its own set of &lt;a href="https://bleedingcool.com/collectibles/funko-pop-the-queens-gambit-netflix/"&gt;Pop! Vinyl figurines from Funko&lt;/a&gt;. The three figurines will feature Anya Taylor-Joy’s main character, Beth Harmon, in a variety of outfits from the show, none of which are chess-related, but all of which are stylish. Fans can purchase the Pops to own a piece of the show’s unique aesthetic, filtered through Funko’s dead-eyed one, but the real question is, why is &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Queen’s Gambit&lt;/em&gt; getting Funko Pops?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VL6obX"&gt;If you’ll allow me to speculate wildly, maybe &lt;em&gt;The Queen’s Gambit &lt;/em&gt;is getting a Funko Pop, not because it’s a Netflix show that’s both &lt;a href="https://www.vulture.com/article/the-queens-gambit-netflix-review-anya-taylor-joy.html"&gt;critically well-received&lt;/a&gt; and popular &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2020/digital/news/queens-gambit-netflix-viewing-record-1234838090/"&gt;according to Netflix’s own metrics&lt;/a&gt;, but rather because “getting Funko’ed” (coining that now) solidifies popular content that can be a little bit transient because of streaming algorithms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tha14v"&gt;Netflix has been able to maintain &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/22/21231023/netflix-tv-shows-movies-new-2020-pandemic-production-disney-universal-warner-bros-sony"&gt;an aggressive release schedule during 2020&lt;/a&gt; because of how many shows and movies it had already banked up. But can you honestly say you remember any of those early hits from February and March, like &lt;em&gt;Tiger King &lt;/em&gt;or &lt;em&gt;Love is Blind&lt;/em&gt;? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="IdcXgd"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Coming Soon - Pop! Television: The Queen’s Gambit. Celebrate one of the most popular Netflix series of 2020 by pre-ordering your favorite Grandmaster today! &lt;a href="https://t.co/r52BYBu3XG"&gt;https://t.co/r52BYBu3XG&lt;/a&gt;   &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FunkoPop?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#FunkoPop&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Pop?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Pop&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/R4a16S0h1k"&gt;pic.twitter.com/R4a16S0h1k&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Funko at Peppermint Lane   (@OriginalFunko) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OriginalFunko/status/1341450987739987979?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 22, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iJGkv1"&gt;More broadly, was your media property really popular if it didn’t “get Funko’ed”? I’d argue no. And Netflix’s other Funko collaborations have immortalized similarly popular streaming mega-hits like &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Funko-POP-Television-Money-Professor/dp/B07HJDSXBX?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Money Heist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Funko-Stranger-Things-Eleven-Figure/dp/B01M5IK8M9/ref=sr_1_6?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=stranger+things+funko&amp;amp;qid=1608758641&amp;amp;s=toys-and-games&amp;amp;sr=1-6&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;before they got folded into the Netflix soup, only to resurface for new seasons. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PgNgFz"&gt;Getting Funko’ed is almost like getting a panel at Comic-Con; it signals a level of fan engagement that warrants capitalizing on, at least monetarily. A show might fade from interest (or Netflix’s many carousels), but plastic junk is forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2d2Ypb"&gt;Funko’s ability to spin up figurines fast certainly helps in that regard. Even if Netflix’s deal was set before the show was a hit, Funko’s fast-fashion approach to manufacturing allows it to get a Pop into production in under two months, according to &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2019/8/13/20798910/funko-pop-vinyl-figurines-collectibles"&gt;a report from &lt;em&gt;The Goods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Given the October 23rd premiere date for &lt;em&gt;The Queen’s Gambit&lt;/em&gt;, the Beth Harmon Pops fall well within Funko’s compact production window. (Another weird thing: these Funko Pops &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Ftoys-collectibles%2Ffunko%2Fpop%2Fproducts%2Fpop-television-the-queens-gambit-beth-harmon-with-trophies%2F11113245.html%3Fcondition%3DNew" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;start shipping on April 20th of next year&lt;/a&gt;.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0tpzkx"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Queen’s Gambit&lt;/em&gt; Funko Pop! is an interesting flex of Funko’s manufacturing power, Netflix’s development skills, and the weird ways popularity surfaces in culture. No one will likely be talking about the show 40 years from now, but when I’m scavenging the wastelands of California and I find a Beth Harmon Pop in a busted-out suburb, I’ll remember, and barter for water accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="45yYHa"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J4n32B"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2020/12/23/22197935/netflix-the-queens-gambit-funk-pop-post-apocalypse"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2020/12/23/22197935/netflix-the-queens-gambit-funk-pop-post-apocalypse</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-23T18:03:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-23T18:03:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>Verge readers can get two years of PlayStation Plus for only $58</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gTy1FtPiD2kOiFhhoc84LzPUSrY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68574482/vpavic_4261_20201023_0104.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="NWohEz"&gt;If you own a PS4 or PS5 and need to renew your PlayStation Plus membership soon, Eneba has an incredible deal on its website right now: &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; readers can get two &lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=20387&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=verge&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.eneba.com%2Fus%2Fpsn-playstation-network-card-psn-365-days-usa-psn-key-united-states" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;one-year PlayStation Plus subscriptions for only $58&lt;/a&gt; by entering offer code &lt;strong&gt;VERGEPLUS&lt;/strong&gt; at checkout. This is a real bargain — normally, one year of PlayStation Plus retails for $60. So if you are looking to stock up on this subscription for a couple of years or want to keep one and gift the other, take advantage of this deal — it will likely sell out quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xF1WcC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9734577"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UEqOVA"&gt;PlayStation Plus is a paid online subscription service that comes with a ton of perks for members, including occasional discounts during PlayStation Store sales and free games that switch up usually on a monthly cadence, among other things. A PlayStation Plus subscription is compatible with both the PS4 and the PS5. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ERjldv"&gt;If you have a PS5, you get an additional perk: access to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/16/21440388/playstation-plus-collection-ps5-ps4-games-titles"&gt;PlayStation Plus Collection&lt;/a&gt;, a digital collection of “generation-defining” first- and third-party titles that were originally released for the PS4, such as &lt;em&gt;Bloodborne&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; God of War&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; Persona 5&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Uncharted 4: A Thief’s End&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2020/12/23/22188627/playstation-plus-two-year-membership-ps4-ps5-deal-code-verge"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2020/12/23/22188627/playstation-plus-two-year-membership-ps4-ps5-deal-code-verge</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-23T17:55:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-23T17:55:01-05:00</updated>
    <title>Cyberpunk 2077’s 1.06 update is here to reduce your fear of corrupted savegames</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nqJLQM4LuUmml1jW-z7JaDe3RZw=/0x0:1013x675/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68575320/Ep9GMMjWwAUh_h6.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pRW5Pc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077 &lt;/em&gt;is still fighting its way through some &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22197547/cyberpunk-2077-glitches"&gt;terrible (and hilarious) glitches&lt;/a&gt;, but developer CD Projekt Red is killing the nastiest bugs fairly quickly: &lt;a href="https://www.cyberpunk.net/en/news/37214/hotfix-1-06"&gt;today’s just-released 1.06 hotfix&lt;/a&gt; should keep your PC save files from getting irrevocably corrupted if they grow larger than 8MB in size. Yes, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/20/22192375/cyberpunk-2077-save-file-corrupted-8-mb"&gt;that was actually an issue&lt;/a&gt; before today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="361t1q"&gt;On console, the game should also have “fewer crashes” due to “improved memory management and stability,” and a character named Dum Dum (who I have not yet personally met in my first run at the game, please do not judge me, I have kids) will no longer vanish in the middle of a quest. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/N61B7oNUEuK25mGcSo5lOHxbKPY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22186789/Save_damaged.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://support.gog.com/hc/en-us/articles/360016743298-Cyberpunk-2077-Saved-data-is-damaged-and-cannot-be-loaded-?product=gog&amp;amp;pp=d965a463ac183af4828302b14522bb3371cec49f" target="_blank"&gt;GOG.com support document&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The prompt shown for corrupted saves in &lt;/em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="E9VqzE"&gt;That’s the entire list of changes in this hotfix, so there’s not much reason for you to &lt;a href="https://www.cyberpunk.net/en/news/37214/hotfix-1-06"&gt;click through to the whole changelog&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1jKXsA"&gt;On December 13th, the company addressed the controversy around the game’s unfinished state by promising “two large patches” in January and February &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167303/cyberpunk-2077-ps5-console-google-stadia"&gt;to address its terrible performance on PS4 and Xbox One&lt;/a&gt; in particular, but also said it would issue updates to fix bugs and crashes as fast as it could. We got &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170547/cyberpunk-2077-update-hotfix-cd-projekt-red-epilepsy-risk-braindance"&gt;a 1.04 patch&lt;/a&gt; that addressed epilepsy risks on December 11th, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189893/cyberpunk-2077-update-patch-hotfix-bugs"&gt;a 1.05 patch&lt;/a&gt; on December 18th that squashed loads of bugs, and now this 1.06 patch five days later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hSe6wn"&gt;Though the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/14/22173738/cyberpunk-2077-developer-apologizes-base-ps4-xbox-one-performance-issues-refunds"&gt;has offered refunds&lt;/a&gt; to disappointed players, it hasn’t seemed to affect the game’s overall success: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22195728/cyberpunk-2077-sales-copies-sold-launch-refunds"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077 &lt;/em&gt;sold over 13 million copies even counting those refunds&lt;/a&gt;, more than &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170655/cyberpunk-2077-cd-projekt-red-developers-staff-bonuses-review-score"&gt;making up for&lt;/a&gt; its eight-year development budget and marketing campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vbbjra"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22198029/cyberpunk-2077-106-update-patch-corrupted-save-file-crashes"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22198029/cyberpunk-2077-106-update-patch-corrupted-save-file-crashes</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-23T17:03:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-23T17:03:47-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google reportedly asked employees to ‘strike a positive tone’ in research paper</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V0U8zm3hGiepcU9UwRYQtVXZE9g=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68575059/acastro_180130_1777_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fIulmC"&gt;Google has added a layer of scrutiny for research papers on sensitive topics including gender, race, and political ideology. A senior manager also instructed researchers to “strike a positive tone” in a paper this summer. The news was &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-alphabet-google-research-focus-idUSKBN28X1CB"&gt;first reported by Reuters&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QC8dai"&gt;“Advances in technology and the growing complexity of our external environment are increasingly leading to situations where seemingly inoffensive projects raise ethical, reputational, regulatory or legal issues,” the policy read. Three employees told Reuters the rule started in June. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mSeGOx"&gt;The company has also asked employees to “refrain from casting its technology in a negative light” on multiple occasions, Reuters says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vPSXt4"&gt;Employees working on a paper on recommendation AI, which is used to personalize content on platforms like YouTube, were told to “take great care to strike a positive tone,” according to Reuters. The authors then updated the paper to “remove all references to Google products.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XLN6LV"&gt;Another paper on using AI to understand foreign languages “softened a reference to how the Google Translate product was making mistakes,” Reuters wrote. The change came in response to a request from reviewers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TSLD8c"&gt;Google’s standard review process is meant to ensure researchers don’t inadvertently reveal trade secrets. But the “sensitive topics” review goes beyond that. Employees who want to evaluate Google’s own services for bias are asked to consult with the legal, PR, and policy teams first. Other sensitive topics reportedly include China, the oil industry, location data, religion, and Israel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="djpVVC"&gt;The search giant’s publication process has been in the spotlight &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/3/22150355/google-fires-timnit-gebru-facial-recognition-ai-ethicist"&gt;since the firing of AI ethicist Timnit Gebru in early December&lt;/a&gt;. Gebru says she was terminated over an email she sent to the Google Brain Women and Allies listserv, an internal group for Google AI research employees. In it, she spoke about Google managers pushing her to retract a paper on the dangers of large scale language processing models. Jeff Dean, Google’s head of AI, said she’d submitted it too close to the deadline. But &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/7/22158501/timnit-gebru-team-google-public-statement-fired"&gt;Gebru’s own team pushed back on this assertion&lt;/a&gt;, saying the policy was applied “unevenly and discriminatorily.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xfOZU9"&gt;Gebru reached out to Google’s PR and policy team in September regarding the paper, according to &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/12/23/google-timnit-gebru-ai-ethics/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. She knew the company might take issue with certain aspects of the research, since it uses large language processing models in its search engine. The deadline for making changes to the paper wasn’t until the end of January 2021, giving researchers ample time to respond to any concerns. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PWvWMQ"&gt;A week before Thanksgiving, however, Megan Kacholia, a VP at Google Research, asked Gebru to retract the paper. The following month, Gebru was fired. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p6hXsy"&gt;Google did not immediately respond to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i8s3xJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22197760/google-sensitive-topics-review-research-papers-timnit-gebru"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22197760/google-sensitive-topics-review-research-papers-timnit-gebru</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
