<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-28T16:05:33-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-28T16:05:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-28T16:05:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sable is an adventure made from the most chill parts of Breath of the Wild</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZZzEoWSWL2TjxYTWxs2bvU72Qvo=/300x0:1920x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69922326/2021_09_20__12_.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Shedworks&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Zoom through sandy dunes vibing to the sounds of Japanese Breakfast&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="gG22Am"&gt;When I think of &lt;em&gt;Sable&lt;/em&gt;, trying to conjure for it an elevator pitch that I might use to convince my friends to play, my mind settles on describing it as: what if the pod-racing sequence from &lt;em&gt;The Phantom Menace&lt;/em&gt; made a baby with &lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild &lt;/em&gt;in a world where no one suffers, and everyone’s needs are met? It’s an unwieldy description, but it gets at the heart of what I love about the game. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="shJNSx"&gt;Developed by Shedworks, a small team based in London, &lt;em&gt;Sable&lt;/em&gt; generated a lot of interest &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/14/17462494/sable-xbox-preview-moebius-zelda-e3-2018"&gt;at its E3 2018 preview&lt;/a&gt; with its &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=moebius&amp;amp;rlz=1C5CHFA_enCA717CA718&amp;amp;sxsrf=AOaemvICNzk50BwPfnqvgdtRD1RkPoUIvg:1632857515176&amp;amp;source=lnms&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;sqi=2&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwj5mqShtKLzAhV-Q_EDHWeCC4MQ_AUoAXoECAEQAw&amp;amp;biw=1274&amp;amp;bih=798&amp;amp;dpr=1"&gt;Moebius-inspired art style&lt;/a&gt; and similarities to &lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild&lt;/em&gt;. Comparisons between &lt;em&gt;Sable&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;BotW&lt;/em&gt; are inevitable but welcome, according to its developers, who said they took heavy inspiration from 2017’s nigh universally acclaimed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/13/16771360/legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-game-of-the-year-2017"&gt;game of the year&lt;/a&gt;. In &lt;em&gt;Sable&lt;/em&gt;, as in &lt;em&gt;BotW&lt;/em&gt;, the seemingly endless world lies open to you, demanding no more from you than your attention and appreciation. Almost anything can be scaled, there are hundreds of bugs, clothing items, and cosmetics to collect, and, predictably, there’s a paragliding feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="55quoi"&gt;But that’s where the similarities end. Rather than being driven to defeat an ancient enemy, you are the engine in &lt;em&gt;Sable&lt;/em&gt;. There is no combat, no evil to outwit, nor any grand mystery the game demands you solve. Instead, &lt;em&gt;Sable&lt;/em&gt; gifts you with a pod-racer and some encouraging words of self-determination and discovery, then lets you go. I didn’t think I’d enjoy such a game. I’m a creature of structure, preferring an objective be clearly spelled out for me. Without that kind of guidance, I grow bored of aimless wanderings or become so paralyzed with choice that I simply decide to do nothing and turn off the game. But &lt;em&gt;Sable’&lt;/em&gt;s desert world, hiding discoveries buried within and above the dunes, enticed me into a state of pleasant and quiet contentment instead of mindless wanderings. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/m1jUpUiyRj9bBSvbwy3JO9b2FzY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22885447/Sable_4.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Shedworkds&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="bnmoLZ"&gt;You play as the titular Sable, a person on the cusp of adulthood who embarks on their coming of age journey called “The Gliding.” In Sable’s culture, young people are sent out alone to experience the world and learn their place in it. To figure that out, they must earn masks that denote a particular profession, and at the end of their Gliding, they must choose a mask to lock in the vocation they will be bound to for the rest of their life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5tV5mB"&gt;To earn masks, Sable is given tasks by the people they encounter on their gliding, the reward for which is usually a badge. The tasks are simple, usually involving you collecting some kind of item, which requires a bit of creative platforming, and that’s it. Collect three of the same type of badge and exchange them for a mask. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TQW5NJ"&gt;Do not approach &lt;em&gt;Sable &lt;/em&gt;expecting it to be a bunch of side-quests strung together to form a full game. Though there are the characters who give you badge quests, the majority of what you experience in the game is because of your own exploration, and therein lies its charm. There were often times when I was heading between objectives that I noticed something interesting-looking on the horizon. The landscape unfurled like a kicked piece of carpet, revealing a visually distinct piece of land or a structure that begged to be explored. You’re rewarded for your inquisitiveness with money, clothing, or a bike cosmetic. There are also little Korok-like creatures called Chums that, if you turn them into their mother, will reward you with an increased stamina bar. There are no quests that point to these areas, so you’d never know they existed without wandering into them. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hScgLG7JOPlWR--IUz9sUj8iZ7A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22885450/2021_09_24__3_.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Shedworks&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Sable meeting the chum queen.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="lauRak"&gt;You may run into some problems playing &lt;em&gt;Sable&lt;/em&gt;. The game suffers from frustrating bugs that occur just often enough to distract from an otherwise lovely experience. Quest objectives sometimes don’t spawn or trigger. Saving and quitting usually fixes the issue, but it doesn’t always happen on the first try. Also,&lt;em&gt; Sable&lt;/em&gt; can clip through surfaces you want to climb, which can undo some healthy progress if you’re in the middle of some creative platforming. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lx9U5d"&gt;I also appreciate that the point of &lt;em&gt;Sable&lt;/em&gt; is for you to cruise on your hoverbike &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22688375/sable-soundtrack-music-composer-japanese-breakfast-interview"&gt;vibing to music&lt;/a&gt; that wouldn’t sound out of place on a “lofi beats to chill to” playlist, but sometimes, I wish there was just a little bit more in the world for you to see. The landscape is the attraction, and it is breathtaking, but there were times that after cresting a dune, I had hoped to see a hidden town or a temple to explore instead of just more sand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pQhv0N"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sable&lt;/em&gt; is a soft, slow game that only asks of you to be present in your surroundings. I learned that lesson acutely and by accident. At one point, I noticed that I didn’t know what I could do with the menagerie of bugs I collected. To find out, I fast-traveled to the nearest vendor to see if I could sell them or trade them for a badge. While speaking to the vendor, I noticed smoke billowing in the distance — indicative of some kind of settlement. &lt;em&gt;Sable&lt;/em&gt; refuses to give you explicit direction but will hint at where you can visit on your map. When I saw the smoke, I checked my map to see if there was a village I somehow missed in my travels, but I couldn’t see any of the usual visual cues the map uses to denote a place of interest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="71c1y6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Sable&lt;/em&gt; is a soft, slow game that only asks of you to be present in your surroundings.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="V3Rg8R"&gt;The village was far away and situated atop a plateau too tall for my stamina bar. Since most of my enjoyment of&lt;em&gt; Sable&lt;/em&gt; came from figuring out, “How do I get up there?” — I decided to try. It took a fair bit of planning and stamina management, but I made it to the settlement to find a lone NPC. I opened my map again since, once you visit a place in Sable, it gets named on your map and becomes a fast-travel destination. It was then I noticed that this place was indeed marked on my map, but I was too far zoomed out and covered in quest waypoints to see it. It felt like a bell going off in my head, in which the premise of &lt;em&gt;Sable&lt;/em&gt; revealed itself to me: f you focus too much on the forest, you miss the trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S1Ker7"&gt;At the beginning of the game, your mother figure says that your Gliding can be as long or as short as you want it. Functionally, this means there is no set number of masks you must collect before you can “end” the game. After earning only one, you can simply return home, select a mask, and complete your Gliding. I didn’t focus too much on acquiring masks, knowing I could return home at any time, figuring there would be some point at which all the wandering would finally get to me enough to “end” the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SwxWHh"&gt;While exploring, I found the wreckage of a spaceship. Inside, it was like the shrines in &lt;em&gt;Breath of the Wild&lt;/em&gt;, requiring you to complete a simple puzzle to gain access to the ship’s control room. There, you meet an AI who shares with you a piece of a recording from the long dead crew. The AI suggests you find other ships to piece together the whole recording but can’t tell you where they are. As I went about earning badges and climbing the highest peaks, I slowly found each of the spaceships, and through them, I learned the story of this world and how its people got there. Once I learned the secret of the world, I was satisfied that I had reached a natural ending point. That knowledge was what my Gliding was supposed to show me, and more than that, I had gotten all that I needed out of the game. So I returned home, chose my mask, and ended the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yYM9of"&gt;Most video games are about “beating” them, giving you an objective to satisfy or a quest to complete. &lt;em&gt;Sable&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t need you to complete it. That might be why the game’s best moments don’t happen along some questline but are experienced only through dogged exploration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="phgDSx"&gt;Sable is available now on Steam, Xbox, and Xbox Game Pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gc0uqr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22699023/sable-review-xbox-steam"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22699023/sable-review-xbox-steam</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-28T15:58:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-28T15:58:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>Most people aren’t accessing their medical records on their phones</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="FRANCE-HEALTH-VIRUS-VACCINE" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a7xeQar1qDGtxKY8c-h0T0hD8BA=/0x0:5260x3507/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69922276/1230393274.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by SAMEER AL-DOUMY/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5A0wRE"&gt;Even as more and more people in the United States start to have access to their medical records online, most are still far more likely to use their computers to log in to patient portals than a smartphone app, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.healthit.gov/sites/default/files/page/2021-09/HINTS_2020_Consumer_Data_Brief.pdf"&gt;new report&lt;/a&gt; from the Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Pt07z"&gt;Almost 40 percent of US adults said that they accessed their health records through a patient portal in 2020, according to the report, which analyzed data from the Health Information National Trends Survey (HINTS) run by the National Cancer Institute. That’s up from 25 percent in 2014. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q5aHy5"&gt;The survey only collected data from January through April 2020. That captures the early stages of the COVID-19 pandemic when doctors started to transition to telehealth — which often requires patients to log in through a portal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EAcPee"&gt;Of the people who did use a portal during the study period, around 40 percent said that they only or sometimes used a smartphone app to access it. That lines up with a trend that started even before the pandemic. People have been slow to start using apps for their health records, even though tech companies have been trying to generate interest for years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LPX7kj"&gt;Apple, for example, has a health records section in its Health app, and it is available to patients at around 700 hospitals. It’s hard to tell how many patients are actually using it: most hospitals aren’t tracking that data, &lt;a href="https://medcitynews.com/2021/09/546989/"&gt;a &lt;em&gt;MedCity News&lt;/em&gt; report&lt;/a&gt; found, and Apple declined to tell &lt;em&gt;MedCity News&lt;/em&gt; how many people use the feature. But one hospital that did have the information available, UC San Diego Health Sciences, said that only a small fraction of its patients used Apple’s health records. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xOYWuZ"&gt;Google is also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/12/22379846/google-health-record-data-app-android"&gt;working on a medical records tool&lt;/a&gt;. It would be Google’s second attempt in this space — it launched Google Health in 2008 before shutting the program down in 2012, citing low adoption. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7YLOEE"&gt;The report was not able to differentiate third-party apps, like the Apple feature, from apps directly distributed by a healthcare organization or electronic medical record company. The Office of the National Coordinator told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that it is testing additional questions that it hopes capture that nuance on the 2022 survey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tKw1SZ"&gt;The HINTS data also showed that more and more people are messaging their doctors through their portals. Just under 60 percent of people in the study said they used the systems to send messages in 2020, up from 48 percent in 2017. Again, though, this data only captures the very start of the COVID-19 pandemic. Other analysis of data from electronic health records in 2020 shows that use of the messaging feature &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22679239/patient-messages-health-record-epic-doctor-burnout"&gt;spiked around April 2020&lt;/a&gt;, and that it stayed high through the rest of the year. Doctors say they’re overwhelmed by the volume. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="azukBd"&gt;The reasons people &lt;em&gt;don’t &lt;/em&gt;use their online medical records have stayed consistent: people said that they’d rather speak to a doctor directly, and that they don’t see a need to access their medical records online. Around a quarter of people said they found it difficult to log in, and 20 percent said they were uncomfortable with computers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PeBEe5"&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic, though, accelerated efforts to make digital health and telemedicine more accessible. Doctors spent the past year helping patients set up online access so that they could get the care they needed without leaving home. This report outlines a baseline comfort level with online records before that work took place. Additional analysis on the rest of 2020 could help show how successful those efforts may have been. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22698323/patient-portal-health-records-smartphone-app"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22698323/patient-portal-health-records-smartphone-app</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-28T15:47:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-28T15:47:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla asks owners to share fewer clips of ‘Full Self-Driving’ beta mistakes</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dIdykzp1Qsx46BgGxa7QSRSTPVM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69922179/tesla.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xuJIR4"&gt;Tesla is making owners who opt in to the controversial beta version of its “Full Self-Driving” software sign non-disclosure agreements and is also discouraging them from sharing video clips that show the driver assistance system making mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pwf56r"&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/m7ezxq/how-teslas-self-driving-beta-testers-protect-the-company-from-critics"&gt;a copy of the NDA obtained by &lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Tesla tells those who sign the document that “there are a lot of people that want Tesla to fail; Don’t let them mischaracterize your feedback and media posts.” The company also says owners in the beta should “share on social media responsibly and selectively” and “consider sharing fewer videos, and only the ones that you think are interesting or worthy of being shared.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nmTZoS"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vice’s&lt;/em&gt; report comes as Tesla is now working on expanding access to the “Full Self-Driving” software, all while the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22673497/tesla-nhtsa-autopilot-investigation-data-ford-gm-vw-toyota"&gt;National Highway Traffic Safety Administration investigates&lt;/a&gt; the company’s less-advanced Autopilot driver assistance system currently available on its cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="HuF5P3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“there are a lot of people that want Tesla to fail”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="STU5Pi"&gt;Tesla has allowed a small group of die-hard owners to test the beta version of the “Full Self-Driving” software for about a year now. Some of them take their roles as “beta testers” quite seriously and try to find flaws in the system in an effort to help Tesla make the software better. Many also film themselves traveling around with the software running. Some compress their longer drives into supercuts, speeding up the footage to emphasize just how far the software can take them without human intervention. Others post the raw footage, warts and all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="phvdHD"&gt;(As always, to be clear: this software does not make Tesla’s cars fully autonomous. Tesla CEO Elon Musk has himself even said that he believes the “feature complete” version of the software his company calls “Full Self-Driving” will, at best, only be “&lt;a href="https://electrek.co/2020/01/13/tesla-full-self-driving-feature-complete-soon-elon-musk/#:~:text=When%20Musk%20talks%20about%20a,features%20with%20city%20driving%20capability.&amp;amp;text=So%20feature-complete%20means%20it's,it%20would%20still%20be%20supervised."&gt;likely&lt;/a&gt;” to drive someone from their home to work without human intervention and will still require supervision. That does not describe a fully autonomous car.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="urkwCl"&gt;This whole process — the years of unfulfilled claims of being able to make fully autonomous cars, the idea of beta testing in-development drivers assistance software on public streets with untrained owners behind the wheel — has drawn Musk and Tesla a lot of scrutiny. Recently, though, a clip from a video originally shot by Tesla owner and investor Galileo Russell went viral and charged the conversation even more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="TdLSlV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A few people in the “Full Self-Driving” beta show the software with no edits, warts and all&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="A5ZAlF"&gt;In it, Russell’s car should be merging left, but it &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DavidZipper/status/1439681683880546306"&gt;suddenly takes a dive to the right&lt;/a&gt;, eventually pointing straight at pedestrians in a crosswalk. A hedge fund owner shared this clip on Twitter, where many people (rightfully) were aghast at how close the car came to running over pedestrians. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hfP9N9"&gt;In a follow-up video, Russell made a passing mention about how Tesla “&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/gvgsoRPiWA8?t=118"&gt;doesn’t want&lt;/a&gt;” people in the beta sharing clips that look bad while making a larger point explaining why he posted the video to begin with. But it wasn’t until &lt;em&gt;Vice &lt;/em&gt;reported on the NDA this week that it was clear what he meant.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E3djub"&gt;Tesla is using this language to try and control the public perception of its “Full Self-Driving” software as the company starts to open up access to a much wider group — despite the software still being in development. Tesla added &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/26/22693610/tesla-opens-full-self-driving-beta-software-more-customers"&gt;a button to the user interface of its cars&lt;/a&gt; this past weekend that lets owners request to be a part of the beta. It also launched a “safety score” system, which monitors drivers who apply and evaluates them on a number of metrics, like braking habits or aggressive acceleration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZtQfgS"&gt;At the moment, Musk says drivers with a perfect safety score of 100 will be accepted into the beta, though he tweeted that &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1442707528924684293"&gt;Tesla will lower that bar&lt;/a&gt;. He also said Tesla will soon start adding up to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1442706542839701510"&gt;1,000 new owners per day&lt;/a&gt; to the beta, a dramatic expansion of who will be able to test the driver assistance software out on public roads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vertcf"&gt;Expanding access is sure to bring even more attention to Tesla and Musk’s patchwork approach to rolling out the “Full Self-Driving” software. In fact, it already has. Last week, National Transportation Safety Board chair Jennifer Homendy told the &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; that she wished the company would address “basic safety issues” before allowing new owners into the program. Homendy was one of the more outspoken board members during a 2020 hearing that found Autopilot to be partially at fault for the 2018 death of a driver in Mountain View, California. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U6AHce"&gt;Tesla doesn’t appear to be changing course, though. Over the weekend, in response to a blog post about her comments, Musk tweeted a link to Homendy’s Wikipedia page — which eventually &lt;a href="https://wccftech.com/tesla-tsla-trolls-attack-the-wikipedia-page-of-the-ntsb-director-after-her-stance-on-the-fsd-labeling-was-validated-by-an-mit-study/?utm_source=dlvr.it&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter"&gt;had to be locked&lt;/a&gt; after a sudden rush of edits.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22696463/tesla-fsd-beta-nda-video-clips-controversy-full-self-driving"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22696463/tesla-fsd-beta-nda-video-clips-controversy-full-self-driving</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-28T15:45:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-28T15:45:16-04:00</updated>
    <title>Echoes of the Eye injects a mystifying and scary microcosm into Outer Wilds</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Outer Wilds Echoes of the Eye" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ErMdEYy8Qks83xNhcrk1LWP20FM=/0x0:3176x2117/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69922162/outerwildseote.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Mobius Digital / Annapurna Interactive&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fTSrrk"&gt;Entering a state of desperation is essentially a requirement to solve many of &lt;em&gt;Outer Wilds&lt;/em&gt;’ puzzles. The game’s new $15 expansion, &lt;em&gt;Echoes of the Eye&lt;/em&gt;, features one such puzzle that had me feeling like I’d exhausted every option. I had the right tool in hand, I was in the right room. I had followed the vague tips in the slide reels I had seen so far, left behind by an intelligent species. So I did what I usually do when I lose hope in the game: reset the loop. Maybe I needed to start again with a fresh perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9GU8SD"&gt;Then I woke up in a different world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JqZ6yf"&gt;I hadn’t solved the puzzle completely, but I inadvertently progressed through the story by taking a chance on a hunch. Taking chances is core to progressing in &lt;em&gt;Outer Wilds&lt;/em&gt;, and it’s also the theme of the new storyline in &lt;em&gt;Echoes of the Eye&lt;/em&gt;, which itself feels different (and long) enough to be a standalone game. You won’t get anywhere without being bold, and sometimes they’ll pay off. But you might also end up somewhere you don’t want to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Rq3CbR"&gt;&lt;q&gt;‘Echoes of the Eye’&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;feels different (and long) enough to be a standalone title&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="I14E84"&gt;In case you haven’t played &lt;em&gt;Outer Wilds&lt;/em&gt;, it’s an open-world (more like open-universe) space exploration game where you visit planets and make archaeological discoveries, sometimes accidentally. Each planet plays a role in the greater story, which lures you into figuring out why the sun explodes every 22 minutes, and putting a stop to it. Each time loop resets everything, except your ship’s log, which collects points of interest to make it easier to go back and to piece things together as you go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="88vgJf"&gt;The aforementioned species in this new expansion, which look like wise bipedal owls with antlers, abandoned their home planet in the hopes of a better life after picking up a promising transmission from an entity in another universe, the same one your protagonist inhabits. After a few trips around The Stranger, the new “planet”-like structure added to the roster in &lt;em&gt;Outer Wilds&lt;/em&gt;, you’ll start to piece things together about what life was like, why things didn’t go according to plan, and why no one lives there despite it seeming perfectly capable of harboring life.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hoeNJL6RqJXdo3g604iPLEedAGA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22885380/OW_DLC_GIF_3.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Mobius Digital / Annapurna Interactive&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="YM9lSg"&gt;The base game of &lt;em&gt;Outer Wilds&lt;/em&gt; lets you choose which planet to go to first, and you always start the loop at your Earth-like home planet. In terms of easing the player in, &lt;em&gt;Echoes of the Eye&lt;/em&gt; is far from the easiest destination to get to or navigate within. As you might have seen from the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pt9M6WumjtE"&gt;expansion’s teaser&lt;/a&gt;, The Stranger is invisible. Though, you don’t need to have completed &lt;em&gt;Outer Wilds&lt;/em&gt; to access it; just head to the observatory on the starting planet to get your first hint as to where you’ll find it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="vU7ziY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s nice to play games without objective arrows sometimes&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iDPPeN"&gt;The Stranger offers a landscape layout that’s new to &lt;em&gt;Outer Wilds&lt;/em&gt;, and I often found myself marveling at the artistic and technical achievement on display. Like the rest of the planets, developer Mobius Digital’s knack for effortlessly guiding the player through complex environments without obvious signposting is on display here. It reminded me that it’s nice to play games without objective arrows sometimes. Few games really trust the player to figure everything out with limited information. It feels great when you can solve the puzzles with your own brain, but there were a few moments later in the expansion where I wouldn’t have turned down a little help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ly1kDS"&gt;In case you were curious, The Stranger is impacted by the sun exploding every 22 minutes, as every other planet in the game is. Its terrain changes during that time span, covering up some areas and exposing others that were previously hidden, similar to some other planets in the game. But through some crucial story beats, you’ll figure out why the rules of the universe you might know from the base game don’t necessarily apply here, for better or worse.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Outer Wilds Echoes of the Eye" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AimJCnsaAJXOsEfAUTG4MT-NfwM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22885369/outerwildseote.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Mobius Digital / Annapurna Interactive&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="iz563S"&gt;You’ll utilize the same few game mechanics from the base game, including using your jetpack and flashlight, to enter places to which you otherwise wouldn’t have access. Compared to many other games where you have countless skills at your disposal, I’ve always enjoyed the deliberately small loadout in &lt;em&gt;Outer Wilds&lt;/em&gt; because it makes every new addition — of which there are a few in &lt;em&gt;Echoes of the Eye&lt;/em&gt; — feel important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tWt1rZ"&gt;After about 10 hours with &lt;em&gt;Echoes of the Eye&lt;/em&gt;, it felt different from the main game, but initially it didn’t deliver on the mystique I was expecting — though that changes as you approach the end. I won’t go into details, but the latter sections of the story put you in tense situations that made me feel like I was playing a survival horror game. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g6nx68"&gt;Like the rest of the adventures in &lt;em&gt;Outer Wilds&lt;/em&gt;, once your objectives become clear, the gameplay morphs. The landscapes become obstacle courses, especially as you try to accomplish more with limited time in each loop. And it sheds its chill space exploration facade to reveal that it’s basically a speed-running game where you’re racing against the clock to find the answers to life’s biggest questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="7k51p6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Once your objectives become clear, the gameplay morphs&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TZBQIm"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Echoes of the Eye&lt;/em&gt; diverges from the base game in some welcome ways, but it still feels like it’s a part of the same universe. It was a risk for Mobius Digital to squeeze another planet into &lt;em&gt;Outer Wilds&lt;/em&gt;, which already felt like a complete package with more than enough mystery to unspool. But this spooky, mystifying expansion is an integral part of the experience, as well as a fantastic send-off for a special game.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AfG3LR"&gt;&lt;small&gt;Echoes of the Eye&lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt; and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;Outer Wilds&lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt; are available on PC via Epic Games Store and Steam, along with PS4 and Xbox One (and playable on newer consoles). &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22698855/outer-wilds-echoes-of-the-eye-expansion-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22698855/outer-wilds-echoes-of-the-eye-expansion-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-28T14:40:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-28T14:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Say hello to Astro, Alexa on wheels</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/l7dpf3bWovxrVtkCq25B9PgsALU=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69921026/amazon_astro_home_robot_4773_8.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon’s Astro home robot&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Amazon’s long-awaited home robot is here&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="uWyMCR"&gt;In the fall of 1962, TV-watching audiences were invited to meet the Jetsons, a space-dwelling, flying-car-driving family from the future and their dog, Astro. Today, Amazon wants you to meet a different Astro, one that’s not quite as fantastical or futuristic as the Jetsons, but actually available in our present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kguNTY"&gt;Amazon’s Astro is not a dog; instead, it’s the company’s long-rumored home assistant robot. Though Amazon denies taking inspiration for the name from &lt;em&gt;The Jetsons&lt;/em&gt;, it was hard to ignore the resemblance to a faithful pet when I got to see the Astro in action last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1PkMmz"&gt;The Astro, which will initially cost $999.99 and available as a Day 1 Edition product that you can request an invite for the privilege of buying, is Amazon’s most ambitious in-home product yet. Amazon sees it as bringing together many different parts of the company — robotics, AI, home monitoring, cloud services — all into one device. Best described as the love child between a Roomba and an Echo Show smart display, the Astro is meant to be the next step in what Amazons believes to be the seemingly inevitable home robot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="H4TG3L"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Astro is an attempt to combine a number of Amazon’s strengths&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="duHyjP"&gt;Amazon claims the Astro can do a wide variety of things you might want from a home robot. It can map out your floor plan and obey commands to go to a specific room. It can recognize faces and deliver items to a specific person. It can play music and show you the weather and answer questions like any Echo smart display. It can be used for video calls, always keeping you in frame by literally following your movements. It can roam around your house when you aren’t home, making sure everything is okay. It can raise its periscope camera to show you whether you’ve turned the stove off. It can use third-party accessories to record data like blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OCZCzw"&gt;But as ambitious as the Astro is, it still is very much a first cut at what a home assistant robot could be. It doesn’t have any arms or appendages; it can’t clean your floors; it can’t climb stairs; it can’t go outside of your home; and it probably can’t do a zillion other things I’m not thinking of at the moment. That’s part of the reason why Amazon is limiting its availability at launch — even after years of development, it still has a lot to figure out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YwFIZVGehrzFZPaiLR_o10astWk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22882955/amazon_astro_home_robot_4773_9.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Astro has a 10-inch touchscreen for a “face” and a wide array of sensors for eyes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="Nu5NSx"&gt;The Astro stands roughly two feet high and weighs about 20 pounds. Its main drive wheels are about 12 inches in diameter, large enough to clear door thresholds and move through carpet, while a single caster in the back helps it keep balanced. The Astro can zip along at a top speed of one meter per second and it has the ability to move in 360 degrees, forward, back, or any direction it pleases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U5QMQk"&gt;Inside the plastic-clad shell are five different motors: one for each drive wheel, one to raise and lower its periscope camera, and two to twist and tilt its “face.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LpzbH5"&gt;That face is effectively the screen lifted off an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22297810/amazon-echo-show-10-2021-review"&gt;Echo Show 10&lt;/a&gt;. It’s got an array of sensors in its bezel, plus a standard 5-megapixel video calling camera. Most of the time, the screen displays two circles that behave as “eyes,” allowing you to understand what the Astro is doing or where it’s planning to go. It can also show some limited personality through these circles, contorting them into different shapes and angles, similar to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/3/4/18250104/jibo-social-robot-server-shutdown-offline-dead"&gt;ill-fated Jibo’s expressions&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/29/18523124/anki-drive-robot-toy-company-out-of-business-shutting-down"&gt;also-ill-fated Cozmo&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0V5uSs"&gt;But those circles aren’t what the Astro uses to see you or its environment. It’s actual “eyes” are the variety of sensors and cameras packed into the base of the unit, things like ultrasonic sensors, time-of-flight cameras, and other imaging tools that let the robot know what’s around it and where it’s going. The Astro’s navigational tools are all inside of itself — there’s no need for special boundary markers or other external guidelines like some robot vacuums rely on — and it can tell when it’s about to head down a set of stairs or hit an object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="wuELuL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Amazon’s race to create the disappearing computer","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22696187/amazon-alexa-ambient-disappearing-computer-limp-interview"},{"title":"Amazon’s new Echo Show 15 is meant to hang on your wall","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22693503/amazon-echo-show-15-smart-display-wall-price-specs-features"},{"title":"Amazon marries Ring and Eero in a neat, white package","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22692073/ring-alarm-pro-amazon-event-release-date-specs-price-features"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="vVEEzJ"&gt;In another similarity to a robot vacuum, the Astro will use these sensors to map out your home. You can label each room and adjust the boundaries in the Astro smartphone app. You can also set up specific “viewpoints” in your home that the robot will remember. From there, you can tell the Astro to go to a specific location either with a voice command or remotely through the app. Since the Astro can’t go up or down stairs, Amazon expects most people to place it on the main floor of their home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="icgHLn"&gt;Amazon says all of the processing and storage for these maps happens locally on the device. Then a “portion of that data is sent securely to the cloud” so that you can tell the Astro where to go using the smartphone app. The Astro can only be paired to a single phone at a time — a security measure to help prevent unauthorized access or use. Similarly, its facial recognition data is also stored locally on the Astro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3NRb7I"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Amazon Astro demo clip|104104" data-volume-uuid="f75493661" data-volume-id="104104" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-98" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="chorus"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="caption"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Inside the Astro are five different motors that allow it to move freely. | &lt;/em&gt;Animation: Amazon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UhwiLi"&gt;Between the sensors on the front of the robot are a couple of two-inch speakers. There’s also a passive resonator on the bottom to improve bass output. These can get quite loud when playing music, and since the Astro can literally follow you around and always move itself to the optimal position, you’re almost always going to be able to hear it well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zbqL3W"&gt;To make up for its diminutive size, the Astro has a 12-megapixel periscope camera that can raise up to 42 inches high, enough to see over a typical counter or table. This camera can be used for video calls or viewed through the accompanying phone app to see what’s happening inside your home when you’re not there. Surrounding the telescoping pole are the far-field mics that are used to pick up voice commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tdq4gU"&gt;Around back is a small payload area, capable of carrying 4.4lbs (2kg) of cargo. By default, this area has an insert with two cupholders, but that can easily be swapped for a basic bin. Amazon envisions this area to be something third parties will take advantage of and for which they’ll design accessories. There’s a 15-watt USB-C port in the payload area that you can use to charge your phone, but the real utility of that is for accessories to plug into. Amazon’s executives spoke of a blood pressure cuff that will utilize it, though I wasn’t able to see that in person.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Znw2OvCFTyJD9q8kPp8RLHcLEEQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22882953/amazon_astro_home_robot_4773_10.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A 42-inch tall periscope camera allows the Astro to see over counters or other tall obstacles.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="QclzNK"&gt;Like a robot vacuum (again), the Astro has a charging dock to which it can automatically attach itself. Charging the battery from zero to 100 takes about 45 minutes and it can go for about two hours of motion between charges. The Astro is designed to manage its battery life on its own — if it needs to recharge, it will just go to its dock by itself — but you can also tell it to do so by voice commands, through the touchscreen or in the app. The internal battery is located under the payload area and can be replaced when it no longer holds a charge, but it’s not designed to be changed frequently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OwZ4mV"&gt;The brains of the Astro are Qualcomm chips, not the Amazon-designed AZ2 processor that’s in the new Echo Show 15. The company says it used Qualcomm silicon here because of the Astro’s long development time. Like its maps, all of the Astro’s processing and movements happen locally — for privacy reasons but also for practicality. A cloud-based system wouldn’t be able to respond as quickly when the Astro needs to navigate around an unfamiliar obstacle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g87IU5"&gt;For those interested, the Astro’s functionality is built on top of Fire OS and Linux. Amazon isn’t announcing an official Astro SDK today, but it says, “it’s easy to imagine a world where customers and developers can build unique capabilities that allow Astro to keep getting better over time, and we look forward to sharing more details in the future.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vVtSkP"&gt;The Astro’s design isn’t particularly beautiful or elegant — its utilitarian looks seem to be driven more by functionality than emotion. Amazon executives told me many different form factors and designs were tested and this shape is what they’ve landed on for now. But the design is not offensive or intimidating either, something that is important to get right if people are going to accept a largely autonomous robot in their homes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9hmlMkk8vl0V-2p_lK38S4L8Ikc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22882947/amazon_astro_home_robot_4773_16.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Astro’s large wheels allow it to roll over most obstacles it might encounter in a home, like thresholds or power cables.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="W8c2b3"&gt;Trying to wrap your head around how all of those features and capabilities together might be useful in your home can be a challenge. Amazon envisions a handful of use cases — home security monitoring, remote elder care, and convenience — but it also readily admits that there could be more that just haven’t been found yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ttfkh9"&gt;That first use case is perhaps the most obvious one. The Astro can integrate with Ring’s security alarm system and function much like a Ring camera. It can capture video clips of events and send them to Ring’s cloud, and it can also automatically go to the site of a disturbance, if say a Ring motion or door sensor goes off when you’re not home. You can also program it to make autonomous patrols on a schedule, or direct it manually to go check something out through the Astro app. It’s not unlike the pitch for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22456089"&gt;Ring Always Home Cam drone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tBCMoH"&gt;Remote monitoring of your home is perhaps where the Astro’s periscope camera is most useful. You can tell it to raise the camera to see over a counter or obstacle and switch between the periscope camera and the camera mounted above the screen easily. Amazon’s execs were eager to tell me how useful it is to check if the oven was left on when you aren’t home. The Astro also has Alexa Guard integration, allowing it to alert you to sounds of a broken window or smoke alarm, just like an Echo speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FifZt_-Js2CtWZdeIan-SQmSyVk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22882946/amazon_astro_home_robot_4773_17.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Astro has sensors and cameras all around it help it navigate your home.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LVq3eu6oBujSB0PNQRVuMC2ORPQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22882948/amazon_astro_home_robot_4773_14.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Astro’s rear payload area is customizable — Amazon anticipates third-party companies will make accessories for it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fCB9zC"&gt;Amazon also envisions the Astro as being useful for remote monitoring of elderly relatives. Thanks to its ability to recognize faces, it can look for an elderly person and provide status notifications to their caregivers. Routines can be programmed where it will remind the person to take medication or check their blood pressure when they need to; the Astro’s ability to find them means that it can deliver this reminder even if they aren’t in the same room as it. The Astro will also be integrated into the new Alexa Together service, which provides access to an emergency helpline and support for fall detection devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OoF34h"&gt;Lastly, Amazon sees the Astro as the next level of how Alexa can integrate into your home. Though the Astro’s wake word for voice commands is “Astro” (by default, it can be changed to Alexa, Echo, or Computer, but sadly not Artoo), the intelligence underpinning it all is Alexa. The Astro is effectively an Echo Show on wheels — you can ask it to follow you around as you do things; have it play music or podcasts while you’re doing chores; ask it to set reminders, timers, or take a photo; use it for video calling through Alexa’s calling service; and do all the other things an Echo Show can do. The software on the screen itself is effectively lifted right off the Echo Show, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cZ6OPw"&gt;The Astro’s ability to recognize faces means it knows who it’s looking at and can play a greeting or turn on your favorite music when it sees you. It’s designed to learn your habits, so if you end up using it most of the time in the kitchen, it will park itself there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h3Xxgf"&gt;Amazon has also built more personality into the Astro than we’re used to from Alexa. It will move its body, change the shape of its eyes, and adjust its screen to express attention or emotions. You can ask it to do silly things like dance, and it moves around in a way that’s meant to make it easy to tell where it’s going, when it’s going to turn, and so on. Amazon says that beta testers claimed the Astro’s personality made it feel more like a part of their home than a smart speaker or other gadget; it will surely draw comparisons to the Jibo robot that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/19/18682780/jibo-death-server-update-social-robot-mourning"&gt;engendered similar attachments&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TbYJoDPvp1xr3btFgORYCKOfEoQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22882961/amazon_astro_home_robot_4773_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Astro will turn its “head” to look at you or indicate where it’s going.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="NArSd4"&gt;For all of the things that the Astro can do, however, there’s a laundry list of things it can’t. In a demo of the device ahead of its official announcement, I was able to see Astro perform a variety of tasks, such as go to a specific room, find a particular person, take a photo, and so on. I was able to ask it to follow me around as I walked from one room to another; it had no trouble navigating around random obstacles that ended up in its path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fZpU1u"&gt;But as mentioned, it can’t go outside; it can’t go up or down stairs; it has no arms or appendages to open doors or cabinets; and it can’t help you move or get up if you’ve fallen down. Sure, it can deliver an ice cold beer to a specific person, but someone still has to get the beer out of the fridge and put it in the back of the Astro before telling it where to go. It can show you that the oven was left on, but it has no ability to press the buttons itself to turn it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="9eGTFh"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Astro’s competition will be software assistants as much as other robots&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2RYUTG"&gt;It also doesn’t do a lot of assistant-type things that software is already starting to handle. There’s no ability for it to answer your phone and deal with telemarketers (something Google Pixel phones are already doing) or have it work with your doctor’s office to schedule your next appointment. The Astro can tell you when someone’s rung the doorbell, but it can’t go ahead and sign for that package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KEoOzQ"&gt;Amazon, for its part, is clear-eyed about the Astro’s limitations. That’s part of the reason why it’s releasing it with a limited, invite-only system before launching it to the public. The company told me that things like robot arms and other appendages could certainly unlock many more capabilities, but right now the cost is too great to make them practical or accessible. There’s also the problem of what people will be comfortable with in their home at this stage — the Astro’s current design isn’t a huge leap from a robot vacuum, but add a bunch of R2-D2-like grabber arms and the ability to open doors and people might start getting uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/c2_KpgEqiXwOQtAqeWeOykAbjUU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22882959/amazon_astro_home_robot_4773_5.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Astro uses the circles on its screen to express different emotions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="OsQNTN"&gt;That’s why, as it functions right now, the Astro feels more like an artificial pet than a true robotic assistant. It can do some tricks, provide some entertainment, and help out a little bit here and there, but it’s far from the kind of robots that science fiction has conditioned us to expect. Even the Astro’s insistence on putting itself in the best position for you to see and hear it (a couple feet in front of you, screen tilted up toward you) is undeniably similar to a dog begging for some scratches behind the ears or a piece of jerky. It’s hard not to find the thing just a little bit endearing as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DKp1pR"&gt;Amazon is convinced that everyone will have a robot of some sort in their home in the next five to ten years. The Astro is the company’s attempt to get out ahead of the field, before it’s too crowded with competitors. (It used this exact same approach to great success with the Echo.) It’s also only the first of its attempts at putting a robot in your home, and given the company’s nearly endless resources, it doesn’t need the Astro to be a huge sales success to keep developing on this idea. The introductory price of $999.99 includes a six-month trial of Ring Protect Pro, though Amazon says its price will go up to $1449.99 once it reaches broader release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="wMcoFF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Many questions about the Astro remain unanswered for now&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pdQ09j"&gt;The question for all of us then, is how much do we want to be testing Amazon’s ideas and experiments in our most intimate of spaces? The company has done a lot to mitigate privacy concerns with the Astro’s local processing, but it can’t possibly know every way someone will feel their personal space violated by a robot in their home until it’s already there. That’s why it needs to do larger-scale testing than it’s able to do in secret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2F70vj"&gt;I’m also curious to see how it reacts and behaves in a real-world environment, outside of Amazon’s beta testers. How’s it going to function when a toddler decides it’d be fun to sit on the back and ride it? How will a real-life dog deal with this robotic interloper in its domain? Can it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22660467/irobot-roomba-ai-dog-poop-avoidance-j7-specs-price"&gt;avoid dog poop&lt;/a&gt;? How useful will it actually be when it’s limited to just one floor of a multistory home? How much convenience can it really add beyond the smart speakers that are already in my home?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="XYo9jo"&gt;Those answers will have to wait until we’re able to spend more time with the Astro and push its capabilities first hand. Until then, we’ll have to be content with dreams of robotic dogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1denEK"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PgwXCO"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction, 2:40PM ET, Tuesday, September 28th:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; An earlier version said the maps of a home that the Astro creates are never sent to the cloud. That is incorrect — Amazon says a “portion” of the mapping data is stored in the cloud for remote access via the phone app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FPfKgh"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sCkANI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22697244/amazon-astro-home-robot-hands-on-features-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22697244/amazon-astro-home-robot-hands-on-features-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-28T14:20:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-28T14:20:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Package alerts come to Ring’s wired doorbells</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5va60agsnJ_vGfFz97cVGR84Co0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69920872/dseifert_20210323_4486_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The Ring Pro 2 video doorbell (pictured) and the Ring Video Doorbell (2020) will now be able to tell you when a package is on your doorstep.  | Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="K03c9F"&gt;Ring is bringing package alerts to its Ring video doorbells, and it’s about time, too. This is a much-requested feature that’s already found on most of its competitors’ camera doorbell offerings. When the main selling point for a product is that it will deter porch pirates, it’s kind of important to be able to keep a virtual eye on those packages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3UjgaN"&gt;The pings that will tell you when a package is on your porch will start rolling out to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22359973/ring-video-doorbell-pro-2-review"&gt;Ring Pro 2&lt;/a&gt; and Ring Video Doorbell (2020) in the US and internationally today and should arrive on other buzzers next year. But this still doesn’t address a big issue with most of Ring’s doorbells; the cameras’ wide viewing angles often don’t pick up the spot where the package is left. Only the Pro 2 has a head-to-toe view for seeing the whole porch.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/S_knnMUMfe3Pm_OPE5jz4MY5cN0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22884281/Package_Alerts.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Ring&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Ring Pro 2 is the only Ring doorbell that can show you a head-to-toe view, which is useful for seeing packages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="trcpZF"&gt;Along with playing catch-up in the industry it invented, Ring has a new trick up its sleeve: Custom Event Alerts. This feature lets you create your own alert based on the information you want to know. For example, is the garage door open? Is the car in the driveway? Is the front door shut? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q59NRh"&gt;Custom Event Alerts will only be available on the Spotlight Cam Battery and are scheduled to arrive later this year. Both Package Alerts and Custom Event Alerts require a subscription to a Ring Protect plan (starting at $3 a month or $30 a year).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Q6jvQh"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Ring custom alerts demo video|104114" data-volume-uuid="48c385801" data-volume-id="104114" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-182" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="chorus"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BapcvU"&gt;Ring says the custom alerts work by having you train your camera on the two states you want it to recognize, such as when a garage door is left open or closed or when a car is in the driveway or not. The computer vision algorithm processes images of the scene in the cloud or locally on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22455992"&gt;Ring Alarm Pro (Ring’s new smart security hub)&lt;/a&gt; and sends an alert when it sees a change. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wcIUPc"&gt;“You can literally build your own detector — there’s so many neat things to do with it,” said Ring founder Jamie Siminoff in an interview. He taught a camera to tell him when his HVAC compressor was on or off. “I was having problems with the outdoor compressor and was able to train it to tell me if the fan was spinning or if it wasn’t.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OYXn7G4dSx_TbWjhPm6cLT7e3fc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22884280/Custom_Event_Alerts.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Ring&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A new feature on the Ring Spotlight Cam lets you create custom event alerts to tell you when the state of something changes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SnRKzK"&gt;The camera uses computer vision and machine learning to figure out the difference between the two states and should then recognize when that state changes and alert you to it. This type of AI-powered motion detection is the next arms race in the smart home. Companies are competing to find the best way to send their users fewer annoying alerts in favor of more relevant, useful ones from their smart home cameras. And what’s more relevant than an alert you create yourself and custom design for your home? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kv2cGw"&gt;To date, Ring has been behind here, partly hampered by a reliance on battery-powered tech, which energy-intensive smart alerts can swamp. Category leaders such as Arlo and Google Nest already offer package, people, animal, and vehicle alerts, but Ring could well be the first to let you create your own. This is a bold claim, however, and we won’t know if it holds up until we’ve been able to test it ourselves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="bAJzKN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Ring’s security drone could be flying in your home soon","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22692048/ring-always-home-cam-drone-amazon-price-release-date-specs"},{"title":"Amazon marries Ring and Eero in a neat, white package","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22692073/ring-alarm-pro-amazon-event-release-date-specs-price-features"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="bvI6kV"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated, 2:20 PM, September 28th, 2021: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added details about Ring’s new Ring Alarm Pro that can process event alerts locally.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22691923/ring-video-doorbell-package-alerts-amazon-event"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22691923/ring-video-doorbell-package-alerts-amazon-event</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-28T14:20:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-28T14:20:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon marries Ring and Eero in a neat, white package</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qdTDemyzT-rSDJHnVLpd_48b3_0=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69920854/20210621_us_lifestyle_insitu_alarmpro_keypad_credenza_rgb_16x9.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Ring Alarm Pro is the latest generation of Ring’s home security system and features a built-in Eero mesh Wi-Fi router.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Ring&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;With 24/7 internet backup and on-board video processing, too, this Z-wave alarm system is now a serious smart home hub&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="KPq06A"&gt;Smart home company Ring has announced the third generation of its popular budget Ring Alarm home security product. The Ring Alarm Pro is a single device combining Ring’s security system with an Eero Wi-Fi router, 24/7 internet backup, and local processing and storage for Ring cameras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qdwFu4"&gt;This all-in-one device is designed to offer physical home security as the base station for Ring Alarm’s Z-wave sensors and digital security through the cybersecurity features Eero offers in its Wi-Fi system. It also acts as a smart home hub for compatible third-party gadgets, such as door locks, thermostats, and smoke alarms. And, with a new processor on board, the Ring Alarm Pro can connect to Ring cameras to process and store videos locally.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2c6jRhqG4gixZfHHmB18Ik6oBic=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22881783/20210414_image_device_alarmprobasestation_wht_tabletop_angled_1500x1500_rgb.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Ring&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Larger than the original Ring Alarm, the Alarm Pro is 6.63 x 6.63 x 1.56 inches and is powered by a USB-C connector.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6tPYDT"&gt;The Ring Alarm Pro costs $249.99 for just the base station or $299.99 for an eight-piece security kit including contact sensors, a motion detector, a keypad, and a Z-wave range extender. Ring claims you will be able to swap out an existing Ring Alarm Base station without having to reconnect all your devices, and pre-orders start today in the US only, with shipping beginning November 3rd. The second-generation Ring Alarm is sticking around at $199 for a five-piece kit for those who don’t need these new features. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qj5nCh"&gt;Along with the new hardware come new subscription packages. A new Ring Protect Pro subscription for $20 a month (or $200 a year) is designed to use with the new Ring Alarm Pro. This is a new level of Ring Protect that includes the local storage feature, a new 24/7 backup internet option, and an Eero Secure subscription, in addition to the cloud storage, professional monitoring, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/24/21454582/amazon-alexa-guard-plus-subscription-service-security-price-release-date"&gt;Alexa Guard Plus&lt;/a&gt; that is part of the existing Ring Protect plan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="ZN9Ilk"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“This is really the first time we’ve all rolled up our sleeves and developed a product together.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="U7fdos"&gt;Ring also announced a portable version of Ring Alarm Pro designed for job sites, such as construction sites. The system leverages the cellular connectivity and Eero Wi-Fi capabilities to keep cameras and sensors online in places where you might not have internet up and running yet. It can be set up at one site and then dismantled, packed in a specially designed case and taken to the next job. &lt;a href="https://blog.ring.com/products-innovation/ring-jobsite-security-a-new-way-to-secure-job-sites"&gt;The Ring Jobsite Security Kit &lt;/a&gt;starts at $399.99 and can be pre-ordered at &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2FHomeDepot.com&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F28%2F22692073%2Fring-alarm-pro-amazon-event-release-date-specs-price-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;HomeDepot.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="brV8oY"&gt;This consolidation of services for your home — security and internet connectivity — is a smart move by Amazon, the parent company of both Ring and Eero. And it is notable as the first time Amazon has brought two of its smart home brands together into one piece of hardware. “This is really the first time we’ve all rolled up our sleeves and developed a product together,” Nick Weaver, CEO, and co-founder of Eero, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Simplifying and converging things makes a lot of sense.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EM1Jjw"&gt;For Ring, the move was designed around providing security for the digital side of our lives, as well as the physical. “Historically, we’ve been focused on the physical security of our neighbors (customers),” explained Jamie Siminoff, founder of Ring. “But we’ve seen over the last few years how so many things have moved to digital — everything from money to pictures. We felt that, as a company whose mission is to make your neighborhood safe, just securing the physical things was no longer enough; we had to add the digital as well.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;div id="lrn1d0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10776125"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="z5gXSA"&gt;There is a lot going on with this product. And while the words “smart home hub” were conspicuously absent from the pre-announcement conversations I had with Ring and Eero on the Ring Alarm Pro, this is a white plastic box packed with smart home communication protocols that lets your devices talk to each other. Its specs include two Ethernet ports, Bluetooth for setup, a Z-wave radio, 2.4 GHz and 5Ghz Wi-Fi, Wi-Fi 6, LTE, and a 902-928 MHz Radio (it’s Sidewalk-ready, but it’s not turned on). So, yeah, it’s a smart home hub — and a powerful one at that, although somewhat hampered by being firmly locked into the Ring / Amazon Alexa ecosystem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SvaRKO"&gt;The headline feature here is the built-in Eero router, as this is the first time Eero has put its TrueMesh technology in any non-Eero branded device. It’s not the first time we’ve seen a router in a smart home hub (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/29/15098872/samsung-connect-home-wifi-router-announced-smartthings-price-release-date"&gt;Samsung’s Connect Smart Wi-Fi system&lt;/a&gt; combined mesh Wi-Fi with a SmartThings Hub). Still, the idea of merging a router and smart home / security hub helps simplify things for many everyday consumers — the clear target audience for Ring and Eero here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="eJPpKi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Ring’s $250 Always Home Cam is real and ready to fly into your living room","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22692048/ring-always-home-cam-drone-amazon-price-release-date-specs"},{"title":"Ring Video Doorbells are finally getting package alerts ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22691923/ring-video-doorbell-package-alerts-amazon-event"},{"title":"Amazon’s new Echo Show 15 is meant to hang on your wall ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22693503/amazon-echo-show-15-smart-display-wall-price-specs-features"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="eHjtXq"&gt;Case in point, the Eero inside the Ring Alarm Pro is an Eero 6, not the more advanced Eero Pro 6. It’s capable of speeds up to 900Mbps over 1,500 square feet, but those speeds drop to around 500Mbps if you add more Eero nodes to create a mesh. The Pro offers gigabit speeds throughout the network, and while you can add Pro nodes to the Ring Alarm Pro network, the Eero in the Alarm Pro will need to be the main gateway connected to your ISP. “But if you’re getting less than 500Mbps [from your ISP], there’s really no benefit to having the Pro 6,” Weaver explained. “Unless you have a lot of devices on your network.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k2Fj8A"&gt;From a security perspective, the Eero Secure service included in the $20 a month Ring Protect Pro Plan adds a layer of digital security to your network. “With Eero Secure, we’re basically ensuring that all the devices on your home network are staying safe and secure. So, you know, it blocks different attacks, helps you enable parental controls, and protects you from phishing,” said Weaver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bJf5wZ"&gt;As an alarm system, the Ring Alarm base station does everything the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/9/21215231/ring-alarm-second-generation-update-preorder-features-emergency"&gt;previous generation does&lt;/a&gt;. It can connect to Ring’s sensors and compatible third-party Z-wave devices to monitor your home for intrusion, water leaks, and fire — and send emergency police, fire and medical response in the event of an incident if you pay for 24/7 professional monitoring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9hxrvf"&gt;The most significant change on the Ring side is that the new base station can now be a hub for Ring’s cameras. A new processor in the device enables local processing of videos from Ring cameras — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22455964"&gt;including Ring’s new computer vision event-based alerts.&lt;/a&gt; The new service is called Ring Edge. “With local processing, we can do edge-based computer vision processing,” explained Mike Harris, COO of Ring. “We’ve got a whole ton of ideas that we want to put this thing to work for.” Edge-based processing means the data is processed locally rather than being sent to the cloud, helping increase speed and privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AhRWKk-EbfOT6M67TwXjjT0uBlQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22881786/20210621_us_lifestyle_insitu_alarmpro_secuirtysystem_livingroom_rgb_16x9.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Ring&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Ring Alarm Pro base station connects to Z-wave security sensors in your home.  &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AB50NE"&gt;Ring Edge also enables local storage of video through a removable microSD card (a 64GB that can hold around 47 hours of clips is included; you can use cards up to 512GB). It is part of the $20 per month Ring Protect Pro plan, so it’s not a workaround to avoid paying a monthly fee to view your camera feeds. However, it can help take the pressure off your bandwidth, and you can pick and choose which of your cameras stay local and which use the cloud to store and process video. Local videos will not be stored in the cloud, but as long as the microSD card is installed, you can view them in the Ring app. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ADNQSo"&gt;Local storage does not unlock the option of 24/7 video recording, however. That’s a feature other security camera systems offer but has been missing from Ring since the beginning. Ring Alarm Pro’s local storage is compatible with all of Ring’s current cameras except the Ring Video Doorbell (1st Gen) and Stick Up Cam (1st Gen). It won’t be available on Ring Video Doorbell 4 and Floodlight Cam Wired Pro at launch, but the company says it will be coming soon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E0n1TF"&gt;There are also improvements around the Ring Alarm’s backup capability. The Ring Alarm Pro works with a new Ring Power Pack to provide longer uptime, and its high-speed LTE connection can keep your whole Wi-Fi network online, not just your Alarm Pro. The Power Pack has an 8550mAh battery rated at 10.8V and 92.34Wh and costs $129.99. It connects to the Pro via USB-C to extend its battery life by up to eight hours. You can daisy chain up to four power packs to keep your system up and running for a little over two days. Ring says the Ring Alarm Pro only works with its power packs, so you won’t be able to use a third-party USB-C battery instead.  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i0undLFOJR1nrsXjMpgq2INw9-o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22881788/20210521_image_device_alarmprobasestation_powerpack_wht_front_stacked_1500x1500_rgb.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Ring&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ring’s new Power Packs connect via USB-C to the Ring Alarm Pro base station to get you an additional 8 hours of battery-back-up when the power goes down.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="lv9FIH"&gt;The built-in, high-speed LTE backup for your entire Wi-Fi system is perhaps the most interesting feature here. “The cellular backup went from LTE that was useful for the local connection for backing up your alarm devices to a high-speed connection that can back up basically everything on your Wi-Fi network,” explained Harris. It’s fast enough to keep your internet connection up and running in the event of a power outage and / or internet outage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0R9iW6"&gt;The Ring Protect Pro plan includes up to 3GB of cellular data per month, with the option of extra data for $3 per gigabyte. It’s capable of keeping your entire Eero network online if you want, but within the Ring and Eero apps, you can designate which devices you want to stay online, so you don’t inadvertently eat up all that expensive data because your internet went down while you were streaming Netflix in 4K. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fE1DBx"&gt;This type of built-in redundancy can be handy on a daily basis to alleviate cries of pain from your kid’s bedroom when a power blip kicks them out of their latest Fortnite battle or prevent your Zoom call from dropping at that crucial moment. But it could really come into its own in an emergency situation, such as an evacuation due to a hurricane or wildfire. Knowing you can check in on your battery-powered security cameras and still stream live and recorded video for at least two days after power and internet have gone down (assuming cellular networks are still up) is a compelling use case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DPogXE"&gt;Viewed as a whole, the Ring Alarm Pro is a big leap forward in the smart home security space, especially when combined with the new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22455992"&gt;Virtual Security Guard service Ring also announced today&lt;/a&gt; that allows for real-time monitoring of your exterior cameras. While we’ve seen smart security systems that offer smart home features from several companies, such as Abode, Simplisafe, Vivint, and ADT, this product takes the concept of smart home security to the next level. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="fKu5Mr"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Viewed as a whole, the Ring Alarm Pro is a big leap forward in the smart home security space&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="M4R3VP"&gt;But for homes that don’t need or want a professionally monitored security system, this is overkill. And there’s no easy way to separate the features here: everything is bundled into that Ring Protect Pro plan. If you already have a powerful mesh Wi-Fi network setup and don’t turn on the Eero in the device, then you lose access to that 24/7 backup internet feature, as well as the online protections, as it’s only available for devices connected to the built-in Eero network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FLKHl7"&gt;For the smart home user, there is also a glaring piece of the puzzle missing: Zigbee. Unlike in the other Eero gateway devices, there is no Zigbee chip for enabling smart home devices to connect to your Amazon Alexa smart home system. The Ring Alarm Pro does have Zigbee on board — it’s been in the Ring Alarm since its first iteration. But it’s not turned on, and there is no support for OpenThread. “We may enable Zigbee on Ring Alarm Pro in the future,” says the company. “If a customer wants Zigbee Smart Home Hub or Thread support today, they can add an Eero 6 router or any Eero Pro 6 device to their network.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zaQ2Ip"&gt;We’re also concerned about managing all these new features through the already bloated, confusing, and very slow Ring app (seeing as Ring launched an app called Rapid Ring to more quickly access your camera feed, it’s clear the company knows this is an issue). While the Wi-Fi management stays separately in the excellent Eero app — everything else is routed through Ring, which could be an exercise in frustration. If there ever was a moment for Ring to launch a fully-featured web interface, it is now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="gemldY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s hard not to see the Ring Alarm Pro as a compelling product at a good price&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1yqNIO"&gt;It’s hard not to see the Ring Alarm Pro as a compelling product at a good price. It neatly wraps up some of the key aspects of the modern, connected home into an easy-to-use package. It does lock you into the Amazon / Ring / Eero world, but with the coming of Matter, that may not be as much of an issue as it once was. Ring wouldn’t confirm its participation in Matter and the Ring Alarm Pro, but Harris did say that Ring is “definitely part of all of those conversations.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fAXkPC"&gt;This is also a big move for Amazon, consolidating its disparate smart home brands into a cohesive hardware package and connecting them by more than just the company’s Alexa voice assistant. From Ring’s perspective, it makes a lot of sense to have a reliable Wi-Fi router in its hardware. Keeping its Wi-Fi cameras connected to a strong enough signal in customers’ homes has been a major challenge for the company from day one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="hid2VU"&gt;For an initial outlay of $250 and monthly costs of $20 covering professional monitoring, digital security, and internet backup, we see a lot of value here. How much that value is worth in the real world will have to wait until we’re able to get some first-hand experience with the new system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RwNeXb"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated, 2:20 PM, September 28th, 2021: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added details about Ring’s new computer vision alerts and new Virtual Security Guard service.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22692073/ring-alarm-pro-amazon-event-release-date-specs-price-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22692073/ring-alarm-pro-amazon-event-release-date-specs-price-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-28T14:19:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-28T14:19:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to preorder Amazon’s latest devices</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1jjxC4BqI_R9SA3Y1oRFMewjCKY=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69921621/acastro_190920_1777_amazon_0001.0.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0gqK5Q"&gt;Amazon announced a fleet of new products at its hardware event, including the Astro home robot, several Ring home security products, and other products like a bigger Echo Show 15 and the Amazon Glow for kids. Unlike previous years, the list of products that you’ll soon be able to preorder is rather short, leaving the most interesting products available on an invite-only basis. Still, we’re going to point you to where you can find out more about getting one of them for yourself. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22692147/amazon-devices-event-echo-ring-biggest-announcements"&gt;Here are all of the biggest announcements from Amazon’s show&lt;/a&gt;, if you want to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Amazon Smart Thermostat" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AuXO9KTObeoTutguizMB7OP-fPU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22885088/AMZ_Smart_Thermostat_media_on_white_07_2000.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Amazon&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Fx1cm7"&gt;How to buy Amazon’s Smart Thermostat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="6pbd6V"&gt;One of Amazon’s most affordable devices announced today is its Smart Thermostat, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08J4C8871/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;which costs $59.99&lt;/a&gt;. It will be released on November 4th, 2021, and you can preorder one right now. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22692248/amazon-smart-thermostat-price-ambient-computer-alexa-preorder"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more details on the Smart Thermostat here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Blink Video Doorbell" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OBj-CAFGIxJTnP0n39UEiPkfWaU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22885135/blinkvideodoorbell.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Amazon&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="kazeuF"&gt;How to buy the Blink Video Doorbell&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="LwFI7g"&gt;Blink has jumped from indoor and outdoor cameras to its first video doorbell. It’s releasing on October 21st &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08SG2MS3V?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;for $49.99, and you can preorder it now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YwFIZVGehrzFZPaiLR_o10astWk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22882955/amazon_astro_home_robot_4773_9.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3VYRPP"&gt;How to buy the Amazon Astro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="VIEIjO"&gt;The star of the show was Amazon’s Astro robot. It can roll around, responding to inquiries. And its periscope camera allows it to patrol your home and see above countertops. It’s available on an invite-only basis, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B078NSDFSB/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;costing $999.99&lt;/a&gt;, though, after an introductory period, it’ll go up to $1,449.99. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22697244/amazon-astro-home-robot-hands-on-features-price"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more from our in-person demo with the Astro robot.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SBjvzl400OzMIQsaiMDthMbPZkE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22881764/20210621_us_lifestyle_insitu_alarmpro_keypad_credenza_rgb_16x9.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Ring&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="s59xb8"&gt;How to buy the Ring Alarm Pro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="CxdPR0"&gt;The eight-piece Ring Alarm Pro will be released on November 3rd, 2021, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08HSTJPM5/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;costing $299.99&lt;/a&gt;. you can preorder it now here. The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08HSRZ58F/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;base alone costs $250&lt;/a&gt;, but the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08HSVCB5M/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;14-piece is $379.99&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22692073/ring-alarm-pro-amazon-event-release-date-specs-price-features"&gt;Read more about the new security system right here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cffaqpjcp0DL-N2KbtBM60JOvmc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22884951/Screen_Shot_2021_09_28_at_10.00.30_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="zwtgnb"&gt;How to buy the Ring Always Home Cam&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ktYPNn"&gt;The Ring Always Home Cam drone is coming, following its announcement last year. Though, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08YH144XD?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;it’s invite-only for $249.99 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. There’s no indication when Amazon actually plans to release the product to those who have been invited to purchase or when it’ll allow a wider audience to invest. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22692048/ring-always-home-cam-drone-amazon-price-release-date-specs"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more about this product in our coverage right here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4U0h28QvWJvCuaWHru2ZkN4ngkA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22884036/amazon_glow_drawing.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ysBbm7"&gt;How to buy Amazon’s Glow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="5gnoAT"&gt;Amazon’s Glow is an interactive projector and video chatting gadget that you can request an invite to purchase now. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09DWNZQYM/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;It’s $249.99 during the introductory period&lt;/a&gt;, then it’ll cost $299.99. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22695707/amazon-glow-video-chat-kids-games-price-features-release-date"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more about our coverage right here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FSKG_Fc-jYS6TCc9T5B_KDS0rFA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22883479/echo_show_15_media_lifestyle_5.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Amazon&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="b2MMU8"&gt;How to buy Amazon’s Echo Show 15&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ZpxxXX"&gt;Amazon’s Echo Show 15 is its biggest smart display yet, and it’s coming out later this year. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08MQLDFF6?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;It’ll cost $249.99 when it releases&lt;/a&gt;, and you can preorder it right now. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22693503/amazon-echo-show-15-smart-display-wall-price-specs-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check out more on this device right here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LlKxQw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JY6yl4"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22698138/amazon-preorder-blink-doorbell-echo-show-15-alexa-astro-ring-alarm-pro-thermostat-glow"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22698138/amazon-preorder-blink-doorbell-echo-show-15-alexa-astro-ring-alarm-pro-thermostat-glow</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-28T14:01:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-28T14:01:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft starts testing xCloud integration on Xbox consoles</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eVREN-kBpKMbZbP2Iw9VsnvNWjk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69921471/acastro_210429_1777_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="E4SVqv"&gt;Microsoft is starting to test its Xbox Cloud Gaming (xCloud) integration with Xbox consoles today. Some Xbox Insiders in the Alpha Skip-Ahead and Alpha rings will be able to access the xCloud integration today, a feature that lets you click play on an Xbox Game Pass game and stream it immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Obvnzm"&gt;This new xCloud integration will allow Xbox owners to try games before they fully download them and potentially demo or try before you buy in the future. More than 100 Xbox Game Pass titles will be available as part of this initial xCloud integration, and Xbox players can even jump into multiplayer games as soon as friends send an invite.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4X8ax_K8ERgdjzJOa0K7L7dUOMU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22802296/Play___Minecraft_Dungeons.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;xCloud integration in the Xbox dashboard.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fA5Sjfsim5U23N2FXiJUwzr7yjA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22802300/Xbox_Game_Pass___Minecraft_Dungeons.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A cloud logo will appear on games that can be streamed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ZoCVVE"&gt;Games that are compatible with the xCloud integration will appear with a cloud symbol next to them, indicating you can stream them instantly. Microsoft will support 1080p 60fps streams of games through this integration, just like the regular web streams of Xbox Cloud Gaming. This feature isn’t being positioned as streaming for 4K TVs and more of a try before you download bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jxmtYl"&gt;Microsoft is starting testing with a “random subset of Alpha Skip-Ahead and Alpha Insiders” today, and the company will expand to other testers over time. Microsoft has promised xCloud integration will appear on all Xbox consoles by the end of the year, which will mean the Xbox One will be able to eventually stream Xbox Series S / X exclusive games like &lt;em&gt;Microsoft Flight Simulator&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Medium.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22698101/microsoft-xcloud-xbox-cloud-gaming-console-integration"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22698101/microsoft-xcloud-xbox-cloud-gaming-console-integration</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-28T13:54:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-28T13:54:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to sign up for an Amazon Astro invite</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tbTM_4DuNMdhhjFOqdLtsPj5mlk=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69921375/amazon_astro_home_robot_4773_5.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Astro features cameras, sensors, and motors to assist as it rolls around your home.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="cSOQ7y"&gt;Amazon announced a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22697244/amazon-astro-home-robot-hands-on-features-price"&gt;home robot called Astro&lt;/a&gt; during its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22692147/amazon-devices-event-echo-ring-biggest-announcements"&gt;fall hardware event today&lt;/a&gt;, September 28th, which is designed to serve as a helpful mobile assistant that can navigate around the main floor of your home. Amazon promises Astro will be able to patrol your home while you’re away, carry small objects from room to room (as long as a human places the object in its storage compartment), follow a person around with its periscope camera while on a video call, play music, and play games with children, as well as carry out a bevy of other small tasks. It’s essentially an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22297810/amazon-echo-show-10-2021-review"&gt;Echo Show 10&lt;/a&gt; on wheels, complete with Alexa support, mixed with some of the expectations of a robot vacuum sans vacuuming — room assignment, navigation, and self-charging via a dock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="dPyGKC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Amazon marries Ring and Eero in a neat, white package","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22692073/ring-alarm-pro-amazon-event-release-date-specs-price-features"},{"title":"Amazon is now accepting your applications for its home surveillance drone","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22692048/ring-always-home-cam-drone-amazon-price-release-date-specs"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="BzBoE4"&gt;The Astro is being made in small quantities to start, as Amazon figures out exactly what the robot will be capable of in a larger amount of people’s homes, so it’s starting it off as an invite-only product. The Alexa-enabled assistant robot will ultimately cost $1,449.99, but it’s available as part of Amazon’s Day 1 Editions program for $999.99 and comes bundled with a six-month trial of Ring Protect Pro service. You can submit &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B078NSDFSB/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;invite requests on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, and the company has indicated that it will begin granting invitations and shipping Astro devices to US customers “later this year.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="eExzCz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10778499"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="K4ZtcM"&gt;For those interested in the invite, be aware that clicking the big yellow button on the Amazon listing submits the request and brings up a survey with numerous advisories and inquiries about your living space, which can help you assess whether you can accommodate Astro’s various limitations. To start, Amazon asks you to indicate if your home has certain physical features or layouts. The first set of home interior features Amazon lists are “compatible with Astro, but may require special attention during setup.” These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="IQnfZZ"&gt;Frameless windows or mirrors that extend to the floor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BG2CzV"&gt;Glass coffee tables or translucent acrylic furniture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="v8ycsi"&gt;A space greater than 3,500 square feet where Astro is to be used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="mRc2ta"&gt;The next feature is not compatible with Astro, but compatibility may come in the future:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="RC8GDF"&gt;Ramps between spaces or over stairs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="YgEeUE"&gt;The remaining features Amazon lists are not compatible with Astro. They are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="em6srY"&gt;One or more steps down with a curved top edge &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="651Elk"&gt;A sunken area with a 90-degree inside corner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0Pyvmf"&gt;Flooring transitions thicker than 1.375 inches or 3.5 centimeters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="IsTpc1"&gt;Glossy black floors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="FzSMYi"&gt;If you forget to fill out this survey right away, your email confirmation from Amazon will prompt you to complete it later. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jWtPgl"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 28th, 4:17PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;: Added details regarding Astro’s various mobility restrictions as taken from Amazon’s invite survey.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22698401/amazon-astro-invite-preorder-how-to-info-early-access-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22698401/amazon-astro-invite-preorder-how-to-info-early-access-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
