<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-11-03T17:50:46-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T17:50:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T17:50:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>Roku is booting Pornhub and cutting off other private channels</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NlW4pCHF6GHhhgVB1O0_lw-99Cw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70088430/cwelch_20210428_4565_0003.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PppaZ0"&gt;After Roku announced last week that it will soon remove non-certified channels from its service, it appears the change will close a loophole that allowed apps like Pornhub to exist on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4TtmUU"&gt;The company announced last week that it would be removing so-called “non-certified channels” by March of 2022. The change comes as Roku &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22753332/roku-independent-developer-kit-idk"&gt;introduces new tools&lt;/a&gt; for developers, including a new independent developer kit that operates separately from its primary software developer kit for commercial-use channels. It also announced that it’s launching new beta testing capabilities that will allow app makers to run tests on their apps before making the changes live on the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C7YpMO"&gt;The independent developer kit will allow developers to tinker with and customize their Roku experience for personal use, such as by developing games that work with the Roku remote or connecting their Roku devices to their smart home gadgets. Roku says these changes are about aligning its platform with industry-standard approaches and development tools used by other companies. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RP1lpsv3vNmdHBngsPTqbnfV7pA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22983927/Screen_Shot_2021_11_03_at_1.42.02_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: The Verge/Roku&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A warning sign shown to users when they add a non-certified channel on Roku.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="UmIj8l"&gt;But with these changes, Roku has opted to pull “non-certified channels” that were previously used by developers for testing. These channels aren’t available in the Roku channel store because, as the company told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; last week, they are, in “most cases,” used for testing channels ahead of their launch on Roku. In a statement, a spokesperson said this week that because of its recently announced changes, these non-certified channels “are no longer necessary.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nLCmoj"&gt;It’s not clear how many non-certified channels will be removed as a result of the change, and the company declined to comment when asked by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; last week. But it’s expected to impact several adult entertainment apps that could be added to Roku &lt;a href="https://www.dailydot.com/nsfw/how-to-install-adult-time/"&gt;with unique codes&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Protocol&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.protocol.com/workplace/intel-wont-mandate-vaccines"&gt;reported this week&lt;/a&gt; that beyond Pornhub, the change is expected to impact other private channels like Adult Time and Wicked, among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CqEIob"&gt;Users who attempt to sideload channels this way are shown warning messages that the platform “does not test or review non-certified channels” and that some content may be “offensive or inappropriate for some audiences.” Additionally, Roku warns, these channels may be removed at any time, and a user’s account may be blocked from adding other non-certified channels if it determines that the channel in question contains illegal content or otherwise violates its terms. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22762236/pornhub-roku-private-channels-march-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22762236/pornhub-roku-private-channels-march-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T17:50:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T17:50:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>Alexa’s October updates let your music follow you around the house</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eBwvUEqhaYPfjg_6M-CxUdqhfLI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70088428/dseifert_201020_4247_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4csScd"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/b/?node=23657445011"&gt;Alexa’s October update&lt;/a&gt; introduces a number of new helpful commands that let you start listening to audio in one room and continue listening on an Echo device in another. There are a few different commands for this, and the ones you use will depend on your situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O1lSJh"&gt;The first command lets you move audio between groups, also known as the smart speakers that you’ve assigned to specific locations throughout your home. Simply say, “Alexa, move my music to [desired group],” and you can transfer your podcast, radio show, or music to the room that you plan on spending time in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OYVvJs"&gt;You can also continue listening to audio when you walk out the door — keep in mind that you’ll need a pair of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22432633/amazon-echo-buds-2021-review-features-specs-price"&gt;Echo Buds&lt;/a&gt; in order for this to work. Once your Echo Buds are connected to your phone, say, “Alexa move my music here,” and the audio will continue playing on your earbuds when you walk out the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5u6OiM"&gt;There’s another way to have your audio follow you throughout your house, but you’ll have to pause your music to do so. Just say “Alexa, pause” to the Echo device playing audio, and then say “Alexa, resume music here” to the Echo device you want to use. You can use the same commands when you want to resume your music in your car as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4vqUh5"&gt;This is a major improvement, considering that &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/amazonecho/comments/j03gzj/anyone_ever_managed_to_get_music_thats_playing_in/"&gt;users have asked&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.amazonforum.com/s/question/0D54P00006zSvfz/continue-or-move-music-to-another-device"&gt;Amazon to add a&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.amazonforum.com/s/question/0D54P00006zSoh6/pause-play-in-one-room-resume-in-another"&gt;feature that lets audio follow&lt;/a&gt; them throughout the house for years. It looks like Amazon is taking feedback into account, as these commands should finally provide a way to get seamless audio playback throughout your entire home.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22762103/alexa-october-updates-music-follow-around-house"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22762103/alexa-october-updates-music-follow-around-house</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T17:37:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T17:37:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s reportedly bidding to be a military cloud provider</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/twoFJe0CSEQLJKUfP1x-3US3m6M=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70088386/acastro_180508_1777_google_IO_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZzoCzY"&gt;Google is reportedly “aggressively” working on winning a contract with the Pentagon, even though some of its previous Department of Defense work &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/4/17199818/google-pentagon-project-maven-pull-out-letter-ceo-sundar-pichai"&gt;sparked major backlash from employees&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/11/03/technology/google-pentagon-artificial-intelligence.html"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. According to the report, Google’s Cloud division has reassigned engineers to work on a proposal for Google to contribute to the Joint Warfighting Cloud Capability program, which &lt;a href="https://www.defense.gov/News/Releases/Release/Article/2682992/future-of-the-joint-enterprise-defense-infrastructure-cloud-contract/"&gt;the DoD describes&lt;/a&gt; as an attempt to “achieve dominance in both traditional and non-traditional warfighting domains.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SSXPpN"&gt;The contract Google is reportedly looking into is one that will open to multiple companies to submit proposals and do work for, and the DoD estimates it could be a multi-billion dollar project. In a &lt;a href="https://sam.gov/opp/54ce941a25a14932809b5d83ac52a09a/view"&gt;document describing what cloud providers will be expected to do&lt;/a&gt;, the DoD says that anyone hoping to win a contract will have to “enable access to crucial warfighting data” with a variety of classification levels (including Secret and Top Secret info). Additionally, the program requires that applicants be able to “provide advanced data analytics services that securely enable data-driven and timely decision-making at the tactical level.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="K0aGyR"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Googles AI ethics guidelines prevent it from working on AI-powered weapons&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8Ew7XM"&gt;Google says it has &lt;a href="https://ai.google/principles/"&gt;rules on how it can use AI with regards to the military&lt;/a&gt;, which it set after employee backlash. In 2018, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/6/17086276/google-ai-military-drone-analysis-pentagon-project-maven-tensorfow"&gt;reports came out that&lt;/a&gt; Google was developing AI tech to analyze video captured by military drones as a part of the Pentagon’s Project Maven initiative. Thousands of employees &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/1/17418406/google-maven-drone-imagery-ai-contract-expire"&gt;signed a letter to CEO Sundar Pichai&lt;/a&gt; saying that Google shouldn’t be involved in war and that the work put the company’s reputation at risk and went against its stated values. Eventually, the company gave in and said it would stop working on the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G1EeDt"&gt;After Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/1/17418406/google-maven-drone-imagery-ai-contract-expire"&gt;told employees&lt;/a&gt; it would let its Project Maven contract expire, it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/7/17439310/google-ai-ethics-principles-warfare-weapons-military-project-maven"&gt;announced its AI ethics principles&lt;/a&gt;, promising that it wouldn’t work on AI-powered weapons or AI surveillance projects that were likely to draw ire from human rights or privacy advocates. The company did, however, say it would continue working with the military “in many other areas.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lcSyZR"&gt;At the time, Google said any Pentagon work it pursued would have to fit within those principles. At this point, according to the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;, it’s unclear whether what the DoD wants would be allowed under those guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="YTZ5CE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Google Cloud is still used by parts of the US military&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Y2oVEW"&gt;The company has continued to do work with the military since its pledge, with some projects involving AI. As the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; reports, &lt;a href="https://www.googlecloudpresscorner.com/2020-08-27-Google-Cloud-and-STS-to-Automate-U-S-Navy-Maintenance-Inspections-Using-AI-and-ML-Technology"&gt;Google announced&lt;/a&gt; in August that its Cloud services would be used by a contractor to analyze footage from inspection drones to determine when Navy ships needed maintenance. The Air Force is &lt;a href="https://www.googlecloudpresscorner.com/2021-07-16-U-S-Air-Force-Rapid-Sustainment-Office-Partners-with-Google-Cloud-to-Solve-Its-Toughest-Sustainment-Challenges"&gt;also looking to use Google Cloud&lt;/a&gt; to help manage airplane maintenance. In a statement emailed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, a Google spokesperson said that the company is “firmly committed to serving [its] public sector customers, including the DoD.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kkcABv"&gt;Obviously, military-related work isn’t completely off the table for Google, but given its history, it’s likely employees pay extra-close attention when the company is looking to work with the Pentagon. Google employees’ responses to Project Maven helped kick off organization within the company — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/4/22212347/google-employees-contractors-announce-union-cwa-alphabet"&gt;union organizers cited it&lt;/a&gt; as one of the collective actions that inspired unionization. The union has &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AlphabetWorkers/status/1455997325315231744?s=20"&gt;responded to the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;’ story&lt;/a&gt; about the current work on the DoD bid on Twitter, pledging that workers will fight the contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0xY3Dt"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Our working conditions include our ethical concerns. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Workers should have full transparency on the real world impacts of our labor AND our labor should not be used to perpetuate violence at home or abroad. &lt;a href="https://t.co/VD1KmjOxwL"&gt;https://t.co/VD1KmjOxwL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Alphabet Workers Union (AWU-CWA) #Strikesgiving (@AlphabetWorkers) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AlphabetWorkers/status/1455997325315231744?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 3, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761961/google-military-cloud-services-bid-joint-warfighting-project-maven"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761961/google-military-cloud-services-bid-joint-warfighting-project-maven</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T16:20:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T16:20:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Boeing gets green light for satellite internet constellation</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1k4sE2hma2WRBuWv-g6paCjPtTc=/88x0:1675x1058/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70088003/69486_boeingbuilding_987313.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Y1svZF"&gt;The Federal Communications Commission has &lt;a href="https://www.fcc.gov/document/fcc-authorizes-boeing-broadband-satellite-constellation"&gt;authorized&lt;/a&gt; a satellite internet project from Boeing first proposed in 2017. Boeing can now move forward with building, launching, and operating its own broadband internet network from space, joining its main aerospace competitor SpaceX. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FN580p"&gt;Boeing’s plan involves placing 132 satellites into low Earth orbit at an altitude of 1,056 kilometers (about 656 miles). Another 15 will be launched to “non geostationary orbit” at an altitude between 27,355 and 44,221 km (16,998 to 27,478 miles). The company says it wants to use the satellites to offer “broadband internet and communications services to residential consumers, government and business users in the United States, Puerto Rico and the US Virgin Islands” while the network gets built out, and on a global basis once it’s complete. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qpqhOK"&gt;All 147 satellites would broadcast in the V-band, a higher-frequency slice of the wireless spectrum than the Ka and Ku bands used by SpaceX’s Starlink network or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/1/22752469/amazon-project-kuiper-prototype-satellite-fcc-2022-abl-space-systems"&gt;Amazon’s yet-to-be-deployed Project Kuiper&lt;/a&gt; satellites. Using V-band could allow for faster data transfer rates but runs a greater risk of interference because the higher frequencies have more trouble penetrating solid objects. (SpaceX has plans to use the V-band in some future satellites, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/26/22350643/oneweb-spacex-racing-broadband-internet-arctic-military"&gt;so does OneWeb&lt;/a&gt;. The Ka and Ku bands are also used by satellites that provide in-flight internet on commercial airlines.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="rOLlmd"&gt;&lt;q&gt;SpaceX had told the FCC it was concerned Boeing’s network would crowd low Earth orbit&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pI4L0J"&gt;SpaceX has previously expressed concern that Boeing’s proposal to launch into already-crowded low orbits could increase the risk of a collision with other satellites. In 2019, SpaceX said to the FCC that it believed Boeing’s network would create a “clear danger of harmful interference,” &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/media-telecom/us-telecom-regulator-circulates-boeing-satellite-plan-approval-2021-10-08/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. SpaceX’s Starlink satellites orbit the Earth at an altitude of around 550 km (roughly 342 miles), which is around where OneWeb’s internet satellite constellation can be found (and where Amazon’s satellites will go once they launch). SpaceX and OneWeb narrowly avoided a collision &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22374262/oneweb-spacex-satellites-dodged-potential-collision-orbit-space-force"&gt;earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OBXVpb"&gt;Boeing now has six years to launch half of its satellite constellation and nine years to deploy the entire network. The company had asked the FCC to loosen those requirements — it wanted to only commit to launching five satellites in the first six years, and asked for a 12-year window to launch the entire constellation — but the commission denied that request, &lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22983622/FCC_21_115A1.pdf"&gt;according to the order published Wednesday&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CA09rt"&gt;By comparison, SpaceX and Amazon have far grander plans for their networks, with each consisting of thousands of satellites. Boeing is a major satellite manufacturer, and so it spent the years before and after its initial 2017 proposal selling to early space-based internet providers as the market matured. But providers are now expected to collectively &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/52-33-billion-space-based-broadband-internet-markets-2031--301405932.html"&gt;generate more than $50 billion by 2031&lt;/a&gt;, which could explain why Boeing bothered slogging through four years of the approval process. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761963/boeing-satellite-internet-network-constellation-spacex-amazon"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761963/boeing-satellite-internet-network-constellation-spacex-amazon</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T16:13:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T16:13:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to create a signature for PDF documents on an iPhone</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MZkS02gRzr7f1BK84MZY4HSji1w=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70087981/akrales_210917_4760_0361.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3Stupd"&gt;More and more official papers are being turned into PDF documents, and you may be asked to sign one electronically while you’re away from your computer (here, by the way, is how to sign a PDF document using a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22323097/pdf-signature-windows-pc-adobe-how-to"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt; or a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22323097/pdf-signature-windows-pc-adobe-how-to"&gt;PC&lt;/a&gt;). If you’re using an iPhone, it’s actually not all that difficult; you can create a signature and reuse it by using the iPhone’s built-in Markup tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZRNifU"&gt;Here’s what to do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="lMxrqY"&gt;Open the PDF document in Markup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="VujaGy"&gt;Tap the plus sign at the bottom right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wiXtpr"&gt;Tap on the Signature button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0EwA9i"&gt;If you haven’t created any signatures yet, tap on the label at the top titled “New Signature.” (If you don’t see “New Signature,” tap the plus sign in the upper left corner.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="In Markup, tap on the plus and then the Signature button." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MRS3AJXiLlTB2Xs-qRejNFZFz4A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22983485/IMG_AA00365EEDAD_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;In Markup, tap on the plus and then the Signature button.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can label your saved signature." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VYv-trmKLqK75dLdB4Ky3LZ8KTM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22983494/IMG_68BC3F57889A_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can label your saved signature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="5WufAk"&gt;You’ll be given the option of labeling your new signature with your full name, family name, nickname, etc. Or you can choose not to have a label at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nu2PJP"&gt;Once you’ve chosen your label, you can then sign your name at the bottom of the screen. There is a “Clear” button if you decide you need to try more than once to get it right. Tap “Done” at the top right corner when you’re ready.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="MjSXxO"&gt;Your signature will then appear in a box on your document. You can move it and / or resize it until you’re happy with how it looks on the document. When you’re ready, tap anywhere outside the box. You can then use Markup for any other edits. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Draw your signature; tap “Clear” if its not to your liking." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/t2afLYe2GLP3hrMm_21MgAQ7RKY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22983496/IMG_1685F699DBDE_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Draw your signature; tap “Clear” if its not to your liking.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Move the completed signature to where you want it." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yyYFi8hvsHWs1juWmzlhtkJ_ngc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22983500/IMG_4E10B05B0701_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Move the completed signature to where you want it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="qkO4Dd"&gt;When you’re ready, tap “Done” in the upper left corner and save the file.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="FYj2EX"&gt;The next time you open a PDF in Markup on your phone, tap on the Signature button, and the signature (or signatures) that you saved will be there. Just tap on it, and it will be dropped into your document. You can always select “Add or Remove Signature” if you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Next time you need to sign something, your signature will be waiting." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Dj75IynoxNJmqhfMkAkBiJW5-lo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22983503/IMG_C343BCA08DEF_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Next time you need to sign something, your signature will be waiting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Get rid of an old signature by tapping “Add or Remove Signature.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Aq-aYbwWLW7t8CG3s0Mvd9XfuY4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22983511/IMG_75635B9A7071_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get rid of an old signature by tapping “Add or Remove Signature.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="SKMEbj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to create a signature for PDF documents on a PC ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22323097/pdf-signature-windows-pc-adobe-how-to"},{"title":"How to create a signature for PDF documents on a Mac","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22321383/signature-pdf-mac-pdf-how-to-preview"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="XQL6Tp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jqnxUd"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XbJQcJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22761773/iphone-apple-pdf-signature-markup-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22761773/iphone-apple-pdf-signature-markup-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T15:42:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T15:42:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>‘Sideloading is a cyber criminal’s best friend,’ according to Apple’s software chief</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wVyvU_-XAFY6dXHoDdqHGFmPB2Q=/64x0:706x428/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70087804/Screen_Shot_2021_11_03_at_9.59.39_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DdARwO"&gt;“Sideloading is a cyber criminal’s best friend and requiring that on iPhone would be a gold rush for the malware industry,” according to Apple senior vice president Craig Federighi, who delivered a dramatic speech at &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iwstKnhWs6k"&gt;Web Summit 2021&lt;/a&gt; declaiming the security risks if Apple were required to let users sideload apps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M23152"&gt;Federighi, who oversees Apple’s iOS and macOS software divisions, was specifically protesting the &lt;a href="https://ec.europa.eu/info/strategy/priorities-2019-2024/europe-fit-digital-age/digital-markets-act-ensuring-fair-and-open-digital-markets_en"&gt;European Commission’s proposed Digital Markets Act&lt;/a&gt;, which, if passed, would require Apple to let users install apps outside of the iOS App Store. According to Federighi, the lack of sideloading is what separates Apple’s relatively low rate of malware on iOS from the “5 million Android attacks per month,” and that if Apple were forced to let users install their own apps, “the floodgates are open for malware.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WFEnxF"&gt;Federighi also argues against a popular proposed solution of letting users decide for themselves whether to take the risk of sideloading apps. The problem is that “criminals are clever, and they’re really good at hiding in plain sight,” and that even informed users might get caught by misleading websites, or even get stuck with fake app stores installed on their phones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="jUn5TT"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple is still very much against sideloading&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="llCjh0"&gt;And even if &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;, a tech-savvy smartphone expert, might not be fooled, Federighi plays on the heartstrings and asks the audience to think of the children or parents who might be fooled. “The fact that anyone can be harmed by malware isn’t something that we should stand for,” Federighi concludes, despite the fact that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/8/22272849/apple-app-store-scams-ios-fraud-reviews-ratings-flicktype"&gt;Apple still routinely deals&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/3/22654197/apple-app-store-editorial-scams-refunds"&gt;with multimillion-dollar scams&lt;/a&gt; that the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22705405/apple-report-a-problem-button-app-store-scams"&gt;only just added the ability to report&lt;/a&gt; in September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j7BA5H"&gt;Federighi’s picture of doom doesn’t just stop there, though: he also raises the concern that if Apple were to allow sideloading, “some social networking apps will probably try to avoid the pesky privacy protections of the App Store and only make their apps available via sideloading.” According to Federighi, Apple’s privacy requirements in the App Store go beyond those of the letter of the law, and social media companies looking to escape those could force customers to choose between “losing touch with your friends online, or taking on the risks of sideloading.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SmjV5j"&gt;“Sideloading undermines security and puts people’s data at risk,” according to Federighi, and that if customers and regulators want the option to sideload apps, the alternative of Android should be enough to meet that without requiring it for iPhones. But all the concerns on iOS are curious, given the other half of his job description: leading the macOS software team, where apps can be freely installed outside of Apple’s app store (and have been for decades) without suffering from apocalyptic malware attacks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="azTcgJ"&gt;If Apple wanted, it could enable iOS sideloading in a similar manner and require something like the Gatekeeper system on macOS, which allows for Apple to check signed developer IDs to confirm the software is genuine. It’s an argument that Judge Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22667256/apple-vs-epic-trail-judge-craig-federighi-macos-security-arguments-iphone-ios-response"&gt;noted as well during the Apple / Epic trial&lt;/a&gt;, commenting that Federighi may be “stretching the truth” on Mac malware concerns and that Apple could likely make a similar system work on iOS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ElfKnD"&gt;And most notably, Federighi’s speech completely ignores the fact that by requiring all apps to be installed through the App Store, it forces all app commerce to flow through the App Store, too — where Apple collects its highly contested 30 percent cut, to the tune of billions of dollars every year. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761724/apple-craig-federighi-ios-sideloading-web-summit-2021-european-commission-digital-markets-act"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761724/apple-craig-federighi-ios-sideloading-web-summit-2021-european-commission-digital-markets-act</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T15:40:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T15:40:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix adds a trio of movies from Squid Game director</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qdTXKdKdkAzIo3m-Ii2ccgt0uAM=/480x0:3360x1920/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70087786/SquidGame_Season1_Episode1_00_44_44_16.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gxxjc9"&gt;Hwang Dong-hyuk is known for more than just the Netflix hit Squid Game, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723452/netflix-squid-game-biggest-ever-show-at-launch"&gt;garnered 111 million viewers&lt;/a&gt; in its first 17 days on the service. He previously directed several critically acclaimed South Korean films, three of which Netflix is adding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MTcTXN"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Before bringing the visually astounding and socially relevant Squid Game to life, Hwang Dong-hyuk directed several acclaimed South Korean feature films — and now, three of those movies are available on Netflix in The US! &lt;a href="https://t.co/FV0nUQV91D"&gt;pic.twitter.com/FV0nUQV91D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Netflix (@netflix) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/netflix/status/1455929209826656259?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 3, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PLBnDf"&gt;Based on real events, Dong-hyuk’s &lt;em&gt;Silenced &lt;/em&gt;centers around a teacher who just started working at a school for the hearing impaired. When he discovers that its faculty members have been abusing the students, he works to bring the truth to light, only to realize the surrounding community is willing to cover it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nzjCmC"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k3BUIreDAeY?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="R39UwF"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Miss Granny&lt;/em&gt; is a lot more lighthearted when compared to &lt;em&gt;Squid Gam&lt;/em&gt;e&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Silenced&lt;/em&gt;, following a 74-year-old woman who escapes her future of confinement at a retirement home in an unusual way. After wandering into a strange photo studio and getting her picture taken, she walks out as a 20-year-old woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="UJtY0R"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gdhX0tM0mOg?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wCIBZL"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Fortress&lt;/em&gt; is the most recent of the three, coming out in 2017. It transports you all the way back to 17th century Korea during the Qing invasion of Joseon, when King Injo and his court are forced to retreat into a fortress known as Namhansanseong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="F51Y7H"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EYsv-rSW3n0?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UF1ZXS"&gt;All three of these films are available on Netflix for viewers in the US. While they may not reach the same &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/1/22704313/sk-broadband-netflix-suing-for-payment-squid-game"&gt;level of popularity that &lt;em&gt;Squid Game&lt;/em&gt; has&lt;/a&gt;, they may help hold us over while we wait for season two.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761602/netflix-squid-game-director-movies"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761602/netflix-squid-game-director-movies</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T15:18:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T15:18:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s colorful HomePod Minis are a fun addition to your smart home decor</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5wy-pGeNtFTeKSbgtMx2DlUJupc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70087598/jtuohy_211102_4860_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s HomePod Mini now comes in three new color options.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Eaq9PQ"&gt;Three colorful HomePod Minis were announced last month and went on sale this week, adding yellow, orange, and blue options to our smart speaker home decor selections. I got to try out the trio of bright speakers, and have to say I quite like adding a pop of color to my smart home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yq3o9S"&gt;Apple is a bit behind the ball here; both Google and Amazon have had color choices for their smart speakers for a while now. The Nest Minis come in coral and light blue colors, and Amazon’s Echo speakers have blue, tiger orange, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22688035/billie-eilish-echo-studio-price-release-date-preorder"&gt;Billie Eilish-beige&lt;/a&gt; options. But as usual, Apple has gone the extra mile with its design here, creating something quite genuinely delightful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0A7k9z"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10844191"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PatSkt"&gt;Each $99 HomePod Mini comes with a matching colored box and a different shimmering, shimmying Mini logo, presumably mimicking the sounds your HomePod will deliver courtesy of that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734185/new-apple-music-voice-plan-price-features-app"&gt;Apple Music Voice subscription&lt;/a&gt; you’re planning to use it with (right?). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VDj2ub"&gt;The braided USB-C power cable (which still can’t be removed) is color-coordinated with the speaker and is a pastel version of the main event. The volume up and down buttons on the white control plate perfectly match the Mini’s color. Also — and this is very Apple — when you set up the Mini using your iPhone, the graphic that pops up matches the color of the Mini you’re pairing (actually useful when you are setting up three different colors at once).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/u9IiJJ3GuT9P9EWnmpUzMpvklfE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22982938/jtuohy_211102_4860_0030.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Each pod comes with matching control buttons and a color-coordinated cord.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="UQlyvd"&gt;Speaking of those colors, they are a lot more impressive in person. When they were first announced at &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22723141/apple-homepod-mini-new-colors-price-release-date-features"&gt;Apple’s fall hardware event&lt;/a&gt;, my initial thought was they were a bit underwhelming. Orange and yellow aren’t top of mind when it comes to interior design color choices, although they are great for the odd “pop” of color. And the blue looked so dark as to not be that dissimilar to the existing dark grey option. Also, where were the green and red, Apple?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/G0DJJsvzAD8e8HxGqd7Jz5S6H4o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22982935/jtuohy_211102_4860_0019.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;I was able to color coordinate my Samsung Frame TV with the new HomePod Minis.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XnnwlC"&gt;Once I got my hands on the speakers, though, and tried them out in a few different situations around the house, I found I had plenty of spots where they could fit right in. Although, admittedly, it was primarily in my children’s rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iJ7zkr"&gt;The yellow is very bright, definitely lemon on the color wheel, and the orange has a much more blood orange, reddish hue — closer to coral than the fruit Florida is famous for. However, next to a coral-colored Nest Mini, it pops a bit more and there is no hint of pink. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/15q4S8AN58suscRPYdvrOSbmvoE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22982926/jtuohy_211102_4860_0008_cropped.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6l95h9MpukTcMRY9-UgFOqiIG74=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22982930/jtuohy_211102_4860_0010_cropped.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vvkDsR_QJ_Bd_NjyVoX4ORrWdxc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22982928/jtuohy_211102_4860_0009_cropped.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/j09WB9IEkMSbLvpBZWkIAnxX2pQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22982933/jtuohy_211102_4860_0014.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Orange, yellow, blue, and the threesome.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YlfJU2"&gt;The blue is my favorite (likely because I just redid my kitchen and chose dark blue cabinets, so it is the perfect fit there). It’s a deeply rich, almost royal blue and really pretty. The blue also doesn’t show as much shadow through the mesh, something that gives the brighter colors a bit of a muddy look when you get up close. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ni8BjgsqbkTC-EyualirjXAqp7M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22982941/jtuohy_211102_4860_0038.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The blue HomePod Mini is a perfect match in my kitchen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gKIuIj"&gt;One advantage of these colors, and the dark grey option, over the white Mini, is they are less likely to start greying as they collect dust and dirt, something that’s been noticeable on the white version in my testing. Clearly, we need a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733198/apple-polishing-cloth-clean-devices"&gt;special Apple cleaning cloth&lt;/a&gt; for our HomePods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="utt0Bb"&gt;The new HomePod Minis are identical in function to the existing models. They work with Siri, can use your iPhone to make calls and send messages, act as a hub for your HomeKit home, and set alarms and timers. We will be testing them out shortly though, to explore some of the features added since &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21561589/apple-homepod-mini-review"&gt;our first review&lt;/a&gt;. They ship with software version 15.0, so you will need to upgrade to 15.1.1 out of the box to take advantage of new features such as spatial audio and lossless music with Apple Music. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nzkM1X"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tViKbx"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Jennifer Tuohy / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22761626/apple-homepod-mini-hands-on"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22761626/apple-homepod-mini-hands-on</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T15:04:27-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T15:04:27-04:00</updated>
    <title>Googler who helped lead 2018 walkout is joining the FTC </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yn4D1okjhjETHWi5LmoGt9C6e-4=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70081183/acastro_180320_1777_cambridge_analytica_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3OFSSD"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update November 3rd, 3:04PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Meredith Whittaker &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mer__edith/status/1455970454963998723"&gt;&lt;em&gt;confirmed Wednesday&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; that she will be joining the Federal Trade Commission as a senior advisor on AI. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JC8Za1"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Thrilled to confirm the rumors: I will be joining &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FTC?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@FTC&lt;/a&gt; as a Senior Advisor on AI. I'm humbled and beyond excited to get to work with + learn from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/linakhanFTC?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@linakhanFTC&lt;/a&gt; and her brilliant team.&lt;/p&gt;— Meredith Whittaker (@mer__edith) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mer__edith/status/1455970454963998723?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 3, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="S4U8DF"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our original story about a report that she would be joining the agency follows below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="IOVTmD"&gt;
&lt;p id="mlyYCy"&gt;Former Google employee Meredith Whittaker could soon be working at the Federal Trade Commission as an AI policy advisor, &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/former-google-activist-whittaker-expected-to-join-ftc-as-ai-adviser"&gt;according to a report by &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Whittaker may be best known for helping to organize a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/2/18057716/google-walkout-20-thousand-employees-ceo-sundar-pichai-meeting"&gt;2018 walkout at Google&lt;/a&gt;, where 20,000 employees protested against how the company handled alleged sexual harassment, and for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/16/20695964/google-protest-leader-meredith-whittaker-leaves-company"&gt;leaving Google afterward&lt;/a&gt;, claiming that it had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/23/18512413/google-employees-walkout-organizers-retaliation-punishment"&gt;retaliated against her and other organizers&lt;/a&gt;. Now, the FTC seems to be in the process of hiring her to help shape regulations around AI and Big Tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nqcmYK"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;, Whittaker hasn’t been officially appointed yet, as steps like running a background check aren’t complete. If she is hired, though, she’ll bring a good deal of experience — she worked at Google &lt;a href="https://googlewalkout.medium.com/onward-another-googlewalkout-goodbye-b733fa134a7d"&gt;from 2006 to 2019&lt;/a&gt; and has done work around AI ethics since leaving the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="RFaEuu"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Whittaker accused Google of only caring about the appearance of ethics debate&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xQp8u1"&gt;Besides helping with the walkout, Whittaker also advocated for Google to stop building AI for the military and spoke out against its ethics reviews, saying that it only gave the “appearance of an inclusive debate, rather than seriously contending with the problems in the company.” Upon leaving the company, she said that it was “clear” that it wasn’t a place where she could work toward tech accountability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0wsa4S"&gt;Whittaker has also dealt with difficulties in the public sphere — she worked on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/15/18309437/new-york-city-accountability-task-force-law-algorithm-transparency-automation"&gt;New York City’s algorithm task force&lt;/a&gt;, which was designed to make sure that the city’s automated systems were equitable and had appropriate oversight and transparency. When NYC ended up releasing the report, though, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/20/20974379/nyc-algorithm-task-force-report-de-blasio"&gt;she called the effort “a waste,”&lt;/a&gt; echoing concerns raised by other members that dissenting opinions weren’t taken seriously or included. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="XoNm1o"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The FTC has struggled to regulate Big Tech but now appears to be gearing up for a fight&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nKc6uW"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt; points out, though, there are signs that the FTC could be a more hospitable place for her ideas if she actually ends up working there. The regulator’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/15/22527709/lina-khan-ftc-commissioner-competition-facebook-amazon-google-apple"&gt;new chair, Lina Khan&lt;/a&gt;, has said she wants to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22690176/ftc-chair-lina-khan-focus-antitrust-consumer-amazon"&gt;focus attention on tech giants and antitrust&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/30/22557456/amazon-lina-khan-recusal-petition-federal-trade-commission-antitrust"&gt;Amazon has even requested&lt;/a&gt; that she not be involved in cases involving the company because of her past statements about breaking it up. The current administration seems serious about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671880/biden-alvaro-bedoya-privacy-ftc-commissioner-facial-recognition"&gt;nominating experts to work at the agency&lt;/a&gt;, which has struggled to regulate Big Tech in the past few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d8O3CH"&gt;If the FTC is looking to bring on industry veterans like Whittaker, it could be a further sign that the agency is getting serious about regulating Big Tech. It could help give some say to people who have the technical knowledge and firsthand experience working at companies like Google, Amazon, Apple, or Meta, even if efforts to change things from within were largely ignored.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759776/google-meredith-whittaker-ftc-nomination-ai-ethics-regulation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759776/google-meredith-whittaker-ftc-nomination-ai-ethics-regulation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T14:36:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T14:36:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>Starlink delays orders by years for unlucky customers who played with the site’s digital map</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qcmr106brLmwJoWqt3fQfr9vhgA=/0x85:2040x1445/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70087362/npatel_20210512_4552_0048.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Nilay Patel / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HOVnm4"&gt;It was an exciting moment when &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22435030/starlink-satellite-internet-spacex-review"&gt;Starlink&lt;/a&gt; rolled out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274385/musk-spacex-starlink-deposit-price-satellite-internet"&gt;preorders for its satellite internet service&lt;/a&gt; in February since it can potentially provide faster speed and better service to those in rural areas or with spotty internet access. But a single feature on the Starlink site is causing preorders to be delayed by years and there appears to be no fix in sight, an issue first spotted by &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2021/11/starlink-nightmare-moving-service-location-a-few-feet-delays-orders-until-2023/?utm_brand=arstechnica"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="urIvIG"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“If you don’t already have service and move your address you go straight to the back of the line”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6RreHm"&gt;According to the report, some users on the &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Starlink/"&gt;r/Starlink&lt;/a&gt; subreddit moved their service area by just a few feet using the digital map tool on the site and wound up having their preorder dates moved from late 2021 to as far as 2023. &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Starlink/comments/qiiprb/comment/hijupd9/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3"&gt;One user&lt;/a&gt; wrote, “I moved it from the end of my driveway to my house this morning and just looked back and it had changed to 2022-2023.” In the same conversation, &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Starlink/comments/qiiprb/comment/hikyhmy/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3"&gt;another noted&lt;/a&gt;, “I moved the location from my barn to my house which is literally 13 feet in real-time and now I'm mid to late 2022.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m5D6JN"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/em&gt; notes, the map tool was always on the site, but Starlink recently made some changes to the site’s layout and also removed any mention of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/18/22681185/spacex-ceo-elon-musk-starlink-internet-service-leaving-beta-october"&gt;Starlink being in beta&lt;/a&gt;. The update seemed to have pushed the map tool to a more prominent location and also gave users a notification to check their location for “accuracy.” Naturally, anyone excitedly checking the status of their preorder would feel inclined to change their service location if they noticed an error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0So8qk"&gt;Apparently, this type of preorder delay with Starlink isn’t a new issue either — it’s just been become more common due to the new map location. Another &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Starlink/comments/qhhcln/comment/hicr9id/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3"&gt;Reddit user&lt;/a&gt; says “people here have been warning others about it for nearly a year now. If you don’t already have service and move your address you go straight to the back of the line.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jmW7QC"&gt;Elon Musk’s vision for Starlink is a grand one, and yet, it’s small issues like these that undermine the service’s potential. Customer service issues aren’t a new thing among Musk-owned brands — &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/03/11/teslas-biggest-problem-is-customer-service-new-bernstein-survey.html"&gt;Tesla is notorious for having poor customer service&lt;/a&gt;, and Starlink isn’t following far behind. In September, frustrated &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/spacex-starlink-customers-angry-service-contact-order-update-internet-2021-9"&gt;Starlink customers said that they were unable to reach the company&lt;/a&gt; to check the status of their orders months after their purchase. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OhCihv"&gt;Customers who’ve fallen victim to the temptation of moving their service area have also been contacting Starlink via email — but to no avail. Musk is rushing to expand space exploration and define an era of electric vehicles, but some of his customers here on Earth would just like a response to their emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b1ejDD"&gt;We reached out to SpaceX about the situation but didn’t immediately hear back.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22760268/starlink-delay-order-location-map-satellite-internet"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22760268/starlink-delay-order-location-map-satellite-internet</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
