<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-07-02T05:54:18-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-02T05:54:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-02T05:54:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft warns of Windows ‘PrintNightmare’ vulnerability that’s being actively exploited</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CO7Zc7_W1iKZZqRh9BPeVcriFg4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69533180/acastro_170629_1777_0008_v2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2lvTar"&gt;Microsoft is warning Windows users about an unpatched critical flaw in the Windows Print Spooler service. The vulnerability, dubbed PrintNightmare, was uncovered earlier this week after security researchers accidentally published a proof-of-concept (PoC) exploit. While Microsoft hasn’t rated the vulnerability, it allows attackers to remotely execute code with system-level privileges, which is as critical and problematic as you can get in Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K3OKmz"&gt;Researchers at Sangfor &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/edwardzpeng/status/1409810304091889669"&gt;published the PoC&lt;/a&gt;, in what appears to have been a mistake, or a miscommunication between the researchers and Microsoft. The test code was quickly deleted, but not before it had already been forked on GitHub. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dRz3ob"&gt;Sangfor researchers had been &lt;a href="https://www.sangfor.com/en/info-center/blog-center/cyber-security/two-sangfor-security-research-results-selected-at-black-hat-usa-2021"&gt;planning to detail&lt;/a&gt; multiple 0-day vulnerabilities in the Windows Print Spooler service at the annual Black Hat security conference later this month. It appears the researchers thought Microsoft had patched this particular vulnerability, after the company published patches for a separate Windows Print Spooler flaw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="SpSiMx"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The vulnerability is being actively exploited&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HvPmGH"&gt;It has taken Microsoft a couple of days to finally issue an alert about the 0-day, and &lt;a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/microsoft-shares-mitigations-for-windows-printnightmare-zero-day-bug/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bleepingcomputer &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; that the company is even warning customers that it’s being actively exploited. The vulnerability allows attackers to use remote code execution, so bad actors could potentially install programs, modify data, and create new accounts with full admin rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nw7yI0"&gt;&lt;a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2021-34527"&gt;Microsoft admits&lt;/a&gt; “the code that contains the vulnerability is in all versions of Windows,” but it’s not clear if it’s exploitable beyond server versions of Windows. The Print Spooler service runs by default on Windows, including on client versions of the OS, Domain Controllers, and many Windows Server instances, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ysbLaN"&gt;Microsoft is working on a patch, but until it’s available the company recommends disabling the Windows Print Spooler service (if that’s an option for businesses), or disabling inbound remote printing through Group Policy. The Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/current-activity/2021/06/30/printnightmare-critical-windows-print-spooler-vulnerability"&gt;has recommended&lt;/a&gt; that admins “disable the Windows Print Spooler service in Domain Controllers and systems that do not print.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VBW5py"&gt;Vulnerabilities in the Windows Print Spooler service have been a headache for system administrators for years. The most infamous example was the Stuxnet virus. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/4/12/2944329/stuxnet-computer-virus-planted-israeli-agent-iran"&gt;Stuxnet used&lt;/a&gt; multiple 0-day exploits, including a Windows Print Spooler flaw, to destroy several Iranian nuclear centrifuges more than a decade ago.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22560435/microsoft-printnightmare-windows-print-spooler-service-vulnerability-exploit-0-day"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22560435/microsoft-printnightmare-windows-print-spooler-service-vulnerability-exploit-0-day</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-02T05:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-02T05:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Don’t back down from Facebook fight, lawmakers tell FTC</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7P9HUakoPHYz7EXpSVfRMA7vYbo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69533142/acastro_180406_1777_facebook_Congress_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gQ2NRG"&gt;A bipartisan group of lawmakers have asked that the FTC continue its antitrust lawsuit against Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/28/22554476/ftc-facebook-instagram-antitrust-case-whatsapp-federal-court"&gt;after setbacks in court&lt;/a&gt;. Senators Amy Klobuchar (D-MN) and Mike Lee (R-UT), together with House representatives David Cicilline (D-RI) and Ken Buck (R-CO), &lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22694505/FTC_letter_7_1_21.pdf"&gt;signed a letter&lt;/a&gt; addressed to FTC Chair Lina Khan detailing why the regulatory action is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3vUVbH"&gt;“It is essential that the Commission take action to deter anticompetitive conduct by digital monopolists by ensuring that they are held liable for antitrust violations to the full extent of the law,” the lawmakers wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Rw19qf"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It is essential that the Commission take action”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iMFlXl"&gt;This letter comes just four days after Judge James E. Boasberg &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/28/22554476/ftc-facebook-instagram-antitrust-case-whatsapp-federal-court"&gt;dismissed&lt;/a&gt; the federal government’s key antitrust complaint against Facebook on Monday, as well as a complaint from 48 state attorneys general. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3DApAc"&gt;The FTC has until July 29th to refile its complaint, although it will have to offer more comprehensive evidence that Facebook does indeed wield monopoly power in social networking. In the Monday dismissal, Boasberg wrote he was unimpressed with the FTC’s attempt to classify Facebook as a monopoly, as the initial complaint only provided “the naked allegation” that the social media giant had a 60 percent market share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rib9Sm"&gt;The dismissal does offer some metrics that might be persuasive to the court, like how much users spend on Facebook apps, or an explanation of Facebook’s competition in the sector. However, each of those suggestions are caveated with how examples of how difficult these metrics can be to prove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BBnafi"&gt;In the dismissal, Boasberg also noted how difficult it was to fit Facebook’s service into the existing antitrust regulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="org1gh"&gt;“This case involves no ordinary or intuitive market,” he wrote. “Rather, PSN [Personal Social Networking] services are free to use, and the exact metes and bounds of what even constitutes a PSN service — i.e., which features of a company’s mobile app or website are included in that definition and which are excluded — are hardly crystal clear.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qqi3vk"&gt;This point hasn’t been lost on lawmakers, who have rallied around changing antitrust law to better address modern tech giants. Buck, one of the letter’s signatories, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RepKenBuck/status/1409594342860283904"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; Monday that the dismissal showed antitrust reform is urgently needed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l5PTzm"&gt;“Congress needs to provide additional tools and resources to our antitrust enforcers to go after Big Tech companies engaging in anticompetitive conduct,” he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22559549/lawmakers-tell-ftc-to-continue-facebook-antitrust-lawsuit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22559549/lawmakers-tell-ftc-to-continue-facebook-antitrust-lawsuit</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dave Gershgorn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-02T02:49:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-02T02:49:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook confirms tests of a new anti-extremism warning prompt</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="facebook stock art" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6A_w0wpZvZky7K0Hzdg-GuCDkrI=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69533067/acastro_180928_1777_facebook_hack_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TmCli8"&gt;Facebook is testing prompts that will link users to anti-extremism support and resources if the company believes the user knows someone who could be on the path to extremism, or if the user has been exposed to extremist content themselves, &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/07/01/tech/facebook-extremist-notification/index.html"&gt;according to a report by &lt;em&gt;CNN Business&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jvwrfw"&gt;In a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, a Facebook spokesperson said that the test is part of the company’s “larger work to assess ways to provide resources and support to people on Facebook who may have engaged with or were exposed to extremist content, or may know someone who is at risk.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KrKbGE"&gt;Facebook says that it’ll continue to remove extremist content that &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/communitystandards/dangerous_individuals_organizations"&gt;violates its rules&lt;/a&gt;, though the company has had issues tracking down and removing similar content, even from groups that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/12/21365278/facebook-boogaloo-tech-transparency-right-wing-extremist-platform"&gt;it’s actively tried to kick off the platform.&lt;/a&gt; Facebook has long been the subject of scrutiny from the public and lawmakers, as many say that its algorithms divide people and push them towards extreme ideologies, something &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/26/21270659/facebook-division-news-feed-algorithms"&gt;the company has itself recognized&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="fHDl5L"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A history of failing to track and remove extremist content&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zFzxlO"&gt;Facebook says that the tests go along with &lt;a href="https://counterspeech.fb.com/en/initiatives/redirect/"&gt;its Redirect Initiative&lt;/a&gt;, which “helps combat violent extremism and dangerous organizations” in several countries. According to its webpage, the program (as the name implies) redirects users to educational resources instead of further hateful content. It also says the test is part of &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2020/05/combating-hate-and-dangerous-organizations/"&gt;its response to the Christchurch Call for Action campaign&lt;/a&gt;, and the test identifies both users who may have seen extremist content, and those who have had enforcement actions taken against them by Facebook in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wEjpBf"&gt;The test links to resources intended to help someone intervene if they’re concerned about a loved one joining a violent extremist group or movement. On &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/help/139388761595380/"&gt;a Facebook support page&lt;/a&gt; titled “What can I do to prevent radicalization,” Facebook links to Life After Hate’s ExitUSA program, which Facebook says helps people find “a way out of hate and violence.” The support page also gives tips on engaging with someone who’s trying to leave a hate group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iIsyNk"&gt;Facebook, like other platforms, has had issues with extremism for a long time, and though it’s good that it’s trying to combat it, some of its efforts feel like they should’ve been implemented long ago. This is the case with many forms of bad behavior online, as many platforms are still struggling to get a hold on users &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559115/twitter-tiktok-google-facebook-protect-women-abuse"&gt;who harass women&lt;/a&gt;, or display &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22558731/twitter-trusted-friends-facets-features-pre-announce"&gt;other general toxic behavior&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22560108/facebook-anti-extremism-prompt-user-resources-content-moderation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22560108/facebook-anti-extremism-prompt-user-resources-content-moderation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T20:26:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T20:26:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nike brings hands-free entry shoes to the Olympics with the Glide FlyEase</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Nike Glide FlyEase" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AbwshNTf8ouVdJi7lHR6n7m6CtE=/0x0:2066x1377/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69532396/Nike_Medal_Stand_FlyEase_Glide_original.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Nike&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="E0Ardb"&gt;The Olympics are back on this summer in Japan — despite &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/health-coronavirus-pandemic-2020-tokyo-olympics-olympic-games-sports-dd8098040f1f965ae90d289ca35c7423"&gt;local opposition&lt;/a&gt; — and athletes will of course find themselves outfitted in the lightest, slickest gear to assist in record-breaking performances. Ahead of the games, Nike has unveiled some of the apparel the US team will wear (including &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fnews.nike.com%2Ffootwear%2Fnike-rawdacious-colorway-tokyo-official-images-release-date&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fdesign%2F2021%2F7%2F1%2F22560002%2Fnike-glide-flyease-olympics-sneakers" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;“Rawdacious” themed&lt;/a&gt; track spikes with carbon fiber plates), but you may want to keep an eye on outfits reserved for medal winners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TdY9hK"&gt;Nike is highlighting sustainability themes with pants and jackets that are made from 100 percent recycled material, and while the accompanying footwear is made partially from recycled materials, that’s not the only thing special about it. This year’s medal stand features Nike’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/7/20/9002197/nike-flyease-zipper-disabilities"&gt;FlyEase tech&lt;/a&gt;, which is made for easy entry that brings comfortable athletic shoes to people who might not be able to put on other shoes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Nike Go FlyEase" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uWPYDWASMJIx4c7RihAYwbS3OQQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22694879/c748bc50_64f5_11eb_bfed_408b02ac5810.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Nike&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Go FlyEase&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="mT7MRx"&gt;The Glide FlyEase is similar to the &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/tldr/2021/2/1/22260179/nike-go-flyease-shoes-hands-free-pricing-release-day"&gt;Go FlyEase model Nike introduced earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;. However, instead of that shoe’s “bistable hinge,” Nike said the Glide FlyEase has a flexible heel. We haven’t seen it in action, but apparently you simply step into the shoe and it snaps back into place while an elastic cord goes over the foot for a snug fit.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Nike Glide FlyEase" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sEw67iH6OWhKVAM6bAtXpcNuDO8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22694865/Nike_Medal_Stand_FlyEase_Glide_3_original.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Nike&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Glide FlyEase&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="X2YGJK"&gt;Despite &lt;a href="https://www.wired.co.uk/article/nike-go-flyease-review"&gt;glowing reviews&lt;/a&gt;, Nike has been &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/03/28/981197687/nike-accused-of-using-disability-to-hype-new-hands-free-sneaker"&gt;criticized over the Go FlyEase launch&lt;/a&gt; as limited quantity releases make it hard for the people who need the shoes to get them. Putting the Glide FlyEase on the medal stand will provide another highlight of accessible sportswear that lets people know they exist, but it can only have a larger impact if you can actually get them. Nike has said there will be more opportunities to get the $120 FlyEase Go, and tells The Verge that these Glide FlyEase shoes will be released at a later date.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/design/2021/7/1/22560002/nike-glide-flyease-olympics-sneakers"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/design/2021/7/1/22560002/nike-glide-flyease-olympics-sneakers</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T20:07:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T20:07:44-04:00</updated>
    <title>Humble Bundle will start capping charitable donations in mid-July</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1zkW0ITGSxzFl6tlAPQlUNoWLpE=/0x238:2688x2030/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69532331/Screen_Shot_2021_07_01_at_3.32.42_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tzCZCK"&gt;Humble Bundle has announced that it’s going to change how payment sliders will work in its storefront by removing the ability to donate all of what you spend to charity and setting an average minimum cut for Humble Bundle itself between 15 to 30 percent (&lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/despite-backlash-humble-bundles-donation-limit-returns-1847212248"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Kotaku&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The change goes into effect in “mid-July.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gHkheq"&gt;When you buy a bundle of games, ebooks, or software on Humble Bundle, you’re traditionally given the option to choose how much of your money goes to Humble Bundle, the creator of what you’re buying, and a charity via a slider for each. Those sliders are sticking around, but now they’ll have a bit less range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="05hhkK"&gt;The company justified the change &lt;a href="https://blog.humblebundle.com/2021/07/01/changes-coming-to-humble-bundle-sliders/"&gt;in a blog post&lt;/a&gt; announcing its plans:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="736VXQ"&gt;Why change after ten years? The PC storefront landscape has changed significantly since we first launched bundles in 2010, and we have to continue to evolve with it to stay on mission. The update will allow us to continue to offer great prices on amazing games, books and software all while supporting important charitable initiatives with every single purchase. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K2Yb4RA5rulN2_IHTK61x8_-xHE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22694718/blog_charity.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Humble Bundle&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Humble Bundle’s proposed “toggle” redesign. The new set-up still exists, with the option for making custom donations with sliders buried in a menu.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="8sUuZx"&gt;Humble Bundle first committed to &lt;a href="https://blog.humblebundle.com/2021/04/23/a-note-about-sliders-and-our-bundle-pages/"&gt;changing how payments would work in April&lt;/a&gt;, announcing it would eliminate sliders completely, cap donations to charity at 15 percent, and introduce a series of toggles “with defined splits that clearly show what amount of your purchase will support Humble, publishers, and charity.” Users were &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/humble-bundle-moves-to-limit-charitable-donations-to-15-1846751524"&gt;critical of the idea of shrinking donations&lt;/a&gt; while Humble Bundle would have been guaranteed to get a piece of every purchase, and the company ultimately &lt;a href="https://blog.humblebundle.com/2021/05/05/an-update-on-bundle-sliders/"&gt;rolled back its planned changes&lt;/a&gt; and announced it would explore other ways to improve upon payments. Thursday’s news is the company’s alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WAJIQk"&gt;Humble Bundle became well-known for its flexible pay-what-you-want bundles. The original form of sliders allowed a customer to kick more of their money towards the developer or a charity, including reducing Humble Bundle’s cut to zero in favor of the other two. Humble said going forward after its planned change, splits will vary on bundles, but it expects to take a cut somewhere between 15 to 30 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="AHioie"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Sliders don’t matter, but flexibility does&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cxZbTq"&gt;It makes sense that the cost of getting games to participate in bundles would have gone up, with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/12/22380895/epic-games-store-afford-give-away-17-5-billion-free-games"&gt;some storefront’s like the Epic Games Store&lt;/a&gt; writing checks to give away exclusive games for free, but it is disappointing that Humble Bundle has backed away somewhat from the more altruistic model it made its name on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hkrXJ2"&gt;As someone who’s used Humble Bundle to buy games in the past, I wasn’t as attached to sliders as I was the flexibility they represented — the idea that if I wanted to, I could know all of my money was going to the people who might need it most. Other stores like Itch.io allow you to send more money to developers directly, but Humble Bundle’s setup was unique. Come mid-July, it’ll just be a little less flexible.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559894/humble-bundle-payment-sliders-100-percent-donations"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559894/humble-bundle-payment-sliders-100-percent-donations</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T18:52:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T18:52:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Richard Branson aims to fly to space before Jeff Bezos, Virgin Galactic confirms</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-ECONOMY-NYSE-VIRGIN" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2qMKHAdCBShjPmUvbU1_yg8Cics=/18x0:5381x3575/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69532035/1178650261.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by JOHANNES EISELE/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aYs7oy"&gt;Space tourism firm Virgin Galactic will fly its founder Richard Branson on its next test flight slated for July 11th, the company confirmed Thursday. Branson’s new flight date will come before rival Jeff Bezos is expected to fly in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522313/jeff-bezos-space-launch-brother-blue-origin-july-20"&gt;his own space tourism rocket on July 20th&lt;/a&gt;, setting the stage for a largely symbolic showdown between two billionaires racing to validate their space tourism rockets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8U2Rgu"&gt;Branson, 70, wasn’t set to fly on&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Virgin Galactic’s VSS Unity spaceplane for another two tests — until Thursday, when the company announced he’d fly on July 11th “testing the private astronaut experience” alongside four mission specialists and two pilots. “I’ve always been a dreamer,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/richardbranson/status/1410729503337418756"&gt;Branson tweeted after the announcement&lt;/a&gt;. “My mum taught me to never give up and to reach for the stars. On July 11, it’s time to turn that dream into a reality aboard the next Virgin Galactic spaceflight.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nEBf1s"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I’ve always been a dreamer. My mum taught me to never give up and to reach for the stars. On July 11, it’s time to turn that dream into a reality aboard the next &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/virgingalactic?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@VirginGalactic&lt;/a&gt; spaceflight &lt;a href="https://t.co/x0ksfnuEQ3"&gt;https://t.co/x0ksfnuEQ3&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Unity22?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Unity22&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/GWskcMSXyA"&gt;pic.twitter.com/GWskcMSXyA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Richard Branson (@richardbranson) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/richardbranson/status/1410729503337418756?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 1, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ekw90u"&gt;The mission, dubbed Unity 22, will mark Virgin Galactic’s fourth crewed test flight of VSS Unity, a spaceplane that launches from a carrier aircraft mid-air and ascends toward the edge of space to give passengers a few minutes of weightlessness. It will be “the first to carry a full crew of two pilots and four mission specialists in the cabin, including the Company’s founder, Sir Richard Branson, who will be testing the private astronaut experience,” the company said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WdH47i"&gt;Unity, designed to carry up to six passengers and two pilots, has been tested 22 times, with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/22/22448928/virgin-galactic-spaceplane-vss-unity-space-branson"&gt;most recent test&lt;/a&gt; taking place at Virgin Galactic’s lavish Spaceport America base in New Mexico. Three more test flights including Branson’s remain this year before Virgin Galactic carries out its first revenue-generating mission for the Italian Air Force. The company has some 600 reservations for paying customers on future space flights, with each ticket going for around $250,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="soIpoW"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Something “very exciting” will be announced after the flight&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Wst5j9"&gt;Branson, in a video he tweeted, teased an additional announcement after his July 11th flight. “When we return, I will announce something very exciting to give more people a chance to become astronauts, because space does belong to us all,” he said. “So watch this space.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="piYllT"&gt;Blue Origin announced last month that Bezos, its founder, will be on board its first crewed mission of New Shepard, a suborbital rocket designed to send passengers to the same heights as VSS Unity for a few minutes of weightlessness. That rocket launches vertically from the company’s remote spaceport in Van Horn, Texas. New Shepard has flown 15 times without crews on board, with the most recent uncrewed flight serving as an astronaut training rehearsal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tBdKuK"&gt;Virgin Galactic’s announcement comes on the same day Blue Origin announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22558908/wally-funk-flight-jeff-bezos-blue-origin-space-new-shepard"&gt;the fourth crew member&lt;/a&gt; for its first crewed New Shepard flight — Wally Funk, a legendary aviator who also holds a ticket for Virgin’s VSS Unity. Bezos, his brother Mark, and the winning bidder of a $28 million auction for a New Shepard seat will also be on board for that July 20th mission. Unlike Virgin Galactic, Blue Origin hasn’t announced the ticket price for future New Shepard flights just yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="LdXvUp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;July 11th — “pending tech checks and weather, of course.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Leb7hV"&gt;The Federal Aviation Administration granted Virgin Galactic approval to fly space customers last week as a tweak to the company’s commercial space transportation operator license, marking the first time the FAA licensed a spaceline to fly customers. Blue Origin doesn’t have the same FAA approval to fly customers ahead of its July 20th flight with Bezos yet, but is getting close to securing it, according to a person familiar with the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IJOfeX"&gt;Space blogger Parabolic Arc was the &lt;a href="http://www.parabolicarc.com/2021/06/07/virgin-galactics-richard-branson-aims-to-fly-to-space-before-jeff-bezos/"&gt;first to report&lt;/a&gt; on an accelerated timeline for Branson’s flight. Spokespeople for Virgin Galactic had neither confirmed nor denied the report until Thursday. A company spokeswoman said Branson’s July 11th flight hinges on “tech checks and weather, of course.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559964/richard-branson-space-before-jeff-bezos-virgin-galactic"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559964/richard-branson-space-before-jeff-bezos-virgin-galactic</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T18:12:26-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T18:12:26-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft’s Blue Screen of Death is changing to black in Windows 11</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/psATsoCzSgIoZvY08Yy16XEHg48=/0x0:1320x880/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69531788/windows11bsod.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Windows 11’s new Black Screen of Death.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lvvm49"&gt;Microsoft is changing its famous Blue Screen of Death (BSOD) to black in Windows 11. The software giant started testing its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22557060/microsoft-windows-11-hands-on-preview"&gt;new design changes in a Windows 11 preview&lt;/a&gt; earlier this week, but the Black Screen of Death isn’t fully enabled yet. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; understands Microsoft will be switching to a Black Screen of Death for Windows 11, matching the new black logon and shutdown screens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x7z9if"&gt;It’s the first major change to the BSOD since Microsoft added a sad face to the screen in Windows 8 in 2012, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/4/12/11412906/microsoft-windows-10-blue-screen-of-death-qr-code"&gt;QR codes in 2016&lt;/a&gt;. Microsoft first introduced the BSOD in Windows 3.0, offering a way for IT professionals and support personnel to diagnose hardware and memory faults. A BSOD is Windows’ own kernel error or bug check, and it usually includes a dump of data that can help system administrators analyze what system fault caused the blue screen.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3KVhnFRMv3GivX5jsTATqJguW4s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22694673/windows11bsod.gif"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new Black Screen of Death in Windows 11.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="wgdQW0"&gt;While Microsoft is switching to a Black Screen of Death in Windows 11, the screen is identical to the one found in Windows 10 otherwise. The sad face remains, as does the stop code and crash dump. The current preview of Windows 11 includes a green BSOD, a color that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/12/29/14111584/microsoft-windows-10-green-screen-of-death"&gt;Microsoft has been using for Windows Insider builds since 2016&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O78K4r"&gt;We’re not entirely sure why Microsoft is changing the color from blue to black, and the company isn’t commenting on the change yet. I have some theories, though. Microsoft is overhauling many parts of Windows 11, with a fresh approach to the OS. It’s likely because Windows 11 includes a visual overhaul to modernize the OS in key areas, including classic parts like the Start menu, File Explorer, and now even the BSOD.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559852/microsoft-windows-11-black-blue-screen-of-death-bsod-change"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559852/microsoft-windows-11-black-blue-screen-of-death-bsod-change</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T17:33:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T17:33:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple is reportedly trying a ‘retail flex’ work-from-home program for store employees</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mTS4UOxf8ngm7iYOViexxXAdujA=/0x154:3036x2178/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69531620/IMG_20171003_180359.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="91L5C2"&gt;Apple is reportedly working on a program called “Retail Flex,” which will give its store employees the chance to work from home some weeks, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-07-01/apple-to-test-hybrid-work-from-store-and-home-for-retail-staff"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;’s&lt;/a&gt; Mark Gurman. According to the report, the employees would be remotely handling things like tech support and online sales part of the time, and working at the store as usual at other times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QuXefm"&gt;Having employees who traditionally work in a store transitioning to a remote role, even if it’s only a partial change, is a big shift, likely brought on by the pandemic. It doesn’t seem like Apple is just jumping into it. The company is reportedly starting a pilot program that will last at least six months, with participating employees being paid the same salary, plus some extra for internet and office equipment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OleH27"&gt;If Apple does end up adopting a model that sees fewer employees working retail, it likely won’t be alone. With the US starting to enter its post-pandemic stage, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/09/29/how-coronavirus-pandemic-forever-altered-retail.html"&gt;physical stores will have to contend&lt;/a&gt; with the new habits people have formed of shopping online and doing in-store pickup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yQbKMM"&gt;For its non-retail staff, Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465846/apple-employees-return-office-three-days-week-september"&gt;will require at least some office time&lt;/a&gt;, with employees having to return to the office at least three days a week. Some of Apple’s workers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/4/22491629/apple-employees-push-back-return-office-internal-letter-tim-cook"&gt;pushed back against having to return to the office&lt;/a&gt;, but the company will reportedly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22556615/apple-response-hybrid-work-model-employee-letter-remote"&gt;still go through&lt;/a&gt; with the hybrid work model. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="4dKmIm"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s hard to imagine many retail employees working from home during the iPhone launch&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OTSWdZ"&gt;There’s an interesting contrast with Apple potentially lowering the number of retail employees it has working at most given times, and the other retail moves it’s been making. Over the past few years, it’s been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/12/16296460/apple-self-love-iphonex-iphone8-event"&gt;rebranding some of its stores as “town halls”&lt;/a&gt; where events and classes can take place, and it just recently restored two historic buildings &lt;a href="https://www.macstories.net/stories/a-palazzo-reborn-inside-apples-stunning-new-store-in-via-del-corso-rome/"&gt;in Rome&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/06/apple-tower-theatre-opens-thursday-in-downtown-los-angeles/"&gt;Los Angeles&lt;/a&gt; into decadent stores. Now, with news of this plan, it seems like there could be fewer employees around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ipapZ3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;does say that Apple’s plan is to scale employee presence with retail demand — it’s hard to imagine many employees scheduling work-from-home weeks during the iPhone launch — but we may be soon see the first steps toward a different, more online-focused Apple Store experience.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559713/apple-retail-flex-work-from-home-store-employees"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559713/apple-retail-flex-work-from-home-store-employees</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T17:14:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T17:14:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to install the tvOS 15 beta on Apple TV</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jIyMLvWhtpqhoZXAlkrSFk2uxUs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69531553/DSCF3875_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Bi79e4"&gt;The next big software update for Apple TV will arrive with tvOS 15. While it won’t become widely available until later this year, users who are part of Apple’s public beta program can now take it for a spin ahead of time. It’s possible and even likely that Apple will continue tinkering with tvOS 15 features ahead of its official launch, but particularly for those looking to test-drive Apple’s forthcoming SharePlay feature, the public beta has officially landed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lx63fz"&gt;The goodies arriving in tvOS 15 that Apple has disclosed so far are small — you’re not going to notice a massive redesign of the tvOS interface, for example — but they’re not insignificant, either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wgo0ei"&gt;Though, a warning: once you install tvOS 15 on a newer Apple TV 4K box, there’s no turning back. Uninstalling the beta from your Apple TV device may not be possible with newer models. Resetting an Apple TV HD requires &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/guide/tv/reset-apple-tv-atvbf9db0a52/tvos"&gt;connecting a USB-C cable&lt;/a&gt; to your computer (I’ll describe the process more thoroughly later), which isn’t possible on the Apple TV 4K boxes. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; has contacted Apple to ask about whether it’s possible to revert back to tvOS 14 on newer Apple TVs and will update this guide if we hear back, but a simple factory reset doesn’t cut it. (This is the case with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22558944/watchos-beta-install-how-to"&gt;watchOS 8&lt;/a&gt; as well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SgbbwS"&gt;WHAT ARE THE NEW FEATURES ON tvOS 15?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ebM5qU"&gt;For one, tvOS 15 will bring support for SharePlay to Apple TV, allowing users to stream movies and TV shows with others over FaceTime on an iPhone, iPad, or Mac. It’s Apple’s spin on group watch features that have largely been supported by individual services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z4gSHm"&gt;There was just a handful of streaming services that Apple confirmed during WWDC would support the tool — Disney Plus, Twitch, Hulu, and Prime Video included — but we’ll &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22526742/apple-facetime-shareplay-ios-15-watch-party"&gt;likely see wider support&lt;/a&gt; before tvOS officially rolls out later this year, as Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22526742/apple-facetime-shareplay-ios-15-watch-party"&gt;confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; last month that the feature will be available to any streaming service that wants to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sYXbu7"&gt;Two new rows will appear in the Apple TV app in tvOS 15 as well: For All of You and Shared with You. When enabled, Shared with You will populate content that’s been shared with a user through Messages — for example, if a friend recommends &lt;em&gt;For All Mankind&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Lisey’s Story&lt;/em&gt; from Apple TV Plus. (Though you’ll need to enable it using another Apple device, and I couldn’t seem to set it up this way.) For All of You, meanwhile, will surface content that Apple believes would be a good fit for everyone in the household.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cuXTVz"&gt;Some additional features coming to Apple TV in tvOS 15 include support for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525028/apple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on"&gt;spatial audio&lt;/a&gt; with AirPods Pro or AirPods Max as well as on-screen connectivity notifications for AirPods. Additionally, HomeKit will allow users to view multiple camera feeds at once. And lastly, the update will support pairing two HomePod mini speakers to an Apple TV 4K.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SKaZG3"&gt;WHAT DEVICES ARE SUPPORTED FOR tvOS 15?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="W1o1cA"&gt;Apple TV 4K (2021)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="bkDwMg"&gt;Apple TV 4K (2017)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kaLnAz"&gt;Apple TV HD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hMkR9v"&gt;HOW TO DOWNLOAD THE tvOS 15 BETA&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="L3z3td"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="From the settings menu, toggle on “Get Public Beta Updates”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mipuoDUWSjpu5UNVRk0Pvu6GaaU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22694425/Screen_Shot_2021_07_01_at_4.24.52_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;From the settings menu, toggle on “Get Public Beta Updates.” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Vx0KXZ"&gt;On your computer, sign up for &lt;a href="https://beta.apple.com/sp/betaprogram/"&gt;Apple’s beta program&lt;/a&gt;, or sign in if you’re an existing member&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rFbzTY"&gt;Once you’re signed in, navigate to the tvOS tab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="UM82hE"&gt;Scroll down to the “Get Started” section of the tvOS beta page and &lt;a href="https://beta.apple.com/sp/betaprogram/enroll#tvos"&gt;enroll your Apple TV&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="pCtpwq"&gt;Now head for the settings menu on your Apple TV and select “Users and Accounts.” Make sure you’re signed in with the same Apple ID you used to register for the beta program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uDuuym"&gt;From the settings menu, select “System” &amp;gt; “Software Update,” and toggle on “Get Public Beta Updates”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AjrqKU"&gt;Once this setting is enabled, update your Apple TV from your system settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="6KSLzZ"&gt;How to restore your Apple TV HD to its factory settings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Pq3lqu"&gt;If the beta isn’t working for you, you can &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/guide/tv/reset-apple-tv-atvbf9db0a52/tvos"&gt;restore an Apple TV HD&lt;/a&gt; (but again, &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the Apple TV 4K) to its factory settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="jPNroI"&gt;Disconnect both the HDMI and power cables from the box, then connect it to your computer using a USB-C cable. Apple suggests connecting it to a Mac running macOS Catalina or later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0XLP6g"&gt;Open Finder from your computer, and choose “Restore” from the Apple TV menu &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Dn6Uc8"&gt;If you’re attempting to reset your box with a PC, you’ll need to use iTunes to restore the Apple box from the Source list. The same goes for Macs running Mojave or older.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22559665/tvos-15-beta-apple-tv-how-to-install"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22559665/tvos-15-beta-apple-tv-how-to-install</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T16:31:12-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T16:31:12-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon is ending Evangelion by bringing the final film to Prime Video</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZVY0eCjscsxzq5Q_3iDILBUCRhE=/0x820:1562x1861/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69531324/EVANGELION_3.0_1.01_THRICE_UPON_A_TIME.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Amazon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vjIibO"&gt;Amazon is bringing the conclusion to the Rebuild of Evangelion film series — adaptations of the beloved anime &lt;em&gt;Neon Genesis Evangelion &lt;/em&gt;created by Hideaki Anno&lt;em&gt; — &lt;/em&gt;to &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GZfuWMDEJpw"&gt;Prime Video on August 13th&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Evangelion: 3.0 + 1.01 Thrice Upon a Time&lt;/em&gt; came out in Japan in March but will be making its global premiere on Prime Video in over 240 countries and territories, Amazon says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xf9epA"&gt;Alongside the final fourth film, Amazon will also stream the other films in the series, &lt;em&gt;Evangelion: 1.11 You Are (Not) Alone&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Evangelion: 2.22 You Can (Not) Advance&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Evangelion: 3.33 You Can (Not) Redo&lt;/em&gt;. The company hasn’t said when those films will be available on its service, but hopefully in time to catch up for &lt;em&gt;Thrice Upon a Time&lt;/em&gt;’s August release. You can watch a trailer for the new movie below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="y2hNaO"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GZfuWMDEJpw?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YINBPX"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Evangelion&lt;/em&gt; “Rebuilds” are an interesting mix of reworked moments from the original anime and entirely new plot lines and character backstories that only appear in the film series. If you caught up with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/27/18114331/netflix-neon-genesis-evangelion-anime-series"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neon Genesis Evangelion&lt;/em&gt; when it came to Netflix in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, there are lots of interesting departures and fully animated Eva battles to discover in the Rebuilds. Plus the show and films’ &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/22/18701441/neon-genesis-evangelion-hedgehogs-dilemma-shinji"&gt;darker psychological themes&lt;/a&gt; probably hit too close to home for anyone who’s had a mini-existential crisis during the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3HXPAJ"&gt;That Amazon managed to snag &lt;em&gt;Thrice Upon a Time&lt;/em&gt; and its predecessors seems like a pretty big knock against Netflix’s anime empire. Most streaming services are now trying to have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/23/21003549/anime-streaming-wars-netflix-amazon-att-sony-crunchyroll-funimation"&gt;some kind of anime strategy&lt;/a&gt;, either through the acquisition of other platforms or just by throwing money at popular creators. Netflix missing out on scooping up more &lt;em&gt;Evangelion&lt;/em&gt; to go with the series and original two feature films it already offers is a loss. More mechs for Bezos, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jfPSMq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="32hI4X"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5nHVwN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559498/amazon-prime-video-evangelion-rebuild-us-streaming-release"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559498/amazon-prime-video-evangelion-rebuild-us-streaming-release</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
