<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-05-27T01:01:02-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-27T01:01:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-27T01:01:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nintendo’s OLED Switch could come in September</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/C6-kwfFZdgva84FPfm8faVrcoEg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69349128/acastro_190530_1777_switch_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustrations by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GmFIg4"&gt;Nintendo could release its heavily rumored new version of the Switch in September or October, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-27/nintendo-plans-upgraded-switch-replacement-as-soon-as-september"&gt;report by Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt;. Manufacturing is reportedly planned to start as soon as July, and Bloomberg says the system may be announced before the E3 trade show, which kicks off in virtual form on June 12th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9o48tq"&gt;As Bloomberg notes, an announcement ahead of E3 would allow third-party publishers, as well as Nintendo itself, to show their games running on the new hardware. This version of the Switch is said to use &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/23/22346041/oled-nintendo-switch-dlss-nvidia-chip-report"&gt;more powerful silicon from Nvidia&lt;/a&gt; that works with DLSS technology, allowing for 4K output to a TV. It also reportedly has a 7-inch OLED display sourced from Samsung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="sFJX1G"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How AI could make the new Nintendo Switch a powerhouse overnight","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/26/22348095/nintendo-switch-nvidia-dlss-graphics-ai-explained"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Us7UqY"&gt;Bloomberg says Nintendo’s suppliers are “confident” in their ability to fulfill the orders even though there’s a global shortage of chips and other components. “Production lines are better prepared for the potential component shake-up and the parts Nintendo is using are subject to less competition than those in its rivals’ more powerful consoles,” according to the report, though it still warns that “the company’s ability to meet consumer demand won’t be guaranteed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uUE2kD"&gt;The current model of the Switch has been difficult to find in many regions throughout the past year, with increased demand during the pandemic exacerbated by challenges with the  supply chain.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/27/22456160/new-nintendo-switch-release-date-september-e3-announcement"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/27/22456160/new-nintendo-switch-release-date-september-e3-announcement</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-27T00:25:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-27T00:25:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>Square Enix announces Dragon Quest XII: The Flames of Fate</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0EghJY8-F3JYEuzRXu6qeHlP_Jo=/0x1:800x534/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69349068/dq12.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KjUUaQ"&gt;Square Enix has announced the latest mainline entry in the &lt;em&gt;Dragon Quest&lt;/em&gt; series. &lt;em&gt;Dragon Quest XII: The Flames of Fate &lt;/em&gt;was revealed on a livestream to celebrate the series’ 35th anniversary. Not much beyond the game’s logo and title was revealed, but series creator Yuji Horii hinted at some changes to the traditional turn-based battle system, and said Square Enix was aiming for a simultaneous worldwide release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yA3erY"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dragon Quest&lt;/em&gt; is the most popular RPG series in Japan. The last game, &lt;em&gt;Dragon Quest XI: Echoes of an Elusive Age&lt;/em&gt;, was released for the PlayStation 4 and 3DS in its home market in 2017, though the original Western release only came to the PS4 and PC. An updated version, &lt;em&gt;Dragon Quest XI S&lt;/em&gt;, was released for the Nintendo Switch and later came to Xbox, PS4, PC, and Stadia. In total, Square Enix has shipped more than six million copies of &lt;em&gt;Dragon Quest XI&lt;/em&gt; worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lKbfqk57maaQomU2VScY1q7rkyc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22542702/IMG_0141.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MgbAT2"&gt;Square Enix also announced five more new &lt;em&gt;Dragon Quest&lt;/em&gt; titles during the broadcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="6np4Pu"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Dragon Quest Treasures&lt;/em&gt;, a treasure-hunting RPG starring characters from &lt;em&gt;Dragon Quest XI&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lfUzTt"&gt;A remake of &lt;em&gt;Dragon Quest III&lt;/em&gt; in a similar “HD-2D” visual style to Square Enix’s &lt;em&gt;Octopath Traveler&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="bFadxr"&gt;The next major expansion to &lt;em&gt;Dragon Quest X&lt;/em&gt;, the Japan-only MMO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DkR95B"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Dragon Quest X Offline&lt;/em&gt;, a top-down version of &lt;em&gt;X&lt;/em&gt; that doesn’t require an internet connection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vubDtN"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Dragon Quest Keshikeshi&lt;/em&gt;, a mobile puzzle game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="qPAqPP"&gt;That’s a lot of &lt;em&gt;Dragon Quest&lt;/em&gt; to be getting on with, although only &lt;em&gt;III&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Treasures&lt;/em&gt; are confirmed for a worldwide release at this stage.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/27/22456124/dragon-quest-xii-announced-35th-anniversary-event"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/27/22456124/dragon-quest-xii-announced-35th-anniversary-event</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-26T21:08:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-26T21:08:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook will no longer stop the spread of a theory that COVID-19 was manufactured</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/67RlQuQ7ve-fxsdcow_8n5_uw0Y=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69348583/acastro_180828_1777_facebook_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nXBbhE"&gt;Facebook won’t remove claims that COVID-19 was man-made anymore, according to &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2021/05/26/facebook-ban-covid-man-made-491053"&gt;a report from &lt;em&gt;Politico&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that cites a Facebook spokesperson. The company altered its policy because of a renewed focus on the origins of the virus, including an order from President Joe Biden to his intelligence agencies to investigate the so-called lab-leak hypothesis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kOBS6R"&gt;Facebook’s policy change was made “in consultation with public health experts,” that spokesperson told Politico. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/31/21116500/facebook-instagram-coronavirus-misinformation-false-cures-prevention"&gt;The social network’s policy mandates&lt;/a&gt; that false claims and conspiracy theories about the virus be removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="pZENM1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The company has been trying to stem the tide of misinformation&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Z4T8Qy"&gt;Misinformation has often &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/interface/2020/4/17/21223742/coronavirus-misinformation-facebook-who-news-feed-message-avaaz-report"&gt;circulated on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/10/22/7028983/fake-news-sites-are-using-facebook-to-spread-ebola-panic"&gt;during the Ebola crisis in 2014&lt;/a&gt;. The company is &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/newsletters/morning-tech/2021/03/23/tracing-misinformation-to-the-tech-ceo-hearing-794198"&gt;under pressure from lawmakers&lt;/a&gt; to clean up its act. Early in the pandemic, dangerous hoaxes — falsely suggesting that drinking bleach might cure the coronavirus, for instance — circulated widely on Facebook, and were shared thousands of times, &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2020/12/coronavirus/"&gt;despite Facebook’s January 2020&lt;/a&gt; announcement that it would be applying its misinformation policies to posts about the coronavirus and its subsequent efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b5POVS"&gt;Since then, Facebook has updated its &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/help/230764881494641"&gt;list of statements that will be removed&lt;/a&gt; to include anti-vaccination propaganda as well. To try to stem the tide of misinformation, the company created &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22187298/instagram-coronavirus-covid19-misinformation-notifications"&gt;notifications about where to get information&lt;/a&gt; about vaccines across its platforms. It’s also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22177085/facebook-covid-19-misinformation-notifications"&gt;attempted to warn users&lt;/a&gt; if they’ve interacted with posts that were found to contain misinformation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7MO1bm"&gt;Earlier today, &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/26/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-investigation-into-the-origins-of-covid-19/"&gt;Biden released a statement&lt;/a&gt; saying that the intelligence community believes that two scenarios are possible: that the virus started spreading when a human contacted an infected animal, or that the spread was the result of a lab accident. Most in the intelligence community believe there isn’t enough evidence to determine which scenario is more likely, according to the statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bK2PnT"&gt;The renewed interest and discussion of the “lab leak” theory has raised concerns about anti-Asian hate. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22393622/asian-hate-crime-reporting-community-group-statistics"&gt;Anti-Asian violence&lt;/a&gt; has risen since since the beginning of the pandemic, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447553/anti-asian-american-hate-story-aapi-belong"&gt;fueled by former president Donald Trump’s use of terms&lt;/a&gt; such as “China virus” and “kung flu.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S2GzBl"&gt;YouTube and Twitter did not immediately respond to request for comment on whether they would implement similar policy updates. Facebook also did not respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455797/facebook-covid-19-man-made-moderation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455797/facebook-covid-19-man-made-moderation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-26T20:41:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-26T20:41:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>LeBron James may have just proved the unannounced Beats Studio Buds are real</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f_8v8cL4aa1hJ14i-4Xt45GtYoI=/0x2:780x522/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69348543/191152746_211492840634582_216780930635838230_n.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;LeBron James wearing what appear to be Beats Studio Buds.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CPWWyKHhWr-/" target="_blank"&gt;LeBron James on Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Qz926I"&gt;Earlier this month, an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22440700/beats-studio-buds-leak-ios-tvos-design"&gt;unannounced pair of Beats wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt;, apparently called the Beats Studio Buds, showed up in beta releases of iOS and tvOS. While those betas were a good start, a flood of new leaks — including actual photos of mystery earbuds from superstar athlete LeBron James — suggest that they could be available very soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pGPjqk"&gt;Here’s what we already knew: on May 17th, people digging into the iOS and tvOS 14.6 betas found evidence of the new headphones, with perhaps the clearest look at them coming from animations in the OS shared by &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt; contributor Steve Moser (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SteveMoser/status/1394361761571254272"&gt;he has a whole thread of them here&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Rmle67"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Beats Studio Buds ‘charged’ &lt;a href="https://t.co/xTqj1vo8Mq"&gt;pic.twitter.com/xTqj1vo8Mq&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Steve Moser (@SteveMoser) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SteveMoser/status/1394361883457724417?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 17, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kQVHxT"&gt;This week, the Beats Studio Buds appeared under that name in &lt;a href="https://fccid.io/BCGA2513"&gt;FCC&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://fccid.io/BCGA2512"&gt;filings&lt;/a&gt;, a sign that the product has been cleared for sale in the US. Diagrams in &lt;a href="https://fccid.io/BCGA2513/Label/FCC-ID-Label-and-Location-5250626"&gt;these&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://fccid.io/BCGA2512/Label/FCC-ID-Label-and-Location-5250503"&gt;filings&lt;/a&gt; also give us a clear look at the shape of the buds from one specific angle.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8-NOHOSoySTqmkx9jH255WMG1WM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22542107/Screen_Shot_2021_05_26_at_3.46.30_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://fccid.io/BCGA2513/Label/FCC-ID-Label-and-Location-5250626" target="_blank"&gt;fccid.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Diagrams of the Beats Studio Buds.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="h2KMfh"&gt;Photos &lt;a href="https://www.mysmartprice.com/gear/apple-beats-studio-buds-live-images-leaked-design-revealed/"&gt;published by &lt;em&gt;MySmartPrice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; this week show devices that have a very similar design to those FCC diagrams — though it looks like these new photos are just of the plastic casing for the earbuds. While &lt;em&gt;MySmartPrice&lt;/em&gt; said it “could not independently verify the authenticity of these images,” the design seems to match other leaks. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Z76_kCoB_ZbwwUNH3t8BeUiMUTY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22542113/Apple_Beats_Studio_Buds.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.mysmartprice.com/gear/apple-beats-studio-buds-live-images-leaked-design-revealed/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MySmartPrice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This looks pretty similar to the design in the FCC filings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5E3RE0"&gt;Now, on Wednesday evening, we may have gotten our first look at the earbuds in the wild in the ears of LeBron James, who posted &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CPWWyKHhWr-/"&gt;new photos on Instagram&lt;/a&gt; where he is seemingly wearing the buds (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/markgurman/status/1397676604512407560"&gt;via &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/05/26/lebron-james-beats-studio-buds/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). At first glance, it’s hard to tell exactly what headphones he’s wearing, but if you look &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; closely, you can see a squared off ridge on the outside of the headphones that looks an awful lot like the headphones shown in the animation shared by Moser. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/amTKEe5QxV5NdIs9CyMIQt15Xt4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22542250/lebron_james.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CPWWyKHhWr-/" target="_blank"&gt;LeBron James on Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;That earbud sure looks like a Beats Studio Bud.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="S0Hwdy"&gt;LeBron surely knows what he’s doing. At this point, it seems like the Beats Studio Buds are the real deal and they could arrive at any moment. Now we just need Apple to announce them.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455747/beats-studio-buds-apple-lebron-james-instagram-photos"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455747/beats-studio-buds-apple-lebron-james-instagram-photos</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-26T19:37:45-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-26T19:37:45-04:00</updated>
    <title>You can join Twitter’s Clubhouse-like Spaces rooms from a browser starting Wednesday</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oEr1zsvOkaWfotJCU_-4_Kd8_uw=/0x14:1292x875/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69348418/E2WWJjqVkAM5hDk.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter Spaces on the web.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Twitter&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="i9ENh9"&gt;You’ll be able to join Twitter’s Clubhouse-like Spaces from desktop and mobile web browsers starting Wednesday, the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSpaces/status/1397688581846568961"&gt;company announced&lt;/a&gt;, making the company’s social audio rooms much more widely accessible. Previously, you could only join Spaces from Twitter’s iOS and Android apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9fpHPc"&gt;You can get a look at what a Spaces look like on the web in screenshots below, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1397692324830908417"&gt;from Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. The image on the left shows what you’ll see before joining a Space. The one on the right shows a Space off to the side so you can continue scrolling through Twitter while you listen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TgabEm"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Spaces are making their way to Twitter for web! &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Now you can join a Space to listen in, test out the new transcription design, and set reminders to join a scheduled Space. &lt;a href="https://t.co/xFTEeAgM4x"&gt;https://t.co/xFTEeAgM4x&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Twitter Support (@TwitterSupport) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1397692324830908417?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 26, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sh0AhO"&gt;Spaces on the web have a big caveat, though: you can join Spaces, but you can’t host them yourself just yet, a Twitter spokesperson confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BDqpXl"&gt;Twitter has been quickly opening up Spaces and adding features over the past several months to compete with the dedicated social audio app &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22380290/clubhouse-social-audio-twitter-facebook-platforms"&gt;Clubhouse&lt;/a&gt; and similar features from companies like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/31/22356682/discord-stage-channels-clubhouse-like-feature-voice"&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22391551/facebook-audio-podcasts-clubhouse-competitor-spotify-live-rooms"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. Early in May, Twitter began rolling out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22413033/twitter-spaces-android-ios-ticket-schedule-clubhouse-captions"&gt;the ability to host spaces on mobile&lt;/a&gt; to anyone with 600 or more followers. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455799/twitter-spaces-web-browser-clubhouse-social-audio-room"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455799/twitter-spaces-web-browser-clubhouse-social-audio-room</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-26T19:33:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-26T19:33:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>The PS5 will be profitable next month — and Uncharted 4 is coming to PC</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cDbizi2RovSW4ZMGGwFAZYcAunY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69348402/vpavic_4278_20201030_0247.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HMEua5"&gt;In February, Sony revealed &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2021/2/3/22264242/playstation-5-sales-loss-manufacturing-costs-msrp-sony"&gt;it was selling the PlayStation 5 at a loss&lt;/a&gt; — but that’s imminently about to change. The PS5 should hit break-even in June, and become profitable the very same month, according to &lt;a href="https://www.sony.com/en/SonyInfo/IR/library/presen/irday/pdf/2021/GNS_E.pdf"&gt;a presentation the company shared with investors (PDF)&lt;/a&gt; during its investor day today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rLBKgh"&gt;Needless to say, that’s fast — happening before the company has even managed to catch up with demand, in the midst of a global chip shortage. (We bemoaned &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/23/22434905/ps5-restock-best-buy-walmart-sony-playstation-5"&gt;the needless drama of buying a PS5&lt;/a&gt; just days ago!) &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i_5D1mIG58KjUl--ihU90jlE6P8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22542156/breakeven_ps5.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="jGYdCX"&gt;Mind you, this is for the standard PS5, the one where Sony has to supply a 4K Ultra HD Blu-ray drive and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/10/21430240/how-much-will-sony-ps5-cost-xbox-series-x-s-editorial"&gt;pay as much as $8 per console in licensing fees&lt;/a&gt;, and charges you an extra $100 at retail. It’s not clear if Sony’s driveless PS5 Digital Edition is more or less profitable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qO6X7r"&gt;Profitability isn’t the only intriguing disclosure in Sony’s presentation, though. Buried in the filing is the &lt;em&gt;excellent&lt;/em&gt; news that an incredible game is coming to PC — the previously PS4/PS5 exclusive &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/5/5/11579498/uncharted-4-review-ps4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Uncharted 4: A Thief’s End&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a blockbuster action game that we loved enough to write both &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/5/5/11579498/uncharted-4-review-ps4"&gt;spoiler-free&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/5/14/11671134/uncharted-4-nathan-drake-goodbye-nostalgia-theme"&gt;multiple&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/5/20/11719308/uncharted-4-better-pacing-less-shooting"&gt;spoiler-iffic&lt;/a&gt; reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GVFAcwZm_yjRWIvs5zUdXt4cAFI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22542152/pc_uncharted_4.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="NLPwZn"&gt;Sony had previously promised &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297091/days-gone-pc-playstation-games-ports-jim-ryan"&gt;more PlayStation exclusives would come to PC&lt;/a&gt;, and Sony’s presentation makes it clear why the company is interested. See that little “&lt;strong&gt;ROI 250%+&lt;/strong&gt;” note? If I’m reading it correctly, that means &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21363127/horizon-zero-dawn-pc-port-review-performance"&gt;the iffy PC port of &lt;em&gt;Horizon: Zero Dawn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; nonetheless managed to make &lt;em&gt;more than double the money &lt;/em&gt;that Sony invested in bringing it to gaming computers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NeIHLH"&gt;It makes me wonder, very strongly, about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/17/21444039/ps5-playstation-5-final-fantasy-xvi-demons-souls-pc-announcement"&gt;the mysterious circumstances that surrounded Sony’s announcements of &lt;em&gt;Demon’s Souls&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XVI&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KrgoBl"&gt;Oh, by the way: sure looks like Sony just confirmed that &lt;em&gt;God of War: Ragnarok &lt;/em&gt;is the official name of that upcoming game! Could be a mistake or a juxtaposition of two vaguely related logos, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="cr6y8r"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Also genuinely surprising to see them maybe just confirm God of War: Ragnarok as the next game's official title?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;After we've all spent so long calling it that, makes sense to lean in, I suppose! &lt;a href="https://t.co/7YYm6cngZ9"&gt;pic.twitter.com/7YYm6cngZ9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Jonathon Dornbush (@jmdornbush) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jmdornbush/status/1397690881285660677?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 26, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="VZTXuu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Epic wanted Sony’s PlayStation PC games to compete with Steam, documents show","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/11/22424596/epic-games-store-sony-playstation-pc-games-steam-competition"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="OM3YMY"&gt;Correction: Sony’s presentation today came from its Investor Day, not its Corporate Strategy Meeting. The Corporate Strategy Meeting &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22454377/sony-ai-playstation-game-agents-corp-document-presentation-2021-strategy"&gt;was yesterday&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455810/sony-ps5-profitable-uncharted-4-pc-investor-presentation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455810/sony-ps5-profitable-uncharted-4-pc-investor-presentation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-26T18:01:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-26T18:01:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Uber finally recognizes UK driver union in historic agreement </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Uber Drivers Win Supreme Court Appeal To Be Considered Workers" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NLTi80En8gobQMbnSY5shC0ASrM=/0x0:7116x4744/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69347985/1231264249.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo illustration by Matthew Horwood/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Z1nYvF"&gt;Uber has finally recognized a union of its own drivers. Allow yourself that single moment of elation before we get to the rest of the details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HLi2lj"&gt;GMB trade union in the UK (it’s not really an acronym for anything, as it was shortened from General, Municipal, Boilermakers’ and Allied Trade Union some 40 years ago) managed to clinch union recognition from the jaws of the famously labor-hostile app company today. As &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; reported, “GMB will have access to drivers’ meeting hubs [...] It will also be able to represent drivers if they lose access to the Uber app, and it will meet quarterly with management to discuss driver issues and concerns.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kPkGQS"&gt;It’s not clear whether this arrangement hews closer to traditional union representation as we envision it in the US, or if this more so resembles the Independent Drivers Guild — an outsized advocacy group in New York that meets with Uber and has been &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/new-yorks-rideshare-organizers-clash-amid-unprecedented-1834623838"&gt;widely criticized&lt;/a&gt; as a company union. Drivers won’t be automatically enrolled in the union as a result of working for Uber. That’s an arrangement we’d refer to as an “open shop” on this side of the Atlantic, and the company is almost assured to leverage it to its benefit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v9Hjmg"&gt;Drivers in the UK &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/03/18/uber-is-reclassifying-uk-drivers-as-workers-heres-what-happens-next.html"&gt;recently won&lt;/a&gt; — via the courts — the right to be considered Uber “workers,” a category distinct from “employees” but which still confers basic employment benefits like minimum wage and a pension. However, that ruling did not apply to couriers on the Uber Eats food delivery side, nor does this new union agreement cover them. From the start then, this new agreement leaves an estimated 30,000 Uber laborers out in the cold. (We’ve reached out to GMB and Uber for additional details on that oversight.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dq13oz"&gt;GMB has undoubtedly made history here, but Uber’s track record gives onlookers every reason to doubt the efficacy of this new union. The company has a habit of threatening to pull out of locations that fail to provide the legal favoritism it has come to expect — &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/uber-threatens-to-leave-quebec-over-driver-rules-1506453196"&gt;Quebec in 2017&lt;/a&gt;, for example. It has also been engaged in attempts to rewrite labor law in the US to suit its business interests, successfully &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/5/21551136/uber-prop-22-victory-national-q3-2020-earnings"&gt;overturning a California law&lt;/a&gt; via a ballot proposition during the 2020 election which cost the company — along with fellow travelers Lyft, DoorDash, and Postmates — an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/22291580/prop-22-instacart-doordash-uber-lyft-postmates-grubhub-price-hike"&gt;estimated $200 million&lt;/a&gt;. Since then, drivers in the state have reported their &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/16/uber-lyft-drivers-california-prop-22"&gt;wages falling&lt;/a&gt; even further. (Uber is &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-18/labor-gig-companies-are-said-to-be-near-bargaining-deal-in-n-y"&gt;attempting&lt;/a&gt; a similar legal maneuver in New York currently.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tuTjxc"&gt;Further compounding matters, one of the parties which helped win worker status for UK drivers — the App Drivers &amp;amp; Couriers Union — refused to sign on to a similar deal for recognition, claiming &lt;a href="https://www.adcu.org.uk/news-posts/uber-gmb-union"&gt;in a statement&lt;/a&gt; that it believes “closer trade union engagement with Uber management is always a welcome development but there is good reason for workers and their unions to be cautious.” The group cited Uber’s continued hostility toward workers, in and out of court, in the UK and in the US. “For us compliance with legal minimums should be the point of departure for any union agreement with Uber,” the ADCU wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YaMshQ"&gt;Still, a win is a win. “This ground-breaking deal between GMB and Uber could be the first step to a fairer working life for millions of people,” the delightfully named GMB national officer Mick Rix noted in identical press releases sent to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; by both the union and Uber, “We now call on all other operators to follow suit.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7BrMM5"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V2AYHH"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455533/uber-union-uk-gmb-eats-labor"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455533/uber-union-uk-gmb-eats-labor</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bryan Menegus</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-26T17:50:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-26T17:50:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>SanDisk’s new card reader dock is all I could ever want and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3sBxriZVVgGB_cYWXV309h5ml4w=/0x166:4000x2833/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69347893/SanDiskProfessionalPRO_DOCK4.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Sandisk&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="AgW1lb"&gt;Western Digital, owner of the SanDisk brand, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.westerndigital.com%2Fcompany%2Fnewsroom%2Fpress-releases%2F2021%2F2021-05-26-western-digital-debuts-sandisk-professional-brand&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F5%2F26%2F22455534%2Fsandisk-pro-dock-4-video-workflow-lexar-sd-cfast-cards-thunderbolt" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;has announced&lt;/a&gt; a new product called the Pro-Dock 4, and it’s all I’ve ever wanted in a card reading solution: it lets you mix and match four card reading modules, which can all be read simultaneously, and connect them all to your computer using a single Thunderbolt 3 cable. This dock not only fills the hole that was left in my heart by &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Lexar-Professional-Workflow-Thunderbolt-LRWHR2RBNA/dp/B00KYK1KZK/ref=sr_1_7?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=lexar%2Bworkflow&amp;amp;qid=1622063026&amp;amp;sr=8-7&amp;amp;th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Lexar’s Workflow hub&lt;/a&gt;, but it makes me completely forget it existed: the Workflow didn’t have Thunderbolt daisy-chaining or a 260W power supply for charging devices and accessories (though I will admit that Lexar’s SSD modules were kind of neat).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9XRtB6"&gt;SanDisk says it’ll be making modules for the dock that support CFast, CFexpress, Red’s Mini-Mags, CF, microSD, and SD formats. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Xgli01byarUz4LlcC9BjUVRhJU8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22541842/SanDiskProfesssionalPRO_READER_Family_stacked.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: SanDisk&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;SanDisk’s readers, which work independently or as part of the dock.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="DzcZtQ"&gt;The modules themselves will be available individually, which is great for a few reasons. For one, it lets you mix and match your dock’s card reading abilities: mainly shoot Red but use a Canon R6 as a B-cam? You can load up three Red Mini-Mag readers and a combo SD / microSD / CF card reader. If you’re all-in on CFast, you could load up four of those readers. And if you change what you’re shooting with in the future, you can buy new modules instead of having to get a whole new dock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="19dBcn"&gt;The modularity also allows for portability. If you’re going to a location and just need to bring along one reader, you can pop it out of the dock and take it along with you — the individual readers use USB-C 10Gbps to connect to either your computer or the dock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4b7TZW"&gt;To be clear, I’m not a video or photo professional, and I certainly don’t need this much card-reading capacity. I’ve never even held half the cards these things can read. But does that stop me from wanting one of these docks, loaded out with enough card readers to dump every SD card I own at once? Absolutely not. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ES4zlp"&gt;The prices for the dock and readers haven’t yet been announced, but SanDisk expects them to go on sale this summer. Lexar’s hub &lt;a href="https://www.anandtech.com/show/11546/lexar-professional-workflow-hr2-4bay-thunderbolt-2-usb-30-reader-hub-review/8"&gt;cost around $200&lt;/a&gt; at launch, plus the price of modules (I paid around $40 for the XQD module), and it did way less. I can only wait in fear to see the price tag of SanDisk’s version.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455534/sandisk-pro-dock-4-video-workflow-lexar-sd-cfast-cards-thunderbolt"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455534/sandisk-pro-dock-4-video-workflow-lexar-sd-cfast-cards-thunderbolt</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-26T17:38:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-26T17:38:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>Stadia’s loss is Clubhouse’s gain: the social audio company has poached a longtime Google engineer</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yM6Qk9Be2eeGDOm6aDjde3w5log=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69347831/acastro_210430_1777_audioApps_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="J0jRVa"&gt;Clubhouse has hired Justin Uberti, creator of the WebRTC standard and the Google Duo video chat app. He leaves Google after nearly 15 years at the company, where he was most recently the engineering lead for Google’s Stadia cloud gaming service and led the team that made the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22176273/google-stadia-ios-beta-live-now-mobile-safari-iphone-ipad-cloud-gaming"&gt;Stadia iOS web app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VHQ7rB"&gt;“Justin is a phenomenal engineering leader and one of the original inventors of WebRTC, on top of which Clubhouse is built,” Clubhouse co-founder and CTO Rohan Seth said in a statement. “There’s so much that goes into crafting a fantastic audio experience — the quality, the latency, the ability to use spatial distance when multiple speakers are talking. This will be a critical area of investment for us as we open Clubhouse to the whole world, and among other things, Justin will be helping lead that effort.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8TcOyQ"&gt;Uberti’s title will be head of streaming technology, a Clubhouse spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dQeH17"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Some news: after almost 15 years at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Google?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Google&lt;/a&gt;, today is my first day at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Clubhouse?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Clubhouse&lt;/a&gt;! I'm impressed with what &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/pdavison?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@pdavison&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rohanseth?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@rohanseth&lt;/a&gt; have built, and I'm super excited to be joining the team and figuring out where this can go! &lt;a href="https://t.co/WcTSI8AAof"&gt;pic.twitter.com/WcTSI8AAof&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Justin Uberti (@juberti) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/juberti/status/1397612890601889792?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 26, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ux6QyU"&gt;“I’m really optimistic about the potential [of Clubhouse]: everyone in the world knows how to use voice, it’s such an expressive medium (compared to text), and advancements like AirPods are making it easier to consume audio,” Uberti said at the end of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/juberti/status/1397612898596261894"&gt;a Twitter thread&lt;/a&gt; discussing the move. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oMj3Ms"&gt;WebRTC is an &lt;a href="https://webrtc.org/"&gt;open-source project&lt;/a&gt; that lets developers add real-time communication (RTC) features to applications, and it works on modern browsers and is supported within many native apps. The fact that Discord can instantly drop you into a voice chat in a browser? &lt;a href="https://blog.discord.com/how-discord-handles-two-and-half-million-concurrent-voice-users-using-webrtc-ce01c3187429"&gt;WebRTC helps power that&lt;/a&gt;. And if you’ve used Clubhouse, you’ve probably experienced how easy it is to jump in and out of audio rooms on the fly — that’s also powered by WebRTC. (Uberti commended Clubhouse as a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/juberti/status/1397612891663003650"&gt;“great example”&lt;/a&gt; of a novel RTC use-case.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q87MM8"&gt;As Clubhouse looks to compete with social audio products from bigger companies like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22391551/facebook-audio-podcasts-clubhouse-competitor-spotify-live-rooms"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22413033/twitter-spaces-android-ios-ticket-schedule-clubhouse-captions"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/31/22356682/discord-stage-channels-clubhouse-like-feature-voice"&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;, and even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22359332/linkedin-clubhouse-clone-social-audio-networking-room"&gt;Microsoft’s LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, hiring the creator of a key technology backing its app could give Clubhouse an advantage in an increasingly crowded field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZRykdG"&gt;In addition to Stadia and Duo, Uberti also had a key role in the development of Google Hangouts Video and was the chief architect for AOL Instant Messenger, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/juberti/"&gt;according to his LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455357/clubhouse-google-engineer-webrtc-justin-uberti-stadia"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455357/clubhouse-google-engineer-webrtc-justin-uberti-stadia</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-26T17:25:15-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-26T17:25:15-04:00</updated>
    <title>Big Oil and Gas had a no good, very bad day </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Environmental Group Takes Royal Dutch Shell Plc To Court Over Global Emissions" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pTAne_C-zzDcA-NSY-w4AI72KyM=/0x0:4000x2667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69347751/1233120319.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Members of the environmental group MilieuDefensie celebrate the verdict of the Dutch environmental organisation’s case against Royal Dutch Shell Plc, outside the Palace of Justice courthouse in The Hague, Netherlands, on Wednesday, May 26, 2021. Shell was ordered by a Dutch court to slash its emissions harder and faster than planned, dealing a blow to the oil giant that could have far reaching consequences for the rest of the global fossil fuel industry | Peter Boer/Bloomberg via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Iqy7y2"&gt;Fossil fuel companies are having a big reckoning with climate change this week. Shareholders for Exxon and Chevron voted for measures that could force them to take more responsibility for their emissions, while a Dutch court is forcing Shell to slash its pollution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yk2tC4"&gt;Taken altogether, the actions reflect a growing push for&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;the energy sector to phase out&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;fossil fuels. Major oil companies had already taken some steps to at least appear to address climate change, but activists are pushing for more action on a faster timeline to meet the scale of the climate crisis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="lYfFZQ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A growing push for&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;the energy sector to phase out&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;fossil fuels&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KcVAr2"&gt;Climate activist Bill McKibben called it a “&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/billmckibben/status/1397602737106325506"&gt;watershed day&lt;/a&gt;,” adding that the ruling against Shell could be “&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/billmckibben/status/1397560462955499520"&gt;game-changing&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NkKrgi"&gt;Exxon shareholders, during an annual meeting today, voted in at least two new board members who might force more climate-related change on the company. If they can sway others on the 12-member board of directors, they could direct Exxon to do business differently. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7UVmnn"&gt;A small hedge fund called Engine No. 1, which has just a 0.02 percent stake in Exxon, nominated four “independent” candidates it says are capable of pushing the company in a more sustainable direction. Each new board member that’s voted in ousts a sitting member. One of the new board members is Kaisa Hietala, who previously helped lead oil refining company Neste’s venture into renewable energy products. Shareholders also voted in Gregory Goff, a former CEO for refinery company Andeavor. The other two seats were still too close to call after preliminary results came out this afternoon. This is the first time activist investors have successfully voted their picks onto Exxon’s board, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2021/05/26/business/economy-stock-market-news"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="hg7IuM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“the Company has failed to evolve in a rapidly changing world”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QZTkjM"&gt;“Over the past decade, the Company has failed to evolve in a rapidly changing world, resulting in significant underperformance to the detriment of shareholders and risking continued long-term value destruction,” Engine No. 1 said in a &lt;a href="https://sec.report/Document/0000902664-21-001931/"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; about why it put forward its slate of candidates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a76qaA"&gt;Exxon, the United States’ biggest fossil fuel producer, has been slower than its peers to pivot toward renewable energy sources. In December, it pledged to cut CO2 emissions by just 15-20 percent per barrel of oil and gas by 2025, and reduce &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22422824/natural-gas-infrastructure-methane-emissions-climate-change-air-pollution"&gt;methane emissions&lt;/a&gt; (a greenhouse gas more potent than CO2) by 40-50 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I952jp"&gt;Both Exxon and Chevron, the second-largest US oil producer, have set less ambitious environmental goals than peers in Europe. Chevron said in March that it wants to cut CO2 emissions from its operations by 35 percent per unit of production by 2028. Chevron’s shareholders &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com./business/energy/chevron-shareholders-approve-proposal-cut-customer-emissions-2021-05-26/"&gt;approved&lt;/a&gt; a proposal today that forces deeper cuts. It calls on the company to specifically target emissions from the oil and gas it sells, which accounts for a majority of the emissions for which the company is responsible. Shareholders for ConocoPhillips passed a &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com./business/environment/conocophillips-shareholders-back-proposal-set-scope-3-targets-2021-05-11/"&gt;similar resolution&lt;/a&gt; earlier this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t62pIu"&gt;Dutch company Shell went further than its American counterparts by recently announcing that it would get to net-zero emissions for both its operations and the products it sells by 2050 — a commitment to reduce, capture, and offset all of its pollution. But promises to reach milestones decades from now aren’t very helpful unless they’re backed up by a plan to take immediate action. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="Q0CTFl"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“People around the world are demanding climate justice”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oJ7m47"&gt;A landmark ruling from a Dutch court now pushes the company to act much faster. Instead of reducing emissions 20 percent by 2030, as the company had planned, the court ruled that Shell should slash emissions by 45 percent by 2030. Globally, emissions should drop roughly in half by the end of the decade in order to stave off more severe effects from climate change, according to &lt;a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/sr15/chapter/spm/"&gt;United Nations climate scientists&lt;/a&gt;. Shell reportedly &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/05/26/dutch-court-rules-oil-giant-shell-must-cut-carbon-emissions-by-45percent-by-2030-in-landmark-case.html"&gt;plans to appeal&lt;/a&gt; the decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PZlea9"&gt;Environmental groups, including Greenpeace and Friends of The Earth, filed the suit against Shell in &lt;a href="https://www.ciel.org/news/historic-climate-case-against-shell-filed-in-the-netherlands/"&gt;2019&lt;/a&gt;, claiming the company endangered Dutch citizens through its role in the climate crisis. “Shell cannot continue to violate human rights and put profit over people and the planet. This verdict is a clear signal to the fossil fuel industry. Coal, oil and gas need to stay in the ground. People around the world are demanding climate justice,” Andy Palmen, interim director of Greenpeace Netherlands, said in a &lt;a href="https://www.greenpeace.org/international/press-release/47934/historic-verdict-in-climate-case-against-shell/"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A3EayL"&gt;A mountain of &lt;a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/sr15/chapter/spm/"&gt;evidence&lt;/a&gt; points to the need to keep global warming from surpassing 1.5 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels, a target enshrined in the Paris climate agreement. Investments in new fossil fuel projects need to stop immediately in order to hit that target, the International Energy Agency said in a big &lt;a href="https://www.iea.org/news/pathway-to-critical-and-formidable-goal-of-net-zero-emissions-by-2050-is-narrow-but-brings-huge-benefits-according-to-iea-special-report"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; last week. The intergovernmental agency’s energy outlooks are often heeded by governments and energy companies, so its new advice on fossil fuels was widely seen as a sort of death knell for oil and gas growth. So while today might have been an unusually rough day for fossil fuel companies, there are probably more to come. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6av4l2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455387/big-oil-gas-shell-exxon-chevron-climate-change"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455387/big-oil-gas-shell-exxon-chevron-climate-change</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
