<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-19T11:01:52-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-19T11:01:52-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-19T11:01:52-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to score a COVID-19 vaccine appointment </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_u2r1v0qpkmDCofvfzLEcU6WDG4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68809161/acastro_201217_1777_vaccine_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DzZXIa"&gt;One of the most frustrating tasks for many of us these days is finding how and where to get an appointment for a COVID-19 vaccination. It can be a real exercise in exasperation: the websites are often difficult to navigate and prone to frequent crashes; in addition, after finding an open appointment slot and filling out multiple pages of questions, you are often told that the opening has disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Vp4Bt"&gt;In view of all this, we’ve tried to gather as much helpful information as we can about ways to research and snag vaccination appointments for yourself and others. We’ll update this as more information presents itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="JYv8ZW"&gt;Research the vaccination qualifications in your state&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="jJJ2mU"&gt;To begin with, it’s a good idea to try to pin down if you or the person you are assisting is currently qualified for the COVID-19 vaccine. Find the vaccine information site (or sites) that is being run by your state and / or city. This will also help you figure out when you might be qualified if you aren’t already. If you can’t find it via a quick search, &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/specials/plan-your-vaccine/"&gt;NBC News has created a simple website&lt;/a&gt; that lets you find out what the current situation is in your specific state. &lt;a href="https://www.goodrx.com/covid-19/where-to-get-covid-19-vaccine"&gt;Prescription company GoodRx&lt;/a&gt; offers similar information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="N5dWHX"&gt;Find all the places that might offer appointments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="XK1Cc0"&gt;There are, fortunately or unfortunately, many different sites where you can go to find out if you can get an appointment to be vaccinated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dgvDmn"&gt;For example, here in New York City, we’ve had to navigate separate sites run by the city and the state. Various hospital systems also have their own sites, as do pharmacies such as Walgreens and CVS, which have recently begun offering appointments for vaccinations. It’s a lot to check — and it can be enormously confusing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="usTdFX"&gt;As a result, your first step is probably to check your state’s government health website (searching your state name and “COVID vaccine” will probably do it). If you’re an urban dweller, check for your city’s information site as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H8ot2F"&gt;While most personal physicians do not have access to vaccines, your doctor may be able to tell you some of the places to check. Other resources include your local hospital system, your union (especially if your employment qualifies you for a vaccination), and, of course, friends and colleagues, many of whom have probably been doing their own searches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WZ6Bfn"&gt;As you find resources and sites, make sure to bookmark them. I keep a folder on my bookmarks bar called “COVID” — you may want to name yours something more cheerful.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Looking for an available vaccine appointment can be frustrating, but persistence can pay off." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8lP4_R3np2CX9crqTcg9Mq6I2Js=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13963741/IMG_1653.1419968302.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Looking for an available vaccine appointment can be frustrating, but persistence can pay off.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="6uguNM"&gt;Have all your information ready&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="1Dt0LZ"&gt;Many of us who have tried to register for vaccination appointments have gone through the experience of filling out several screens of information only to find that, by the time we got to the end, the appointment was gone. So it’s a good idea to have all your data — such as your name, age, address, insurance info, and the registration ID / password for the site — immediately at hand. The faster you can go through the registration process, the more likely you are to actually get an appointment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tRD8jU"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; colleague Cory Zapatka says that he highly recommends using a password manager if you have one. He created accounts with all the vaccination sites in his area, even if they didn’t have appointments available at the time, so that if / when the time came, he could just auto-fill and get in right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q9bBlc"&gt;And if you do get an appointment, make sure you have the appropriate paperwork already handy — especially since available appointments can be last minute. Necessary paperwork could include proof of employment, proof of age, or proof of a qualifying condition. Since the last one may require a doctor’s note or other record, it’s a good idea to call your doctor now — or if you’ve got access to a doctor’s or hospital website, that may offer you access to the proof you need. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5dqUcf"&gt;One more thing: check to see if you’ve gotten all the email that has been sent to you by your vaccine supplier. At least one staff member of &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; found a necessary consent form hiding in her spam folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="wCK4vB"&gt;Watch for news of upcoming vaccination sites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="bDlWg4"&gt;Keep an eye on the news. More and more sites and hubs are being added as the US gears up for a stronger push. If you see a news item saying that a hub is about to open, find the site for the hub and keep checking — once it does open, the available slots will probably go quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rz172X"&gt;One thing that sometimes helps is to look for patterns in the appearance of new appointments. For example, when I heard that the pharmacy chain Walgreens was going to begin giving out vaccines in my area, I spent a couple of days going onto the site, and suddenly realized that there was a pattern: the company was only scheduling appointments two to four days in advance and was adding new appointments each day just after midnight. Once I understood the pattern, I was able to get appointments for a couple of friends, and let others know about it as well. (Note: since vaccine supplies and scheduling methods can change on a dime, this particular strategy may no longer work by the time you read this.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Sites like the NYC Vaccine List can help by gathering together available resources in one place." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FsRia6ki1VqiuNodQvjKHdK9-ek=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22299690/Screen_Shot_2021_02_12_at_8.47.56_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sites like the NYC Vaccine List can help by gathering together available resources in one place.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gz26d4"&gt;Look for help online&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="PgrwN8"&gt;There are a number of online resources popping up headed by developers and other technology-savvy folks who have taken the time and effort to try to make sense of this confusion. (Thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/02/10/covid-vaccine-appointment-websites/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/09/nyregion/vaccine-website-appointment-nyc.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for some of these listings.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Vhk2GI"&gt;An NYC site called &lt;a href="https://www.turbovax.info/"&gt;TurboVax&lt;/a&gt; pulls “the latest appointments from 43 city and state-run vaccine sites in the NYC area” and puts them on Twitter. Followers who set their Twitter notifications for &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/turbovax"&gt;@turbovax&lt;/a&gt; can quickly find out about newly opened appointment slots. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="c0AX5B"&gt;Another called &lt;a href="https://nycvaccinelist.com/"&gt;NYC Vaccine List&lt;/a&gt; uses a combination of scripts and checks by volunteers to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/31/22256167/covid-vaccine-website-nyc-appointment"&gt;scour various sites for openings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="111Dwk"&gt;In California, &lt;a href="https://www.vaccinateca.com/"&gt;VaccinateCA&lt;/a&gt; checks pharmacies and hospitals for information about open appointments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZYJAS8"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://vaccinatenj.com/"&gt;Vaccinate NJ&lt;/a&gt; also uses volunteers to try to help state residents find vaccine opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZJic26"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.covid19vaccinetx.com/"&gt;Covid 19 Vaccine TX&lt;/a&gt; is a crowdsourced resource for registering with local counties and finding locations where vaccines may be available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WLYqtL"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.macovidvaccines.com/"&gt;MA Covid Vaccine Appointments site&lt;/a&gt; offers lists of and links to sites with available appointments. A volunteer-run Massachusetts site, &lt;a href="https://vaccinatema.com/"&gt;Vaccinate MA&lt;/a&gt;, tries to improve on the state website with a map-based design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yR8waA"&gt;A volunteer group in the state of Washington has launched the &lt;a href="https://www.covidwa.com/"&gt;WA COVID Vaccine Finder&lt;/a&gt; as an aggregation resource for vaccination appointments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="C1YLfR"&gt;There is also a site that aggregates the aggregators: &lt;a href="https://wherecanigetavaccine.com/"&gt;Where Can I Get A Vaccine?&lt;/a&gt; offers a list of sites available for various US states. And &lt;a href="https://covidshotfinder.com/"&gt;COVIDShotFinder&lt;/a&gt; lets you select a state or county and look for the various vaccine resources available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jdCWU8"&gt;One possible strategy is to use page-change-monitoring tools such as &lt;a href="https://visualping.io/blog/how-to-be-alerted-of-covid-19-vaccine-availability-in-your-local-pharmacy/"&gt;Visualping&lt;/a&gt; to generate alerts for when new appointments become available. These apps watch websites for you and send alerts to your email, text, or even Slack account when new information appears. They can be very useful (and allow you to take time for, say, lunch). But since these are, for the most part, business apps, you may need to pay for the privilege. For example, while &lt;a href="https://visualping.io/pricing"&gt;Visualping does have a free service&lt;/a&gt;, it is limited to pinging you once an hour up to 65 times a month, which may not be often enough if you’re trying to score an appointment.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="nhHjOx"&gt;By the way, if you’re a developer and / or coder who wants to help, check out &lt;a href="https://www.usdigitalresponse.org/"&gt;US Digital Response&lt;/a&gt;, an independent organization which, according to its website, “connects experienced, pro-bono technologists with local government and non-profit organizations responding to crisis.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Reservation Of The Anticovid Vaccine For Over Eighty In Apulian Pharmacies" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4leCSmB_jTd6jhw7V_SvQQsfQ8Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22299704/1231117569.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Davide Pischettola / NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are able, it’s a good idea to reach out and help those who may not be able to get appointments on their own.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="8mSy40"&gt;If you can, help others&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Kz9AlN"&gt;One of the worst things about the distribution of the COVID-19 vaccines is that those who need it the most are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22227531/covid-vaccine-website-appointments-accessible-seniors"&gt;often the least likely to be able to navigate the technology required to get an appointment&lt;/a&gt;: older people, differently abled people, or those who don’t have or can’t afford computers and / or internet connections. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W2VOR9"&gt;If you have the time and talent, reach out to anyone you know who may not be able to get an appointment on their own. This could be as simple as finding phone numbers they can call to try to schedule an appointment, going online and getting an appointment for them, or helping them get to and from the vaccination site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Evm4o5"&gt;You could also see if there are any groups that are organizing help. &lt;a href="https://www.westsiderag.com/2021/01/19/need-help-signing-up-for-a-vaccine-a-young-tech-savvy-person-can-help-you"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The West Side Rag&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, for example, reports that a group of New Yorkers created the &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScO11RAr7tqHU6LJp_ZNMl5mRbxdg-zc1lO1SuVHBBDLTyJrg/closedform"&gt;Vaccine Appointment Assistance Team (VAAT)&lt;/a&gt; to help their non-technically-savvy neighbors navigate the process. (At the time this was written, because of low supplies of vaccine, VAAT had temporarily suspended their services.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="rm5plO"&gt;Look for leftover vaccine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="M5v0nn"&gt;While the vaccines can last for six months while they’re kept frozen, once thawed and refrigerated, the Pfizer vaccine will last five days while the Moderna vaccine will last for 30 days. As a result, when people don’t show up for their appointments, some centers will &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/22229169/leftover-vaccines-random-people-grocery-stores-pharmacies"&gt;offer vaccinations to those who may not immediately qualify&lt;/a&gt; rather than waste vaccines that would otherwise be rendered unusable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EI3933"&gt;However, running to a nearby pharmacy or vaccine hub in the hit-and-miss hopes that there will be some shots waiting at the end of the day isn’t the most effective way to be vaccinated. (Besides, getting hypothermia while waiting in the cold isn’t going to help.) At least one group is trying to ameliorate the situation: a pilot project called &lt;a href="https://vaxstandby.com/"&gt;Vaccination Standby&lt;/a&gt; says that it will monitor providers around the US for word of extra doses and text notifications to those whose zip codes are near the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nAc3tM"&gt;There are also local organizations that are offering standby lists. For example, Buncombe County in North Carolina has a &lt;a href="https://www.buncombecounty.org/countycenter/news-detail.aspx?id=19137"&gt;vaccination waitlist and standby list&lt;/a&gt;, as does the &lt;a href="https://www.co.monroe.in.us/egov/documents/1611179705_09719.pdf"&gt;Monroe County Health Department&lt;/a&gt; in Indiana. Check your local government site to see if there’s one in your area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Fg3eNk"&gt;Be persistent!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="JTTPvK"&gt;Yes, it’s frustrating as hell, but keep at it. If a website crashes, try again. If you’re dropped from a phone call, call again (and have a game, video, or book ready to keep yourself occupied while you’re on hold). If you can’t find anything during working hours, try late at night or very early in the morning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cBXxUO"&gt;Persistence may be one of the most important aspects of getting an appointment for a COVID-19 vaccination. You may be tempted to give up, especially after hitting the “no appointments available” wall time and time again. But until vaccine production is ramped up enough to cover more of our population, and until distribution becomes more organized and easier to manage, simple stubbornness may be your best tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lwiVs8"&gt;And hopefully this article, and all the advice it contains, will soon be unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1QdqaC"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 12th, 11:10AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article has been updated to include the WA Covid Vaccine Finder.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rW1K6i"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 16th, 10:10AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article has been updated to include a mention of webpage change monitoring tools.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Jkqbm"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 19th, 11AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article has been updated to include another Massachusetts site and two general vaccination finding sites.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZwQk0g"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c0F1RM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22279023/covid-19-vaccine-appointment-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22279023/covid-19-vaccine-appointment-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-19T10:40:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-19T10:40:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>Animal Crossing: New Horizons manga is getting localized for the West on September 14th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SAOC7aIcfyDycvWfAZ5PNPXZLLY=/0x0:1080x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68842491/acnh_manga.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing New Horizons&lt;/em&gt; Volume 1 Deserted Island Diary | Image: Viz Media&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MrQqON"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing: New Horizons&lt;/em&gt; is one of the most popular titles on the Nintendo Switch right now. But if you’re interested in experiencing one of Nintendo’s popular franchises in other media forms, an official manga based on the latest entry is getting an English translation this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q0oH8Q"&gt;Viz Media announced that the first volume, titled &lt;em&gt;Deserted Island Diary,&lt;/em&gt; will release in the West on September 14th. The manga will focus on what the villagers residing on a deserted island are up to. The manga was originally released in Japan in 2020 and currently has &lt;a href="https://www.shogakukan.co.jp/books/volume/49514"&gt;two volumes&lt;/a&gt; available. &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing: New Horizons&lt;/em&gt; also inspired &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P7MLd2fJfcs"&gt;a separate manga series&lt;/a&gt;, with the first chapter debuting in the February 2020 issue of &lt;em&gt;Ciao&lt;/em&gt; magazine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="0wZ77v"&gt;&lt;q&gt;This year is important for the ‘Animal Crossing’&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;series as the original game celebrates its 20th anniversary&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Zot7m8"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing&lt;/em&gt; is no stranger to the manga form, as previous games in the series like &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ebay.com%2Fitm%2FJAPAN-manga-LOT-Animal-Crossing-New-Leaf-Tobidase-Doubutsu-no-Mori-vol-1-2-%2F313065605706&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F19%2F22289384%2Fanimal-crossing-manga-release-date" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;New Leaf&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ebay.com%2Fitm%2FAnimal-Crossing-manga-Oideyo-Doubutsu-no-Mori-Shiawase-Tsuushin-Japan-Comic-%2F173875876031&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F19%2F22289384%2Fanimal-crossing-manga-release-date" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wild World&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; also received manga adaptations. Last year, Nintendo also shared a four-panel comic strip on the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/animalcrossing/status/1235263744948592640?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1235263744948592640%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.polygon.com%2Fcomics%2F2021%2F2%2F19%2F22289463%2Fanimal-crossing-new-horizons-manga-deserted-island-diary"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing&lt;/em&gt; Twitter account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TlLZAg"&gt;This year is important for the &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing &lt;/em&gt;series, as the original game celebrates its 20th anniversary. &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing&lt;/em&gt; has always been one of Nintendo’s more popular franchises. Its latest installment, &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing: New Horizons&lt;/em&gt;, has been met with critical acclaim, and the entry has provided &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/18/21185608/animal-crossing-new-horizons-nintendo-switch-coronavirus-escape-interview"&gt;a sense of escapism&lt;/a&gt; for many players during lockdowns caused by the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic.  &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/22289384/animal-crossing-manga-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/22289384/animal-crossing-manga-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-19T09:33:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-19T09:33:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s Magic Keyboard is still $100 off at several retailers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nQGSsgTaTgKIdrdk9BGvc6fNh0Q=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68842047/vpavic_042018_3979_0072.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2WwO3t"&gt;With the right keyboard accessory, you can transform your iPad into a laptop. Apple’s Magic Keyboard for the 11-inch iPad Pro and fourth-generation iPad Air can add a laptop-like experience to either tablet. It includes a set of backlit keys and a trackpad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YprKv7"&gt;At $300, the Magic Keyboard accessory is not cheap, but you can sometimes find it at a much lower price. It is currently going for $199 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0863BQJMS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Magic-Keyboard-for-11-inch-iPad-Pro-2nd-generation%2F984505060&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="LDuKNu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10295314"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cm7W5h"&gt;If you’re in the market for a new TV for your home, Best Buy has an incredible deal: you can buy &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1728939351250604130" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Hisense’s 75-inch 4K LED TV (model H6510G) for only $600&lt;/a&gt;, which is $400 off its usual price of $1,000. The model includes Android TV software built in, four HDMI ports, plus a panel that supports Dolby Vision, HDR 10, and HLG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="BUysEF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10265690"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="As8ore"&gt;Over at Walmart, you can grab a new pair of &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSAMSUNG-Galaxy-Buds-White-Charging-Case-Included%2F245851301%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy Buds for $49&lt;/a&gt; in white. Despite the product being almost three years old, at $49 this is a good alternative for people looking for a decent pair of wireless earbuds without shelling out too much cash. As pointed out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/8/18255221/samsung-galaxy-buds-headphones-truly-wireless-review-price-specs-features"&gt;in our review&lt;/a&gt;, the Galaxy Buds feature a six-hour battery life, a comfortable design, and include better sound isolation compared to Apple’s standard AirPods. The Galaxy Buds also include a company case that supports wireless charging. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="KlVX18"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9586872"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="pv9aaw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/2/19/22290991/samsung-galaxy-buds-hisense-75-inch-4k-led-tv-apple-magic-keyboard-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/2/19/22290991/samsung-galaxy-buds-hisense-75-inch-4k-led-tv-apple-magic-keyboard-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-19T09:02:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-19T09:02:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to stop your emails from being tracked</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nHKkuFlkTI9-ornuyWoyTQgbwg8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68841883/acastro_190703_1777_pixel_tracking_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wmDbQw"&gt;All of those obnoxious marketing emails that crowd your inbox aren’t just pushing a product. They’re also tracking whether you’ve opened the email, when you opened it, and where you were at the time by using software like MailChimp to embed tracking software into the message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1f75NZ"&gt;How does it work? A single tracking pixel is embedded into the email, usually (but not always) hidden within an image or a link. When the email is opened, code within the pixel sends the info back to the company’s server. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yYBZIp"&gt;There have been some attempts to restrict the amount of information that can be transmitted this way. For example, since 2014, &lt;a href="https://gmail.googleblog.com/2013/12/images-now-showing.html"&gt;Google has served all images through its own proxy servers&lt;/a&gt;, which could hide your location from at least some tracking applications. And extensions such as &lt;a href="https://uglyemail.com/"&gt;Ugly Email&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/pixelblock/jmpmfcjnflbcoidlgapblgpgbilinlem"&gt;PixelBlock&lt;/a&gt; have been developed to block trackers on Chrome and Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y6EFgJ"&gt;There is also a simple basic step you can take to avoid trackers: stop your email from automatically loading images since images are where the majority of these pixels hide. You won’t be able to avoid all of the trackers that can hide in your email this way, but you will stop many of them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qjXsAd"&gt;Here’s how to do it in the major desktop and mobile email apps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="91Fgwl"&gt;Disable image autoloading in Gmail:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="zbqpz9"&gt;Click on the gear icon in the upper right corner to access your settings, and click on “See all settings.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZEfys0"&gt;In the “General” tab (the first one), scroll down to “Images.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="z0QTtq"&gt;Select “Ask before displaying external images.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="VeQHzw"&gt;Scroll down to the bottom of the page and click on “Save Changes.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="yRek5v"&gt;Note that this will also turn off &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/26/18282636/amp-gmail-shopping-rsvp-forms-inbox-google-beta"&gt;Gmail’s dynamic email feature&lt;/a&gt;, which makes emails more interactive. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Disable image autoloading gmail" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rt4n2w6dt0YA29AkQaJs88b8OSk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/18278777/Gmail_settings.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id="XrhZKY"&gt;Disable image autoloading in Microsoft Outlook (Office 365):&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="MIRvx9"&gt;Click on “File” &amp;gt; “Options.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="132JwF"&gt;In the “Outlook Options” window, select “Trust Center.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="bgp9g6"&gt;Click on the “Trust Center Settings” button. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8dvLox"&gt;Check the boxes labeled “Don’t download pictures automatically in standard HTML messages or RSS items” and “Don’t download pictures in encrypted or signed HTML email messages.” You can make a number of exceptions to the first item if you want by checking the boxes underneath it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Disable image autoloading in Microsoft Outlook " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/c5oSbMQ9LNmjTkrf0o1boDgulmk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/18278781/outlook_6.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sN1ICl"&gt;Disable image autoloading in Apple Mail:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="0n9f5S"&gt;Select “Mail” &amp;gt; “Preferences.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="A7ND3F"&gt;Click on the “Viewing” tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qwEieV"&gt;Uncheck “Load remote content in messages.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Disable image autoloading in Apple Mail: " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3aKO2_n5Ebb00LdepxXPrCAzEn4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/18278801/Apple_Mail_preferences_2.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id="HHDXvZ"&gt;Disable image autoloading in Android Gmail:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="c5Wulc"&gt;Tap on the three lines in the upper left corner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="R8HSTQ"&gt;Scroll down to and select “Settings.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="KjX4Gw"&gt;Tap on the email account that you want to work with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="g1X0ro"&gt;Scroll down to and select “Images.” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="eEYbil"&gt;Tap on “Ask before displaying external images.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Disable image autoloading in Android Gmail: " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0WEEv9FyZisUtRpDpCK4ZFZ-3Xo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/18278832/Gmail_a__1_.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Disable image autoloading in Android Gmail: " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SIPHfcdjyw0EzWrK6Vq0BMMkdco=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/18278833/Gmail_2__1_.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="xbW3d5"&gt;Disable image autoloading in iOS Gmail:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="eUXclZ"&gt;Open Gmail for iOS, tap the hamburger menu in the upper left, and scroll down to settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dr88Ar"&gt;Tap the account you want to personalize, and tap into “Images.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xTabJG"&gt;Switch from “Always display external images” to “Ask before displaying external images.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="lo9CuX"&gt;Note that for those wishing to do this on Gmail’s mobile client, it appears it will only work for personal accounts and not enterprise ones managed through G Suite, for now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="M1JF9m"&gt;Disable image autoloading on iOS Mail:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="MIPm7O"&gt;Tap on “Settings” &amp;gt; “Mail.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8CgUR7"&gt;Find the “Messages” section and toggle off “Load Remote Images.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Disable image autoloading on an iPhone: " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8J0Rc6S3VmfrsQIy1rnx9Ne4Fwg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/18278978/IMG_2A872FA43FDA_1.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Disable image autoloading on an iPhone: " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wqH9jGDkO4JBmuzkqV8X-MeiqBg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/18278984/IMG_DFD17EB54AF5_1.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="w1Qtvj"&gt;Another option is to use an email client such as &lt;a href="https://www.thunderbird.net/en-US/"&gt;Thunderbird&lt;/a&gt;, which blocks remote images by default; the application allows you to download embedded content on an individual basis or allow pictures from contacts that you trust not to send hidden code in their images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="06msoO"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update July 3rd, 2019, 3:47PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article has been updated to include additional information about email clients.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GbvWNJ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 3rd, 2019, 7:35PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article has been updated to include directions for disabling image autoloading on Gmail for iOS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B7Bwbn"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 17th, 2021, 5:30PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Instructions for Microsoft Mail have been removed, and a few instructions updated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L7cPsv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22288190/email-pixel-trackers-how-to-stop-images-automatic-download"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22288190/email-pixel-trackers-how-to-stop-images-automatic-download</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-19T08:50:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-19T08:50:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>The best smartphone you can buy for under $500</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cZYqwTfbX2vk4FqDWTzaFfIYSDU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67732462/vpavic_200805_4131_0086_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;You can get a great smartphone at this price, whether you want an iPhone, a big screen, or a great camera&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="6vCZGK"&gt;If you’re shopping for a new phone on a budget, we’ve got good news: there are more great, affordable phones on the market than ever. Companies like Apple, Google, and Samsung are spreading the wealth of features enjoyed by their flagships down to less expensive options. Other brands like OnePlus are finding ways to challenge more established manufacturers with budget devices that make smart sacrifices to keep costs down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="16ya9R"&gt;The bad news is this makes the job of picking the best budget phone that much harder. Bear in mind that it’s impossible to buy a phone that does everything at this price point; instead, prioritize the features that matter most to you. You’ll have an easier time deciding, and you’ll end up with a great phone that you should be able to use for years to come. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BWHEzs"&gt;Our pick for the best inexpensive iPhone is the 2020 edition of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/22/21230308/apple-iphone-se-2-2020-review-features-specs-camera-price"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple iPhone SE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Even though it’s coming up on a year old, we think it’s still the best bet for most people.  While it does a competent job at everything, its standout feature is that it should last four or more years if treated well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cXvGVa"&gt;If you’re looking for the best cheap Android phone, then we think the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21351770/google-pixel-4a-review-camera-specs-price"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Pixel 4A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a great option. It has an excellent camera and good software, though its screen is smaller than a lot of the competition at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kHj2r3"&gt;What most people are looking for in a sub-$500 smartphone are the same things people want in a more expensive model: long battery life, good screen, good camera, and decent performance. It’s difficult to get high straight A’s in every single one of those categories, but if you’re able to decide where you’ll tolerate the occasional B grade, you’ll find a phone you’ll love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wu38Dv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9556638"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="2Gej3D"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9556642"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="GatTSx"&gt;
&lt;h1 id="xLIfAi"&gt;The best smartphone for under $500 in 2021&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Apple iPhone SE is a great choice if you want a phone that lasts for years." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dBU6PLPRcKtVVTdfTrprm4mAigQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19916232/vpavic_042019_3980_0024.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Apple iPhone SE is a great choice if you want a phone that lasts for years.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="PEjixV"&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/22/21230308/apple-iphone-se-2-2020-review-features-specs-camera-price"&gt;Apple iPhone SE&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="YvXuY9"&gt;The best smartphone under $500&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="R7dgPY"&gt;The phone that strikes the right balance of camera, build quality, speed, battery life, software, and longevity for most people is the Apple iPhone SE 2020. Even though it’s almost a year old now, it should still give you an excellent return on your investment. We recommend upgrading to the model with 128GB of storage for $449, which is $50 over the base price but well worth it long term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FnYJlm"&gt;The iPhone SE follows a very tried and true formula. It has the same body and 4.7-inch LCD screen that Apple has been using since the iPhone 6. That puts the display on the smaller end of screen sizes today and also means the phone’s bezels are bigger than anything else sold on the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z4OnLv"&gt;It’s a familiar design and not one that screams “modern.” But in exchange, you get a lot of value. The 2020 SE is part of the iPhone 11 generation, so its A13 Bionic processor is a year behind the latest and greatest. (That would be the A14 chipset in the iPhone 12 lineup.) However, it’s still one of the fastest processors you can get on any phone, but &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; one in this price bracket. Normally, speed isn’t something we prioritize on phones at this price point, but it’s nice to have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yFxDqg"&gt;Why that processor &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; matters, though, is overall longevity. Apple consistently supports its phones for four or more years with software updates. (That’s in opposition to Android, where getting software updates on anything but the Pixel is still a struggle.) So Apple’s choice of a fast processor means, in a few years, the iPhone SE will still feel snappy and still be supported with iOS updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="XX01cV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;As a total package, the 2020 iPhone SE is the best smartphone under $500 for most people&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BTqdjy"&gt;Battery life is good but not best in class. It should last about a day. Luckily, this iPhone supports wireless charging, which is still uncommon at this price point. And because it has the exact same shape as the iPhone 6, 6S, 7, and 8, there is a huge ecosystem of chargers and cases for it. Unlike many inexpensive Android phones, finding compatible accessories for the iPhone SE will be a breeze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bBJCKR"&gt;The iPhone SE has just one camera on the back and just one selfie camera on the front, 12 megapixels and 7 megapixels, respectively. Neither is great by 2021 standards, but both are significantly better than what Apple shipped in older iPhones. It’s also fairly good by the standards of sub-$500 phones, though the Google Pixel 4A continues to win this category by a knockout. You will get a lot of camera features on the iPhone SE, including portrait and HDR, but unfortunately, there is no night mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lM0nvh"&gt;As a total package, the 2020 iPhone SE is the best smartphone under $500 for most people. If you think of it on a cost-per-year metric, it ends up being significantly less expensive than the competition because it’s likely to last four or five years if you take care of it. Just as importantly, it’s a great phone on its own merits. You get access to the vast array of iOS apps, Apple’s strong support network, and a huge ecosystem of accessories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="ykrqeX"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Google Pixel 4A has an incredible camera." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uGMHIJ_EFkQE2rMcf3ISzHc3EYU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21691927/vpavic_4113_20200721_0041.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Google Pixel 4A has an incredible camera.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="lIP45s"&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21351770/google-pixel-4a-review-camera-specs-price"&gt;Google Pixel 4A&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="PmYbc8"&gt;The best inexpensive Android phone&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="ndqid1"&gt;If you prefer Android, want to spend a little less money, or just want the best camera, then the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21351770/google-pixel-4a-review-camera-specs-price"&gt;Google Pixel 4A is the obvious choice&lt;/a&gt;. Its screen is on the small side, and it doesn’t have the fastest processor, but it does have a clean version of Android and is first in line for updates from Google. The 4A came out in August last year, but it’s still guaranteed to get software updates until at least August 2023. It comes in either black or baby blue with 128GB of storage for $349. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HlVUW4"&gt;The Pixel 4A’s main claim to fame is its camera, which can go head-to-head with smartphones that cost $1,500 or more. That’s because Google does so much of the image processing in software. (The sensor itself is actually quite old and not very special.) That means the Pixel 4A can take night photos, do astrophotography, and has a passable portrait mode. It can’t hang with the iPhone SE for video but beats it for photos every time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="XiTOqY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Pixel 4A uses Google’s version of Android, which means it’s easy to navigate and free of extra stuff&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rrz5GM"&gt;The rest of the Pixel 4A’s specs are good but not great. It has a 5.8-inch screen, just enough RAM to keep apps from closing in the background, and a headphone jack. There’s no wireless charging, no fancy face unlock, and the body is made out of plastic instead of something more premium like glass. The Pixel 4A doesn’t even offer any IP water resistance ratings (but a splash of water is probably fine).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jI4c7K"&gt;The Pixel 4A uses Google’s version of Android, which means it’s easy to navigate and free of extra stuff you probably don’t want. More importantly, it means that Google can supply the software updates directly instead of waiting for another manufacturer or carrier to approve it. That puts you first in line for Android updates and also guarantees you’ll get them for three years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zkeXFo"&gt;Unfortunately, in a couple of years, it’s quite likely that the Pixel 4A will be on its last legs. Android phones generally don’t last quite as long as iPhones do because Android tends to bog down on older hardware more quickly. The Pixel 4A’s processor is fast enough today to not be a bother, but over time, it’s possible that it won’t age well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zlXbHh"&gt;But for all that, the Pixel 4A is probably the safest bet if you want to get an Android phone for less than $500. You’ll get better software support and a better camera for $350. Not a bad deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="0FM1jw"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The OnePlus Nord has very good specs for its price." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QLGyEbYOEFNw7_Knc2RmCAHngOo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/20149535/vpavic_4112_20200721_0034.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The OnePlus Nord has very good specs for its price.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bFMC0d"&gt;3. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21337235/oneplus-nord-review-specs-features-camera-performance-battery-life-90hz-screen-oled"&gt;OnePlus Nord&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="PWBCf6"&gt;The best all-around Android phone outside the US&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="VceItk"&gt;Technically, saying the OnePlus Nord costs less than $500 doesn’t make much sense because it’s not available in the US, and the company doesn’t plan to sell it in the States. But if you live in a market where it’s available, the OnePlus Nord is the kind of phone that aims for a solid B grade in every category instead of trying to ace one or two. For £379 / €399, it’s a safe Android bet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OCe0u5"&gt;The OnePlus Nord has a couple of features that are normally reserved for much more expensive phones: support for sub-6 5G networks and a high refresh rate 90Hz display. If you live in an area where 5G is built out, you may notice faster download speeds. But it’s the display that’ll have a bigger impact on your day-to-day experience. It makes everything feel smoother and better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AdWibC"&gt;You will miss out on wireless charging and a headphone jack with the Nord, but they’re really the only big things that are lacking. Battery life is strong, the 6.44-inch screen is big and beautiful, and the software is less annoying than some competitors (though not as clean as Google’s). The £379 / €399 model comes with 128GB of storage and 8GB of RAM, both plenty good for this price point. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g5llXq"&gt;As for cameras, there are a bunch of them — maybe even too many. There’s a standard, an ultrawide, and a macro camera on the back as well as a couple of selfie cameras on the front. As is the norm with most smartphone cameras these days, they will get you decent photos in decent light but fall down a bit in the dark. You’ll mostly want to use the main camera, as the ultrawide has a noticeable drop in quality, and the macro is only good for, well, macro or close-up shots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ijydf9"&gt;All too often, phones at this price point have some critical compromise you’re forced to make in order to get the feature you really want. With the OnePlus Nord, there’s no big flaw you’ll have to work around. Again, though, it’s not available in the US. You can import it, but it’s not recommended as it won’t work correctly on US LTE networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="FtL0ba"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9556646"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="PNDiYl"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You probably don’t need 5G yet, but the Google Pixel 4A 5G has other strong benefits." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lqavDX9Dr3x8QhTCGr_XsRCbpvM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21956765/akrales_201013_4137_0289.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Even without considering 5G, the Pixel 4A 5G has other strong benefits.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ARB606"&gt;4. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21514296/google-pixel-4a-5g-review-camera-speed-video"&gt;Google Pixel 4A 5G&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="L6XTYh"&gt;A big screen with timely software updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="0TPXKd"&gt;The Pixel 4A 5G is good for all the reasons that the Pixel 4A is good: it has a great camera, good battery life, and clean Google software. Maybe most importantly, it has a bigger 6.2-inch screen, which is spacious but doesn’t make the phone feel too gigantic. It also uses Qualcomm’s Snapdragon 765G processor, which means it’s faster than the Pixel 4A and nearly all the rest of the sub-$500 Android phones you can find. And there’s support for 5G, of course, which is largely underwhelming in the US right now, but might actually be good toward the end of this phone’s lifespan. It all adds up to a $499 price that’s just under the wire for this category, though the Verizon version, unfortunately, costs $100 more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ll5Zxc"&gt;The Pixel 4A 5G has a slightly better camera system compared to the Pixel 4A, thanks to the inclusion of an ultrawide sensor. Google has also made its excellent Night Sight mode automatic and improved video with some new stabilization modes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0i98AR"&gt;Otherwise, it follows the standard low-cost Pixel formula. It has a plastic back with a fingerprint sensor and a headphone jack. Google doesn’t load down the software with extra crapware you don’t want, but it does include some nice little touches like a voice recorder that automatically creates a transcription as it records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CvxYa1"&gt;Someday, not having 5G will be a serious downside for smartphones, but that reality is still at least a year or two away. Even if you ignore the potentially faster network speeds, the Pixel 4A 5G is a surprisingly great phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="z78Vx3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9503882"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="nkRaIa"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BXMhOf_K6HW_6jVKD9akUraWoYk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22214229/ajohnson200104_4354_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The N10 5G is priced well under $500.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2pPPrl"&gt;5. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22214280/oneplus-nord-n10-5g-review"&gt;OnePlus Nord N10 5G&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="qyzV16"&gt;If you want 5G for the least amount possible&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="0wGhHB"&gt;At $299, the N10 5G is well below the threshold for this category. Given its price, you might expect to see some significant sacrifices compared to a $400 or $500 phone, and OnePlus has made a few. But they’re smart sacrifices that add up to a device that’s really quite good for the money. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vb4uVX"&gt;You won’t find a fantastic screen here, although its large 6.46-inch LCD does come with a faster-than-average 90Hz refresh rate. Worth noting is the device’s somewhat “tall” 20:9 aspect ratio, which is a little unusual at first glance but makes the phone slightly narrower and easier to use with one hand. Its processor is capable enough, though it sometimes shows its limits. It also ships with Android 10, which OnePlus says it will update to 11, and is only offering two years of security updates in addition to that.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VXW2WO"&gt;On the camera side, the N10 offers a 64-megapixel main camera that’s surprisingly good in daylight and even moderately low light. There’s an 8-megapixel ultrawide, too, along with macro and monochrome cameras that aren’t really worth talking about. It’s not Pixel 4A-level good, but if you don’t push it too hard, the N10’s main camera takes good photos in the right light. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y00B08"&gt;If you can afford to spend a little more, you probably should. A device with better support in the long run will save you some money later. But if budget is a major consideration, the N10 5G is about as good as it gets at this price. It offers the future-proofiness of sub-6GHz 5G support, a thoroughly decent camera, good battery life, a capable processor, and a fairly clean implementation of Android. It’s not a standout in any one way, but as a total package, it’s very hard to argue with its capabilities at this price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2zE49h"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10348332"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="BDpLQj"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Samsung Galaxy A51 has a huge screen and is otherwise a pretty decent phone." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r6gGzxS0kO-_Qkwy_XyWUOyb1Jo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19951824/vpavic_052004_4007_0022.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Galaxy A51 offers an excellent screen for the price.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="CzLtDJ"&gt;6. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21251569/samsung-galaxy-a51-review-price-screen-camera-battery-life"&gt;Samsung Galaxy A51&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="KnMCx2"&gt;The best phone if you want a big screen&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="T9fywV"&gt;Samsung’s $399 Galaxy A51 Android phone may well turn out to be the bestselling phone of 2020. Its predecessor, the Galaxy A50, outshone all expectations. For the A51, Samsung focused on nailing a big screen, good battery life, and the camera. It got the screen just right; the other two are just fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rJX5CI"&gt;The 6.5-inch OLED display on the A51 is bright and vivid, and you’d have to be pretty persnickety to find fault in it. It doesn’t offer the same high refresh rate you can get on the OnePlus Nord, but it makes up for that with Samsung’s great quality. If there’s one weird thing about the screen, it’s that Samsung put a chrome bezel around the hole punch for the front-facing selfie camera. It’s distracting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pCdhK7"&gt;The A51 sports nice build quality, though you can definitely feel that it’s plastic on the back. It has a headphone jack and 128GB of storage, which is the number you should be aiming for on any phone these days. Battery life should be superb, thanks to a 4,000mAh battery, but because it has to power that big screen, it nets out to being just so-so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jy99L8"&gt;As is becoming a (weird) standard on this class of phone, the A51 has a regular wide-angle, an ultrawide, a depth sensor, and a macro camera. And as is also standard, the regular wide-angle will get you the best images. The A51 can’t beat the Pixel 4A for quality, but the different lens options might be more fun for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ryPHx5"&gt;Samsung recently committed to providing the A51 with three generations of Android software updates, which is great news. Less great is that it usually takes Samsung longer than you may like to get software updates out to the A-line of phones. Samsung has also started to junk up its previously elegant One UI software interface with ads and other junkware, so be prepared to do some cleanup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HNhSDh"&gt;On the whole, though, what the A51 gets you is a very big, very beautiful screen. If that’s your highest priority — and for many people, it is — the A51 is a solid choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="HgXPEc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9556648"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="gqTSBC"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0vEWlb7XvHUYvgaOoRi3Ex_G3cw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22290840/ajohnson_210205_4399_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 2021 Moto G Power offers days-long battery performance but makes a lot of sacrifices for it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Qq9tmB"&gt;7. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22268805/motorola-moto-g-power-2021-review"&gt;Motorola Moto G Power (2021)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="tXDuyi"&gt;The phone with maximum battery life&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="NSb4tw"&gt;The Moto G Power does exactly what it says it will: provide days and days of power on a single charge, thanks to its larger-than-average 5,000mAh battery. This is a slightly different version of last year’s phone with the same name, and it starts at a lower $200 price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H7tVXv"&gt;The lower price tag does come with trade-offs. It includes just 32GB of built-in storage, so adding a microSD card for some extra space is a must. There’s also a slightly slower processor on board, and while it’s capable enough for all of your daily needs, it’s a little laggy jumping between apps and opening the camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8syWIE"&gt;As for the camera: it’s just okay. Motorola did away with the ultrawide in this year’s models, so you’ll just be working with the 48-megapixel standard wide and 2-megapixel macro cameras in addition to an 8-megapixel selfie cam. Photos in bright outdoor light look good with plenty of detail, though colors can be a little washed out. The camera struggles with high-contrast scenes and low light, but all things considered, it’s fine for a $200 phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5bJEGA"&gt;If top-notch battery performance is an extremely important feature in your smartphone, then the Moto G Power should be on your shortlist. It’s capable, and you really will get multiple days of battery life on a charge. But if you’re fine getting by on a battery that’s just average, then we think you’ll be happier with a more well-rounded device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="cyQK5V"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10348305"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8QnTKL"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21420196/best-budget-smartphone-cheap"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21420196/best-budget-smartphone-cheap</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-19T08:30:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-19T08:30:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>Oppo Find X3 Neo leaks, showing off third handset in upcoming X3 lineup  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IYPAfAMFk3RMlM4_Q-6O4iJlpfg=/0x0:1078x719/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68841745/find_x3_neo.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Oppo Find X3 Neo.&lt;/em&gt; | &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.nieuwemobiel.nl/022356/16021/Exclusief-Alle-persafbeeldingen-van-de-Oppo-Find-X3-Neo-5G.html" target="_blank"&gt;NieuweMobiel.nl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zoieCF"&gt;Images of the unannounced Oppo Find X3 Neo have leaked again, this time giving us our best look yet at the third phone in Oppo’s upcoming Find X3 phone lineup, &lt;a href="https://www.nieuwemobiel.nl/022356/16021/Exclusief-Alle-persafbeeldingen-van-de-Oppo-Find-X3-Neo-5G.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;NieuweMobiel.nl&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;. As tipster Evan Blass has &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1362703973522751489"&gt;subsequently pointed out&lt;/a&gt;, the handset appears to be a rebranded version of Oppo’s Reno5 Pro Plus 5G. The phone is expected to be announced next month alongside the Find X3 Pro and Find X3 Lite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JYnlF5"&gt;Since the Find X3 Neo is based on an existing phone, we already have a pretty good idea of what its specs might be. These include a Snapdragon 865 processor, 4,500mAh battery with 65W fast charging, and a 6.55-inch 90Hz OLED display. Around back there are four cameras: a 50-megapixel wide-angle camera, a 13-megapixel telephoto, a 16-megapixel ultrawide, and a 2-megapixel macro. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dNZCj4JGf0QZIF5sOLHXEy2sSiU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22314505/find_x3_pro.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.voice.com/post/@evan/oppo-find-x3-pro-first-official-images-1610466378-772606832" target="_blank"&gt;Evan Blass / &lt;em&gt;Voice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Oppo Find X3 Pro.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4LVmcn_D8aqFgjAdAfOE-_eIeBA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22314504/find_x3_pro_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.voice.com/post/@evan/oppo-find-x3-pro-first-official-images-1610466378-772606832" target="_blank"&gt;Evan Blass / &lt;em&gt;Voice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Oppo Find X3 Pro.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MyuaG6"&gt;The Find X3 Pro, meanwhile, appears to be an all-new device. Blass detailed many of its features in a &lt;a href="https://www.voice.com/post/@evan/oppo-find-x3-pro-fussi-detailed-1607361964-1"&gt;post on &lt;em&gt;Voice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; last December, noting that it’ll be powered by a Snapdragon 888 processor and will have a 6.7-inch 1440p display with a dynamic refresh rate that goes up to 120Hz. It also has a 4,500mAh battery with support for 65W fast charging, but it’ll also be able to wirelessly charge at up to 30W.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N91mR7"&gt;The Find X3 Pro’s cameras are particularly interesting. It’s reportedly got a pair of 50-megapixel sensors — one wide-angle and one ultrawide — as well as a 13-megapixel camera with a 2x optical zoom and a 3-megapixel macro camera. According to Blass, this macro camera could offer a 25x zoom, allowing it to work like a microscope. Check out more images of the upcoming phone &lt;a href="https://www.voice.com/post/@evan/oppo-find-x3-pro-first-official-images-1610466378-772606832"&gt;over on &lt;em&gt;Voice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zf5BhLI2sGUiGBCv0D6e-TH8mQI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22314507/2a78e57b7f5cc9b6fc8073d395b216cfedd3bc70779c4acef193f98d73e40ba9.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.voice.com/post/@evan/oppo-find-x3-lite-will-be-a-reno5-rebadge-1610105255-1817111864" target="_blank"&gt;Evan Blass / &lt;em&gt;Voice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Oppo Find X3 Lite.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="lwBc52"&gt;Finally there’s the Find X3 Lite, which &lt;a href="https://www.voice.com/post/@evan/oppo-find-x3-lite-will-be-a-reno5-rebadge-1610105255-1817111864"&gt;Blass notes&lt;/a&gt; appears to be a rebranded Oppo Reno5 5G. That means it’s likely to have a 6.43-inch 90Hz OLED display and four rear cameras: a 64-megapixel wide camera, an 8-megapixel ultrawide, a 2-megapixel macro, and a 2-megapixel depth camera. Internally, it’ll be powered by a Snapdragon 765G, and there’s a 4,300mAh battery that’s also capable of 65W fast charging. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="91Z1yv"&gt;All three phones are expected to be announced soon, with a release in April.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/22290921/oppo-find-x3-neo-leaks-news-images-release-date-rumors-pro-lite"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/22290921/oppo-find-x3-neo-leaks-news-images-release-date-rumors-pro-lite</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-19T08:16:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-19T08:16:38-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple reportedly developing magnetic battery pack for iPhone</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AtM7sJ_nVFOMcQTgL86zzKsEotU=/0x0:1152x768/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68841695/magsafe_main_3_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The iPhone 12 was announced alongside a range of MagSafe accessories last year.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GkN3R9"&gt;Apple is reportedly developing a new iPhone charging accessory in the form of a battery pack that magnetically attaches to the rear of the device using MagSafe, &lt;a href="https://chorus.voxmedia.com/compose/ac4534a6-8226-4c02-89c8-89b7e0d3d439"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;. Although some prototypes have a rubber exterior, the battery pack isn’t thought to act as a protective case &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/1/18206642/apple-smart-battery-case-iphone-xs-xr-max-reveiw-test-specs-price-features"&gt;like previous iPhone battery accessories&lt;/a&gt; from Apple. Alongside details of the new battery case, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; also notes that the iPhone lineup is unlikely to receive support for reverse wireless charging anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aJdoq5"&gt;The battery pack accessory is thought to have been in development for at least a year, but it’s reportedly faced development issues relating to the iPhone’s software thinking that the pack is overheating. &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; notes that Apple is cautious about announcing charging accessories, after it was forced to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/3/29/18287383/apple-airpower-wireless-charger-cancelled"&gt;cancel its AirPower charging mat in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, a year and a half after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/12/16278310/apple-iphone-8-wireless-charging"&gt;it was first announced&lt;/a&gt;. Development problems could mean that the new battery pack accessory is delayed or even scrapped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Ro5Cht"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s reportedly faced development issues&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PfV6fm"&gt;The charging pack would be the latest in Apple’s lineup of iPhone 12 MagSafe accessories, which attach onto the back of the phone with the assistance of an embedded circle of magnets. Previous accessories have included wall chargers, as well as magnetically attaching wallets. MagSafe is said to be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/22/22244011/apple-new-macbook-air-design-magsafe-charger-report"&gt;returning to Apple’s laptops&lt;/a&gt; as well, only with a connector reminiscent of the old pill-shaped design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="joluiK"&gt;Rumors of the new battery pack first emerged after a reference to it was found in code in the iOS 14.5 beta, &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/02/16/everything-new-ios-14-5-beta-2/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; earlier this week. &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; notes that the reference has subsequently been removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KcHjrW"&gt;As well as the new battery pack, Apple is reportedly interested in allowing its devices to charge one another. &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; notes that it had planned for its 2019 iPhone lineup to be able to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/23/18278557/apple-iphone-11-wireless-charging-other-devices-airpods-watch-rumor"&gt;wirelessly charge AirPods&lt;/a&gt;, but the plans were later scrapped. The functionality is “unlikely in the near future,” according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WrqO9g"&gt;Other accessory manufacturers are already attempting to offer similar functionality to the rumored MagSafe battery pack. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/10/27/21536837/mophie-juice-pack-connect-wireless-battery-qi-charging"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; on one such pack late last year, which was being sold on Alibaba and Aliexpress under a variety of names.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/22290938/apple-magsafe-iphone-battery-pack-report"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/22290938/apple-magsafe-iphone-battery-pack-report</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-19T07:14:14-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-19T07:14:14-05:00</updated>
    <title>John Carmack proposes GPU and console auctions to beat scalpers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZflQw6v3-zCwLCo0bE4hy_omQjc=/7x0:2034x1351/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68841511/twarren_200909_4184_0016.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Tom Warren / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mbPvrk"&gt;John Carmack has proposed an auction system for popular gaming products like GPUs, the PS5, and Xbox Series X. Carmack, the co-founder of id software, believes “we really would be better off with a transparent auction system directly from the manufacturers and a more efficient market.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="clZ5q9"&gt;This type of auction system could be used to beat scalpers, who wouldn’t be willing to pay inflated prices on highly prized new products. “There would be much indignation at reported prices out of the gate, but removing intermediaries should net out better for consumers in the end,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ID_AA_Carmack/status/1362619560763949060"&gt;says Carmack on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9UXyoZ"&gt;Due to a global chip shortage and incredible demand, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/6/22155611/price-ps5-xbox-series-x-nvidia-rtx-3080-3070-3090-3060-amd-rx-6800-xt-scalpers-ebay"&gt;true price of a PS5 was more than $1,000 in December&lt;/a&gt;, and RTX 3080s were selling for $1,227 instead of the $699 sticker price. Even older graphics cards are sold out right now, and resale value on eBay is climbing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="80IXab"&gt;Nvidia is even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278562/nvidia-rtx-2060-gtx-1050-ti-gpu-shortage-global-chip"&gt;bringing back&lt;/a&gt; its old RTX 2060 and GTX 1050 Ti GPUs to deal with this global chip shortage. The supply situation looks set to last for months, too. Microsoft has warned the Xbox Series X will be in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260564/microsoft-xbox-series-x-stock-june-supply-constraints"&gt;short supply until June&lt;/a&gt;, and Nvidia says its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227040/nvidia-amd-gpu-shortage-rtx-3080-3070-3060-ti-3090-rx-6800-xt"&gt;supplies will be lean&lt;/a&gt; until at least May. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/l9kx3eg8rATAf8MoroOdTwtkjR4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21868764/twarren_rtx3080.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Tom Warren / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nvidia’s RTX 3080 has been in high demand.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="zQWct1"&gt;Supply constraints are obviously a problem, but Nvidia revealed last month that its $499-and-up RTX 30-series GPUs have sold almost twice as much as the RTX 20-series did after the same amount of time. A lot of people are clearly trying to upgrade their PCs, and even the PS5 has been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/3/22263821/sony-earnings-q3-2020-ps5-launch-sales"&gt;selling just as well as the PS4&lt;/a&gt; did during its launch period despite the supply constraints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZF5427"&gt;An auction system may cut out the scalpers who try to profit off this supply and demand cycle, but unless every manufacturer participates then it’s unlikely to have a significant impact. We’ve seen many attempts at stopping scalpers, including retailers with their own queue systems, or through bundling these new GPUs and consoles with additional products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mYqas9"&gt;All of the latest AMD and Nvidia GPUs can still be found at inflated prices on eBay, and additional taxes on graphics cards imported from China have also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22217206/nvidia-amd-gpu-trump-tax-china-tariff-exemption-expire"&gt;bumped up the prices in the US&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UnCSBz"&gt;Nvidia is even trying to tackle the demand for its upcoming $329 RTX 3060 graphics card by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289154/nvidia-rtx-3060-ethereum-mining-drivers-limit-cryptocurrency"&gt;making it less appealing to Ethereum cryptocurrency miners&lt;/a&gt;. The drivers that you need for the RTX 3060 to work will nerf the hash rate of Ethereum mining by around 50 percent, to make the cards more focused on gaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qVSEkk"&gt;Carmack isn’t a fan of Nvidia’s latest approach. “What a terrible engineering task to give someone — figure out when we are being used for this thing we are quite good at, and break it,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ID_AA_Carmack/status/1362525734946840578"&gt;said Carmack on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/22290905/john-carmack-gpu-console-auctions-proposal-scalpers"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/22290905/john-carmack-gpu-console-auctions-proposal-scalpers</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-19T06:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-19T06:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Acast acquires RadioPublic to become the biggest podcasting company in the US</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YiUFHkXK5yiY5oR-JC1Vz-T9-iA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68841309/acast_radiopublic.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Acast&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eemai7"&gt;Acast, a podcast host and ad network, is looking to improve its tech and broaden its reach. The company announced today that it’s acquiring RadioPublic for an undisclosed amount with the goal of using RadioPublic’s tech to bring more creators to the Acast platform and make inroads in the US market. RadioPublic’s podcast app will remain live, and its team will stay based in the US. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D4mXGP"&gt;Among the tools that RadioPublic created — and that intrigued Acast — is something called Podsite, which helps podcasters set up a complimentary website for their show as well as a feature called &lt;a href="https://about.radiopublic.com/2017/09/12/introducing-affinity-promotions-for-podcasts-on-radiopublic/"&gt;Affinity Promotions&lt;/a&gt;, which helps podcasters target their most loyal listeners with text-based messages. They can use these messages to promote a newsletter, for example, or highlight new merch. RadioPublic, more than anything else, homed in on podcast creators and designed tools especially for them, similarly to Acast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BJ8gej"&gt;The Acast team operates a hosting platform, ad network, and listening app and is mostly interested in the creator side of the business. It &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/10/21557233/patreon-acast-podcasters-rss-feed-private-subscribers"&gt;partnered with Patreon&lt;/a&gt; to host its users’ shows and more easily distribute their private RSS feeds, as one example, and it makes hosting free at its most basic level. And while RadioPublic understands the US podcasting market well, which Acast plans to target moving forward, Acast is better known in other places around the world, which RadioPublic would like to reach. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VcM1we"&gt;“I think it was a match made in heaven,” says Leandro Saucedo, Acast’s chief business and strategy officer, in an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. He also points out that beyond RadioPublic’s consumer-facing tools, their technology was superb. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JSy7d6"&gt;“It’s hard for me to explain because you get so down to the technical side, but let’s say  within the car that’s Acast there’s a gearbox, which you never see but you definitely feel it if you drive, and there’s some nice gearbox stuff in RadioPublic that you wouldn’t think of, but once we put that gearbox into our car, our car runs smoother,” he says. “I think there’s a lot of that behind the scenes, which really makes sense for us, which is deep tech within the realm of podcasts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="naxEH5"&gt;Broadly, Acast’s goals mirror Spotify’s. The team wants to bring as many creators to its platform as possible so that it can learn from their data and monetize their programming by selling ads through its advertiser marketplace. The more shows it has, the larger inventory it can sell. Spotify, comparatively, has tried to create a similar situation through Anchor and Megaphone, which offer sponsorships and access to an ad marketplace, respectively. The only difference in Spotify’s case is Anchor itself, which makes creating a show easier through software. Acast hasn’t focused on the actual creation toolset yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vbGARX"&gt;Still, Saucedo claims to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that Acast is “the largest podcasting business in the world,” based on its revenue and investments. He says he can’t share specifics but points to the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/acast"&gt;$120 million in funding&lt;/a&gt; and says that, if backtracked, someone could figure out the brand’s valuation, which he wouldn’t divulge. Whether Saucedo is accurate in his claim is somewhat irrelevant, as it speaks to Acast’s ambitions and the wider race to the top in podcasting. Everyone wants to capture the podcast advertising market and ride that revenue to being the biggest name in podcasting. Acast is taking its shot now, and RadioPublic is one way it thinks it’ll win.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/22289742/acast-radiopublic-podcasting-platform-acquisition"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/22289742/acast-radiopublic-podcasting-platform-acquisition</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-19T05:20:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-19T05:20:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>Uber loses final appeal against drivers’ employment status in UK</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Gg5tguUBRywFIgBrxq-aGhnqLIo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68841287/acastro_180927_1777_uber_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="y6AOnK"&gt;Uber has lost the final appeal in a long running UK legal battle over whether its drivers are self-employed or legally-recognized workers with all the attendant rights, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-02-19/uber-loses-u-k-top-court-ruling-on-drivers-employment-status?utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_content=business&amp;amp;cmpid=socialflow-twitter-business&amp;amp;utm_campaign=socialflow-organic&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;. The ruling is the conclusion of the company’s five-year legal fight in the country and a major setback for Uber that could affect all gig workers in the UK, regardless of employer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cyBrsS"&gt;Today, the UK’s Supreme Court ruled that Uber drivers are, indeed, workers, confirming the decision made by three lower courts. The unanimous decision means that drivers are entitled to a minimum wage, paid holiday, and other legal protections. Judge George Leggatt said Uber drivers working time isn’t limited to time spent driving passengers, but also “includes any period when a driver is logged into the app and ready and willing to accept trips.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="VXS5JL"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The ruling dates back to a case from 2016&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UXd6GV"&gt;The ruling could have a significant impact on the UK’s estimated 4.7 million gig economy workers, affecting not just tech giants like Uber and food delivery firm Deliveroo, but also less well known companies like couriers CitySprint and plumbing outfit Pimlico Plumbers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ayPTkm"&gt;In response to the ruling, Uber’s regional general manager for northern and eastern Europe Jamie Heywood said that the company respect’s the court’s decision, but added that it “focused on a small number of drivers who used the Uber app in 2016,” and that the ruling doesn’t reclassify all of its UK drivers as workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eAWDLF"&gt;“Since then we have made some significant changes to our business, guided by drivers every step of the way,” Heywood said. “These include giving even more control over how they earn and providing new protections like free insurance in case of sickness or injury. We are committed to doing more and will now consult with every active driver across the UK to understand the changes they want to see.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kNVu1F"&gt;In a &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.uber.com%2Fen-GB%2Fblog%2Fsupreme-court-verdict&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F19%2F21330906%2Fuber-uk-supreme-court-employee-rights" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, Uber said that the ruling classifies the drivers as “workers” rather than “employees,” which is a legally distinct category. It also says that certain elements of its service which were described in the judgement no longer apply, including penalties for drivers who reject multiple trips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XSmLyY"&gt;The original case against Uber was brought in 2016 by two drivers for the company, James Farrar and Yaseen Aslam. They argued that Uber controlled nearly all the aspects of their working conditions, including who they could accept for rides and how much they would be paid, meaning the company was acting as their employer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u0ezZZ"&gt;Uber lost three cases against Farrar and Aslam in 2016, 2017, and 2018. But today’s judgement from the Supreme Court, the UK’s final court of appeal, ends their legal options. The dispute will now return to a specialty tribunal, according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;, which will decide how much to award the 25 drivers. Uber also faces another 1,000 similar claims that had been stayed pending today’s ruling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="emREnN"&gt;In a statement, the GMB Union, which helped bring the case against Uber, welcomed the “historic” win. “The Supreme Court has upheld the decision of three previous courts, backing up what GMB has said all along; Uber drivers are workers and entitled to breaks, holiday pay and minimum wage,” Mick Rix, GMB national officer, said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BO75f2"&gt;“Uber must now stop wasting time and money pursuing lost legal causes and do what’s right by the drivers who prop up its empire,” Rix said, adding that the union now plans to work towards helping its members claim compensation.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/21330906/uber-uk-supreme-court-employee-rights"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/21330906/uber-uk-supreme-court-employee-rights</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
