<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-15T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-15T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-15T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google Earth’s historical 3D time lapses show the ravages of climate change</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AKUECUrVZMurM19yggRdP3it2Z8=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69130042/Columbia_Glacier_BG_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7mgBvj"&gt;Google Earth is getting a new 3D time-lapse feature that lets you observe how Earth has changed from 1984 to 2020, allowing you to see just how much the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/28/20836891/amazon-fires-brazil-bolsonaro-rainforest-deforestation-analysis-effects"&gt;devastating&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/9/18302006/sea-level-rise-charleston-norfolk-glaciers-climate-change-the-weather-channel"&gt;effects&lt;/a&gt; of climate change have already shaped the geography of the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="221byq"&gt;“It’s best for a landscape view of our world,” Rebecca Moore, director of Google Earth, Google Earth Engine, and Google Earth Outreach, said in a call with reporters this week. “It’s not about zooming in. It’s about zooming out. It’s about taking the big step back. We need to see how our only home is doing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0nFcaS"&gt;The feature (which Google calls “Timelapse,” one word) will be available in Google Earth starting Thursday. To access it, &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/earth/"&gt;launch Google Earth&lt;/a&gt; and then click or tap on the Voyager tab (which has an icon that looks like a ship’s wheel). You can search for a place of interest or check out one of Google’s five “guided tours” about forest change, urban growth, warming temperatures, mining and renewable energy sources, and “the Earth’s fragile beauty.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VnR2R6"&gt;To get an idea of what the feature lets you see, check out this time lapse GIF of the changing shores of Cape Cod, Massachusetts, from Google:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/INCb1q_ptJMtI0pzQvOMG2u5r7w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22445675/Chatham_Massachusetts_US.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="tk3Lsc"&gt;Or this GIF of the Columbia Glacier’s retreat:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/G_R-M06J9mkhCfKouOsoYkbZlb4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22445668/Columbia_Glacier___Timelapse_in_Google_Earth.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7MwhCV"&gt;To create the 3D time-lapse imagery for Google Earth, the company says it used more than 24 million satellite images taken from 1984 to 2020 to create one 4.4 terapixel-sized video mosaic. (To give you a sense of the scale there, one terapixel is 1 million megapixels.) The company worked with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/20/21583468/nasa-launch-satellite-sea-level-rise-climate-change-esa"&gt;NASA&lt;/a&gt;, the US Geological Survey (USGS), the European Commission, and the European Space Agency (ESA) to collect the data used in the time lapses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mhp9Ba"&gt;“Timelapse and Google Earth sits at the nexus of science, technology, public-private partnerships, and the next generation as we think about both climate change and climate action,” Moore said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Retdtl"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5W-zPqrGQWA?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0VQQX5"&gt;This isn’t the Google Earth team’s first time-lapse feature. In May 2013, the team released a &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/earth/a-picture-of-earth-through-time/"&gt;time-lapse feature displaying 2D images of Earth&lt;/a&gt; from 1984 to 2012, and it made &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/11/29/13785130/google-earth-timelapse-climate-change-effects"&gt;a big update to that in November 2016&lt;/a&gt;. The feature announced Thursday, however, offers a &lt;em&gt;3D&lt;/em&gt; time lapse of the Earth’s geological changes, allowing you to look at the changes in the Earth in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VlqN89"&gt;Google has also released 800 time-lapse videos of different areas around the planet as free downloads. The company aims for them to be used by teachers, nonprofits, policymakers, and others to show how the geography of Earth has changed over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ht6z3W"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22383964/google-earth-3d-timelapse-climate-change"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22383964/google-earth-3d-timelapse-climate-change</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-15T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-15T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>DJI’s new Mavic Air 2S comes with one big upgrade</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;A much better camera in a familiar body&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="cZwNJy"&gt;Despite it not even being a year old, DJI is already upgrading its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21243887/dji-mavic-air-2-2020-drone-flight-photography-video-review-price-specs-features"&gt;mid-tier Mavic Air 2 drone&lt;/a&gt;. The new $999 Mavic Air 2S (yes, $200 more than the prior model) comes with some notable new features and upgrades, including a much larger image sensor. The new one-inch sensor is capable of shooting 20-megapixel photos, 5.4K video, and 4K up to 60fps. But hold your horses (or wallets), there are a few caveats to those impressive capabilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="UvEyLu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10447814"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CF4isw"&gt;The Mavic Air 2S’s camera sensor is the same size as what you get in the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/6/17826384/dji-mavic-2-pro-zoom-drone-review-specs-price"&gt;higher-end Mavic 2 Pro&lt;/a&gt;. It’s much larger than the half-inch sensor used in last year’s Air 2. The Air 2S should shoot almost equally good photos and better video as the Mavic 2 Pro, at least on paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7M29Hx"&gt;The Air 2S’s maximum video resolution is 5.4K, versus 4K on the Mavic 2 Pro. And the Air 2S’s 4K video even has a higher bit rate — 150Mbps compared to 100Mbps. Lastly, the Air 2S’s 4K video also has a higher frame rate. All of those are nice upgrades over what you get in the more expensive model, not to mention the benefits of the smaller Air 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5okd3g"&gt;Once you switch to 4K 60fps, though, the highest 4K frame rate you can capture, there will be some significant cropping because it isn’t using the full one-inch sensor in that mode. It looks roughly like a 1.3x crop to my eyes, but DJI wouldn’t confirm exactly how much crop there is. That shouldn’t discourage you from using 4K / 60fps. The video quality still holds up and the image looks great in the final result. But if you’re just comparing spec sheets, you won’t see that there’s a crop in this mode. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V6dnbV"&gt;That also might explain why the Air 2S has a slightly wider focal length than others in the Mavic lineup. When using the full one-inch sensor, the focal length is 22mm. Typically, DJI drones are either 24 or 28mm. I personally like the slightly wider look, but if you prefer a tighter composition, you can use the built-in digital zoom or crop in edit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/17fZ_qXXOReTk-dgI2PMvRSQWAg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22443889/vpavic_210413_4527_0070.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s no optical zoom on the Air 2S, but the digital zoom is very useful.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xakJiG"&gt;The digital zoom availability depends on which shooting mode you’re in. In 1080p / 60fps, you can zoom 6x; 1080p / 30fps lets you zoom 8x; 4K / 60 up to 3x; 4K / 30 has 4x zoom; and lastly there’s no digital zoom at all when in 5.4K. Historically, digital zoom is not something that tickles my fancy, but having a one-inch sensor with a max resolution of 5.4K really helps here and the loss in quality isn’t that steep. Even at 3x, you can capture some very usable footage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eo5miI"&gt;However, here’s where we get to another caveat: none of this matters if you’re filming in D-Log or HDR because you can’t zoom in while shooting in any of those color profiles, only the standard color profile. You have to do all your zooming and cropping again after the fact in the edit when you shoot in either of these modes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vLL58v"&gt;Also, you can’t use the digital zoom at all while taking photos, which is a bit perplexing.  There’s another caveat between color profiles: the maximum ISO in D-Log color profile is 1600, while the standard color profile goes up to 3200. For comparison, the Mavic 2 Pro’s max ISO in standard color profile is 6400. It’s not a dealbreaker, but like the 4K 60 crop, it’s good to be aware of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QErhv_-UvYrRNzmzwV4gcR4X5Ls=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22443893/vpavic_210413_4527_0096.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Air 2S and the Mavic 2 Pro both share a one-inch sensor, but there are many differences between the two cameras.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Wb4P82"&gt;The Air 2S also debuts a new automated flight mode called SmartShots. Once you activate it, the drone takes a few minutes to capture a few pre-programmed videos. It has options like wide circular shots, tight circular shots, dronies, top-downs, and so on. It records five to ten “must-have” clips, and the app automatically generates a short edit. It’s like the slideshows on GoPro’s Quik iOS app but for drones. It’s a great option for less experienced pilots who just want something reliable and easy to share with their friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zo8AS5"&gt;One big selling point of the Air 2 was the ability to shoot 48-megapixel photos with the help of pixel binning. You won’t have that option here, but I’d always choose sensor size over pure resolution, and the Mavic Air 2S proved me right. The photos look phenomenal. As someone who prefers taking drone photos over video, having a one-inch sensor in a smaller body than the Mavic 2 Pro is a dream come true. Both drones take 20-megapixel photos, but there are a few noticeable differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lsbo9h"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10447034"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="r68TZl"&gt;There’s the focal length I mentioned earlier, but also the dynamic range on the 2 Pro is better. It offers 14 stops compared to 12.4 stops on the new Air 2S, which helps keep your sky from blowing out in high-contrast scenes. Sure, you lose a bit of information to work with, but the difference is not super noticeable. Photos look impressive at both low and higher ISOs. You’ll also be missing out on that Hasselblad color science, if that’s worth anything to you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qsoScm"&gt;The Mavic 2 Pro does have one big feature over the Air 2S: adjustable aperture. That’s useful for both photos and video and gives you another control point when trying to nail the perfect exposure. On the Air 2S, the only controls you have are for ISO and shutter speed, so DJI has included a set of ND filters in its Fly More bundle ($1,299, also includes extra batteries and other accessories) to allow you to limit the amount of light coming into the lens. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FUXuFF"&gt;There is also a small change to the hyperlapse mode. You can no longer get 8K hyperlapse exports like you did on the Mavic Air 2 — only 4K or below since the max photo resolution is 20MP. That export now has an additional post stabilization applied, but it’s not perfect; I still saw some unwanted shake in a few of the videos I recorded. I’d still recommend running another stabilizer in post.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hR9rd-hdti3y9lyeY_IjSi5Q9Z4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22443891/vpavic_210413_4527_0081.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The two new APAS sensors sit above the front sensors and help with obstacle detection at higher speeds.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LgiSrg"&gt;Most of the hardware on the Air 2S is identical to the Air 2, but there’s an extra set of sensors that sit right at the top of the drone to help with obstacle detection and avoidance, especially at higher speeds. DJI is calling this APAS (Advanced Pilot Assistance System) 4.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nfcD6C"&gt;Obstacle avoidance is a thing you need to manually turn on and you pick how you want your drone to act — either it’ll brake in front of an obstacle or try to go around it. In my testing, the drone was a bit more hesitant than I anticipated. It would often choose to brake in front of obstacles instead of avoiding them. Again, there’s a caveat here: APAS or focus tracking won’t work in modes above 4K 30fps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PUzWtD1XYM0VeGp_raM9v_b_QHw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22443885/vpavic_210411_4527_0029.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Mavic Air 2S has a slightly worse battery than its predecessor: 31 minutes compared to 34 on the Air 2.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CefPBeiOOPI8FYkqFIBYHmRsma4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22443886/vpavic_210412_4527_0036.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Fly More combo now also comes with a set of four ND filters.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="p5zvak"&gt;It’s encouraging to see some extra attention in that area, but DJI is nowhere near Skydio when it comes to autonomous flights. This is still only a safety option, not something that will help you get smooth shots while narrowly avoiding obstacles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pZq36B"&gt;Lastly, all the upgrades come with a slight hit on battery life. DJI rates the battery at 31 minutes of flight time compared to the 34 minutes on the previous Mavic Air 2. It’s a fair compromise, and I haven’t noticed it impacting my approach to flying. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2lJC7R"&gt;Despite some odd limitations in its features, the Mavic Air 2S is still a fantastic drone, especially for beginners who want something more capable than a DJI Mini 2. There are a few trade-offs compared to the Mavic 2 Pro, but frankly, most people will be okay with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="Q9xJsb"&gt;I recently wrote about how the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22277238/dji-mini-2-drone-review-price-specs-features"&gt;underestimated Mini 2&lt;/a&gt; became my favorite drone due to its unmatched portability and &lt;em&gt;better than expected&lt;/em&gt; image quality. The Air 2S nearly took that title away. If you prioritize image quality, it’s an obvious choice provided you can stomach the extra hit to your wallet. The Mavic Air 2S now has the perfect balance between a compact size and great image quality, despite all of the asterisks and caveats it may have.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="HW9xIV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10447092"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6dWrJ4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22384692/dji-mavic-air-2s-drone-2021-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22384692/dji-mavic-air-2s-drone-2021-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Vjeran Pavic</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-15T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-15T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Lyft launches health care transportation program </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nvC2vFF-HEuu3-c76i7wJrzySAY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69129666/acastro_180927_1777_lyft_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GAoqDy"&gt;Lyft launched a program that will let health care organizations send patients prepaid passes that they can use for rides to doctor’s appointments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7hjLRW"&gt;“We’ve automated an important piece of health access that allows patients to be self-sufficient and in control, while allowing our partners to focus on the services they provide, rather than on administrative processes,” said Megan Callahan, vice president of Lyft Healthcare, in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bxhwqR"&gt;The program, called Lyft Pass for Healthcare, lets health care organizations or social services agencies create a budget and set approved pickup and drop-off locations. They can share the pass with patients, who can apply it to their ride. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2geVG4"&gt;Non-emergency medical transportation is &lt;a href="https://www.kff.org/medicaid/issue-brief/medicaid-non-emergency-medical-transportation-overview-and-key-issues-in-medicaid-expansion-waivers/"&gt;estimated&lt;/a&gt; to be a $3 billion market. Transportation is a major &lt;a href="https://ajph.aphapublications.org/doi/10.2105/AJPH.2020.305579"&gt;barrier to health care&lt;/a&gt;, and millions of people each year put off medical appointments because they don’t have a way to get to them. Lyft &lt;a href="https://www.lyftbusiness.com/industries/healthcare"&gt;already partners with&lt;/a&gt; a number of health care organizations to schedule trips for patients, but the new program aims to make it easier for patients to request trips themselves in the app, rather than wait for the health system to schedule them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L6p5UJ"&gt;Uber has a similar medical transportation program. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/1/17061862/uber-health-non-emergency-medical-transportation-hipaa"&gt;Uber Health&lt;/a&gt;, which launched in 2018, also lets health care providers book rides for patients. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ckwmO1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22383498/lyft-health-care-rides-doctor"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22383498/lyft-health-care-rides-doctor</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-15T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-15T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>In an about-face, Xfinity Mobile will offer discounts on additional unlimited plan lines</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uZAn9hFCgK1qnzrWebEU7RaqtGs=/89x0:2519x1620/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69129670/xfinity_mobile_laydown_6_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Xfinity Mobile offers cell service on Verizon’s network in addition to 20 million Wi-Fi hotspots across the country.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Xfinity Mobile&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aNvg2F"&gt;Comcast’s wireless service, Xfinity Mobile, is changing the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xfinity.com%2Fmobile%2Flearn%2Fplan&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F15%2F22384272%2Fxfinity-mobile-unlimited-plan-5g" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;pricing structure on its unlimited plans&lt;/a&gt;. The company will now discount additional lines on its unlimited plan: a single-line plan will still cost $45 per month, but additional lines become cheaper the more you add. With four lines on a plan, you’ll pay $30 per month per line. That’s in contrast to a previous policy of charging the same fee per line, regardless of the number of lines on a plan &lt;em&gt;—&lt;/em&gt; a practice touted on its website as recently as yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rGqz8U"&gt;The company points out that its $45 per month unlimited plan is still cheaper than single-line plans among the major wireless carriers, which is true: postpaid unlimited plans from the big three cost between $60 and $70 per month. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/goejcoTYS5PtgGqTzo0WSflEtQM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22444379/Screen_Shot_2021_04_14_at_12.43.02_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Xfinity Mobile&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Until recently, single-line customers on Xfinity Mobile enjoyed the same per-line pricing as subscribers with multiple lines, as touted on the company’s website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="lZwEkn"&gt;But it’s also worth noting that Xfinity Mobile reduces speeds on all of its unlimited plans once a user reaches 20GB of data per month, which isn’t something you’ll see on the major carriers’ plans. That’s separate from the temporary slowdowns customers might experience when the network is busy, which is a fairly common policy across network providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GLw2mX"&gt;Prices for its “By the Gig” metered plans remain the same: 1GB for $15, 3GB for $30, and 10GB for $60. It’s also still possible to mix data-capped and unlimited lines on the same plan. This isn’t the first time Xfinity Mobile, which operates on Verizon’s network, has changed pricing policies: in 2019, it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/1/20750181/xfinity-mobile-hd-pass-unlimited-plan-extra-fee"&gt;began charging a fee&lt;/a&gt; to add HD streaming to accounts. Previously, it had capped streaming video resolution at 480p but would waive this limitation at no cost on request. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="8FKpIm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Cellphone plan fine print, explained","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/31/22360228/unlimited-plan-verizon-att-t-mobile-premium-data-tethering-limits"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="tFQLp3"&gt;To be fair, both this change and the new unlimited plan pricing structure follow standard practices across the industry. Most unlimited plans limit streaming video to 480p, and all major wireless carriers charge more per line on single versus multiple-line plans. For a change, Comcast isn’t inventing creative new ways to make your bill more confusing — it’s just going with the flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TIuJFI"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclosure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Comcast is an investor in Vox Media, The Verge’s parent company.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22384272/xfinity-mobile-unlimited-plan-5g"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22384272/xfinity-mobile-unlimited-plan-5g</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-15T07:46:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-15T07:46:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nvidia warns the great GPU shortage will continue throughout 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M5UTV2MkGhIYN7SFDId_07AIq9Y=/8x0:2632x1749/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69129615/twarren_rtx3080.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Tom Warren / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tiEQDe"&gt;If you were hoping to pickup a new RTX 30-series GPU in the coming months, Nvidia is warning about supply shortages for the rest of 2021. “We expect demand to continue to exceed supply for much of this year,” said Colette Kress, Nvidia CFO, on an &lt;a href="https://nvidianews.nvidia.com/news/nvidia-announces-first-quarter-fiscal-2022-revenue-tracking-above-outlook?ncid=afm-chs-44270&amp;amp;ranMID=44270&amp;amp;ranEAID=kXQk6*ivFEQ&amp;amp;ranSiteID=kXQk6.ivFEQ-u_56nr2EJ2TBzDSKQ9NTsg"&gt;investors call earlier this week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pzGEDh"&gt;That means the difficulties of finding a new 30-series GPU will likely continue, possibly into 2022. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227040/nvidia-amd-gpu-shortage-rtx-3080-3070-3060-ti-3090-rx-6800-xt"&gt;Nvidia previously warned&lt;/a&gt; that supplies would “likely remain lean” through its fiscal Q1, and now that we’re approaching that milestone (end of April) it’s clear that supply hasn’t improved significantly to meet demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uw36tF"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22385240/tsmc-chip-shortage-2022-intel-ceo-earnings-graphics-cards-cpus-gpus"&gt;TSMC and Intel are also both warning&lt;/a&gt; that chip supply issues could last through 2022. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22368552/global-chip-shortage-end-tsmc-samsung-ps5-supply-demand-intel"&gt;global chip shortage&lt;/a&gt; has forced some car manufacturers to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/10/22222166/semiconductor-shortage-ford-idle-kentucky-toyota-nissan-volkswagen"&gt;scale back production&lt;/a&gt;, and consumers have found it near impossible to find new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227040/nvidia-amd-gpu-shortage-rtx-3080-3070-3060-ti-3090-rx-6800-xt"&gt;graphics cards&lt;/a&gt;, CPUs, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297039/playstation-ceo-ps5-supply-2021-stock-consoles-jim-ryan"&gt;PS5s&lt;/a&gt;, and Xboxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lugFpP"&gt;Nvidia does note that despite the issues, supply should still increase as 2021 progresses. “We will see supply continue to increase throughout this quarter as well as throughout the year,” said Kress. Regardless, it’s still going to be difficult to find a new GPU when you have to compete with fellow gamers, cryptominers, and scalpers that are pushing the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/23/22345891/nvidia-amd-rtx-gpus-price-scalpers-ebay-graphics-cards"&gt;real prices of GPUs way out of control&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22385261/nvidia-gpu-shortage-rtx-3080-warning-comments-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22385261/nvidia-gpu-shortage-rtx-3080-warning-comments-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-15T07:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-15T07:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The ZTE Axon 30 Ultra 5G is coming to the US with a 144Hz display and a whole lot more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EkhPadMVYUi0mDj-aJ7Ot6tlvas=/164x0:1373x806/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69129504/Axon_30_Colors_1536x806.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Axon 30 Ultra 5G offers a whole bunch of rear-facing cameras.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo: ZTE&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8TTDaP"&gt;ZTE has unveiled the Axon 30 Ultra alongside two other 30-series devices — the Axon 30 and Axon 30 Pro — though the Ultra has at least one unique feature: it will be sold in the US and Canada. Exact availability and pricing are still TBD, but we do know that the 30 Ultra has all of the trappings of a high-end Android device. It will offer a Snapdragon 888 processor with 8GB or 12GB of RAM, a 6.67-inch 1080p OLED with adaptive refresh rates up to 144Hz, four rear cameras including a 5x zoom, and 66W fast charging. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IB0C0e"&gt;The 30 Ultra features a prominent camera bump that houses plenty of pixels, starting with a 64-megapixel f/1.6 main camera with optical image stabilization. There’s another 64-megapixel camera — unstabilized with a 35mm-equivalent f/1.9 lens — and an ultrawide with (you guessed it) a 64-megapixel sensor. A periscope-style telephoto lens is coupled with an 8-megapixel sensor and includes optical stabilization. Unlike the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/21/22191459/zte-axon-20-5g-under-display-camera-hands-on"&gt;Axon 20 5G&lt;/a&gt;, it offers a traditional hole-punch 16-megapixel selfie camera around front; no under-screen camera here, which is a good thing in our book. Video recording from the main camera tops out at 8K/30fps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lnvIjV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10447167"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SFwKTt"&gt;ZTE calls the phone’s 6.67-inch display a “borderless, curved” OLED panel with a 95% screen-to-body ratio. It’s protected with Gorilla Glass 5 — as is the rear panel — and includes HDR10 support. It offers adaptive refresh rates of 60Hz, 90Hz, 120Hz, and 144Hz, which it uses depending on the application to save battery life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IvmXfH"&gt;Rounding out the feature set, the Axon 30 Ultra 5G includes a large 4,600mAh battery that supports fast 66W wired charging. It ships with Android 11 and offers an in-screen fingerprint reader for biometric unlock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GCRBLq"&gt;The step-down Axon 30 Pro still includes the Snapdragon 888 chipset, but features a different rear camera configuration, a non-variable 120Hz screen, and less-speedy 55W charging. The Axon 30 base model is the only one to get the next iteration of the in-display selfie camera, &lt;a href="https://www.gizmochina.com/2021/01/20/zte-teases-axon-30-smartphone-will-have-an-under-display-camera/"&gt;as teased by ZTE&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z1mW1C"&gt;For now, the Ultra looks like a whole lot of phone, but it’s hard to judge just how competitive it will be in the US until we have a confirmed price. When it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; available, it’ll be &lt;a href="https://www.ztedevices.com/en/"&gt;sold online&lt;/a&gt; unlocked from ZTE. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22384596/zte-axon-30-ultra-5g-specs-launch-us"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22384596/zte-axon-30-ultra-5g-specs-launch-us</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-15T06:37:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-15T06:37:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>Chip manufacturer TSMC warns shortages could continue through 2022</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="TAIWAN-ECONOMY-SEMICONDUCTORS-TECHNOLOGY" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tyiRs0MALULXRot3KLFwxYIYhB0=/5x0:4775x3180/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69129467/1231936348.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by SAM YEH/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rHjFEX"&gt;TSMC, which makes processors for Apple, Qualcomm, AMD, and numerous other big consumer tech companies, has warned that chip shortages could last through 2022. “We see the demand continue to be high,” TSMC CEO C. C. Wei said in comments &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-04-15/tsmc-profit-beats-as-chip-shortage-shows-no-sign-of-abating?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;reported by &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, “In 2023, I hope we can offer more capacity to support our customers. At that time, we’ll start to see the supply chain tightness release a little bit.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QQshNE"&gt;Wei’s comments mirror predictions made by Intel’s new CEO Pat Gelsinger earlier this week, who warned that it could take a few years to address the shortage, &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/04/13/intel-ceo-semiconductor-chip-shortage/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post &lt;/em&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;. “It just takes a couple of years to build capacity,” Gelsinger said. Likewise, Nvidia’s CFO Colette Kress &lt;a href="https://nvidianews.nvidia.com/news/nvidia-announces-first-quarter-fiscal-2022-revenue-tracking-above-outlook?ncid=afm-chs-44270&amp;amp;ranMID=44270&amp;amp;ranEAID=kXQk6*ivFEQ&amp;amp;ranSiteID=kXQk6.ivFEQ-u_56nr2EJ2TBzDSKQ9NTsg"&gt;recently said&lt;/a&gt; the graphics card manufacturer expects “demand to continue to exceed supply for much of this year.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="pU048f"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“In 2023, I hope we can offer more capacity to support our customers”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aeQ2m0"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22368552/global-chip-shortage-end-tsmc-samsung-ps5-supply-demand-intel"&gt;global chip shortage&lt;/a&gt; has impacted everyone from automakers to games console manufacturers. Car manufacturers have had to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/10/22222166/semiconductor-shortage-ford-idle-kentucky-toyota-nissan-volkswagen"&gt;scale back production&lt;/a&gt;, while anyone looking to upgrade their gaming setup has struggled to find stock of new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227040/nvidia-amd-gpu-shortage-rtx-3080-3070-3060-ti-3090-rx-6800-xt"&gt;graphics cards&lt;/a&gt;, CPUs, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297039/playstation-ceo-ps5-supply-2021-stock-consoles-jim-ryan"&gt;PS5s&lt;/a&gt;, and Xboxes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TppA3m"&gt;TSMC does have good news for its automaker clients, saying they could expect chip supply to improve next quarter. But comments from TSMC, Intel, and Nvidia suggest that the broader shortages are unlikely to abate anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jjXwkJ"&gt;TSMC says it’s already running its fabs at “over 100 percent utilization,” but in the medium term it’s increasing investment in new production. “We have acquired land and equipment, and started the construction of new facilities. We are hiring thousands of employees and expanding our capacity at multiple sites,” Wei said in comments &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-tsmc-results-idUSKBN2C20IH"&gt;reported by &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WeuzF5"&gt;TSMC now plans to invest $30 billion on upgrading and expanding its production capacity this year (up from a previous forecast of between $25 and $28 billion). It reiterated that construction at its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/14/21259094/apple-tsmc-factory-chips-arizona-a-series"&gt;$12 billion Arizona plant&lt;/a&gt; is still scheduled to begin this year. Overall, the company plans to invest $100 billion to increase capacity in its plants over the next three years.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22385240/tsmc-chip-shortage-2022-intel-ceo-earnings-graphics-cards-cpus-gpus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22385240/tsmc-chip-shortage-2022-intel-ceo-earnings-graphics-cards-cpus-gpus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-15T06:33:58-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-15T06:33:58-04:00</updated>
    <title>This is the best Windows File Explorer design concept I’ve ever seen</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-HnCHUXF1kw4jH_5hTJ9MhrxO8s=/0x0:1500x1000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69129461/fileexplorer.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;File Explorer concept.&lt;/em&gt; | Alur2020 (&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Windows10/comments/mqsp10/redesigned_file_explorer/" target="_blank"&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="K62khu"&gt;Microsoft’s Windows File Explorer has existed in the operating system since Windows 95, and it has served as a focal point for design concepts ever since. I’ve seen a variety of mockups over the years that try to redesign the File Explorer and modernize it, but &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Windows10/comments/mqsp10/redesigned_file_explorer/"&gt;Reddit user Alur2020&lt;/a&gt; has really nailed what modern file management should look like in Windows 10. This is the best Windows File Explorer concept I’ve ever seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bdnNDA"&gt;The concept, spotted by &lt;a href="https://www.neowin.net/news/mouth-watering-user-concept-of-windows-10-file-explorer-has-reddit-salivating/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neowin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, is immediately striking for its sheer simplicity and usability. The default home area imagines a location where you can quickly see pinned items, drives, and recently used files. It’s a simple location to find anything important. Alur2020 has also incorporated Microsoft’s new Windows 10 system icons, and even color coded groups for files and folders much like macOS’ Finder.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nIGZkSYosBT6JmlQ7tNU2z6rcjQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22445533/qr815nfao5t61.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Alur2020 (&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Windows10/comments/mqsp10/redesigned_file_explorer/" target="_blank"&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;File Explorer concept.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="J487z5"&gt;Aside from the pure design, this concept also imagines what tabs might look like in a modern File Explorer. It looks very similar to Microsoft Edge browser tabs, allowing File Explorer users to open up multiple folders in a single view. Microsoft was working on its own &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/7/17092752/microsoft-windows-10-file-explorer-tabs"&gt;Sets feature for Windows 10&lt;/a&gt; that included tabs in File Explorer, but the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/23/18512250/microsoft-windows-10-sets-feature-app-tabs-removal"&gt;put this work on hold&lt;/a&gt; a couple of years ago. It’s not clear whether File Explorer will ever officially get tabs support in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cMnxS4"&gt;This concept File Explorer also offers up a cleaner way to deal with images in folders, with a minimalist ribbon of options. There’s even nested folders on the side panel, allowing Windows users to quickly switch between folders that are buried deep in multiple folder structures. The breadcrumb bar has worked well for navigation at the top of the File Explorer for years, but this nested folders option offers even more ways to navigate around.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AI-F_tfre5N0nthEHeXpWMj8r4E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22445534/d24v4rfao5t61.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Alur2020 (&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Windows10/comments/mqsp10/redesigned_file_explorer/" target="_blank"&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This File Explorer concept also imagines how nested folders would work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="os25cz"&gt;Alur2020’s concept has proved &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Windows10/comments/mqsp10/redesigned_file_explorer/"&gt;popular over on Reddit&lt;/a&gt;, with hundreds of comments praising the design, thousands of upvotes, and a number of Reddit awards. The concept comes just weeks after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/24/22348639/microsoft-windows-10-file-explorer-new-icons-system-update"&gt;Microsoft unveiled new File Explorer icons&lt;/a&gt; as part of a larger visual overhaul for Windows 10. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ON73aX"&gt;Microsoft has also created &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/4/22313037/microsoft-windows-10-new-system-icons-ui-overhaul-sun-valley"&gt;new system icons&lt;/a&gt; for Windows 10 this year, as part of a planned “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/4/22212817/microsoft-windows-10-visual-changes-update-sun-valley-2021"&gt;sweeping visual rejuvenation of Windows&lt;/a&gt;,” codenamed “Sun Valley.” The company is expected to detail its Windows UI plans and more about the future of the OS in the coming months as part of a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22261997/microsoft-news-events-gaming-cloud-windows"&gt;dedicated news event&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22385247/windows-file-explorer-design-concept-tabs-nested-folders"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22385247/windows-file-explorer-design-concept-tabs-nested-folders</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-15T05:03:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-15T05:03:44-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nvidia’s GeForce Experience now optimizes settings for creative apps</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d_dC01ffSimR3w9c8JJfjka0CuM=/0x0:1500x1000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69129299/NVIDIA_Studio_Optimal_Settings.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ua1U8O"&gt;Nvidia has &lt;a href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/2021/04/14/studio-gtc-apr-14/"&gt;released&lt;/a&gt; a new feature for its GeForce Experience software that helps users of creative applications make sure they’re getting the best performance out of their GPUs. GeForce Experience can now tell you whether you have the best settings enabled for more than 30 creative apps including DaVinci Resolve, Adobe’s Lightroom and Illustrator, and Autodesk’s AutoCAD. If certain GPU features aren’t active, you can turn them on from within GeForce Experience itself “with a single button press.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0wdtG3"&gt;For example, DaVinci Resolve users can automatically optimize settings for GPU acceleration in various modes, which may or may not have been switched on already. The idea is that GeForce Experience can now be a central hub for creative apps that helps you maximize performance. Nvidia isn’t doing anything specific here to actually improve how the apps work — though it is also releasing a new Studio Driver today for creative software — this is just a convenient way to make sure that you’ve set them up in the best way possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="NlyN5F"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Nvidia focuses further on creators&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2aIAAX"&gt;GeForce Experience is an application for Nvidia GPU owners that’s usually associated with gaming-related functionality. For example, Nvidia releases “Game Ready Drivers” through GeForce Experience that optimizes new games for its GPUs, and the application can serve as a launcher for those games. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B3qs7R"&gt;With this move, the software is further expanding its focus to encompass creative users as well, which is an area that Nvidia continues to concentrate on. Earlier today the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22383572/open-broadcaster-software-obs-nvidia-noise-removal-rtx-voice-broadcast"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that its RTX-powered audio noise removal feature would be directly integrated into Open Broadcaster Software (OBS), the popular streaming software.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22385195/nvidia-geforce-experience-creative-app-settings-optimization-feature"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22385195/nvidia-geforce-experience-creative-app-settings-optimization-feature</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-15T04:33:56-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-15T04:33:56-04:00</updated>
    <title>Bang and Olufsen’s latest speaker disappears into your bookshelf</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VuFnBC2uAegi9TLsdcL8eDwFkh8=/0x1:1920x1281/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69129265/Beosound_Emerge_0037.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Emerge’s design was “inspired by the compact form factor of a book.”&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Bang &amp;amp; Olufsen&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="cXyBDB"&gt;Bang and Olufsen’s latest connected speaker is the Emerge. Its thin form-factor should blend right in to most bookshelves, and that’s no accident. In a press release &lt;a href="https://press.bang-olufsen.com/d/gKpSDxqk8eyT/news#/april-2021/bang-olufsen-introduces-beosound-emerge-an-incredibly-slim-yet-powerful-home-speaker"&gt;announcing the speaker&lt;/a&gt;, the company says its design was “inspired by the compact form factor of a book” with side panels that wrap around like a cover, and a logo on the front that’s meant to evoke a title printed on the spine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="seJuu6"&gt;It’s a nice contrast from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/10/7/9470909/40000-speaker-bang-olufsen"&gt;some&lt;/a&gt; of Bang and Olufsen’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/29/17795192/bang-olufsen-edge-speaker-price-release-date-ifa-2018"&gt;previous speakers&lt;/a&gt;, which have had huge, hulking form-factors that are hard to imagine in any normal home. Instead, the Emerge takes a similar approach to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/25/20726409/ikea-sonos-symfonisk-table-lamp-bookshelf-speaker-review-sound"&gt;Ikea’s Symfonisk speakers&lt;/a&gt;, which have pulled double duty as lamps or shelving to help them blend in with the rest of your furniture.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ej1XNnSteAinXaMG66GaGIq6uyY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22445488/Beosound_Emerge_0041.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Bang &amp;amp; Olufsen&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get it? Like a title on a book spine?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="jM8rD4"&gt;B&amp;amp;O says the Emerge speaker’s small form-factor shouldn’t make it a slouch in the sound quality department, however. “The vision for Beosound Emerge was to create the slimmest speaker possible that could still deliver full range, ultra-wide sound despite its size through its revolutionary driver configuration,” says the company’s head of product management Christoffer Poulsen. Internally there’s a triple-driver configuration consisting of a 4-inch woofer, a 1.45-inch mid-range, and a 0.6-inch tweeter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OZ5ETC"&gt;In terms of connectivity, the Emerge supports all the standards you’d expect out of a modern connected speaker. There’s Spotify Connect support, Bluetooth 5.0, Airplay 2, and Chromecast streaming, as well as a built-in microphone with Google Assistant support. Physical connections include a line-in/optical jack, Ethernet, and a USB-C port for power. And yes, you can pair two Emerge’s together to create a stereo pair. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="snGSOu"&gt;B&amp;amp;O says the speaker uses the same replaceable connectivity module that appeared in its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22264409/bang-and-olufsen-beosound-level-modular-streaming-smart-speaker-bluetooth-airplay"&gt;recent Beosound Level&lt;/a&gt;, which will allow it to receive “new performance updates and features for years to come.” Eventually this module can be replaced if it gets outdated, B&amp;amp;O says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZGB7po"&gt;The Bang and Olufsen Emerge is available in select European markets starting today, and will release globally this autumn. Pricing starts at £539 / €599 9around $717) for the black model, while the gold model which has an oak wood cover costs slightly more at £669 / €749 (around $879).&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22385189/bang-and-olufsen-emerge-connected-speaker-airplay-2-spotify-connect-release-date-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22385189/bang-and-olufsen-emerge-connected-speaker-airplay-2-spotify-connect-release-date-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
