<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2020-12-18T18:32:25-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-18T18:32:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T18:32:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>Shigeru Miyamoto tours Super Nintendo World theme park in new video</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d9DxPa4-ZbtR0KPrOHzLL053XmQ=/158x0:1583x950/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68551221/Screen_Shot_2020_12_18_at_3.25.43_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iZB6In"&gt;Nintendo’s Shigeru Miyamoto led a video tour of the company’s Mario-themed Super Nintendo World attraction at Universal Studios Japan in Osaka during the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hQaRBOI-9kg"&gt;latest Direct livestream&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T3k0oy"&gt;The theme park looks to be packed with Mario iconography that will be familiar to Nintendo fans. Even the entrance Mario-themed: you enter the park by walking through a giant pipe that spits you out in the atrium of Princess Peach’s castle that first debuted in &lt;em&gt;Super Mario 64&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="SDUVFU"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A smart wristband lets you interact with elements of the park&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="t3s64K"&gt;Miyamoto showed how you can you use a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/13/21064777/super-nintendo-world-mario-theme-park-osaka-japan-wristbands-mobile-app"&gt;special smart wristband&lt;/a&gt;, called the “Power-Up Band,” to interact with different parts of the zone. In one example, he punched a question mark block with the hand wearing the device, and the block made the classic Mario coin-collecting sound. In another moment, Miyamoto hit a POW block near a spinning Koopa shell at the right time to make it bounce up and collect a key coin. The band links to your smartphone so you can track your activities around the park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Vf72Y"&gt;Miyamoto also walked through an underground area that had oversized elements to create the illusion of being a smaller Mario, a vast cafe with video screens of Toads making food, and Bowser’s Castle, which is where the AR &lt;em&gt;Mario Kart&lt;/em&gt;-themed roller coaster is located.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XI3Shp"&gt;As a long-time Mario fan, the park looks delightful, and I hope I can experience it for myself someday. Super Nintendo World is scheduled to open &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/30/21726093/super-nintendo-world-osaka-japan-opening-date-announced"&gt;on February 4th&lt;/a&gt;. The zone was originally set to open before the 2020 Summer Olympics in Tokyo, but the opening &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/29/21306781/super-nintendo-world-opening-delayed-indefinitely-coronavirus"&gt;was delayed&lt;/a&gt; due to the COVID-19 pandemic (which also pushed back the Olympics). At some point, Universal Studios also plans to open Super Nintendo World zones in Hollywood, California; Orlando, Florida; and Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="9faf2t"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Super Nintendo World opens on February 4th with AR Mario Kart rollercoaster","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/30/21726093/super-nintendo-world-osaka-japan-opening-date-announced"},{"title":"Japan’s Super Nintendo World will open in spring 2021","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/7/21505457/super-nintendo-world-opening-date-spring-2021"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189601/super-nintendo-world-theme-park-universal-studios-japan-mario-shigeru-miyamoto"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189601/super-nintendo-world-theme-park-universal-studios-japan-mario-shigeru-miyamoto</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-18T18:20:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T18:20:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>A Facebook bug exposed Instagram users’ personal email addresses and birthdays</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/F9rvVWJkc9YoNwD6Uo7Uk0NZrbM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68550595/acastro_190919_1777_instagram_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BUiIHc"&gt;When signing up for an Instagram account, the service promises that your email and birthday won’t be publicly visible. A bug discovered by security researcher Saugat Pokharel, however, made it so that an attacker could easily get that private information. The bug, which was patched after being reported to Facebook, was exploitable by business accounts that were given access to an experimental feature the company was testing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Qoi1mI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The attack worked on private accounts, and ones that don’t accept public DMs&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0E00Zu"&gt;The attack used Facebook’s Business Suite tool, available to any Facebook business account. The experimental upgrade meant that if a Facebook business account was linked to Instagram and was included in the test group, the Business Suite tool would show additional information about a person alongside any direct message — including their supposedly private email address and birthday. All business users had to do was send a direct message on Instagram to call up the information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3zMPbB"&gt;Pokharel found that the attack worked on accounts that were set to private and accounts that were set to not accept DMs from the public. If an account did not accept DMs, the user potentially would not receive any notification indicating their profile may have been viewed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hs53HU"&gt;An experienced bug hunter, Pokharel also discovered that Instagram &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/14/21368602/instagram-kept-deleted-photos-messages-on-servers-year-bug-fixed"&gt;wasn’t actually deleting deleted posts&lt;/a&gt; back in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YTN7La"&gt;In a statement provided to&lt;em&gt; The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, a Facebook spokesperson said that the bug was only accessible for a short period of time, as the experiment was started in October. The company doesn’t disclose how many users were given access to the feature, but it says that it was a “small test,” and that an investigation found no evidence of abuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EYWByA"&gt;The full text of the statement is below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="nCejhA"&gt; A researcher reported an issue where, if someone was a part of a small test we ran in October for business accounts, personal information of the person they were messaging could have been revealed. This issue was resolved quickly, and we discovered no evidence of abuse. Through our Bug Bounty Program we rewarded this researcher for his help in reporting this issue to us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="4qDXVF"&gt;According to Pokharel, Facebook engineers fixed the issue within a few hours of being notified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JIExn1"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update December 18, 6:20 PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clarified a point in the second paragraph that only accounts that were included in the experiment had access to the information.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189494/facebook-bug-instagram-email-birthdays-messages"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189494/facebook-bug-instagram-email-birthdays-messages</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-18T18:00:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T18:00:38-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra will have six cameras</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Samsung Galaxy S21" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ncHc-NQdnFXhEsi3BDMXZvmm9qU=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68551093/41821.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The upcoming Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo: WinFuture&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Gl5Wyo"&gt;Today, we have another Galaxy S21 leak, which seems to confirm some of the specs that have been floating around, &lt;a href="https://winfuture.de/news,120117.html"&gt;published by &lt;em&gt;WinFuture&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167208/samsung-galaxy-s21-january-14th-launch-india-plus-ultra-s-pen"&gt;Information about&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22187074/samsung-galaxy-s21-leaked-colors-plus-ultra"&gt;images&lt;/a&gt; of Samsung’s upcoming Galaxy S21-series phones have been landing almost daily in the run-up to Samsung’s January event. With this newest leak, we now have a better idea of what to expect — especially in the camera department. In short, the hardware appears to be a big part of Samsung’s plan to take on the highly capable iPhone 12 Pro Max.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WEPWZl"&gt;The S21 Ultra will reportedly offer 3x &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; 10x telephoto cameras (72mm and 240mm equivalent focal lengths, respectively), both with optical image stabilization. That’s one additional rear-facing camera compared to the S20 Ultra’s three rear sensors. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Dd4YyGk5Sl73FJRSV1V7y9LOCSA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22183371/41804.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: WinFuture&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SPua0d"&gt;The S21’s 10x lens will use a folded optic design like that of the S20’s telephoto camera. We expect that Samsung will once again offer hybrid zoom that reaches much farther than that 10x optical range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fSy8aS"&gt;Some other subtle camera updates look to be on the way, too. The main 108-megapixel camera gets a slightly wider 24mm (versus 26mm) equivalent lens. It will also get laser-assisted autofocus: something that the S20 Ultra didn’t offer but the Note 20 Ultra later introduced. And &lt;em&gt;WinFuture&lt;/em&gt; says that despite the main camera sensor’s on-paper similarities to the last generation, this is a new sensor that should offer better image quality than the last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TF4xl8"&gt;Samsung will need every advantage to compete with the iPhone 12 Pro Max, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21555901/iphone-12-pro-max-review"&gt;which we think is the best smartphone camera&lt;/a&gt; on the market today. Historically, Samsung has taken more of a hardware-heavy approach to mobile imaging, increasingly using its own house-made sensors rather than grabbing Sony’s off the shelf, and being early to adopt dual- and triple-lens cameras on its devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Whdfag"&gt;Part of the reason Samsung has leaned so hard into advanced hardware is that its computational photography hasn’t kept up with either Apple or Google. Only recently has it come up to par with features like Night Mode. But now it’s another year, and there’s more work to be done to catch up to the iPhone 12 Pro Max. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zWQk7y"&gt;Video may prove to be grounds for Samsung to level the playing field with Apple, too. It’s one area where software can only do so much without the right hardware behind it. Samsung has usually had big specs to tout when it comes to video — the S21 Ultra will offer 8K recording to the 12 Pro Max’s 4K — but the proof will be in the footage. Samsung &lt;a href="https://news.samsung.com/us/samsung-defies-one-size-fits-all-mobile-experiences/"&gt;says it’s committed&lt;/a&gt; to continuing to push its capabilities in this area. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="jMtF32"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Samsung Galaxy S20 Ultra review: shutter bug","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/27/21155012/samsung-galaxy-s20-ultra-review-5g-screen-camera-space-zoom-price"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="pXwHna"&gt;There are a few notable non-camera-related details in &lt;em&gt;WinFuture’s&lt;/em&gt; report. These specs confirm a 6.8-inch display with variable refresh rates from one to 120Hz, a battery-saving move also adopted from the Note 20 Ultra. There’s also S Pen support, which will be sold separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jGNcHv"&gt;Samsung will also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21514480/apple-iphone-charging-brick-charger-earbuds-box-environmental-impact-carbon-emissions"&gt;follow Apple’s lead&lt;/a&gt; by shipping the S21 devices without wall chargers in the box. The company will probably, like Apple, cite the environmental benefits as the motivation for this change, though cynics among us will note that it’s also beneficial to each company’s bottom line. But the reduction of e-waste is no doubt a good thing, and Samsung’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21522980/apple-iphone-12-pro-usb-c-lightning-environment-charger-box-electronic-waste"&gt;use of USB-C rather than a proprietary connector&lt;/a&gt; scores it even more environmental bonus points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AWjQAx"&gt;There’s no confirmed launch date or pricing yet for the S21 Ultra, though reports point to an announcement on January 14th. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189305/samsung-s21-ultra-spec-leak-cameras"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189305/samsung-s21-ultra-spec-leak-cameras</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-18T17:51:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T17:51:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>FAA and Boeing manipulated 737 Max tests during recertification</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="FAA Chief Steve Dickson Pilots Boeing 737 MAX Test Flight" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/01XhNQXv5ndHZ0DScWj_TT19hOU=/0x64:4478x3049/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68551030/1228808006.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Mike Siegel / Pool / Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="NynK0y"&gt;Boeing and the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) worked together to manipulate 737 Max recertification tests following two fatal crashes in 2018 and 2019, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.commerce.senate.gov/2020/12/wicker-releases-committee-s-faa-investigation-report"&gt;damning new Senate report&lt;/a&gt;. Boeing “inappropriately coached” some FAA test pilots to reach a desired outcome during the recertification tests, and some were even performed on simulators that weren’t equipped to re-create the same conditions as the crashes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IdcqOQ"&gt;In doing this, the Senate report’s authors say the “FAA and Boeing were attempting to cover up important information that may have contributed to the 737 MAX tragedies.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="DrP7Ef"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The FAA is also accused of retaliating against whistleblowers&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BNgmvJ"&gt;The FAA is also accused of retaliating against whistleblowers, possibly obstructing the Office of the Inspector General’s investigation into the crashes, failing to hold senior managers accountable, and allowing Southwest Airlines to operate dozens of improperly certified planes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4tcIAJ"&gt;The 102-page report, released Friday, was compiled by the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and is built on information from 50 whistleblowers, FAA staff interviews, and more than 15,000 pages of documents. It comes one month after the FAA &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/18/21573113/boeing-737-max-cleared-fly-grounding-faa-crashes"&gt;cleared the 737 Max to return to flight&lt;/a&gt;, and as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22165956/boeing-737-max-flight-brazil-gol-airlines"&gt;airlines around the world&lt;/a&gt; start &lt;a href="https://www.flightglobal.com/fleets/united-to-return-boeing-737-max-to-service-on-11-february/141683.article"&gt;reintroducing the plane into their fleets&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OcLF09"&gt;While Boeing’s own failures leading up to the 737 Max crashes &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/9/21059420/boeing-employees-messages-737-max-investigation-simulator-crash"&gt;have been thoroughly probed and well-documented&lt;/a&gt;, the new Senate report is one of the most intimate looks at problems inside the regulator that was supposed to keep the company in check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pHu9Q9"&gt;“Our findings are troubling,” Sen. Roger Wicker (R-MS), who chairs the committee, said in a statement. “The report details a number of significant examples of lapses in aviation safety oversight and failed leadership in the FAA. It is clear that the agency requires consistent oversight to ensure their work to protect the flying public is executed fully and correctly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gtctUc"&gt;The FAA said in an email that it is “reviewing the report and will get back to you.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8VrrT6"&gt;Boeing said &lt;a href="https://boeing.mediaroom.com/news-releases-statements?item=130790"&gt;in a prepared statement&lt;/a&gt; that it “take[s] seriously the Committee’s findings and will continue to review the report in full.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p4yrvW"&gt;“Boeing is committed to improving aviation safety, strengthening our safety culture, and rebuilding trust with our customers, regulators, and the flying public,” the company wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="myAAiH"&gt;Southwest Airlines did not immediately respond to a request for comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xF8slS"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The 737 Max was rushed through development so Boeing could keep pace with rival Airbus&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5PDDSK"&gt;The 737 Max was rushed through development so Boeing could keep pace with rival Airbus, which had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/2/18518176/boeing-737-max-crash-problems-human-error-mcas-faa"&gt;surprise-announced a more fuel-efficient plane in 2011&lt;/a&gt;. Instead of developing a new plane from the ground up, Boeing modified the 737 NG with bigger, more fuel-efficient engines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M2CzRW"&gt;The placement of those engines made the plane susceptible to stalls in certain takeoff situations, though, so Boeing equipped the plane with a piece of software that would automatically pitch the nose down to prevent this from happening. Boeing didn’t tell regulators or customers about the software, though, in a bid to cut down on costly flight training. This left the pilots of Lion Air Flight 610 in 2018 and Ethiopian Airlines Flight 302 in 2019 fighting, and ultimately losing out to, a piece of software they didn’t know was working against them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sCIcFA"&gt;That software, known as Maneuvering Characteristics Augmentation System (MCAS) was a big focus of the recertification tests following the two crashes, especially in simulators meant to recreate the crash conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SFgXmv"&gt;The problem, broadly, that the Commerce Committee found was that this testing process was rife with its own problems. Some FAA investigators left tests early, while others were performed in simulators that weren’t equipped with the same software that doomed the 737 Max flights, meaning the results were meaningless. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="71SG9S"&gt;In one particular FAA test performed on the right simulator, a whistleblower says Boeing officials were present and told the test pilots when to hit the switch that killed MCAS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sVSJqI"&gt;When these actions were reported by whistleblowers, they were often ignored or retaliated against, according to the report. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ClRtUx"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189609/faa-boeing-737-max-senate-report-coverup-tests-whistleblowers"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189609/faa-boeing-737-max-senate-report-coverup-tests-whistleblowers</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-18T17:50:52-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T17:50:52-05:00</updated>
    <title>China-based Zoom employee charged for secretly censoring Tiananmen Square anniversary events</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UauYzuRYy-Nav1zLJBrg0tYizN0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68551028/acastro_200331_1777_zoom_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xmx7VW"&gt;A China-based former Zoom employee is being charged with harassment for allegedly disrupting video calls commemorating the 1989 Tiananmen Square massacre. Brooklyn federal prosecutors &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-edny/pr/china-based-executive-us-telecommunications-company-charged-disrupting-video-meetings"&gt;unsealed a case&lt;/a&gt; against Xinjiang (also known as Julien) Jin today. The complaint doesn’t identify Jin’s employer, but Zoom &lt;a href="https://blog.zoom.us/our-perspective-on-the-doj-complaint/"&gt;published a blog post&lt;/a&gt; acknowledging that it employed him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UOPrbs"&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-edny/press-release/file/1346966/download"&gt;the complaint&lt;/a&gt;, Jin was a liaison between Zoom and Chinese law enforcement and intelligence services. He allegedly used this position to target dissidents and activists both inside and outside the People’s Republic of China, collecting account information and disrupting meetings. “The allegations in the complaint lay bare the Faustian bargain that the PRC government demands of U.S. technology companies doing business within the PRC’s borders, and the insider threat that those companies face from their own employees in the PRC,” said acting US attorney Seth D. DuCharme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="TsoaId"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Jin allegedly got meetings banned by reporting “disgusting pics” from fake accounts&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AV1Oxe"&gt;While serving as a “security technical leader” at Zoom, Jin allegedly identified users who discussed “disfavorable” political and religious topics, then worked with other employees to stop these users from participating in calls. As the 31st anniversary of the protests approached, the complaint says, he asked US-based employees to provide account information about dissidents planning to commemorate the events. Chinese authorities subsequently detained potential participants inside China and in at least one case, it threatened the family of a participant living abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vTGhdn"&gt;Most dramatically, Jin reportedly led a conspiracy to get Tiananmen Square-related events and their participants banned for violating Zoom’s terms of service. A group of employees allegedly set up accounts under false names using profile pictures with terrorism-related or pornographic imagery. Then they infiltrated Zoom event rooms and reported the meetings for hosting “disgusting pics,” “child abuse,” and content “inciting violence” — based on images from their own fake accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rr48Wk"&gt;Zoom &lt;a href="https://blog.zoom.us/improving-our-policies-as-we-continue-to-enable-global-collaboration/"&gt;apologized earlier this year&lt;/a&gt; for terminating public commemorative events and the accounts of their hosts. At that point, it said it shut down the meetings because they had a large number of participants from mainland China, and Chinese authorities had called the events unlawful. “Going forward Zoom will not allow requests from the Chinese government to impact anyone outside of mainland China,” the company promised. An update to the post acknowledged that at least one session was terminated due to “an apparent terms of service violation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pu0J6x"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.zoom.us/our-perspective-on-the-doj-complaint/"&gt;In a post&lt;/a&gt; following the unsealing, Zoom said it had cooperated with the Department of Justice and launched its own internal probe, resulting in Jin being terminated and other unnamed employees placed on leave while the investigation concludes. Zoom says it appointed Jin after the Chinese government abruptly terminated its service and demanded it comply with local censorship laws. “The shutdown put Zoom in an unfamiliar and uncomfortable position,” the post reads. “As we worked to resolve the shutdown, China requested that Zoom confirm it would comply with Chinese law, including designating an in-house contact for law enforcement requests.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aR4b5n"&gt;Jin is charged with conspiracy to commit interstate harassment and unlawful conspiracy to transfer means of identification, based on his alleged impersonation of Zoom users. The charges carry a maximum sentence of 10 years, but the Department of Justice says that Jin has not been taken into custody.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189519/zoom-julien-xinjiang-jin-charged-harassment-tiananmen-square-anniversary-events"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189519/zoom-julien-xinjiang-jin-charged-harassment-tiananmen-square-anniversary-events</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-18T17:43:31-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T17:43:31-05:00</updated>
    <title>Foxconn tells Wisconsin it never promised to build an LCD factory</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A man walks past an office building with the Foxconn name displayed outside on Wednesday, May 8 2019 in Milwaukee, Wisconsin. Foxconn is a electronics contract manufacturing company, which is constructing a plant in south eastern Wisconsin creating thousands of jobs. " src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gFUdbVvxlg7qtm8xY75EPUhM1Yw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68550991/jlott_190508_3414_0028.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A man walks past an office building with the Foxconn name displayed outside on Wednesday, May 8 2019 in Milwaukee, Wisconsin. Foxconn is a electronics contract manufacturing company, which is constructing a plant in south eastern Wisconsin creating thousands of jobs. | Photo by Joshua Lott for The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bYeysa"&gt;In October, Wisconsin denied Foxconn subsidies because it had failed to build the LCD factory specified in its contract with the state. As &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21507966/foxconn-empty-factories-wisconsin-jobs-loophole-trump"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reported, it had created a building one-twentieth the size of the promised factory, taken out a permit to use it for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/21/21526765/foxconn-lcd-factory-not-real-confirmation-wisconsin-report-exclusive"&gt;storage&lt;/a&gt;, and failed to employ anywhere near the number of employees the contract called for. Nevertheless, Foxconn publicly objected “on numerous grounds” to Wisconsin’s denial of subsidies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q1qW83"&gt;Documents obtained through a records request show Foxconn’s rationale: it doesn’t think it was specifically promising to build an LCD factory at all. According to a November 23rd letter to the Wisconsin Economic Development Corporation (WEDC), Foxconn does not think the factory specified in the contract, an enormous Generation 10.5 LCD fabrication facility, was actually a “material” part of the contract. (“Material” is a legal term that means relevant or significant.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0IKddr"&gt;“As you confirmed on November 10, 2020, the only reason the WEDC made the determination that the Recipients are ineligible for tax credits is because the WEDC believes the Recipients have failed to carry out the ‘Project,’” Foxconn wrote. “Thus, WEDC’s determination of ineligibility is based off its belief that the Generation 10.5 TFT-LCD Fabrication Facility is a material term of the Agreement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="aTlSJp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Thus, WEDC’s determination of ineligibility is based off its belief that the Generation 10.5 TFT-LCD Fabrication Facility is a material term of the Agreement.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="npuOdN"&gt;Rather, Foxconn claimed it and WEDC had a “mutual understanding” that it would build something more vaguely defined, “a transformational and sustainable high-tech manufacturing and technology ecosystem in Wisconsin that brings long-term investment and jobs.” However, Foxconn did express openness to amending its contract to allow for more flexibility in what it was building in exchange for lower subsidies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1CBrHM"&gt;Foxconn’s letter was written in response to repeated requests from WEDC to explain why exactly Foxconn was objecting to WEDC’s denial of subsidies. “Your notice of objection stated that there are numerous grounds on which the Recipients object, but it did not detail what those were,” a WEDC lawyer wrote to Foxconn earlier in November.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pUTdt9"&gt;WEDC is standing by its denial of subsidies. In a letter dated December 4th, the agency wrote that the definition of the project as a Gen 10.5 LCD factory was in fact central to the contract, calling Foxconn’s claim that jobs and investment were the only terms that mattered “incomplete and flawed in several respects.” (It also noted that Foxconn hasn’t performed on the jobs or investment parts of the contract, either.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="tdiTr2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Foxconn also expressed openness to amending its contract&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TpT4FY"&gt;The contract explicitly defined the project as a Gen 10.5 LCD factory, and its enormous size and economic impact was the justification for the record-breaking subsidy package Foxconn received, WEDC pointed out, as it has numerous times before. “Without a Generation 10.5 TFT-LCD Fabrication Facility, there is no justification, or consideration, for the enormous tax credit incentives or expense to Wisconsin taxpayers,” WEDC wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z3iIkI"&gt;WEDC ended the letter by reiterating it was open to amending the contract to reflect Foxconn’s current plans. There are signs that such an agreement might be close. After claiming the specifics of what it was building were never important, Foxconn added that it does wish to discuss amending the contract to “lower the taxpayer liability in exchange for a flexible business environment in Wisconsin.” Foxconn has previously expressed interest in such an amendment only to revert to insisting it was building an LCD factory after all, but it’s possible that with President Trump exiting the White House, the company will feel less pressure to maintain the facade that it’s building the project Trump touted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="X9dq3q"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Incomplete and flawed in several respects.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ND3AkM"&gt;But such an amendment hinges, as always, on Foxconn telling Wisconsin what it is actually building. In a November 24th email, WEDC CEO Missy Hughes wrote to Foxconn executive Jay Lee expressing enthusiasm for revising the contract and imploring the company to provide its plans, something the company has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/13/21020885/foxconn-wisconsin-deal-renegotiate-tax-subsidy-lcd-factory-plant"&gt;refused to do&lt;/a&gt; for over a year and a half. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6FGpKo"&gt;“WEDC’s practice is to understand the company’s plan and award incentives based on that plan and its projected impact on Wisconsin’s economy,” Hughes wrote. “We base our investment on the company’s plans. Should these plans change, WEDC is prepared to amend the contract. But fundamental to an initial award is an understanding of the company’s plans. Accordingly, the next clear step for WEDC and Foxconn is to meet and for Foxconn can outline its plans for Wisconn Valley, its planned investment, and job creation. By providing specific plans about what Foxconn will build, the type of business, the types of jobs and salaries, WEDC will be able to run our analysis of the taxpayer’s return on investment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="f07emx"&gt;&lt;q&gt;An amendment hinges, as always, on Foxconn telling Wisconsin what it is actually building&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pQY9N6"&gt;A Foxconn lawyer responded with an email agreeing to a video meeting on December 4th, saying, “I am confident that after months of discussions we are on the brink of coming to acceptable terms that will lead to an exciting future for our smart manufacturing park in Mount Pleasant.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SVH0wb"&gt;Neither WEDC nor Foxconn responded to a request for comment on the status of negotiations or to questions about whether Foxconn provided the required plans and projections. However, an interview with Hughes published yesterday indicates a continued lack of clarity around the project. Talks are ongoing, she told the &lt;a href="https://www.bizjournals.com/milwaukee/news/2020/12/17/q-a-with-wedc-ceo-missy-hughes.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Milwaukee Business Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and “Foxconn is helping WEDC understand what their plans are and helping us understand what their projections are so that we can analyze that and think about how we support it from the taxpayer side.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RveBZq"&gt;But Hughes seemed to acknowledge that Foxconn itself is still figuring out what to do. “For Foxconn, because they’re right at the beginning stages, there’s a lot of different ways that they’re thinking about what they’re going to be working on, whether it’s artificial intelligence or smart manufacturing, and so understanding that — and I will say get overwhelmed by the terminology and the different things — but I do think they’re very forward thinking and I think if there’s anything that Wisconsin can benefit from, from Foxconn, is that forward thinking mindset.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zFDxaY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Gr6zvX"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/20432429-wedc-foxconn-121820/?embed=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="WEDC-Foxconn 12.18.20 (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="905" style="border: 1px solid #aaa;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189436/foxconn-wisconsin-lcd-factory-trump-contract-negotiation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189436/foxconn-wisconsin-lcd-factory-trump-contract-negotiation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Josh Dzieza</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-18T16:13:49-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T16:13:49-05:00</updated>
    <title>Caliphate’s bad source shows the dangers of the podcasting gold rush</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/87mrYoVx8Q8EXHYTFgV97xNKGCU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68550392/acastro_201218_1777_mute_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UhG0TM"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;’ &lt;em&gt;Caliphate&lt;/em&gt; podcast was a hit — until it wasn’t. The 2018 show, which chronicled the radicalization of a man who joined the Islamic State, was a finalist for the Pulitzer Prize, won a Peabody, and was widely regarded as a feat of narrative nonfiction storytelling. The &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;’ head of film, TV, and audio, Sam Dolnick, &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/michael-barbaro-daily-podcast-team-launching-weekly-fx-series-1200451"&gt;described the show&lt;/a&gt; as a “cinematic experience” that “absolutely lends itself to TV” and came with “a lot of interest from Hollywood.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5rfmkq"&gt;Today, however, those days seem far away. The &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/18/business/media/new-york-times-caliphate-podcast.html"&gt;appended&lt;/a&gt; a lengthy and apologetic editor’s note to the show’s landing pages after doubts about the central character’s story surfaced. The &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; reassigned the show’s star reporter and host, Rukmini Callimachi, and dropped a full episode in its feed discussing what went wrong. The paper of record, well-known for its audio work with &lt;em&gt;The Daily&lt;/em&gt;, now has a stain on its podcasting endeavors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sxRdf6"&gt;This is a monumental moment for the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;, for sure, but also for the much-hyped and growing podcasting industry. Podcasting has become a critical bet for many media companies that hope a cheaper investment in audio and podcasting might yield high returns in IP deals from streaming or video production companies. For many, podcasting has become a major revenue source, both because of advertising and IP opportunities. But the push for monetizable content, specifically that which can be sold to Hollywood executives, goes against typical journalist rigor. Fact-checking takes time, as does fully reporting a story. Hollywood moves fast — and who knows how long those podcasting deals will stick around.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="6a1cVi"&gt;&lt;q&gt;‘Caliphate’ generated interest from Hollywood&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7ECVyA"&gt;In an interview with &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2020/12/18/944594193/new-york-times-retracts-hit-podcast-series-caliphate-on-isis-executioner"&gt;NPR today&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; executive editor Dean Baquet admitted that the paper wanted &lt;em&gt;Caliphate&lt;/em&gt;’s story so badly that it didn’t adequately vet the facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NfSPee"&gt;“I think we were so in love with it that when we saw evidence that maybe he was a fabulist, when we saw evidence that he was making some of it up, we didn’t listen hard enough,” he says, of Shehroze Chaudhry, the central character in &lt;em&gt;Caliphate&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yuiUiE"&gt;In this case, Baquet says the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; did not have evidence Chaudhry had ever been to Syria or that he had joined ISIS or killed civilians for the group, all of which is claimed in the podcast. NPR also reports that top editors who have edited complex written investigative pieces saw red flags but ended up giving in to an “ambitious audio investigative team presenting a compelling narrative yarn.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gegkSh"&gt;But the problem is much bigger than &lt;em&gt;Caliphate &lt;/em&gt;or &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;. The true crime genre, while widely popular, was in this spotlight last year over &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/stephaniemcneal/crime-junkie-podcast-accused-plagiarism-episodes"&gt;allegations of plagiarism&lt;/a&gt; against the show &lt;em&gt;Crime Junkie&lt;/em&gt;. Cathy Frye, a former journalist who worked for 15 years at the &lt;em&gt;Arkansas Democrat-Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, claims the show’s hosts ripped off her reporting without crediting her. The episodes in question were then suddenly deleted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9K3VHD"&gt;Robin Warder, who hosts&lt;em&gt; The Trail Went Cold&lt;/em&gt; podcast, told &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/stephaniemcneal/crime-junkie-podcast-accused-plagiarism-episodes"&gt;&lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; at the time that the broader true crime genre has a problem with sourcing and facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gN3iE5"&gt;“There are sometimes issues in the true crime podcasting world with shows not citing their sources, and some podcasts don’t do any research besides reading off Wikipedia,” he told &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/em&gt;. “But &lt;em&gt;Crime Junkie&lt;/em&gt; is probably the most high-profile example of this.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZZDq0u"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Many shows look to real life for podcast material&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="briOic"&gt;Meanwhile, reputable shows like &lt;em&gt;S-Town&lt;/em&gt;, from Serial Productions, which is now owned by the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;, have had to handle the drama of working with real names and people. Serial Productions &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2020/biz/news/s-town-podcast-producers-settle-lawsuit-with-subjects-estate-1234610011/"&gt;settled a lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; in May this year over the alleged use of the deceased subject’s name for commercial purposes, violating the Alabama Right of Publicity law. (Participant Media &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2018/06/s-town-podcast-movie-tom-mccarthy-directing-this-american-life-participant-media-samuel-hunter-1202409617/"&gt;acquired the show’s feature rights&lt;/a&gt; and is currently developing it to become a full-length film.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t9Zeuy"&gt;The push for IP is clearly strong, as is the possibility for revenue for the media companies, stars, their agents, and all of the other Hollywood players. A &lt;em&gt;Deadline&lt;/em&gt; report &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2020/12/podcasts-hollywood-film-tv-adaptations-trend-deals-1234636040/"&gt;published last week&lt;/a&gt; claims the number of podcasts in various stages of development to be adapted into TV or film programs is now well into three figures. Wondery, a podcasting network &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/amazon-in-talks-to-buy-podcast-maker-wondery-11606931396"&gt;reportedly in acquisition talks&lt;/a&gt; with Amazon, has over 16 shows in different stages of television adaptation, for example. The gold rush for podcast-generated IP is driving demand for shows like &lt;em&gt;Caliphate&lt;/em&gt;, which have a clear plot and characters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jD6dWX"&gt;“We’re first and foremost a podcast company and we create stories for the ear first,” Jen Sargent, Wondery’s COO tells &lt;em&gt;Deadline&lt;/em&gt;. “But the very nature of the types of shows that we’re greenlighting – they’re character rich – means they do lend themselves to TV. We do now have an eye on whether [a show] can be developed for TV because it’s become such a lucrative part of our revenue stream.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xBRAkk"&gt;Wondery has made its name through high-profile narrative nonfiction shows, like &lt;em&gt;Dirty John&lt;/em&gt;, which was buoyed by &lt;em&gt;Los Angeles Times&lt;/em&gt; reporting. But today’s &lt;em&gt;Caliphate&lt;/em&gt; news shows that strategy has its own risks. The desire to produce a cinematic but true podcast naturally creates tension — all storytellers want a good plot, but an especially juicy narrative likely has a better chance of high returns. The snag happens when producers seek a story but have to contend with facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="F03IN5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Hollywood is combing through podcasts looking for visual stories&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zDQMaB"&gt;Even well-established, audio-focused endeavors can get fact-checking wrong. In 2012, Ira Glass’ team at &lt;em&gt;This American Life&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="http://podcast.thisamericanlife.org/special/TAL_460_Retraction_Transcript.pdf"&gt;retracted its most popular episode at the time&lt;/a&gt; about a man visiting Apple’s manufacturing plant in China. The person behind the episode, Mike Daisey, is a theater performer rather than a reporter. Critically, he’d been telling a story similar to the one that aired on &lt;em&gt;This American Life&lt;/em&gt; on stage for years. But apparently, many details in that show were made up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iVQZCN"&gt;“Mike’s monologue in reality is a mix of things that actually happened when he visited China and things that he just heard about or researched, which he then pretends that he witnessed first hand,” Glass said in an episode detailing the retraction. “And the most powerful and memorable moments in the story all seem to be fabricated.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kTac6z"&gt;Glass says his team fact-checked the story’s details about Apple and its manufacturer Foxconn, but when they asked Daisey for his interpreter’s contact information, who’s referred to as Cathy in the episode, Daisey said her real name was actually Anna and didn’t provide any contact information for her. The team didn’t push him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aTeIdc"&gt;“I can say now in retrospect that when Mike Daisey wouldn’t give us contact information for his interpreter we should’ve killed the story rather than run it,” Glass said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TGEOJZ"&gt;Real life gets mundane, and Daisey seemingly knew an embellished story performed better on stage, and in podcasting, than the true one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="khwLdo"&gt;None of this is to say nonfiction podcasts are in dire trouble, but when dealing with real facts and truth, extra scrutiny is needed. That isn’t ideal for a burgeoning industry that’s looking to cash in fast on remarkable stories. But as&lt;em&gt; The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; now knows, the desire for a good story can’t outweigh fact-checking. As more journalistic outfits look to podcasting for revenue, they’ll have to solve the real problem: facts aren’t always sexy, and Hollywood wants a good story.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189200/podcasting-caliphate-new-york-times-ip-media"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189200/podcasting-caliphate-new-york-times-ip-media</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-18T15:54:42-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T15:54:42-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft reportedly designing its own ARM-based chips for servers and Surface PCs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PKctk22it-9UmXLSjkAmD02nXpc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68550255/akrales_190930_3682_0030.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Vgzfj1"&gt;Microsoft is designing its own ARM-based processors for servers and possibly a future Surface device, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-12-18/microsoft-msft-is-designing-its-own-chips-in-move-away-from-intel-intc?sref=SvwPxqpB"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The processors will be used in servers for Microsoft’s Azure cloud services and be based around ARM designs, according to the report. Microsoft is also reportedly “exploring” using another chip for some of its Surface devices, but it’s not clear if this will progress into a final product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nHk1wJ"&gt;Microsoft currently uses Intel-based processors for the majority of its Azure cloud services, and most of the company’s Surface lineup run on Intel chips, too. Microsoft has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/2/20888999/microsoft-surface-pro-x-laptop-3-custom-processor-qualcomm-amd-specs"&gt;worked with AMD and Qualcomm&lt;/a&gt; for custom chips for its Surface Laptop 3 and Surface Pro X devices, showing a willingness to move away from just Intel.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Osx2JGpWq-JuqaS_bxzHkKo8OPw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19250204/akrales_190930_3682_0006_right.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft’s custom chips for Surface devices.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="HCKfRC"&gt;Microsoft co-engineered an ARM-based SQ1 processor for the Surface Pro X last year and followed this up with an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/1/21496677/microsoft-surface-pro-x-refresh-sq2-processor-new-platinum-color-option"&gt;SQ2 variant a couple of months ago&lt;/a&gt;. AMD also worked with Microsoft to create a custom version of its Ryzen processor for the Surface Laptop 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="736Jt6"&gt;A move to ARM on the server side is certainly more significant, particularly for Intel. Apple has already signaled its move away from Intel chips for its Mac products, with its own &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"&gt;M1 silicon&lt;/a&gt; based on ARM designs. Intel’s server chips currently rule the server market, and AMD has already been chipping away at this lucrative market with its own EPYC processors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4ynFEX"&gt;Amazon, Microsoft’s main cloud rival, also looks like a significant threat to Intel and AMD, with its own ARM-based Graviton2 processors that were launched a year ago on AWS. Still, ARM-based servers are a small part of the market right now, despite the performance and cost benefits that they can deliver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YiDd74"&gt;We reached out to Microsoft to comment on the rumors, and the company didn’t deny them. “Because silicon is a foundational building block for technology, we’re continuing to invest in our own capabilities in areas like design, manufacturing and tools, while also fostering and strengthening partnerships with a wide range of chip providers,” says Microsoft’s communications chief Frank Shaw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WoaVaI"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, December 18th 17:05PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Article updated with comment from Microsoft.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189450/microsoft-arm-processors-chips-servers-surface-report"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189450/microsoft-arm-processors-chips-servers-surface-report</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-18T15:40:05-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T15:40:05-05:00</updated>
    <title>12 predictions for the consumer internet in 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Verge 2021 Lede" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/j29AMlqbCfKlCxrvldn9OYPMk90=/1x0:5001x3333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68550169/VRG_2021_v02.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="AbaTxN"&gt;I like to end each year by surveying you all about your predictions for social networks and the broader consumer internet in the 12 months to come. One, it’s a lot of fun. And two, a year later I get to read the predictions back and feel extremely dumb. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/interface/2019/12/20/21030123/social-media-predictions-2020-facebook-tiktok-slack-google"&gt;Our collective guesses for 2020 weren’t &lt;em&gt;terrible&lt;/em&gt;, exactly&lt;/a&gt; — we nailed Libra (er, Diem) failing to launch, the rise of Discord, the splinternet accelerating, and a total stalemate on Section 230 reform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c3VCki"&gt;But we missed a lot, too: a rise in curated experiences did not cause algorithms to “fade into the background”; a deepfake app did not go mainstream in the United States; and Twitch streaming did not power the rise of Oculus. (But the pandemic sort of did? It powered the rise of Twitch, anyway.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BPt5Kv"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/caseynewton/status/1339622589199618048?s=21"&gt;I asked you&lt;/a&gt; what you thought was going to happen on the consumer internet in 2021: product changes, breakout apps, regulation, lawsuits, culture trends, and more. Hundreds responded. Here are the best (admittedly US-centric) guesses I saw:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VFutk8"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social networks go crazy for commerce&lt;/strong&gt;. This one is well on its way — witness Facebook’s move this fall with the Instagram shopping tab and WhatsApp shopping carts — but look for others to try it on in 2021. “Live video shopping,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gRamblings/status/1339682855509606400"&gt;says Gautam Gupta, former CEO of NatureBox&lt;/a&gt; — one of several folks to predict that this is the year QVC is reborn on mobile phones. “We believe that storytelling has always been a huge part of driving commerce (online and offline) and the ability to combine storytelling with community in the form of live and social shopping will change the face of e-commerce.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d5WxPe"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Silicon Valley accelerates its investment in products and services for individual creators&lt;/strong&gt;. Platforms &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/goodtakesalex/status/1339624259170267137"&gt;explore new ways to let creators monetize their audiences directly&lt;/a&gt;, while taking a cut for themselves. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/freialobo/status/1339628012720033798"&gt;Charli D’Amelio for Instagram head of product&lt;/a&gt;? VidCon CEO Jim Louderback predicts &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jlouderb/status/1339663655999209472"&gt;a Cameo / OnlyFans tie-up&lt;/a&gt;. Everything is available via subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0mQBN8"&gt;Still, a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Austin_Federa/status/1339637589121372161"&gt;gulf begins to appear between those who pay for content and those who do not&lt;/a&gt;. Subscription fatigue &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/N3on_Online/status/1339623840289198080"&gt;will turn out to be real&lt;/a&gt;. And perhaps &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MtthwKrl/status/1339652091686518786"&gt;we lose at least one more paid streaming service&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="upmzAF"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remote work reshapes the industry&lt;/strong&gt;. With tech giants telling workers they can stay home through June or later — and possibly forever — a thousand new problems will lead to 100 new businesses. Priya Sanger predicts 2021 is &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CaseyNewton/status/1339622589199618048"&gt;the year that we see major advances in augmented reality and virtual reality focused on office uses&lt;/a&gt;. Meanwhile, everyone begins spending more time in Austin and Miami.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b2BsbQ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The internet has a reckoning over porn&lt;/strong&gt;. The Pornhub payment processor deplatforming and related lawsuits &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/qbeeert/status/1339628888616480768"&gt;may be just the beginning&lt;/a&gt;. Think: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/N3on_Online/status/1339625864934215680?s=20"&gt;new fights over content moderation, distribution, and ownership&lt;/a&gt;. Open question: what role will OnlyFans play in all this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vOBL0u"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dating apps have a big moment&lt;/strong&gt;. Many of you predict that when the COVID-19 vaccines have been widely distributed, the Earth will experience &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ozskier/status/1339623033116401664"&gt;a period of prolonged horniness&lt;/a&gt; unlike anything that has been seen in generations. Tinder, Grindr, and all the rest are poised to thrive as a result. Wrote consultant Matt Klein, via direct message:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H0vWgc"&gt;Dating apps continue to thrive as 1. people come out of their homes, and/or 2. people still remain indoors/protective. Both are tailwinds. Match Group stock continues to balloon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zlArOv"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audio apps take their turn in the spotlight&lt;/strong&gt;. Twitter Spaces and Clubhouse have captured a good deal of attention in Silicon Valley. But lots of you think &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/vishalchandra/status/1339623301493112833"&gt;the party may end before 2021 is out&lt;/a&gt;. “They all get relegated to phone sex apps with podcast energy,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/negroprogrammer/status/1339623364713828354"&gt;predicts Regynald Augustin of Dispo and &lt;em&gt;Subtweets&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. (Incidentally, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/buhlakay11/status/1339693259669590022?s=21"&gt;phone sex &lt;em&gt;is &lt;/em&gt;happening on Clubhouse&lt;/a&gt;, and no that link is not safe for work.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i2uPgf"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public social networks continue to fragment.&lt;/strong&gt; Parler won’t be the last breakaway republic from Facebook and Twitter. “I think that there will be more popular ‘free speech’ social networks, and it might even become a separate market, with all social networks either left-wing or right-wing echo chambers,” says &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/stuffundefined/status/1339661013977804800"&gt;this pseudonymous reader&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vStZZR"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The United States will need a strategy for the regulation of Chinese apps.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/alexstamos/status/1339623918366203905"&gt;Says ex-Facebook chief security officer Alex Stamos&lt;/a&gt;: “There will be another breakout consumer app from a Chinese-aligned multinational and the Biden administration will have to assemble a cohesive strategy out of the wreckage of the Trump-TikTok phony war.” And what of TikTok? I think it will probably end 2021 owned by the Oracle-Walmart consortium, but perhaps not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D1osnx"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The internet saves movie theaters.&lt;/strong&gt; Maybe &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dneumann/status/1339628542628409345"&gt;a streaming service buys one of the chains as a perk for subscribers&lt;/a&gt;. Or maybe the chains stay independent and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/javajoint/status/1339627571684790273"&gt;rent themselves out as virtual conference centers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yolwF5"&gt;Some other things that didn’t pop in my replies but seem likely to me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A3yXPM"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiple ongoing lawsuits and proposed regulations — related to antitrust in the United States, and data privacy and competition in the European Union — will slow down Big Tech.&lt;/strong&gt; The US case against Microsoft famously caused it to miss the threat posed to it by the internet; Sundar Pichai and Mark Zuckerberg will have to be on guard for the distractions that these cases could bring. (They’re students of Silicon Valley history, and so I imagine they already are.) Still: look for a slower pace of innovation and acquisitions than we might have seen otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fGOLZW"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tech’s labor issues accelerate&lt;/strong&gt;. The divide between management and labor at tech companies big and small seems to be getting bigger all the time — and so far, nothing that managers have done to date has seemed to mollify their employees. Look for more controversies related to failures here, especially with regard to diversity, equity, and inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zVgZi7"&gt;As always, there were joke suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="rt77tC"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Tambulla/status/1339638993500184576"&gt;“Section 230 would be repealed and replaced with something that is exactly the same thing.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rq6fZt"&gt;“&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CaseyNewton/status/1339622589199618048"&gt;The greatest builders of technology, now all in Miami, start to realize the beach is more fun than staring at a text editor for 16 hours a day. No new apps are released in 2021.&lt;/a&gt;” Thank you, Alex Kantrowitz of &lt;a href="https://bigtechnology.substack.com/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Big Technology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="q7Mz9d"&gt;Related, from Glossier’s Ashley Mayer: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashleymayer/status/1339646816048959488?s=21"&gt;VCs learn about hurricanes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="G9hPpI"&gt;And from Brian Merchant, senior editor at &lt;em&gt;OneZero:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="l0kLeX"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bcmerchant/status/1339632168012709888"&gt;As the single-creator subscription model for journalism enters a make-or-break year, writers will increasingly turn to social media platforms to crowd-source content to pad out their Substacks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="V827bq"&gt;Dammit, Brian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HAHBR9"&gt;There are also plenty of much harder-to-predict questions about 2021. Will 2020 election denialists gather into a coherent and possibly violent movement? What, if anything, will President Joe Biden do to rein in Big Tech? Will citizen (or candidate) Donald Trump be banned from Twitter or another social network — and if so, why? What are the long-term effects of the massive Russian intrusion into American infrastructure in the second half of this year? Can Facebook’s Oversight Board create a sense of justice in social networks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BYV7YW"&gt;I don’t know — but I’m looking forward to finding out. If we learned anything from 2020, it’s that a fresh year is usually full of surprises. I look forward to exploring them together when &lt;a href="https://www.platformer.news/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Platformer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; returns on January 4th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="vchM78"&gt;
&lt;p id="TPOuVk"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This column was co-published with &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.platformer.news/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Platformer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, a daily newsletter about Big Tech and democracy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nL5MDS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22188075/12-predictions-consumer-internet-2021-labor-apps-social-networks"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22188075/12-predictions-consumer-internet-2021-labor-apps-social-networks</id>
    <author>
      <name>Casey Newton</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-18T14:55:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T14:55:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>CD Projekt Red promises Cyberpunk 2077 refunds ‘out of our own pocket if necessary’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BunwQQDcr3cYBtJ1Y8YZy1J70Ms=/125x0:1475x900/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68549827/screen_image_about_b_40a8febe.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: CD Projekt Red&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wh15ny"&gt;CD Projekt Red (CDPR) has &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CyberpunkGame/status/1340013516628103170"&gt;issued yet another statement&lt;/a&gt; regarding the ongoing &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077 &lt;/em&gt;debacle, this time clarifying its stance on retail refunds for the PlayStation 4 and Xbox One versions of the game that have been riddled with bugs and performance issues since launch last week. The developer now says it will honor every refund request it receives between now and December 21st out of its own pocket. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3JeOVR"&gt;“We’ve just started reaching out to people who sent us a message with a confirmation of receipt. We send these emails out in waves, so don’t worry if you don’t receive an answer immediately,” CDPR writes in its new statement, issued via the official &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; Twitter account on Friday afternoon. “At the same time, we’d like you to know that our intention is for every owner of a physical copy, or a digital copy bought at retail, who has valid proof of purchase (and sends us an email at helpmerefund@cdprojektred.com within the time window) to receive a refund. We will do this out of our own pocket if necessary.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="tbZLaI"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Update on Retail Refunds &lt;a href="https://t.co/7hAHo19jfa"&gt;https://t.co/7hAHo19jfa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/nFMbhvokvl"&gt;pic.twitter.com/nFMbhvokvl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Cyberpunk 2077 (@CyberpunkGame) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CyberpunkGame/status/1340013516628103170?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 18, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="71o91L"&gt;CDPR says digital buyers should pursue refunds from Microsoft and Sony, as both companies have now established formal refund programs for the game. Best Buy is also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189238/best-buy-cyberpunk-2077-returns-cd-projekt-red-refund-xbox-one-ps4"&gt;now taking refunds&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077 &lt;/em&gt;through Monday of next week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JS7SGW"&gt;This latest clarification from CDPR follows the general confusion the studio caused earlier in the week when it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/14/22173738/cyberpunk-2077-developer-apologizes-base-ps4-xbox-one-performance-issues-refunds"&gt;advised disappointed buyers to pursue refunds&lt;/a&gt; through Microsoft, Sony, and retail stores. CDPR at the time also said it would accept refund requests itself, but it did not disclose until after it issued that initial statement that it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22176279/cyberpunk-2077-performance-issues-refunds-microsoft-sony-ps4-xbox-one"&gt;had not established any kind of formal refund program&lt;/a&gt; with any of its partners. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9CwGim"&gt;What followed were revelations that while Microsoft would indeed honor most requests for digital Xbox versions of the game, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22178872/cyberpunk-2077-refund-sony-ps4-ps5-playstation-issue"&gt;Sony would not&lt;/a&gt; for PlayStation buyers due to its more stringent refund policy. Sony &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22188007/sony-cyberpunk-2077-removed-playstation-store-full-refunds-policy"&gt;ultimately pulled the game from its digital storefront&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday evening in an unprecedented move, prompting Microsoft to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189059/microsoft-cyberpunk-2077-refunds-xbox-microsoft-store"&gt;expand its existing refund policy&lt;/a&gt; specifically for buyers of &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;, though the game can still be bought digitally for Xbox devices. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189322/cyberpunk-2077-refund-cd-projekt-red-ps4-xbox-one"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22189322/cyberpunk-2077-refund-cd-projekt-red-ps4-xbox-one</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
