<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-11-11T12:56:05-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-11T12:56:05-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-11T12:56:05-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitch is now on the Switch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MTyO8Qha90Awtibew6HUHAa2NEQ=/0x0:1080x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70128187/screenshot02.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A screenshot of Twitch on the Nintendo Switch.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Twitch&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="owQUeh"&gt;There’s now a Twitch app for the Nintendo Switch. It’s a free download &lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/twitch-switch/"&gt;that’s available now on the eShop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y3oMYd"&gt;The app is pretty straightforward. There’s a Home tab with recommended streams for you to watch, a Browse tab to look for streams by game or category, and a Search tab. I checked out a couple streams, and they looked great, especially on the Switch OLED’s screen. The app is only for watching streams; you can’t use it to stream your gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wijc-cfws2Vi5JjXquAoGuFDmLo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23005969/screenshot01.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Twitch&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nintendo’s profile on the Nintendo Switch Twitch app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="vCeKSD"&gt;The Switch Twitch experience is somewhat more limited than what you might be used to from the Twitch website or app. One big change is that you can’t see a stream’s chat on your Switch’s screen or a TV screen, though you can scan a QR code to see chat on your phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3y9wJg"&gt;If you want to sign in to your account, you fortunately won’t have to wrestle with typing your password in using the Switch’s controls or the touchscreen. You can either scan a QR code on your phone or enter an eight-digit code shown on your screen at &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/activate"&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/activate&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zS77AN"&gt;Streaming options on the Switch are still fairly limited, though there is also &lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/youtube-switch/"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/hulu-switch/"&gt;Hulu&lt;/a&gt; if you want to watch something in between trips to your &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing: New Horizons&lt;/em&gt; island. Here’s hoping we get Netflix someday.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22776560/twitch-app-nintendo-switch-launch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22776560/twitch-app-nintendo-switch-launch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-11T12:40:29-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-11T12:40:29-05:00</updated>
    <title>Russian “King of Fraud” sentenced to 10 years in prison for Methbot digital ad scheme</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LO4s8ZUqqYYjmLTIACtESAJA4rQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70128073/acastro_170621_1777_0001_fin.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="d8dDsA"&gt;A Russian man convicted on wire fraud and money laundering charges for his role in the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/27/18115230/3ve-methbot-operation-eversion-online-ad-fraud-arrest-indictment"&gt;Methbot digital advertising scheme&lt;/a&gt; was &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-edny/pr/russian-cybercriminal-sentenced-10-years-prison-digital-advertising-fraud-scheme"&gt;sentenced to 10 years in prison&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MF9j36"&gt;The Department of Justice said between September 2014 and December 2016, Aleksandr Zhukov, 41, and several co-conspirators made deals with ad networks to place online ads but used a bot farm and rented servers to simulate users visiting spoofed versions of websites like the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;New York Daily News&lt;/em&gt;. The ads were never shown to human users, but Zhukov raked in $7 million running the fake traffic scam (which became known as “Methbot,” after the name of his phony ad network Media Methane), according to the DOJ. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IfLe82"&gt;“Sitting at his computer keyboard in Bulgaria and Russia, Zhukov boldly devised and carried out an elaborate multi-million-dollar fraud against the digital advertising industry, and victimized thousands of companies across the United States,” US Attorney Breon Peace said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Iys1OH"&gt;As part of the elaborate plan, Zhukov recruited programmers and others to help build the infrastructure that made the scheme possible. Authorities said he referred to the recruits as his developers and to himself as “the king of fraud.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sITp2K"&gt;In May, a &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-28/russian-king-of-fraud-is-found-guilty-of-online-ad-scam"&gt;jury convicted Zhukov&lt;/a&gt; of wire fraud conspiracy, wire fraud, money laundering conspiracy, and money laundering. In addition to the 10-year prison term, Zhukov was ordered to pay $3.8 million in forfeiture.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22776481/russian-king-of-fraud-sentenced-10-years-prison-methbot-digital-ad-scheme"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22776481/russian-king-of-fraud-sentenced-10-years-prison-methbot-digital-ad-scheme</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-11T12:40:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-11T12:40:16-05:00</updated>
    <title>The PS5 is available now at Best Buy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0gBvzMWRhNp_29ctfxIPxLLeHp4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70128071/acastro_210511_1777_psRestock_0006.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="But9MD"&gt;If you still haven’t been able to land one of Sony’s next-gen consoles, Best Buy is giving you another shot right now. The &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfYMoENUTqt" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$499.99 PS5 with a disc drive&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfYMojat7P1" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$399.99 digital edition&lt;/a&gt; are available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xUL1fG"&gt;Unlike some of Best Buy’s console restocks, this one is available to the general public online and not just for its TotalTech subscribers. Restocks like these may happen more frequently as we get closer to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/black-friday" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Black Friday&lt;/a&gt;. Still, we recommend heading to the link of choosing as quickly as possible to hop in the queue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="SacwVZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"PS5 review: next-gen feel","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21550146/sony-playstation-5-ps5-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="mhH6xx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10384391"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="eCLQSx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9563999"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="rlMz0K"&gt;A few must-haves for PS5 owners&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="AcAFUa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10499033"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="A03WdX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10499071"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="r2IVEn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10420564"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="DqcXmE"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9734577"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="H0iJHW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22639500/playstation-5-ps5-restock-available-best-buy-queue"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22639500/playstation-5-ps5-restock-available-best-buy-queue</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-11T12:08:49-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-11T12:08:49-05:00</updated>
    <title>Discord CEO says the company won’t add a crypto wallet — for now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YO_jlZ307pfmWuzRvGJsEfLUgzI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70127856/acastro_200318_1777_discord_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="q2YRKh"&gt;On Monday, Discord CEO Jason Citron struck fear (or joy) into the hearts of Discord fans by tweeting a screenshot of what appeared to be &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jasoncitron/status/1457841222995693570"&gt;crypto wallets in the app&lt;/a&gt;, but Wednesday evening, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jasoncitron/status/1458607550677405699"&gt;he said&lt;/a&gt; the company doesn’t actually plan to ship what he was showing off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6QHDkR"&gt;“Thanks for all the perspectives everyone,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jasoncitron/status/1458607550677405699"&gt;Citron said&lt;/a&gt;. “We have no current plans to ship this internal concept. For now we’re focused on protecting users from spam, scams and fraud. Web3 has lots of good but also lots of problems we need to work through at our scale. More soon.” Discord told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; this week that the image was from an internal hackfest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8l8sbu"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Thanks for all the perspectives everyone. We have no current plans to ship this internal concept. For now we're focused on protecting users from spam, scams and fraud. Web3 has lots of good but also lots of problems we need to work through at our scale. More soon.&lt;/p&gt;— Jason Citron (@jasoncitron) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jasoncitron/status/1458607550677405699?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jAzEHp"&gt;Citron’s statement doesn’t entirely rule out the possibility of some kind of crypto / NFT integration in Discord in the future. Based on Citron’s tweet, it sounds as if the company is looking into how it can use “Web3,” which is a shorthand that often refers to a decentralized and crypto-based internet, as well as how it can protect &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22683766/nft-scams-theft-social-engineering-opensea-community-recovery"&gt;against crypto / NFT scams that take place on the platform&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bpyzd6"&gt;The company told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; something similar about its interest in crypto when we asked about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22772164/discord-nft-viral-tweet-social-media-backlash"&gt;a survey mentioning NFTs&lt;/a&gt; that happened to make the rounds just hours before Citron’s Monday tweet. Though that survey was apparently just for research, “we’re always exploring and hacking away at things we think will improve Discord for all the communities we serve,” a Discord spokesperson said. “This includes research that helps us learn about what people want.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lN2EKn"&gt;It doesn’t appear that there will be an official crypto integration with Discord just yet. But don’t be surprised if there eventually is.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22776422/discord-ceo-crypto-nft-wallet-jason-citron-tweet"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22776422/discord-ceo-crypto-nft-wallet-jason-citron-tweet</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-11T12:04:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-11T12:04:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>GM is building a prototype for the US military based on the Hummer EV</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QTffWfHuVRGA8-88GkJr1Mf_eSI=/99x0:1169x713/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70127838/hummer_ev_reveal_suv_gal_my23_hummer_suv_VP33__1_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: General Motors&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5myjs3"&gt;The Hummer has been resurrected as an electric vehicle, and now its military counterpart may be as well. General Motors is making a prototype vehicle for the US military that is based on the forthcoming Hummer EV in 2022, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/11/09/gm-plans-to-produce-military-vehicle-based-on-hummer-ev-in-2022.html?__source=sharebar%7Ctwitter&amp;amp;par=sharebar"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZxryTY"&gt;The so-called “electric Light Reconnaissance Vehicle,” or eLRV, will use modified versions of the Hummer EV’s frame, electric motors, and GM’s new Ultium battery pack, though it may not look exactly like the consumer version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="su6Oyt"&gt;GM resurrected its defense unit in 2017 and said last year that it believes there’s &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/12/22/gms-defense-unit-sees-25-billion-market-in-potential-military-contracts-for-automaker.html"&gt;a $25 billion market for creating new vehicles for the military&lt;/a&gt;, including EVs. It has already nabbed a $214 million contract to build infantry squad vehicles for the Army, including one version that uses parts from the Chevy Bolt EV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HnHz4q"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://watson.brown.edu/costsofwar/files/cow/imce/papers/Pentagon%20Fuel%20Use%2C%20Climate%20Change%20and%20the%20Costs%20of%20War%20Revised%20November%202019%20Crawford.pdf"&gt;2019 study from Brown University&lt;/a&gt; calculated that the US military is the largest institutional polluter in the world and produces more greenhouse gas emissions than 140 countries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XKvjoU"&gt;That has inspired a few other would-be electric vehicle manufacturers to target the military fleet in addition to GM. Both Nikola and Lordstown Motors have built demonstration vehicles and pitched them as potentially huge lines of business — though neither struggling startup has been able to strike a deal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ma7Xc7"&gt;While GM sees great opportunity selling EVs to the military, it doesn’t sound like the Hummer-based eLRV will become as ubiquitous as the original gas-powered Hummer — at least not right away. Kathleen Hicks, the deputy secretary of the defense department, told &lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt; that she believes integrating electric vehicles in the military’s fleet will be “very challenging,” especially because of charging infrastructure. But, she said, “[e]lectrifying the non-tactical fleet, that’s a no-brainer.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22776324/general-motors-hummer-ev-us-military-prototype-defense"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22776324/general-motors-hummer-ev-us-military-prototype-defense</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-11T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-11T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Patreon’s building native video hosting for creators to sidestep YouTube</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Patreon clip art" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Kg9VGB9PUOzifhNA4NdturY0jwY=/200x0:1400x800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70127710/International_Patreon_send.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Patreon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="72fJ9S"&gt;Patreon is building a video hosting solution and native player. CEO Jack Conte confirmed the project to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, alongside news that he is joining many executives before him in &lt;a href="https://www.creatoreconomypodcast.com/"&gt;launching a podcast&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;em&gt;The Creator Economy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Q5Ib2"&gt;“We already host podcasts, and now we’re starting to host video, as well,” he says. “We’re building a video product ... So in terms of how we’ve approached our strategy, and what exactly it is that we’re building, we’re building the horizontal architecture for any creator, no matter their medium, or no matter the upload format, to be able to build a business around their work.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ODd0SX"&gt;Conte didn’t share more details on the product, but it’s presumably a way for creators to host and share video without leaving the platform. It’s still unclear when it might launch or how broadly it would be deployed. We’ve reached out to a spokesperson for additional context and will update if we hear back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NI8h40"&gt;Still, Conte’s acknowledgment of the goal and progress on allowing creators to natively host their videos on Patreon could allow more people to avoid YouTube, or at least not rely on it so heavily. The company also &lt;a href="https://support.patreon.com/hc/en-us/articles/360017431292-Share-my-videos-with-patrons"&gt;maintains an integration&lt;/a&gt; with Vimeo that might become less important as this feature launches. Of course, the idea of a company launching its own native video product in the year of 2021 feels bold but speaks to the broader discontent brewing over YouTube’s dominance and Patreon’s own interest in becoming fully self-reliant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="oAtT52"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"podcasts"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Atgi4F"&gt;The timing of the announcement is particularly interesting because Conte’s podcast focuses on the techier side of creators. Conte won’t be interviewing Patreon creators, but rather people who are building and funding tools for them to use, like Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian and Li Jin, founder and managing partner at Atelier. Conte says the idea is to put Patreon’s name next to these folks and share its vision for the creator world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BgaYry"&gt;“We want to attract the most awesome, forward-thinking, curious people who are building for the creator economy to Patreon,” he says. “We want those people to hear how we think about the world, and our vision, and what we want to build, and what we believe in, and who we are.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SHMtFS"&gt;The show will be ad-free and free to access on all platforms — there’s no Patreon-funded tier — and will be released seasonally with 12 episodes planned.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22774301/patreon-jack-conte-video-player-podcast-youtube-launch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22774301/patreon-jack-conte-video-player-podcast-youtube-launch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-11T11:25:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-11T11:25:30-05:00</updated>
    <title>Now Dollar General will do same-day deliveries via DoorDash</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Dollar General is on DoorDash" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BUlQaDqJiT5kY_FqHviACovh_fw=/140x0:1660x1013/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70127486/Dollar_General_PR_Image.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Dollar General&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7zMifA"&gt;Besides its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774485/doordash-acquires-wolt-stock-europe-international"&gt;European expansion&lt;/a&gt;, DoorDash is reaching into new areas within the United States via an expanded &lt;a href="https://newscenter.dollargeneral.com/news/dollar-general-and-doordash-announce-partnership-to-offer-on-demand-delivery-of-everyday-essentials.htm"&gt;partnership with Dollar General that’s already available via 9,000 locations&lt;/a&gt;. Gig economy services initially proliferated in urban areas, using venture capital money to push the convenience of getting everything from cold medicine to a single candy bar hand-delivered within the hour. However, if you don’t live around tall buildings, the services become fewer and farther between, and so do the shops that work with them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fvT8YU"&gt;Now the two promise same-day delivery with no time slot or minimum order size required. A pilot program started this summer with 600 Dollar General locations, and a press release states that more than 10,000 will appear in DoorDash listings by December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tEPPH5"&gt;The arrangement highlights many realities of American life, both pre- and peri-pandemic. For some people, it could open up access and independence that otherwise wasn’t available because they live somewhere without Instacart or a fleet of electric Ubers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="vTa2Ix"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Sick Days: The human cost of Instacart’s grocery delivery ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21267669/instacart-shoppers-sick-extended-pay-quarantine-leave-coronavirus"},{"title":"Revolt of the NYC Delivery Workers","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22667600/delivery-workers-seamless-uber-relay-new-york-electric-bikes-apps"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="jj4qw6"&gt;It also puts together workers who have been among those hardest-pressed during the last two years. &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/26/opinion/covid-workers-dollar-general.html"&gt;Dollar store employees&lt;/a&gt; and couriers have frequently faced &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/09/30/business/dollar-stores-struggling-pandemic.html"&gt;low wages&lt;/a&gt;, risky conditions, lack of sick leave or health insurance, and a tense customer base despite being deemed “essential.” Now they’ll combine to provide on-demand deliveries (“in under an hour on average”) across some areas that haven’t been living with the services yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Uh4WTl"&gt;And even if the partnership works out perfectly for DoorDash, Dollar General, customers, and the people who deliver everything from a pack of Skittles to fresh groceries, their competition will have to deal with it. Reports over the last few years from &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/07/13/nyregion/dollar-stores-thriving.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://slate.com/business/2021/07/dollar-general-food-deserts-grocery-stores.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reflect how independent discount stores and grocery stores can struggle to compete with or operate in areas where dollar stores open. Dollar General sees itself as a solution for food and &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/09/08/dollar-general-ceo-says-majority-of-its-stores-are-in-health-deserts.html"&gt;health deserts&lt;/a&gt;, but if other stores close, that could further impact local economies and access to healthy options.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22776139/doordash-dollar-general-store-delivery"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22776139/doordash-dollar-general-store-delivery</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-11T10:22:32-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-11T10:22:32-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s second-gen AirPods are back down to their lowest price ever</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Apple’s second-generation AirPods" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eU2mdpThIKzda2eDhRtOQxRloUE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70127040/akrales_190327_3315_0012.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="C2cDn1"&gt;Grab the second-gen Apple AirPods at &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/994132/9383?subId1=VergeBestAirPods030121&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Charging-Case-Latest-Model%2F604342441%3F&amp;amp;veh=aff" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart for just $89&lt;/a&gt;, matching the lowest price we’ve seen for these earbuds. This model normally costs around $120 and doesn’t include the wireless charging case. This model of the ubiquitous white earbuds wasn’t a big step forward compared to the first iteration, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;our reviewer&lt;/a&gt; was still happy with their wireless performance and overall reliability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Ss1wLM"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xPd26T"&gt;A pair of Samsung’s best QLED TVs have been marked down at Amazon and Best Buy as part of their &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22759214/black-friday-early-deals-best-headphones-laptops-gaming-tvs-tech-sale"&gt;early Black Friday deals&lt;/a&gt;. QLED TVs aren’t quite as feature-packed as competing OLED models, but they come closer to reaching parity with their brightness and contrast ratios than cheaper LED TVs. The 65-inch QN90A from Samsung is currently marked down to $1,700 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08V3K77SC?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfYn0pZSaa5" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, roughly $400 cheaper than the MSRP, and the lowest price we’ve seen for this model. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qE8BKi"&gt;The high-end 65-inch QN800A has also hit its all-time low at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfYnu6caUw0" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-65-Inch-Class-QN800A-Built/dp/B08VJMWWHJ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and is marked down to $2,500 at both retailers. This model has many of the same benefits as the QN90A above, such as smart assistant capability and access to the Tizen streaming platform, however, the GN800A is capable of a maximum 8K resolution in addition to 4K playback at 120Hz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="VMx7cU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10462562"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="pwW56P"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10857302"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="laR87h"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best gaming TV to buy for the PS5 and Xbox Series X ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22399437/best-gaming-tv-playstation5-ps5-xbox-series-x-s"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="NB9tPD"&gt;This 48-inch soundbar from the audio experts at Klipsch is currently enjoying a deep discount at Woot. This same system is discounted elsewhere for as low as $600, but &lt;a href="https://www.kqzyfj.com/click-8836598-13140759?url=https%3A%2F%2Felectronics.woot.com%2Foffers%2Fklipsch-bar48-5-1-surround-sound-system-4%3Fref%3Dw_cnt_lnd_cat_elec_5_5" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Woot currently has the best price at $480&lt;/a&gt;. This is easily the best price we’ve seen on this system so far, and it matches the price we’ve seen for similar 5.1 sound systems from JBL and Sony. This system comes packaged with wireless rear-channel speakers and a wireless subwoofer to keep cable clutter to a minimum, and while this soundbar only has a single HDMI port, this shouldn’t be an issue as long as your TV has an audio return channel (HDMI ARC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TJtMvl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10857246"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZZRMVt"&gt;A mainstay of the noise-canceling headphone category, the Bose QuietComfort 35 Series II are currently discounted by $100 at &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fbose-quietcomfort-35-noise-cancelling-wireless-headphones-ii%2F-%2FA-52955552&amp;amp;subid1=VergeDeals111121" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;. Normally $300, they’re $200 for now. Available in black and silver, these robust noise-canceling headphones offer up to 20 hours of playtime between charges, and you have the choice between using Alexa or Google Assistant capabilities to direct playback or search for music. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3Sm2ou"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10833603"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FL3azF"&gt;A great companion to any streamer or podcaster, the Blue Yeti USB microphone is on sale at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Blue-Yeti-USB-Microphone-Blackout/dp/B00N1YPXW2?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon for $100&lt;/a&gt;, matching one of its best prices to date. The Yeti can conform to a number of recording environments with its optional software download, which also allows you to change pickup patterns, modulate, and fine-tune your audio in other ways you might find to be useful. The mic comes packaged with its own stand but is also compatible with a wide variety of mic arms if that’s more your style. The current discount applies to the black, blue, gray, and silver models, meaning you’ve got a variety of styles to choose between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="P0EAmE"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10650797"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BAsMY2"&gt;Available by itself or as part of a bundle, the Abode Cam 2 is an excellent entry point for anyone who wants to step up their home security, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fgoabode.com%2Fproduct%2Fabode-cam-2&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F11%2F11%2F22774231%2Fapple-airpods-samsung-tv-soundbar-bose-headphones-steelseries-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;and at $25&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll have a hard time finding a better value. This versatile little indoor / outdoor camera can be mounted nearly anywhere and provides you with motion detection, two-way communication, and low-light recording. While it isn’t compatible with Apple HomeKit, it does play well with both Alexa and Google Assistant. However, this camera doesn’t have local storage, so access to some of its best features requires a subscription to one of the Abode plans, either $6 / month for motion-activated recording or $15 / month to have the camera record 24/7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XILNgW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10856996"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tVCt71"&gt;The tail end of our deals roundup today is a big one. In anticipation of Black Friday, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fsteelseries.com%2Fblackfriday&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F11%2F11%2F22774231%2Fapple-airpods-samsung-tv-soundbar-bose-headphones-steelseries-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SteelSeries has discounted the entirety of its peripheral catalog by as much as 50 percent&lt;/a&gt;, with many of these accessories available for their lowest price ever. The only caveat is that you need to have a SteelSeries account to take part. The Arctis Pro headset and GameDAC is &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fsteelseries.com%2Fgaming-headsets%2Farctis-pro-gamedac%3Fcolor%3Dblack&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F11%2F11%2F22774231%2Fapple-airpods-samsung-tv-soundbar-bose-headphones-steelseries-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;down to $160&lt;/a&gt; — a wired headset available in black or white and compatible with PlayStation or Windows platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Bxoisb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10750030"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="0ZMUis"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best wired or wireless gaming headsets to buy","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21549510/best-gaming-headset-wired-wireless-features-specs-price-sound-microphone-test-buy"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="XqPboy"&gt;The Apex Pro keyboard, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fsteelseries.com%2Fgaming-keyboards%2Fapex-pro&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F11%2F11%2F22774231%2Fapple-airpods-samsung-tv-soundbar-bose-headphones-steelseries-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available for $160&lt;/a&gt;, does something unique among mechanical keyboards by allowing you to fine-tune the actuation distance for each individual key. Another neat addition is a small OLED screen that can provide you with contextual info like profile selection or volume adjustment, or you can use it to play GIFs, if that's your thing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8OEXdh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10612568"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tDyNdo"&gt;Adopting the incredibly popular honeycomb shell design to shed a few ounces, the Aerox 3 Wireless has been &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fsteelseries.com%2Fgaming-mice%2Faerox-3-wireless&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F11%2F11%2F22774231%2Fapple-airpods-samsung-tv-soundbar-bose-headphones-steelseries-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;discounted to $70&lt;/a&gt;, taking $30 off the regular retail price. Weighing in at a paltry 68 grams, the Aerox 3 Wireless features Bluetooth and 2.4GHz wireless connectivity and has a maximum DPI of 18K. The mouse is rechargeable via USB-C and SteelSeries claims it lasts up to 200 hours between charges. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XJEozH"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10221749"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="4bfzKu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best wired or wireless gaming mouse you can buy","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21252193/best-gaming-mouse"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="TQva6F"&gt;Some more deals that you might be interested in&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="rBkj1p"&gt;The Beats Studio Buds are available refurbished in every color through Best Buy, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfYJKNQOC64" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;costing $95&lt;/a&gt;. These originally sold for $150, and Best Buy claims that they include all original accessories (three sizes of ear tips, a USB-C cable, and a sticker).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="xiTQBv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/11/11/22774231/apple-airpods-samsung-tv-soundbar-bose-headphones-steelseries-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/11/11/22774231/apple-airpods-samsung-tv-soundbar-bose-headphones-steelseries-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-11T09:36:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-11T09:36:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>Subaru reveals the Solterra SUV, its first electric vehicle</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="World Premier Of Subaru’s First All-Electric SUV Solterra" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kX8bMJWQtwmz9_6nc66EnnKiVNw=/161x73:3743x2461/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70126763/1236489408.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="NTvRaB"&gt;Here’s our first good look at the 2022 Subaru Solterra, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/11/22430524/subaru-solterra-ev-electric-suv-2022-release-us-europe-japan-toyota"&gt;the Japanese automaker’s first electric vehicle&lt;/a&gt;. Coming to the US, Canada, and Europe in 2022, the Solterra SUV will be powered by an electric vehicle platform that Subaru has been co-developing with Toyota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r41mon"&gt;The Solterra will come in both front-wheel and all-wheel drive variants, with either a 150kW (201 horsepower) AC synchronous motor driving just the front wheels or a pair of 80kW (107 hp) motors, one powering each axle, for a total output of 160kW (214hp). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iPA7qV"&gt;Both models sport a 71.4kWh battery beneath the floor of the vehicle, which Subaru estimates will supply approximately 530km (329 miles) of range based on the WLTC standard in Japan. (The EPA rating in the US is likely to be less.) And the all-wheel drive version will get 460km (286 miles) of range. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JMHH4K"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10859067"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rtnEVe"&gt;When the battery is running low, the Solterra can support DC fast charging up to 150kW — although Subaru didn’t provide estimates for how long it would take. By comparison, Toyota has said that its BZ4X, which is built on the same EV platform, will take 30 minutes to charge to 80 percent capacity. The BZ4X is also due out in 2022 and will be built on this shared platform, which Toyota calls the e-TNGA and Subaru calls e-Subaru. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="FkTnth"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Both models sport a 71.4kWh battery beneath the floor of the vehicle&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VG5CDy"&gt;Unlike the BZ4X, though, the Solterra appears to have a normal interior and steering wheel. (Toyota is including an optional &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22752539/toyota-bz4x-electric-suv-steering-yoke-solar-roof"&gt;steering yoke&lt;/a&gt; in its electric SUV.)  Subaru says that like its other gas-powered SUVs, the Solterra will feature the company’s X-Mode AWD control system that “enhances the sense of security on rough roads.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y6D2xL"&gt;It’s also added a new “Grip Control function, which enables the vehicle to run at a constant speed while stabilizing the vehicle even on rough roads, the capability is further enhanced.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4PxSHG"&gt;When it comes out next year, Subaru will no doubt be competing with Rivian for its customer base of outdoorsy adventure types. The company hasn’t revealed the Solterra’s starting price, but it’s likely to be less expensive than &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/27/18113257/rivian-r1s-suv-electric-la-auto-show-2018"&gt;the Rivian R1S SUV&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22776173/subaru-solterra-electric-suv-specs-range"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22776173/subaru-solterra-electric-suv-specs-range</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-11T09:13:09-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-11T09:13:09-05:00</updated>
    <title>Rivian’s mega IPO is a good test of the meme stock craze</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="EV Maker Rivian Raises $11.9 Billion In Year’s Biggest IPO" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mlcKe6Cix6EDDS9n_j7VqfnohQw=/0x0:4000x2667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70126669/1236479813.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;‘Lmaoooo 80B do they think we’re fucking stupid?’&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="aTsRub"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774403/rivian-ipo-debut-evs-12-billion-amazon-tesla-valuation"&gt;Rivian’s hotly anticipated public debut is finally here&lt;/a&gt;, but the electric vehicle company is not generating the same kind of feverish online posting as its rival Tesla or other EV startups — and that’s probably a good thing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Et3tjS"&gt;Don’t get me wrong. The company’s IPO, which will net $12 billion on an $80 billion valuation, is proving to be an immensely attractive stock and is already drawing comparisons to other historic public offerings like Facebook. But for anyone who gets their investment news from Reddit forums like r/WallStreetBets, the Rivian IPO was more likely to draw an eye-roll, an off-color remark, or a crude emoji. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MwcapE"&gt;“Lmaoooo 80B do they think we’re fucking stupid?” &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/wallstreetbets/comments/pcp4jv/comment/hakj2nl/?utm_source=reddit&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3"&gt;one user wrote last month&lt;/a&gt; in response to the news about Rivian’s upcoming IPO. “Bro they must think since stonks only go up, this shit will surpass it with no prob. What a crazy year.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="7eYSPJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Lmaoooo 80B do they think we’re fucking stupid?”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Jw9bqR"&gt;Tesla’s status as a meme stock has helped propel the Bay Area-based (and soon to be Austin, Texas-based) company’s share price into the stratosphere and make its CEO Elon Musk one of the richest people in the world. The share price has been on an upward trajectory since early 2020 and has shown little signs of flagging. Even mundane headlines like Tesla’s not-a-deal with rental car agency Hertz was enough to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744504/hertz-tesla-order-100000-vehicles-electrify-fleet"&gt;push Musk’s company past the $1 trillion mark&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uTYsA4"&gt;Which is not to say being a meme stock is a safe space to occupy. An errant tweet from Musk last year about the stock being overvalued sent the share price tumbling and wiped out $14 billion of Tesla’s market value. The Federal Reserve thinks meme stocks &lt;a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/story/the-fed-thinks-meme-stocks-threaten-the-financial-structure-retail-investors-say-thats-kind-of-the-point-11636498740"&gt;threaten the stability of the financial system&lt;/a&gt;, to which retail investors say that’s kind of the point. Meanwhile, Tesla has regained the value it lost after Musk’s tweet, and then some. (Musk is in the midst of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22775485/elon-musk-twitter-poll-tesla-stock-option-sold-taxes"&gt;selling off 10 percent&lt;/a&gt; of his shares in Tesla.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Z1HUg"&gt;On November 10th, the day of Rivian’s big public debut, Tesla’s stock was still the most popular ticker on Reddit, according to &lt;a href="https://apewisdom.io/"&gt;Ape Wisdom&lt;/a&gt;, which tracks the popular stocks on the message board. Rivian is listed as the seventh most popular stock, beating other meme stocks like GameStop and AMC but trailing regular ones like DoorDash and Palantir. The next day, Rivian had dropped to ninth place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qxwkEW"&gt;“Being a meme stock, to some extent, is conjuring the dark arts of the world,” said Reilly Brennan, general partner at venture capital firm Trucks. “It’s really hard to do it consistently over a long period of time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="0E1PqY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Being a meme stock, to some extent, is conjuring the dark arts of the world”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tsdMcb"&gt;Rivian’s future is unwritten, but the company doesn’t seem to have the necessary ingredients to make a meme stock. Its founder and CEO, RJ Scaringe, is not especially active on Twitter, does not court controversy for the sake of controversy, and doesn’t appear to aspire to anything other than leading a company that makes really great electric trucks, SUVs, and vans. If he has an edgy sense of humor, we’ve yet to see evidence of it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZCSp3E"&gt;Rivian has far fewer online fans than Tesla by virtue of the fact that its vehicles have yet to reach customers. (The company’s electric truck, the R1T, is expected to begin deliveries before the end of the year.) But the company appears to be cultivating a customer base of wealthy outdoors types — not necessarily the type of person who would project their own identity onto an EV company and then respond to any criticism of said company by &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/10/28/cars/tesla-ntsb-cummings/index.html"&gt;losing their shit online&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2t8DMq"&gt;If meme stocks, in essence, represent a middle finger to institutional investors and short-sellers, then Rivian was already going to have a tough row to hoe. The company has yet to find itself in the crosshairs of any major short-seller. And Rivian has a host of brand-name backers, such as Amazon (which owns 20 percent of the company) and Ford (which helped manufacture all of the company’s preproduction vehicles). Investing in Rivian would hardly demonstrate any rebellion against the system. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cVeRpOt3F5Ow0Mn0slwbUDifDEY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22883223/mclark_210923_4776_0019.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Mitchell Clark / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="xqs3Mt"&gt;Rivian’s slow and deliberate approach stands in contrast to other companies that briefly achieved meme stock status, only to watch it slip away. Hydrogen trucking startup Nikola was able to run up a $30 billion valuation on little more than a few buzzy videos and a CEO doing his best Musk impression. But after going public, and just as the startup was about to secure an investment from General Motors, Nikola’s then CEO Trevor Milton was accused of lying to investors. Milton eventually stepped down and, this year, was arrested and indicted on multiple counts of fraud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a92zyg"&gt;Rivian’s lack of meme-worthy moments makes it an interesting test case for the public market’s appetite for what Brennan calls a “pure play” EV company — an automaker that is only making electric vehicles. Major car companies like Ford and GM are often left talking out of both sides of their mouth, touting huge investments in EV production and battery manufacturing, while also continuing to sell gas-guzzling trucks and SUVs that pollute the environment. Other pure EV companies, like Lucid Motors, went public by merging with a blank-check company, or SPAC, and all the risks that entails. Rivian doesn’t have that same kind of baggage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ahfyKt"&gt;“The company has very little in the way of meme currency,” Brennan, who is not an investor in the company, said. “They haven’t done a lot of the things that the rest of the market has done, whether you’re talking about the brand new EV SPAC [special acquisition] companies or Tesla. So I just think inherently there’s a quiet storm aspect of Rivian’s growth over the next few years, which is utterly fascinating.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22774719/rivian-ipo-meme-stock-tesla-reddit-wallstreetbets"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22774719/rivian-ipo-meme-stock-tesla-reddit-wallstreetbets</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
