<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-03T14:43:52-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-03T14:43:52-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-03T14:43:52-05:00</updated>
    <title>Valve says DayZ and five other games are now anti-cheat ready for Linux (and Steam Deck)</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/whEbcF56vIcAGHnrHFZZfXz_7_k=/0x0:1620x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70225471/steam_deck.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Valve&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aceLth"&gt;Valve’s Steam Deck handheld &lt;a href="https://partner.steamgames.com/doc/steamdeck/faq"&gt;won’t have any exclusive games&lt;/a&gt;, but it is slowly filling in some holes in its Windows game library — &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/group/4145017/view/3104663180636096966"&gt;Valve says&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Arma 3&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; DayZ&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Unturned&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Planetside 2&lt;/em&gt; now have functioning BattlEye anti-cheat when you’re using the Proton compatibility layer to play Windows games in Linux. That brings the total to six games, including &lt;em&gt;Ark: Survival Evolved&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Mount &amp;amp; Blade II: Bannerlord. &lt;/em&gt;(Those two already had support &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22737127/valve-steam-deck-battleye-anti-cheat-pubg-dayz-r6-siege"&gt;as of November 8th&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jGOeGB"&gt;That compatibility is important for Linux in general (and the Steam Deck handheld specifically) because they don’t play Windows games out of the box &lt;em&gt;unless&lt;/em&gt; they work with Proton, and third-party anti-cheat software is known to interfere. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E78wga"&gt;But for two of the most popular flavors of anti-cheat, this shouldn’t be a difficult fix! Epic Games has said enabling Easy Anti-Cheat (EAC) in Proton should take “just a few clicks” in the game developer portal. Valve has said enabling BattlEye is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22737127/valve-steam-deck-battleye-anti-cheat-pubg-dayz-r6-siege"&gt;as easy as sending an email&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="2lRxXp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Destiny 2 feels like an obvious Steam Deck candidate&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="O6tZoA"&gt;And yet, the developers in charge of many of the top anti-cheat games on Steam have been unwilling or unable to confirm whether they’ll actually send that email or make those clicks, including Bungie, Crytek, EA, Krafton, Microsoft, and Ubisoft. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PEyPN3"&gt;While many top games run on the Steam Deck, we do not currently know if &lt;em&gt;Apex Legends, Destiny 2, Halo,&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;PUBG&lt;/em&gt; will be among them, for example. Epic would also not commit to &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;, despite enabling Easy Anti-Cheat for Proton in general. That’s not a Steam title, though, and Epic does see Valve as a competitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NkC2Om"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22709918/valve-steam-deck-supported-games-anti-cheat-proton-eac-battleye-epic"&gt;Here’s our full running list of responses from game studios with top anti-cheat games&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="5FTGt9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Steam Deck: Five big things we learned from Valve’s developer summit","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22779252/steam-deck-things-we-learned-from-valve-developer-summit"},{"title":"This is the Steam Deck’s box","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/2/22814910/steam-deck-box-package-power-adapter"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="EF9A89"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Steam Deck: a Switch-like portable gaming PC|103274" data-volume-uuid="2d2697872" data-volume-id="103274" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-833" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816279/valve-proton-battleye-anti-cheat-dayz-linux-steam-deck"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816279/valve-proton-battleye-anti-cheat-dayz-linux-steam-deck</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-03T14:41:27-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-03T14:41:27-05:00</updated>
    <title>US State Department phones were reportedly hacked by NSO spyware</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iYl3CTius06V-4PQrxvyFxyHDf4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70225455/acastro_170621_1777_0006_v4.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="npOy6x"&gt;At least nine employees of the US State Department working in or with Uganda had their iPhones hacked with spyware made by NSO Group, according to &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/exclusive-us-state-department-phones-hacked-with-israeli-company-spyware-sources-2021-12-03/"&gt;a report from &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. While it’s unclear who carried out the attacks, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22589942/nso-group-pegasus-project-amnesty-investigation-journalists-activists-targeted"&gt;NSO Group says&lt;/a&gt; it only sells its software to government organizations that have gotten approval from the Israeli government. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CjB8yZ"&gt;NSO has claimed that its spyware isn’t able to target US phone numbers (that is, numbers with a country code of +1). This case doesn’t seem to disprove that claim — &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; reports that, while the people targeted were employees of the State Department, they were using foreign telephone numbers. Still, the devices were used for official State Department business, suggesting NSO may now be implicated in an espionage effort against the US government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N0GCDk"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;, the attacks happened in “the last several months.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="fPIev3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Pegasus is powerful spyware that could infect phones without the user noticing&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aeITGI"&gt;NSO’s Pegasus spyware is capable of remotely logging data from an infected iOS or Android device and can be used to covertly turn on a phone’s microphones or cameras. It’s also designed to infect phones using a “zero-click” attack, in which spyware can be installed without the target clicking a link or otherwise taking action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hjxCuD"&gt;Pegasus is also not supposed to leave any traces, though investigators have developed some methods to determine if a phone was hacked by it. You can &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22589942/nso-group-pegasus-project-amnesty-investigation-journalists-activists-targeted"&gt;read our explainer on it here&lt;/a&gt;, which goes into the media investigations of its usage by governments to target journalists, politicians, and activists. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S2nLMU"&gt;NSO, based in Israel, has to get approval from the Israeli Ministry of Defense before it sells its software to another government agency. NSO co-founder Shalev Hulio has insisted that the company doesn’t know who its clients are spying on using its software. The company also says that it will investigate clients if they’re using Pegasus on off-limits targets and cut off the client’s access to the software if there’s evidence of abuse. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="smQ4B7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Pegasus is meant to be used against criminals and terrorists but has a long history of abuse&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="axdAIx"&gt;An NSO spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; that the company would be investigating its reports, and the Israeli embassy told the outlet that a government targeting US officials with Pegasus would be “a severe violation” of its licensing agreements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ISa9ZP"&gt;The US recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761565/nso-group-pegasus-spyware-entity-list-us-government-human-rights"&gt;added NSO to its entity list&lt;/a&gt;, which puts heavy restrictions on American companies being able to sell their products or services to the group. In the private sector, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22798917/apple-nso-group-spyware-pegasus-cybersecurity-research"&gt;Apple filed a lawsuit against NSO Group&lt;/a&gt;, claiming that the company broke Apple’s terms of service by creating over a hundred iCloud accounts to send malicious data via iMessage. Apple says that it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22672352/apple-spyware-gateway-iphone-software-update-nso-pegasus"&gt;patched the specific vulnerability NSO used&lt;/a&gt; to install Pegasus with iOS 14.8 and that it had added additional protections in iOS 15, which the company says it hasn’t seen Pegasus breach yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3zeNci"&gt;When the company announced its lawsuit, Apple said it would also notify users who had been targeted by a state-sponsored spying campaign. Ugandan politician Norbert Mao &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/norbertmao/status/1463364241688305664"&gt;tweeted in November&lt;/a&gt; that he received one of the notifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ex6GDO"&gt;There are also reports that the US government is working on an initiative with other countries to prevent surveillance tools and technology from being sold to authoritarian governments. &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/biden-us-china-export-surveillance-human-rights-11638471880"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the effort will focus on export controls and will likely be announced at the Summit for Democracy, which starts December 9th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816068/us-state-department-officials-nso-pegasus-uganda-government-spyware"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816068/us-state-department-officials-nso-pegasus-uganda-government-spyware</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-03T14:36:02-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-03T14:36:02-05:00</updated>
    <title>As warehouses take off, they need to kick natural gas </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Snarled Supply Chain Is Making U.S. Warehouse Shortage Worse" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GiFfAeeseSNyi_u4b-N2PUGqfxg=/2x0:4199x2798/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70225425/1236465519.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Warehouses in Redlands, California, U.S., on Sunday, Nov. 7, 2021.&amp;nbsp; | Roger Kisby/Bloomberg via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RFMCX3"&gt;Warehouses are increasingly dominating the commercial building landscape in the US, which could have ramifications for efforts to tackle climate change. According to &lt;a href="https://www.eia.gov/todayinenergy/detail.php?id=50496"&gt;data&lt;/a&gt; recently released by the US Energy Information Administration (EIA), warehouses and storage units have become the most common commercial buildings in the country — outpacing offices. That has the potential to cause greenhouse gas emissions to climb or tumble, and it largely hinges on whether warehouses can ditch natural gas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S82waM"&gt;Compared to office buildings, warehouses that store everything from food to clothes tend to rely more heavily on gas heating systems because upfront costs of those systems are cheap, and they’re easy to install, an expert tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Even though warehouses typically use less energy than offices, there’s a risk that their reliance on gas could increase the share of emissions coming from commercial buildings, which are already responsible for &lt;a href="https://www.energy.gov/eere/buildings/about-commercial-buildings-integration-program"&gt;16 percent&lt;/a&gt; of the country’s greenhouse gas pollution. For the Biden administration to reach its goal of &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/04/22/fact-sheet-president-biden-sets-2030-greenhouse-gas-pollution-reduction-target-aimed-at-creating-good-paying-union-jobs-and-securing-u-s-leadership-on-clean-energy-technologies/"&gt;halving&lt;/a&gt; America’s&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;planet-heating carbon pollution compared to 2005 levels by 2030, it’ll have to work to clean up warehouse operations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2KGMsi"&gt;“If the building sector itself has moved, that means our strategy has to be adapted,” says Bing Liu, building subsector leader at the Pacific Northwest National Laboratory. “If you look at space heating energy use, because [warehouses use] less efficient technologies, it’s actually concerning.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="nJqZsp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;E-commerce has fueled the boom in warehouses&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NSXp8z"&gt;E-commerce has fueled the boom in warehouses. Online retail giants like Amazon use massive distribution centers to sort and send out their goods. Every $1 billion in online sales generates 1.25 million square feet of warehouse space demand, according to commercial real estate firm &lt;a href="https://www.cbre.us/research-and-reports/2021-US-Real-Estate-Market-Outlook-Industrial-Logistics"&gt;CBRE&lt;/a&gt;. The square footage of storage spaces in the US has ballooned from just over 10 billion square feet in 1999 to roughly 17 billion square feet in 2018 (the most recent year for which the EIA has data). That’s more floorspace than more than 295,000 football fields would cover.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TbmGFs"&gt;While we don’t have data yet from the EIA beyond 2018, the pandemic has driven up demand for warehouse space even further. Online shopping became even &lt;a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/marketing-and-sales/our-insights/the-great-consumer-shift-ten-charts-that-show-how-us-shopping-behavior-is-changing"&gt;more popular&lt;/a&gt;. And with consumers still demanding quick deliveries despite kinks in supply chains, retailers are increasingly &lt;a href="https://12exx71wc3m46es1m3w8fvx1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/ElionPartners_iREOCMemberReport_Jun2020.pdf"&gt;storing excess inventory&lt;/a&gt; in warehouses. At the same time, demand for &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/02/business/economy/remote-work-manhattan-storefronts.html"&gt;retail&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/29/nyregion/remote-work-coronavirus-pandemic.html"&gt;office&lt;/a&gt; space has taken a hit during the pandemic because of remote work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hrap2p"&gt;There is a lot of room for warehouses to improve when it comes to their impact on the environment. Liu says warehouse developers can take the lead of office buildings that have been quicker to electrify and switch from natural gas heating systems over to electric&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;heat pumps. Some climate-conscious cities, starting with Berkeley, California, in the US, have moved to ban natural gas hook-ups in new construction — efforts that the gas industry is &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/02/22/967439914/as-cities-grapple-with-climate-change-gas-utilities-fight-to-stay-in-business"&gt;trying to derail&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="5ItLgY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There is a lot of room for warehouses to improve&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jRJyu6"&gt;Other trends could make pollution from warehouses’ gas heating a bigger problem. A lot of e-commerce warehouses are clustered in sunny Southern California, where &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/29/22808388/amazon-target-port-congestion-pollution-maritime-shipping"&gt;Amazon sends much of its imported goods&lt;/a&gt;. But there’s recently been more warehouse growth in colder regions in the midwest — which raises the urgency for transitioning warehouses to cleaner heating, according to Liu. On top of that, warehouses tend to be less insulated against the elements than office buildings.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;And as the Biden administration moves to keep &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22800410/black-friday-holiday-shopping-supply-chain-pollution-ports-warehouses-california"&gt;ports open 24/7&lt;/a&gt; to ease supply chain backlogs, that might mean bigger heating bills for warehouses because of longer operating hours stretching into colder evenings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cw0wKX"&gt;On the other hand, if warehouses sort out the heating issue, their rising popularity could potentially drive down greenhouse gas emissions for the commercial building sector. Unrefrigerated warehouses, which make up the biggest chunk of storage buildings, typically use less than half as much energy per square foot compared with office buildings, according to the EIA. That’s because there aren’t so many computers to keep running or people to keep comfortable with air conditioning and hot water. Ultimately, having a larger share of less energy-intensive buildings like warehouses “has the potential to bring down total commercial energy use,” Zack Marohl, an economist at the EIA, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; in an email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mx2wQw"&gt;There are, of course, other environmental issues to tackle with warehouses. Building materials and construction are responsible for about &lt;a href="https://wedocs.unep.org/bitstream/handle/20.500.11822/34572/GSR_ES.pdf?sequence=3&amp;amp;isAllowed=y"&gt;10 percent&lt;/a&gt; of global greenhouse gas emissions, so Liu says finding sustainable alternatives to materials like cement should be a priority this decade. What’s more, warehouses can be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22800410/black-friday-holiday-shopping-supply-chain-pollution-ports-warehouses-california"&gt;magnets for tailpipe pollution&lt;/a&gt; from diesel trucks — which can pose health threats to nearby neighborhoods. That only underscores the extra benefits turning to clean energy can have. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="kDmo6o"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Satellite images show online shopping’s growing footprint ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21611862/satellite-images-online-shopping-growing-footprint-warehouses"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id="nveQMH"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Amazon and Target play ‘outsized’ role in port congestion and pollution, report finds ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/29/22808388/amazon-target-port-congestion-pollution-maritime-shipping"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="v8lPXO"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d23HoE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816131/warehouses-natural-gas-emissions-climate-change"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816131/warehouses-natural-gas-emissions-climate-change</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-03T13:46:09-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-03T13:46:09-05:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook Messenger is getting a built-in bill splitting feature</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7vu6_71DkSn7mMgUKxYsr4lArrY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70225139/acastro_180522_facebook_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lhLLC8"&gt;Facebook parent company Meta is introducing a &lt;a href="https://messengernews.fb.com/2021/12/03/close-out-the-year-with-messengers-new-expression-tools/"&gt;built-in bill splitting feature&lt;/a&gt; in Facebook Messenger that it will test with users in the US beginning next week. The feature could be useful for situations like divvying up a restaurant bill with your friends or splitting a bill with roommates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gf2zN6"&gt;With the feature, you can ask for money from people right in a group chat and see who has paid their portion of the request. You can see how it all works in a series of screenshots below from Meta. The feature arrives shortly after David Marcus, Meta’s cryptocurrency chief and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/6/9/5794548/david-marcus-leaves-paypal-to-lead-facebook-messaging"&gt;former Messenger lead&lt;/a&gt;, announced he would be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22810220/facebook-crypto-david-marcus-novi-diem-meta"&gt;leaving the company&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5FCgifFJor5OSLcdLmHdQf2WTrw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23060856/Messenger_Split_Payment.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Meta&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook Messenger’s upcoming bill splitting feature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="0rpZBS"&gt;Meta has also added new Group Effects, which let people on Messenger and Instagram video calls use &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/21/22737991/facebook-messenger-group-calls-ar-effects-augmented-reality"&gt;the same augmented reality effects together&lt;/a&gt;, it has made with popular creators. Three are available now, including one that makes it look like your connection is buffering created with Zach King, and one from Emma Chamberlain arrives on December 6th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x98iFQ"&gt;Meta recently introduced new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578633/facebook-messenger-sound-emoji-soundmojis"&gt;“soundmoji”&lt;/a&gt; as well. Two are inspired by &lt;em&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/em&gt; (ahead of the new season &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/6/22765226/stranger-things-4-netflix-trailer-eleven-netflix-release-date"&gt;coming out next summer&lt;/a&gt;) and one that plays a clip from Taylor Swift’s “Red.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22815981/facebook-messenger-bill-splitting-feature-meta-group-effects"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22815981/facebook-messenger-bill-splitting-feature-meta-group-effects</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-03T13:38:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-03T13:38:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>NASA funds three companies to develop commercial space stations</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DGb_5d8qwbn9neXjfnd4Dd0KZvM=/256x0:1635x919/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70225086/cdff_awardee_3.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Northrop Grumman space station | Image: Northrop Grumman&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tsBh4d"&gt;NASA &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/nasa-selects-companies-to-develop-commercial-destinations-in-space"&gt;announced the selection&lt;/a&gt; of three US companies that will receive government funding to further&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;develop private space stations on Thursday. From a set of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HhrrzNiauZg"&gt;11 proposals&lt;/a&gt;, NASA selected Blue Origin, Nanoracks LLC, and Northrop Grumman to receive over $400 million in federal funds through three separate Space Act Agreements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9jQaCw"&gt;NASA &lt;a href="https://spacenews.com/nasa-seeks-proposals-for-commercial-space-station-development/"&gt;began seeking proposals&lt;/a&gt; in July for its Commercial Low Earth Orbit Development (CLD) program, which aims to support the development of commercial space stations. It is a part of a bigger plan to eventually replace the International Space Station (ISS) with commercial space stations. Through this model, NASA would be a customer of the commercial space industry, allowing it to save on costs and focus on basic research and&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lwdfrY"&gt;Blue Origin is set to receive $130 million to develop Orbital Reef, a free-flying space station concept the company first &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744526/blue-origin-space-station-orbital-reef-announcement"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; in October. Orbital Reef is being developed in partnership with Sierra Space, maker of the winged spaceplane Dream Chaser. Blue Origin says the station&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;will be operational by the second half of the decade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mdTxZX"&gt;Nanoracks LLC is receiving $160 million for its Starlab station concept. Also announced in October, Starlab is a &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/22/voyager-nanoracks-and-lockheeds-starlab-is-the-latest-sign-that-the-low-earth-orbit-economy-is-coming/"&gt;collaboration with&lt;/a&gt; Voyager Space and Lockheed Martin. Designed to hold up to four astronauts and conduct advanced research on biology, materials science and more, Starlab is targeted for launch in 2027 on a single flight, according to the NASA press release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SnsLhB"&gt;Northrop Grumman’s $125.6 million award will give it the opportunity to develop a commercial space station using existing technologies like its Cygnus spacecraft, which currently ferries cargo to the ISS. Northrop is working with Dynetics on its concept for a modular space station, with other partners to be announced in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SFxCTg"&gt;Axiom Space, a Houston company that was the &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/nasa-selects-first-commercial-destination-module-for-international-space-station"&gt;first awarded&lt;/a&gt; funds in January 2020 to develop its commercial module to be added to the ISS, said &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Axiom_Space/status/1466504467113816065/photo/1"&gt;in a statement &lt;/a&gt;on Twitter that it did not bid to receive one of the CLD awards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9d1Q4k"&gt;According to NASA, the awards are the first part of a two-phase approach to ensure a smooth transition to commercial stations in LEO. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QGghu3"&gt;The first phase, expected to continue through 2025, will allow the grant recipients to create a plan and designs that meet both private sector and government needs. During the second phase, NASA wants to certify these stations for human astronauts to use and, ultimately, start using them.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22815695/nasa-space-act-award-recipients-commercial-space-development"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22815695/nasa-space-act-award-recipients-commercial-space-development</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jasmine Hicks</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-03T13:08:13-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-03T13:08:13-05:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook took down a fake Swiss scientist account that was part of an international misinfo campaign</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="facebook stock art" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V7uzEkVOjzTOwjK9H9FpjPV8FVw=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70224911/acastro_180928_1777_facebook_hack_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Pi9PXp"&gt;Buried deep within Facebook’s November report on &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/November-2021-CIB-Report.pdf"&gt;Coordinated Inauthentic Behavior&lt;/a&gt; is a tale of international intrigue that seems more like a Netflix drama than an attempted disinformation campaign (although the way &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22815541/netflix-thanksgiving-mom-viral-twitter-thread-feature-film"&gt;Netflix mines social media&lt;/a&gt; for ideas these days, maybe stay tuned). On July 24th, a Swiss biologist named Wilson Edwards claimed on Facebook and Twitter that the US was pressuring World Health Organization (WHO) scientists studying the origins of COVID-19. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qbV7TG"&gt;His claims spread quickly on social media, as such claims are wont to do, and within a week’s time, the &lt;em&gt;Global Times&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;People’s Daily&lt;/em&gt;, two state-run Chinese media outlets, were denouncing Wilson Edwards’ claims as “intimidation” by the US. Wilson Edwards created his Facebook account two days after &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/coronavirus-live-updates/2021/07/22/1019244601/china-who-coronavirus-lab-leak-theory?t=1633552763404"&gt;China refused to accept a plan&lt;/a&gt; by the WHO for a second phase study into the origins of the coronavirus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="id__nda7cd9rc3b"&gt;Have you guessed the plot twist yet? Turns out, according to the Swiss Embassy in Beijing, that there is no such Swiss citizen by the name Wilson Edwards. “If you exist, we would like to meet you! But it is more likely that this is a fake news, and we call on the Chinese press and netizens to take down the posts,”&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SwissEmbChina/status/1425042973289504770"&gt; the embassy tweeted&lt;/a&gt; from its official account on August 10th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0e1mGK"&gt;Facebook investigated and removed the Wilson Edwards account the same day the Swiss embassy tweeted. Ben Nimmo, global IO threat intel lead (excellent title for our drama) at Facebook parent company Meta, writes that the Wilson Edwards account was part of a misinformation campaign that originated in China. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R1vtFyjn_XFgxbp6TglvnkpiTd0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23060925/wilson_edwards.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Meta&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Faked profile picture of one of the fake accounts Meta says liked the post by “Wilson Edwards”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rmGT7e"&gt;“In essence, this campaign was a hall of mirrors, endlessly reflecting a single fake persona,” Nimmo says. Meta’s investigation found that nearly the entire initial spread of the Wilson Edwards story on Facebook was inauthentic: “the work of a multi-pronged, largely unsuccessful influence operation,” which brought together hundreds of fake accounts as well as some authentic accounts that belonged to employees of “Chinese state infrastructure companies across four continents.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cqvOaw"&gt;Only a handful of real people engaged with Wilson Edwards, Meta says, despite the 524 Facebook accounts, 20 Facebook pages, four Facebook groups, and 86 Instagram accounts that the company has removed as part of its investigation. The scammers spent less than $5,000 on Facebook and Instagram ads as part of the campaign and used VPNs to conceal the accounts’ origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ToF13y"&gt;“This is consistent with what we’ve seen in our research of covert influence operations over the past four years: we haven’t seen successful IO campaigns built on fake engagement tactics,” Nimmo says. “Unlike elaborate fictitious personas that put work into building authentic communities to influence them, the content liked by these crude fake accounts would typically be only seen by their ‘fake friends.’” (And we all know what &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_txiRmH8NDY&amp;amp;ab_channel=FallOutBoy-Topic"&gt;happens to sham friends&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wTWjyk"&gt;The cluster of fake accounts that Meta connected to the Wilson Edwards scheme, along with some people associated with information security firm Silence in China, apparently has made (unsuccessfully, Meta says) other attempts at influence operations that were “typically small-scale and of negligible impact.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LGzWbD"&gt;It’s not the most exciting end to our story, but at least Wilson Edwards won’t try to catfish any other international health organizations. Now, if we could just get someone to rein in the tenacious people who keep &lt;a href="https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/blog/2021/05/hang-auto-warranty-robocalls"&gt;calling about the car warranty&lt;/a&gt; I didn’t know I had... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YCae1L"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22815906/facebook-meta-instagram-fake-swiss-scientist-account-china-misinformation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22815906/facebook-meta-instagram-fake-swiss-scientist-account-china-misinformation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-03T13:05:17-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-03T13:05:17-05:00</updated>
    <title>Walmart’s in-store Gamer Drop might be your best shot at a PS5, Xbox, or Switch OLED</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Rt0PYBOnRxkLcojJ-czXOIwglQI=/0x24:672x472/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70224897/k2__dd3aea10_166c_434f_9b7f_7b3287ed4b4e.v1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Walmart’s Gamer Drop prominently features the big three new consoles that are difficult to get.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Walmart&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xEHRxJ"&gt;Walmart has announced a new &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fcp%2Fgamer-drop&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Gamer Drop event&lt;/a&gt; coming to select stores on December 11th, where the retailer is promising to have the latest gaming titles and consoles. This marks the first in-store console restock from Walmart, and it’s billing it as a holiday shopping event, complete with discounts and exclusive gear. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="prXoF1"&gt;Details are a bit sparse, but &lt;a href="https://i5.walmartimages.com/dfw/4ff9c6c9-4866/k2-_331621d6-7642-4095-82d1-ecac1d3f3bc9.v1.pdf"&gt;the posted circular on Walmart’s website&lt;/a&gt; prominently features the major consoles, including the Nintendo Switch OLED Model, Xbox Series X / S, and both models of the PlayStation 5 with the note of “Available in-store or online at &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=http%3A%2F%2FWalmart.com%2FGamerDrop.&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart.com/GamerDrop.&lt;/a&gt;” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jolFad"&gt;This event is exclusive to select Walmart stores. You can find the closest Walmart that’s participating in the Gamer Drop event on Saturday, the 11th, by searching your address or zip code on the &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fcp%2Fgamer-drop&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Gamer Drop&lt;/a&gt; page. Listed stores indicate Gamer Drop hours of 10:30AM to 7PM, which is a limited window compared to store hours of many Walmart stores. We have reached out to Walmart for further details and will keep an eye out for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/El80Hxes451sAXELbpszKPVjkDw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23060926/Screen_Shot_2021_12_03_at_12.12.18_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Walmart Gamer Drop site allows users to search if their local store is participating. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816004/ps5-xbox-series-x-switch-walmart-gamer-drop-restock"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816004/ps5-xbox-series-x-switch-walmart-gamer-drop-restock</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-03T12:49:06-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-03T12:49:06-05:00</updated>
    <title>‘Face with tears of joy’ is once again the most-used emoji</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-jFvW61PaVAqelRr8LMowUZsvBg=/0x0:1200x800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70224782/emoji.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;24 face with tears of joy emoji, each more terrifying than the last.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HwM6qY"&gt;Until recently, I was a firm believer in the &lt;a href="https://emojipedia.org/slightly-smiling-face/"&gt;traditional smiley emoji&lt;/a&gt;. “It’s cute!” I used to think, as I happily used it to indicate my gentle amusement at everything from puns to fun weekend plans. But apparently, this was a mistake, and when I thought I was expressing sincere happiness, I was actually sending an emoji that’s “colossally insulting in every conceivable way,” &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/11/dont-put-on-a-happy-face-are-you-using-the-smiley-emoji-all-wrong"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vJsLOX"&gt;It seems the rest of the world agrees, and the “slightly smiling face,” to use its full name, doesn’t feature in the &lt;a href="https://home.unicode.org/emoji/emoji-frequency/"&gt;top 10 of the most used emoji in 2021&lt;/a&gt;. In fact, according to data from the Unicode Consortium, the slightly smiling face isn’t even in the top 20. It’s down at number 28, sandwiched between “clapping hands” and “flushed face.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-qZ_7v9HoVQWxM68avh_YHTrh9A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23060869/msedge_76CGmm0r7F.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Unicode Consortium&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;How the ranking of the top 10 emoji has changed, according to Unicode Consortium data.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="4e3AbA"&gt;Instead of embracing the subtle joys of the slightly smiling face, the world has continued its love affair with “face with tears of joy,” a crass, blunt instrument of an emoji that leaves no room for subtlety or ambiguity. It’s reportedly been on top since &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/3/16602352/face-with-tears-of-joy-emoji-most-popular-apple-study"&gt;at least 2017&lt;/a&gt;, and in 2021, it accounted for over 5 percent of emoji sent online. Ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o2rNOr"&gt;Jokes aside, it’s interesting to see from this data how broadly consistent the emoji we use has been, even as the world has been turned upside down by the pandemic. In its blog, the Unicode Consortium points out that the top 10 emoji has only seen one change between the two years, and even then, it was to swap two very similar emoji (“two hearts” with “smiling face with 3 hearts”). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6kCxCP"&gt;That’s not to say there weren’t any big movers. The birthday cake emoji shot up from 113 to 25, while the balloon gently floated from 139 to 48. My personal favorite, the pleading face, also broke the top 20, rising from 97 to 14. But surprisingly, actual pandemic-related emoji haven’t seen much of a change, like the &lt;a href="https://emojipedia.org/microbe/"&gt;microbe emoji&lt;/a&gt;, which barely made it into the top 500 (there are 3,663 emoji overall, in case you’re wondering). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6vobLY"&gt;Beyond this sort of data being just plain interesting, it’s useful for the Unicode Consortium to understand which emoji are most popular as it decides which characters to add next. The way emoji are created is a surprisingly interesting process, and you can read about it in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21327599/how-to-make-emoji-yawning-face-waffle-proposal-unicode"&gt;this article from my colleague Jay Peters&lt;/a&gt; (who submitted proposals for the yawning face and waffle emoji).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="byphg7"&gt;Still, at least there’s hope for us slightly smiling face fans out there. The emoji saw a pretty dramatic increase in popularity between 2019 and 2021, where it previously sat down at the 50th mark. At this rate, we might yet make it into the top 10 [fingers crossed emoji].&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816001/most-popular-emoji-2021-face-with-tears-of-joy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816001/most-popular-emoji-2021-face-with-tears-of-joy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-03T12:47:35-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-03T12:47:35-05:00</updated>
    <title>Sony’s ‘Spartacus’ could be PlayStation’s answer to Xbox Game Pass</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SLnDyi2JzTURtIx6hTvmMZOOexo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70224770/vpavic_4278_20201030_0292.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4JHBPv"&gt;Sony is planning to create an Xbox Game Pass-like subscription service, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-12-03/playstation-plans-new-service-to-take-on-xbox-game-pass"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The company already offers two subscription services, PlayStation Plus (which is required for the majority of online multiplayer games) and PlayStation Now (which offers a catalog of games to download or stream), and they will reportedly be merged in this new offering. Sony will likely keep the PlayStation Plus brand, reporter Jason Schreier &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jasonschreier/status/1466821381568536578"&gt;said on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, but “phase out” PlayStation Now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HKFRZJ"&gt;This new service, which is codenamed Spartacus, would have three tiers. One would offer current PlayStation Plus perks, another would include a catalog of PS4 and “eventually” PS5 games, and a third would have “extended demos, game streaming and a library of classic PS1, PS2, PS3 and PSP games,” &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reports, adding that it’s “likely” to be available on PlayStation 4 as well as the PS5. The company would launch the service in the spring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d9Af19"&gt;Sony didn’t immediately reply to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; adds that some details of the service, including its membership tiers, may not yet be finalized. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xkxAtC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Sony’s service could run on Microsoft’s cloud platform&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MhxR6E"&gt;The company is also “putting resources into expanding its efforts in cloud gaming,” &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reported, perhaps to keep up with efforts like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/21/22738006/nvidia-rtx-3080-geforce-now-features-price-release-date-streaming-option"&gt;Nvidia’s RTX 3080 tier of GeForce Now&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/7/22714067/xbox-cloud-gaming-custom-xbox-series-x-hardware-upgrade"&gt;Microsoft’s Xbox Series X upgrade for xCloud&lt;/a&gt;. However, it’s unclear if Spartacus would run on Microsoft Azure following the deal signed between Microsoft and Sony &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/20/18632374/microsoft-sony-cloud-gaming-partnership-amazon-google"&gt;in 2019&lt;/a&gt;; if it does, it would mean that Sony’s service runs on the same platform as its competitor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DFK7Lh"&gt;This new Spartacus service sounds like it would put Sony on par with Microsoft’s Game Pass Ultimate subscription, which allows people to play online multiplayer, access a huge library of titles from Microsoft and other companies, and stream games from the cloud. Sony also appears to be emulating Microsoft’s approach to offer &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-US%2Fxbox-game-pass%23join&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F3%2F22816087%2Fsony-playstation-5-game-subscription-service-xbox-games-pass-now-spartacus" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;multiple tiers&lt;/a&gt; of services — only the $15 per month Game Pass Ultimate plan offers cloud gaming, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GmqYW3"&gt;However, one of the key perks of Game Pass and Game Pass Ultimate is day-one access to Microsoft’s first-party titles, but that might not be available with Spartacus. Schreier said in a tweet that “don’t expect Sony to include its big new games day one like Game Pass does.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816087/sony-playstation-5-game-subscription-service-xbox-games-pass-now-spartacus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816087/sony-playstation-5-game-subscription-service-xbox-games-pass-now-spartacus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-03T11:58:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-03T11:58:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>Once you’re done with Arcane, play this League of Legends RPG</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0cHOURATf2fIE7mbtyTwerqt9Ls=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70224455/38_Artstyle_Group.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1lpFDA"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Arcane&lt;/em&gt; isn’t just one of the best new animated shows on Netflix — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22763818/netflix-league-of-legends-arcane-review"&gt;it’s also a great introduction to the vast and often inscrutable world of &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. If you’ve finished the show and have found yourself intrigued by the fantasy realm of Runeterra, you might be wondering where to go next. There are a few options, but thankfully developer Riot has just released a new role-playing game that’s a perfect next step for budding fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1D1Ybr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ruined King: A League of Legends Story&lt;/em&gt; is available now on the Switch, PC, PS4, and Xbox One, and it’s a bite-sized RPG that lets you explore a different part of &lt;em&gt;League&lt;/em&gt; mythology. It stars a handful of iconic characters — including the hulking Braum and the kraken-wielding priestess Illaoi — and lets you wander through the port city of Bilgewater as you investigate a mysterious phenomenon known as the Black Myst, which eventually leads you to the unsettling Shadow Isles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1qgFz3"&gt;Part of what makes &lt;em&gt;Ruined King&lt;/em&gt; such a great follow to &lt;em&gt;Arcane &lt;/em&gt;is that — unlike the multiplayer-focused &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; — it’s completely story-driven. While many of &lt;em&gt;League&lt;/em&gt;’s characters and locations have long, detailed backstories, you don’t get much of that from the main game. It’s more like background, something you can dig into if you want, but it’s not really a necessary component of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4z7e_pfuz0Y3O6vPahhJL2xEoaE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23060721/01_Battle_Hullbreaker.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="KeY9Ii"&gt;But here, story is the whole point. It’s a chance to really spend some time with these characters and get to know them. There’s lots of fun banter (it’s even fully voiced) and gorgeous comic book-style cutscenes that set up important moments. The game also provides also a great chance to linger in the world; I loved wandering around the bustling districts of Bilgewater, rendered with a &lt;em&gt;Diablo&lt;/em&gt;-style isometric look, going from seedy back alleys to opulent mansions. The places feel alive and full of detail. You can even go fishing. The main &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; game tells you these are important places and heroes, but in &lt;em&gt;Ruined King,&lt;/em&gt; you find out why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="osWKph"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ruined King&lt;/em&gt; also happens to be a solid RPG. Most notably, it has a clever turn-based battle system involving lanes, which essentially means you can decide whether attacks should be quick or strong, with obvious pros and cons for each. There are also environmental hazards and bonuses that impact you depending on how you time those actions. It adds a nice layer of strategy to even standard battles, especially once you get a chance to explore all of the different characters, each of whom has very different abilities. Illaoi, with her ability to summon ghostly tentacles that serve as writhing minions, is my favorite. It’s all fairly straightforward stuff if you’ve played a lot of RPGs, but it’s polished and has just enough of a twist to feel fresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mEAsqL"&gt;Ever since &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/15/20915506/riot-games-league-of-legends-10th-anniversary-marc-merrill-interview"&gt;&lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; turned 10&lt;/a&gt;, Riot has been steadily expanding its fictional universe in different ways. There’s a digital card game, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22772338/league-of-legends-spinoff-netflix-games-nintendo-switch-hextech-mayhem"&gt;a rhythm game&lt;/a&gt;, an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22187980/riot-games-league-of-legends-mmo-greg-street"&gt;upcoming MMO&lt;/a&gt; and fighting game, comic books, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/31/21408504/league-of-legends-tellstones-board-game-spinoff"&gt;even an in-universe board game&lt;/a&gt;. So far, &lt;em&gt;Arcane&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Ruined King&lt;/em&gt; are the best examples of how this strategy can work. While the core &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; can be as demanding as it is engrossing, these latest efforts are much more palatable. They also do a better job at showing what makes Runeterra such an interesting fantasy universe in the first place. Unfortunately, the success of these does come with a side effect: I can’t stop reading up on &lt;em&gt;LoL&lt;/em&gt; lore.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22815884/league-of-legends-ruined-king-rpg"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22815884/league-of-legends-ruined-king-rpg</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
