<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-08T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Rescuing discarded fabric for designer bow ties</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Nisha Blackwell, CEO of Knotzland" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FCGPmJmzZ8uutGVIS2vwxo64QYk=/0x1:2040x1361/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68918765/shyoung_210218_4417_0018.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nisha Blackwell is CEO of Knotzland, a Pittsburgh-based company that makes bow ties from upcycled textile waste.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Giving wasted material a new life&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="6wfiLl"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="yoXgW9"&gt;Nisha Blackwell remembers wearing a lot of hand-me-down clothes as a kid and sorting through things to try on with her mother and grandmother. Thrifting was just a thing everyone did, long before it was rebranded as upcycling, she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NvEO7r"&gt;“The idea of thrifting is embedded with who I am as a person,” Blackwell says. “When you have to wear something someone else already wore, you have to learn to be resourceful to be fashionable.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yI9vBz"&gt;Using every bit of available fabric became the foundation of &lt;a href="https://knotzland.com/"&gt;Knotzland&lt;/a&gt;, the bespoke bow tie company Blackwell founded in Pittsburgh in 2014. It gave her the chance to marry her experience with upcycling thrifted clothes and other discarded materials to her interest in protecting the environment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Knotzland bow ties, made from upcycled textile waste, are displayed on a table" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Dcdo5ocavcQ9LCqOFOpIj4kJkzI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22347314/shyoung_210218_4417_0015.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nisha Blackwell says Knotzland has rescued more than 3,000 pounds of textile waste for its bow ties.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ALkkA7"&gt;The process of upcycling takes an item like a piece of clothing or an old piece of furniture and turns it into something new, usually giving it a new function and a second life. It’s not the same as recycling, which applies a process to break the item down into its raw materials for reuse in another product. An upcycled item has its original material, just presented or remade into a new final form. It’s a natural process for clothing and other textiles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IDeb5p"&gt;Upcycling also helps offset some less environmentally-friendly manufacturing processes, from the energy and water used in production to the air pollution caused by transporting goods to stores. And while it has grown in popularity over the past decade, as Blackwell notes, the roots of upcycling lie in much older traditions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S7UCaF"&gt;“That helps us just really enhance the life cycle of these materials, and then we’re actually disrupting them from entering landfills,” Blackwell says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Nisha Blackwell at her sewing machine" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FXiT8QpzNMFmY-oZlGPM9O-IaJw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22347335/shyoung_210218_4417_0011.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blackwell taught herself to sew and turned her love of thrifting into a full-time business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rMxXcL"&gt;In 2018 alone, US landfills received &lt;a href="https://www.epa.gov/facts-and-figures-about-materials-waste-and-recycling/textiles-material-specific-data"&gt;11.3 million tons&lt;/a&gt; of textile waste, according to the Environmental Protection Agency. Blackwell notes that a lot of materials used in clothing —particularly in so-called fast-fashion lines — are synthetics like polyester, which are plastic-based. So keeping these materials out of landfills is significant for the larger environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cjLBjV"&gt;“Within the circular economy, you focus on continuing to design and redesign, and design for the life beyond the initial consumer. We’re creating things of quality that people can hand down and pass down to the next generation,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SQKgnp"&gt;A lot of the first year of Knotzland was about educating people about why she felt it was important to reuse materials, Blackwell says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="28Vm1q"&gt;“I knew I wanted to use reclaimed material. I wanted to be part of the solution to reduce textile waste,” she says. “I would go to fashion meetups in Pittsburgh, and things like Pittsburgh Earth Day, and it was like all these things were meshing for me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3q10rA"&gt;Many of Knotzland’s customers weren’t aware of the life cycle of a piece of clothing, and that their bow ties are more than just a piece of restyled cloth. “We serve as an entry conversation about sustainability,” she says, “so now the customer can go out into the world and speak about it. Now we have these little pieces of information in the world and our customers are excited about it because it’s a product that is expressive and true and unique to them &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; good for the environment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vixw29"&gt;Knotzland sources material from upholstery companies, drape makers, and other thrift shops. Blackwell says these can be deadstock, discontinued products, or last year’s fashions that are still like-new fabrics, but just aren’t usable by a manufacturer or textile supplier. And as a board member of the Pittsburgh Center for Creative Reuse (PCCR) — which bills itself as a nontraditional art supply shop where people can donate and shop for used art and craft supplies — she had access to its wide collection of reusable materials that one might not find at other thrift shops. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Pittsburgh Center for Creative Reuse storefront" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0OklXqMInSSiSOa-0apvzw1_Mjg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22347321/shyoung_210220_4417_0035.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;People can donate and shop for used craft supplies that other shops may not have at the Pittsburgh Center for Creative Reuse.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="GBbZ79"&gt;“We take discards and other donations that might be difficult to donate to a regular thrift store,” says PCCR executive director Ash Andrews. “Someone might have a half-used tube of paint. A lot of those kinds of things might get thrown away because you can’t really donate them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qvsFwl"&gt;And while upcycling in fashion started with thrifters and indie designers, it’s also being recognized by larger mainstream brands as a way to reduce waste in the industry. For instance, women’s clothing brand Eileen Fisher’s Renew program buys back clothing from customers and resells it for a second life. Garments that can’t be resold as-is are upcycled into artwork, pillows, and wall hangings for a third life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LPZrwLF2NQKshKFrmmKVhYXn2Jk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22347318/shyoung_210218_4417_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Knotzland employs work-from-home “sewists” who help create its bow ties and masks.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QsaD8Uo8Gbobddpg5WMRcOiWNRs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22347319/shyoung_210218_4417_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Knotzland’s ties are upcycled and fashionable.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hrYzde"&gt;Blackwell estimates that Knotzland has “rescued” more than 3,000 pounds of textile waste to date. She’s also proud that Knotzland created work-from-home jobs for the seamstresses who make the bow ties, long before the pandemic struck, which helped the company weather the uncertainty of the past year. Instead of the focus on weddings she was planning in 2020, Knotzland instead pivoted to making masks. The process reminded Blackwell why she was determined to scale Knotzland ethically, not just quickly. “This is slow fashion,” she says, “which is much better for the environment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mzftK8"&gt;Andrews says a company like Knotzland is a uniquely Pittsburgh kind of company. “In a postindustrial town like Pittsburgh, reuse is just part of how we do things,” they said, pointing to old steel mills that have been repurposed into things &lt;a href="https://www.cmu.edu/news/stories/archives/2017/november/hazelwood-groundbreaking.html"&gt;like manufacturing hubs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.post-gazette.com/business/businessnews/2006/07/30/Homestead-Works-Steel-lives-in-its-stories/stories/200607300258"&gt;shopping plazas&lt;/a&gt;, and the Carrie Furnace, a former US Steel blast furnace-turned-museum on the Monongahela River. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dt7OXw"&gt;“Pittsburgh’s been through a lot of hard times, but it’s sort of that mindset of ‘use it up, make do, or do without.’ Especially among folks who don’t have a lot of resources, it’s just the way we grew up,” Andrews said. “Like you can wash off that plastic bag and use it again.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Bsg2oAoQLevrO1SddEPjl6itO-A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22347343/shyoung_210218_4417_0031.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blackwell says locating in Pittsburgh allowed Knotzland to grow at its own pace.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="HpzBiU"&gt;Blackwell says having a fashion company located in Pittsburgh rather than a bigger city like Los Angeles has come with its downsides. “I go to the West Coast and talk about what we do, and it feels like second nature to them, they’re more far along in their sustainability journey,” she says, with concepts like upcycling and environmental concerns about food much more ingrained into everyday practices. The “convincing” conversations didn’t take as long, she says.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m04wqF"&gt;“But in return, I do think Pittsburgh has allowed us to become more well-rounded at our own pace.” Blackwell adds that she grew up in a community that was disinvested in, making her always feel like the underdog who had to work a little bit harder. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="NDoDmE"&gt;“Being a Black woman in sustainability, a Black woman in a menswear company, acceptance took a while. ‘Is she going to keep making bow ties?’ But people realized this wasn’t just a hobby, that we were really committed to doing good for the community and for the environment.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22309827/knotzland-bow-ties-upcycling"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22309827/knotzland-bow-ties-upcycling</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Logitech’s Circle View Doorbell is the closest thing we have to an Apple-made doorbell</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;For better and worse&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="GhXL48"&gt;There are a lot of video doorbells on the market. You can get one from Amazon’s Ring, Google’s Nest, Arlo, Eufy, August, or countless other companies. But none of those video doorbells will natively work with Apple’s HomeKit platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BILuxk"&gt;For a long time, if you wanted a video doorbell and you were committed to building your smart home around HomeKit, the only option you had was to use hacky workarounds such as Homebridge to integrate unsupported devices into the Home app. That changed late last year as two HomeKit-compatible video doorbells finally hit the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iBAbC8"&gt;I’ve been testing the one from Logitech, the $199.99 Circle View Doorbell (the other is the $299.99 Netatmo Smart Video Doorbell), on my front door for the past few months. It is a very capable video doorbell, with excellent performance and a number of useful features. But it also comes with some significant asterisks attached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2agUWO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10379340"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LShaV2"&gt;The Circle View Doorbell is a wired doorbell and does not have a battery option. In order to use it, you’ll have to have existing low-voltage doorbell wiring rated at 8-24 volts AC, 10vA or higher, or run wiring from an AC adapter wall wart (not included) to it, as I did. It supports existing doorbell chimes if you have one and includes the accessories you need to make it work. You can check the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.logitech.com%2Fen-us%2Fcircleviewdoorbell%2Fsetup&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22318478%2Flogitech-circle-view-doorbell-homekit-review-test-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;online installation guide&lt;/a&gt; (there aren’t any instructions included in the box, so you have to follow the instructions from your phone or a computer) to see if your existing hardware is compatible. I don’t have a chime in my home, so I skipped the parts of the setup related to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D2OEzF"&gt;The Circle View comes with all of the other hardware necessary to install it, except for a Micro USB cable and A/C adapter, which is required to power the doorbell and configure it before you mount it at your door. It’s likely that you already have one lying around at home, but it’s still an odd omission. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w15rk4"&gt;Installation and setup are relatively simple: you get the doorbell powered up, scan the barcode on the back using the Apple Home app on your iPhone to add it to your virtual home, and then install the hardware at your door. The whole process took me about 15 minutes and shouldn’t be much of a challenge for anyone with a screwdriver, a power drill, and even the smallest amount of home repair experience. (Trust me, I’m no Bob Vila.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iMzAxb0ZQ7oJYHLdefUDg1q39Ec=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22338163/dseifertt_210225_4448_0006.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;All of the setup for the Circle View Doorbell is done through Apple’s Home app on an iPhone or iPad, including scanning the barcode on the back of the unit to begin.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sjJZ792AIE2F4joP0qC5emE94nc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22338162/dseifertt_210225_4448_0005.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Circle View Doorbell comes with straight and angled brackets to aim the camera’s view best for your setup.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GUsBlp"&gt;But if you want to avoid all of that and just have someone else do it for you (an impulse that I strongly relate to, no judgment here), Logitech has partnered with HelloTech to have someone come to your home and install the doorbell. The service costs $100 on top of the price of the doorbell and includes setting it up and wiring it up at your door. It does not include running wire to your door; you have to have the wiring in place already (likely from an existing doorbell).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o42j5K"&gt;Because the Circle View doesn’t have an internal battery, it’s much more compact than something like the Ring Video Doorbell 3 and is closer in size to the Nest Hello or Ring Video Doorbell Pro. There’s the camera in its expected place, a built-in nightlight below that, and a round illuminated circle indicating where to press. The whole bottom half of the doorbell is the button to ring it, so you don’t have to be particularly precise when using it. In the box are straight and angled mounts to better position the camera’s view depending on your home layout. Unfortunately, the angled mount’s 20-degree tilt is not enough for me to see the one spot on my porch where most packages are left through the doorbell’s vertical view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2CmHfF"&gt;Lastly, the Circle View only comes in black and has a modern and gadget-y look to it. I don’t mind it, but it might not fit your home’s decor or your style, and there isn’t much you can do to change it. Other companies offer white or black versions of their doorbells, and some even have interchangeable faceplates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L5kuZf0OQdFc9cbOlmTFkcMfFzM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22338159/dseifertt_210225_4448_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Circle View Doorbell has a 5-megapixel camera with a tall aspect ratio that lets you see visitors from head to toe.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lEWGiB"&gt;At its core, the Circle View is very similar to other video doorbells. It will ping your phone with a push notification when someone rings the doorbell, including a video thumbnail preview; you can view a live feed from your phone; and use the two-way speaker to talk to the person at the door like an intercom. The video feed is a tall 160-degree view, which is meant to let you see a person from head to toe or be able to see if a package was left on the stoop. It has a 5-megapixel sensor with 1200 x 1600 HD resolution and HDR functions resulting in image quality that generally looks good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5W7Gui"&gt;It also functions very well. Pulling up the video feed from my phone or an iPad is noticeably faster than with other video doorbells, likely due to the Circle View’s support for 5GHz Wi-Fi and my strong mesh Wi-Fi network (a must for any smart home). Push notifications to my phone and watch are nearly instant, though the thumbnail preview rarely loaded on my Apple Watch, just showing a gray square. The speaker and microphone work well for two-way communication, should you desire to ever use it (I don’t). If you’re watching something on an Apple TV when someone rings the bell, you will get a thumbnail preview right there on your TV screen (though you can’t do anything but see it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8OxOPcpHFfQ6ctUk6BiYjZLqs7w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22338166/dseifertt_210225_4448_0009.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The built-in nightlight comes on automatically and is searingly bright, which is unpleasant for those walking up to your door.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wEpvct"&gt;The Circle View has some functions that make it slightly unique. The built-in nightlight below the camera will come on automatically when it’s dark out to enable what Logitech calls “color night vision.” It allows you to view a full-color feed even at night, unlike the grayscale view that most other video doorbells offer, and it’s much nicer to use as a result. The light is either on or off — there’s very little in the way of customization — and it is searingly bright, which is unpleasant if you’re the person walking up to the door to press the doorbell. If you have a porch light, the built-in nightlight is unnecessary, and I ended up just turning it off permanently. One thing to note is the Circle View doesn’t have any sort of IR night vision (that grayscale view other cameras offer), so it doesn’t quite have the same range in the dark as others. But in my experience, the range it has with the color night vision is more than adequate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/s87lz4buvxI59LrQsTbe6XlzVmY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22353482/circle_view_3up.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;From left to right: the Circle View’s image at night with the nightlight on, the nightlight off, and with a porchlight on.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="acpw2J"&gt;The other thing that makes it unique is its support for Apple’s HomeKit platform. The Circle View is so committed to HomeKit that there isn’t even a Logitech app to set it up — &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; related to the doorbell’s functions is handled in the Apple-developed Home app on an iPhone, iPad, or Mac. It also supports Apple’s HomeKit Secure Video, which when paired with a HomeKit hub such as an Apple TV, iPad, or HomePod, allows for storage of video clips in iCloud and face detection features. You can also use a HomePod or HomePod mini as a chime for the doorbell — though in my tests, this was less reliable than I had hoped, working about half the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KlawCJ2Z5TRMftDEsxiMnhPqr8Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22353483/IMG_0589.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Apple Home app allows you to see a live feed, timeline of recorded events, control nearby smart home gadgets, and manage the features of the Circle View Doorbell.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4DsGdN"&gt;The HomeKit Secure Video features require an iCloud subscription of 200GB per month or more and allow you to view up to 10 days of end-to-end-encrypted clips captured by the camera. The clips don’t count against your storage quota in iCloud, but the base plan only supports one camera. If you have other HomeKit Secure Video cameras in your home, you’ll need to pony up for the 2TB plan that handles up to five. If you have more than that, well, I’m sorry, five cameras is all HomeKit currently supports. The facial recognition features can tie into your Apple Photos library to identify certain visitors and even announce their names on a HomePod when they ring the doorbell. I didn’t find this function very useful. Most of the people in my Photos library are my own family, and they aren’t ringing the doorbell to their own home very often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ajbkER"&gt;Within the Home app, you can view the camera’s feed, see a timeline of recorded clips (if you use HomeKit Secure Video), manage notifications, choose when the camera will record video, set up the face recognition features, turn on and off the nightlight, and customize the activity zones for motion detection. You can also set up automations that control other smart home devices when the doorbell detects motion. (Third-party HomeKit apps such as Eve’s will let you set up automations triggered by the doorbell’s built-in light sensor as well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iXsooU"&gt;While all of that sounds like a lot of options, it’s actually quite limited compared to other doorbells. There’s no way to customize the sound of the doorbell chime, like you can do with Ring or Nest, so forget about any fun holiday-themed chimes. Motion detection alerts cannot be limited to just people or vehicles, so the branches of the tree near my porch would cause the doorbell to ping my phone whenever the wind blew. While you can set an activity zone, you can’t adjust the sensitivity of the motion detection or limit alerts to certain times of the day. I ended up turning the motion detection alerts off entirely as a result. I also couldn’t use the motion detection to trigger automations because of how often it would get tripped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PFxwhQwqGZJnogcIr-G6KdALsRU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22338165/dseifertt_210225_4448_0008.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Circle View is much smaller than battery-powered doorbells like the Ring Video Doorbell 3.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Zp81JV"&gt;All of those limitations are because the Circle View relies entirely on the Home app, so it can only do what Apple has built support for. A dedicated Logitech app, while obviously more cumbersome, would likely allow for more options and customization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sXizu2"&gt;A dedicated app would also address the other big limitation with the Circle View: it doesn’t work with anything other than Apple’s devices and platform. That’s fine if you’re fully committed to HomeKit and don’t ever think you’re going to buy a different phone or use a different platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;div id="R0jYPu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10379412"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Pizp2Z"&gt;But if you share a home with just one person who isn’t fully invested in Apple’s ecosystem and uses an Android phone, the Circle View is effectively a dumb doorbell to them. There’s no way for them to get alerts on their phone when the bell is rung or to view the video feed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZghCy6"&gt;The Circle View also doesn’t work with Amazon Alexa or Google Home, so forget about hearing chimes through an Amazon Echo or viewing the video feed on a Home Hub. (More advanced smart home enthusiasts who are working with platforms like Home Assistant can skip right past the Circle View, too. It doesn’t support any standard protocols.) You are tied to buying an iPhone and using HomeKit for as long as you have this doorbell installed. It’s much like the Apple Watch in that respect. The Circle View Doorbell is effectively an accessory to an iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kQ6cKD"&gt;Other doorbells may not integrate as nicely with Apple’s platform, but all of them at the very least offer apps for both iOS and Android to view video feeds and manage features. And most of them support Amazon’s and Google’s smart home platforms, giving you a lot more flexibility should you ever want to change things. In my experience covering and using smart home tech for the better part of a decade, limiting yourself to compatibility with just one platform is a recipe for disappointment and frustration down the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aENe8o"&gt;Still, there are obvious advantages if you’re okay with the Circle View’s limitations. Nothing is ever sent to Logitech’s cloud, so you don’t have to worry about yet another privacy policy or potential security issues. The video that’s stored in iCloud’s HomeKit Secure Video service is end-to-end encrypted, so only you and those you give access to in the Home app can view it. It’s about the closest thing you can get in terms of security to local storage for video clips (which, no, the Circle View doesn’t support) while still having easy access to them from anywhere you might be. You also don’t have to worry about police partnerships or unsavory social networks tied to your doorbell’s camera, as you might with other devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="9jhIfV"&gt;The Circle View’s privacy features and platform limitations align so closely with the features of products that Apple itself produces that you could almost imagine an Apple logo on the front of the doorbell instead of Logitech’s. It’s fast, performs the basics very well, and provides a sharp, detailed view of your doorway from your phone. If that’s what you’ve been waiting for from a video doorbell, and you’re not turned off by its limitations, then the Logitech Circle View is an easy choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iBC4vM"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22318478/logitech-circle-view-doorbell-homekit-review-test-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22318478/logitech-circle-view-doorbell-homekit-review-test-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google TV is adding kids profiles this month in the US</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SXi_YBCbR1E30d5aWOzyTWVoeP8=/0x1:1115x744/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68928908/kidsprof.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="o52NQP"&gt;Google today announced that it’s adding a popular customer request to its Google TV software: separate profiles for kids. Kid profiles will let you choose which apps are available to young viewers. If a Google account for the child already exists, you can add that as a kid profile — but a Google account is not &lt;em&gt;required&lt;/em&gt;; you can also create a profile simply by adding a child’s name and age. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cvgiuG"&gt;Similar to Google TV for adults, kids will see rows of recommended, age-appropriate shows to watch. You can also opt to share movies and TV shows you’ve already purchased to the kid profile with Google Play Family Library. At least now you won’t have to deal with kiddie content infiltrating your own recommendations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bNALUB"&gt;Parents can set daily watch time limits for child profiles and enter a designated bedtime. “Your kids will be greeted with three countdown warning signs before a final ‘Time is up’ screen appears and ends their watch time,” Google TV product manager Saleh Altayyar wrote in a blog post. “You’ll always have the option to add some extra bonus time when it’s not a school night.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/et79T2NQOwA4W0fMTsk32a9GwCw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22352839/screentime.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="FTRbe0"&gt;Parents can keep kids from switching over to regular profiles by setting a profile lock, which requires a PIN to bypass. You can also check Google’s Family Link smartphone app to “see how much time your kids are spending in their favorite apps, block and unblock apps, control app activity and more.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HOJEYVxkprHVjjOd_tY4lxJBBnc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22352849/theme.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="PDAZFy"&gt;The background on kid profiles can be customized with various themes, and Google says it will be adding profile avatars “in the coming weeks.” Keep in mind that while Google TV is adding kids profiles, it still doesn’t offer the ability to create more than one &lt;em&gt;adult&lt;/em&gt; profile — so hopefully that isn’t far behind. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pAXd2j"&gt;Child profiles will roll out to the Chromecast with Google TV and other Google TV devices in the US starting this month, with a global expansion following “over the next few months.” The feature was definitely needed and helps solidify Google TV as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21375098/best-streaming-device"&gt;the streaming interface to beat&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22318824/google-tv-kid-profiles-announced-features-parental-controls"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22318824/google-tv-kid-profiles-announced-features-parental-controls</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>How scientists scrambled to stop Donald Trump’s EPA from wiping out climate data</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BRM8J32ryGu7ZqLi6HURGc5zr2U=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68919401/acastro_210226_4426_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Their work isn’t done yet&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="LtS5K1"&gt;After hearing the news that then President-elect Donald Trump had appointed a &lt;a href="https://www.pbs.org/wgbh/frontline/article/meet-myron-ebell-the-climate-contrarian-leading-trumps-epa-transition/"&gt;notorious climate change denier&lt;/a&gt; to lead the Environmental Protection Agency transition team in 2016, Nicholas Shapiro, an environmental anthropologist, penned an urgent email to a dozen or so fellow scientists. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ncvpOA"&gt;He was worried that the EPA was about to be torn apart from the inside under Trump’s leadership. Others on the email thread were concerned that vital environmental data would be taken down from federal websites and destroyed. They’d just seen brutal attacks on science in Canada — irreplaceable scientific records were &lt;a href="https://thetyee.ca/News/2013/12/09/Dismantling-Fishery-Library/"&gt;dumped in the trash&lt;/a&gt; under conservative Prime Minister Stephen Harper — and they feared that something similar could happen in the US. So Shapiro took a cue from his sister, an organizer for the Women’s March, and tried to bring researchers together to mount an offensive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CgmA9P"&gt;“Does anyone know of any social scientists inside the EPA that might be able to document its dismantling?” Shapiro, now an assistant professor at UCLA, wrote at the top of his note. “It seems like it could be a humble contribution of our craft — just one stopgap idea that came to mind.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="hXWkWN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The email eventually snowballed into a movement&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="puuRRL"&gt;The effort sparked by the email eventually snowballed into a movement to rescue key environmental datasets and information about climate change from government websites. Shapiro and his colleagues succeeded in connecting with scientists within the EPA to document the agency’s transformation into an antagonist to environmental efforts in the US. And in some cases, the scientists were even able to mitigate the damage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y2x0zU"&gt;The scrappy cadre of scientists is now a largely volunteer-based group called the Environmental Data and Governance Initiative (EDGI). Their work is far from over, despite Trump leaving office, as they work to make sure another president can’t drastically remake federal websites or destroy data in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="7TjIRH"&gt;Data Rescue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="SXfN56"&gt;“Trump wanted to tear the EPA into little bits,” says Sara Wylie, an associate professor at Northeastern University who responded to Shapiro’s email. “We started talking on that email thread about what we might be able to do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TaVQvi"&gt;The scientists worried that if records started disappearing, it would be harder to build on prior research or to use it to hold polluters accountable. On top of that, the public would lose information that could keep them safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GId7HN"&gt;In a matter of weeks, they launched “&lt;a href="https://technoscienceunit.org/2016/12/04/guerrilla-archiving-event-saving-environmental-data-from-trump/"&gt;guerrilla archiving&lt;/a&gt;” events that made &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/12/13/13937938/climate-change-data-download-government-websites-donald-trump"&gt;headlines&lt;/a&gt; for attracting hundreds of volunteers across the US and &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-38324045"&gt;Canada&lt;/a&gt; who helped to identify and save environmental datasets. The EPA keeps records, for example, of the most dangerous substances at toxic Superfund sites that have been placed on a national priority list for cleanup. At each archiving event, volunteers identified important URLs and determined whether they needed to be manually backed up or if they could be harvested by the nonprofit Internet Archive, which stores a history of website changes over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="NOfhn9"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“This was paid for by taxpayer dollars. You don’t really have the right to delete or remove it.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QyIw79"&gt;The effort dovetailed with a &lt;a href="http://eotarchive.cdlib.org/partners.html"&gt;collaboration&lt;/a&gt; called the End of Term Web Archive, which saves content on government websites before every presidential transition and makes it publicly available through the Internet Archive. They also collaborated with researchers at the University of Pennsylvania, who still &lt;a href="https://www.datarefuge.org/dataset"&gt;house data&lt;/a&gt; that needed to be manually archived. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3gtyOGWGJIq2J0yOIa_jx4wRylw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22349991/20161217___Volunteers.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: EDGI&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Volunteers at EDGI’s first data rescue event at the University of Toronto on December 17th, 2016. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VvO42c"&gt;“It was really a public outcry of saying, this is public data,” Wylie says. “Federal government: This was paid for by taxpayer dollars. You don’t really have the right to delete or remove it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vlJTZR"&gt;Beyond saving data, Wylie worked to make it more accessible to people. Over the past year, EDGI began aggregating data on the EPA’s enforcement actions to make it easier for communities to see where companies violated environmental law. Last year, they created &lt;a href="https://www.environmentalenforcementwatch.org/reports"&gt;report cards&lt;/a&gt; for congressional districts and found an enormous jump — a median &lt;a href="https://envirodatagov.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Democratizing-Data-Summary-Report.pdf"&gt;98 percent increase&lt;/a&gt; — in violations to the US Clean Water Act across 55 districts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bKCDv2"&gt;Website Watchdogs &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="M6IbFU"&gt;Soon after Trump stepped into office, EDGI noticed changes to government websites that made it harder to find information about climate change and pollution. Science agencies overhauled their websites, taking down pages and paring down information. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="RsTmNc"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“A very hazy, fast-moving time”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="c06xZD"&gt;“You’re asking about a very hazy, fast-moving time,” Gretchen Gehrke, one of the recipients of Shapiro’s email and now a program leader for EDGI, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; with a laugh as she recalls the early days of the group’s work to monitor government websites. A five-person team was put together to monitor tens of thousands of web pages. “We were all working all hours of the night. Everybody had full-time jobs, and we’re working on this 40 hours a week on the side.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Side by side screenshots of the EPA’s website about climate change showing the 2016 content removed by 2020." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_ZRh9Fukw6uYTP2MyMOaxdTB0AY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22353515/journal.pone.0246450.g001__1_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0246450" target="_blank"&gt;EDGI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;EDGI documented changes to the EPA’s climate change webpage from 2016 to 2020.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="cTHEVk"&gt;Before the group developed more sophisticated software, it started with a version that flagged all kinds of changes to websites. In those early days, Gehrke and her small team had the tedious job of looking through what was flagged to sort out which changes were actually meaningful. “It was like searching for a needle in the haystack,” Gehrke says. “Every difference showed up — which, for a lot of pages, was a date stamp change or removal of an excess space somewhere.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3TPiM4"&gt;Typos and date stamps aside, Gehrke’s team found changes and deletions that could have grave consequences. Official websites not only reflect the priorities of agencies like the Environmental Protection Agency; they also are an important resource for the public to learn about issues like air and water pollution that impact their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pJHp6EiCK0-kWlI0-UAKuVJUHWc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22349999/DataRescue_SFBay_WebArchiving_KyalaShea.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: EDGI&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;EDGI volunteers gathered for a data rescue event in San Francisco in spring 2017.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="EDGI members met in person for the first time to craft the organization’s mission, vision, and values. " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dVQg3cNoEqjd_TNam0xBIkgNFtY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22350002/20170828_edgi_meeting_postits2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: EDGI&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;After working from different states for months, EDGI founders finally met in-person in Boston in September 2017. The team came together to craft the organization’s mission, vision, and values. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XwHVfq"&gt;Months into Trump’s presidency, the term “climate change” was already disappearing from government websites, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/20/climate/epa-climate-change.html"&gt;EDGI found&lt;/a&gt;. It also found that webpages for major environmental regulations aimed at protecting Americans’ air and water were taken down months before Trump’s administration even proposed rolling them back. Gehrke says that undermined the public’s ability to understand the rules and participate in public comment periods before they could be repealed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mBNlBT"&gt;When the National Park Service took down plans from its website about how individual parks would respond to climate change, Gehrke’s group sounded the alarm with &lt;a href="https://envirodatagov.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/AAR-6-NPS-Climate-Action-Plans-171221.pdf"&gt;a report&lt;/a&gt; on the deletion. Following that report, the NPS said that it had temporarily taken the information down to make it more &lt;a href="https://envirodatagov.org/answering-questions-accessibility-regulations-access-climate-action-plans/"&gt;accessible&lt;/a&gt; to people with disabilities — &lt;a href="https://envirodatagov.org/climate-action-plans-for-national-parks-removed-from-site/"&gt;saying&lt;/a&gt; in a statement to EDGI at the time that it would bring the information back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="fEq5gS"&gt;Storytelling for Science  &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="GdM8r0"&gt;As Trump attacked the EPA on his election campaign trail, Chris Sellers, a professor of environmental history at Stony Brook University, realized there was another crucial source of information that was at risk: the people who actually made science agencies tick. Months before he was elected, Trump called the EPA the “&lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/donald-trump-vows-to-slash-funding-for-education-epa-1452551107"&gt;laughingstock of the world&lt;/a&gt;” and proposed funding cuts to the agency that were sure to lead to staff cuts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qRn94o"&gt;Ultimately, more than 1,600 federal scientists left their positions during the first two years of Trump’s presidency, &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/climate-environment/science-ranks-grow-thin-in-trump-administration/2020/01/23/5d22b522-3172-11ea-a053-dc6d944ba776_story.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post &lt;/em&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; in January 2020. “Much of the expertise of the federal bureaucracy has fled in horror,” Michael Gerrard, founder and faculty director of the Sabin Center for Climate Change Law at Columbia University, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/science/21562765/joe-biden-climate-change-epa-scientists"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; last year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cW8M0V"&gt;Hoping to archive the wealth of knowledge those people hold, Sellers and others at EDGI began confidentially interviewing staff at the EPA and OSHA. By June 2017, &lt;a href="https://100days.envirodatagov.org/epa-under-siege/"&gt;EDGI published a report&lt;/a&gt; compiling 60 confidential interviews. Morale among agency staff “plummeted,”  the report showed. Their work was “paralyzed.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="za0oMF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Another crucial source of information was at risk: the people&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hjQWef"&gt;A few months later, &lt;a href="https://100days.envirodatagov.org/mustafa-ali-interview/"&gt;EDGI published an interview&lt;/a&gt; with Mustafa Ali, who led efforts to address environmental racism at the EPA, after his high-profile &lt;a href="https://insideclimatenews.org/news/09032017/epa-environmental-justice-mustafa-ali-flint-water-crisis-dakota-access-pipeline-trump-scott-pruitt/"&gt;exit from the agency&lt;/a&gt;. When asked which programs and projects he was worried about at the agency, Ali responded: “I’m worried about all of them… There’s not too many places in the agency that I think this new administration has not placed some really tough times ahead of.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eSEAqb"&gt;Now, with a new president in power, more of the people who EDGI spoke to are willing to come forward with their stories. Since December, EDGI has slowly released previously anonymous individual interviews on a new website, &lt;a href="https://www.apeoplesepa.org/"&gt;apeoplesepa.org&lt;/a&gt; — now with names attached to the stories. The interviews aren’t just an indictment of the Trump administration’s attack on science; they also make up a library of lessons learned about how to serve people and the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NNDEAk"&gt;“In a time when you feel so many of these institutions are being trampled upon just willy nilly, to be able to do something towards reversing all that damage [has] been a really gratifying experience,” Sellers says. “It really helped me survive the Trump years.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="MZQhLZ"&gt;
&lt;p id="paaAnc"&gt;Some of the EDGI scientists’ initial fears came to fruition. By the end of Trump’s term, the use of the words “climate change” fell by almost 40 percent across websites for US federal environmental agencies. And access to as much as 20 percent of the EPA’s website was removed, &lt;a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0246450"&gt;according to EDGI&lt;/a&gt;. Trump’s administration rolled back more than 100 environmental regulations. And science agencies indeed suffered a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/science/21562765/joe-biden-climate-change-epa-scientists"&gt;brain drain&lt;/a&gt;. But EDGI celebrated some victories throughout Trump’s administration, and their work isn’t done now that someone else is in office. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="TYIFaT"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Their work isn’t done now that someone else is in office&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xFzi5Y"&gt;All in all, EDGI and its collaborators managed to archive over 200 terabytes of data and content from government websites between fall 2016 and spring 2017. There was so much hype over the effort that EDGI members think they may have deterred the Trump administration from actually trying to delete data. The datasets that they took care to save, for the most part, stayed up on federal websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tT0gQi"&gt;They’re still trying to keep that data safe for posterity. They don’t want the data to fall victim to any future administration’s whims. One approach they’re looking into is the so-called “&lt;a href="https://2020.cascadiajs.com/speakers/kelsey-breseman"&gt;distributed web&lt;/a&gt;.” It’s still a developing concept, but the idea would be to back up the data across a peer-to-peer network so no one person can control it. “There are so many copies [of the data] that it can kind of never be magically deleted,” Wylie says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="Vg5Sus"&gt;EDGI is also pushing for policies that provide high standards for web governance. Information on government websites should be archived and easily accessible, the group says in a &lt;a href="https://envirodatagov.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Access-Denied-Report.pdf"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; released in February. That means that even if a web page is taken down, its address should lead to an archived version of the page — not a “Page Not Found” notification. If knowledge is power, they want to make sure that people always have access to it. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22313763/scientists-climate-change-data-rescue-donald-trump"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22313763/scientists-climate-change-data-rescue-donald-trump</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T08:49:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T08:49:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>OpenAI’s state-of-the-art machine vision AI is fooled by handwritten notes</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6z_xFM1uUxZiqKuGjMCLSAEt3CQ=/0x15:1196x812/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68928867/apple_ipod_test.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Need to trick OpenAI’s latest vision system? Simply add a handwritten label to your target.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: OpenAI&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1tPBSY"&gt;Researchers from machine learning lab OpenAI have &lt;a href="https://openai.com/blog/multimodal-neurons/"&gt;discovered&lt;/a&gt; that their state-of-the-art computer vision system can be defeated by tools no more sophisticated than a pen and a pad. As illustrated in the image above, simply writing down the name of an object and sticking it on another can be enough to trick the software into misidentifying what it sees. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1hbl38"&gt;“We refer to these attacks as &lt;em&gt;typographic&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;attacks&lt;/em&gt;,” write OpenAI’s researchers in a &lt;a href="https://openai.com/blog/multimodal-neurons/"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;. “By exploiting the model’s ability to read text robustly, we find that even photographs of hand-written text can often fool the model.” They note that such attacks are similar to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/3/16844842/ai-computer-vision-trick-adversarial-patches-google"&gt;“adversarial images”&lt;/a&gt; that can fool commercial machine vision systems, but far simpler to produce. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Ob1JC5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Adversarial images pose a real threat, but this particular example is not too serious&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IP9D5T"&gt;Adversarial images present a real danger for systems that rely on machine vision. Researchers have shown, for example, that they can trick the software in Tesla’s self-driving cars to &lt;a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/cars-that-think/transportation/self-driving/three-small-stickers-on-road-can-steer-tesla-autopilot-into-oncoming-lane"&gt;change lanes without warning&lt;/a&gt; simply by placing certain stickers on the road. Such attacks are a serious threat for a variety of AI applications, from the medical to the military.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yv6COx"&gt;But the danger posed by this specific attack is, at least for now, nothing to worry about. The OpenAI software in question is an experimental system named CLIP that isn’t deployed in any commercial product. Indeed, the very nature of CLIP’s unusual machine learning architecture created the weakness that enables this attack to succeed. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kZd4lGPx2REMgyRvL2L_67I0nn8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22353512/Screen_Shot_2021_03_08_at_1.11.48_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: OpenAI&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Multimodal neurons” in CLIP respond to photos of an object as well as sketches and text. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="lC5wJH"&gt;CLIP is intended to explore how AI systems might learn to identify objects without close supervision by training on huge databases of image and text pairs. In this case, OpenAI used some 400 million image-text pairs scraped from the internet to train CLIP, which was &lt;a href="https://openai.com/blog/clip/"&gt;unveiled in January&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mtW7Gp"&gt;This month, OpenAI researchers published a new paper describing how they’d opened up CLIP to see how it performs. They discovered what they’re calling “multimodal neurons” — individual components in the machine learning network that respond not only to images of objects but also the associated text. One of the reasons this is exciting is that it seems to mirror how the human brain reacts to stimuli, where single brain cells have been observed &lt;a href="https://phys.org/news/2005-06-single-cell-recognition-halle-berry-neuron.html"&gt;responding to abstract concepts&lt;/a&gt; rather than specific examples. OpenAI’s research suggests it may be possible for AI systems to internalize such knowledge the same way humans do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lDIyeT"&gt;In the future, this could lead to more sophisticated vision systems, but right now, such approaches are in their infancy. While any human being can tell you the difference between an apple and a piece of paper with the word “apple” written on it, software like CLIP can’t. The same ability that allows the program to link words and images at an abstract level creates this unique weakness, which OpenAI describes as the “fallacy of abstraction.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NhAEY4ThinG6mogatvaIgaYJLFg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22353485/chain_saw_piggy_bank.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: OpenAI&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Another example of a typographic attack. Do not trust the AI to put your money in the piggy bank. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="u2dhao"&gt;Another example given by the lab is the neuron in CLIP that identifies piggy banks. This component not only responds to pictures of piggy banks but strings of dollar signs, too. As in the example above, that means you can fool CLIP into identifying a chainsaw as a piggy bank if you overlay it with “$$$” strings, as if it were half-price at your local hardware store. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wQwMFl"&gt;The researchers also found that CLIP’s multimodal neurons encoded exactly the sort of biases you might expect to find when sourcing your data from the internet. They note that the neuron for “Middle East” is also associated with terrorism and discovered “a neuron that fires for both dark-skinned people and gorillas.” This replicates an infamous error in Google’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/12/16882408/google-racist-gorillas-photo-recognition-algorithm-ai"&gt;image recognition system&lt;/a&gt;, which tagged Black people as gorillas. It’s yet another example of just how different machine intelligence is to that of humans’ — and why pulling apart the former to understand how it works is necessary before we trust our lives to AI.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319173/openai-machine-vision-adversarial-typographic-attacka-clip-multimodal-neuron"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319173/openai-machine-vision-adversarial-typographic-attacka-clip-multimodal-neuron</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T08:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple and nonprofit Common Sense Media team up to provide kid podcast recs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5yi4JxpFcgJiPb1wdfjGZdTZY_s=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68928583/acastro_190218_1777_apple_streaming_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BJce2y"&gt;Apple is making it easier for parents to find podcasts to listen to with their kids. The company is teaming up with nonprofit Common Sense Media, which specializes in age-based content reviews, to curate various collections that’ll appear in the Apple Podcasts app in the US and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshowsforkids&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F8%2F22316197%2Fapple-podcasts-common-sense-media-kids-content" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;. The initial four themes focus on narrative storytelling, shows that kids themselves recommend, mysteries and dramas, and Common Sense’s “all-time” picks. Programming comes from Tinkercast, American Public Media, WNYC Studios, Rebel Girls, and Nickelodeon, among others, and Common Sense will provide age group recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9nljTL"&gt;The collections will be updated monthly with new themes being tied to “important historical and cultural moments,” like Women’s History Month. You’ll see these show suggestions starting today in Apple Podcasts’ main homepage carousel, and then they’ll be available through the Browse tab indefinitely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZWk5bi"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Four collections will launch today&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wTL4E9"&gt;Podcasts for children have become increasingly popular as the hype around audio grows and parents look for ways to keep their kids entertained without relying on a screen. Common Sense &lt;a href="https://www.commonsensemedia.org/blog/the-best-podcasts-for-kids"&gt;previously published&lt;/a&gt; podcast recommendations, but this new partnership with Apple represents its biggest commitment to audio programming yet. Hot Pod writer Nick Quah &lt;a href="https://hotpodnews.com/kids-podcasts-see-a-bump/"&gt;reported last year&lt;/a&gt; that kid podcast creators saw huge bumps in listenership at the start of the pandemic. One company, Gen-Z Media, said its show &lt;em&gt;Six Minutes &lt;/em&gt;performed about 2 million downloads a month, but during the pandemic, it was on track for 3 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JYSdcw"&gt;Other companies, like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/31/21200272/spotify-kids-playlist-rollout-app-launch-beta"&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/14/21436457/amazon-kids-rebranding-freetime"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, place their kid-approved content into separate apps and experiences. Apple seems to think that’s unnecessary for now and that parents can instead rely on themed collections to oversee what their kids enjoy listening to. Apple &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; provide a kid-oriented device experience, but that’s more to give parents control and insight into what their children are consuming than having Apple actually whitelist content. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22316197/apple-podcasts-common-sense-media-kids-content"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22316197/apple-podcasts-common-sense-media-kids-content</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T05:39:18-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T05:39:18-05:00</updated>
    <title>WhatsApp reportedly working on password-protected encrypted chat backups</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sLWmI7R-3aW_rlXybIchZHCzvWs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68928314/acastro_210119_1777_whatsapp_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Zg9UBA"&gt;WhatsApp is reportedly working to increase the security of its cloud backups with a new password protection feature that’ll encrypt chat backups, making them accessible only to the user. &lt;a href="https://wabetainfo.com/whatsapp-is-rolling-out-the-qr-code-support-for-ios-beta-users/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WABetaInfo&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; on the work-in-progress feature last year, and today it &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WABetaInfo/status/1368837911471403009"&gt;shared screenshots&lt;/a&gt; of how it could be presented in the service’s iOS and Android apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VNszMl"&gt;“To prevent unauthorized access to your iCloud Drive backup, you can set a password that will be used to encrypt future backups,” one of the screenshots reads. “This password will be required when you restore from the backup.” The app then asks the user to confirm their phone number, and select a password that’s at least eight characters long. Another screenshot warns that “WhatsApp will not be able to help recover forgotten passwords.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="POqSWj"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;• The chat database is already encrypted now (excluding media), but the algorithm is reversible and it's not end-to-end encrypted. &lt;br&gt;• Local Android backups will be compatible with this feature.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The chat DB and media will be encrypted using a password that only you know. &lt;a href="https://t.co/WAliLUnF18"&gt;https://t.co/WAliLUnF18&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— WABetaInfo (@WABetaInfo) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WABetaInfo/status/1368839686102384640?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 8, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="blSNQF"&gt;Although WhatsApp chats are end-to-end encrypted, meaning they’re only visible to the sender and recipient, the service warns that this protection doesn’t extend to online backups stored on &lt;a href="https://faq.whatsapp.com/android/chats/about-google-drive-backups/"&gt;Google Drive&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://faq.whatsapp.com/iphone/chats/how-to-back-up-to-icloud"&gt;iCloud&lt;/a&gt;. Once on these servers, the security of the backups is the responsibility of the cloud service providers, who in the past have made them &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/zm8q43/paul-manafort-icloud-whatsapp-bad-opsec-witness-tampering"&gt;accessible to law enforcement authorities&lt;/a&gt; with valid search warrants. Encrypting the backups with a password only you know would theoretically prevent anyone from accessing your chat history without your authorization. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HBQ5O7"&gt;These latest reports about the feature come as WhatsApp’s reputation has taken a hit from a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289595/whatsapp-privacy-policy-app-banner-explanation-telegram"&gt;new privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;, which has stoked fears that it may store more information with parent company Facebook. Although WhatsApp insists the new policy doesn’t affect the security of users’ personal messages, rival messaging services like Signal and Telegram have seen a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226792/whatsapp-privacy-policy-response-signal-telegram-controversy-clarification"&gt;surge in interest&lt;/a&gt; as users explore other options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F4F3JW"&gt;WhatsApp declined to comment on the unannounced feature when contacted by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, but &lt;em&gt;WABetaInfo &lt;/em&gt;has a good track record of unearthing features before they become official. It’s spotted features like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/22/21267292/whatsapp-qr-codes-adding-contacts-beta-ios-android"&gt;adding contacts via QR codes&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/1/20893033/whatsapp-disappearing-messages-beta-self-destruct-privacy-security"&gt;disappearing messages&lt;/a&gt; long before their &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/1/21309982/whatsapp-contact-qr-codes-animated-stickers-video-call-improvements"&gt;official&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/5/21550634/whatsapp-disappearing-messages-feature"&gt;announcements&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mak8hm"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4iviKC"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319136/whatsapp-cloud-backups-icloud-google-drive-password-encryption-security"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319136/whatsapp-cloud-backups-icloud-google-drive-password-encryption-security</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T04:17:52-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T04:17:52-05:00</updated>
    <title>EU approves Microsoft’s $7.5 billion Bethesda acquisition</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rxA1FKWo9liaTlYi4cGanFj2azQ=/1x0:1848x1231/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68928256/xboxbethesda.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MRXMdN"&gt;The European Commission has approved Microsoft’s $7.5 billion deal to acquire ZeniMax Media, the parent company of &lt;em&gt;Doom&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Fallout&lt;/em&gt; studio Bethesda Softworks. Microsoft’s deal has been &lt;a href="https://ec.europa.eu/competition/elojade/isef/case_details.cfm?proc_code=2_M_10001"&gt;approved by the EU&lt;/a&gt; without conditions, as it “does not raise serious doubts as to its compatibility with the common market.” The acquisition required EU approval before Microsoft could finalize the Bethesda deal and bring future games to its Xbox Game Pass subscription. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g3OJq7"&gt;“The Commission concluded that the proposed acquisition would raise no competition concerns, given the combined entity’s limited market position upstream and the presence of strong downstream competitors in the distribution of video games,” says a European Commission statement. “The transaction was examined under the normal merger review procedure.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pgdwHE"&gt;Once the deal is fully closed, Microsoft’s list of first-party studios will jump to 23, following the addition of Bethesda sub-studios like &lt;em&gt;Dishonored&lt;/em&gt; developer Arkane, &lt;em&gt;Wolfenstein&lt;/em&gt; studio MachineGames, &lt;em&gt;Doom&lt;/em&gt; maker id Software, and &lt;em&gt;The Evil Within&lt;/em&gt; studio Tango Gameworks. Microsoft appears to be planning to keep Bethesda running separately, with its existing leadership. That approach seems to have worked for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/9/15/6151477/microsoft-minecraft-mojang-acquisition"&gt;Mojang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/6/13/11920072/microsoft-linkedin-acquisition-2016"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/4/17422788/microsoft-github-acquisition-official-deal"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, which have all continued to run separately after Microsoft acquired them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="5YFNLo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Why Microsoft bought Bethesda for $7.5 billion ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21449178/microsoft-xbox-bethesda-zenimax-media-acquisition-xbox-game-pass"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="ha3Rnn"&gt;Microsoft originally &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/21/21448877/microsoft-bethesda-softworks-zenimax-acquisition-xbox-game-pass-series-x"&gt;announced its plans&lt;/a&gt; to acquire Bethesda in September, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/21/21449121/microsoft-bethesda-ps5-playstation-5-xbox-series-x-s-consoles-exclusives"&gt;promising to honor PS5 exclusivity commitments&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;em&gt;Deathloop&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;GhostWire: Tokyo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Games like &lt;em&gt;The Elder Scrolls: Online &lt;/em&gt;will also “continue to be supported exactly as it was.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hbzm1w"&gt;How Microsoft handles future Bethesda titles will come down to a “case-by-case” basis, according to comments from Microsoft’s gaming chief Phil Spencer in September. It’s still not clear how Microsoft plans to handle the upcoming space epic &lt;em&gt;Starfield&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1eiaA8"&gt;Microsoft might not even have to launch future Bethesda games exclusively on Xbox. Just having them on day one on Xbox Game Pass might be a big enough draw in itself for players to subscribe. Xbox gaming chief Phil Spencer has also &lt;a href="https://www.gamereactor.eu/phil-spencer-on-exclusivity-monetisation-and-game-development/"&gt;questioned the viability&lt;/a&gt; of exclusivity deals for games recently, and Microsoft’s plans for Xbox are very much centered on Xbox Game Pass and xCloud game streaming reaching millions more people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="srO87z"&gt;In fact, Microsoft is reportedly planning to outline its plans for Xbox later this month. A “future of gaming” event is rumored to take place on March 23rd, and it could be an ideal opportunity for Microsoft to discuss the future of Bethesda, xCloud on iOS, and its plans for Xbox Game Pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eq4iqe"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, March 8th 6:40AM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Article updated with full statement from the European Commission. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22315104/microsoft-bethesda-acquisition-eu-approval-deal"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22315104/microsoft-bethesda-acquisition-eu-approval-deal</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T01:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T01:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>OnePlus’ next phones will come out on March 23rd</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gd20eAxmGutUK_pqXNBPCzRYU9o=/94x0:1107x675/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68928031/Image_2.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;OnePlus confirms it will launch its 9-series devices later this month. | Image: OnePlus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HJkiMb"&gt;OnePlus has announced an official launch date for its next phones: the OnePlus 9 series will be formally announced on March 23rd at 10AM ET. It’s also confirming a partnership with Swedish camera maker Hasselblad to improve the devices’ camera systems — something that’s been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/8/22272052/oneplus-9-pro-hasselbland-quad-rear-cameras-ultrawide-telephoto-zoom-specs"&gt;leaked&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/1/22306934/oneplus-9-launch-event-date-moonshot-pete-lau"&gt;hinted at&lt;/a&gt; previously. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l81V8D"&gt;Rumors thus far have pointed to the announcement of a OnePlus 9 Pro with curved 1440p 120Hz display, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/4/22213390/oneplus-9-pro-45-watt-wireless-charging-reverse"&gt;45W fast charging&lt;/a&gt;, and reverse wireless charging. OnePlus’ reference to the “series” product launch would seem to confirm more than one device debuting later this month. There’s also confirmation of 5G, which isn’t surprising in this year of our lord 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="07e4P0"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The companies have tweaked the cameras’ color reproduction to look more natural&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Y0mobt"&gt;As for the Hasselblad partnership, details aren’t super promising. The two companies have agreed to a three-year deal to “co-develop the next generation of smartphone camera systems for future OnePlus flagship devices.” That includes the upcoming 9-series devices. For a start, the companies claim to have tweaked the cameras’ color reproduction to look more natural. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZSWx1S"&gt;The 9-series will also use a new Sony IMX789 sensor and offer 12-bit RAW image capture, which the Samsung S21 Ultra and iPhone 12 Pro and Pro Max also include. That’s a nice step forward to capture and retain this large amount of data, and it’s helpful for post-processing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ct36Tw"&gt;But a standard RAW file — even one that’s 12-bit — still misses out on the benefits of computational photography that you’ll enjoy taking a regular JPEG image with the native camera app. It would be even better to offer something like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/14/22174433/apple-ios-14-3-pro-raw-iphone-12-pro-max-update-features"&gt;Apple’s ProRAW&lt;/a&gt;, which combines the benefits of those computational techniques and RAW image capture. That doesn’t seem to be what OnePlus is describing here, but we’ve reached out to ask and will update this story accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="oPalkR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"OnePlus 8 Pro review: big league","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/14/21219861/oneplus-8-pro-review-specs-features-price-camera-battery-photos-video"},{"title":"OnePlus 8 review: familiar formula","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/14/21219278/oneplus-8-review-specs-features-camera-battery-screen-price-photos-video"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="SYLFho"&gt;It’s fair to treat this Hasselblad partnership with some skepticism. OnePlus is far from the first smartphone manufacturer to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/2/25/11111022/huawei-leica-collaboration-mobile-photography"&gt;partner with a legacy camera brand&lt;/a&gt;, and results from previous partnerships &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/4/26/11507260/leica-phone-huawei-p9-no"&gt;haven’t amounted to much&lt;/a&gt;. This isn’t even Hasselblad’s first partnership with a phone manufacturer. The company previously &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2016/8/31/12729838/hasselblad-true-zoom-announced-moto-z"&gt;loaned its name to a MotoMod&lt;/a&gt; that was more or less just an underwhelming point-and-shoot camera. In this case, at least, the results of this joint venture will go into the phone itself — not on something that attaches to it.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22315517/oneplus-9-launch-date-hasselblad-camera"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22315517/oneplus-9-launch-date-hasselblad-camera</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T00:00:35-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T00:00:35-05:00</updated>
    <title>Oppo overtakes Huawei to lead Chinese smartphone market for first time</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KE_veaLpsdmmpG5MQIUdKpc8ApY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68927938/DSCF7293.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="M3PqSc"&gt;Oppo has become the best-selling smartphone brand in China for the first time ever, &lt;a href="https://www.counterpointresearch.com/oppo-becomes-number-1-smartphone-brand-china-first-time-ever/"&gt;according to figures from Counterpoint Research&lt;/a&gt;. Counterpoint’s report says that Oppo managed to capture 21 percent of the world’s biggest smartphone market in January, ahead of Vivo and Huawei, which both achieved 20 percent. Apple and Xiaomi rounded out the top five with 16 percent apiece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vwWkpF"&gt;Oppo’s sales were up 26 percent year on year and increased 33 percent from the previous month. Counterpoint says that the new Reno 5 series had a successful launch due to offering better specs at a lower price point than the earlier Reno 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EktVGt"&gt;But for Oppo to gain market share, someone has to lose it, and the report shows that Huawei’s smartphone troubles are taking hold in China too. Counterpoint says Huawei has increased its focus on the premium market because of component shortages caused by US sanctions, so Chinese distributors have been focusing on other brands for volume. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/16/21570744/huawei-honor-sale-announced-us-sanctions"&gt;Huawei’s sale of Honor&lt;/a&gt;, which was also sparked by sanctions, will cut its market share down further, with Honor now considered a competitor as opposed to an asset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="v720FG"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Introducing the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/OPPOFindX3Pro?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#OPPOFindX3Pro&lt;/a&gt;, our latest high-end flagship series. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AwakenColour?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#AwakenColour&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/GxerLioEq3"&gt;pic.twitter.com/GxerLioEq3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— OPPO (@oppo) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/oppo/status/1368748571101597698?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 8, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="U8NFzq"&gt;These figures are just for one month, but Counterpoint expects Huawei’s share of the market to continue its decline throughout 2021. Oppo will look to capitalize on the opportunity with the launch of its latest flagship phone, the Find X3 Pro, which is being announced in full on Thursday. If you want an early look, the company just tweeted a teaser that doesn’t leave a whole lot to the imagination.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22318941/china-smartphone-market-share-oppo-huawei-vivo-apple-xiaomi-january-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22318941/china-smartphone-market-share-oppo-huawei-vivo-apple-xiaomi-january-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
