<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-05-05T15:30:38-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-05T15:30:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-05T15:30:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>A bug in Peloton’s API may have exposed a whole lot of user data</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Pelton Bike Plus in an apartment" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jQMm6eftHNSsz4GbT1j4SRw9VsI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69242235/akrales210108_4344_0020.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ncQozM"&gt;An old version of Peloton’s API, the software that allows the company’s bikes and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22420918/peloton-treadmill-recall-tread-accidents-cpsc-voluntary-refund"&gt;recalled treadmills&lt;/a&gt; to communicate with its servers, may have exposed private customer profiles, according to &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/05/peloton-bug-account-data-leak/"&gt;a report from &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;The bug was first spotted by Jan Masters, a security researcher at Pen Test Partners, and reported to Peloton on January 20th, but the company is only just now confirming that the bug has been fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fuZLzG"&gt;Using Peloton’s API, Masters was able to scrape all sorts of customer information that would typically be private, depending on the individual user’s settings. That includes customer profiles, which can potentially feature their age, location, birthday, and workout history. All Masters had to do was make an unauthenticated request to Peloton’s API and customer data was his. Masters has a more thorough explanation of how the exploit worked &lt;a href="https://www.pentestpartners.com/security-blog/tour-de-peloton-exposed-user-data/?=050420210000"&gt;on Pen Test Partners’ blog&lt;/a&gt; and also summarized his findings in the video below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iEKwp2"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WMgvMajthkI?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="75le1b"&gt;After reporting the bug to Peloton, Masters set a 90-day deadline to address the issue. That deadline came and went without Peloton saying whether the API was fixed, which prompted Masters to turn to &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;. Peloton finally responded and shared the following statement with the publication:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="iTuetT"&gt;It’s a priority for Peloton to keep our platform secure and we’re always looking to improve our approach and process for working with the external security community. Through our Coordinated Vulnerability Disclosure program, a security researcher informed us that he was able to access our API and see information that’s available on a Peloton profile. We took action, and addressed the issues based on his initial submissions, but we were slow to update the researcher about our remediation efforts. Going forward, we will do better to work collaboratively with the security research community and respond more promptly when vulnerabilities are reported. We want to thank Ken Munro for submitting his reports through our CVD program and for being open to working with us to resolve these issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="dWdC3P"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/4/25/15408338/bike-peloton-review-indoor-cycle-live-streaming-cycling"&gt;The screens on Peloton’s bikes&lt;/a&gt; and treadmills are what make the company’s workout ways so compelling. It’s how subscribers attend classes, track their workouts, and even do other non-bike or treadmill exercises. It’s a feature that Peloton charges $39 per month for an all-access membership to. Yet, like all connected devices, particularly fitness ones, it can leave private customer information more vulnerable than a non-connected stationary bike would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tSNrpr"&gt;Masters writes that Peloton apologized and said it resolved a majority of the API issues within a week of his report. What’s not immediately clear is if anyone other than Masters gained access to customer data while the API was in a leaky state. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p86hZq"&gt;When &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;followed up to check&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;Peloton said it had nothing new to share that it hadn’t already provided &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt; and Pen Test Partners. The company also reiterated it responded to the API issue immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZsxuNt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ii07Lf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421329/peloton-api-bug-customer-data-exposed"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421329/peloton-api-bug-customer-data-exposed</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-05T15:16:40-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-05T15:16:40-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon wants to make sure drivers who don’t work for the company are well-groomed and nice online</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cAb6seFMQ-ia5NylhdGN8motOt4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69242157/acastro_181114_1777_amazon_hq2_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5ZrK3F"&gt;Amazon is infamous for tightly controlling its workers and contractors, but &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-05/amazon-work-rules-govern-tweets-body-odor-of-contract-drivers"&gt;a report from &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; shows that it also tries to control the employees of companies that it contracts. The company has explicit policies concerning personal grooming and social media etiquette that apply to the drivers from other delivery companies. The rules govern everything from how the delivery people look (they must have clean fingernails, teeth, ears, and hair) to how they smell (no bad breath, body odor, or immodest perfume). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JHHUeG"&gt;The rules also apparently forbid drivers from making social media posts that could be considered obscene. That by itself wouldn’t be remarkable, but it’s worth noting that these policies are applied to drivers that don’t work for Amazon, and so reach much further than the company’s official employee base. The drivers are instead employees of local delivery companies that are contracted by Amazon through its Delivery Service Partners program. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KhY8Xh"&gt;The workers for these companies are the same ones affected &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/24/22347945/amazon-delivery-drivers-ai-surveillance-cameras-vans-consent-form"&gt;by the company’s AI-powered cameras&lt;/a&gt;. Drivers have to consent to always-on cameras monitoring them for things like distracted driving or traffic violations if they want to work (or keep working) by delivering packages for the retail giant. Amazon’s plan to install the cameras was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/3/22265031/amazon-netradyne-driveri-survelliance-cameras-delivery-monitor-packages"&gt;discovered through a video&lt;/a&gt; where an Amazon manager explained the partnership between the company and the camera manufacturer. &lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt; has since discovered driver consent forms as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HAa5JQ"&gt;Amazon is well-known for not giving its employees (or those who work under its umbrella) much leeway when it comes to handling their personal lives — many warehouse employees &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/1/20892693/amazon-protest-time-off-part-time-workers-sacramento-fired"&gt;have to micromanage their time away from work&lt;/a&gt; to avoid being fired, and the company allegedly constantly texted employees during &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22374540/amazon-union-vote-outcome-bessemer-alabama-rwdsu-bhm1"&gt;the recent Alabama union drive&lt;/a&gt;. Amazon’s leadership, including Jeff Bezos, has claimed that it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22385762/bezos-letter-shareholders-amazon-workers-union-bessemer-workplace"&gt;doesn’t treat its employees like robots&lt;/a&gt; — but it’s hard to look at rules like this for drivers who aren’t even contractors and believe that’s the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nWfxyP"&gt;Amazon did not immediately reply to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421327/amazon-drivers-delivery-service-partner-rules-grooming-online-conduct"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421327/amazon-drivers-delivery-service-partner-rules-grooming-online-conduct</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-05T14:25:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-05T14:25:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft’s feud with Apple over xCloud on iOS got a rival kicked from the App Store</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fpd1t7o7MzXlDkz8zfhVU81tQI0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69241844/acastro_210429_1777_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="59ak2k"&gt;In 2020, Microsoft was battling to bring xCloud or Xbox Game Streaming to the iPhone and iPad, and the conversations had an unlikely victim: Shadow — a third-party cloud gaming app that lets you stream PC games to an iPhone or iPad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5cZfC5"&gt;Emails between Microsoft and Apple, revealed in the &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;/em&gt; trial today, show how the Xbox maker was trying to get xCloud on iOS. Microsoft was trying to figure out how Shadow, Netflix, and other similar “interactive” apps were able to exist in the App Store while Apple was refusing to approve xCloud. Microsoft put forward Shadow as an example of such a service, only to see it suddenly removed from the store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bSJBCU"&gt;“We were showing two examples where a game or an application was able to exist, and we didn’t understand why we couldn’t,” explained Lori Wright, Microsoft’s head of business development for Xbox, during the &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;/em&gt; trial today. “I believe they [Apple] ended up pulling Shadow out of the App Store based off this email we sent until they submitted changes. That was not our intention of course, it was a byproduct.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kwP09JyRmiWPgyGUd-04tZfidVE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22493777/0_yXBrpxirKTDnT7a8.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Shadow&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shadow on iPhone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="REs2dG"&gt;While Shadow’s removal wasn’t permanent, Apple has temporarily removed the app from the App Store twice in the past year. Shadow was &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ShadowPC/comments/f9wtjl/shadow_ios_app_removed_from_the_app_store/"&gt;first removed in February&lt;/a&gt; last year, with Apple reportedly citing a “failure to act in accordance with a specific part of the Apple App Store Guidelines.” Apple once again &lt;a href="https://forum.shadow.tech/news-announcements-42/shadow-removed-from-apple-app-store-what-you-should-know-2314"&gt;removed Shadow from the App Store&lt;/a&gt; in February, and the app returned a week later. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zDi8OE"&gt;Shadow revealed that the app was removed the second time “due to a misunderstanding” around the nature of the app. “Unlike game streaming services, Shadow provides a full Windows 10 PC, rather than a library of games,” explained Luc Hancock, a community manager for Shadow. “This unique approach allows Shadow to comply with the App Store guidelines, so that you can access your Shadow PC on any iOS device to run your favorite games and software.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vb5FdM"&gt;Valve struggled for more than a year to launch its Steam Link game streaming service on iOS. Apple rejected the app, likely because it allowed an iOS user to access another app store, Steam, within Apple’s tightly controlled ecosystem. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/5/17430532/apple-app-store-rules-valve-steam-link-game-streaming"&gt;Apple revised its rules&lt;/a&gt; after rejecting Steam Link, and the app was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/15/18627110/steam-link-app-ios-apple-tv-released"&gt;finally approved two years ago in May 2019&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WRtJ8-ceGVFKfD2OG5ld53IrfgM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22457649/xcloudiphone.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Tom Warren / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;xCloud on iOS via the web.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="HOUoIU"&gt;Apple continued to make it difficult for services like xCloud and Stadia to run the way Microsoft and Google wanted to on iOS devices after those conversations, only &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/11/21432695/apple-new-app-store-guidelines-streaming-game-services-email-purchases"&gt;slowly making App Store policy carve-outs&lt;/a&gt; that would let the services operate under severe restrictions. Apple now insists that developers individually submit games as separate apps using their streaming tech, only then bundling them together as a “catalog”-style app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XoZYSl"&gt;Microsoft &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/11/21433071/microsoft-apple-app-store-rules-xcloud-game-streaming-xbox-game-pass"&gt;wasn’t impressed with Apple’s approach&lt;/a&gt;, calling it a “bad experience for customers.” This public spat has now boiled over into the courtroom battle between Epic Games and Apple, with lawyers on Epic’s side questioning Microsoft and Nvidia representatives about their struggles to bring cloud gaming apps to iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KRnKrD"&gt;Both Microsoft and Nvidia have had to give in to Apple’s restrictions and launch their cloud gaming services &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22391561/microsoft-xcloud-ios-pc-xbox-game-streaming-beta-features"&gt;through the Safari web browser&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421290/microsoft-apple-xcloud-ios-shadow-cloud-gaming-removal-app-store"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421290/microsoft-apple-xcloud-ios-shadow-cloud-gaming-removal-app-store</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-05T14:10:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-05T14:10:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook has no reason to ever resolve the Trump ban</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AgW1WrELnnFDGsPn02JIhq9NZj8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69241739/acastro_180501_1777_facebook_dating_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WIpHQY"&gt;After months of waiting, today Facebook’s Oversight Board &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22320329/facebook-oversight-board-trump-ban-decision"&gt;finally handed down&lt;/a&gt; the biggest ruling of its short existence — the question of whether to uphold the ban on Donald Trump. The verdict? Send the question back to Facebook, and give them six more months to decide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zak47n"&gt;In fairness, it wasn’t quite that bad. The initial ban was upheld, and the board &lt;a href="https://oversightboard.com/decision/FB-691QAMHJ/"&gt;made specific rulings&lt;/a&gt; on the questions of whether Trump’s posts were inciting violence, and whether world leaders should get special treatment. For now, Facebook can continue to block Trump, which means that on the face of it, this is a win for anti-Trumpers. Unless you’re visiting his self-hosted website, you’ll remain blessedly safe from Trump posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="QiG0V5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“an endless cycle of uncertainty”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UJuF0J"&gt;But the ruling also went out of its way to avoid settling the long-term question of whether Facebook is allowed to permanently ban leaders like Trump. The board found the initial ban was justified since Trump’s January 6th posts really did incite violence — but it wasn’t enough to justify a permanent ban. So even as the board affirmed the initial ban, it called on Facebook to set a new policy for how and when Trump could regain Facebook access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FZjw9c"&gt;“It is not permissible for Facebook to keep a user off the platform for an undefined period, with no criteria for when or whether the account will be restored,” the ruling reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YCm3aZ"&gt;In practical terms, that means Facebook is going to keep litigating the specifics of the Trump ban for at least the next six months, and probably a whole lot longer. Facebook has until October to come up with a specific policy to justify the ban, to be put in place across the platform. But that policy will likely need more review from inside Facebook once it’s developed, and then another round of appeal to the Oversight Board. Then Trump can try to get back on Facebook (or make just enough effort to justify restarting his feud with the platform), and there will need to be another round of reviews on that, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="yum3oR"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Republicans who are mad can make their case to the board and have their opinions heard — whether it does them any good or not&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NZ0o1c"&gt;And of course, because none of the Oversight decisions are binding on Facebook, the company is free to delay past any of those deadlines if it wants more time. In a statement after the decision, the progressive group Common Cause described it as “an endless cycle of uncertainty,” and it’s hard to disagree. The process could easily stretch through the 2024 election, and given the political interests involved, it’s not clear how it could ever fully resolve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bCZBcV"&gt;If you were hoping to stop talking about Donald Trump online, this is close to a worst-case scenario. The moderation merry-go-round is a political liability for Facebook, and the longer it goes unresolved, the more anger will be stirred up against the platform. The point of founding the Oversight Board was to shovel some of that responsibility onto another group, but this decision puts the ball right back in Facebook’s court. You can already see conservative media figures using the ruling to take shots at the company — and I’m sure lots of Facebook employees are shuddering at the prospect of doing it all again in six months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="phsC3k"&gt;But there’s a deeper logic to the ruling, one that benefits both the Oversight Board and Facebook itself. As &lt;a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2021/05/05/americans-divided-on-whether-trump-should-be-permanently-banned-from-social-media/"&gt;a Pew Research poll&lt;/a&gt; showed this morning, America is split over the question of whether Trump should be on Facebook, and a final ruling is sure to alienate one side or another. So from Facebook’s perspective, the less final this ruling is, the better. What looks like kicking the can down the road is really just leaving the door open for the losing side. Republicans who are mad can make their case to the board and have their opinions heard — whether it does them any good or not. And the next time Mark Zuckerberg is called before Congress, he can tell Republicans he’s working on a final policy that will get Trump back online. When he’s called a year later (or two years, or five years), he can say the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="UEewBd"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Making a decision means taking sides&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SzDkZV"&gt;Platforms love keeping policy questions in limbo this way, in part because making a firm decision is so likely to cause trouble. Look at Twitter, which is always “thinking about” new features like &lt;a href="https://www.socialmediatoday.com/news/is-tweet-editing-coming-does-it-really-matter/547614/"&gt;editable tweets&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-02-08/twitter-considers-subscription-fee-for-tweetdeck-unique-content"&gt;paid subscriptions&lt;/a&gt;, but never seems to launch them. Or look at Facebook’s own behavior in politically unstable countries like Sri Lanka and Myanmar, where civil society groups said they worked with the platform for years &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/18/17369570/facebook-coalition-myanmar-syria-sri-lanka-moderation-transparency-audit"&gt;without ever getting a real response to their demands&lt;/a&gt;. Making a decision means taking sides — and for a platform built on scale, that gambit rarely pays off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gY5QCd"&gt;You can see the same logic working in the Oversight Board itself. The board is slightly better positioned than Facebook to make unpopular decisions, but it’s still been careful to guard its credibility. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/28/22254155/facebook-oversight-board-first-rulings-coronavirus-misinformation-hate-speech"&gt;The rulings so far&lt;/a&gt; have mostly made fine distinctions on existing policies, whether it’s ethnic slurs in Russia or not-quite hate speech in Burma. If the board makes an unpalatable decision — either kicking Trump off the platform permanently or, worse, letting him back on — it would face the same problem as Facebook: potentially losing credibility with an entire portion of Facebook’s user base. Better to kick the can down the road, “keep thinking,” and never land too hard on any one ruling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8DaMBt"&gt;That’s not to say the Oversight Board won’t do anything unpopular. Today’s ruling has already made a lot of conservatives angry, just as the initial ban did. Plotting a middle course doesn’t mean no one will be angry, and there will surely be more moments in the future when Facebook’s refusal to take sides makes one side particularly angry. But if you’re looking for certainty or finality from the Oversight Board’s appeal system, you’re looking in the wrong place. For now, the performative pondering of hard questions is just too convenient to give up.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421334/facebook-donald-trump-oversight-board-ban-decision-criticism"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421334/facebook-donald-trump-oversight-board-ban-decision-criticism</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-05T13:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-05T13:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter updates offensive tweet warnings, accepts that you like to swear at your friends</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Twitter bird logo in white against a dark background with outlined logos around it and red circles rippling out from it." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UDYOT-6zV8Y_ZdFhKyxTqO3asaA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69241394/acastro_180827_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Riigw1"&gt;Twitter is updating its “be nice, think twice” system that prompts users to reconsider when they’re about to tweet a “potentially harmful or offensive” reply. The upgraded feature is now better at spotting “strong language,” claims Twitter; is more aware of vocabulary that has been “reclaimed by underrepresented communities” and is used in non-harmful ways; and also now takes into account your relationship with the person you’re messaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XOFaLj"&gt;In other words, if you’re tweeting at a mutual who you interact with regularly, Twitter will assume “there’s a higher likelihood [you] have a better understanding of preferred tone of communication” and &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; show you a prompt. So, you can call your friend a **** or a ****-**** or even a ****-******* son of a ****-less ***** and Twitter won’t care. That’s freedom, folks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6JudW4"&gt;Twitter first started testing this system in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/5/21248201/twitter-reply-warning-harmful-language-revise-tweet-moderation"&gt;May 2020&lt;/a&gt;, paused it a little later, then brought it back to life in &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/02/22/twitter-relaunches-review-before-you-tweet-offensive-language/"&gt;February this year&lt;/a&gt;. It’s one of a number of prompts the company has been testing to try and shape user behavior, including its “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/25/21455635/twitter-read-before-you-tweet-article-prompt-rolling-out-globally-soon"&gt;read before you retweet&lt;/a&gt;” message.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/X6j91hL3Q9k25ZzPdylAwu74Xns=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22493024/pasted_image_0.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Twitter&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A sample prompt shown to a user before sending an offensive reply. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XXvRLu"&gt;Improvements to the offensive-tweets prompt will roll out to English users of the Twitter iOS app today and to Android users “in the next few days.” The company says it’s already making a difference to how people interact on the platform, though. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="itdoQE"&gt;Twitter claims internal tests show 34 percent of people who were served such a prompt “revised their initial reply or decided to not send their reply at all.” After receiving such a prompt once, people composed, on average, 11 percent “fewer offensive replies.” And people who were prompted about a reply (and therefore may have toned down their language) were themselves “less likely to receive offensive and harmful replies back.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gX0O3k"&gt;These “statistics” are as opaque as you would expect from any major internet platform (how exactly has the company quantified “less likely” in that last example? How many people are included in any of these tests? How do we know that people who revised their reply made it less offensive, or did they just use offensive language the system didn’t recognize?). But the ongoing roll-out does suggest that the feature is, at least, not making things &lt;em&gt;actively&lt;/em&gt; worse on Twitter. That’s probably the best we can hope for. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22420586/twitter-offensive-tweet-warning-prompt-updated-success-rate"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22420586/twitter-offensive-tweet-warning-prompt-updated-success-rate</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-05T13:29:56-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-05T13:29:56-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix switches from prestige pics to shredded zombies for its widest theatrical release yet</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rb6xTYn9GSxdIS6hcPMjG71lMro=/708x0:4188x2320/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69241389/Screen_Shot_2021_05_05_at_9.42.44_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HQMh8K"&gt;Netflix is taking a different route for its new Zack Snyder-directed zombie heist movie, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22300924/army-of-the-dead-trailer-zack-snyder-netflix-vegas-heist-movie"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Army of the Dead&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Rather than skip theaters and drop the new thriller directly in subscribers’ laps and homes, the company has reached an agreement with theater chains to screen the movie a week early starting May 14th in around 600 theaters, &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/film/news/zack-snyder-army-of-the-dead-netflix-theaters-1234966466/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OgCMet"&gt;That’s Netflix’s widest US release yet for one of its feature projects, and it positions the film and the company to capture summer theatergoers’ attention and dollars right as screens are beginning to reopen across the country, and newly vaccinated film fans feel comfortable enough to watch how they used to. &lt;em&gt;Variety &lt;/em&gt;says Netflix has partnered with Cinemark, Alamo Drafthouse, iPic, Landmark, Harkins, and Cinépolis theaters to make the release happen. Cinemark will reportedly screen &lt;em&gt;Army of the Dead &lt;/em&gt;in 200 of its theaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="89SlsZ"&gt;In comparison to a traditional blockbuster release that can reach thousands of theaters, 600 might seem minor, but this is Netflix, a company that’s usually scorned the traditional theatrical release model. Theaters typically want a 90-day window for theatrical releases so that people have a reason to go see a movie in person. This is why &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/3/22150605/hbo-max-warner-bros-movies-2021-simultaneous-release-matrix-godzilla-suicide-squad-space-jam"&gt;Warner Bros.’ same-day streaming and theater release strategy&lt;/a&gt; on HBO Max films stirred up so much controversy. Theaters need a reason for people to show up, especially during the pandemic when they’re at their most vulnerable. Streaming services might not feel so generous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4XT4ll"&gt;Past major Netflix releases have only chosen to screen in theaters to qualify for awards like the Golden Globes and the Academy Awards, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/7/20903107/netflix-the-irishman-martin-scorsese-belasco-theater-screening-award-eligibility"&gt;and have sometimes struggled&lt;/a&gt; to find cinemas that wanted to play ball. &lt;a href="https://www.vulture.com/2018/08/roma-movie-review-alfonso-cuaron.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roma&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;which won Best Foreign Language Film at the 91st Academy Awards, was only shown in around 250 theaters, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/11/01/business/irishman-netflix-theaters.html#:~:text=The%20film%20eventually%20played%20on,them%20in%20the%20United%20States.&amp;amp;text=%E2%80%9CThe%20Irishman%E2%80%9D%20will%20move%20on,short%20of%20a%20major%20release."&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Martin Scorsese’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/27/20887812/the-irishman-movie-review-netflix-martin-scorsese-robert-de-niro-al-pacino-joe-pesci-nyff"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Irishman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; received a limited release in eight theaters initially and hit around 550 theaters at its widest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="onE0CY"&gt;There’s only &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H83kjG5RCT8"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Army of the Dead&lt;/em&gt;’s trailer&lt;/a&gt; to go off of, but shooting for something closer to a big blockbuster summer release seems to make sense for a zombie movie. It could be fun! &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421065/zack-snyder-army-of-the-dead-netflix-theater-release"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421065/zack-snyder-army-of-the-dead-netflix-theater-release</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-05T13:27:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-05T13:27:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>New climate goals are going to need a lot more minerals</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Operations At Bald Hill Lithium Mine As Lithium Sector’s Newest Exporter Sees No Threat of an Oversupply" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xfoRIpjgbRbS7B16Wt6ClTOMduM=/4x0:3997x2662/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69241383/1015906156.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A excavator operates next to a dump truck on a mine floor at the Bald Hill lithium mine site, co-owned by Tawana Resources Ltd. and Alliance Mineral Assets Ltd., outside of Widgiemooltha, Australia, on Monday, Aug. 6, 2018.&amp;nbsp; | &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?family=editorial&amp;amp;photographer=Bloomberg" target="_blank"&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp;Contributor via Getty News&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gmlmGs"&gt;The world isn’t mining enough minerals to reach a future that runs on clean energy, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.iea.org/news/clean-energy-demand-for-critical-minerals-set-to-soar-as-the-world-pursues-net-zero-goals"&gt;new report&lt;/a&gt; by the International Energy Agency (IEA). Minerals like lithium, cobalt, and nickel are the building blocks for clean energy economies. Countries can’t meet their new climate goals without them. If supply chains can’t meet skyrocketing demand, mineral shortages could mean clean energy shortages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="Q4dFOU"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The building blocks for clean energy economies&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MzF9ND"&gt;Many of the world’s biggest economies have set goals to nearly eliminate climate pollution from fossil fuels in the next few decades. Leading climate scientists &lt;a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/sr15/chapter/spm/"&gt;have found&lt;/a&gt; that greenhouse gas emissions need to reach net zero globally by around 2050 to stave off the worst effects of climate change. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JnqE6i"&gt;Hitting that 2050 target would require six times more critical minerals than are produced today, the IEA found. For some minerals, the gap between supply and predicted future demand is way bigger. Demand for lithium, for example, is expected to grow 70 times over the next couple decades. But the supply from existing lithium mines and projects under construction can only meet about half the projected demand this decade.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1oqPDK"&gt;“This mismatch is something that worries us,” Fatih Birol, the executive director of the IEA, said at a press conference today. “Our numbers show that the critical minerals are not a sideshow in our journey to reach climate goals. It’s a part of the main event.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WDE4ll"&gt;Batteries for electric vehicles (EVs) and renewable energy storage are the biggest factor driving the potential mineral shortage. An EV requires six times more mineral resources than a car that runs on fossil fuels. Cobalt, nickel, graphite, and manganese are essential for batteries, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OJxn0q"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Existing supply chains for these minerals are already vulnerable&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lG4bW2"&gt;Wind and solar power generation are also mineral-hungry industries. Wind turbines need rare earth minerals for magnets, while solar panels are made with copper, silicon, and silver. An increase in renewable energy is also spurring the need to modernize electrical grids, which can’t be done without more copper and aluminum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FKJHa5"&gt;Existing supply chains for these minerals are already vulnerable, the IEA notes. Mining for certain minerals tends to be concentrated in a few places — sometimes in just one country. About seventy percent of the world’s cobalt came from the Democratic Republic of Congo in 2019, while some 60 percent of rare earth minerals were mined in China. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SkPING"&gt;Relying on a single source for these minerals means that the whole world could be affected by otherwise localized disasters like flooding, drought, or conflict. It can also breed human rights, labor, and environmental abuses. Major tech companies and Tesla have already faced a &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2019/dec/16/apple-and-google-named-in-us-lawsuit-over-congolese-child-cobalt-mining-deaths"&gt;lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; over children killed while mining cobalt in the DRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ldLFUM"&gt;Leaders will need to grapple with these problems as they work to transition their economies to clean energy. Designing technologies that minimize the use of these minerals could help alleviate some of the pressure on supply chains, according to the IEA. So could more recycling of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/6/20951807/electric-vehicles-battery-recycling"&gt;EV batteries&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/25/18018820/solar-panel-waste-chemicals-energy-environment-recycling"&gt;solar panels&lt;/a&gt;, and wind turbines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="j6uRCi"&gt;&lt;q&gt;investors aren’t convinced that world leaders are fully committed&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VYN6BD"&gt;Even with that kind of progress, the IEA expects a shortfall unless new mineral deposits are tapped. Production of new critical minerals isn’t ramping up fast enough because investors aren’t convinced that world leaders are fully committed to their climate goals, according to Birol. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GI8Zs5"&gt;“If they get from the governments unmistakable signals that clean energy technologies are the technologies of tomorrow, then I believe this investment will flow,” he says. Until then, limited supplies of critical minerals will loom large over any global action on climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1I8QQe"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7JtnL0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421081/critical-minerals-climate-change-goals-clean-energy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421081/critical-minerals-climate-change-goals-clean-energy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-05T13:02:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-05T13:02:52-04:00</updated>
    <title>Clubhouse is funding 50 pilot audio shows from creators</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Clubhouse App Photo Illustrations" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_3wXEjIlPw_woVRTO4MRw-1zt_o=/0x0:3543x2362/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69241242/1232148642.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Jakub Porzycki/NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FYlVtX"&gt;Clubhouse is funding the creation of &lt;a href="https://www.joinclubhouse.com/blog/meet-the-creator-first-finalists"&gt;50 audio shows&lt;/a&gt; made by creators on its platform. The concepts include everything from an interview series with Taryn Southern to a pair of shows discussing the culture of hairstyles to a game show called “Serial Killer Speed Dating.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zQyShb"&gt;Participants will each get a $5,000-per-month stipend for three months, plus gear and creative support, to help them create the series. The goal is to develop and pilot each show over the next three months. If shows take off, there’s a possibility Clubhouse will sign some of them to a longer-term deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="YnyIjy"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Clubhouse’s goal is to “support new voices” on its platform&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cvv3WL"&gt;This is the first round of creators to benefit from Clubhouse’s accelerator program, which it says will “help support new voices with tools and resources to unlock their creativity on the platform.” Clubhouse says it’s not taking any ownership of the content or shows that creators develop. “The goal is to ensure that the creators themselves enjoy complete control and ownership over their creative output,” Clubhouse says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dCRHa7"&gt;Clubhouse announced its accelerator program &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330281/clubhouse-accelerator-creators-davison-app"&gt;back in March&lt;/a&gt; ahead of the service’s first anniversary. Its popularity with the Silicon Valley venture capitalist crowd has led to a large amount of early buzz around the service that’s arguably disproportionate to its mainstream popularity. For example, as of this writing, you still need an invite to sign up for Clubhouse, and it doesn’t have an Android app. Despite this, a recent funding round &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theinformation.com%2Farticles%2Fandreessen-horowitz-values-clubhouse-at-4-billionwith-dst-tiger&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F5%2F5%2F22420644%2Fclubhouse-creator-first-pilot-program-season-audio-social" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;valued the company at $4 billion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tV3Iz8"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22362980/clubhouse-social-audio-facebook-twitter-android"&gt;Established tech firms have responded&lt;/a&gt; to Clubhouse with plans to build similar social audio features into their own services. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22391551/facebook-audio-podcasts-clubhouse-competitor-spotify-live-rooms"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22413033/twitter-spaces-android-ios-ticket-schedule-clubhouse-captions"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22356993/spotify-locker-room-clubhouse-launch-acquisition"&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/slack-wants-to-be-more-than-a-text-based-messaging-platform/"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22359332/linkedin-clubhouse-clone-social-audio-networking-room"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/31/22356682/discord-stage-channels-clubhouse-like-feature-voice"&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; have all expressed varying levels of interest in launching their own Clubhouse-style features. With competitors circling, Clubhouse’s success is likely to rely on the strength of the creators found on its platform. Initiatives like its accelerator program appear designed to help with exactly that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZkqY4g"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction May 5th, 2:02PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clubhouse’s most recent valuation is $4 billion; it was valued at $1 billion in January.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22420644/clubhouse-creator-first-pilot-program-season-audio-social"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22420644/clubhouse-creator-first-pilot-program-season-audio-social</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-05T12:36:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-05T12:36:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>Loki’s show is coming out two days earlier, in the spirit of the trickster god</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AjPkKNnxmhanu6d_OnLw4KpW29Q=/533x0:2336x1202/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69241096/Screen_Shot_2021_02_24_at_12.21.03_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Disney&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EenqOj"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loki&lt;/em&gt;, the upcoming Disney Plus show about the trickster god and brother of Thor, will be coming out slightly earlier &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299343/loki-premiere-date-disney-plus-marvel-tom-hiddleston-wandavision-black-widow"&gt;than originally planned&lt;/a&gt;: the premiere date has moved to June 9th, from the 11th. The show will also air on a new day of the week, with new episodes airing on Wednesdays instead of Fridays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y3L2MP"&gt;The announcement was made in a video uploaded to Marvel’s YouTube channel. The video starts with a typical Marvel montage, but then is interrupted by Tom Hiddleston talking about how Loki is always left out of superhero montages. (It’s understandable that he’d feel left out — even in articles about a show dedicated to the character, he’s typically described in relation to his brother.) “Wednesdays are the new Fridays,” he says, before the new date is revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jufhUL"&gt;A Disney spokesperson explained the shift as being part of the company’s ongoing experiments with release timing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="vTm9kG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Disney Plus ","description":"Subscribe to Disney Plus ","label":"Sign-Up ","url":"https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/c/482924/1061256/9358?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.disneyplus.com%2Fseries%2Floki%2F6pARMvILBGzF"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="vig0Y3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update May 5th, 2:23PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated with information from Disney.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421140/loki-disney-plus-show-new-date-wednesday"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421140/loki-disney-plus-show-new-date-wednesday</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-05T12:35:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-05T12:35:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>Trump objects to continued Facebook ban in email screed calling for ‘political price’ to be paid</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="American Conservative Union Holds Annual Conference In Florida" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ft-rtzlNV9jtjhyXn5q4tMbACgw=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69241090/1304610267.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Joe Raedle/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zgfNiw"&gt;Former President Donald Trump’s Facebook ban is sticking around for now, following the decision from Facebook’s Oversight Board to uphold its original ban from earlier this year. And Trump is not pleased, according to his first official statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qLpams"&gt;“Free speech has been taken away from the President of the United States,” an emailed statement from Trump &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MikeIsaac/status/1389962790467620866"&gt;obtained by &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; reads&lt;/a&gt;, calling for a “political price” to be paid not just by Facebook, but by Google and Twitter as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="TEn1qw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Facebook’s Trump ban can stay in place, says Oversight Board","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22320329/facebook-oversight-board-trump-ban-decision"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="5FMU3n"&gt;Facebook’s Oversight Board is a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/6/21249427/facebook-oversight-board-nobel-peace-prize-instagram-snowden"&gt;panel of independent experts&lt;/a&gt; established to oversee high-stakes moderation and policy disputes on the social media platform.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;In its decision, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22320329/facebook-oversight-board-trump-ban-decision"&gt;the Oversight Board explained&lt;/a&gt; that while Facebook’s initial decision to suspend Trump’s account following the Capitol Riot was valid, the company’s institution of an indefinite suspension was not. Instead, the Board asked that Facebook “apply and justify a defined penalty” — whether that be permanently banning the former president or instilling a set amount of time before Trump is allowed back. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="oAvSb2"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Trump statement, over email (not his new blog) via &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/maggieNYT?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@maggieNYT&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/mA3MVDCt9Y"&gt;pic.twitter.com/mA3MVDCt9Y&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— rat king (@MikeIsaac) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MikeIsaac/status/1389962790467620866?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 5, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AbRBW8"&gt;Notably, Facebook’s Oversight Board chose to punt the decision over whether Trump should be permanently banned, instead choosing to pass the final call back to Facebook. Per that decision, Facebook will be taking the next six months to “determine and justify a proportionate response that is consistent with the rules that are applied to other users of its platform,” meaning that the former president’s fate on the platform is still up in the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DGj9SY"&gt;Trump’s statement doesn’t actually comment specifically on Facebook’s Oversight Board decision or advocate for Facebook to make any direct changes as it looks to create more concrete rules for how to handle both Trump’s ban and future incidents. Instead, Trump sticks to his typical inflammatory rhetoric and insults, rather than addressing specific policy concerns with the ongoing review process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="NT3UnX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Donald Trump’s ‘social media platform’ has launched and it’s just a blog","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419850/donald-trump-social-media-platform-ban-twitter-facebook"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Dy2euQ"&gt;Having access to Facebook is more than just a place for Trump to post content on social media. &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/trump-facebook-reinstate-2024-bid-c9e51b54-7b35-4751-b620-0ceccd0979f8.html?utm_campaign=organic&amp;amp;utm_medium=socialshare&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;Axios&lt;/em&gt; notes&lt;/a&gt;, Facebook is a huge part of Trump’s political strategy and future, giving the former president and his team the ability to specifically target supporters with ad campaigns, in addition to serving as one of the biggest sources of Trump’s grassroots fundraising efforts. And a return to Facebook could be a major factor in whether Trump decides to run for office again in 2024. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XAfMcK"&gt;In lieu of access to Facebook, Twitter, and other major social media platforms, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419850/donald-trump-social-media-platform-ban-twitter-facebook"&gt;Trump has started a new, short-form blog&lt;/a&gt; that mimics the format (if not the broad reach) of his former Facebook and Twitter accounts. And while Trump is free to post to the internet, it’ll ultimately be Facebook’s decision whether to hand him back the platform that he last used to help incite the Capital riot in the first place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QR65Fg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8vOd8h"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421052/trump-facebook-ban-email-statement-objection-social-media"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421052/trump-facebook-ban-email-statement-objection-social-media</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
