<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-06-02T11:14:05-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T11:14:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T11:14:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>Donald Trump has shut down his blog</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Celebrity Sightings In New York City - May 18, 2021" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KaYI5CnWgvHcswUppm6f6yFElx8=/0x196:4729x3349/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69377268/1318749429.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by James Devaney/GC Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IYyiLS"&gt;Former President Donald Trump’s blogging days are officially over. On Wednesday, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/06/02/trump-blog-page-shuts-down-for-good.html"&gt;CNBC&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; that Trump’s blog has shut down less than a month after its launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ee4l9r"&gt;The blog, “From the Desk of Donald J. Trump,” launched May 4th as a substitute messaging platform for the former president after he was banned from Facebook and Twitter earlier this year. But as of Wednesday, the blog had been completely removed from Trump’s website. Jason Miller, senior aide to Trump, confirmed to CNBC&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Wednesday that the site “will not be returning.” The old blog posts are now archived as press releases in a separate section of the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="puBaBy"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The site ‘will not be returning’&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GP9Sym"&gt;Trump was banned from Facebook and Twitter in January after a deadly right-wing riot broke out at the US Capitol as lawmakers were set to vote to certify Joe Biden as president. Shortly after the ban, Trump announced that he would be launching his own competing social media platform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nDVIHB"&gt;When the blog launched last month, Miller tweeted that the “website is a great resource to find” Trump’s latest statements, but that it wasn’t his long-promised “social media platform.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d1l1r9"&gt;“We’ll have information coming on that front in the near future,” Miller said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9iSuJT"&gt;As of Wednesday, Trump’s office had no new details related to the platform. Last month, &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/trump-considers-contenders-to-be-his-new-social-media-outlet-after-big-tech-crackdown-11621013567"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal &lt;/em&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; that Trump has engaged in talks with platforms like CloutHub and FreeSpace to become his new favored messaging platform. The &lt;em&gt;Journal &lt;/em&gt;said that Trump isn’t looking for equity in the new company, but what could be a licensing fee if he decides to join.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DbLPmc"&gt;Much of Trump’s success can be attributed to his social media following. But his blog struggled to find the audience his Twitter feed did. Last month, &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/trumps-blog-isnt-lighting-internet-rcna890"&gt;&lt;em&gt;NBC News &lt;/em&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; that the blog gained only 212,000 total engagements, a much lower engagement rate than the former president’s tweets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WTbcJJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l8WhEG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22464930/donald-trump-blog-facebook-twitter-social-media-platform"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22464930/donald-trump-blog-facebook-twitter-social-media-platform</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T10:53:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T10:53:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>Huawei teases its upcoming P50 flagship phone</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Huawei P50" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wwJ9hdrUkEV_R4Nm77RuwLEJxBs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69377115/huaweip50.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Behold, the P50’s mammoth-sized camera array&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lXhnzs"&gt;During &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22227756"&gt;Huawei’s HarmonyOS&lt;/a&gt; livestream, the company provided a first look at its upcoming P50 series phone. Few specs were given, and it didn’t talk pricing or tease a release date, but the sizzle reel did reveal a close-up look at its interesting camera array. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZPYJGs"&gt;Four camera lenses are visible, along with two flashes. It’s tough to say exactly what we’ll be getting with this phone in terms of megapixel count and sensor size; the photo below confirms that Huawei is working alongside Leica with its optics. We’ll have to wait to see if Huawei improved on its periscope telephoto lenses that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/18/21444946/huawei-p40-pro-plus-vs-iphone-pixel-10x-zoom-camera"&gt;my colleague Sam Byford saw great results with on the P40 Pro Plus&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Huawei P50" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/z2YxM8rkri-ytMpf8ftE2x6ax28=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22554597/huaweip50lens.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The teaser hinted at Huawei’s continued camera partnership with Leica.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="eDsTGF"&gt;The company claims it will “lift mobile photography to a new level.” Given that the size of the camera bump seems to have increased compared to the P40 Pro Plus (which we deemed “the smartphone zoom king”) it seems reasonable that Huawei might have crammed some even larger sensors and lenses in the P50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zmz3VF"&gt;You can see the tease time-stamped in the YouTube video below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="04bL1K"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/y2101ics8jc?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=7039&amp;amp;start=7039" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9UadeN"&gt;As for the rest of the phone, all we have to go on so far is what Huawei executive Richard Yu said during the livestream: that it will have a “lightweight design” and an “iconic” design language. The P50 will likely ship with Huawei’s new HarmonyOS operating system built in, but it didn’t confirm it in video (or even show the display powered on, for that matter). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yvZbXc"&gt;As for when it might release, the company said that it is “trying to figure out how to make this great product available to you.” That reads to me as Huawei — like all tech companies right now — dealing with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/2/22363232/global-semiconductor-chip-shortage-pandemic-consoles-cpus-graphics-cards-cars"&gt;impacts of a global semiconductor shortage&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/9/21360598/huawei-chips-us-sanctions-trump-china-privacy-smartphone"&gt;US sanctions placed on the company have slowed its production of in-house parts&lt;/a&gt;, which might also be causing supply strains around its Kirin processors. To that end, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22463666/huawei-matepad-pro-harmonyos-tablet-features-specs"&gt;the MatePad Pro tablet&lt;/a&gt; it announced today has a Qualcomm Snapdragon processor instead of one of Huawei’s own processors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="rd3ZaI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Huawei’s Watch 3 is its first HarmonyOS watch","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22463529/huawei-watch-3-pro-harmonyos-smartwatch-features-specs"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22464776/huawei-p50-phone-camera-periscope-telephoto-leica-harmonyos"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22464776/huawei-p50-phone-camera-periscope-telephoto-leica-harmonyos</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T10:42:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T10:42:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>Huawei announces HarmonyOS update for its smartphones</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bpl6v5xN7q1wNLOHD-XmJNtn_gM=/90x0:1038x632/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69377091/u970l2SYwX.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Huawei&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="96iVZo"&gt;Huawei has announced that its HarmonyOS operating system is coming to its smartphones via a forthcoming update. &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/y2101ics8jc?t=6792"&gt;Huawei’s consumer business CEO Richard Yu says&lt;/a&gt; the company is updating around 100 of its devices globally to the new operating system, which also includes tablets like the MatePad Pro. In theory, it’s a big change from its previous phones, which have run the open-source version of Android with Huawei’s own services replacing the Google software it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/19/18631558/google-huawei-android-suspension"&gt;been unable to include&lt;/a&gt; on new devices as a result of US sanctions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0YFibo"&gt;HarmonyOS will initially come to recent flagships like the Mate 40, P40, and Mate 30 series, before releasing on more devices later in the year. Older phones like the Mate 9, Mate 10, P20, and P10 will receive the update in the first half of next year, the company says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZLvmRm"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The update is coming to recent flagships as well as older models&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7h0hNo"&gt;The company advertises that HarmonyOS allows its phones to offer more seamless connectivity across different devices, including easier pairing with compatible headphones and speakers via a drag-and-drop interface. There’s also improved support for homescreen widgets, Huawei says, which have a similar look to what we saw with Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21451018/ios-ipados-14-review-iphone-ipad-features-widgets-app-library-scribble"&gt;iOS 14 last year&lt;/a&gt;. The operating system is also said to be better at returning to previously opened apps without losing your place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kXFO41"&gt;The Chinese tech giant first announced HarmonyOS &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/9/20798251/huawei-harmonyos-hongmengos-smartphones-internet-of-things-operating-system-android"&gt;in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, and the first device announced with the operating system was the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/10/20798260/huawei-honor-smart-tv-vision-pro-harmonyos-china"&gt;Vision TV&lt;/a&gt; from its then-sub brand Honor (it later &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/16/21570744/huawei-honor-sale-announced-us-sanctions"&gt;sold off the brand&lt;/a&gt; due to the pressures created by ongoing US sanctions). However, at last year’s Huawei developer conference, its consumer business CEO Richard Yu hinted that the operating system &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/10/21430275/huawei-harmonyos-smartphones-release-date"&gt;could appear on smartphones in 2021&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hlzd7a"&gt;Despite being marketed as a brand-new operating system, reports have suggested that HarmonyOS shares a lot of code with the open-source version of Android that it’s replacing. Earlier this year, &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/02/harmonyos-hands-on-huaweis-android-killer-is-just-android/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ars Technica &lt;/em&gt;did a deep dive into HarmonyOS&lt;/a&gt;, and reported that it “is essentially an Android fork.” Huawei did not respond to our requests for comment on the report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4LaOS1"&gt;As well as phones, Huawei has also announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22227707"&gt;new MatePad tablets running HarmonyOS&lt;/a&gt;, as well as the new HarmonyOS-powered &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22227570"&gt;Huawei Watch 3 smartwatch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22463715/huawei-harmonyos-smartphone-mate-40-30-20-p40-p30-device-updates"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22463715/huawei-harmonyos-smartphone-mate-40-30-20-p40-p30-device-updates</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T10:23:37-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T10:23:37-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nintendo’s E3 event will be ‘focused exclusively’ on Switch games</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jEVC3jIoNUtYaAcogdVZCT-sk4A=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69376995/jbareham_1492_170228_0173.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DEHJHo"&gt;Nintendo is holding an E3 event on June 15th, and the company promises it will be “focused exclusively on Nintendo Switch games mainly releasing in 2021.” The Nintendo Direct presentation will begin at 9AM PT / 12PM ET on June 15th, and Nintendo will hold three hours of gameplay deep dives once the event has concluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IfhNu9"&gt;Nintendo’s wording suggests we won’t be seeing any hardware announcements at the company’s E3 show. A “Switch Pro” has been rumored for months, with recent reports suggesting it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/27/22456160/new-nintendo-switch-release-date-september-e3-announcement"&gt;may be announced ahead of E3&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cRbH4-P0zAvsylqnolbCXbVKay4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22554599/NOA_Lead.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nintendo’s E3 event starts at 9AM PT / 12PM ET on June 15th.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="eU8x2r"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;has previously reported that this new Switch model will use &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/23/22346041/oled-nintendo-switch-dlss-nvidia-chip-report"&gt;more powerful silicon from Nvidia&lt;/a&gt; that supports DLSS (Deep Learning Super Sampling). The updated Switch is also said to support 4K output when connected to a TV and reportedly includes a seven-inch OLED display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y6CuMm"&gt;If a new Switch is imminent, Nintendo’s E3 show would be the perfect opportunity to show how games run at 4K and to demonstrate the power of Nvidia’s latest chip and DLSS support. As E3 kicks off in virtual form on June 12th, there are only 10 days left to see if Nintendo is ready to announce an updated Switch ahead of E3.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22464828/nintendo-e3-event-june-15th-software-exclusive"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22464828/nintendo-e3-event-june-15th-software-exclusive</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T10:03:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T10:03:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>This scientist shoots trees to study how they migrate</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KvfXikZzFrayfhGf0IUxW6EJmAk=/15x0:2040x1350/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69376928/Container.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="AZ7xjG"&gt;In Black Rock Forest, just north of New York City, Angie Patterson aims a shotgun at a northern red oak tree. Patterson is a plant ecophysiologist, and the leaves that she’s shooting out of the canopy will give her data to understand how and why trees migrate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZRzD23"&gt;Trees have been on the move since at least the last ice age. As their native habitats become inhospitable, tree ranges shift, slowly, to areas they can thrive. But climate change is disrupting the process, scientists say. As of 2019, the &lt;a href="http://www.fao.org/state-of-forests/en/"&gt;IUCN Red List categorized&lt;/a&gt; more than 20,000 tree species as threatened, and upward of 1,400 as critically endangered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l68bsI"&gt;As scientists scramble to learn more about what drives tree migration, others are planning for the future. To preserve biodiversity, both citizens and researchers are employing interventionist tactics once steeped in controversy like “assisted migration” — taking tree seedlings and planting them in new locations. Rising global temperatures may force wildlife agencies and forest managers to decide what to save and what to leave behind. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ri6H9E"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt; video team trekked into the woods with “the shotgun scientist” to learn how and why trees move to new locations. Can we do anything to help the trees? And what tough calls will we have to make if we can’t? Watch our latest video to see what we discovered. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22457294/tree-migration-climate-change-scientist"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22457294/tree-migration-climate-change-scientist</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jeanette Moreland</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Spotify wants to make the yearly Wrapped experience more than a once a year thing</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/25-dFJRDefOwTztI67HJKBUx6YI=/0x0:1920x1280/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69376909/spotifyonlyyou.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Spotify’s Only You feature will visualize listeners’ data. | Spotify&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="frnxic"&gt;Spotify loves when people share its annual Wrapped music breakdown on social media, so it’s making that more of a year-round treat. The company &lt;a href="https://newsroom.spotify.com/2021-06-02/celebrate-your-unique-listening-style-with-spotifys-only-you-in-app-experience"&gt;is announcing&lt;/a&gt; a new digital experience today called Only You, which will give users personalized playlists in a shareable form. The in-app experience will give users a variety of playlists and data insights based on their music listening habits, and a new feature called Blend will let two friends automatically merge their musical tastes into a playlist. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RhbGzb"&gt;Among the new experience highlights is “Your Dream Dinner Party,” which lets users pick three artists they’d invite to a dinner party with Spotify making a mix for each artist. Another is “Your Artist Pairs,” which highlights unique pairings that show off a listener’s musical range, as well as “Your Audio Birth Chart,’ which gives users their “Sun artist,” or the person they listened to the most over the past six months; their “Moon artist,” which is the artist they listen to that shows off their emotional side; and their “Rising artist,” which is one they’ve recently found. The Audio Birth Chart and Dream Dinner Party will update daily, while the other data visualization aspects of the feature, like Your Artist Pairs, is based on a limited set of time and won’t update regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b3hgEanZoTkZ6N6VSWMoEUFO_xY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22554497/Spotify_OnlyYou_InApp_05_DinnerParty.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Spotify&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spotify’s Your Dream Dinner Party feature lets people pick the artists they’d want at a dinner party and receive playlists in return.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7FOKLV"&gt;None of these features are revolutionary, but people seemingly love seeing visualized data on their listening habits. During Wrapped season last year, when Spotify gives users a year-in-review look at their listening data, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-12-02/spotify-technology-soars-to-record-amid-2020wrapped-buzz?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;its stock jumped&lt;/a&gt; 16 percent and the app rose rapidly in the App Store rankings. Clearly, the company is trying to replicate that success and build buzz with another data visualization offering. The idea is, of course, that if you want access to these unique features, you’ll have to sign up and listen on Spotify to do so. Peer pressure works wonders.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22464677/spotify-only-you-share-data-playlist-birth-chart"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22464677/spotify-only-you-share-data-playlist-birth-chart</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T09:23:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T09:23:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>Invasive snails on the run leave behind DNA evidence </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Mark Abramson, of Heal the Bay, displays a New Zealand mud snail on the tip of his little finger at" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OS-eEs3Onbkx7urVyQZyx85FmkA=/53x0:1948x1263/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69376714/566073327.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Mark Abramson, of Heal the Bay, displays a New Zealand mud snail on the tip of his little finger at in Medea Creek at Natural Park in Oak Park on Friday March 3 2010. | Photo by Brian Vander Brug/Los Angeles Times via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZMfTv8"&gt;DNA sleuthing helped scientists spot early outcrops of a spreading snail invasion in Pennsylvania. The method could be used to spot the unwanted critters before they cause serious damage. That way, conservationists can stop them from conquering even more places. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DGF6zJ"&gt;New Zealand mud snails became a global pest in part because they can reproduce asexually — just one snail in a new area can essentially clone itself until there are 500,000 snails in a single square yard. They’re about the&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;length of a pencil eraser so they’re hard to find until there are so many in a location that it’s nearly impossible to stop their spread. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZI03nk"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It opens the door for us to be able to use this technology to detect the snail at a much wider scale”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FIS3oK"&gt;“It’s kind of weird because as an invasive ecologist, I never really want to find this thing,” says Edward Levri, a Pennsylvania State University-Altoona professor and senior author of a new &lt;a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10530-021-02576-7"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; published this week in the journal &lt;em&gt;Biological Invasions&lt;/em&gt;. “It’s sort of an exciting feeling, it opens the door for us to be able to use this technology to detect the snail at a much wider scale.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZmxOug"&gt;Levri and his colleagues successfully used DNA present in the environment (something researchers call environmental DNA or eDNA) to track down the tiny snails. But over the past decade, Levri has spent a lot of time looking for the tiny rascals by turning over rocks and casting nets. “It is an arduous process, and there’s very limited success,” he tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6FRVYp"&gt;So this time, he worked with the lead study author James Woodell to collect water samples from eight different locations across Pennsylvania and scour them for the snails’ DNA. Just like humans slough off skin cells in the shower, snails shed DNA in the water. The researchers used a technique called a polymerase chain reaction, or PCR, to amplify small amounts of snail DNA found in water samples. They use a dye to make the DNA glow so that it can be spotted with a special machine. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Biologists led by the University of Iowa used a special technique called eDNA to discover an invasive species of tiny snails in streams in central Pennsylvania where the snails’ presence had been unknown. The invasive New Zealand mud snail has spread to the Eastern Seaboard after arriving in the western United States decades ago." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dk0m2P1LU1lVIUTm2fHv3nZnz8Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22554398/265895_web.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Edward Levri&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Biologists led by the University of Iowa used a special technique called eDNA to discover an invasive species of tiny snails in streams in central Pennsylvania where the snails’ presence had been unknown. The invasive New Zealand mud snail has spread to the Eastern Seaboard after arriving in the western United States decades ago.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="okxCKo"&gt;They ultimately found eDNA from the mud snails in five of the eight locations they sampled. Levri has since been able to go back and find an actual New Zealand mud snail at one of those locations. He hasn’t yet found the snails at the other locations — he hasn’t been able to be out in the field as much as he’d like because of the pandemic. While there’s a possibility that some of the eDNA drifted there from other locations, Levri and co-authors hope the state will consider the eDNA findings as enough evidence to take action. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jY1grc"&gt;“From the conservation perspective, that’s enough to say, ‘Hey, we should really be more careful with these sites,” says Maurine Neiman, an associate professor of biology at the University of Iowa and another one of the authors of the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m3NlG9"&gt;The snails are small enough to hitch a ride on fishing gear unnoticed, which is one way they’ve been able to spread across the US and other parts of the world (they can also tag along on boats). The state could put signs up to warn people who fish at these locations to take extra precautions, like cleaning their waders with certain &lt;a href="https://www.fws.gov/columbiariver/ANS/factsheets/mudsnail.pdf"&gt;disinfectants&lt;/a&gt; before they visit a new fishing location&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;(sticking them in the freezer overnight accomplishes the same thing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="1kPbFr"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“These snails are tiny, but they seem to have the potential to pack a really big ecological punch”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lYv0Ib"&gt;The New Zealand mud snail was first found in Pennsylvania in 2013 at Spring Creek, and now there are “millions” there, according to Levri. That’s bad news for the area’s fish and the people who like to catch them. The snails are difficult to digest and have been known to come out the other end of a fish alive after being eaten. Since they’re a poor source of nutrition, studies have shown that fish that eat them lose weight. The snails also crowd out native snails and aquatic insects. In some cases, the invasive snails make up 90 percent of the invertebrate biomass in a location. That’s “amazing for just one species to do,” says Levri. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mIo4qR"&gt;“These snails are tiny, but they seem to have the potential to pack a really big ecological punch to these invaded ecosystems,” Neiman says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SLjcKf"&gt;eDNA could help researchers find the snails a year or more sooner than they otherwise might have. That gives conservationists crucial time to stop the snails before people unwittingly give them a ride to other, snail-free locales. Conservationists haven’t been very successful in getting rid of the snails once they’ve shown up, Levri says, so that’s all the more reason to stop their spread in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3Atkk7"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8ZdvQS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22463725/dna-invasive-species-snails-pennsylvania"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22463725/dna-invasive-species-snails-pennsylvania</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Valorant is the latest big shooter to get a mobile spinoff</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bnLd5oQGKxa5xug793iWlvXfLPc=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69376560/VALORANT_Viper.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FMQuLZ"&gt;Riot is bringing its tactical shooter &lt;em&gt;Valorant&lt;/em&gt; to mobile devices. There aren’t a lot of details yet — such as when it will launch, on what hardware, or how it will differ from the main game — but Riot says the new version will simply be called &lt;em&gt;Valorant Mobile&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y4jtMu"&gt;The developer claims that the PC version of the game, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/5/21280796/valorant-riot-games-launch-overwatch-league-blizzard-esports-competitive-gaming"&gt;which launched last year&lt;/a&gt;, currently averages 14 million monthly players. Valorant is also coming off of its biggest competitive tournament to date, with an event in Iceland, and Riot says that more than 1 million concurrent viewers tuned in to the finals on May 31st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lFUxas"&gt;The news shouldn’t be too surprising. Earlier this year, Riot made a similar move with &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358213/league-of-legends-wild-rift-iphone-android-preview"&gt;launching a mobile-focused spinoff called &lt;em&gt;Wild Rift&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Meanwhile, some of the most popular shooters in the world have moved to smartphones as well; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/25/22350782/pubg-mobile-one-billion-downloads-tencent"&gt;&lt;em&gt;PUBG Mobile&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/9/20906035/call-of-duty-download-number-biggest-launch-ever"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Call of Duty Mobile&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are both huge hits, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22391634/apex-legends-mobile-beta"&gt;a smartphone iteration of &lt;em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is also on the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wN2tWT"&gt;It also sounds like Riot is looking to build out &lt;em&gt;Valorant&lt;/em&gt; in other ways. Without getting into details, aside from the mobile version, the developer says that it is “preparing to expand the franchise in order to bring &lt;em&gt;Valorant&lt;/em&gt; to more players around the world.” Again, this would be following the &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; playbook, which currently has expanded into everything from comic books to digital card games to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22417254/league-of-legends-animated-series-arcane-netflix"&gt;an upcoming animated series on Netflix&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22458279/valorant-mobile-spinoff-riot-games"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22458279/valorant-mobile-spinoff-riot-games</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>No Man’s Sky is getting a ‘visual overhaul’ and flying pets</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uDZtxoeEMSc-F4xf7dSxyDkmX8U=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69376568/No_Mans_Sky_Prisms_Screen_2.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="S0eFcw"&gt;&lt;em&gt;No Man’s Sky&lt;/em&gt; is getting yet another big update, this time focused on the way the sci-fi adventure looks. The update is called “Prisms,” and developer Hello Games describes it as “a visual overhaul” of the game. It’s available starting today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="CS8p2c"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:579707"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1wG6bI"&gt;The changes include new weather effects, volumetric lighting, furry aliens, skies full of stars, and more. The studio also says that PC and next-gen versions of the game will get “detailed reflections, improved lighting quality, more detailed biomes, and more.” You can get a good rundown in the trailer above. As part of the update, &lt;em&gt;No Man’s Sky&lt;/em&gt; is also getting a very cool new feature: flying pets that you can ride. These include giant beetles, flying worms, and huge butterflies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qg5Jcv"&gt;As always, the update is available for free. Thanks to a steady stream of expansions, &lt;em&gt;No Man’s Sky&lt;/em&gt; is a vastly different game today compared to when it launched in 2016. This year alone has seen added features like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22285801/no-mans-sky-companions-pets-update-hello-games"&gt;alien pets&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/31/22358926/no-mans-sky-expeditions-update-hello-games"&gt;a new quest structure&lt;/a&gt;, and even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22446499/no-mans-sky-mass-effect-normandy-starship"&gt;the Normandy starship from &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22463668/no-mans-sky-prism-update-graphic-overhaul-flying-pets"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22463668/no-mans-sky-prism-update-graphic-overhaul-flying-pets</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-02T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-02T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>I broke off a tiny piece of the world with a self-flying drone</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DXME7X7sOEMN5KMOK5u4oBHxpl0=/0x0:1766x1177/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69376551/skydio_3d_model.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4vAmLZ"&gt;With photogrammetry, hundreds of still photos can be transformed into an incredibly realistic 3D model of a real place on Earth — assuming you capture them all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vJh1u8"&gt;This Memorial Day weekend, a self-flying robot cameraman did that entire job for me. I simply designated where to fly and where not to fly, kicked back in a chair, and a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/11/21009994/skydio-2-review-self-flying-autonomous-drone-camera-crash-proof-price"&gt;Skydio 2 drone&lt;/a&gt; nabbed those photos all by itself. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WyFqoqbLayUf2YkyctAyMB92Ifw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22554185/skydio_scan_test_448.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="IQIi7G"&gt;Today, Skydio is launching &lt;a href="https://www.skydio.com/3d-scan"&gt;Skydio 3D Scan&lt;/a&gt;, an optional software suite for its self-flying drones that lets them build incredibly detailed models for &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; more important tasks than my holiday backyard BBQ. We’re talking about scanning bridges that might be in need of structural repair, accident reporting at crash sites, and allowing clients to inspect construction sites from most any angle, anywhere in the world, during and after structures are built. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EEN172"&gt;Those aren’t theoretical, by the way: Skydio says the North Carolina Department of Transportation &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/6/21505064/faa-visual-line-of-sight-skydio-2-waiver-ncdot-chula-vista"&gt;is using it for bridges&lt;/a&gt;; the Boston Police Department for crime and accident scene reconstruction; and, below, you can see an real-life interactive 3D example of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Tcv16-lLsA4"&gt;a water treatment plant for an upcoming semiconductor facility&lt;/a&gt; being built in Chandler, Arizona by Sundt Construction, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/23/22347250/intel-new-factories-arizona-20-billion-chips-outsourcing-foundry-services-manufacturing"&gt;presumably for Intel&lt;/a&gt;. (Skydio says it doesn’t know for sure.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="cIxHif"&gt;
&lt;div class="sketchfab-embed-wrapper"&gt; &lt;iframe title="OC WATR" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="true" webkitallowfullscreen="true" allow="fullscreen; autoplay; vr" xr-spatial-tracking="" execution-while-out-of-viewport="" execution-while-not-rendered="" web-share="" width="640" height="480" src="https://sketchfab.com/models/d09e905ce2104465a2364d1e27bf3b8e/embed"&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;p style="font-size: 13px; font-weight: normal; margin: 5px; color: #4A4A4A;"&gt; &lt;a href="https://sketchfab.com/3d-models/oc-watr-d09e905ce2104465a2364d1e27bf3b8e?utm_medium=embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=share-popup&amp;amp;utm_content=d09e905ce2104465a2364d1e27bf3b8e" target="_blank" style="font-weight: bold; color: #1CAAD9;"&gt; OC WATR &lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://sketchfab.com/skydio?utm_medium=embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=share-popup&amp;amp;utm_content=d09e905ce2104465a2364d1e27bf3b8e" target="_blank" style="font-weight: bold; color: #1CAAD9;"&gt; Skydio &lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://sketchfab.com?utm_medium=embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=share-popup&amp;amp;utm_content=d09e905ce2104465a2364d1e27bf3b8e" target="_blank" style="font-weight: bold; color: #1CAAD9;"&gt;Sketchfab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YiH4MC"&gt;As you can imagine with that kind of clientele, the feature doesn’t come cheap: $2,999 per year, per drone, for the ability to autonomously grab all those photos given a designated volume that you’d like to capture. That also doesn’t include the drone, a controller, or the software you’ll need to actually stitch the images together: $99+ a month for DroneDeploy, or &lt;a href="https://www.virtuosity.com/product/reality-modeling-worksuite/"&gt;several thousand dollars per year&lt;/a&gt; for Bentley Systems’ ContextCapture, as a couple examples — the embedded Sketchfab models in this post use Bentley’s solution. 3D Scan will come to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22418785/skydio-enterprise-drones-x2-x2e-x2d-prices-specs"&gt;the company’s $10,999-and-up Skydio X2 drone&lt;/a&gt; later this summer as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lfDoK7"&gt;&lt;div class="sketchfab-embed-wrapper"&gt; &lt;iframe title="Mock Helicopter Crash Scene" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="true" webkitallowfullscreen="true" allow="fullscreen; autoplay; vr" xr-spatial-tracking="" execution-while-out-of-viewport="" execution-while-not-rendered="" web-share="" width="640" height="480" src="https://sketchfab.com/models/a9691d3134f04b63bfe57159965d22eb/embed"&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;p style="font-size: 13px; font-weight: normal; margin: 5px; color: #4A4A4A;"&gt; &lt;a href="https://sketchfab.com/3d-models/mock-helicopter-crash-scene-a9691d3134f04b63bfe57159965d22eb?utm_medium=embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=share-popup&amp;amp;utm_content=a9691d3134f04b63bfe57159965d22eb" target="_blank" style="font-weight: bold; color: #1CAAD9;"&gt; Mock Helicopter Crash Scene &lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://sketchfab.com/skydio?utm_medium=embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=share-popup&amp;amp;utm_content=a9691d3134f04b63bfe57159965d22eb" target="_blank" style="font-weight: bold; color: #1CAAD9;"&gt; Skydio &lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://sketchfab.com?utm_medium=embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=share-popup&amp;amp;utm_content=a9691d3134f04b63bfe57159965d22eb" target="_blank" style="font-weight: bold; color: #1CAAD9;"&gt;Sketchfab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="L799Un"&gt;Though it’s aimed at professionals with money to spend, a few short sessions showed me you don’t need to &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; a pro to use 3D Scan, or necessarily even know how to fly a drone. Assuming you’re following all local drone laws, it’s simply a matter of powering up a standard Skydio 2 drone (with two high-capacity microSD cards) and a Skydio controller, then following a series of prompts on a phone. You fly the drone to the top, bottom, and corners of the area you’d like to capture, pick how much detail you want, and then it does the rest on its own — taking pictures with its 12-megapixel front camera while the drone’s other six eyes and navigation system keep it from crashing. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Eb9eJgWR_KeONwxdlpXAIi9GGa4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22554227/skydio_scan_sean_002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The larger and more detailed your scan, the longer it’ll take, but you can resume after a battery swap — Skydio recommends you don’t stay out longer than four batteries.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="9Ystn1"&gt;Like I wrote &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/11/21009994/skydio-2-review-self-flying-autonomous-drone-camera-crash-proof-price"&gt;in our Skydio 2 review&lt;/a&gt;, you can trust this drone not to crash, and the 3D Scan mode adds a geofencing feature that can help you keep it from flying into unwanted areas, too. Frankly, I didn’t feel a pressing need to hang onto the controller during my backyard patio scan, so I left it on a table while I watched. The only thing that confused me was knowing when the scan was done: it turns out you have to land the drone, then leave it powered on to finish processing. Then, it was a matter of uploading a couple gigabytes of photos to DroneDeploy or Bentley and waiting for them to process.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ajXHGtLzvmNORuTP9pJ8bGoNGlU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22554226/skydio_scan_sean_004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s an AR mode where you can keep track of a virtual Skydio drone as it makes its rounds.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="PKam8Y"&gt;As you’ll no doubt see in the 3D models (or failing that, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Tcv16-lLsA4"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;), they’re not quite seamless yet — not something you’d want to explore in virtual reality, for instance. (I tried.) Even though I can make out the exact texture of the cement slab and tiles in my backyard, and &lt;a href="https://sketchfab.com/3d-models/mock-helicopter-crash-scene-a9691d3134f04b63bfe57159965d22eb"&gt;the metal carnage in this Swiss cheese of a busted helicopter&lt;/a&gt;, here are loads of holes and smudges that photogrammetry is just failing to provide. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wxfNFR"&gt;Skydio CEO and co-founder Adam Bry admits that 3D isn’t everything, and that some clients will simply use 3D as a guide to all of the individual high-res photos that Skydio also provides. “If you set the closest resolution, you’re talking about something like .5mm per pixel ... it’s enough to see fine cracks in concrete, it’s enough to see rust on a bolt, it’s enough to see details of a skid mark on the ground.” And while he says the system works in indoor environments, it’s currently optimized for flying &lt;em&gt;around &lt;/em&gt;an object you’d like to capture instead of capturing the world around the drone, like you might for an indoor tour. (Skydio is “fairly active” in pursuing inside-out capture as well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="620Uwh"&gt;&lt;div class="sketchfab-embed-wrapper"&gt; &lt;iframe title="Back" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="true" webkitallowfullscreen="true" allow="fullscreen; autoplay; vr" xr-spatial-tracking="" execution-while-out-of-viewport="" execution-while-not-rendered="" web-share="" width="640" height="480" src="https://sketchfab.com/models/8b1c874249374d67b0cdc55fe53031f4/embed"&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;p style="font-size: 13px; font-weight: normal; margin: 5px; color: #4A4A4A;"&gt; &lt;a href="https://sketchfab.com/3d-models/back-8b1c874249374d67b0cdc55fe53031f4?utm_medium=embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=share-popup&amp;amp;utm_content=8b1c874249374d67b0cdc55fe53031f4" target="_blank" style="font-weight: bold; color: #1CAAD9;"&gt; Back &lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://sketchfab.com/skydio?utm_medium=embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=share-popup&amp;amp;utm_content=8b1c874249374d67b0cdc55fe53031f4" target="_blank" style="font-weight: bold; color: #1CAAD9;"&gt; Skydio &lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://sketchfab.com?utm_medium=embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=share-popup&amp;amp;utm_content=8b1c874249374d67b0cdc55fe53031f4" target="_blank" style="font-weight: bold; color: #1CAAD9;"&gt;Sketchfab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XMnz5d"&gt;Long term, Bry thinks the automated aerial scanning might come in handy for digitizing the world for other reasons, like augmented and virtual reality, but for now it seemed like simple, detailed 3D structure modeling was a problem Skydio could solve. “There are countless examples of the world’s best drone pilots keeping this mental model of the path they’ve flown,” says Bry. Now, scanning may not need to be about flying, or even programming a path on a map. It’s just another app on your phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m0HcZ1"&gt;Skydio’s holding a special live webinar at the US Space and Rocket Center today at 9AM PT / 12PM ET to show a bit more of what 3D Scan can do. They’ll be scanning some exhibits inside the center, Bry tells me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vtjVC8"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Skydio 2 drone review: beginner vs. intermediate vs. expert|74224" data-volume-uuid="bd7023482" data-volume-id="74224" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-836" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vNZsUl"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BSOhxt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LCUR2u"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gzMF0x"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22464280/skydio-2-x2-3d-scan-photogrammetry"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22464280/skydio-2-x2-3d-scan-photogrammetry</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
