<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-11-15T15:08:22-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-15T15:08:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-15T15:08:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter Blue’s Nuzzel-like top articles summary has arrived for iOS</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/U47MV3jDHzxQ6koU6x0q6tUQkqc=/0x0:4320x2880/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70145890/3_Twitter_Blue_Blue_BG_Top_Articles.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Twitter&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SVYlHC"&gt;Twitter’s Top Articles feature, which creates a report of articles popular in Blue subscribers’ networks, is &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterBlue/status/1460291564895416322"&gt;now available on iOS&lt;/a&gt; after the company promised last week that it’d be coming “very soon.” It’s been available on Android and the web, but now everyone who subscribes to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22766286/twitter-blue-subscription-service-scroll-nuzzel-undo-tweets-ad-free-articles-us"&gt;Twitter’s paid service&lt;/a&gt; should be able to see a roundup of what people were reading and tweeting about over the past day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4o2l0q"&gt;Top Articles is a sort of spiritual successor to a service called Nuzzel, which provided a similar roundup through email. Nuzzel was run by a company called Scroll, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22417852/twitter-buying-scroll-subscription-service-news-revue-newsletter"&gt;was shut down when Twitter acquired the company&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year. Twitter said at the time it planned to bring Nuzzel back, and now its most popular feature is available to anyone who is willing to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22766286/twitter-blue-subscription-service-scroll-nuzzel-undo-tweets-ad-free-articles-us"&gt;pay the price for Twitter Blue&lt;/a&gt;. The premium service also gives users extra features like the ability to “undo” tweets or read ad-free articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2BJmp2"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Available now on iOS — see what your network is sharing in the last 24 hours with Top Articles so you’ll always know what’s *really* going on. Check it out and add it to your Custom Navigation bar &lt;a href="https://t.co/NxLW8fTTPn"&gt;pic.twitter.com/NxLW8fTTPn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Twitter Blue (@TwitterBlue) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterBlue/status/1460291564895416322?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pZIJYK"&gt;While Twitter Blue subscribers who miss Nuzzel will likely be excited that Top Articles is now available on all the major platforms, it does feel like there should be a lite-version for those who don’t want to directly pay for Twitter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="De2bNi"&gt;While it makes sense that ad-free articles will incur a subscription cost, Twitter Blue as a whole &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/14/22778827/twitter-blue-undo-button-paywall-features-paid-free"&gt;creates the impression that Twitter is paywalling basic features&lt;/a&gt; that should be available to everyone, regardless of which tier of Twitter they’re using. In that vein, Threader (an app that makes Twitter threads more readable by formatting them as articles) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/threader/status/1460258719711694855?s=20"&gt;announced on Monday&lt;/a&gt; that it had been acquired by Twitter, and that it would be included in Twitter Blue. While this is likely good news for those with Blue, it being paywalled won’t help general Twitter users navigate threads any easier. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="HNsPlf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Twitter shouldn’t be hiding basic app improvements behind its Blue paywall  ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/14/22778827/twitter-blue-undo-button-paywall-features-paid-free"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22783594/twitter-blue-nuzzel-top-articles-ios-arrivial-top-articles"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22783594/twitter-blue-nuzzel-top-articles-ios-arrivial-top-articles</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-15T14:48:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-15T14:48:37-05:00</updated>
    <title>The remastered GTA Trilogy is back on PC</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Grand Theft Auto The Trilogy Definitive Edition" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eqrMjlJEFonqcD1AO52BbSnedkc=/129x0:1521x928/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70145783/unnamed.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Rockstar Games&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="p0pg3K"&gt;After &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/13/22779798/remastered-gta-trilogy-unavailable-pc"&gt;a delay lasting around 72 hours&lt;/a&gt;, Rockstar Games finally made &lt;a href="https://store.rockstargames.com/en/game/buy-grand-theft-auto-the-trilogy-the-definitive-edition"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy - Definitive Edition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; playable and purchasable again on PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3OpFC0"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy - The Definitive Edition is again available through the Rockstar Games Launcher for play and purchase. We sincerely apologize for the inconvenience, and are working to improve and update overall performance as we move forward: &lt;a href="https://t.co/hAfEKqYS3o"&gt;https://t.co/hAfEKqYS3o&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Rockstar Support (@RockstarSupport) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RockstarSupport/status/1460037716322795528?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZqxRzI"&gt; “We sincerely apologize for the inconvenience, and are working to improve and update overall performance as we move forward,” Rockstar said in a tweet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ar0UiW"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Trilogy&lt;/em&gt;, which includes remastered versions of &lt;em&gt;GTA III&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;GTA Vice City&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;GTA San Andreas&lt;/em&gt;, was only accessible on PC during a brief window on its botched &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/22/22739195/remastered-grand-theft-auto-trilogy-release-date-november-11th-gta3-vice-city-san-andreas"&gt;November 11th launch date&lt;/a&gt;. The Rockstar Games Launcher went down that same day, preventing anyone from playing the &lt;em&gt;GTA&lt;/em&gt; bundle on PC (or any other Rockstar games, for that matter). Rockstar brought the Launcher back online on November 12th but &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RockstarSupport/status/1459311246789038089"&gt;noted&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;em&gt;GTA: The Trilogy&lt;/em&gt; was unavailable to buy or play because Rockstar had to delete files that were “unintentionally included in these versions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SEKqHk"&gt;Regarding which files were removed, it might’ve had something to do with unlicensed music files and the &lt;a href="https://gta.fandom.com/wiki/Hot_Coffee_Modification"&gt;“Hot Coffee” minigame&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/gta-trilogy-chaos-continues-as-hot-coffee-sex-files-reportedly-uncovered/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Video Games Chronicle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;VGC&lt;/em&gt;) reports that &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/the_agent_man/status/1459317181934624772?"&gt;data&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ThisPurpleCat/status/1458880644021473286"&gt;miners&lt;/a&gt; uncovered code in the remastered edition for the notorious Hot Coffee sex minigame that players could only access via a mod in the original version of &lt;em&gt;GTA San Andreas&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qWwry1"&gt;Despite this, &lt;a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2006/06/08/rockstar-ftc-settle-over-hot-coffee"&gt;the Federal Trade Commission charged Rockstar and Take-Two&lt;/a&gt; at the time for allegedly deceiving the ESRB — &lt;em&gt;GTA San Andreas&lt;/em&gt; was originally rated Mature, but the explicit Hot Coffee minigame would raise that rating to Adults Only. Rockstar released an M-rated version of &lt;em&gt;San Andreas&lt;/em&gt; without the minigame but ended up losing $24 million after stores took the AO version off their shelves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ILNMXt"&gt;Additionally, a separate report from &lt;a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/as-gta-trilogy-pc-is-pulled-dataminers-discover-it-contains-missing-music-and-holy-grail-dev-notes/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;VGC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; highlights data miners who claim they found the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NationalPepper/status/1458831498757423105"&gt;“holy grail”&lt;/a&gt; of developer notes in the remastered games, along with a trove of unlicensed music that &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Ash_735/status/1458844542417973257"&gt;developers left disabled&lt;/a&gt;. Any of this content could’ve been the files Rockstar rushed to remove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="pXlzTU"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Wtf is this? I asked for a refund, I expect a refund. Not an attempt at stalling for time in the hope that I'll be happy I can play this broken mess again. &lt;a href="https://t.co/z6arNSpPFG"&gt;pic.twitter.com/z6arNSpPFG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Lee Rodger (@LRodger501) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LRodger501/status/1460244740591529986?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sPtBdl"&gt;Now that &lt;em&gt;The Trilogy&lt;/em&gt; is back on PC, Rockstar will have to address growing complaints about its performance and graphical issues. Some players were so disappointed in the bundle’s quality that they &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Waffle_64/status/1460037958803861505"&gt;refunded it&lt;/a&gt; before it could even become playable again. And as you can see from the tweet above, Rockstar is annoyingly emailing some players who previously asked for refunds just to confirm that they really don’t want the games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IsO3YX"&gt;Even the entire &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/grandtheftauto/"&gt;r/grandtheftauto&lt;/a&gt; subreddit has gone dark to protest the muddy release of &lt;em&gt;The Trilogy&lt;/em&gt;, as well as Rockstar’s removal of the original &lt;em&gt;GTA&lt;/em&gt; trilogy from game stores like Steam. If you try to visit the subreddit, you’ll be met with this message:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="DIIFQW"&gt;Going dark to protest Rockstar/Take-Two taking down modders, pulling Trilogy PC version from paying customers, pulling ALL PC TITLES from paying customers for 30 hours, removing the original GTAs from sale (including 1/2/1969), letting Sony deny Trilogy refunds, No official statements. Please don’t blame modders for looking at files. Thank you to Grove Street Games for doing the best that you could. PC: https://help.xsolla.com/i-made-a-payment-and-need-a-refund&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="NG9RgK"&gt;The problems players are experiencing with the games aren’t isolated to the PC version either — glitches and bugs are plaguing the remastered games across all platforms. Players are shocked at the appearance of some of the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ovedrivera/status/1459313516133892107"&gt;“remastered”&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Kurashiville/status/1460132714443587586"&gt;characters&lt;/a&gt; and other graphical issues, such as one that &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MikeyPanik/status/1460047006471237633"&gt;causes blinding rainstorms&lt;/a&gt;. Rockstar says it’s working towards improving the game’s “overall performance” in the future, but it may already be too late.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22783286/grand-theft-auto-the-trilogy-pc-hot-coffee-rockstar-games-launcher"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22783286/grand-theft-auto-the-trilogy-pc-hot-coffee-rockstar-games-launcher</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-15T14:32:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-15T14:32:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>Russia blows up a satellite, creating a dangerous debris cloud in space</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MtTwLfagvErSA-xOKMtb8EW8A_A=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70145701/acastro_190809_1777_space_debris_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Verge/Alex Castro&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="w2rWm5"&gt;This morning, Russia destroyed one of its own satellites with a ground-based missile, creating thousands of pieces of debris that have spread out into Earth orbit, according to the US State Department. The US has identified at least 1,500 trackable pieces of debris from the event, and many thousands of smaller ones that cannot be traced, Ned Price, a spokesperson for the State Department, said during a briefing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IqS7jH"&gt;The news comes amid reports from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/roscosmos/status/1460256220124782595"&gt;Russia’s space agency&lt;/a&gt; Roscosmos, independently verified by &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;via NASA’s live feed,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;that the astronauts living on board the International Space Station had to shelter in place this morning due to a cloud of space debris that seems to be passing by the station every 90 minutes, the time it takes for the ISS to orbit the Earth. NASA has yet to confirm if the debris field passing the ISS is the same one created by the Russian anti-satellite, or ASAT, test, and the agency did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dnBE0r"&gt;However, the State Department indicated that the debris field is a danger to the space station. “This test will significantly increase the risk to astronauts and cosmonauts on the International Space Station, as well as to other human spaceflight activities,” Price told reporters. “Russia’s dangerous and irresponsible behavior jeopardizes the long term sustainability of our space and clearly demonstrates that Russia’s claims of opposing the weaponization of space are disingenuous and hypocritical.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="sCFSSY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We are actively working to characterize the debris field.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3au6we"&gt;US Space Command, which oversees the tracking of space objects and debris in orbit around Earth, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; in a statement that it was “aware of a debris-generating event” in space this morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2HZpQh"&gt;“We are actively working to characterize the debris field and will continue to ensure all space-faring nations have the information necessary to maneuver satellites if impacted,” US Space Command said in a statement. “We are also in the process of working with the interagency, including the State Department and NASA, concerning these reports and will provide an update in the near future.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DFNZHu"&gt;US Space Command has been tracking ASAT tests from Russia over the last couple of years. In 2020, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/15/21222751/russia-asat-test-us-space-command-satellite-nudol-missile"&gt;US Space Command reported&lt;/a&gt; two tests of Russia’s ASAT technology, known as Nudol. However both tests did not seem to actually destroy any targets in space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZROFBn"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;With new data from Kiwi Space Radar gathered at 1620 UTC, we confirm detection of multiple objects near expected location of Cosmos 1408. We will share supporting data as we gather it today.&lt;/p&gt;— LeoLabs, Inc. (@LeoLabs_Space) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LeoLabs_Space/status/1460295107152949256?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fBcJ9r"&gt;Private space tracking company LeoLabs confirmed on Twitter that it has observed multiple objects are now in the location of an old Russian satellite called Kosmos 1408, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/planet4589/status/1460250989731192846"&gt;which was rumored&lt;/a&gt; to be the target of the ASAT test. If that is the case, it seems likely that the debris cloud created from the test is the same one that threatened the International Space Station this morning, according to space tracking expert Jonathan McDowell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W9UC5G"&gt;During &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/multimedia/nasatv/iss_ustream.html"&gt;NASA’s live feed recording from the International Space Station&lt;/a&gt; this morning, mission controllers in NASA’s Johnson Space Center in Houston discussed the cloud of debris passing by the astronauts. “We are a minute and a half from the next debris field transit at this point,” a mission controller said to the astronauts during one passt, &lt;a href="https://www.space.com/space-debris-astronauts-shelter-november-2021?utm_campaign=socialflow"&gt;according to audio from the live feed recorded by Space.com&lt;/a&gt;. “This is going to be a four-minute transit.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uogDOs"&gt;During the first few debris passes this morning, NASA astronauts sheltered inside the SpaceX Crew Dragon currently docked with the ISS, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22772552/spacex-crew-3-dragon-launch-nasa-interenational-space-station-success"&gt;which just brought four new astronauts to the space station last week&lt;/a&gt;. However, the astronauts eventually opened the hatch to their vehicle and entered the ISS, according to the live feed audio. Currently there are seven people living on the ISS, two of which are Russian cosmonauts. Later this morning, Roscosmos stated that “the crew is routinely performing operations according to the flight program,” after sheltering this morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3nAa78"&gt;Jonathan McDowell, an astrophysicist at Harvard and satellite tracker, calculated the time of the first debris field pass, which occurred around 2:06AM ET this morning. He found that the passes have occurred roughly every 93 minutes since that first pass. After figuring out the orbit of Kosmos 1408, he found that the paths of the satellite and the ISS do come close to each other every hour and a half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="mY3F43"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Here is the orbit of ISS (blue) compared to that of the Ikar No. 39L satellite (cover name Kosmos-1408) (magenta)  and the part of the orbit where the crew have been warned of possible collisions  with a debris field (red). This shows Kosmos-1408 is a plausible candidate &lt;a href="https://t.co/oGJtQxWxkV"&gt;pic.twitter.com/oGJtQxWxkV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Jonathan McDowell (@planet4589) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/planet4589/status/1460261416414420995?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XIBLFl"&gt;“What I showed was that the orbital plane of this satellite actually is right through the part of the ISS orbit where they’re getting these warnings,” McDowell tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rI04TU"&gt;ASAT tests are often considered political moves that showcase a nation’s capability of taking out satellites. But they are a source of concern for those in the space industry, because of their propensity to cause giant fields of satellite fragments. These fields of debris can span many miles, jumping into higher and lower altitudes. The resulting debris pieces often vary wildly in size, and they can sometimes stay in orbit for years, threatening functioning satellites. Objects in low Earth orbit are moving at roughly 17,500 miles per hour, so if a fragment of space debris collides with another fast-moving satellite, it can cause significant damage or even create more fragments that then threaten other satellites. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="966D40"&gt;China famously conducted an ASAT test in 2007, using a kinetic missile to destroy its Fengyun 1C satellite. &lt;a href="https://swfound.org/media/9550/chinese_asat_fact_sheet_updated_2012.pdf"&gt;The event created thousands of pieces of debris&lt;/a&gt;, some of which are still circulating above Earth. In fact, the International Space Station had to boost its orbit last week to avoid one of the fragments from the satellite still in orbit. In 2019, India also conducted its own ASAT test, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/27/18283730/india-anti-satellite-demonstration-asat-test-microsat-r-space-debris"&gt;known as Mission Shakti&lt;/a&gt;, creating hundreds of debris pieces after taking out a decaying satellite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FjSoUe"&gt;The United States also conducted an ASAT test in 2008, &lt;a href="https://appel.nasa.gov/2008/06/01/operation-burnt-frost-the-power-of-social-networks/"&gt;known as Operation Burnt Frost&lt;/a&gt;. The US military destroyed a satellite launched by the National Reconnaissance Office that was falling out of orbit. The satellite’s fuel tank contained more than 1,000 pounds of a toxic fuel called hydrazine, and the ASAT test was considered a way to protect people on the ground while exercising anti-satellite technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kWEzb1"&gt;The US State Department is strongly condemning today’s ASAT test by Russia, calling it “dangerous, reckless, and irresponsible.” Price of the State Department did not say exactly what the US’s response would be, however. “[We] don’t telegraph specific measures, but as I said before, we will work with our allies and partners in different ways to make clear that the United States — that the international community — is not going to tolerate this kind of irresponsible behavior,” he said during the briefing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KGSkJk"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22782946/russia-asat-test-satellite-international-space-station-debris"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22782946/russia-asat-test-satellite-international-space-station-debris</id>
    <author>
      <name>Loren Grush</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-15T14:27:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-15T14:27:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>If you can’t play Halo Infinite right now, you’re not alone</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KqOix_W5NINlpwaBaO65Strpy7o=/393x0:3447x2036/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70145677/HaloInfinite_RXJtJxSVSl.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Halo Infinite’s&lt;em&gt; multiplayer beta is here, but the rollout is hitting some snags.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZCRDaR"&gt;Microsoft surprise-launched &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite’s&lt;/em&gt; free-to-play multiplayer beta &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22782786/halo-infinite-multiplayer-available-download-launch"&gt;on Monday&lt;/a&gt;, but if you’re having trouble jumping into the game, you’re not the only one.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1iOeoX"&gt;According to Brian Jarrard, Halo community director at 343 Industries, some players playing on Xbox or from the Windows store are “likely hitting some blue screens / errors” while trying to launch the game. “The build is still publishing and rolling out, expected to resolve in due time,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ske7ch/status/1460322913895079940"&gt;he said&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ksi83p"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;PSA: We're in the thick of things at the moment but FYI that players on Xbox/WinStore are likely hitting some blue screens / errors trying to launch. The build is still publishing and rolling out, expected to resolve in due time. Hang in there!&lt;/p&gt;— Brian Jarrard (@ske7ch) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ske7ch/status/1460322913895079940?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="t3QoTV"&gt;The Xbox support Twitter account also acknowledged issues in a now-deleted tweet, saying that some people might be having trouble downloading and launching the game. In that tweet, the company suggested rebooting your console to try and fix the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CJQHHzkHziy3GYAlukEdky3lDhw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23016841/Screen_Shot_2021_11_15_at_11.45.10_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A screenshot I took from Tweetdeck of Xbox support’s deleted tweet.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="72xKKH"&gt;I had been running into the blue screen problem while trying to play on my Xbox Series X. But as I was writing this article, I tried to open the &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; again, and it finally kicked off the update that looks to be installing the full multiplayer. The update comes in at 25.90GB for me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="llxOri"&gt;And that makes sense, as Jarrard said &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ske7ch/status/1460329862980247556"&gt;in a tweet&lt;/a&gt; shortly after we published this article that “we’re getting reports this issue should be mostly resolved.” He similarly recommended restarting your Xbox or relaunching Xbox Game Pass for PC if you are still seeing the blue screen on &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;. The Halo support Twitter account has also shared good news, saying that you &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HaloSupport/status/1460330547859771397"&gt;should be able to download the beta&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OWdQqt"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;The time is here, Spartans! You should know be able to download the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/HaloInfinite?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#HaloInfinite&lt;/a&gt; beta! If you're still experiencing an issue downloading the game, please restart console or Xbox app on PC. If you encounter a blue screen after that, please file a Halo Support ticket. &lt;a href="https://t.co/KkDEVPhiP0"&gt;https://t.co/KkDEVPhiP0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Halo Support (@HaloSupport) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HaloSupport/status/1460330547859771397?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DLQMaN"&gt;Two &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; editors have been able to play on PC via Steam without issue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hu8w5l"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update November 15th, 2:50PM ET: Added information from Jarrard and from the Halo support Twitter account.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2ODE3S"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction November 15th, 2:50PM ET: We misspelled Brian Jarrard’s last name in a previous version of this article. We regret the error.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22783654/halo-infinite-multiplayer-blue-screen-error-download-xbox-pc-windows"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22783654/halo-infinite-multiplayer-blue-screen-error-download-xbox-pc-windows</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-15T14:18:14-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-15T14:18:14-05:00</updated>
    <title>A $219 Windows on Arm PC is finally available for developers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PysuBUcDsByTl_sItia2V-_VHeY=/25x0:835x540/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70145629/gldn_8Z247H1H3SKP_DHF01846_ECSLIVAMiniBoxQC710_HighlightHero_VP2_859x540.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="le2sKX"&gt;Developers, historically, have had somewhat limited options when it comes to testing apps for Windows on Arm. They’ve commonly needed to purchase costly Arm devices like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/23/21526702/microsoft-surface-pro-x-2020-review-arm-windows-10-apps-features-specs-price"&gt;Surface Pro X&lt;/a&gt;, which &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=VergeWindowsArmPC111521&amp;amp;murl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fsurface-pro-x%2F8xtmb6c575md%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%3Aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;starts at $899.99&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22452710/microsoft-qualcomm-windows-on-arm-dev-kit-pc-features-release-date"&gt;Microsoft and Qualcomm&lt;/a&gt; aim to lower that barrier to entry with the new &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=VergeWindowsArmPC111521&amp;amp;murl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fecs-liva-mini-box-qc710-desktop%2F8z247h1h3skp%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%3Aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ECS Liva Mini Box QC710 Desktop&lt;/a&gt;, a tiny Snapdragon-based PC that’s now available for $219 on the Microsoft Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sZUxTw"&gt;The QC710 is powered by Qualcomm’s Snapdragon 7c Compute SC7180 (the first-generation Snapdragon 7c, rather than the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/24/22451392/qualcomm-snapdragon-7c-gen-2-arm-processor"&gt;second-generation chip&lt;/a&gt; that Qualcomm announced earlier this year). It also comes with 4GB of memory and 64GB of storage, as well as various expansion ports including USB 2.0 Type-A, HDMI, USB 3.2 Gen 1 Type-A, USB Type-C, and a microSD slot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="AxJXOb"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Powered by Qualcomm’s Snapdragon 7c Compute SC7180&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7Z0DkH"&gt;In other words, this isn’t a high-end rig that will replace a Mac Mini or other fully fledged desktop. It’s specifically intended for developers to test Arm64 apps at an affordable price point (apps which consumers could then, of course, run on fancier devices like the Surface Pro X). It’s also something you could feasibly bring back and forth to the office, weighing just over half a pound. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lhRjCt"&gt;There are only a handful of Arm-based Windows PCs and Chromebooks available currently, as high-profile releases gradually trickle into the consumer space. Qualcomm’s second-generation Snapdragon 7c, announced in May, currently powers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22660761/lenovo-chromebook-duet-detachable-release-oled"&gt;Lenovo’s $429 Duet 5 Chromebook&lt;/a&gt; and Samsung’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22466164/samsung-galaxy-book-go-laptop-windows-arm-snapdragon-price-specs"&gt;$349 Galaxy Book Go&lt;/a&gt;. But app compatibility is still a gamble, which is a barrier for many potential buyers. Microsoft and Qualcomm are no doubt hoping that the availability of a $219 developer kit will help build out the ecosystem of Arm64-compatible apps — though whether that will come to fruition remains to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22783174/windows-arm-microsoft-qualcomm-developer-kit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22783174/windows-arm-microsoft-qualcomm-developer-kit</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-15T14:15:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-15T14:15:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Surprise: Amazon has four new smart switches</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jgjtTeorUjPE0pQoOdSoxwAG1R8=/0x213:1500x1213/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70145615/713t73yvUpL._AC_SL1500_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon Basics new smart switches add simple smart control to existing lighting.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Amazon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CJP0eE"&gt;A new line of &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-Basics-Single-Neutral-Required/dp/B095X911T8?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Basics Smart Switches&lt;/a&gt; has landed on &lt;a href="http://Amazon.com"&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/a&gt;, bringing the Amazon-branded smart home gadgets count up to seven, including the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-Smart-Thermostat/dp/B08J4C8871?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;new smart thermostat&lt;/a&gt; and smart &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Introducing-Amazon-Smart-Quality-Monitor/dp/B08W8KS8D3?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;indoor air quality monitor&lt;/a&gt;. That’s a big leap from the one, lonely &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/20/17882918/amazon-smart-plug-price-release-date-alexa-voice-control-routines-lights-ac"&gt;Amazon smart plug&lt;/a&gt; the company had left after discontinuing its indoor smart security camera last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zCUPoX"&gt;Spotted by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/danwroc/status/1460277219503353864"&gt;Dan Wroclawski of Consumer Reports&lt;/a&gt;, the four smart switches launched on November 11th and include a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-Basics-Single-Neutral-Required/dp/B095X911T8?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;single-pole switch ($17.99)&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-Basics-Single-Neutral-Required/dp/B095X5H16X?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;single-pole dimmer ($19.99)&lt;/a&gt; both for controlling one lighting circuit, and a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-Basics-Switch-Neutral-Required/dp/B095X8YD3Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;three-way switch ($18.99) &lt;/a&gt;and a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-Basics-Dimmer-Neutral-Required/dp/B095X5HTLS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;three-way dimmer ($20.99)&lt;/a&gt;, which can control one circuit from two locations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QQofml"&gt;A smart switch turns existing hardwired lighting into smart lighting, adding app and voice control. It’s a good alternative to smart bulbs when you want to automate lighting in a room with lots of lightbulbs or decorative fixtures. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qwkK0sC4-vHi6f7fKYOtjCL6M8M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23016479/71pPnO0kwHL._AC_SL1500_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Amazon&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new Amazon Basics 3-Way Smart Dimmer Switch needs a neutral wire.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="WWfFfg"&gt;One advantage of Amazon’s own smart home devices is that they work with Amazon’s Frustration Free Setup and Certified for Humans programs, which means they should be simple to set up, especially if you already have an Echo smart speaker in your home. The downside is that these switches will not work with any other smart home system or voice assistant; they are only Alexa-compatible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nuArjs"&gt;You also have to install them. These smart switches need to be hardwired into your home’s wiring and require a neutral wire. If you have an older home with no neutral, then &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Lutron-Wallplate-Assistant-Incandescent-PDW-6WCL-WH/dp/B07SJJBTYY?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Lutron Caseta&lt;/a&gt; or GE Lighting &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/GE-3-Wire-Smart-Switch-Motion-Sensing/dp/B082LK4X4X/ref=sr_1_3_sspa?keywords=ge+cync+no+neutral+wire+switch&amp;amp;qid=1636995782&amp;amp;sr=8-3-spons&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;spLa=ZW5jcnlwdGVkUXVhbGlmaWVyPUFFSlk4MDBGTVdVRDImZW5jcnlwdGVkSWQ9QTAxODI0MzgzQ1BHSkhBWVRIN1I2JmVuY3J5cHRlZEFkSWQ9QTAxNzgwNDkxRjg3MEVTUlFZNVFMJndpZGdldE5hbWU9c3BfYXRmJmFjdGlvbj1jbGlja1JlZGlyZWN0JmRvTm90TG9nQ2xpY2s9dHJ1ZQ%3D%3D&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Cync’&lt;/a&gt;s neutral-wire free options will be a better fit. But if you have the right wiring, these are a good value for a smart switch, prices for which generally range from around $25 to upwards of $60.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="klEIDj"&gt;The new Amazon switches do not require a smart home hub to connect to the internet for automation and will work with Alexa for voice and app control. Once installed, they can be used as a traditional light switch, with the added smarts that come from being able to ask the voice assistant to turn them on and off with an Echo speaker, add them into Alexa Routines in the Alexa app, and create schedules for them. The two switches with dimming capability can also adjust the brightness with voice or app control.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PABHh4_s1t0no5MmOX1bOeNq6nM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23016521/61Kt4yA1e5L._AC_SL1500_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Amazon&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The single-pole smart switch costs $17.99 and adds smart control with Alexa to a single lighting circuit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hgDEOq"&gt;As is the theme with Amazon Basics devices, these are simply designed. The single-pole switches look just like a regular paddle switch and have a small status light LED at the bottom. The dimmer options have a plus or minus button above the paddle to adjust the brightness and a row of green LEDs up top for a visual indicator of brightness level. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2j1EJy"&gt;It’s surprising, however, to see Amazon stating on the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-Basics-Single-Neutral-Required/dp/B095X5H16X?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;product page&lt;/a&gt; that these smart switches are for exclusive use with Alexa and will not support other voice assistants or smart hubs, especially considering the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761340/amazon-matter-smart-home-standard"&gt;recently reaffirmed its support of Matter&lt;/a&gt;, the open smart home standard coming in 2022. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22783275/amazon-basics-smart-switches-price-release-date-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22783275/amazon-basics-smart-switches-price-release-date-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-15T14:01:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-15T14:01:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter makes big changes for devs as it eyes decentralized future</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Twitter’s blue bird silhouette logo on a black background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pjJLKeEMVI9KKoL2PIdB90dXTO4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70145565/acastro_180827_1777_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Twitter’s new API is finally official, which could mean good things for third-party clients&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="vkXyVO"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.twitter.com/developer/en_us/topics/tools/2021/build-whats-next-with-the-new-twitter-developer-platform"&gt;Twitter has announced&lt;/a&gt; that the second version of its application programming interface, or API, is ready to come out of early access and become the default for developers. When Twitter &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/12/21364644/twitter-api-v2-new-access-tiers-developer-portal-support-developers"&gt;announced API v2 in August 2020&lt;/a&gt;, it seemed like a chance to rebuild not only the infrastructure on which developers build their apps and bots, but Twitter’s relationship with the people using its platform as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NgqRCw"&gt;API v2 is taking over API v1.1’s job of letting third-party clients access and interact with Tweets and letting other developers create bots that do various things across the platform (like &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CraigWeekend"&gt;introduce people to the weekend&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://tweepsmap.com"&gt;gather analytics for companies&lt;/a&gt;). When I talked to Amir Shevat, Twitter’s developer platform lead, about what the official switch to API v2 meant for the platform, he told me that it would make things better for users who wanted third-party Twitter clients. He also revealed that the change was another step in the company’s goal to become a decentralized platform that developers built apps and experiences on top of, making conversations better in ways that Twitter itself couldn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="CshcxV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;API v2 and Developer Policy changes allow for more freedom for better Twitter apps&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JMhzLL"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.twitter.com/developer/en_us/topics/tools/2021/build-whats-next-with-the-new-twitter-developer-platform"&gt;In its press release&lt;/a&gt;, Twitter says it’s removing restrictions from its Developer Policy on “how you build with Twitter’s core features and limited the number of users you can support through your app.” Shevat elaborated on this, saying that the new policy will make it clear what’s allowed and make it easier for developers to compete with Twitter in ways that the company didn’t allow before. This could mean a real impact on how Twitter’s users interact with the service, as it gives developers more freedom to build third-party Twitter clients like Tweetbot, Twitterrific, or Fenix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pk1VeI"&gt;While there are unofficial Twitter apps available, the company’s relationship with the developers behind those apps has been mixed — limits on how many users could use a third-party app, as well as missing features, meant that the de facto way to access Twitter has been by using its official app. This is in contrast to some other social platforms like Reddit, where many users recommend apps made by indie devs like Apollo or Narwhal over the official one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aVPTz0"&gt;When Twitter first announced API v2, it seemed like the company was trying to be more friendly toward those who were looking to make their own clients. It seems to have panned out for some — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/26/22250899/tweetbot-6-tapbots-ios-app-update-subscription-service-twitter-api"&gt;Tweetbot’s latest version uses the new API&lt;/a&gt;, and Twitter has &lt;a href="https://twittercommunity.com/t/announcing-manage-tweets-endpoints-for-the-twitter-api-v2/161501"&gt;recently added API support&lt;/a&gt; for newer features like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301375/twitter-super-follows-communities-paid-followers"&gt;Super Followers&lt;/a&gt; and the ability to tweet &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/11/21362514/twitter-reply-limiting-features-all-users-harassment-rollout-available-now"&gt;with limitations on who can reply&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="9fgVWE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Twitter’s API has changed more in the last year than in the 5 before that”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WMv62x"&gt;Paul Haddad, one of the developers of Tweetbot, told me that calling the prior guidelines rocky was “really understating it,” and that he wouldn’t be surprised if other developers wrote Twitter’s announcement off as cheap talk. From his point of view, though, Twitter’s API team has recently been better at openly communicating with developers (echoing a comment Shevat made about building in public), and he said that the API had “changed more in the last year than in the 5 before that.” Haddad also told me that Twitter’s policy change assured him that basing Tweetbot 6 on API v2 was a good decision. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="1RwAdf"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Twitter has bigger dreams than really good third-party clients&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fElSGK"&gt;Twitter has bigger aspirations than developers being able to make really good Twitter clients, though. Its press release says the company is “doubling down” on making it easier for developers to “drive the future of innovation on Twitter.” The company says it wants to see developers helping to improve the community, make better content recommendations to users, and overall make the platform a friendlier place to be on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z64vOo"&gt;I asked Shevat why Twitter was looking to outside developers to “improve the health and safety of the public conversation,” as its press release puts it, instead of doing the job itself. He said Twitter wants to let developers tackle issues that wouldn’t be practical for the company to handle — his example was a vegetarian developer working on an algorithm that would let other like-minded users avoid content about meat that they might find upsetting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="8Q6C6c"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Twitter still wants to become more of a communications protocol than a social network&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dmFO3u"&gt;He also tied the decision to Twitter’s interest in making its platform decentralized. He said that the goal was for Twitter to end up like iOS or Android — a platform that was interesting because of the apps and features other developers were building on top of it. Twitter has been working on becoming, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/21/22242718/twitter-bluesky-decentralized-social-media-team-project-update"&gt;as CEO Jack Dorsey put it&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year, a “standard for the public conversation layer of the internet” instead of a traditional social media platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DCqFNB"&gt;It calls these efforts &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22627435/twitter-bluesky-lead-jay-graber-decentralized-social-web"&gt;Project Bluesky&lt;/a&gt;, and the Bluesky team is tasked with making the networking technology Twitter would need to actually become a distributed platform (there are also, of course, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774501/twitter-crypto-dedicated-team-dorsey-square-decentralization"&gt;teams working on crypto&lt;/a&gt;). API v2, Shevat explained, was a part of Twitter working toward that ambitious goal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="vltfhK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"A decentralized Twitter would bring the company back to its past","url":"https://www.theverge.com/interface/2019/12/12/21011055/twitter-decentralization-jack-dorsey-blue-sky-app-net-dalton-caldwell"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="csweJP"&gt;To help make the platform easier to start working with, Twitter is making some changes to the tiers that determine what developers can do with its platform. It’s creating an “Essential access” tier that lets you start playing with the Twitter API without having to wait for a manual approval process (Shevat told me it was a matter of seconds, instead of the hours or days it used to take) and which will let you pull 500,000 tweets a month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oP7D3D"&gt;If you’re willing to go through the application process, you can gain access to the Elevated tier, which lets you use Twitter’s API to pull 2 million tweets a month. That’s a lot of tweets, enough for 80 percent of the developers currently using API v1.1, according to Shevat. As a bonus, if your project is currently using API v2, you should automatically get access to the Elevated tier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EyjQo2"&gt;While rewriting an API is an ambitious task, especially for a company as big as Twitter, it’s clear the platform has much larger ambitions. It’s hard to say whether it’ll be able to achieve them, but at the very least it’s been able to rewrite its API and tweak its policies to make things easier for those who want to build on the platform. With v2 now official, and v1.1 being put into maintenance mode (getting only “critical bug fixes”), developers now have more freedom with what they want to create and more responsibility in the eyes of Twitter. To top it all off, users may end up getting a nicer experience out of the deal as well.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22779149/twitter-api-version-2-official-decentralized"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22779149/twitter-api-version-2-official-decentralized</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-15T13:39:19-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-15T13:39:19-05:00</updated>
    <title>The live-action Halo TV show on Paramount Plus gets its first brief teaser</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aZSzo82xIZEsmwO0KApDU83HWOA=/166x0:1918x1168/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70145414/Screen_Shot_2021_11_15_at_1.26.34_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="s4VwM4"&gt;The long-in-the-works &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HaloTheSeries/status/1460313378572832768"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; TV series&lt;/a&gt; finally has its first — very brief — teaser trailer, revealed today at Microsoft’s 20th anniversary Xbox event, giving a first glimpse at the live-action adaptation of the iconic games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3iyF3F"&gt;The teaser is &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; short, offering just a few close-up shots of Master Chief’s Mjolnir armor (set to be filled by &lt;em&gt;American Gods&lt;/em&gt;’ Pablo Schreiber in the live-action show), before a voice that sounds a lot like Cortana (Jen Taylor, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/11/21561137/halo-tv-show-cortana-recast-jen-taylor"&gt;reprising her role from the games&lt;/a&gt;) says “Hello, Master Chief.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="t5Faob"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Hello, Master Chief. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/HaloTheSeries?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#HaloTheSeries&lt;/a&gt; streaming 2022, exclusively on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/paramountplus?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@ParamountPlus&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://t.co/xjmMNrvwLO"&gt;pic.twitter.com/xjmMNrvwLO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Halo on Paramount+ (@HaloTheSeries) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HaloTheSeries/status/1460313378572832768?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vnpprK"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; has had several attempts at live action before, including &lt;em&gt;Halo: Landfall&lt;/em&gt; (a series of promotional shorts made as &lt;em&gt;Halo 3&lt;/em&gt; ads), &lt;em&gt;Halo 4: Forward Unto Dawn &lt;/em&gt;(a web series that served as a marketing campaign for &lt;em&gt;Halo 4&lt;/em&gt;), and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/11/6/7164047/ridley-scott-halo-nightfall-thoughts"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo: Nightfall&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (a prequel series to &lt;em&gt;Halo 5: Guardians&lt;/em&gt;). &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; on Paramount Plus, however, looks to be the most ambitious attempt yet to adapt the sci-fi franchise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gaxuIK"&gt;It’s not clear yet what &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; will actually be about beyond the broad strokes of the franchise or whether it’ll be adapting the already released games, telling a new story, or existing in some other space in the &lt;em&gt;Halo &lt;/em&gt;universe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gXhQTD"&gt;It’s been a long road for the live-action &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; series, which is set to debut on Paramount Plus sometime in 2022. The show was first announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/28/17514578/halo-tv-series-showtime-microsoft-xbox"&gt;all the way back in 2018&lt;/a&gt; as a Showtime series, before getting shifted to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299828/halo-tv-show-paramount-plus-exclusive-showtime-microsoft"&gt;become a Paramount Plus exclusive&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year following COVID-related delays in production. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uKx8nX"&gt;But with the release of today’s teaser, it seems like fans won’t have to wait too much longer. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22783546/halo-tv-show-paramount-plus-live-action-teaser-trailer"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22783546/halo-tv-show-paramount-plus-live-action-teaser-trailer</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-15T13:31:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-15T13:31:30-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft surprises with early Halo Infinite multiplayer launch today</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VFzSyEVMP6rHVbVD1ASXHEvHWnI=/0x2:2155x1439/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70145377/haloinfinitemp.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PX9CEl"&gt;Microsoft is surprising Xbox fans today with an early launch for &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; multiplayer. Rumors of the early &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; multiplayer drop appeared over the weekend, and Microsoft is now making it official as part of today’s 20-year Xbox anniversary. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L3BjOw"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;’s cross-platform multiplayer mode should now be live for everyone on Xbox One, Xbox Series S / X, and PC to try out in beta. This beta includes access to season one with all the core maps and battle pass features. Any progress in the multiplayer mode will also carry over to launch day on December 8th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jkO73p"&gt;Initially, there were a few hurdles downloading it from Xbox or via the Windows Store — at first, the free-to-play game only showed up as part of a paid Xbox Game Pass subscription, and some players had issues launching it as well. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/XboxSupport/status/1460326904502775808"&gt;Microsoft suggested&lt;/a&gt; players might want to reboot their consoles, and Halo community director Brian Jarrard &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ske7ch/status/1460322913895079940"&gt;confirmed&lt;/a&gt; that some players were experiencing errors on launch since “the build is still publishing and rolling out.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i9vbqy8v1j2K8I16p8OIOLFpyC0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23016839/Screen_Shot_2021_11_15_at_1.50.08_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;At first, the game didn’t offer a free download option.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="TETKHJ"&gt;But we’re now seeing the game working on Xbox, and we had no issue firing up matches on PC &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1240440/Halo_Infinite/"&gt;via Steam&lt;/a&gt; from the get go. They did take a bit longer than you might expect to load, lingering on the startup screens. On Xbox, it’s a 25GB install; Steam starts with a 23.7GB download expanding to 26GB installed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tCdyx8"&gt;343 Industries, the developers of &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;, first started &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22597498/halo-infinite-multiplayer-technical-preview-beta-july-29th"&gt;previewing the multiplayer mode&lt;/a&gt; of the game in July. A &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; multiplayer &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665435/halo-infinite-multiplayer-preview-september-24th"&gt;preview in late September&lt;/a&gt; was available to all Xbox players. We couldn’t get enough of the multiplayer mode of &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;, and it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22725770/halo-infinite-multiplayer-preview"&gt;felt like an exciting return to form&lt;/a&gt;. But do note that if you played the beta on PC, you’ll need to rebind any controls you’ve changed. The new release appears to be using a different client than the earlier test flights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oEqvb6"&gt;November 15th marks 20 years since the original Xbox debuted alongside &lt;em&gt;Halo: Combat Evolved&lt;/em&gt;. Microsoft announced the &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; early multiplayer drop during a special anniversary stream celebrating the 20th anniversary. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4wESL4"&gt;It’s no surprise that the Xbox event featured &lt;em&gt;Halo &lt;/em&gt;heavily today, after more than 81 million copies of &lt;em&gt;Halo &lt;/em&gt;games have been sold worldwide. It’s a popular franchise that saw more than 3 million players of Halo: The Master Chief Collection on PC and Xbox One during its launch week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fidK1n"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.halowaypoint.com/news/welcome-to-the-halo-infinite-mp-beta"&gt;Here’s the full Halo Waypoint blog post&lt;/a&gt; about Halo Infinite’s multiplayer launch, including a list of which game modes and features it does and doesn’t include. Here’s a chart of the PC system requirements, too. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mLv_SHZivvyU-Yl7tsULCIhi0k4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23016766/halo_pc_specs_infinite.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LHHXk7"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, 2:43PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The game now seems to be working (and free-to-play) on Xbox as well.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22782786/halo-infinite-multiplayer-available-download-launch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22782786/halo-infinite-multiplayer-available-download-launch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-15T13:30:06-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-15T13:30:06-05:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon releases Prime Video app for Mac with downloads, AirPlay, and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/j_MW0Sxkf8z-gbm8nPCZHmfrxbA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70145372/DSCF6095.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JkQ8Ir"&gt;Better late than never, as they say: Amazon today launched a Prime Video app for macOS that’s available as &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/amazon-prime-video/id545519333"&gt;a free download in the Mac App Store&lt;/a&gt;. Prime Video for Mac includes support for offline downloads, and you can choose your preferred video quality both for regular streaming and downloads. (At the “best” setting, Amazon estimates around 5.8GB of data usage per hour when streaming. The figure is slightly lower for downloads, with Amazon quoting 2.9GB per hour of downloaded video.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CCaHFu"&gt;When you first open Prime Video for Mac, the app asks whether you want to receive notifications for content recommendations and other alerts. But from there, it’s much the same experience as on other platforms. Oddly, the Prime Video app itself can’t be made full-screen — but that changes as soon as you start playing a movie or TV show. Amazon is supporting native macOS features like picture-in-picture and AirPlay, and it’s also baked in its own extras like X-Ray with cast and behind-the-scenes info.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7E5FNR"&gt;Aside from the regular free-with-Prime-subscription selection, there’s also a dedicated store tab where you can rent or purchase content. Amazon will use your account’s stored payment info when making charges. Other settings in the app include auto play and subtitle preferences, parental controls, and you can also view other devices that have been registered to your Prime account. Any deeper account management than that will require going to Amazon’s site in a browser. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="93BTw0"&gt;From a functionality standpoint, most of what you’d want out of a Prime Video app is now on the Mac. That new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22751921/apple-macbook-pro-14-16-inch-2021-m1-pro-max-review"&gt;16-inch MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt; makes for quite a portable movie-watching experience. Amazon’s Prime Video app for Mac is compatible with macOS Big Sur and later.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22783432/amazon-prime-video-mac-app-store-now-available"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22783432/amazon-prime-video-mac-app-store-now-available</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
