<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-15T13:28:59-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T13:28:59-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T13:28:59-04:00</updated>
    <title>HBO’s QAnon documentary is a megaphone for extremists — and it’s unbelievably boring</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Q: Into the Storm teaser image" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p-PU0R4UPCvL_AWWu1ULLzlPAtw=/147x0:1716x1046/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68969015/Screen_Shot_2021_03_15_at_12.52.09_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;HBO&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZtkmY3"&gt;QAnon has become a nearly inescapable part of politics. The conspiracy is organized around an anonymous figure called Q, who was supposedly operating inside the Trump administration. Using anonymous online message boards, Q has sent a string of cryptic messages about a plan to mass-arrest Democratic politicians and celebrities, who are supposedly kidnapping and murdering huge numbers of children. (They are not.) Q has now spent three years promising imminent arrests, while the QAnon group has become a kind of super-conspiracy theory attracting people from across the world, built around cheering for mass executions and martial law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tBw5hI"&gt;On paper, then, unmasking the person (or people) behind Q sounds like a big deal. And that’s the goal of &lt;em&gt;Q: Into the Storm&lt;/em&gt;, an HBO documentary series from director Cullen Hoback. Hoback tracked down some of the people who have supported and popularized QAnon, seeking what HBO calls the “mastermind” behind the theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rrKrNF"&gt;Unfortunately, &lt;em&gt;Into the Storm&lt;/em&gt; isn’t a deconstruction of QAnon so much as a grimy mirror of it. The six-hour series tediously and obsessively charts an alleged inner circle of the movement, while glossing over the myriad reasons that Q’s messages appeal to people, as well as QAnon’s effect on believers and the people around them. It embodies all the ways that idealistic journalistic values — a devotion to humanizing subjects, a goal of exposing powerful wrongdoers, and a belief that exposing truth will set people free — fail in the face of extremist movements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="c7WpSO"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Imagine ‘Tiger King’, but about forum trolls checking Twitter&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zqJnNy"&gt;Earlier this month, a teaser trailer for Hoback’s series &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/28/22304518/hbo-trailer-upcoming-qanon-movie-disinformation-researchers"&gt;drew criticism from anti-disinformation researchers&lt;/a&gt;, who worried it could become a QAnon recruiting tool. The bad news is that &lt;em&gt;Into the Storm&lt;/em&gt; breaks several best practices for reporting on extremism. The good news (I guess?) is that it’s almost so boring it’s unwatchable. Instead of a big-picture overview of QAnon or a meticulous argument for Q’s identity, the series focuses on a handful of feuding message board operators and YouTube (or “QTube”) influencers, documenting them with a combination of formal interviews and interminable slice-of-life scenes. Imagine &lt;em&gt;Tiger King&lt;/em&gt;, but about forum trolls checking each other’s Twitter feeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mYecRd"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Into the Storm&lt;/em&gt; is largely about the operators of 8chan (later relaunched as “8kun”), the anything-goes message board where “Q drops” are posted. Hoback spent years visiting the Philippines to speak with 8chan’s creator Fredrick Brennan; its current owner Jim Watkins; and Watkins’ son Ron, the site’s former administrator. &lt;a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/men-qanon/story?id=73046374"&gt;Brennan has publicly&lt;/a&gt; — and &lt;a href="https://gimletmedia.com/shows/reply-all/llhe5nm"&gt;fairly believably&lt;/a&gt; — &lt;a href="https://www.insider.com/who-is-q-why-people-think-jim-watkins-qanon-8chan-2020-10"&gt;accused the Watkins family&lt;/a&gt; of being potentially behind Q, and Hoback got what appears to be unprecedented access to all of them. For people who study QAnon, gleaning new details from his interviews will be the show’s main draw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oGHnoB"&gt;But &lt;em&gt;Into the Storm&lt;/em&gt; is too aimless to make that access compelling. After the first episode, it becomes mostly a documentary about 8chan in general, including a bitter feud between Brennan and the Watkins family fueled by 8chan’s role in several far-right mass shootings. While some of its subjects claim they’re apolitical, they’re enmeshed in right-wing politics, prone to supposedly ironic bigotry, and extremely cavalier about racist violence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Nvab0M"&gt;&lt;q&gt;‘Into the Storm’ takes an approach anti-extremism researchers have warned against&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="m5LXed"&gt;The series halfheartedly gestures at how these events tie into larger right-wing politics, including the Watkins’ interactions with QTubers. But huge chunks are devoted to Hoback just hanging out with the trio — covering their blow-by-blow interpersonal drama, lobbing softball questions about 8chan’s many controversies, and letting them pontificate about free speech and their favorite hobbies. The series could be hours shorter if it cut supposedly entertaining scenes like Jim Watkins making fart noises with his hands or explaining how to fill a fountain pen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zF7d2F"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Into the Storm&lt;/em&gt; is seemingly trying to make QAnon’s best-known players look absurd. Taking that outcome for granted, Hoback barely bothers to rebut their statements or offer outside context, a tactic researchers have spent years discouraging. What some viewers might see as crassness or a bad argument, others could easily buy as charming foibles or a rhetorical triumph. And compared with extremism documentaries &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/14/17113514/alt-right-age-of-rage-antifa-film-review-sxsw-2018"&gt;like &lt;em&gt;Alt-Right: Age of Rage&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Into the Storm&lt;/em&gt; barely acknowledges that there are forces taking QAnon seriously and trying to counter it — or at least &lt;a href="https://www.dailydot.com/debug/reddit-qanon-casualties/"&gt;providing support&lt;/a&gt; for the people it’s hurt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LDE3Zh"&gt;The approach also makes Hoback’s hunt for Q seem bizarrely ineffectual. &lt;em&gt;Into the Storm&lt;/em&gt; implies that if you just talk to a bunch of internet trolls for long enough, they’ll slip up and reveal their secrets. So the series’s visible research basically involves training a camera on people who are known to enjoy tricking and manipulating journalists, then asking if they’re Q.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="dXaszg"&gt;&lt;q&gt;QAnon is, at its core, a grift&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="L3Fmbe"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Into the Storm&lt;/em&gt; touches on one compelling thesis: QAnon is, at its core, a grift. Jim and Ron Watkins admit QAnon is the only thing keeping 8kun afloat, and they have a huge incentive to keep Q on the platform. QTubers seem to truly believe some Q claims, but they also describe being enticed by how QAnon boosted their traffic. Hoback outlines how the theory spread from an obscure forum post through a right-wing influence machine, including former Trump officials like Michael Flynn and prominent media figures like Alex Jones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qMjdsO"&gt;But in addition to being padded by hours of 8chan drama, this is all wrapped in a needlessly conspiratorial framing. The series ominously emphasizes officials’ military ties or their links to “psyop” research, when all that often seems necessary is a good handle on viral marketing. It seems remarkably willing to buy subjects’ self-aggrandizing stories, so when a detail &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; seem weird and alarming, it’s hard to separate that from the hype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9AIUaI"&gt;Hoback touts a big reveal about Q’s identity, or at least the name of one person who has allegedly operated the account. His claim echoes a fairly well-known theory about QAnon, and it’s based on parsing some cagey and noncommittal statements by an interview subject. For the reasons mentioned above, &lt;em&gt;Into the Storm&lt;/em&gt; makes it incredibly hard to evaluate this big reveal — because there’s little to indicate that, say, the subject hasn’t just been messing with him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="oZwFDY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Does exposing Q actually matter?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sThwxr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Into the Storm&lt;/em&gt; also elides a major issue: exposing Q probably wouldn’t stop QAnon. The movement appeals to long-standing mistrust of powerful institutions, and it’s notoriously resistant to fact-checking or debunking. Since Q’s original posts, it’s insinuated itself into &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2020/08/21/904798097/how-qanon-conspiracy-is-spreading-in-christian-communities-across-the-u-s"&gt;Christian churches&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/09/28/technology/save-the-children-qanon.html"&gt;anti-sex trafficking campaigns&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-55957298"&gt;wellness communities&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/93wq73/conspirituality-explains-why-the-wellness-world-fell-for-qanon"&gt;New Age spirituality&lt;/a&gt;, sometimes in ways that don’t even reference Q as a person. The people &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/election-us-2020-55090145"&gt;promoting QAnon ideas&lt;/a&gt; aren’t hidden in the shadows; they’ve been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266731/smartmatic-fox-news-lawsuit-rudy-giuliani-defamation-election-disinformation"&gt;speaking on Fox News&lt;/a&gt; and other right-wing networks, while Q goes months without posting. The series references all this — but only as a quick recap of other reporters’ work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zYFmcN"&gt;Grasping for a master manipulator sounds like a compelling idea. But if &lt;em&gt;Into the Storm&lt;/em&gt; is any indication, it’s far less interesting than the mundane structures that made QAnon so popular. (Also, a &lt;em&gt;six-hour series&lt;/em&gt; should have room to delve into both.) As a documentary about pro-Trump online extremism, Hoback’s work is adjacent to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/5/21113587/pepe-frog-feels-good-man-matt-furie-trolling-documentary-review-sundance-2020"&gt;last year’s film &lt;em&gt;Feels Good Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;which used the Pepe cartoon frog meme to incisively chronicle modern politics’ chaotic weirdness. By contrast, &lt;em&gt;Into the Storm&lt;/em&gt; simply tries to answer a false conspiracy by finding a true one — subjecting viewers to some of the world’s dullest political crusaders along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4zRKYY"&gt;Q: Into the Storm&lt;em&gt; premieres March 21st on HBO and HBO Max.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22330129/hbo-qanon-documentary-q-into-the-storm-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22330129/hbo-qanon-documentary-q-into-the-storm-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T13:13:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T13:13:44-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft’s Xbox Wireless Headset is a mic-drop moment</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;The best budget-friendly headset for Xbox cuts very few corners&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="18Tu1w"&gt;Microsoft’s new $99 Xbox Wireless headset isn’t perfect, but it’s the best attempt at being an Xbox gaming headset and an everyday set of wireless headphones I’ve tried yet. It’s compatible with the Xbox Wireless protocol, making it easy to pair with any Xbox One or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21548987/xbox-series-x-review"&gt;Xbox Series X&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549021/xbox-series-s-review"&gt;S&lt;/a&gt; console. It’s also compatible with Bluetooth (version 4.2, SBC codec), and better yet, it can connect through both protocols simultaneously. So you can take a call or have audio from any app come through from a phone, tablet, or a PC mixed in with the sound coming from your Xbox console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pym0p3"&gt;This is far from the first gaming headset to do this, or even do it well. Microsoft’s latest headset just stands out as being particularly impressive for the number of things it gets right for $99. Its design is stellar, a logical fit in the company’s headphone lineup. Next to the Series X, it looks the part with a touch of glossy green detailing around the ear cup dials, covered in matte black plastic. The little holes in the recessed areas between the faux leather ear pads and the dials seem to be there just for cosmetic reasons, but it looks fantastic nevertheless. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="roexZK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10387161"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DS9nuI"&gt;Crucially, these are comfortable, even though my head size nearly pushes them to their size limits. The sidearms require two hands to make adjustments, which I like. There’s no worry that they’ll resize just from being moved around. And while I wish this model had a bungee-style headband and swiveling ear cups like most SteelSeries headsets, not having these features didn’t equate to comfort issues here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S24wqX"&gt;In addition to how the headset looks, its functionality is similar to the Surface Headphones, with twistable dials on the outside of each ear cup for adjusting elements of the audio. Unlike the company’s more premium headphones, there’s no active noise cancellation here (I’d complain, but they’re $99), though the passive noise isolation is better than average for this price. The left dial acts as a chat and game audio mixer, so you can tune your playmates down a bit during a dialogue-heavy cutscene or vice versa. I appreciate that Microsoft put it front and center. On the other dial is the volume control. Twist to increase or decrease, nice and simple — no buttons necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Xbox Wireless headset" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EROyPAjGtRSmBN7ajrHrigTdHDM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363677/cfaulkner_210311_4469_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The green button pulls double duty, serving as the pairing and power button.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Xbox Wireless headset" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rR2bCiXK85_7eHXSsFkqe3vX1XM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363685/cfaulkner_210311_4469_0009.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s an LED on the mic facing your, well, face, indicating when the mic is active.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JOKh5H"&gt;Over on the right ear cup, there’s a USB-C port for charging. Microsoft includes a USB-C to USB Type-A cable to charge it, but you’ll get all of the same headset features if you plug into a Windows 10 machine with your own USB-C to USB-C cable. That’s not the case when plugged into a MacBook Pro, which won’t work over a wired connection with the headset. You can still connect to a macOS device and use the headset over Bluetooth, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="x8eeqr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best wired or wireless gaming headsets to buy","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21549510/best-gaming-headset-wired-wireless-features-specs-price-sound-microphone-test-buy"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="ZDpKTn"&gt;There are only two buttons on the headset: one to manually mute the bendable microphone (an LED on the inner section of the boom microphone angled toward your face is illuminated when the mic is hot), and another that serves as the all-in-one pairing and power button, both of which reside on the left ear cup. Most gaming headsets require days of continued use to fully learn their respective button layouts, but this one’s dead simple. I would have taken one more button if it served as a multifunction button to control my device over Bluetooth, but Microsoft has limited the headset to just two buttons. There’s no way to independently control, say, a phone outside of just adjusting the volume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5DQuG3"&gt;The sound performance from this headset is better than I expected. During my tests, I listened to Spotify, and the music sounded good enough to stick with this headset instead of automatically reaching for my Sony 1000XM3s. People with a knack for stellar audio quality will find quibbles, like that the sound can come off as muddled at times, and the soundstage isn’t as expansive as you’d find in a more expensive set of headphones. But again, these are $99 and meant for gaming first. And for that price, I’m pleased. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Xbox Wireless headset" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sBzN4vGCvi7BGhEN7LcMNTAb2BA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363680/cfaulkner_210311_4469_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Both rotating ear cups have instructions that are simple to digest.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Xbox Wireless headset" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GY3ej0-CJ8y6kU-hFgduDuUtJE8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363679/cfaulkner_210311_4469_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;These charge via USB-C, and they also work wired via USB-C to a Windows 10 PC.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0H4eYZ"&gt;Hopping over to gaming, I instantly booted up &lt;em&gt;Doom (2016)&lt;/em&gt; on the Series X. The soundtrack and all of the various hellish sound effects have an adequate amount of crunch and punch, and I was head-banging to the music while I played. It sounded as it was intended to sound, though, again, the same nitpicks apply here as they do for music. When there’s a lot happening in the mid and high frequencies, the sound can lack clarity if you’re listening closely. I didn’t notice that as much in &lt;em&gt;Yakuza: Like a Dragon&lt;/em&gt;, for instance. This headset works with the Dolby Atmos (Microsoft is giving buyers a trial of Dolby Atmos with purchase that will last until the end of September) and DTS: X paid apps available for Xbox and PC, which might enhance the sound. But for the purposes of this review, I tested just the out-of-the-box experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WPZibO"&gt;The battery life and range are competitive with other gaming headsets I’ve tested in this price range. Microsoft claims 15 hours per charge, and both times I ran the non-replaceable battery down during testing, it lasted for about that long. I was able to roam about my studio apartment, straying about 25 feet or so from the Xbox without experiencing any drop-outs. It started cutting out when the signal had to go through multiple walls, but that’s to be expected. As for charge speeds, Microsoft says it can gain four hours of use out of a 30-minute charge, or a full charge in three hours. In case you were wondering, you can use the Xbox Wireless headset while it’s being charged, but obviously, it’ll then take longer to recharge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Xbox Wireless headset" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/63xjlEdwqD8mjoxazoDqKAxAb9s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363684/cfaulkner_210311_4469_0008.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The polyurethane leather-covered pads are comfortable and deliver good noise isolation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Xbox Wireless headset" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bcvxJXSwhCMLDRLEHUuKJNtdXCw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363678/cfaulkner_210311_4469_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A closer look at the left ear cup shows the instructions for the chat / game audio mixer and the pairing button.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="j7JrXM"&gt;To give you a sense of how this headset handles connections, I first paired the Xbox Wireless headset to my PC with Microsoft’s &lt;a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/633495/10014?prodsku=6253924&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fmicrosoft-xbox-wireless-adapter-for-windows-10-black%2F6253924.p%3FskuId%3D6253924&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;USB Wireless Adapter&lt;/a&gt; (not included with this headset, but it operates on the same Xbox Wireless protocol as the consoles) for music and to take some video calls. Pairing the headset required pressing and holding the pair button for four seconds and doing the same to the Wireless Adapter. To use them on the Xbox Series X, I had to run through the same process. Frustratingly, the headset can’t handle juggling between two previously paired devices that use the Xbox Wireless protocol, so I had to manually re-pair it when I wanted to hop between my PC and the Xbox. I don’t want to overblow this issue, though. Microsoft’s pairing process for Xbox accessories is very simple. This won’t be a problem at all if you connect to your PC via Bluetooth (as I imagine most people will) since the headset can connect to both concurrently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GelArV"&gt;If you’re someone who’s likely to lean heavily on the concurrent wireless connection feature, I like that this headset automatically lowers the audio streaming from the Xbox Wireless protocol device when a call is incoming so you can hear it. You can adjust the volume of just your Bluetooth device with its own controls, but not from the headset itself. Cranking the volume with the dial makes it louder for both devices you’re connected to.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/O-v7S22yTaHIXYd7Bvr3MNtHJ6k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363752/xboxconfigureheadset.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Xbox Accessories app on PC and Xbox lets you fine-tune adjustments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="8dvEqO"&gt;The level of customization this headset allows is also impressive for the price. Through the Xbox Accessories app for Windows 10 or Xbox, you can adjust the equalizer (movie, music, game, heavy bass, and speech are the presets, or make your own) and boost the bass. Additionally, there’s an auto-mute feature that can mute noises happening in your surroundings. There are three levels (low, medium, and high), and Microsoft says each step up will increase how aggressively the mic mutes things that aren’t your voice. During a video call, it seemed to work as intended, if not better than I expected. The person on the other end said that my speech wasn’t getting cut off, which is something that can happen with these kinds of features, and that happenings in the background weren’t noticeable. Of course, the effectiveness of this auto-mute feature can vary depending on your household situation. If you’re skeptical, it’s easy enough to just tap the mute button to avoid potential embarrassment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TvmKPc"&gt;Two other small but cool features in the Xbox Accessories app let you tweak how bright the mute light is, making it easier to see in your peripheral vision. You can also customize the level of mic monitoring or how much outside sound is fed through the mics and then funneled into your ears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Uf3qSh"&gt;Up until now, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/5/21545683/razer-kaira-pro-xbox-wireless-gaming-headset-series-x-s-one-pc-microsoft-usb-c"&gt;$150 Razer Kaira Pro&lt;/a&gt; was the Xbox-specific headset I told people to get because it’s comfortable, and it supports Bluetooth in addition to the Xbox Wireless protocol. Microsoft’s new Xbox Wireless headset is well ahead of that model in terms of design, ease of use, and functionality — all in a more affordable package. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7Ns40bYUPWPFJ4BkU9iA5JBW-x0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363686/cfaulkner_210311_4469_00010.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If it fits my head and can also fit around the Series X, it should fit you fine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="WgEl04"&gt;If Microsoft is to be judged compared to Sony on how well it designed a headset to accompany its latest consoles — as it inevitably will be — this one handily edges out the Pulse 3D even though they’re the same price. Sony’s model is comfortable and looks equally dashing next to the console it was made for, and it has a 3.5mm headphone jack and 3D Audio support in its court. But it’s tough to compete with the Bluetooth support and button-lite design built into Microsoft’s model. I would have loved it if a USB dongle was included for more support with devices, like the Nintendo Switch. But by design, it can’t connect to other gaming consoles. Microsoft is keeping this one in the family. If you’re in the family, though, you’re in for a treat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q0gB5f"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2wLXRQ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction: The Xbox Wireless headset can get four hours of use from a 30-minute charge. This review incorrectly stated that a 15-minute charge could get you three hours of use. We regret this error.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22325883/microsoft-xbox-wireless-headset-gaming-series-x-s-pc-windows-10-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22325883/microsoft-xbox-wireless-headset-gaming-series-x-s-pc-windows-10-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T12:50:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T12:50:44-04:00</updated>
    <title>The trailer for Netflix’s The Irregulars paints a supernatural picture of Sherlock Holmes’ London</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/F4mq-5uBLtSR6ps0_S9ammeq2ok=/240x0:1500x840/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68968736/irregulars.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lTE5MAGpflw&amp;amp;t=1s&amp;amp;ab_channel=Netflix" target="_blank"&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3sas8A"&gt;After dropping an ominous teaser for it in February, Netflix has now released a full trailer for its upcoming series &lt;em&gt;The Irregulars&lt;/em&gt;. It’s part of the streaming channel’s Sherlock Holmes cinematic universe (no that’s not a thing, but it could be!) after last year’s charming &lt;em&gt;Enola Holmes&lt;/em&gt; series, which told the story of Sherlock’s younger sister, based on the novels by Nancy Springer (although Arthur Conan Doyle’s estate has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/25/21302942/netflix-enola-holmes-sherlock-arthur-conan-doyle-estate-lawsuit-copyright-infringement"&gt;sued Netflix&lt;/a&gt; for that series’ portrayal of Sherlock as too emotional).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vtxbdI"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Irregulars&lt;/em&gt; is loosely based on the street urchin gang called the Baker Street Irregulars, who appeared in several of Arthur Conan Doyle’s &lt;em&gt;Sherlock Holmes&lt;/em&gt; stories. In the books, the Irregulars are sort of like confidential informants for Holmes and Dr. Watson, giving them info from the streets and helping them solve cases in Victorian London. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QmspGU"&gt;The Netflix production, however, casts Sherlock and his sidekick in a decidedly sinister light. It also puts the supernatural elements that typically lurk around the edges of Holmes stories front and center, with Jessie (Darci Shaw), a girl who “can see things normal people cannot,” like perhaps dead people, and something called a “Rip” (capital R, says the closed captioning) in “the barrier between our world and the next,” which sounds very not good. The Irregulars — Jessie, Bea (Thaddea Graham), Billy (Jojo Macari), Spike (McKell David), and Leo (Harrison Osterfield) — have to close the Rip, or everyone’s doomed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ucQjrp"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lTE5MAGpflw?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=1&amp;amp;start=1" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="q0jBTa"&gt;The series director is Tom Bidwell, who has &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/blogs/writersroom/entries/3f5c208a-d2f4-4a14-9e55-a6a05c9c2ddc"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; this project has been a dream of his for more than a decade. Judging by the trailer, Sherlock (Henry Lloyd-Hughes) himself is a minor character — he only appears in five of the series’ eight episodes — and Dr. Watson (Royce Pierreson) as a baddie is a fun twist. &lt;em&gt;The Irregulars&lt;/em&gt; debuts on Netflix March 26th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eXZFWq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331604/netflix-the-irregulars-sherlock-holmes-watson"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331604/netflix-the-irregulars-sherlock-holmes-watson</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T12:50:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T12:50:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>Some Bethesda games now on Xbox Game Pass get frame rate boosts on Xbox Series X / S</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Xbox logo (a white sphere with an X through it) against a dark green background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4FQiXBZhmiC2FLvEWKeMGoiAaPA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68958201/acastro_190530_1777_xbox_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Ea9XbM"&gt;Microsoft’s Xbox Game Pass platform received a huge boost with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22325044/microsoft-xbox-game-pass-bethesda-games-list"&gt;addition of 20 new Bethesda Softworks titles&lt;/a&gt; across Xbox consoles, PC, and xCloud last week. And now, a quarter of those games are getting performance boosts on the next-gen Xbox consoles in a new update. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="89aA1D"&gt;The performance gains are in frame rate, thanks to an appropriately named &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287001/microsoft-xbox-series-x-s-fps-boost-feature-games"&gt;new feature Microsoft revealed last month called FPS Boost&lt;/a&gt;, which can roughly double frame rates of older games using new Xbox hardware without requiring developers to do any manual work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tqMm8P"&gt;The games seeing performance boosts with frame rate jumps up to 60 frames per second include Arkane Studios’ &lt;em&gt;Dishonored: Definitive Edition &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Prey&lt;/em&gt; and Bethesda Game Studios’ &lt;em&gt;The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim Special Edition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Fallout 4&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Fallout 76. &lt;/em&gt;Microsoft &lt;a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2021/03/15/five-legendary-bethesda-titles-get-fps-boost/"&gt;announced on March 15th&lt;/a&gt; that the updates are going out that day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WCgbG4"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SzJxrUXnadU?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=881&amp;amp;start=881" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zUXwqW"&gt;The announcement was initially made during a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SzJxrUXnadU&amp;amp;t=881s"&gt;YouTube live stream on March 12th&lt;/a&gt; between Xbox Live programming director Larry Hryb (aka “Major Nelson”) and comms chief Jeff Rubenstein, in which Rubenstein discussed the benefits the new Xbox Series X / S can bring to older Bethesda titles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J8Wqi9"&gt;Microsoft said in its announcement last week that “a handful of these games will also benefit from FPS Boost on Xbox Series X / S,” though it did not specify which at the time. it also said 16 of the 20 Bethesda games coming to Xbox Game Pass would be available across PC and xCloud in addition to Xbox consoles. You can find a list of which platforms which games are available &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22325044/microsoft-xbox-game-pass-bethesda-games-list"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pWpne8"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 15th, 12:50PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added information from a blog post Microsoft published on Monday indicating the updates would be pushed live later today. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DYLUdU"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nm44j0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NKWDpM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22328089/microsoft-xbox-series-x-bethesda-frame-rate-boost-game-pass"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22328089/microsoft-xbox-series-x-bethesda-frame-rate-boost-game-pass</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T12:23:27-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T12:23:27-04:00</updated>
    <title>Zoom Escaper lets you sabotage your own meetings with audio problems, crying babies, and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k1Fmn37R3I89uiWWMI0bF6UDXlY=/157x0:1218x707/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68968532/Screen_Shot_2021_03_15_at_3.46.29_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zoom Escaper offers a range of sound effects to help with self-sabotage. &lt;/em&gt; | Image: Zoom Escaper&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="o0XjSE"&gt;Had enough Zoom meetings? Can’t bear another soul-numbing day of sitting on video calls, the only distraction your rapidly aging face, pinned in one corner of the screen like a dying bug? Well, if so, then boy do we have the app for you. Meet &lt;a href="https://zoomescaper.com/"&gt;Zoom Escaper&lt;/a&gt;: a free web widget that lets you add an array of fake audio effects to your next Zoom Call, gifting you with numerous reasons to end the meeting and escape, &lt;em&gt;while you still can&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uERXZE"&gt;You can choose from barking dogs, construction noises, crying babies, or even subtler effects like choppy audio and unwanted echoes. Created by artist &lt;a href="https://lav.io/"&gt;Sam Lavigne&lt;/a&gt;, Zoom Escaper is fantastically simple to use. All you need do is download a free bit of audio software called &lt;a href="https://vb-audio.com/Cable/"&gt;VB-Audio&lt;/a&gt; that routes your audio through the website, then change your audio input in Zoom from your microphone to VB-Audio, and play with the effects. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z4M7I9"&gt;You can watch a video tutorial on how to set up Zoom Escaper and listen to a sample of the various sound effects &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/r_LhwsMAaAc"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wanLdk"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/r_LhwsMAaAc?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2mKEKG"&gt;If you’re running Zoom Escaper, you can’t actually hear the sound effects yourself. But I was able to test the site’s functionality with the help of my colleague, &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; news editor Chaim Gartenberg. Here was his opinion of the various effects Zoom Escaper had to offer: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="wGavb5"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Urination&lt;/strong&gt;: “That sounds very fake. Also, I’m not entirely sure what the plan is to sell this as a reason to leave a call?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="liIg4G"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Construction&lt;/strong&gt;: “This sounds like you literally stood in the middle of a construction site. I think the sounds need to be a bit more muffled to sell it, but it’s very good.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rzRimd"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Man Weeping&lt;/strong&gt;: “Those are the sobs of a broken man. But who’s crying — is it your roommate, your partner?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dZNfLd"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Bad Connection&lt;/strong&gt;: “This one works really well. Your audio is coming through broken up and disrupted. Get off the call.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="gQGijo"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Echo&lt;/strong&gt;: “Extremely annoying and very convincing. This sounds like a busted Zoom connection. If someone I was speaking to had this, I’d tell them to get it fixed. It wouldn’t be feasible to have a meeting with that.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3RFSrC"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Wind&lt;/strong&gt;: “If you were trying to skive off work, I’m not sure how you’d convincingly sell gale force winds in your own office.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yFVFoq"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Dog&lt;/strong&gt;: “That sounds very real. It sounds like a dog barking outside, but maybe not the sort of thing you’d need to take care of?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8eoFu3"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Upset Baby&lt;/strong&gt;: “That baby sounds decently upset! This is definitely something you should go and check on! Go and take care of your baby!”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="m8GvxY"&gt;Our opinion was that Upset Baby provided the most excusable reason to drop a call, but also requires that people believe you &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; a baby. And if you’re prepared to fake the existence of a child in order to get out of Zoom meetings with your co-workers, then perhaps you have bigger issues with work than a few annoying video meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="luDsoT"&gt;Zoom Escaper isn’t the first of Lavigne’s projects to self-inflict computer harm. His 2017 work &lt;a href="https://lav.io/projects/the-good-life-enron-simulator/"&gt;The Good Life&lt;/a&gt; let users sign up to receive 225,000 emails confiscated from Enron during its 2001 implosion, while 2016’s &lt;a href="https://lav.io/projects/slow-hot-computer/"&gt;Slow Hot Computer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;is a website that... makes your computer run slow and hot. “Use it at work to decrease your productivity,” says Lavigne.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zDWWa4"&gt;If Zoom Escaper isn’t direct enough for you, there’s also &lt;a href="https://lav.io/projects/zoom-deleter/"&gt;Zoom Deleter&lt;/a&gt;, another of Lavigne’s creations. As he writes on his website, this is just a small program that runs in your menu bar or system tray: “It continually checks for the presence of Zoom on your computer, and if found, immediately deletes it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g01252"&gt;Speaking to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, Lavigne describes the underlying ethos of his art as: “Deliberate slowdown, reducing productivity and output, self-sabotage, etc.” When asked by &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;why these values were important to him, Lavigne did not respond. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331744/zoom-escaper-sabotage-meetings-fake-audio-problems"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331744/zoom-escaper-sabotage-meetings-fake-audio-problems</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T12:16:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T12:16:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>Some new GM trucks will pollute more thanks to microchip shortage </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="General Motors Vehicles At A Car Dealership Ahead Of Earnings Figures" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/O8nKAyVLovHVZ6kP-9ErFiA6IsI=/0x1:4000x2668/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68968464/1231061209.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MFuvX4"&gt;General Motors has decided to make some 2021 full-size pickups without a certain fuel management module because of the ongoing microchip shortage. As a result, those trucks will get around one fewer mile per gallon of gas, meaning they’ll burn more fuel to go the same distance, releasing more carbon emissions into the atmosphere. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oKU8NJ"&gt;The trucks affected are models that use GM’s 5.3-liter EcoTec3 V8 engine (including versions with six-speed or eight-speed automatic transmissions), according to &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;, which &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-gm-semiconductors/gm-builds-some-2021-pickups-without-certain-modules-due-to-global-chip-shortage-idUSKBN2B71P5"&gt;first reported the decision&lt;/a&gt;. That includes the popular Chevy Silverado and GMC’s Sierra. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dk5Xfy"&gt;The module is what powers the trademarked “Active Fuel Management” or “Dynamic Fuel Management” systems GM promotes on these trucks, which deactivates some of the engine’s cylinders to boost fuel economy. A company spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; that the decision would affect GM’s fleet-wide average fuel economy, but that it wouldn’t be a “major impact.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bumli7"&gt;GM decided to make the trucks without the fuel module so as not to affect production. Ford previously announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266483/ford-f150-production-slowdown-semiconductor-chip-shortage"&gt;it was briefly reducing output of its ultra-popular F-150 pickup&lt;/a&gt; as a result of the chip shortage. Automakers are dealing with a dearth of semiconductors in part because they originally lowered their forecasts of how many they’d need when sales first took a hit last year during the early stages of the pandemic. A spike in demand for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278431/biden-administration-global-semiconductor-chip-shortage-executive-order"&gt;consumer electronics only upped the scarcity&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331766/gm-pickups-semiconductor-shortage-fuel-economy-emissions"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331766/gm-pickups-semiconductor-shortage-fuel-economy-emissions</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T12:15:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T12:15:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitch and Facebook Gaming exploded during the pandemic — and they’re even bigger a year later</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M2n8nt8vg6n-tsRBhdHG4BRhtbE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68968458/acastro_210115_1777_twitch_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="r9m5uw"&gt;Today, StreamElements and its partner, analytics company Rainmaker.gg, have put out the February issue of their “State of the Stream” report. It’s something of a fascinating document because, as the end of the pandemic draws near, it’s another piece of evidence that live-streaming platforms were one of the winners of the crisis. (You know, assuming there can be winners to a global mass death event.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lXU8bj"&gt;The biggest finding in this month’s report is that, in terms of hours watched, both Twitch and Facebook Gaming are up around 80 percent year over year. To be slightly more specific: Twitch has grown by 82 percent, while Facebook Gaming grew by 79 percent. For Twitch, that translates to more than 1.8 billion hours of watch time in February; Facebook Gaming, on the other hand, cleared 400 million hours. (For reference: in March 2020, as the pandemic was beginning, Twitch cleared 1.1 billion watch hours. And last April, Facebook Gaming had crossed 291 million hours watched.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l9EQ5J"&gt;Those numbers are both massive and, I think, durable: both figures are actually a decrease from January, which was a longer month. To me, that suggests that the total number of people who watch live streams has materially increased over the course of the global coronavirus pandemic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iOcXxK"&gt;That said: those numbers don’t reflect the ongoing vaccine rollout — which, in the US, has only recently started ramping up exponentially. I’ll be interested to see if the numbers go down as the world returns to some semblance of normalcy. Even if they do, this hellish season of our lives &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; pulled live-streaming as a practice firmly into the mainstream. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331623/twitch-facebook-gaming-pandemic-hours-watched"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331623/twitch-facebook-gaming-pandemic-hours-watched</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bijan Stephen</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T12:06:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T12:06:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>People aren’t missing their second COVID-19 vaccine dose, CDC data says</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-HEALTH-VIRUS-VACCINE" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ENGF95RLZTyZL-dg2PDUVgCjrho=/0x65:5284x3588/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68968384/1231700282.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Andrew Caballero-Reynolds / AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="beB7vy"&gt;Nearly everyone who got their first dose of a two-shot COVID-19 vaccine got their second dose within the recommended window, according to &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/70/wr/mm7011e2.htm?s_cid=mm7011e2_e&amp;amp;ACSTrackingID=USCDC_921-DM51989&amp;amp;ACSTrackingLabel=MMWR%20Early%20Release%20-%20Vol.%2070%2C%20March%2015%2C%202021&amp;amp;deliveryName=USCDC_921-DM51989"&gt;new data&lt;/a&gt; from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HOoAbx"&gt;During the first two months of the United States COVID-19 vaccination campaign, around 12 million people got their first dose and were also scheduled for their second dose. The second dose is supposed to be given three weeks after the first for the Pfizer / BioNTech vaccine and four weeks for the Moderna vaccine (with a few days’ buffer on each side). In that group, 88 percent of people had their second shot on schedule. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SCqsHn"&gt;Around 9 percent of people who had their first shot between December 14th and February 14th had not yet received their second dose but were still within 42 days from their first dose. The CDC says that when a delay is unavoidable, people can wait that long. Three percent of people were outside of the 42-day window and had missed the dose. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="379OT5"&gt;To look at those numbers in a different way, the CDC also looked at everyone who’d received a &lt;em&gt;second&lt;/em&gt; dose during those two months to see how many people received it within the recommended period. Over 95 percent of people were on schedule. Just under 3 percent of people were late (but within the 42-day window), and 1.5 percent of people had their second injection early. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="7wwh7f"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Over 95 percent of people were on schedule&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uUDySe"&gt;Such high numbers of people getting their second dose — and getting it on time — are reassuring, the CDC wrote in its report. The Pfizer / BioNTech and Moderna vaccines may have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163146/covid-vaccine-fda-review-safe-effective-time-pfizer-biontech"&gt;some protection&lt;/a&gt; with just one dose, but a single dose wasn’t part of the clinical trials, and it’s not clear how long that protection might last. The second shot &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/20/21587664/pfizer-moderna-covid-19-coronavirus-vaccine-two-doses-shots"&gt;boosts the immune system&lt;/a&gt; and gives people the full benefits of the vaccines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bGFiTt"&gt;When the COVID-19 vaccines were developed and authorized, experts worried about the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/4/22153908/covid-vaccine-dose-tracking-digital-registry-fda"&gt;challenges&lt;/a&gt; of a two-shot series. They were concerned they would struggle to bring people back in for a second shot. In other multidose vaccines, like the HPV vaccine and the shingles vaccine, there’s &lt;a href="https://www.kff.org/coronavirus-covid-19/issue-brief/what-does-a-multi-dose-series-mean-for-the-covid-19-vaccination-effort/"&gt;a drop-off&lt;/a&gt;. Around a quarter of people who get their first shingles shot don’t get a second, and only around half of people finish a three-shot HPV vaccine series. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aDrKfM"&gt;Despite the low numbers of people missing a second dose, CDC director Rochelle Walensky said the agency is still hoping to close even the small gap. “CDC is working across the government and with state and local partners to identify and address barriers to getting both doses,” she said during a press briefing today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K9ZMnN"&gt;States and health organizations have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/4/22153908/covid-vaccine-dose-tracking-digital-registry-fda"&gt;high- and low-tech strategies&lt;/a&gt; to get people back in for the correct second dose. Many central state immunization registries can notify doctors and patients when people are due for a second dose. So can electronic health records. Everyone who gets a COVID-19 vaccine also gets a card that tells them when their second dose should be, and which vaccine they got. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aTvA7G"&gt;The CDC data shows that those methods seem to be working. It’s consistent with anecdotal reports from immunizers. “I am not hearing major challenges with bringing people back in,” Claire Hannan, the executive director of the Association of Immunization Managers, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;in February. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TzAmvQ"&gt;However, the CDC noted in its report that most people who received the COVID-19 vaccine during the first two months they were available were health care workers and residents in long-term care facilities because they were the first to be eligible. Those groups may be more likely to stick to the schedule because they could get vaccinated where they work or live. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jJT3Bh"&gt;The CDC report also says that 90,484 people got the first dose of one vaccine and the second dose of another — 0.2 percent of the total. The agency &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/vaccines/covid-19/info-by-product/clinical-considerations.html"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; the Pfizer / BioNTech and Moderna vaccines should not be mixed except in the most exceptional circumstances when a second dose of the same brand is not available. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h44ltA"&gt;Over &lt;a href="https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/#vaccinations"&gt;37 million people&lt;/a&gt; in the United States are now fully vaccinated, either through two doses of the Pfizer / BioNTech or Moderna vaccine or one dose of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/5/22315138/covid-vaccine-single-shot-johnson-distribution"&gt;Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson vaccine&lt;/a&gt;, which only takes one shot. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331619/covid-vaccine-second-dose-cdc"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331619/covid-vaccine-second-dose-cdc</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T12:05:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T12:05:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>Cruise acquires Voyage in another autonomous vehicle merger</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/X9G40bFen5UdxbHqSVMsVZFlDoM=/319x0:3777x2305/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68968378/Ewh6OQ3UcAAUIjy.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PfPYz0"&gt;Cruise, a majority-owned subsidiary of General Motors, will acquire self-driving startup Voyage in another major autonomous vehicle merger. The announcement came less than a week after news first surfaced that the two companies were in talks about an acquisition. The terms of the deal were not disclosed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4F2u5v"&gt;Cruise mainly operates its autonomous vehicles in dense, urban settings like downtown San Francisco, while Voyage oversees a fleet of low-speed autonomous vehicles providing trips to residents of several &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/10/16874410/voyage-self-driving-cars-villages-florida-retirement-communities"&gt;retirement communities&lt;/a&gt;. Both companies have tested their vehicles without a safety driver behind the wheel and aspire to launch full-fledged commercial robot taxi services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="5NMOjP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The self-driving industry is consolidating”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ysUpK1"&gt;“The self-driving industry is consolidating, and the leaders of a trillion-dollar market are fast emerging,” Voyage CEO Oliver Cameron said &lt;a href="https://news.voyage.auto/voyage-acquired-by-cruise-d5f76011032f"&gt;in a statement&lt;/a&gt;. “After being intimately involved with the AV industry for the last five years, I can say with certainty that Cruise — with its advanced self-driving technology, unique auto-maker partnerships, and all-electric purpose-built vehicle with no human controls — is poised to be &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; clear leader.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ON1hzq"&gt;Voyage is a spinoff from Udacity, an online learning service that offers courses in driverless technology. Cameron headed the startup’s open-source self-driving project before launching his own venture. Sebastian Thrun, Udacity’s chairman and one of the founders of Google’s self-driving car project, was briefly chairman of Voyage before a conflict forced him to step down. The company operates a fleet of self-driving cars in two retirement communities, one near San Jose, California, and the other north of Orlando, Florida, both called The Villages. But Voyage doesn’t want to be seen as the exclusive AV service for senior citizens. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NWO6IB"&gt;“I think sometimes people think Voyage is all about just low speed, zero to 25 mile-an-hour autonomy,” Cameron said in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/12/20862659/voyage-self-driving-startup-funding-oliver-cameron"&gt;an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;in 2019&lt;/a&gt;. “We’re not. We’re going to expand our capabilities over time, to zero to 35 [mph], to zero to 55 [mph], to zero to 65 [mph]. And one day we’ll connect all the roadways in the US with a Level 4 self-driving car. But we’re not going to say that’ll be delivered next year. And we’re not going to wait to build a business before that’s ready.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Rdm8U5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I think sometimes people think Voyage is all about just low speed, zero to 25 mile-an-hour autonomy”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="F1TYLI"&gt;Cruise is certainly one of the best capitalized autonomous vehicle companies in the world. In 2018, it secured both a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/31/17412716/gm-cruise-self-driving-car-softbank-investment"&gt;$2.25 billion investment from the SoftBank&lt;/a&gt; Vision Fund and a $2 billion investment from Honda. In 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/7/18535194/gm-cruise-self-driving-car-investment-valuation"&gt;Cruise landed a $1.15 billion investment&lt;/a&gt; from GM, SoftBank, Honda, and T. Rowe Price Group, which put the company’s valuation at $19 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HNEUhy"&gt;There have been a rash of mergers in the world of autonomous vehicles over the past few years: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/26/21304111/amazon-zoox-acquisition-self-driving-car-autonomous-vehicles-startup-robotaxi-bi-directional-vehicle"&gt;Amazon acquired Zoox&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/7/22158745/uber-selling-autonomous-vehicle-business-aurora-innovation"&gt;Aurora absorbed Uber’s autonomous vehicle division&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/25/18758820/drive-ai-self-driving-startup-shutting-down-apple"&gt;Apple bought distressed startup Drive.ai&lt;/a&gt; and was (at one point) considering a tie-up with Hyundai; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/13/14906304/intel-mobileye-acquisition-self-driving-cars"&gt;Intel bought Mobileye&lt;/a&gt;; and Delphi acquired nuTonomy and became Aptiv, which then joined with Hyundai to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/11/21362322/hyundai-aptiv-motional-autonomous-vehicle-joint-venture"&gt;become Motional&lt;/a&gt;. The AV industry has gotten smaller as target dates for mass adoption of autonomous vehicles gets further away. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ENHHrR"&gt;Cruise recently began testing its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22165597/cruise-driverless-test-san-francisco-self-driving-level-4"&gt;fully driverless vehicles in San Francisco&lt;/a&gt; for the first time, but the company still doesn’t allow non-employees to ride in its vehicles. Cruise had planned to launch a commercial taxi service in 2019 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/24/20707242/cruise-gm-self-driving-taxi-launch-delay-2019"&gt;but failed to do so&lt;/a&gt;, and it has yet to publicly commit to a new date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3z0Tjz"&gt;Last year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/21/21075977/cruise-driverless-car-gm-no-steering-wheel-pedals-ev-exclusive-first-look"&gt;Cruise unveiled the Cruise Origin&lt;/a&gt;, a fully driverless prototype vehicle without a steering wheel, pedals, or any controls typically associated with human driving. The vehicle, which will go into production at &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/16/21519358/gm-factory-zero-detroit-hamtramck-electric-autonomous-vehicles"&gt;GM’s Detroit-Hamtramck plant&lt;/a&gt;, is built to be shared by multiple passengers — though it remains to be seen how much appetite there is for shared vehicles in a post-COVID world. Cruise recently unveiled a new set of safety protocols intended to keep people socially distant during trips and the vehicle sanitized between fares.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331794/cruise-acquires-voyage-self-driving-car-merger"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331794/cruise-acquires-voyage-self-driving-car-merger</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T11:15:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T11:15:52-04:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the biggest announcements from Volkswagen’s battery event</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NtNDNts9qhH3ZXNNba-ifqK4fDM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68967900/akrales_200915_4161_0071.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="L5DmnU"&gt;Volkswagen Group unveiled a massive push to drive down the cost of producing batteries for its electric vehicles in the hopes of speeding the transition away from gas-powered cars. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NEZVvc"&gt;The automaker, which is the second largest in the world based on sales, said it would reduce the costs of producing its batteries by up to 50 percent, build multiple battery factories around the world, expand its network of charging stations, and eventually transition to solid-state technology that would cut costs and boost efficiency. The ultimate goal is to make electric cars with longer ranges and quicker charging times — two of the biggest barriers to mass EV adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TzXehC"&gt;The race for huge improvements in battery technology is one of the most expensive and hotly contested on the planet right now. Practically every automaker is betting that electric vehicles will be the future, with some of the largest countries (and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/23/21452825/california-ban-combustion-gas-vehicles-cars-2035"&gt;largest auto markets&lt;/a&gt;) in the world moving to phase out gas-powered cars and trucks. To ensure that shift, batteries need to be more powerful, last longer, and be cheaper to make in order to entice enough customers to make the switch from gas to electric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oG2jgp"&gt;“Our transformation will be fast, it will be unprecedented,” said VW Group CEO Herbert Diess. “The transformation will be bigger than anything the industry has seen in the last century.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="tqjWS3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Our transformation will be fast, it will be unprecedented”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6tMMeV"&gt;The automaker’s nearly two-hour “Power Day” was widely seen as an echo of Tesla’s recent “Battery Day” event. Both automakers touched on issues around battery chemistry, supply chain, production, and charging as a way to make electric vehicles more affordable and attractive to a wider swath of customers. Here are the biggest announcements from VW’s Power Day event:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="MMTNyX"&gt;Unified battery cells&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="b7gpYB"&gt;Starting in 2023, VW plans to roll out a new unified prismatic cell design of its batteries that will be installed across the automaker’s brands. The goal is to have this unified cell design powering up to 80 percent of VW’s electric vehicles by 2030. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gnJpMX"&gt;Thomas Schmall, Volkswagen Group Board Member for Technology, said the goal was to drive down the cost of battery production below $100 per kWh, which most experts believe will make EVs roughly the same price as gas-powered vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="yb7Hhi"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;A picture of the unified cell. &lt;a href="https://t.co/OusTHdgwB8"&gt;pic.twitter.com/OusTHdgwB8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Jordi Sastre (@jordi_sastr3) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jordi_sastr3/status/1371444247178584068?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="h8XKMl"&gt;The price per kilowatt-hour (kWh) is the unit of energy most commonly used to measure the capacity of the battery packs in modern electric vehicles. Those prices have been falling dramatically over the last decade, from $1,100 / kWh in 2010 to $156 / kWh in 2019, a drop of 87 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LyZoVU"&gt;“We aim to reduce the cost and complexity of the battery and at the same time increase its range and performance,” Schmall said. “This will finally make e-mobility affordable and the dominant drive technology.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hyuGQ9"&gt;VW hopes to drive the cost down even further with more efficient production and a robust recycling process. The automaker aims to “gradually” reduce battery costs in the entry-level segment by up to 50 percent and in the volume segment by up to 30 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="udof4L"&gt;Volkswagen “gigafactories”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="oFPjJy"&gt;One way Volkswagen plans to boost production of battery-powered vehicles is through a massive expansion of its manufacturing footprint. The automaker plans to have six battery cell production plants operating in Europe by 2030, which it will build alone or with partners. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z1IjLg"&gt;The first two plants will be in Salzgitter, Germany, and Skelleftea, Sweden; a third plant will be established either in Spain, Portugal, or France; and the fourth factory will be based in Eastern Europe. The plants will have a production capacity of 240 gigawatt-hours a year, Schmall said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iuo1Nk"&gt;On the same day as VW’s event, Swedish battery maker Northvolt said it had received an order from the automaker worth $14 billion. Northvolt will also sell its share in joint-venture Northvolt Zwei to Volkswagen. The Swedish company has said it plans to increase its market share in Europe to 25 percent by 2030. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="UCbMoT"&gt;Charging expansion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="COuuIV"&gt;Volkswagen said it intends to have 18,000 public fast-charging points in operation in Europe by 2025, a fivefold increase over the current state of EV charging in the continent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MJSUJK"&gt;This will be accomplished through a series of strategic partnerships that were announced today. VW said it would team up with oil giant BP and top European utilities Enel and Iberdrola to expand electric vehicle charging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="dP583O"&gt;&lt;q&gt;18,000 public fast-charging points in Europe by 2025&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LpvAua"&gt;With BP, Volkswagen said it wants to establish about 8,000 fast-charging points throughout Europe, with most of the stations concentrated in Germany and the UK. The fast-chargers with a charging capacity of 150 kW will be installed at a total of 4,000 BP and ARAL fuel stations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lKpgNh"&gt;In partnership with Spain’s Iberdrola, Volkswagen will cover main traffic routes across that country. In Italy, Volkswagen will work with Enel to establish fast-charging stations along major highways and in urban areas. The automaker plans to spend about €400 million to expand its European EV charging network by 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VOMDqZ"&gt;The company also said it would have 17,000 public fast-charging stations in China and was on track to reach 800 stations in the US through its Electrify America subsidiary by the end of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="t124AQ"&gt;Two-way charging&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="tYZGl5"&gt;Starting in 2022, vehicles built on VW’s modular MEB electric vehicle platform will support bidirectional, or two-way, charging. “This will allow green electricity from the solar energy system to be stored in the vehicle and fed back into the home network if needed,” the company said. “Not only will customers be more independent of the public power grid, they will also save money and reduce CO2 emissions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="12vT74"&gt;VW plans to offer a range of products to enable this, including a home energy storage system and a mobile EV charger that is unconnected from the grid. This will enable car owners to “become their own utility,” the company claims. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dt6u0y"&gt;The company also unveiled an adorable EV charger robot intended for fleet owners. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WjFxSR"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Is this a robotic EV charger? &lt;a href="https://t.co/FiZTYo1Xg3"&gt;pic.twitter.com/FiZTYo1Xg3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Jordi Sastre (@jordi_sastr3) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jordi_sastr3/status/1371449999482105857?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="fpBkJr"&gt;Why now?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="hzMx8T"&gt;Volkswagen will need to boost its battery expertise and secure its supply chain if it is to deliver on its bold promise of making electric vehicles 50 percent of its sales in the US by 2030. The company recently unveiled a &lt;a href="https://www.caranddriver.com/news/a35741685/vw-to-build-ev-trinity-2026/"&gt;concept sedan called Trinity&lt;/a&gt; that it promised would feature “high range” and “short charging time” by 2026. The automaker’s mass-manufactured modular electric vehicle platform, or “MEB,” will serve as the foundation for this massive shift. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W5ZcZp"&gt;Volkswagen announced the MEB platform in 2018 as part of its multibillion-dollar push into electric vehicles. It consists of a modular battery pack that can scale to fit differently sized vehicles, a motor, and other electronics — basically all of the technical underpinnings required to make an electric vehicle move. All of Volkswagen’s upcoming &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/11/21288572/volkswagen-id3-ev-delay-software-vw-herbert-diess"&gt;ID-branded electric vehicles&lt;/a&gt; are being built on the MEB platform, and it will also power certain vehicles from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/7/21316580/audi-q4-etron-sportback-suv-2021-volkswagen-meb"&gt;Volkswagen Group brands like Audi&lt;/a&gt;, Seat, and Skoda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sgAIBB"&gt;Volkswagen &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/roadshow/news/volkswagen-share-meb-electric-car-platform/"&gt;has said it plans to sell access to MEB&lt;/a&gt;, an idea that already attracted Ford, which is going to build a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/12/20690722/ford-vw-alliance-self-driving-argo-investment-valuation"&gt;commercial vehicle powered by the German automaker’s platform&lt;/a&gt;. But it is also open to partnering with startups. The first attempt, with Germany’s e.Go Mobile, fell apart after the &lt;a href="https://www.electrive.com/2020/06/22/vw-will-not-produce-the-id-buggy/"&gt;small startup became insolvent&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ac8i9k"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The race for huge improvements in battery technology is one of the most expensive and hotly contested on the planet right now&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4o7kTi"&gt;VW, which is the second largest automaker in the world based on volume, just released its first pair of long-range EVs, the Europe-only ID 3 hatchback and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22302883/vw-id4-review-volkswagen-ev-specs-range-photos-video"&gt;the ID 4 compact SUV&lt;/a&gt;, which just started making deliveries in the US. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iPu74d"&gt;Initially, the ID 4’s battery pack, which is comprised of 288 pouch cells in 12 modules, will be produced by South Korea’s LG Chem. But once ID 4 production shifts to Chattanooga, Tennessee, in 2022, the batteries will be &lt;a href="https://www.timesfreepress.com/news/breakingnews/story/2020/jun/26/sk-innovation-plans-940-million-expansion-georgia/526225/"&gt;supplied by SK Innovation&lt;/a&gt;, another South Korean company that recently opened a $2 billion factory nearby VW’s plant there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9fY5Yg"&gt;Before the event, reports surfaced that VW would be pivoting away from its main battery supplier, South Korea’s LG Chem, and was turning to China’s CATL, &lt;a href="https://www.autonews.com/technology/vw-switch-ev-battery-type-leaving-supply-deals-doubt-report-says"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Automotive News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;citing South Korea’s &lt;em&gt;Money Today&lt;/em&gt; online news site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A5VZLD"&gt;VW also has contracts with two other major battery producers, Samsung and CATL. And the company is backing a startup based in San Jose, California, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22158573/quantumscape-solid-state-battery-ev-range-charge-vw"&gt;QuantumScape&lt;/a&gt;, which is working on more energy-efficient solid-state batteries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qnzYYn"&gt;QuantumScape says its solid-state batteries will represent a significant improvement over conventional lithium-ion batteries, enabling electric vehicles that can travel 80 percent further than an EV with a traditional battery. They retain more than 80 percent of their capacity after 800 charging cycles, they’re noncombustible, and they’ll have volumetric energy density of more than 1,000 watt-hours per liter at the cell level, which is nearly double the density of top-rate commercial lithium-ion packs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7HBt3n"&gt;VW called solid-state batteries “the end game.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22325813/vw-volkswagen-power-day-battery-electric-car-announcement"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22325813/vw-volkswagen-power-day-battery-electric-car-announcement</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
