<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-11-02T14:39:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T14:39:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T14:39:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Fired #AppleToo organizer files labor charge against the company</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/INY46vctDvgoNd95OBIXuJkYgwM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70080565/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="O0HhUg"&gt;Janneke Parrish, a leader of the #AppleToo movement, has filed an unfair labor practice charge against the company, alleging the tech giant &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22727123/apple-fires-leader-apple-too-movement"&gt;fired her in retaliation for organizing&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ubzf2D"&gt;Parrish &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22638150/apple-appletoo-employee-harassment-discord"&gt;created the #AppleToo platform&lt;/a&gt; to help colleagues air their concerns with Apple’s culture of “pervasive sexism” and pay equity, according to the complaint. Then, in October, she was fired, allegedly for failing to comply with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22687747/tim-cook-employee-leak-memos-do-not-belong-at-apple"&gt;workplace investigation into leaks&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t9emqc"&gt;Parrish says the company terminated her based on “false and pretextual reasons” — namely because she “spoke up regarding her personal experiences regarding workplace concerns and helped give voice to her co-workers’ concerns in a workplace where such issues have been systematically siloed, suppressed, and unaddressed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EhM1VW"&gt;“It seems like all the tech companies are using the same playbook,” says labor attorney Laurie Burgess. “They get rid of outspoken organizers by asserting they are responsible for a leak without any proof or documentation that that person was indeed responsible. My client denies having leaked this information.” Burgess is also representing the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/29/22751847/netflix-employees-dave-chappelle-file-charges-nlrb"&gt;fired and suspended Netflix organizers&lt;/a&gt;, as well as prominent Google organizers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZoiwGm"&gt;This is the seventh unfair labor practice charge that has been filed against Apple since August. Last month, former senior engineering program manager Ashley Gjøvik &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-12/apple-ceo-s-anti-leak-edict-broke-the-law-ex-employee-alleges?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;accused Tim Cook of violating the National Labor Relations Act&lt;/a&gt; when he warned employees that “people who leak confidential information do not belong here.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V4auhi"&gt;Cher Scarlett, an Apple software engineer, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-national-labor-relations-board-investigating-two-complaints-apple-workers-2021-09-02/"&gt;filed a complaint in September&lt;/a&gt; alleging the company stopped employees from engaging in protected activity when they tried to discuss their pay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sfGsTl"&gt;An employee on the AppleCare team, Apple’s version of customer service, filed a charge on September 28th alleging they were unlawfully fired. This charge has not been previously reported. The employee’s identity is not known at this time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xa0mbe"&gt;The NLRB is currently investigating claims against the tech giant. If it finds they have merit, it can try to secure a settlement. The labor board can also issue its own complaint if settlement talks fail. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CLmubA"&gt;Apple did not immediately respond to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759715/fired-apple-too-organizer-files-labor-charge-nlrb"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759715/fired-apple-too-organizer-files-labor-charge-nlrb</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T14:27:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T14:27:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>The free laptop program built into the Biden reconciliation plan</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="BRITAIN-UN-CLIMATE-COP26" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kIULLwyeEWiSVhK_6FGcKx4406g=/0x0:4130x2753/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70080502/1236277724.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by EVAN VUCCI/POOL/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZCk80b"&gt;After months of negotiations, President Joe Biden’s Build Back Better agenda advanced into its last phase of debate this week. The bipartisan infrastructure contains billions to expand high-speed broadband across the country, aiming to close the digital divide over the next 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="byG7Ei"&gt;But the administration’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22598636/white-house-infrastructure-broadband-package-bipartisan"&gt;$65 billion down payment&lt;/a&gt; on broadband can only help connect families who can afford a computer. So Biden’s latest version of the Build Back Better program goes further, allocating new funds to bring federally funded desktops, laptops, and tablets to poor Americans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UPTq3L"&gt;Last week, the White House released its latest version of the Build Back Better plan, outlining &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751099/white-house-budget-climate-electric-vehicles-ev-tax-credit-deal-manchin-sinema"&gt;a $1.75 trillion budget proposal&lt;/a&gt; to tackle climate change and invest in other social services like Medicare. Deep within the over 1,600 pages of the bill is a new initiative — the Connected Device Grant Program — that would help provide free or discounted desktops, laptops, or tablets to low-income households. To accomplish that goal, the Commerce Department would receive $475 million to award community groups that want to distribute these devices locally. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="w5qvmk"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We’re not going to close the digital divide if we don’t make sure people have the computers and tablets they need”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="E3YrAJ"&gt;“We can invest all of this money in the infrastructure package in broadband deployment,” said Jenna Leventoff, Public Knowledge senior policy counsel, in an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; last week, “but we’re not going to close the digital divide if we don’t make sure people have the computers and tablets they need.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="adzqfr"&gt;As of June of this year, only four in 10 lower-income adults have access to a desktop or laptop computer, and a majority are not tablet owners, &lt;a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2021/06/22/digital-divide-persists-even-as-americans-with-lower-incomes-make-gains-in-tech-adoption/"&gt;according to the Pew Research Center&lt;/a&gt;. Only 43 percent of low-income adults have access to in-home broadband connections as well. These devices and technology are prevalent in households making $100,000 or more every year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zLHewz"&gt;The device program has been championed by Sen. Raphael Warnock (D-GA) and Rep. A. Donald McEachin (D-VA), who introduced the Device Access for Every American Act in September. The original bill would have established &lt;a href="https://mceachin.house.gov/media/press-releases/rep-mceachin-sen-warnock-introduce-bicameral-legislation-establish-voucher"&gt;a $5 billion Federal Communications Commission program&lt;/a&gt; to distribute up to $400 vouchers to low-income Americans for computers and tablets. The language was later roped into the Build Back Better budget reconciliation package and amended into the nearly half a billion grant program currently authorized under the measure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tmsjew"&gt;“It is nearly impossible to get by without access to a laptop or tablet — especially after a year of adjusting to virtual learning, working, and more,” Warnock said in a Monday statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “My bill will help ensure every American, regardless of their income or zip code, has the ability to participate and thrive in our increasingly digital economy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yVNS7j"&gt;While a majority of lower-income adults own smartphones, experts argue that mobile devices are not enough for people to compete and advance in the digital economy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RKVi9r"&gt;“A mobile phone isn’t sufficient. It’s not where I work. It’s not where I write my resume. It’s not where I work on spreadsheets,” Angela Siefer, National Digital Inclusion Alliance executive director, said. “Folks have been getting by with a mobile phone, but you certainly can’t thrive with only a mobile phone.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="FEuZDd"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“A mobile phone isn’t sufficient”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HJEi7S"&gt;Funding the program through the grant model leaves the specifics of implementation up to local groups, which could include anything from housing authorities to local libraries. Experts like Siefer and Leventoff also expect the private sector to play a significant role in distributing devices once the grant funding is approved by Congress. Hoping to stretch the grant dollars further, community groups could partner with device manufacturers to buy devices in bulk or offer them at a discounted rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pnMpbP"&gt;Microsoft launched its own free or low-cost refurbished device program called Airband earlier this year. The program partners with civil society organizations to provide devices to poor Americans. Starting in Los Angeles and New York City, the program expects to roll out to six more cities &lt;a href="https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=https-3A__nam02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com_-3Furl-3Dhttps-253A-252F-252Fblogs.microsoft.com-252Fon-2Dthe-2Dissues-252F2021-252F06-252F02-252Fracial-2Ddigital-2Dinequity-2Dairband-2Dbroadband-2Daccess-252F-26data-3D04-257C01-257Cadorsett-2540we-2Dworldwide.com-257Cc0f3563eb1fe44f4f39008d99b2f1db4-257C3ed60ab455674971a5341a5f0f7cc7f5-257C0-257C0-257C637711448947035986-257CUnknown-257CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0-253D-257C1000-26sdata-3DfbFGckAFJ-252BDUgiqJXX1Wl3gAN5YpkZATiI-252Bxrqf2BfE-253D-26reserved-3D0&amp;amp;d=DwMF-g&amp;amp;c=7MSjEE-cVgLCRHxk1P5PWg&amp;amp;r=HNNpVffGdDpwb__vVTedbxA45oxwn1GdeQ8euhDLKmk&amp;amp;m=qxCWW59whJYpU9rcl4OiRvLJPtv-1Fe1q2PNLdkz9jE&amp;amp;s=C7DWTuMzfLnLcOph7V1Au18ssc4LVfBdutLkiIjyk9g&amp;amp;e="&gt;in the coming months&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8utSxl"&gt;Many universities offer loaner devices to adult students, but these laptops or tablets usually must be returned after the school year ends. This means adult learners might not have access to free or low-cost devices until the following school year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kQhdvU"&gt;“There’s a big difference between using a loaner computer and having your own,” Siefer said. “It’s the understanding of what you can do with it. You’ll play with the settings. We all learn by doing that. There’s huge value in ownership over loan programs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GTj1dC"&gt;In a Tuesday call with House Democrats, Speaker Nancy Pelosi (D-CA) said she expects to finish negotiations over lingering issues, like climate and drug pricing, before the end of the day. This could set up a final vote on both the bipartisan infrastructure and budget reconciliation packages on the House floor either Thursday or Friday, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sarahnferris/status/1455528621485985799?s=20"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Politico&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="DyvLfx"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I’m not going to stop working until we get it passed”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="q0oNKZ"&gt;While the infrastructure package &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22618448/senate-bipartisan-infrastructure-package-schumer-broadband-cryptocurrency"&gt;was approved by the Senate earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;, the budget proposal could face an uphill battle in the higher body. On Monday, Sen. Joe Manchin (D-WV) &lt;a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/joe-manchin-biden-spending-bill-clarity/"&gt;called the social spending framework&lt;/a&gt; a “shell game, budget gimmicks that make the real cost of the so-called $1.75 trillion bill estimated to be almost twice that amount.” Manchin and Sen. Kyrsten Sinema (AZ), both moderate Democrats, have been at the center of negotiations over the budget proposal that has shrunk dramatically in size compared to its initial $3.5 trillion goal. Democrats need Manchin and Sinema’s support in order to pass the resolution and overcome a razor-thin majority in the Senate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B8Dr7e"&gt;Even if the reconciliation is approved within the next few days and weeks, it would be months before local groups could receive grant funding through the device program. The Commerce Department agency in charge of allocating the money would still need to approve new rules for the program, which could take months after the measure is approved. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VjEpHo"&gt;Still, Warnock is optimistic that the program will remain in the bill. “I’m glad we’ve been able to include it in the major economic package we’re debating in Washington, and I’m not going to stop working until we get it passed,” Warnock said on Monday. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759759/build-back-better-biden-laptop-tablet-low-income-manchin-sinema-broadband"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759759/build-back-better-biden-laptop-tablet-low-income-manchin-sinema-broadband</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T14:09:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T14:09:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nintendo is reportedly making 20 percent fewer Switches due to the chip shortage</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ps7fBok3APbSiKqVDQmCSvrA2PE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70080433/cfaulkner_210921_4751_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="phiqLT"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/2/22363232/global-semiconductor-chip-shortage-pandemic-consoles-cpus-graphics-cards-cars"&gt;global chip shortage&lt;/a&gt; is rippling through all areas of technology, and its chokehold on electronics doesn’t seem to be easing up anytime soon. Nintendo is just one brand that continues to suffer due to the shortage, as a report from &lt;a href="https://asia.nikkei.com/Business/Media-Entertainment/Nintendo-to-make-20-fewer-Switch-consoles-due-to-chip-crunch"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nikkei Asia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reveals that Nintendo is slashing the number of Switches it’s producing even further and falling short of original projections by 20 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="JXIvcd"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Nikkei Asia reports Nintendo will only push out 24 million units by the end of March&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AnzFG8"&gt;While Nintendo insists the chip shortage didn’t cause the Switch OLED to miss out on 4K video support, the squeeze could keep the company from meeting its updated projection. &lt;em&gt;Nikkei Asia&lt;/em&gt; reports that instead of producing the 30 million Switches it initially planned on,  Nintendo will only push out 24 million units by the end of March, which is short of the 25.5 million number it gave to investors in May. In a brief statement, a Nintendo spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;Nikkei Asia&lt;/em&gt; that they’re aware of the semiconductor shortage, and they’re evaluating the “impact” on its production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dBrpFw"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;Nikkei Asia&lt;/em&gt; notes, the Switch has seen a 37-percent decline in sales this September when compared to the same period last year. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21562530/nintendo-switch-lite-sales-october-2020"&gt;Demand for the Switch rapidly increased&lt;/a&gt; during the midst of the COVID-19 pandemic, as people looked for ways to keep busy while staying at home. The Switch took the spot as the top-selling console in the US &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21562530/nintendo-switch-lite-sales-october-2020"&gt;from 2019&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22279859/nintendo-switch-lite-ps5-sales-january-2021"&gt;the beginning of 2021&lt;/a&gt;, only to be surmounted by the PS5, which sold fewer units than the Switch but made more money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="86SW1s"&gt;It also doesn’t help that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/8/22660574/nintendo-switch-oled-model-availability-restock-best-buy-target-walmart-amazon-gamestop"&gt;Nintendo just released the Switch OLED model in October&lt;/a&gt; — a slightly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/22711889/nintendo-switch-oled-review"&gt;upgraded version of the Switch&lt;/a&gt; that comes with a better screen and more storage. A newer model typically means more demand, something that Nintendo probably should’ve considered before launching the Switch OLED during a chip shortage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ce3juG"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/news/that-was-quick-scalpers-resell-nintendo-switch-oled-model-pre-orders-for"&gt;Scalpers already bought out and attempted to resell Switch OLED preorders&lt;/a&gt; for outrageously high prices, so it wouldn’t be a surprise if they targeted what remains of the Switch stock in the coming months. After all, scalpers have already benefitted from the chip shortage, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/13/21564282/ps5-sony-playstation-5-xbox-series-x-orders-launch-week"&gt;digging their greedy claws into the Xbox One X and PlayStation 5&lt;/a&gt; — the Switch OLED could be their next feast.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759377/nintendo-making-20-percent-fewer-switches-chip-shortage"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759377/nintendo-making-20-percent-fewer-switches-chip-shortage</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T14:07:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T14:07:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>Harry Potter: Wizards Unite is shutting down next year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hwEGbxkcnUfR3-PHgOuJKORLc7c=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70080422/cgartenberg_190621_3508_3510.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gw74sD"&gt;Niantic, the developers of the smash hit &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt;, will be shutting down its Harry Potter-themed AR game &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter: Wizard’s Unite &lt;/em&gt;on January 31st, 2022. The game will be pulled from the App Store, Google Play, and Galaxy Store on December 6th, and that same day, you will no longer be able to make in-game purchases, according to the game’s website. The game’s community forum and social media channels will be closed on January 31st as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uNJAzb"&gt;In a &lt;a href="https://www.harrypotterwizardsunite.com/"&gt;blog post and FAQ&lt;/a&gt;, Niantic didn’t specify why it decided to shut down &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter: Wizard’s Unite&lt;/em&gt;. But we weren’t impressed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/25/18716146/harry-potter-wizards-unite-pokemon-go-review-ar-augmented-reality-game-foundable"&gt;when we first tried it in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, and the game never reached the same level of popularity as &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt;, which is still &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/6/22565654/pokemon-go-5-billion-fifth-anniversary-revenue-analytics"&gt;incredibly relevant&lt;/a&gt; despite being more than five years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rCUqob"&gt;There hasn’t been another AR hit quite on the level of &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt;; Niantic’s AR adaptation of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22680166/niantic-catan-world-explorers-shutdown-early-access"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Catan &lt;/em&gt;will fully shut down this month&lt;/a&gt;, while Microsoft closed down &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22215253/minecraft-earth-closing-down-june-2021-microsoft"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Minecraft Earth&lt;/em&gt; in June&lt;/a&gt;. That hasn’t stopped Niantic from trying, though, as it just released the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/26/22746427/pikmin-bloom-niantic-nintendo-pokemon-go-release-trailer"&gt;Pikmin-focused AR game &lt;em&gt;Pikmin Bloom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and has an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22529378/transformers-heavy-metal-niantic-pokemon-go-location-game-ar"&gt;AR &lt;em&gt;Transformers&lt;/em&gt; game in the works&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759677/harry-potter-wizards-unite-shutting-down-january-2022-niantic-ar"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759677/harry-potter-wizards-unite-shutting-down-january-2022-niantic-ar</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T13:53:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T13:53:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook is shutting down its Face Recognition tagging program</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Facial Recognition" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9V--JyicblACS2GU9uyjW_-bJZQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70080326/jbareham_170417_1617_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SdIU4b"&gt;Meta (formerly known as Facebook) is discontinuing Facebook’s Face Recognition feature following a lengthy privacy battle. Meta says the change will roll out in the coming weeks. As part of it, the company will stop using facial recognition algorithms to tag people in photographs and videos, and it will delete the facial recognition templates that it uses for identification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yfbhwp"&gt;Meta artificial intelligence VP &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/11/update-on-use-of-face-recognition/"&gt;Jerome Pesenti calls&lt;/a&gt; the change part of a “company-wide move to limit the use of facial recognition in our products.” The move follows a lawsuit that accused Facebook’s tagging tech of violating Illinois’ biometric privacy law, leading to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/27/22304618/judge-approves-facebook-privacy-settlement-illinois-facial-recognition"&gt;a $650 million settlement&lt;/a&gt; in February. Facebook previously &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/3/20847650/facebook-facial-recognition-setting-default-opt-in"&gt;restricted facial recognition&lt;/a&gt; to an opt-in feature in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="swKMyT"&gt;“Looking ahead, we still see facial recognition technology as a powerful tool,” writes Pesenti in a blog post, citing possibilities like face-based identity verification. “But the many specific instances where facial recognition can be helpful need to be weighed against growing concerns about the use of this technology as a whole.” Pesenti notes that regulators haven’t settled on comprehensive privacy regulation for facial recognition. “Amid this ongoing uncertainty, we believe that limiting the use of facial recognition to a narrow set of use cases is appropriate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="m3VQJ2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;More than one-third of active daily users had opted in&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NKGx1W"&gt;Pesenti says more than one-third of Facebook’s daily active users had opted into Face Recognition scanning, and over a billion face recognition profiles will be deleted as part of the upcoming change. As part of the change, Facebook’s automated alt-text system for blind users will no longer name people when it’s analyzing and summarizing media, and it will no longer suggest people to tag in photographs or automatically notify users when they appear in photos and videos posted by others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LhPGdA"&gt;Facebook’s decision won’t stop independent companies like Clearview AI — which built huge image databases by scraping photos from social networks, including Facebook — from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22522486/clearview-ai-facial-recognition-avoid-escape-privacy"&gt;using facial recognition algorithms trained with that data&lt;/a&gt;. US law enforcement agencies (alongside other government divisions) &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641216/facial-recognition-gao-report-agency-dhs-cbp-fbi"&gt;work with Clearview AI and other companies&lt;/a&gt; for facial recognition-powered surveillance. State or national privacy laws would be needed to restrict the technology’s use more broadly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qVhJVX"&gt;By shutting down a feature it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/19/16794660/facebook-facial-recognition-tagging-photos"&gt;used for years&lt;/a&gt;, Meta is hoping to bolster user confidence in its privacy protections as it prepares a rollout of potentially privacy-compromising virtual and augmented reality technology. The company launched &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22662809/facebook-ray-ban-stories-camera-smart-glasses-hands-on"&gt;a pair of camera-equipped smart glasses&lt;/a&gt; in partnership with Ray-Ban earlier this year, and it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22752986/meta-facebook-andrew-bosworth-interview-metaverse-vr-ar"&gt;gradually launching 3D virtual worlds&lt;/a&gt; on its Meta VR headset platform. All these efforts will require a level of trust from users and regulators, and giving up Facebook auto-tagging — especially after a legal challenge to the program — is a straightforward way to bolster it.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759613/meta-facebook-face-recognition-automatic-tagging-feature-shutdown"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759613/meta-facebook-face-recognition-automatic-tagging-feature-shutdown</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T13:40:26-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T13:40:26-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix Games starts global rollout on Android, with iOS ‘on the way’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HWRiddhoSQ380TIb8zSu1Rn4ZXA=/81x0:879x532/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70080259/Screen_Shot_2021_11_02_at_1.24.40_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rRu7mR"&gt;We knew this was coming. Ever since the announcement Netflix was pursuing gaming content for its billion-dollar entertainment mega streaming platform, it was a matter of time before you could actually play games from the Netflix app. &lt;a href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/let-the-games-begin-a-new-way-to-experience-entertainment-on-mobile"&gt;That day is here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Lg0FC7"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;   Let the Games Begin  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Tomorrow, Netflix Games will start rolling out on the Netflix mobile app. First on Android, with iOS on the way.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It’s early days, but we’re excited to start bringing you exclusive games, with no ads, no additional fees and no in-app purchases. &lt;a href="https://t.co/ofNGF4b8At"&gt;pic.twitter.com/ofNGF4b8At&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Netflix Geeked (@NetflixGeeked) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NetflixGeeked/status/1455580571959054341?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 2, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4VbZUi"&gt;Users will be able to choose from one of five games: &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.netflix.NGP.StrangerThings"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stranger Things: 1984&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.netflix.NGP.StrangerThings3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stranger Things 3: The Game&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.netflix.NGP.ShootingHoops"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shooting Hoops&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.netflix.NGP.CardBlast"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Card Blast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; and&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.netflix.NGP.TeeterUp"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Teeter Up&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;Starting today, users can download Netflix games from the Google Play store, requiring a Netflix subscription to play. Then on November 3rd, Netflix will begin rolling out games to the app itself. When on a mobile device, Netflix Games will come packaged in its own dedicated row and have a dedicated tab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JXrCN2"&gt;Though the current game offerings are a bit sparse, Netflix &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22699241/netflix-night-school-acquisition-oxenfree"&gt;has acquired &lt;em&gt;Oxenfree&lt;/em&gt; developer Night School&lt;/a&gt; which might suggest more ambitious titles than the &lt;em&gt;riveting&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Shooting Hoops&lt;/em&gt;, are forthcoming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c2pmfk"&gt;Netflix has been developing its mobile games feature for a while now, testing the service in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22642946/netflix-mobile-games-in-app-android-users-poland-stranger-things-1984-3"&gt;Poland&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22689922/netflix-games-italy-spain-android-beta-mobile"&gt;Spain, and Italy&lt;/a&gt;. Right now, only Android devices can take advantage of the gaming offerings, but Netflix confirms iOS support is on the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MVf7EW"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PubfF9zBTBY?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759628/netflix-games-global-rollout-mobile-android-devices"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759628/netflix-games-global-rollout-mobile-android-devices</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T13:37:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T13:37:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>Go read this investigation on the toxic air crisis plaguing American communities</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hcTPVR0lIgb_hyvJhsGJlTqHprM=/0x1:2130x1421/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70080249/VRG_ILLO_1777_AK_globe.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Ana Kova&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5kohiK"&gt;More than 1,000 communities in the United States are hotspots for toxic air pollution that can cause cancer, according to &lt;a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/toxmap-poison-in-the-air"&gt;an extensive new analysis from &lt;em&gt;ProPublica&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Over a quarter-million people are living in places with a level of cancer risk higher than what the Environmental Protection Agency says is acceptable, and 74 million Americans have a higher level of risk than what the EPA says it “strives to protect” people from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YD8pcv"&gt;&lt;em&gt;ProPublica&lt;/em&gt; used an EPA modeling tool to &lt;a href="https://projects.propublica.org/toxmap/"&gt;map&lt;/a&gt; how carcinogen-laced air spreads from chemical plants across the country. Most areas where people have the highest exposure to that air are in Southern states with weaker environmental regulations, and a quarter of the top 20 hotspots are in Texas. Predominantly Black areas in the US also have more than double the cancer risk of white areas — a finding that affirms years of research showing that communities of color face disproportionate exposure to air pollution. This disparity is tied to racist real estate and zoning practices, which have historically put facilities that emit pollutants in neighborhoods where people of color live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X2djEU"&gt;The top three hotspots of dangerous air in the country are in Port Arthur, Texas, on the Louisiana border, Louisiana’s “&lt;a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/welcome-to-cancer-alley-where-toxic-air-is-about-to-get-worse"&gt;Cancer Alley”&lt;/a&gt; located between New Orleans and Baton Rouge, and parts of the Houston area. Brittany Madison, who lives near an ExxonMobil refinery outside of Houston, has a three-year-old niece with severe asthma and family members who died of cancer. There are over 170 facilities emitting toxic chemicals within around 30 miles of her apartment, &lt;em&gt;ProPublica&lt;/em&gt; found. Madison told &lt;em&gt;ProPublica &lt;/em&gt;she wonders how many of the health problems in her community are because of the air her friends and family breathe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hjXbWx"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;ProPublica&lt;/em&gt; investigation underscored weaknesses in how the EPA regulates air pollution. While the agency strictly regulates “criteria” air pollutants like particulate matter, it doesn’t set limits on emissions of over 180 so-called &lt;a href="https://www.epa.gov/haps"&gt;hazardous air pollutants&lt;/a&gt;. And instead of tracking the cumulative emissions of dangerous chemicals in each area, it looks at pollution like refineries and shipyards one by one — an approach that underestimates the extent to which people living around multiple chemical plants are exposed to toxic air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mVVjKa"&gt;“The public is going to learn that EPA allows a hell of a lot of pollution to occur that the public does not think is occurring,” Wayne Davis, an environmental scientist who used to work at the EPA’s Office of Chemical Safety and Pollution Prevention, told &lt;em&gt;ProPublica&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YbX479"&gt;The Trump administration weakened air pollution protections, causing efforts to improve air quality to backslide. For many communities, growing heat exposure and wildfire risk due to climate change could further amplify the damage. Reducing the use of fossil fuels, a key goal of the U.N. climate talks currently underway in Glasgow, could drive improvements in air quality. But even as President Joe Biden urges countries to cut back, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/11/02/world/reduce-fossil-fuels-long-term-but-pump-more-now-biden-says-angering-activists.html"&gt;he’s asking oil producers&lt;/a&gt; to increase production in the face of rising gas prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KzSd1o"&gt;The EPA told &lt;em&gt;ProPublica&lt;/em&gt; that it was working “to better understand risks for communities who are overburdened by numerous sources of multiple pollutants.” Nicolaas Bouwes, a former senior analyst at the EPA, said the agency has had the data to find the same pollution hotspots &lt;em&gt;ProPublica &lt;/em&gt;identified for years. But there hasn’t been the funding or interest to tackle the problem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5mcjIQ"&gt;Go read the full story &lt;a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/toxmap-poison-in-the-air"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759135/air-pollution-cancer-epa-reuglations-propublica"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759135/air-pollution-cancer-epa-reuglations-propublica</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T13:05:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T13:05:52-04:00</updated>
    <title>Dropbox is adding folders that will automatically organize for you</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Cm_GsoCA-NbpVpCuvbWuubgtZDg=/0x0:1440x960/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70080107/Automated_Folder_DMEP_Primary_1440x960.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Dropbox&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GYNqFZ"&gt;Dropbox is adding a feature that will let you add automation to folders so new files are automatically renamed, grouped into subfolders, or more. The feature is called, perhaps unsurprisingly, Automated Folders, and &lt;a href="https://blog.dropbox.com/topics/product/new-features-to-keep-files-organized"&gt;Dropbox says&lt;/a&gt; it can help you (and any co-workers you share files with) stay organized with standardized names and tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KyrMvQ"&gt;The automation you add to folders can be configured with various rules, so you can tell the system to rename any files you add to the folder following a certain pattern or to sort them into subfolders based on the date the file was uploaded to Dropbox. The rules are currently predefined, but Dropbox says it’s working to make the system more customizable. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1rXy-cL3NKuS2TAyHUnEoI540oc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22979588/DBX076_ProductUI_Organizing_WEB_990x800_V1_Animated_Image__Large_.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF: Dropbox&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can have Dropbox automatically sort your files by month, a system that I’ve hacked together on my own computer but could now just have built in.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Llvsoh"&gt;Dropbox has also added a new tagging system, letting you add words to files and folders (either manually or automatically) that you can search for later.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sZU0868klICOK2abdaiWE652wyM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22978127/TyB_TREI.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Dropbox&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dropbox says its tagging system is rolling out to all users.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="bCTVsS"&gt;In addition to the automatic actions, Dropbox is also adding what it calls Naming Conventions and Multi-file organize actions. Naming Conventions will let you batch renamed files in a folder following a pattern that you choose — for example, you could rename photos to have the date the picture was taken in the file name itself. The Multi-file organize feature will let you have Dropbox sort files into subfolders based on how often people make changes to them, the date they were created, and more. Dropbox says you’ll be able to preview the changes before they’re made, so you don’t end up with files placed somewhere you won’t be able to find them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lsR22xfAMooPkcU_YPu2tCHN654=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22979594/DBX076_ProductUI_Renaming_WEB_990x800_V1_Animated_Image__Large_.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF: Dropbox&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Naming conventions can be set for individual folders, so you don’t have to pick one for your entire system.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fLIZCR"&gt;According to Dropbox, there’s also a dashboard to help you manage automated folders, which could be handy if you can’t remember everything that happens in your system. File automation, along with Naming Conventions and Multi-file organization, is coming first to Dropbox for Teams users starting today and will be available for people with individual or family plans “soon,” according to the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DtgHtp"&gt;This kind of automation has been possible before using programs like &lt;a href="https://www.noodlesoft.com"&gt;Hazel&lt;/a&gt; or custom scripts, it’s nice to see Dropbox building it into its service. Like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/25/17871898/siri-shortcuts-ios-12-iphone-apple-how-to-best-tips-tricks-search"&gt;Apple’s Shortcuts&lt;/a&gt;, it may not be as powerful as some other options, but it can offer people an easy way to start thinking about automation. And, even more importantly, these features could help cut down on the amount of boring file and folder shuffling you have to do to organize your Dropbox (provided you actually have a system and don’t &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22684730/students-file-folder-directory-structure-education-gen-z"&gt;just search for everything&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22758519/dropbox-automated-folder-organization-file-rename"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22758519/dropbox-automated-folder-organization-file-rename</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T12:45:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T12:45:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>Inscryption is part card game, part horror, and all-consuming</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rH7XvnIz-KDVCZYG7D5yyp6JACM=/143x0:1732x1059/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70079993/2021_11_01__24_.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Daniel Mullins Games&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LVuD1b"&gt;For my first session with &lt;em&gt;Inscryption&lt;/em&gt;, knowing nothing about the game and only playing it on the recommendation of a trusted friend, I played for seven hours straight. It meant ignoring my adult responsibilities and most of my bodily functions to do it, but I learned early on that the choice between “eating lunch” and “playing more &lt;em&gt;Inscryption&lt;/em&gt;” was a very easy one to make. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pszUDb"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inscryption&lt;/em&gt; is a collectible card game (or CCG) like &lt;em&gt;Magic: The Gathering&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Hearthstone&lt;/em&gt; while also combining elements of roguelikes and hidden object games that’s also an extremely unsettling horror experience. If none of those genres appeal to you, that’s okay. &lt;em&gt;Inscryption&lt;/em&gt; blends its various elements together to form an experience so damn compelling that even if the idea of playing a &lt;em&gt;Magic: The Gathering&lt;/em&gt;-esque game repulses you, its other parts are enough to keep you rooted to your computer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="eRrn8X"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The choice between “eating lunch” and “playing more &lt;em&gt;Inscryption”&lt;/em&gt; was a very easy one to make&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Ozjd0G"&gt;There is so much of &lt;em&gt;Inscryption&lt;/em&gt; I am desperate to yell about but won’t because a large part of the game’s appeal is the twists and turns that dramatically transform the game from one section to the next. Just when you think you’ve got a handle on what’s going on, the game throws you a massive curveball that shatters all your expectations and forces you to largely forget everything you’ve learned to adapt to new structures. The game is best enjoyed going in knowing absolutely nothing. Continue at your peril.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MBwUBe"&gt;You start in a dark room talking to a creature of whom you can only see its twisted eyes. It invites you to play cards, gifting you a small starter deck filled with different beasts. Like most CCGs, you play by putting down creature cards that have attack and health values and special attributes that vary from card to card. Each card represents a different animal like deer or ants, and you play them by sacrificing other creatures you have on the board, using them for their blood or bones (yeah, it’s dark). Each time you attack, the damage you do is weighed on a scale. Likewise, damage done to you is also weighed on the same scale. If you inflict enough damage to completely tip the scale against your opponent, you win. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1hdKQXZWIVEiWdfGpQpIfiEoZ10=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22976557/2021_11_01__26_.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Daniel Mullins Games&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Tip the scale and you win and there are all kinds of bloody ways to tip the scale in your favor.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="vPYGXR"&gt;Once you win the first game, the battlefield changes to reveal a map that looks kinda like a board game, and &lt;em&gt;Inscryption&lt;/em&gt; starts to open up. Between card games, you move your piece on the board to different symbols that give you different opportunities to improve your deck and the creatures in it. A very valuable space, for instance, is the one that lets you enhance one type of card in your deck with additional powers. While the idol maker can grant powerful boons to any creature type, your best bet is to use it to enhance an important component of your deck: squirrels. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kH66LQ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inscryption&lt;/em&gt; (or at least this part of &lt;em&gt;Inscryption&lt;/em&gt;) is centered around animal sacrifice or, more pointedly, survival of the fittest. You cannot play a card without paying its blood or bones cost, and to help earn that currency, you’re given a nest of squirrels to gleefully sacrifice to your heart’s content. They are free to play, but they have no attack power and little health, meaning they exist only as blood or bone sacrifices in order to play bigger, more powerful creatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KekQ1N"&gt;The game tries to make you feel the weight of sacrificing animals to advance. When you need to play a card that requires a sacrifice, the cards already on the board shiver and shake when your cursor (now transformed into a knife) hovers over them. Some of the cards even talk and beg for you not to sacrifice them, or they die solemnly, exclaiming their death was necessary to advance.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OC2AHQZ-zecau62s7Mv3WCIPDo4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22979557/2021_11_01__30_.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Daniel Mullins Games&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The price you pay for losing is death (and a restart)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5X4vAG"&gt;This early part of the game is unforgiving. If you lose two games, you start over, forced to make new decisions that will hopefully power up your deck better than before. Enhancing your squirrels is the only way to build a powerful enough deck to beat the bosses that lie in wait for you at the end of the game’s four boards. But when you first encounter the idol maker, she doesn’t have a squirrel head to choose from. So how do you get it? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UhInL0"&gt;After you lose your first game, the creature lets you walk freely about the room. There are knick-knacks to touch, poke, and otherwise interact with that look suspiciously like puzzles to solve. At this point, you’ve entered part two of &lt;em&gt;Inscryption&lt;/em&gt; — the escape room wherein the only way to progress is to solve puzzles to get the items that will allow you to break out of the room you’re trapped in. Just like the card matches, this part of the game is not easy. The puzzle solutions can be very opaque, making it difficult to figure out what you need to do next. Thankfully, you have help. Certain creature cards in your deck talk to you and give you clues. One of them is an annoying stoat who negs you when you make a bad play — just like the tryhards that stalk my local card shop during a Friday Night &lt;em&gt;Magic&lt;/em&gt; game and my partner whenever I forget to trigger an instant on his turn.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ENjZLMU-vOM3c2vLD_xEw-5zwRA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22976467/2021_10_27__7_.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Daniel Mullins Games&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Hey, screw you stoat!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="nXBHqk"&gt;I didn’t love the escape room puzzles — one in particular is nigh unsolvable without random guessing. But after some trial and error (emphasis on error), I figured them out. Their rewards — powerful cards, the squirrel head, and a knife that instantly damages your opponent for a lot of health at a gruesome cost — break the game wide open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vthHkq"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inscryption&lt;/em&gt;’s appeal comes from the near-limitless ways you can put together a brutally effective deck. It is fun and, even better, &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt; to assemble a deck that completely steamrolls the creature once you get the right items from solving puzzles. My problem with &lt;em&gt;Magic: The Gathering&lt;/em&gt; and other collectible card games is that there’s a high effort to reward ratio. Even accounting for the balance required for a multiplayer card game, there are so many cards and interactions to account for that building a winning deck is extremely difficult. &lt;em&gt;Inscryption &lt;/em&gt;cuts out most of the bullshit that comes with traditional deckbuilding games and allows me to get to the good stuff: building a deck so overpowered that I feel like a god. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VveeRX"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inscryption&lt;/em&gt; encourages you to build overpowered decks filled with card combos that would be ludicrous to play against in any other kind of card game. Late in the game, I built a deck that essentially granted me an extra point of mana per turn, meaning I could play my high-cost creatures much earlier than normal, reliably killing my opponents by turn three. But &lt;em&gt;Inscryption&lt;/em&gt; also seems aware that too much power can actually legitimately break the game. There’s a boss fight that forces you to create card rules that affect all players. I accidentally created a sickening rule that triggered a never-ending loop of random cards entering and leaving the battlefield. Instead of crashing, the game seemed to realize my folly, canceled the rule, and forced me to create a new one. It was disgusting how much fun it was to create decks and rules and creatures so broken the game itself had to step in to stop me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="gfd1aj"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Inscryption lets you build a deck so overpowered that you feel like a god&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LbgCp8"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inscryption&lt;/em&gt; does tell a story. I won’t spoil it, but it’s an interesting, if not creepy, tale that involves death and questionable game development practices. But despite being well-written and unsettling, it wasn’t compelling enough to make me care (which is not ever something I’d normally ever say because paramount to all things, I play video games for their stories). All I wanted was to play more&lt;em&gt; Inscryption&lt;/em&gt;. The only reason I know the story at all was because my partner shamed me into going through the story sections instead of just skipping them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ESEm82"&gt;To delve into one significant spoiler: &lt;em&gt;Inscyption&lt;/em&gt;’s biggest drawback is that it simply ends. I could play this game forever, but it’s single-player and has a discrete ending that resets the game to the beginning when reached. The game also ends on a bit of a sour note. There’s a point at which it throws so many new game modes at you such that it’s impossible to win. In fact, the game expects you to lose. I hated that. &lt;em&gt;Inscyption&lt;/em&gt;’s deck building system is so sublime that I felt cheated when I wasn’t allowed to spend the same kind of time with the new systems that I had with the previous ones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nh2wlg"&gt;One of the nicknames for &lt;em&gt;Magic: The Gathering&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;a href="https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=cardboard%20crack"&gt;cardboard crack&lt;/a&gt;. It alludes to how deceptively easy it is to spend thousands of dollars amassing the perfect, powerful collection of cards. &lt;em&gt;Inscryption&lt;/em&gt; is an insidious game because it is just as addicting as &lt;em&gt;Magic: The Gathering&lt;/em&gt; for a fraction of its cost and the space it requires to house your menagerie of cards. You want — &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; — to play this game, but if you do, make sure you don’t have adult shit to do because once you sit down with &lt;em&gt;Inscryption&lt;/em&gt;, you won’t get up again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6b2UtK"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inscryption&lt;/em&gt; is available now on PC via Steam, GOG, and Humble Bundle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DKwIvQ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WQFkTu"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22757407/inscryption-review-pc-steam-devolver-digital"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22757407/inscryption-review-pc-steam-devolver-digital</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-02T12:22:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-02T12:22:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft is planning 3D metaverse apps for Xbox and gaming</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Xbox X in a circle logo against a dark background with green lines." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AW16Iz2MCHf8IsidtoCVD8dFFX4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70079832/acastro_190530_1777_xbox_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RRJD8R"&gt;Microsoft just announced its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22758974/microsoft-teams-metaverse-mesh-3d-avatars-meetings-features"&gt;Microsoft Teams metaverse for meetings&lt;/a&gt; and video calls, but the company also has plans for gaming and entertainment. &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-02/microsoft-s-own-metaverse-is-coming-and-it-will-have-powerpoint?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;Speaking to Bloomberg TV&lt;/a&gt;, Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella says the software maker is “absolutely” focused on gaming for the metaverse with Xbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wsaQUv"&gt;“You can absolutely expect us to do things in gaming,” says Nadella. “If you take &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; as a game, it is a metaverse. &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt; is a metaverse, and so is &lt;em&gt;Flight Sim&lt;/em&gt;. In some sense, they’re 2D today, and the question is can you now take that to a full 3D world, and we absolutely plan to do so.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S4dfWX"&gt;We’ve been waiting to see what Microsoft will do for &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt; to transform it into a metaverse for VR and AR headsets for years. The company originally demonstrated the potential for &lt;em&gt;Minecraft &lt;/em&gt;with augmented reality at the initial introduction of the HoloLens headset, wowing those who tried the experience. It looked like a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/6/15/8782595/microsoft-hololens-minecraft"&gt;special version of &lt;em&gt;Minecraft &lt;/em&gt;for the HoloLens&lt;/a&gt; was being worked on six years ago, but so far all we’ve &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/17/18627341/minecraft-earth-ios-android-free-ar-game-features-pokemon-go"&gt;seen is &lt;em&gt;Minecraft Earth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a mobile augmented reality mobile game, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22215253/minecraft-earth-closing-down-june-2021-microsoft"&gt;come and go&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jGKkyk9Ojw3pCID_u881gXBP4FA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22979590/minecraftvr.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Minecraft already supports VR headsets.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="2dgMHC"&gt;Transforming &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Flight Sim &lt;/em&gt;into full 3D worlds is an ambitious project, particularly if these environments will allow players to explore them together side by side with VR or AR headsets. &lt;em&gt;Microsoft Flight Simulator &lt;/em&gt;already does a lot of this, with players able to pilot planes in a multiplayer environment that mimics real-world weather and locations. &lt;em&gt;Flight Sim&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt; even have VR support, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j51vVE"&gt;Nadella hasn’t committed to exactly when we’ll see Microsoft’s push into a 3D metaverse for gaming more broadly. Microsoft’s enterprise announcements today are mainly focused on 3D avatars and shared virtual spaces, and Xbox has had its own 3D avatars for years now. The question will be how Microsoft adapts &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/3/16408626/altspacevr-microsoft-acquisition-vr-community"&gt;its AltspaceVR social network&lt;/a&gt; and first-party games for metaverse applications on the Xbox, and whether the company will ever bring VR or AR headsets to Xbox consoles.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759379/microsoft-xbox-metaverse-halo-minecraft-flight-sim"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759379/microsoft-xbox-metaverse-halo-minecraft-flight-sim</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
