<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-06-12T13:18:52-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-12T13:18:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-12T13:18:52-04:00</updated>
    <title>Like Google Chrome, Chrome OS will be moving to a four-week release schedule</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Asus Chromebook Detachable CM3 open, angled to the left. The screen displays a cartoon city scene on a pink background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IDPxn4Iy8JbCvx7ID2VVh6GkaUM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69444366/mchin_20190829_4618_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="c728S7"&gt;Google will be adjusting the release cycle for Chrome OS later this year, moving to a schedule where it launches a new release every four weeks, the company announced on Friday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AIs64O"&gt;“To deliver new features more rapidly to consumers while also continuing to prioritize the key pillars of Chrome OS – security, stability, speed and simplicity – Chrome OS will move to a 4-week stable channel starting with M96 in Q4,” Chrome OS release TPM lead Marina Kazatcker &lt;a href="https://blog.chromium.org/2021/06/changes-to-chrome-oss-release-cycle.html"&gt;said in a blog post&lt;/a&gt;. For enterprise and education users who may not want that fast of a release cycle, Google also plans to introduce a new update channel with a 6-month cadence by the time of the M96 release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2IV7h7"&gt;The speed of Chrome OS’ release schedule will bring it on par with the Google Chrome browser, which will &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/5/22314992/google-chrome-release-cycle-four-weeks-update"&gt;also be transitioning to a four-week release schedule&lt;/a&gt;. For the Chrome browser, that change will kick in starting in the third quarter of this year. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22530937/google-chrome-os-four-week-release-schedule"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22530937/google-chrome-os-four-week-release-schedule</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-12T13:12:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-12T13:12:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>Blue Origin auctions New Shepard ride with Jeff Bezos for $28 million</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Amazon Chief Executive Officer Jeff Bezos Introduces The Blue Origin&amp;amp;nbsp;New Shepard&amp;amp;nbsp;System" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Wbv6TOaQbNgEfL-FTJ4Bw7jiRQc=/0x0:3519x2346/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69444356/665033904.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LwdrPn"&gt;Blue Origin’s month-long auction for a trip to the edge of space with its billionaire founder Jeff Bezos ended on Saturday with a closing price of $28 million. The flight aboard New Shepard, slated for July 20th, will mark the company’s first mission flying humans, in which the winning bidder will bask in a few minutes of microgravity with Bezos, his brother Mark, and one other passenger before returning back to land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="baNKdh"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The more you pay for it the more you enjoy it”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qn6OKR"&gt;The identity of the winner will be kept secret for a few weeks — “we need to complete some final paperwork with them,” says Blue Origin’s astronaut sales director Ariane Cornell during the live broadcast. The auction took place in a Boston, Massachusetts facility owned by RR Auction, the hosting company. Dozens of telephone operators were gathered in a room representing 20 bidders, who brought the starting price of $4.8 million to $28 million in under 10 minutes. The proceeds will go to Blue Origin’s nonprofit charity Club For The Future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fp32x0"&gt;“The more you pay for it the more you enjoy it,” the auctioneer said at one point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mjMYKR"&gt;New Shepard is a 60-foot-tall reusable rocket designed to shoot a gumdrop-shaped capsule with seats for six roughly 62 miles above ground to the edge of space, a roughly 10-minute mission that gives passengers a sight-seeing experience in microgravity for about three minutes. Jeff Bezos, the founder of Amazon who will step down as its CEO next month, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522313/jeff-bezos-space-launch-brother-blue-origin-july-20"&gt;announced last Monday&lt;/a&gt; he’ll be riding the same mission with his brother Mark to fulfill his lifelong dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7liCld"&gt;The $28 million price tag for the suborbital trip is roughly half the price for a seat on an orbital mission. SpaceX’s Crew Dragon capsule, which has only flown government astronauts to the International Space Station, will launch its first private astronaut mission to orbit later this year, with four passengers spending roughly three days in orbit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cJEQGS"&gt;Blue Origin, which has test-flown the fully reusable New Shepard rocket 15 times since 2015, hasn’t set a price for its passenger seats — years of market research and price data from the month-long auction could inform its starting price point. Cornell said the company will reach out to “the most competitive bidders from today to offer them access.” The fourth and final passenger will be announced soon, she said, without indicating whether it’d be a Blue Origin employee, one of the competitive bidders, or someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="txBiQ2"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JUcQmETFmds?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FKWsdS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qhaDrd"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4cszom"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22530907/blue-origin-auction-new-shepard-jeff-bezos-space-28-million"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22530907/blue-origin-auction-new-shepard-jeff-bezos-space-28-million</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-12T12:51:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-12T12:51:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>New COVID-19 outbreaks in Asia could exacerbate the global chip shortage</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Intel Skylake chip shots" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VyiVC4c0MfFJr--NIDth2d_pDPk=/2x0:1018x677/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69444291/vs09-02_0829cxs.0.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Wp3FXw"&gt;New outbreaks of COVID-19 in Asia could create delays in the global supply chain and exacerbate the global semiconductor shortage, according to a new report from &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-global-logistics-logjam-shifts-to-shenzhen-from-suez-11623403801"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I4hNYR"&gt;Taiwan, which is a significant hub for chip manufacturing, is currently experiencing a surge of COVID-19 cases. On Saturday, Taiwan’s Central Epidemic Command Center announced &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov.tw/En/Bulletin/Detail/eBhjH1ABLVz9Vcff6CXpMg?typeid=158"&gt;that there&lt;/a&gt; were 251 new confirmed cases of COVID-19 and 26 deaths. On Friday, &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov.tw/En/Bulletin/Detail/I542wKZkDsRjERe5S5HTwA?typeid=158"&gt;the agency reported&lt;/a&gt; 287 new cases and 24 deaths. And cases have been on the rise since early May. “Starting on May 10, COVID-19 infections jumped from one to three-digit figures within a matter of days,” &lt;a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3137084/taiwanese-president-tsai-ing-wen-apologises-surge-covid-19"&gt;&lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mq9CW1"&gt;The outbreak is having a big effect on at least one major chip company in Taiwan. “At &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/market-data/quotes/TW/XTAI/2449"&gt;King Yuan Electronics&lt;/a&gt; Co., one of the island’s largest chip testing and packaging companies, more than 200 employees have tested positive for the virus this month, while another 2,000 workers have been placed in quarantine — cutting the company’s revenue this month by roughly a third,” the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt; reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kaGNjl"&gt;TSMC, which makes chips for Apple, Qualcomm, and many other big tech companies, says it has not yet been affected, according to the &lt;em&gt;WSJ. &lt;/em&gt;But the company already warned in April that chip shortages &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22385240/tsmc-chip-shortage-2022-intel-ceo-earnings-graphics-cards-cpus-gpus"&gt;could last through 2022&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s unclear how the COVID-19 outbreak in Taiwan might affect that estimation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r4xcCb"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt; reported that factories in Malaysia have had their manufacturing capabilities slowed due to COVID-19 as well. “All told, the Malaysia Semiconductor Industry Association says the lockdown will reduce output by between 15% and 40%,” according to the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3KsMqB"&gt;Shipping centers in Asia have also been affected by the pandemic. For example, Yantian, a major container port in Shenzhen, is at 30 percent of its normal activity, the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt; reported.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22530908/covid-19-outbreaks-asia-global-chip-semiconductor-shortage"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22530908/covid-19-outbreaks-asia-global-chip-semiconductor-shortage</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-12T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-12T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to watch Ubisoft Forward</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/D_6MVD3mfg4So9FE9Lyo8b71x7k=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69444186/ACV_UbiFwd_0720_Enemy_Variety.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="21Iyb4"&gt;Ubisoft Forward is the publisher / developer’s livestreamed event where we’ll see updates to preexisting Ubisoft titles, as well as announcements of brand-new games. For E3 2021, Ubisoft is teasing the unveiling of its next &lt;em&gt;Rainbow Six&lt;/em&gt; title, formerly known as &lt;em&gt;Rainbow Six Quarantine&lt;/em&gt; (good move changing that name, Ubisoft). It also plans to show more on &lt;em&gt;Far Cry 6&lt;/em&gt;, as well as detailing updates for &lt;em&gt;Assassin’s Creed Valhalla&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Rainbow Six Siege&lt;/em&gt;. Ubisoft promises there will be a few additional surprises, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="PHbMmM"&gt;When does Ubisoft Forward (E3 2021 edition) begin?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="i3FiMX"&gt;A pre-show will start at 2PM ET / 11AM PT on Saturday, June 12th showcasing news and updates for existing games including &lt;em&gt;For Honor&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;TrackMania&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Crew 2&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Brawlhalla&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Watch Dogs: Legion&lt;/em&gt;, and more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OAon5S"&gt;One hour later at 3PM ET / 12PM PT, the show will begin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="w4Q5Pd"&gt;Where can I watch the Ubisoft Forward?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="SwZSm4"&gt;You’ll be able to watch the show at Ubisoft’s &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBMvc6jvuTxH6TNo9ThpYjg"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/ubisoft"&gt;Twitch&lt;/a&gt; channels. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ov9ykA"&gt;Though, if you want to watch the show with subtitles in 12 languages, watch it at &lt;a href="https://ubisoft.pxf.io/c/482924/864200/12050?u=http%3A%2F%2Fubisoft.com%2FForward&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ubisoft.com/Forward&lt;/a&gt;. The company says that its pre-show and main event “will be translated into American Sign Language, with the main show audio described in English.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22529431/ubisoft-forward-live-stream-how-start-time-e3-2021-rainbox-six-far-cry-6"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22529431/ubisoft-forward-live-stream-how-start-time-e3-2021-rainbox-six-far-cry-6</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-12T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-12T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Now’s your chance to get a month of Paramount Plus for free </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CF-SZ1CeoHyHLVXq-irV1G_Xeb0=/93x0:1038x630/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69444046/Paramount_Plus.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: ViacomCBS&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CRAlL3"&gt;If you’ve been weighing whether to take the plunge on Paramount Plus, now’s your chance to take the streaming service for a test drive for a full 30 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9Rz7V8"&gt;The service is currently offering a month-long trial period that extends to both its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/3/22515286/paramount-plus-5-subscription-plan-ads"&gt;recently launched “essential” plan&lt;/a&gt; that’s supported by ads (regularly $5 per month), as well as to its premium ad-free experience (normally $10 per month). While trial periods are fairly standard for most major streaming services — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21514661/netflix-free-trial-us-cancel-content-sampling-streaming"&gt;unless it’s Netflix&lt;/a&gt; we’re talking about — Paramount Plus had most recently offered just a week to try the service before it required users to pay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gfsxwo"&gt;Much like Disney Plus and HBO Max, Paramount Plus is a super-stuffed service with designated hubs for content from CBS, BET, Comedy Central, MTV, Nickelodeon, and Smithsonian Channel, plus originals exclusive to the platform. &lt;em&gt;Star Trek: Picard&lt;/em&gt; (and much more &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;, for that matter), &lt;em&gt;The Real World Homecoming: New York&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;60 Minutes Plus&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Kamp Koral: SpongeBob’s Under Years&lt;/em&gt; are among the service-specific titles you’ll only be able to stream with an active subscription. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="bKA0Vc"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Paramount Plus most recently offered a week-long trial — now’s your chance to get a whole month&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MF9tg5"&gt;The service should automatically apply the coupon code for the month-long trial at checkout, but in case it does not, the offer is valid with the coupon “movies.” The free 30-day subscription offer will end July 1st, &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/paramount-plus-subscription-deal-2021"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Insider&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ct9Ra7"&gt;Earlier this week, Paramount Plus introduced its new, cheaper “essential” plan that normally costs $5 per month. The ad-supported plan replaces an older $6-per-month plan that was grandfathered in from CBS All Access when the service &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22300993/paramount-plus-streaming-wars-netflix-disney-launch-date-price"&gt;relaunched as Paramount Plus&lt;/a&gt; in March. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8IpdGS"&gt;Many of us are already paying for far too many streaming services. We may as well snag the freebies where they’re available — just don’t forget to cancel if you don’t plan to stay.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22530341/paramount-plus-free-month-trial"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22530341/paramount-plus-free-month-trial</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-12T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-12T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung Galaxy A32 5G review: 5G on a budget</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;A sub-$300 phone that’s ready for the future&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="p7mUdG"&gt;If you’re looking for a 5G Android phone and want to spend as little as possible, you can stop right here. At $279, the Samsung Galaxy A32 5G is your best bet right now, especially if you’re in the US where such options are scarce. It offers good 5G support (including the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299903/fcc-cband-auction-results-verizon-att-tmobile"&gt;all-important C-band&lt;/a&gt;!), a huge battery, and four years of security updates. That’s a compelling package for under $300.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zHlDDa"&gt;That’s not to say it’s perfect. The A32 5G’s screen isn’t great, performance is a little laggy, and though capable, its camera is limited. If you can spend just a bit more, you can get a phone that does better in at least one of these areas. And if you can hold off on your phone purchase for even a few more months, we should see many more very affordable 5G phones on the market to choose from, like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522711/oneplus-n200-5g-specs-screen-price"&gt;OnePlus N200&lt;/a&gt;. But if you don’t have time to wait and can’t spare the extra cash, I can’t find a good reason to talk you out of the A32 5G. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="HOLmhP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10602493"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8FbAEW_mnjnHlY8Z1V6mGE19New=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22654071/ajohnson_20210608_4627_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The A32 5G is a big device, housing a 6.5-inch screen and a large 5,000mAh battery.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="GJsj8V"&gt;Samsung Galaxy A32 5G screen, performance, and design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="l4qYTS"&gt;The A32 5G features a big 6.5-inch 720p LCD panel that’s best described as nothing special. Colors look a little flat and washed out, and though it gets bright enough to see in direct sunlight, the screen’s reflective plastic protective panel makes it challenging. It’s also a low resolution to be stretched across such a large screen, so you’ll see a little pixelization if you look close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5LgiW1"&gt;The phone uses a MediaTek Dimensity 720 5G processor that compares well with Qualcomm’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/6/16/21286692/qualcomm-snapdragon-690-processor-5g-budget-phones-120-hz-4k-hdr-video"&gt;Snapdragon 690 5G chipset&lt;/a&gt; for budget 5G phones, used by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22214280/oneplus-nord-n10-5g-review"&gt;OnePlus Nord N10 5G&lt;/a&gt;. The Galaxy A32 5G combines the MediaTek processor with 4GB of RAM (decent) and 64GB of storage (skimpy but just enough to get by, and you can throw in a microSD card to expand it), and it performs well enough for its class. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="QpPgiJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The A32 5G features a big 6.5-inch 720p LCD panel that’s best described as nothing special&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XK7rOH"&gt;There’s noticeable hiccuping with media-dense pages, brief pauses when diving into a demanding task like starting Google Maps navigation, and noticeable camera shutter lag. For the most part, though, I just didn’t notice slowdowns as I jumped between apps, scrolled through Instagram, and just generally went about using the phone normally. That’s about all I’d ask for from a sub-$300 phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mELPZW"&gt;The phone’s headline feature, 5G, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22292074/5g-nationwide-verizon-att-tmobile-c-band"&gt;still isn’t something&lt;/a&gt; we’d recommend you run out and buy a new phone to get. But the A32 5G has a couple of features that make it worth your time, even considering that good 5G is still a year or two away in the US. Crucially, the A32 5G &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/news/samsungs-galaxy-a32-promises-c-band-5g-for-less-money"&gt;has been cleared by the Federal Communications Commission&lt;/a&gt; to use C-band frequencies that Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T, in particular, will be utilizing for 5G in the coming years. Not all 5G phones can use C-band, so that’s a big ol’ checkmark in the A32 5G’s favor. There’s no mmWave support here, which is the fastest and scarcest flavor of 5G, but that’s no great loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tfMqJO"&gt;The second factor here is that you can reasonably expect to keep using this phone for enough years to actually see 5G that’s meaningfully better than LTE because Samsung will keep offering security updates for four years. Many budget devices only get about two years of security update support, but the A32 5G’s lengthy lifespan should see it through to the actual 5G age in a few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="CwkX6s"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The A32 5G’s lengthy lifespan should see it through to the actual 5G age in a few years&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HX9CnL"&gt;Battery life is one of the A32 5G’s strengths. Its 5,000mAh capacity battery is big indeed, and I had no trouble getting two full days of moderate use out of it. My usage was more battery-friendly than someone else’s might be, with battery optimization on and the bulk of my time spent on Wi-Fi, but even the most power-hungry user would be able to get a full day — if not more — out of the A32 5G.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S7a2rr"&gt;With a 6.5-inch screen, the A32 5G is a big phone for sure. It’s a little too bulky and awkward-feeling in my hand. What I dislike even more is that it feels slippery to me — the back panel plastic feels hard to get a decent grip on. On one occasion, I set the phone down on a softcover book, and it somehow shimmied itself across the cover and off of a side table when I wasn’t looking. (There’s a happy ending, though: it only fell about a foot into a box filled with hand-me-down baby clothes waiting to be put away, so there’s a good argument for keeping clutter around your house.) Anyway, get a case for it if you buy this phone, and know that if your hands are small, it won’t be very comfortable to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d9eGBuNVVdirO_Sfgqwjj2ztPGw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22654072/ajohnson_20210608_4627_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s a decent-quality 48-megapixel main camera on the A32 5G’s rear panel.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="DqxxSP"&gt;Samsung Galaxy A32 5G camera&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="VH2X6K"&gt;There are two cameras of consequence on the A32 5G’s rear panel: a 48-megapixel standard wide and an 8-megapixel ultrawide. There’s a 5-megapixel macro camera that’s not very good and a 2-megapixel depth sensor that may or may not help with portrait mode photos. There’s also a 13-megapixel selfie camera around front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Ge8fdB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10602618"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jo6l5C"&gt;Considering the phone’s price, the A32 5G’s main camera performs well enough. Like most any other phone, it takes very nice pictures in good lighting. That’s no surprise, even for a budget phone. But it reaches its limits quickly in less-good lighting, like interiors. That’s where optical stabilization or more sophisticated image processing would come in handy, neither of which the A32 5G offers. Instead, you may find some of your photos indoors are a little blurry, and you’ll be very challenged to get a sharp photo of a moving subject in anything less than bright daylight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nZS8vo"&gt;The ultrawide camera shows its shortcomings if you look close — there’s some distracting flare in direct sunlight, and some noise visible in shadows of high-contrast scenes. There’s no telephoto lens here, with shortcuts in the camera app to jump to 2x (acceptable), 4x (eh), and 10x (don’t use it) digital zoom. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UKNWzLb6yiIqX-5QnIE4W7KaPxA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22654070/ajohnson_20210608_4627_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Galaxy A32 5G’s generous security support timeline means it’s a phone you can plan to use for the next few years.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="AFcAmw"&gt;It’s tough to say how the Galaxy A32 5G compares to the competition because it doesn’t have much yet. It’s among the least expensive 5G phones you’ll find anywhere. Its closest competition at the moment is the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22214280/oneplus-nord-n10-5g-review"&gt;OnePlus Nord N10 5G&lt;/a&gt;, which is a little more expensive at $299 but offers some worthwhile hardware upgrades, like a nicer screen, a bit better camera performance, and faster charging. It’s a nicer phone in a lot of ways, but it’s only slated for two years of security updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="7fRN5R"&gt;&lt;q&gt;If you want a future-proof choice that’s easy on the budget, then the Samsung A32 5G will do the trick&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8BEKVd"&gt;Of course, if you only plan to hold on to your phone for a couple of years, then the N10 5G is worth strongly considering. If that’s the case, then 5G becomes a less important feature, too. If there’s room in your budget, consider the $349 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21351770/google-pixel-4a-review-camera-specs-price"&gt;Google Pixel 4A&lt;/a&gt;, which will get you a much better camera, cleaner software, and timely updates over the next couple of years, albeit without support for 5G at all. It’s a much smaller device, though. So if a big screen is part of the A32 5G’s appeal, you might want to look at something like the $279 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22311690/motorola-moto-g-stylus-2021-review-price-specs"&gt;Motorola Moto G Stylus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="Bd53va"&gt;If you’d like to avoid the hassle of phone shopping again in two years and you want a future-proof choice that’s easy on the budget, then the Samsung A32 5G will do the trick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="97tZV2"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="eGh1VF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10602525"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22529760/samsung-galaxy-a32-5g-review-price-screen-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22529760/samsung-galaxy-a32-5g-review-price-screen-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-12T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-12T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Pharma is winning the big business popularity contest  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Boxes of the Moderna COVID-19 vaccine sitting in freezers..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Aa-37JAlccg0cVgZxFWQikrR0r0=/0x1535:3684x3991/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69443914/1233002445.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Jay L. Clendenin / Los Angeles Times via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vz4onF"&gt;It used to be easy to hate pharmaceutical companies. Between soaring drug costs and the opioid crisis, the industry was widely perceived as one that put profits over people’s health. In a &lt;a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/266060/big-pharma-sinks-bottom-industry-rankings.aspx"&gt;2019 Gallup survey&lt;/a&gt;, pharma was ranked dead last for positive perception among United States institutions. People had more positive feelings about the federal government than Big Pharma. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZuWCke"&gt;That year, technology companies were more popular. In a different survey, &lt;a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/265799/americans-split-regulation-big-tech.aspx"&gt;just under half&lt;/a&gt; of US adults had a positive view of the tech sector. It’s hard to compare two different polls head to head, but the general trend is clear: in 2019, people felt better about tech companies than they did about pharma. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PGcpJc"&gt;But then, the pandemic hit, and the country’s recovery depended on the success of vaccines. Government scrutiny of tech companies — from both sides of the aisle — picked up steam. And the two industries seem to have swapped places in the nationwide popularity contest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="Yt3qds"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9360449"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Gx5ACZ"&gt;The COVID-19 vaccines developed by companies like Pfizer, Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson, and Moderna are astonishingly effective. Their rollout has helped reduce levels of virus in parts of the US to some of the lowest they’ve been since March 2020. That success led to a boost in popularity for the drug companies. There were more people who had a favorable view than people who had an unfavorable view of the companies in a March 2021 &lt;a href="https://www.filesforprogress.org/datasets/2021/3/dfp-pharma-infrastructure-funding.pdf"&gt;Data for Progress survey&lt;/a&gt;, just as the vaccination campaign in the US was picking up steam. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pz4Xak"&gt;Meanwhile, during the pandemic, tech companies’ popularity took a &lt;a href="https://thehill.com/policy/technology/539367-views-of-big-tech-firms-worsen-over-past-18-months-poll?rl=1"&gt;nosedive&lt;/a&gt;. Democrats and Republicans both spent the past year highlighting various tech failures, and congressional hearings brought new attention to their &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21506682/google-apple-amazon-facebook-antitrust-report-house-judiciary"&gt;anti-competitive business practices&lt;/a&gt;. The group of US adults who have a positive view of the tech industry shrunk to around a third, according to a &lt;a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/329666/views-big-tech-worsen-public-wants-regulation.aspx?utm_source=alert&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_content=morelink&amp;amp;utm_campaign=syndication"&gt;February 2021 Gallup poll&lt;/a&gt;. And the number of people with a very negative opinion of the sector jumped to 22 percent, up from 10 percent in August 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yAOXRI"&gt;The past year recalibrated our relationships to both industries: the shine is off tech, and there’s an appreciation for some of the benefits of pharma. But the pandemic also highlighted how deeply they’re entangled in most people’s day-to-day lives, and how much they govern how we live, work, and move through the world. The past year showed that we can’t really go without either one — but that doesn’t mean we have to like them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="KwK39c"&gt;&lt;q&gt;the shine is off tech, and there’s an appreciation for some of the benefits of pharma&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9ati9Y"&gt;After all, drug prices &lt;a href="https://www.goodrx.com/blog/january-drug-price-hikes-2021/"&gt;kept going up this year&lt;/a&gt;, even as pharma racked up goodwill from the COVID-19 vaccines. Pharmaceutical company Biogen just slapped a &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/06/08/biogen-faces-tough-questions-over-56k-a-year-price-of-newly-approved-alzheimers-drug.html"&gt;$56,000 annual price tag&lt;/a&gt; on a new drug for Alzheimer’s that &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-021-01546-2"&gt;may not actually work&lt;/a&gt;. Congress is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301453/antitrust-facebook-google-amazon-apple-reform-cicilline-buck"&gt;still targeting&lt;/a&gt; the industry, and tech CEOs are making headlines for their &lt;a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/the-secret-irs-files-trove-of-never-before-seen-records-reveal-how-the-wealthiest-avoid-income-tax"&gt;tax avoidance&lt;/a&gt;. If trends continue the way they’re going, the popularity contest may be more like a race to the bottom. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KkqCMz"&gt;Here’s what happened this week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1NtbkT"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="wcMgWX"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/07/health/covid-alpha-uk-variant.html?smid=tw-share"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How the ‘Alpha’ Coronavirus Variant Became So Powerful&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="llBcUF"&gt;The coronavirus variant that was first identified in the United Kingdom, now known as the Alpha variant, can evade parts of the the immune system — which is partly why it spread so fast. (Carl Zimmer / &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tIXCLU"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2021/06/would-you-have-your-dna-tested-predict-how-hard-covid-19-would-strike-should-you"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Would you have your DNA tested to predict how hard COVID-19 would strike? Should you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TIprMP"&gt;An Australian company says it can use genetic and demographic data to predict someone’s risk of developing a severe case of COVID-19. But there isn’t much evidence to base those claims on. (Jocelyn Kaiser / &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wO3wsx"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/09/world/wuhan-animal-markets-covid.html?smid=tw-nytimes&amp;amp;smtyp=cur"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wuhan animal markets sold dozens of species that can carry pathogens that infect humans, a study found&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3FejzL"&gt;In another turn in the coronavirus origin story, researchers published data showing that Wuhan markets had dozens of animals that could theoretically harbor viruses dangerous to people. (Raymond Zhong / &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hlBYAS"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="vFYf4E"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2021/06/coronavirus-tests-variants/619112/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coronavirus Variants Have Nowhere to Hide&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Gmrxs"&gt;Coronavirus test makers are readjusting their formulas to make sure our tests can detect the new viral variants. (Katherine Wu / &lt;em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M5K4kz"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/08/health/us-vaccines-children-fall.html?partner=slack&amp;amp;smid=sl-share"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the U.S., vaccines for the youngest are expected this fall.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ObtlJr"&gt;Pharmaceutical companies Pfizer / BioNTech and Moderna are aiming to have data on how well their COVID-19 vaccines work in kids between five and 12 years old by September. The companies are testing lower doses of the shots for this group. (Apoorva Mandavilli / &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="nlMx5U"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perspectives &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="c4BSfd"&gt;We’re only beginning to understand pandemic trauma. Every COVID-19 death has unleashed a river of grief still flooding over the bereaved. Millions of coronavirus survivors are still ravaged by what the disease did to them. Even those who haven’t personally been touched by the virus have had to contend with lost jobs, anxiety, and missed opportunities. But for some people, the past year has also fundamentally broken their moral compass.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="bZPZwW"&gt;— Jonathan Moens &lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2021/06/pandemic-trauma-moral-injury/619129/"&gt;writes in &lt;em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; about the “moral injuries” of the pandemic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="5RnhMc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More than numbers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="CXf322"&gt;To the people who have received the 2.26 &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/covid-vaccine-tracker-global-distribution/"&gt;billion vaccine doses&lt;/a&gt; distributed so far — thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FIR3H3"&gt;To the more than 174,889,847 people worldwide who have tested positive, may your road to recovery be smooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rod8AM"&gt;To the families and friends of the 3,773,555 people who have died worldwide — 598,770 of those in the US — your loved ones are not forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lrpl1p"&gt;Stay safe, everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xs3CIn"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22529863/pharma-tech-opinion-pandemic-vaccines"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22529863/pharma-tech-opinion-pandemic-vaccines</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-12T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-12T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Normal Password System</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An illustration of several characters representing passwords and several question marks surrounding a giant stopwatch." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZHdEkH12q7Sq6E9U37dL_hAZ9cA=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69443896/VRG_4614_11_PasswordGame.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Maria Chimishkyan&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xnfkBW"&gt;A secure password is important for online account integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5MqX3V"&gt;On the following pages, you will be asked to generate a secure password. Please meet all listed requirements to complete your secure password. If you are unsure of the correct input for a given requirement, simply trust your impulses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DqYtLC"&gt;Also, try not to end the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YrPlCW"&gt;Play &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22290990"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Normal Password System: A Game&lt;/em&gt; game here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22526949/normal-password-system-generator-game"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22526949/normal-password-system-generator-game</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
      <name>William Joel</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-12T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-12T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>You can get some great tech and game deals ahead of Prime Day</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IWuEmoeuuKdtMwXlI2LJ0lCq_fc=/0x1:1137x759/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69443721/samsungq70ahero.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="J9ZKiV"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22459166/amazon-prime-day-dates-2021-june-21-22"&gt;Prime Day 2021&lt;/a&gt; is happening in just a little over a week, kicking off on Monday, June 21st, and lasting through Tuesday, June 22nd. In addition to keeping up with our regular deals cadence each day, we’ve been working hard behind the curtain to ensure that we’ll be able to bring you the best Prime Day coverage out there once it starts. To that end, we’re updating each of our useful deal guides, so you’ll be able to tell more easily when something that we recommend is discounted. We recently updated our guide to helping you find the best deals on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22307388/wireless-earbuds-deals-airpods-galaxy-buds-powerbeats"&gt;wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt;, for instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wnRd2b"&gt;It’s going to be a busy but great week ahead for deals. If you’re looking for savings, you’ll definitely want to see what’s coming on Prime Day, whether it’s at Amazon or at other retailers like Best Buy, Walmart, and Target. Until then, I’m going to give you what you came for: the best deals of the week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="OoZJsH"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="5zuwAe"&gt;Get $700 in gifts cards when you buy Samsung’s 85-inch Q70A QLED TV&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="OSxPt4"&gt;At Best Buy, you can get $700 in gift cards when you purchase Samsung’s 85-inch Q70A QLED TV. Originally $3,300, recent price cuts have reduced it to $2,800. Best Buy gifts cards obviously aren’t as good as a cash discount, but once factored in, it’s like getting this gargantuan, but very thin TV for $2,100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UK1DOn"&gt;This model has a 4K 120Hz refresh rate panel and it supports FreeSync, variable refresh rate and auto low-latency mode. It features an HDMI 2.1 port to allow PC and Xbox Series X to display games at up to 4K resolution at 120 frames per second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xXqHgU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10603517"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="F36KX5"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="WnBs98"&gt;Amazon’s Echo Show 5 is just $50 right now&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="hysBf5"&gt;You can stretch $50 pretty far these days, especially on tech. One way to spend your $50 is on Amazon’s first-generation Echo Show 5 smart display. It can display the time, weather, video content, and more. You can also hop on a video chat with its built-in camera and microphones. These originally sold for $90, but you can get one for nearly half the cost right now at one of the retailers below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="fNcjDa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513095"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="dwKocr"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="4Ta92i"&gt;Roku’s capable Ultra streaming box is $30 off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="MPyBss"&gt;If you’re in the market for a new streaming device that supports 4K output with Dolby Vision and HDR 10 as well as Atmos compatibility, Roku’s Ultra at $69 is a great value right now. I can’t forget to mention that the Ultra has an ethernet port, so you can get full speeds for streaming 4K content if your wireless network isn’t up to snuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="rfhAb8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10518754"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="f3sGc9"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Control" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/08uR2eJiVXuOSxa81QyzIZzNVxs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/20062302/control.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="8l1nEJ"&gt;Remedy’s &lt;em&gt;Control &lt;/em&gt;for PC is free at the Epic Game Store&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="3JKmPS"&gt;There’s a new free game at the Epic Games Store nearly every week, &lt;a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/p/control"&gt;and this week’s title is &lt;em&gt;Control&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. That info alone is enough for some people to just go ahead and click the link to grab the game. If you need a little more convincing, it’s a third-person action game in which  you investigate an otherworldly presence that has taken over a fictional version of the FBI. In addition to being a fun game to play, it’s got some dollops of &lt;em&gt;X-Files&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Twin Peaks&lt;/em&gt; inspiration in there, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GrfV4K"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/6/12/22529879/samsung-qled-q70a-amazon-echo-show-control-roku-ultra-streaming-gaming-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/6/12/22529879/samsung-qled-q70a-amazon-echo-show-control-roku-ultra-streaming-gaming-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-12T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-12T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon Echo Show 5 (second gen) review: small screen, small updates</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Amazon’s smallest smart display has gotten the tiniest of refreshes&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="wL02c4"&gt;Amazon recently updated a couple of its Alexa-based Echo Show smart displays. The new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22521948/amazon-echo-show-8-2nd-gen-2021-review"&gt;Echo Show 8 (second gen)&lt;/a&gt; saw a couple of enhancements over its predecessor, but the smaller Echo Show 5 has received an even smaller refresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Dg4dV"&gt;There are only three basic changes in the new &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/All-new-Echo-Show-5-2nd-Gen-2021-release-dp-B08KJN3333/dp/B08J8H8L5T?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$84.99 Echo Show 5 (2nd Gen)&lt;/a&gt;: it has a 2-megapixel camera instead of the 1-megapixel sensor of the first model; it comes in blue as well as the black and white color options; and the 3.5mm output jack on the back is gone. Unlike the larger Echo Show 8, the new 5 didn’t get a new processor, and its camera doesn’t feature the automatic panning and cropping that the Echo Show 8 and 10 offer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ofY0wY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10602714"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nancLy"&gt;That means that this new model provides effectively the same experience as the prior generation. It’s a compact smart display that’s best used as a smart alarm clock or a desk companion in a home office. The 5.5-inch 960 x 480-pixel touchscreen is bright and colorful, but not as easy to read from across the room as Amazon’s larger smart displays. It works as a monitor for a security camera or video doorbell, but I wouldn’t want to watch much video on it — your phone is a better device for that. If you insist, the Echo Show 5 supports Amazon Prime Video, Netflix, and YouTube via its browser, but not as many video services as the larger models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FxFoJKj27YiCmyTnBs4oIqch3Mo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653348/dseifert_4630_amazon_echo_show_5_2nd_gen_10.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new Echo Show 5 is available in blue, in addition to white or black.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T7Wpy12qv80d3zHEjK2SaCcazbE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653351/dseifert_4630_amazon_echo_show_5_2nd_gen_9.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 5’s camera has been upgraded to 2 megapixels, but it’s still not great. Fortunately, you can block it with the built-in privacy shutter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fRXXzK"&gt;The single speaker inside the wedge design gets surprisingly loud and puts out more bass than expected for its size, but it won’t as easily fill a room with sound. It works great for a morning alarm or listening to a podcast at a desk. The Echo Show 5 also has a handy feature that lets you tap the top of the device to snooze an alarm, which is easier than trying to say “Alexa snooze” when you’re half awake. (The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22357214/google-nest-hub-2nd-gen-2021-assistant-smart-display-review"&gt;Google Nest Hub’s&lt;/a&gt; ability to just stop the alarm with a single word, or to snooze when you wave your hand in front of it, is still better, though.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XzBMOL"&gt;Though the camera in the new model is 2 megapixels instead of 1, that’s not a huge upgrade. The Echo Show 5 doesn’t support Zoom, so you can’t use it for work calls, but it’s fine for calling from one Alexa smart display to another or to the Alexa app on a phone. Perhaps a more useful feature is the ability to view the camera’s feed through the Alexa app, so you can see what’s going on at home when you’re gone. If you don’t want to use the camera at all, you can block its view with the built-in privacy shutter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="10Lar9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Amazon’s new Echo Show 8 is a little faster and has a better camera","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22521948/amazon-echo-show-8-2nd-gen-2021-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="uabtP8"&gt;Since the second-gen Echo Show 5 has the same processor as the last model, it’s not any faster. Of Amazon’s smart display lineup, it’s certainly the pokiest, taking the most time to load a video feed from a security camera and taking an extra beat or two to pull up different screens or menus when you interact with it. Most people will probably not find that to be a problem, but if you were hoping for a speed increase this time around, sadly there isn’t one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R2fK2WiPef33PFDkDrBiJ-vjWz8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653346/dseifert_4630_amazon_echo_show_5_2nd_gen_12.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Kids Edition Echo Show 5 comes in a unique chameleon color.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ha2tClCh-INTLP5M4gjzLCgY84s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653342/dseifert_4630_amazon_echo_show_5_2nd_gen_16.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Kids Plus service that comes with the Kids Edition limits what can be played on the device.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TluHbV"&gt;Along with the standard Echo Show 5, Amazon is also now selling a Kids Edition model for $10 more. That gets you a custom blue-green-yellow chameleon color, a year’s subscription to the Kids Plus service, and a two-year warranty against accidental breakage. (A two-year damage warranty for a device that is supposed to stay put on a shelf or dresser doesn’t seem very valuable to me, but I’m sure some kid out there will find a way to break the thing.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wCq8tg"&gt;The Kids Plus service on the Echo Show is similar to what’s available on Amazon’s Fire HD Kids Edition tablets. It allows parents to customize which content and features are available on the devices and tailor them to their child’s age. It will play music from Amazon Music and won’t allow explicit tracks. It also removes certain features like smart home controls from the Show’s touch interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JYTjMT"&gt;On the tablets, it’s possible to have multiple profiles that can be switched between different kids, but the Echo Show doesn’t support that. If you’re planning to have more than one kid share it, you have to set the limitations to the age range of just one.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RmegLe4QIwWgtm5qQ8hwoprOd5g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653355/dseifert_4630_amazon_echo_show_5_2nd_gen_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new Echo Show 5 is effectively the same as the prior model﻿.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="DRFe2N"&gt;In all, the new Echo Show 5 (and its Kids Edition derivative) is basically the same as the prior model. It’s still a handy, compact smart display for a nightstand or desk, but it’s not as capable or fast as the larger Echo models in Amazon’s lineup. Given the limitations with the camera, I would be more interested in a model without a camera at all, similar to Google’s Nest Hub, as the bedroom alarm clock is the ideal use case here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V9atOn"&gt;At $84.99, the new model is $5 less expensive than its predecessor at launch, but Amazon frequently discounts its Echo devices and you’ll likely be able to find it for less than its retail price quite often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MDcCdl"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="TkRQZ9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10602736"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22529891/amazon-echo-show-5-2nd-gen-alexa-smart-display-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22529891/amazon-echo-show-5-2nd-gen-alexa-smart-display-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
