<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-30T12:13:57-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-30T12:13:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-30T12:13:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>Telecom groups sue New York over low-income broadband law</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TLuXQ8xj4fygvXeS0SyBMQTvaRY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69212795/acastro_180608_1777_net_neutrality_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yCLjSM"&gt;Trade groups representing some of the largest telecom companies, including AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon, are suing New York over a new state law forcing them to provide cheaper broadband plans for low-income families in the state, &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/att-verizon-new-york-broadband-law-41448df8-370c-403a-8826-60159daf1877.html"&gt;as first reported by &lt;em&gt;Axios&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ELBJq4"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388184/new-york-affordable-internet-cost-low-income-price-cap-bill"&gt;Earlier this month&lt;/a&gt;, New York Governor Andrew Cuomo signed a bill that would require internet service providers to offer a $15 a month broadband internet option for low-income consumers and families in the state. It’s one of the first laws in the country enforcing such a rule. But groups like USTelecom, CTIA, and the New York State Telecommunications Association argue that the state has no authority to set broadband prices and that the law could impair the companies’ abilities to upgrade their networks in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="y4mRWD"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“While well-intended, this bill is preempted by federal law”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NrsFPx"&gt;“While well-intended, this bill is preempted by federal law and ignores the $50 monthly broadband discount recently enacted by Congress, as well as the many unprecedented commitments, donations and accommodations that broadband providers have made for low-income consumers since the pandemic began,” the coalition said in a statement to &lt;em&gt;Axios &lt;/em&gt;Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="acKujh"&gt;As of right now, some internet providers offer their own low-income options for consumers, but none of these programs are mandated by law. There are other subsidy programs like Lifeline offered by the Federal Communications Commission that help decrease the cost of connectivity for families. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qTrkRJ"&gt;In December, Congress approved &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/21/22193133/us-coronavirus-covid-relief-stimulus-package-broadband-huawei-zte"&gt;over $3 billion&lt;/a&gt; to help consumers pay for internet service during the pandemic. The trade groups cite this law as a reason the New York broadband mandate goes too far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QgzCme"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="njwnEb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22412177/telecom-law-att-verizon-broadband-internet-new-york-state-low-income-plans"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22412177/telecom-law-att-verizon-broadband-internet-new-york-state-low-income-plans</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-30T12:10:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-30T12:10:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>‘Deepfake’ that supposedly fooled European politicians was just a look-alike, say pranksters</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wOaodCoWr8kkdZSdKPnCEyhco94=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69212765/VRG_ILLO_2727_002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deepfakes use AI techniques to generate or manipulate videos and pictures. &lt;/em&gt; | &lt;span data-author="-1"&gt;Artist: William Joel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="70SBoC"&gt;Last week, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/apr/22/european-mps-targeted-by-deepfake-video-calls-imitating-russian-opposition"&gt;numerous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://meduza.io/en/feature/2021/04/22/hello-this-is-leonid-volkov"&gt;news&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://nltimes.nl/2021/04/24/dutch-mps-video-conference-deep-fake-imitation-navalnys-chief-staff"&gt;outlets&lt;/a&gt; reported that a string of European politicians had been tricked by a sophisticated Russian plot. Parliamentarians from the UK, Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia had all arranged video calls with a hoaxer claiming to be Leonid Volkov, chief of staff to imprisoned Russian anti-Putin politician Alexei Navalny. As the politicians tell it, they fell victim to a digital fake: a doppelgänger created it using “deepfake” technology to trick politicians — the latest example of Russia’s misinformation campaigns in the West.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Uqtk2U"&gt;But the Russian men who orchestrated the calls say the “deepfake” claim is itself misinformation. Speaking to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, the hoaxers say their imitation Volkov was created using effects no more sophisticated than makeup and artfully obscure camera angles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="nOq39B"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The case of the fake deepfake&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="w4Ve9v"&gt;“Meet Leonid Volkov, Russian opposition leader,” says Vladimir Kuznetsov in a recent video call with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, introducing his colleague and partner-in-crime Alexei Stolyarov, a man who does indeed bear a passing resemblance to Leonid Volkov.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p9yO7p"&gt;The pair say they tricked their way into various meetings with European politicians and even a live interview on Latvian TV. They did so by cold-calling and emailing their targets from fake addresses, using a real picture of Volkov as their digital avatar. As proof, the pair shared some of this correspondence with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. They’ve also uploaded a meeting between “Volkov” and Ukrainian politicians to &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/MykU8zozL7g"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; and say more videos are coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g0BynE"&gt;“I didn’t need to prepare much to look like the real Volkov,” says Stolyarov. “I just had some brushes and some colors and that was enough.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CMlrnv51IWHACfYiZ9OZ_oH5up8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22481245/lexus_volkov_fake.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Vladimir Kuznetsov and Alexei Stolyarov&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An image showing Alexei Stolyarov, aka Lexus, in costume as Russian opposition leader Leonid Volkov. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="uQtBue"&gt;Kuznetsov and Stolyarov are better known as Vovan and Lexus: a pair of self-described “pranksters” who &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/mar/13/kremlin-calling-russian-pranksters-elton-john-owes-us"&gt;have a history&lt;/a&gt; of fooling Western politicians and celebrities. Over the years, the pair have tricked their way into phone calls with the likes of &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/nov/25/leave-nato-justin-trudeau-pranked-by-russian-duo-posing-as-greta-thunberg"&gt;Justin Trudeau&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/video/2015/sep/17/listen-to-hoax-elton-john-putin-call-by-pranksters-lexus-and-vovan-audio"&gt;Elton John&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://globalvoices.org/2020/02/16/russian-pranksters-target-bernie-sanders/"&gt;Bernie Sanders&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.gq.com/story/lindsey-graham-fooled-by-notorious-russian-pranksters"&gt;Lindsey Graham&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.thetimes.co.uk%2Farticle%2Frussia-hoax-boris-johnson-he-fell-right-into-our-trap-say-lexus-and-vovan-0s9hlqscp&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F30%2F22407264%2Fdeepfake-european-polticians-leonid-volkov-vovan-lexus" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Boris Johnson&lt;/a&gt;, each time aiming to catch these figures off-guard and tease potentially embarrassing statements out of them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="BdtgvW"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We wouldn’t prank Putin. We don’t want to harm our country”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YSf4sT"&gt;Although the pair have &lt;a href="https://www.gq.com/story/lindsey-graham-fooled-by-notorious-russian-pranksters"&gt;denied&lt;/a&gt; any official connections to the Kremlin, there’s no doubt their work is &lt;a href="https://monitoring.bbc.co.uk/product/c1dofhaw"&gt;useful to and supported by&lt;/a&gt; the Russian government. In the past, they’ve had their own show on Russian state TV and their antics approvingly covered by state news. They plainly know which side their bread is buttered. As &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/mar/13/kremlin-calling-russian-pranksters-elton-john-owes-us"&gt;Stolyarov told &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; a few years back: “We wouldn’t prank Putin. We don’t want to harm our country. We don’t want unrest here; we don’t want to do anything that would help the enemies of Russia.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3YubOB"&gt;Creating unrest elsewhere, though, is par for the course. “Our work is to prank high officials and celebrities and to make a lot of fun and publish it to social media,” says Stolyarov. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UlnqyK6u2e2YLB-ygj0IJ-Nqdek=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22481256/Screen_Shot_2021_04_30_at_4.04.35_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://youtu.be/MykU8zozL7g" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A screenshot showing Stolyarov posing as Volkov (top left), speaking with Ukrainian officials, including the country’s youngest MP, Sviatoslav Yurash (top right)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="csqOVU"&gt;The pair say they chose to impersonate Volkov for a number of reasons. Firstly, because of the newsworthiness of Navalny. After leading the most substantial opposition to Russian president Vladimir Putin in years, Navalny has been &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-56919934"&gt;imprisoned&lt;/a&gt;. He recently ended a 24-day hunger strike and continues to criticize the Russian government despite the expectation that his nationwide political movement will be &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/apr/30/russian-state-watchdog-adds-navalny-network-to-terrorism-database"&gt;outlawed soon&lt;/a&gt;. Secondly, because of Stolyarov’s resemblance. And thirdly, because the real Volkov hasn’t sought many meetings with Western politicians, meaning few had any familiarity with how he looks and sounds. An unspoken fourth motivation is to ridicule anti-Putin forces, in line with the duo’s politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BeTxyB"&gt;Kuznetsov and Stolyarov have carried out numerous pranks over the years (you can &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/Vovan222prank/videos"&gt;browse their YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt; for a selection) though not all have gained media attention. What made this particular campaign stand out is its connection with deepfakes — AI-generated or manipulated media that many fear will be used as a tool of political misinformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="m7b6PL"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Despite fears, deepfakes have yet to make a major political impact&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CjYj8l"&gt;Over the years, experts have warned about a so-called “infopocalypse,” where the quality and availability of deepfakes make it impossible for the public to distinguish truth and fiction. So far, this dire prediction &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/5/18251736/deepfake-propaganda-misinformation-troll-video-hoax"&gt;has not come to pass&lt;/a&gt;. The most damaging effects of deepfakes have been in the generation of nonconsensual pornography. And although politics has, indeed, been dogged in recent years by hoaxes and misinformation, such incidents almost always revolve around video and images &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/24/18637771/nancy-pelosi-congress-deepfake-video-facebook-twitter-youtube"&gt;edited the old-fashioned way&lt;/a&gt;. Nevertheless, the specter of deepfakes still haunts politics — as this recent incident shows. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WdT3AR"&gt;It’s not clear when the fake Volkov calls were first blamed on AI technology, but it seems Volkov himself might be the source. Latvian politician Rihards Kols &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/KolsRihards/photos/a.1376884405665151/4129529840400580/?type=3"&gt;posted on Facebook&lt;/a&gt; on April 22nd that he had been tricked into taking a call in March with an unknown prankster, and shared two pictures supposedly showing the real and fake Volkovs. Volkov then &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/leonid.m.volkov/posts/4004434886245781"&gt;reposted the images&lt;/a&gt; that same day, ascribing the prank to Vovan and Lexus, but also suggesting that AI was used. “Looks like my real face — but how did they manage to put it on the Zoom call?” he wrote, according to a Facebook translation. “Welcome to the deep-fake era.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZBAP_jhgQuymA-uAafLnD6BP2vs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22481264/Screen_Shot_2021_04_30_at_4.07.10_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.facebook.com/leonid.m.volkov/posts/4004434886245781" target="_blank"&gt;Leonid Volkov via Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A screenshot showing a Facebook post from Leonid Volkov, shared on April 22nd, in which he suggests a real picture of himself is a deepfake.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="I9YG58"&gt;From here it seems the line spread. The next day, Kols, who is chair of Latvia’s Foreign Affairs Committee, posted a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RihardsKols/status/1385576305056534533/photo/1"&gt;statement on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; co-signed by his counterparts from Lithuania and Estonia. The trio warned about the threat posed by “deepfake technologies,” and say the pranks were “targeted attacks on the Kremlin’s critics.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="NdO4zI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We encourage all to remain vigilant yet open”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SrNhV6"&gt;“During the past few months, disinformation operations with the use of manipulated and artificial intelligence (AI) generated media were carried out against Estonian, Latvian, Lithuanian and the United Kingdom’s politicians, non-governmental organisations, and media representatives,” says the statement. “We encourage all to remain vigilant yet open to communication, as representatives of true democracies always should be!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YTq845"&gt;Kuznetsov and Stolyarov say that they’re surprised the prank was described as a deepfake, not least because the image they used in their accounts, and that was identified by Volkov himself as fake, is &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/Bp4_yz741kc"&gt;taken from a real video&lt;/a&gt;. “It was his real picture but he denied it was him,” says Stolyarov, before Kuznetsov adds that perhaps Volkov didn’t like the picture because he looked “too fat.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4heOK8"&gt;Whether politicians blamed the trick on deepfakes out of genuine confusion or more self-serving reasons isn’t clear. Certainly it’s less embarrassing to be fooled by a sophisticated AI fake than a couple of pranksters with a convincing email manner. But the incident does illustrate that the fear of deepfakes is having as much an effect on misinformation as the technology itself. For those tricked by Kuznetsov and Stolyarov — aka Vovan and Lexus — blaming new technology may simply have been a matter of saving face.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22407264/deepfake-european-polticians-leonid-volkov-vovan-lexus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22407264/deepfake-european-polticians-leonid-volkov-vovan-lexus</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-30T10:45:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-30T10:45:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>How a university got itself banned from the Linux kernel</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZeCW2I447Omi8F36hkCWQ4ws-sA=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69212102/VRG_ILLO_4566_001.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The University of Minnesota’s path to banishment was long, turbulent, and full of emotion&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="XULSBW"&gt;On the evening of April 6th, a student &lt;a href="https://lore.kernel.org/linux-nfs/20210407001658.2208535-1-pakki001@umn.edu/"&gt;emailed&lt;/a&gt; a patch to a list of developers. Fifteen days later, the University of Minnesota was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22398156/university-minnesota-linux-kernal-ban-research"&gt;banned&lt;/a&gt; from contributing to the Linux kernel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KdTpZS"&gt;“I suggest you find a different community to do experiments on,” wrote Linux Foundation fellow Greg Kroah-Hartman in a livid email. “You are not welcome here.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sPhubA"&gt;How did one email lead to a university-wide ban? I’ve spent the past week digging into this world — the players, the jargon, the university’s turbulent history with open-source software, the devoted and principled Linux kernel community. None of the University of Minnesota researchers would talk to me for this story. But among the other major characters — the Linux developers — there was no such hesitancy. This was a community eager to speak; it was a community betrayed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="NjM21b"&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="pqo6z9"&gt;The story begins in 2017, when a systems-security researcher named Kangjie Lu became an assistant professor at the University of Minnesota. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9ZwEna"&gt;Lu’s research, per his &lt;a href="https://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kjlu/"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, concerns “the intersection of security, operating systems, program analysis, and compilers.” But Lu had his eye on Linux — most of his papers involve the Linux kernel in some way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="42jzGk"&gt;The Linux kernel is, at a basic level, the core of any Linux operating system. It’s the liaison between the OS and the device on which it’s running. A Linux user doesn’t interact with the kernel, but it’s essential to getting things done — it manages memory usage, writes things to the hard drive, and decides what tasks can use the CPU when. The kernel is open-source, meaning its millions of lines of code are publicly available for anyone to view and contribute to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="A8yiDu"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Getting a patch on people’s computers is no easy task&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="edPPVd"&gt;Well, “anyone.” Getting a patch onto people’s computers is no easy task. A submission needs to pass through a large web of developers and “maintainers” (&lt;a href="https://www.kernel.org/doc/html/latest/process/maintainers.html"&gt;thousands&lt;/a&gt; of volunteers, who are each responsible for the upkeep of different parts of the kernel) before it ultimately ends up in the mainline repository. Once there, it goes through a long testing period before eventually being incorporated into the “stable release,” which will go out to mainstream operating systems. It’s a rigorous system designed to weed out both malicious and incompetent actors. But — &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/a-teen-threw-scots-wiki-into-chaos-and-it-highlights-a-1844851959"&gt;as is always the case with crowdsourced operations&lt;/a&gt; — there’s room for human error. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FH2Yi5"&gt;Some of Lu’s recent work has revolved around studying that potential for human error and reducing its influence. He’s &lt;a href="https://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kjlu/papers/lrsan.pdf"&gt;proposed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kjlu/papers/deadline.pdf"&gt;systems&lt;/a&gt; to automatically detect various types of bugs in open source, using the Linux kernel as a test case. These experiments tend to involve reporting bugs, submitting patches to Linux kernel maintainers, and reporting their acceptance rates. In &lt;a href="https://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kjlu/papers/crix.pdf"&gt;a 2019 paper&lt;/a&gt;, for example, Lu and two of his PhD students, Aditya Pakki and Qiushi Wu, presented a system (“Crix”) for detecting a certain class of bugs in OS kernels. The trio found 278 of these bugs with Crix and submitted patches for all of them — the fact that maintainers accepted 151 meant the tool was promising. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sgdJH0"&gt;On the whole, it was a useful body of work. Then, late last year, Lu took aim not at the kernel itself, but at its community. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="CnYKoW"&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="hnIyA7"&gt;In “On the Feasibility of Stealthily Introducing Vulnerabilities in Open-Source Software via Hypocrite Commits,” Lu and Wu &lt;a href="https://linuxreviews.org/images/d/d9/OpenSourceInsecurity.pdf"&gt;explained&lt;/a&gt; that they’d been able to introduce vulnerabilities into the Linux kernel by submitting patches that appeared to fix real bugs but also introduced serious problems. The group called these submissions “hypocrite commits.” (Wu didn’t respond to a request for comment for this story; Lu referred me to Mats Heimdahl, the head of the university’s department of computer science and engineering, who referred me to the &lt;a href="https://cse.umn.edu/cs/linux-incident"&gt;department’s website&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YAfw07"&gt;The explicit goal of this experiment, as the researchers have since emphasized, was to improve the security of the Linux kernel by demonstrating to developers how a malicious actor might slip through their net. One could argue that their process was similar, in principle, to that of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382243/counter-strike-global-offensive-game-engine-bug-take-over-pc"&gt;white-hat hacking&lt;/a&gt;: play around with software, find bugs, let the developers know.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ddsgcu"&gt;But the loudest reaction the paper received, on Twitter and across the Linux community, wasn’t gratitude — it was outcry. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4Jnht7"&gt;“That paper, it’s just a lot of crap,” says &lt;a href="https://www.dgregscott.com/"&gt;Greg Scott&lt;/a&gt;, an IT professional who has worked with open-source software for over 20 years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s0uipp"&gt;“In my personal view, it was completely unethical,” says security researcher Kenneth White, who is co-director of the Open Crypto Audit Project. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9I0YgA"&gt;The frustration had little to do with the hypocrite commits themselves. In their paper, Lu and Wu claimed that none of their bugs had actually made it to the Linux kernel — in all of their test cases, they’d eventually pulled their bad patches and provided real ones. Kroah-Hartman, of the Linux Foundation, contests this — he told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;that one patch from the study did make it into repositories, though he notes it didn’t end up causing any harm. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="nFkMS3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“In my personal view, it was completely unethical.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="n9pQxJ"&gt;Still, the paper hit a number of nerves among a very passionate (and very online) community when Lu first shared its abstract on Twitter. Some developers were angry that the university had intentionally wasted the maintainers’ time — which is a key difference between Minnesota’s work and a white-hat hacker poking around the Starbucks app for a bug bounty. “The researchers crossed a line they shouldn’t have crossed,” Scott says. “Nobody hired this group. They just chose to do it. And a whole lot of people spent a whole lot of time evaluating their patches.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K4Phq6"&gt;“If I were a volunteer putting my personal time into commits and testing, and then I found out someone’s experimenting, I would be unhappy,” Scott adds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TfFr6T"&gt;Then, there’s the dicier issue of whether an experiment like this amounts to human experimentation. It doesn’t, according to the University of Minnesota’s Institutional Review Board. Lu and Wu applied for approval in response to the outcry, and they were granted a formal letter of exemption. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lx7v1K"&gt;The community members I spoke to didn’t buy it. “The researchers attempted to get retroactive Institutional Review Board approval on their actions that were, at best, wildly ignorant of the tenants of basic human subjects’ protections, which are typically taught by senior year of undergraduate institutions,” says White. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iI6jly"&gt;“It is generally not considered a nice thing to try to do ‘research’ on people who do not know you are doing research,” says Kroah-Hartman. “No one asked us if it was acceptable.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="zcqpgh"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“That paper, it’s just a lot of crap.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oy5r3K"&gt;That thread ran through many of the responses I got from developers — that regardless of the harms or benefits that resulted from its research, the university was messing around not just with community members but with the community’s underlying philosophy. Anyone who uses an operating system places some degree of trust in the people who contribute to and maintain that system. That’s especially true for people who use open-source software, and it’s a principle that some Linux users take very seriously. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3CmaAX"&gt;“By definition, open source depends on a lively community,” Scott says. “There have to be people in that community to submit stuff, people in the community to document stuff, and people to use it and to set up this whole feedback loop to constantly make it stronger. That loop depends on lots of people, and you have to have a level of trust in that system ... If somebody violates that trust, that messes things up.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q2aWfe"&gt;After the paper’s release, it was clear to many Linux kernel developers that something needed to be done about the University of Minnesota — previous submissions from the university needed to be reviewed. “Many of us put an item on our to-do list that said, ‘Go and audit all umn.edu submissions,’” said Kroah-Hartman, who was, above all else, annoyed that the experiment had put another task on his plate. But many kernel maintainers are volunteers with day jobs, and a large-scale review process didn’t materialize. At least, not in 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="oA0qq4"&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="FLKEe2"&gt;On April 6th, 2021, Aditya Pakki, using his own email address, submitted a patch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i4Casu"&gt;There was some brief discussion from other developers on the email chain, which fizzled out within a few days. Then Kroah-Hartman took a look. He was already on high alert for bad code from the University of Minnesota, and Pakki’s email address set off alarm bells. What’s more, the patch Pakki submitted didn’t appear helpful. “It takes a lot of effort to create a change that looks correct, yet does something wrong,” Kroah-Hartman told me. “These submissions all fit that pattern.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2pAAw9"&gt;So on April 20th, Kroah-Hartman put his foot down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QcinS0"&gt;“Please stop submitting known-invalid patches,” he wrote to Pakki. “Your professor is playing around with the review process in order to achieve a paper in some strange and bizarre way.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bHXBg3"&gt;Maintainer Leon Romanovsky then chimed in: he’d taken a look at four previously accepted patches from Pakki and found that three of them added “various severity” security vulnerabilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="a8qlGl"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There’s the dicier issue of whether an experiment like this amounts to human experimentation&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GI1dpe"&gt;Kroah-Hartman hoped that his request would be the end of the affair. But then Pakki lashed back. “I respectfully ask you to cease and desist from making wild accusations that are bordering on slander,” he wrote to Kroah-Hartman in what appears to be a private message. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VhdhKS"&gt;Kroah-Hartman responded. “You and your group have publicly admitted to sending known-buggy patches to see how the kernel community would react to them, and published a paper based on that work. Now you submit a series of obviously-incorrect patches again, so what am I supposed to think of such a thing?” he wrote back on the morning of April 21st. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eCJc02"&gt;Later that day, Kroah-Hartman made it official. “Future submissions from anyone with a umn.edu address should be default-rejected unless otherwise determined to actually be a valid fix,” he wrote in an &lt;a href="https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/20210421130105.1226686-1-gregkh@linuxfoundation.org/"&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; to a number of maintainers, as well as Lu, Pakki, and Wu. Kroah-Hartman reverted 190 submissions from Minnesota affiliates — 68 couldn’t be reverted but still needed manual review. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cq6KHD"&gt;It’s not clear what experiment the new patch was part of, and Pakki declined to comment for this story. &lt;a href="https://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kjlu/"&gt;Lu’s website&lt;/a&gt; includes a brief reference to “superfluous patches from Aditya Pakki for a new bug-finding project.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E5djNb"&gt;What is clear is that Pakki’s antics have finally set the delayed review process in motion; Linux developers began digging through all patches that university affiliates had submitted in the past. Jonathan Corbet, the founder and editor in chief of &lt;a href="http://LWN.net"&gt;&lt;em&gt;LWN.net&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;recently provided an update on that review process. Per his assessment, “Most of the suspect patches have turned out to be acceptable, if not great.” Of over 200 patches that were flagged, 42 are still set to be removed from the kernel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="Oc8Kad"&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="auc05d"&gt;Regardless of whether their reaction was justified, the Linux community gets to decide if the University of Minnesota affiliates can contribute to the kernel again. And that community has made its demands clear: the school needs to convince them its future patches won’t be a waste of anyone’s time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QMmDNL"&gt;What will it take to do that? In a statement released the same day as the ban, the university’s computer science department suspended its research into Linux-kernel security and &lt;a href="https://cse.umn.edu/cs/statement-cse-linux-kernel-research-april-21-2021"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that it would investigate Lu’s and Wu’s research method. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nmnl4i"&gt;But that wasn’t enough for the Linux Foundation. Mike Dolan, Linux Foundation SVP and GM of projects, wrote a letter to the university on April 23rd, which &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; has viewed. Dolan made four demands. He asked that the school release “all information necessary to identify all proposals of known-vulnerable code from any U of MN experiment” to help with the audit process. He asked that the paper on hypocrite commits be withdrawn from publication. He asked that the school ensure future experiments undergo IRB review before they begin, and that future IRB reviews ensure the subjects of experiments provide consent, “per usual research norms and laws.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="AMJbpW"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The school needs to convince them its future patches won’t be a waste of anyone’s time&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ELMevG"&gt;Two of those demands have since been met. Wu and Lu have &lt;a href="https://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kjlu/papers/withdrawal-letter.pdf"&gt;retracted&lt;/a&gt; the paper and have &lt;a href="https://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kjlu/papers/full-disclosure.pdf"&gt;released&lt;/a&gt; all the details of their study. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d9h2N7"&gt;The university’s status on the third and fourth counts is unclear. In a &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1z3Nm2bfR4tH1nOGBpuOmLyoJVEiO9cUq/view"&gt;letter&lt;/a&gt; sent to the Linux Foundation on April 27th, Heimdahl and Loren Terveen (the computer science and engineering department's associate department head) maintain that the university’s IRB “acted properly,” and argues that human-subjects research “has a precise technical definition according to US federal regulations ... and this technical definition may not accord with intuitive understanding of concepts like ‘experiments’ or even ‘experiments on people.’” They do, however, commit to providing more ethics training for department faculty. Reached for comment, university spokesperson Dan Gilchrist referred me to the computer science and engineering department’s website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lku4VP"&gt;Meanwhile, Lu, Wu, and Pakki apologized to the Linux community this past Saturday in an &lt;a href="https://lore.kernel.org/lkml/CAK8KejpUVLxmqp026JY7x5GzHU2YJLPU8SzTZUNXU2OXC70ZQQ@mail.gmail.com/"&gt;open letter&lt;/a&gt; to the kernel mailing list, which contained some apology and some defense. “We made a mistake by not finding a way to consult with the community and obtain permission before running this study; we did that because we knew we could not ask the maintainers of Linux for permission, or they would be on the lookout for hypocrite patches,” the researchers wrote, before going on to reiterate that they hadn’t put any vulnerabilities into the Linux kernel, and that their other patches weren’t related to the hypocrite commits research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3HqHUW"&gt;Kroah-Hartman wasn’t having it. “The Linux Foundation and the Linux Foundation’s Technical Advisory Board submitted a letter on Friday to your university,” he responded. “Until those actions are taken, we do not have anything further to discuss.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Coronavirus in Minnesota" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WvK57bEtKhXQvNIoYX1jw_VV-WI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22479520/1220247994.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Glen Stubbe / Star Tribune via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Gkbvgw"&gt;From the University of Minnesota researchers’ perspective, they didn’t set out to troll anyone — they were trying to point out a problem with the kernel maintainers’ review process. Now the Linux community has to reckon with the fallout of their experiment and what it means about the security of open-source software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rzmFWO"&gt;Some &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rakyll/status/1385075395884556293?s=20"&gt;developers&lt;/a&gt; rejected University of Minnesota researchers’ perspective outright, claiming the fact that it’s possible to fool maintainers should be obvious to anyone familiar with open-source software. “If a sufficiently motivated, unscrupulous person can put themselves into a trusted position of updating critical software, there’s honestly little that can be done to stop them,” says White, the security researcher. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Th1dgm"&gt;On the other hand, it’s clearly important to be vigilant about potential vulnerabilities in any operating system. And for others in the Linux community, as much ire as the experiment drew, its point about hypocrite commits appears to have been somewhat well taken. The incident has ignited conversations about patch-acceptance policies and how maintainers should handle submissions from new contributors, across Twitter, &lt;a href="https://lore.kernel.org/ksummit/a72a13e56ee5f19b0dee9ae8c1928b020e8809c2.camel@HansenPartnership.com/"&gt;email lists&lt;/a&gt;, and forums. “Demonstrating this kind of ‘attack’ has been long overdue, and kicked off a very important discussion,” wrote maintainer Christoph Hellwig in an email thread with other maintainers. “I think they deserve a medal of honor.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vk2OZA"&gt;“This research was clearly unethical, but it did make it plain that the OSS development model is vulnerable to bad-faith commits,” one user wrote in a &lt;a href="https://lobste.rs/s/9miojb/hypocrite_commits_apology_letter"&gt;discussion post&lt;/a&gt;. “It now seems likely that Linux has some devastating back doors.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UowDM6"&gt;Corbet also called for more scrutiny around new changes in his &lt;a href="https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/854645/e7eff3462424263e/"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; about the incident. “If we cannot institutionalize a more careful process, we will continue to see a lot of bugs, and it will not really matter whether they were inserted intentionally or not,” he wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="0dl7V7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“This method works.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="i3gudX"&gt;And even for some of the paper’s most ardent critics, the process did prove a point — albeit, perhaps, the opposite of the one Wu, Lu, and Pakki were trying to make. It demonstrated that the system worked. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VN6gnK"&gt;Eric Mintz, who manages 25 Linux servers, says this ban has made him much more confident in the operating system’s security. “I have more trust in the process because this was caught,” he says. “There may be compromises we don’t know about. But because we caught this one, it’s less likely we don’t know about the other ones. Because we have something in place to catch it.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y2M3ud"&gt;To Scott, the fact that the researchers were caught and banned is an example of Linux’s system functioning exactly the way it’s supposed to. “This method worked,” he insists. “The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/26/22248631/solarwinds-hack-cybersecurity-us-menn-decoder-podcast"&gt;SolarWinds&lt;/a&gt; method, where there’s a big corporation behind it, that system didn’t work. This system did work.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5FrnAf"&gt;“Kernel developers are happy to see new tools created and — if the tools give good results — use them. They will also help with the testing of these tools, but they are less pleased to be recipients of tool-inspired patches that lack proper review,” Corbet writes. The community seems to be open to the University of Minnesota’s feedback — but as the Foundation has made clear, it’s on the school to make amends. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="0dvAPo"&gt;“The university could repair that trust by sincerely apologizing, and not fake apologizing, and by maybe sending a lot of beer to the right people,” Scott says. “It’s gonna take some work to restore their trust. So hopefully they’re up to it.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kBzo77"&gt;
&lt;script src="https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/jquery/3.5.1/jquery.min.js" type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
$(".c-entry-hero__image").html( '&lt;style&gt;.header-video { position: relative; width:100%; height: calc(var(—vh, 1vh) * 100); background-color: transparent; object-fit: cover; display: block;} @media screen and (max-width:960px) {.header-video {height: 100%;margin-bottom: 24px;} }&lt;/style&gt;&lt;video class="header-video" muted="" loop="" autoplay="" playsinline="" poster="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22480526/VRG_ILLO_4566_003.jpg"&gt;&lt;source type="video/mp4" src="https://volume-assets.voxmedia.com/production/740be0bd4ccb2cfece1b4a1e41a6ae2b/VRG_ILLO_4566_002.mp4"&gt;&lt;/video&gt;');

window.addEventListener('DOMContentLoaded', (event) =&gt; {
  document.documentElement.classList.add('js');
  
  let isAndroid = false;
  let isIOS = false;

  var userAgent = navigator.userAgent || navigator.vendor || window.opera;
  if (/android/i.test(userAgent)) {
    isAndroid = true;
  }
  if (userAgent.match(/iPhone|iPad|iPod/i)) {
    isIOS = true;
  }

  if (isIOS) {
    document.body.classList.add('ios');
  }
  if (isAndroid) {
    document.body.classList.add('android');
  }

  let vh = window.innerHeight * 0.01;
  document.documentElement.style.setProperty('—vh', `${vh}px`);
});
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22410164/linux-kernel-university-of-minnesota-banned-open-source"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22410164/linux-kernel-university-of-minnesota-banned-open-source</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-30T10:11:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-30T10:11:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>You can save up to $147 on a preorder for the latest M1 iPad Pro or iMac</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XuagldWx4arBbKfspjX2DG3qcc0=/156x0:1844x1125/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69211882/lcimg_06ebca85_7eac_4c32_9e8f_4b98fad99ec8.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The latest iPad Pros are powered by the M1 chip.&lt;/em&gt; | Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="F58ugb"&gt;Following the official reveal last week of the new model refreshes for the iMac and iPad Pros, all of which are powered by Apple’s own silicon — the M1 chip — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22409463/apple-m1-imac-ipad-pro-apple-tv-4k-preorders-price-release-date"&gt;preorders began for all three products today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4DCXL7"&gt;As spotted first by &lt;a href="https://9to5toys.com/2021/04/30/apple-m1-imac-expercom-deals/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+9to5macToys+%289to5Mac+Toys%29"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Toys&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Expercom is offering an incentive if you pre-purchase any of the &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fexpercom.com%2Fcollections%2Fipad%2Fproducts%2Fnew-ipad-pro-12-9-inch-2021-model%3Fvariant%3D39316140621858#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;three&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fexpercom.com%2Fcollections%2Fipad%2Fproducts%2Fnew-ipad-pro-12-9-inch-2021-model%3Fvariant%3D39316140621858#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;new&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fexpercom.com%2Fcollections%2Fimac%2Fproducts%2F24-inch-imac-with-apple-m1-7-core-gpu-blue#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;M1 products&lt;/a&gt;, with up to $147 in savings available depending on the configuration you select, making this the first time any of these three brand-new products have seen a discount yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="daDOJC"&gt;The base &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fexpercom.com%2Fcollections%2Fimac%2Fproducts%2F24-inch-imac-with-apple-m1-7-core-gpu-blue" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;M1 iMac is available for preorder at Expercom&lt;/a&gt; for as low as $1,233 ($66 off); this configuration includes 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage. As noted previously, the configurations vary, but there are price reductions for multiple configurations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4AzLJi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10474631"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Fpeu6S"&gt;The 2021 iPad Pros are the first in Apple’s tablet line to include the M1 processor. The 11-inch iPad Pro is more affordable with a starting price of $799. But Expercom is offering the base model, which includes &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fexpercom.com%2Fcollections%2Fipad%2Fproducts%2Fipad-pro-11-inch-1%3Fvariant%3D39316139212834#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;128GB of storage with Wi-Fi only, for $750&lt;/a&gt; — $49 off its usual starting price. You can also select the option to get more storage or 5G network support, all of which vary in price depending on which configuration you choose. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2nBbHZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10474637"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VEfgW0"&gt;Along with the 11-inch iPad Pro, the 12.9-inch model also receives a model refresh, which includes the M1 chip. This flagship tablet has a new Liquid Retina XDR Mini LED screen and starts at $1,099 for the base 128GB storage configuration with Wi-Fi only. But you can get this &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fexpercom.com%2Fcollections%2Fipad%2Fproducts%2Fnew-ipad-pro-12-9-inch-2021-model%3Fvariant%3D39316139999266#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;particular model for $1,032 at Expercom&lt;/a&gt; with up to $147 off if you get the highest storage configuration plus Wi-Fi and cellular support. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="idquVm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10474645"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Q7Ns15"&gt;Mother’s Day is coming up; if you are looking for a good gift to give your mother, an Amazon Echo Show 8 might be a good gadget for consideration. Usually $130, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PF1Y28C?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=6892ea59e23a8ae0553d9a5cddb37193&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724867471427496922#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Famazon-echo-show-8-hd-8in-smart-display%2F-%2FA-81795783%3Fpreselect%3D78656158%26clkid%3D7eebb553N627e11ebb06342010a246e3d%26lnm%3D81938%26afid%3DVox%2520Media%26ref%3Dtgt_adv_xasd0002%26clkid%3D7eebb553N627e11ebb06342010a246e3d%26lnm%3D81938%26afid%3DVox%2520Media%26ref%3Dtgt_adv_xasd0002%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;subid1=VergeEchoDeals03012021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt; have the device on sale for $105. If you’re looking for more Mother’s Day gift ideas, be sure to check out our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22358371/mothers-day-gifts-ideas-best-mom-tech-gadgets" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Mother’s Day 2021 Gift Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="NFzdm8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9573987"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="ncfvgz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Verge’s Mother’s Day Gift Guide 2021","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22358371/mothers-day-gifts-ideas-best-mom-tech-gadgets"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id="4KCJLb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="EE6WnO"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0MpZCq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/4/30/22411755/apple-imac-ipad-pro-m1-preorder-discount-amazon-echo-show-5-deal"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/4/30/22411755/apple-imac-ipad-pro-m1-preorder-discount-amazon-echo-show-5-deal</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-30T10:06:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-30T10:06:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>Next week’s Fortnite trial could upend Apple’s App Store model — even if Epic loses</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0K83EUzfEK24jFSjGX5fNt-lW_s=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69211874/acastro_210429_1777_epicApple_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Epic will put Apple’s business under a microscope&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="G21BQ5"&gt;In August 2020, mega-publisher Epic Games decided to stop paying what’s dubbed the “Apple tax”: a 30 percent fee on digital purchases made through the iOS App Store. The company added a new feature to its blockbuster game &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;, letting users bypass the App Store’s payment system to purchase V-Bucks, &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;’s&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;in-game currency. The move violated Apple’s guidelines, and Apple promptly kicked &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; off the App Store. Epic sued Apple for antitrust violations, and on Monday, the case will finally go to court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fMZP39"&gt;Epic has a clear grievance against Apple: it’s locked out of the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253162/iphone-users-total-number-billion-apple-tim-cook-q1-2021"&gt;billion-plus iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/29/18202736/apple-devices-ios-earnings-q1-2019"&gt;iPad user base&lt;/a&gt;. But US antitrust law focuses on whether a company has hurt &lt;em&gt;consumers&lt;/em&gt; by suppressing competition. So over the next three weeks, Apple and Epic will lay out sharply conflicting stories about how a locked-down App Store affects users. Unlike a lot of tech trial arguments, which focus on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/9/21506172/oracle-google-java-supreme-court-hearings-oral-arguments-metaphors-qwerty"&gt;abstract hypotheticals and metaphors&lt;/a&gt;, these are vivid narratives about some of the most central products in our lives — and they play into one of the most important debates in US politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="pNomsn"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Epic calls Apple a “uniquely powerful” company with “unique control” over iOS&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="emfoi1"&gt;In Epic’s telling, Apple is a “uniquely powerful” company that exerts “unique control” over iOS devices. Apple routes all downloads and purchases through the App Store for financial gain, exercising little oversight over the actual quality of apps — contradicting a public commitment to privacy and security. It leverages its power in one market (the overall iOS ecosystem) to dominate another (app distribution and payments). That’s created less competition to deliver better service at cheaper rates, so users get stuck paying more and miss out on innovative new services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rhPmka"&gt;From the other half of the courtroom, Apple claims Epic is threatening what users love about iOS. Creating a single well-vetted app portal produces a “safe, convenient experience” on a device that stores reams of highly personal information, distinguishing the iPhone from competing platforms. Features that limit app distribution were “conscious, reasonable decisions,” Apple says — not attempts to shut down competition. Far from having consumers’ best interests at heart, Epic would simply force Apple to spend money shoring up new privacy and security holes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RjxHXO"&gt;Epic is losing out on a significant market with its iOS suspension. Court documents say it earned $700 million over its two years in the App Store, even if PlayStation and Xbox consoles &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22407939/fortnite-biggest-platform-revenue-playstation-not-ios-iphone"&gt;were far bigger moneymakers&lt;/a&gt;. Apple plans to argue that iPhone and iPad owners have access to other &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;-supporting devices, but Epic counters that most people choose only one platform to play on, so a stymied iOS user won’t necessarily pick up &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="16GQsv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Apple has a lot more at stake here than Epic does.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NitrDa"&gt;The main impact of the trial, though, won’t be getting one game back on the App Store. A big enough loss for Apple could make the company basically rewrite iOS. “Apple has a lot more at stake here than Epic does, though Apple has the stronger hand,” says Christopher Krohn, adjunct associate marketing professor at the University of Chicago Booth School of Business. Krohn notes that early in the case, Epic worried that Apple might cut off its App Store access altogether, threatening Epic’s ubiquitous Unreal Engine. But Judge Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/25/21400240/epic-apple-ruling-unreal-engine-fortnite-temporary-restraining-order"&gt;blocked that move&lt;/a&gt;. Meanwhile, in Apple’s worst-case scenario, the bench could decide that Apple can’t require all iOS developers to use the App Store — striking at a fundamental tenet of the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WLcoip"&gt;The bench could also conclude that Apple can maintain App Store exclusivity, but it can’t make developers use its in-app purchase system. While that would be less disruptive, it’s still a big deal. In-app purchases — including subscriptions to countless non-gaming services like Spotify — are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/17/21369460/apple-fortnite-app-store-services-business-model-epic-games"&gt;a huge part&lt;/a&gt; of Apple’s business. Apple cut its 30 percent App Store commission to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/18/21572302/apple-app-store-small-business-program-commission-cut-15-percent-reduction"&gt;15 percent for smaller developers&lt;/a&gt;, but according to &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/18/technology/apple-app-store-fee.html"&gt;one outside estimate&lt;/a&gt;, those developers accounted for a tiny share of its revenue. Losing money from big players would make the App Store a lot less profitable for Apple, and it’s a strong incentive for the company to push back against third-party subscription-based services — which, right now, dominate much of the app ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lATlm2"&gt;Epic is facing an uphill battle. US antitrust enforcement has languished over the past decade, in part because the consumer harm standard is slippery in a world where so many services are free. Sen. Amy Klobuchar (D-MN), one of Congress’ biggest proponents of antitrust reform, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22404493/amy-klobuchar-interview-antitrust-book-hearings-big-tech"&gt;called private antitrust suits&lt;/a&gt; “very hard to win” in a recent interview. “This is not straightforward, but Apple probably has an advantage,” concludes Michael Cusumano, deputy dean of the MIT Sloan School of Management. And whoever wins the case, the loser will almost certainly appeal, which could delay any concrete results from the trial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="nCyZHW"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The case will put Apple’s policies and security under a microscope&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jH8AC9"&gt;That said, the trial is just one part of a larger antitrust push against Apple, and even if the company wins in court, the trial could prove to be a political turning point in the fight to unwind the app store. Over the next three weeks, Apple executives — including CEO Tim Cook — will be grilled for hours on the company’s history and business practices, including the minutiae of how apps are reviewed and how secure the iPhone is. Any unflattering comments, like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22385859/apple-app-store-scams-fraud-review-enforcement-top-grossing-kosta-eleftheriou"&gt;one deposition’s claim&lt;/a&gt; that App Review employees were “bringing a plastic butter knife to a gun fight,” could provide fodder for lawmakers and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/3/18650861/apple-department-of-justice-antitrust-authority-facebook-google-amazon-ftc-investigations"&gt;watchdog agencies&lt;/a&gt;. The trial also gives a fresh soapbox to disgruntled iOS developers like Match Group, which sent a witness to Congress last week and is scheduled to testify in the upcoming trial as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3SHPg3"&gt;Epic court documents also raise issues that are tangential to its complaint but pivotal to the larger antitrust debate. That includes Apple’s strategy of vertical integration — a system where it builds incredibly popular devices like the iPhone, then directly competes with the companies making apps and accessories for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZZAsr5"&gt;The European Union has already taken aim at Apple’s App Store practices. Last night, the EU &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22407376/apple-european-union-antitrust-charges-app-store-music-competition-commission-margrethe-vestager"&gt;issued antitrust charges&lt;/a&gt; over the exact issue that sparked the Epic trial: Apple requiring developers to use its in-app purchasing system. That case is limited specifically to music streaming services like Spotify, but it could expand to ebooks and other digital purchases. “This is not the last case we will have when it comes to the App Store,” warned European Commissioner Margrethe Vestager this morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="BqEI4C"&gt;If Epic’s case fails, US lawmakers could use it to argue that the law itself is broken. Klobuchar has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22404493/amy-klobuchar-interview-antitrust-book-hearings-big-tech"&gt;singled out the Apple tax&lt;/a&gt; as an example of anti-competitive behavior run amok, calling for new standards that would apply not only to tech but the entire corporate world. Compared to a court blowing up the iOS ecosystem, that’s still a win for Apple — but it means Epic’s lawsuit could leave a mark well beyond the verdict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dolahs"&gt;&lt;em&gt;With reporting by Elizabeth Lopatto&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4CLzWx"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction: &lt;/strong&gt;The trial is before a bench, not a jury. We regret the error.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22403862/apple-epic-games-fortnite-app-store-antitrust-trial-kickoff"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22403862/apple-epic-games-fortnite-app-store-antitrust-trial-kickoff</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-30T09:16:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-30T09:16:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to use your Oculus Quest 2 to play any PC VR game wirelessly</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Virtual Desktop" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/q8Sb_6aZYKAVgUN-Mu726FoGJrQ=/0x0:1440x960/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68643020/hero.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oh hey, it’s all of my PC games available to play on the Quest 2, wire-free, from within a virtual room. This is getting weird.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vDDDh3"&gt;One of the best features of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21437674/oculus-quest-2-review-features-photos"&gt;Oculus Quest and Quest 2&lt;/a&gt; is that they can be manually linked via USB to your gaming PC so you can play more demanding VR games that couldn’t otherwise be run natively on the headsets. That’s great if you want a way to play games like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/23/21188291/half-life-alyx-review-valve-index-oculus-quest-vr-shooter"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Half-Life: Alyx&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; but the obvious downside is that you’re now physically tethered to a PC — so much for the wireless freedom that the Quest platform advertises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WTupji"&gt;Since then, the developers at Virtual Desktop — and, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22400197/oculus-quest-2-air-link-pc-streaming-v28-launch"&gt;more recently, Oculus itself&lt;/a&gt; — have both figured out how to stream the visual feed from your PC to your VR headset while quickly syncing all of your movements over Wi-Fi. Either option will give you the best of both worlds: letting you play the games you want without being attached by a cable to your computer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f3KFeB"&gt;Oculus’ method, which is called Air Link, now comes as a complimentary feature with the headset (if you’re running v28 software), while using Virtual Desktop requires a $20 app. There are benefits to both options, so we’re going to walk you through setting up each of them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XfdGX2"&gt;Up first is Oculus Air Link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="uPJ4bd"&gt;Installing and enabling Oculus Air Link&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="GkS9lu"&gt;In late April 2021, Oculus released the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382805/oculus-quest-2-facebook-wireless-pc-streaming-120hz-infinite-office"&gt;v28 software&lt;/a&gt; containing Air Link, a feature that enables wireless PC streaming. To check if your Quest is running the right software: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="GNuRoA"&gt;Click the gear icon along the bottom section of the headset’s screen to access the system settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="UyttUw"&gt;Scroll all the way down to bottom to find the “About” section and click that. Once you’re there, make sure that the version number is 28 or above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="2wToEf"&gt;Now, you need to enable the feature within the Oculus app on your PC. First off, make sure that app is updated to v28, like the headset. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="PqDQhD"&gt;Click “Settings” on the left-side navigation panel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dFlpcd"&gt;Go to the “General” tab and scroll all the way down to see the version number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Nw3zq8q1b7fRUlOdIMzZANx9kmI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21885654/Oculus_Quest_2.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="oI4cmb"&gt;Within the settings menu on the Oculus PC app, click the “Beta” tab. That’s where you should find Air Link, at least until it exits beta. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="T9iDm0"&gt;Toggle the switch to turn on Air Link. This &lt;a href="https://support.oculus.com/airlink/"&gt;FAQ on the Oculus site&lt;/a&gt; should show the most up-to-date info for these steps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/air5GeBy-l2KfmNLsZms6nUyNmk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22478856/oculusairlinkPCsetting.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Open settings, go to the beta tab, then toggle Air Link on.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="o9Tdgp"&gt;Switch Air Link on within your Quest headset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="oOUwex"&gt;Now that your software is updated and the feature has been turned on at your host PC, you can enable it within the headset. To do this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="EGHAl6"&gt;Put the headset back on and reopen the system settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yIJSAf"&gt;Find “Experimental Features.” Air Link will be nestled within that menu (at least for as long as Oculus considers it to be an experiment). Tap the toggle switch to activate it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="79aueL"&gt;Activate Air Link to play a game&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="QHTUBN"&gt;The Oculus app for PC must remain open for your headset to connect to it over Wi-Fi. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="nwS0oH"&gt;Physically position yourself within line of sight (or as close as possible) of your Wi-Fi router to get the best possible experience. Then put your headset back on and click once more into its system settings. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="aWUzzc"&gt;The first option on the left-hand side of the menu will say “Quick Actions.” Click that. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7V7LS2"&gt;You should see a large button for Air Link on the right side of this menu pane. Click on it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wG4T1k"&gt;After you click on Air Link, the next prompt will ask you to pick from a list of devices to connect to. Find your computer, and once you’ve successfully connected, you’ll be pushed into Oculus’ desktop interface, which looks a bit different than the Quest interface. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="jEv77u"&gt;If you need to make quick adjustments to Air Link’s bit rate to optimize performance (or if you want to quit using Air Link and return to the Quest interface), the left-most option at the bottom of your field of view will pull up a menu (shown below) that lets you do either.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Oculus Air Link" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ahqf6_Nm35VneWc5jxc0JfCj-8w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22478813/oculusairlink.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s what the Air Link menu looks like within the Oculus Home interface for PC.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="E0oS4h"&gt;Alternatively, buy the Virtual Desktop app for Quest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="qYkSF8"&gt;The Virtual Desktop app also lets you access your PC through the lens of a Quest VR headset. You can use it for games, like we’ll be doing here, but you can also watch movies you have stored on your PC in a variety of different virtual environments, or just browse the internet. &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=43993&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oculus.com%2Fexperiences%2Fquest%2F2017050365004772%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;There’s a Quest-specific version of the app that you can purchase here for $20&lt;/a&gt;. (Make sure it says that it’s compatible with Quest underneath the purchase button.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ViT64X"&gt;Compared to using Air Link, Virtual Desktop doesn’t take you completely out of the Quest interface. You can still hit the Oculus button on the right Touch controller to see the Quest universal menu. Yet, it allows for far more fine-tuning than Air Link currently does. You can adjust myriad settings to find the perfect performance for your setup, and it even has some extra tweaks, like letting you choose the kind of virtual environment the app will boot into. There’s an apartment, a computer room, an auditorium, and the vast expanse of deep space, to name a few examples. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2SQ7Hi"&gt;Get Virtual Desktop if you really want to have a custom experience, or as an alternative if Air Link doesn’t work all that well for you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Virtual Desktop" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iVvcJViGCifzUvXoqbandzJ1-6Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22220864/vd.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Virtual Desktop running on the Quest 2.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="7F3xXK"&gt;Download Virtual Desktop Streamer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="zwiEFT"&gt;There’s yet one more application to download for your PC: &lt;a href="https://www.vrdesktop.net/"&gt;Virtual Desktop Streamer&lt;/a&gt;. It’s free, and made by the same folks who made the Virtual Desktop app you purchased on the Quest or Quest 2. This app is necessary for streaming PC content to your headset via Wi-Fi. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="LRXQqT"&gt;Once this app is downloaded and installed, you’ll need to input your Oculus username in the Streamer window &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Ovpydi"&gt;If you don’t know it off the top of your head, you can find it by opening the Oculus app on mobile, navigating to “Settings,” and then tapping on the area that shows your name and email address. The name that will display next to your avatar is your username.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Oculus app" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R-J0UPjJSbyMOlAcOy2iyZNZhBk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22220804/oculusname.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Having a hard time finding your Oculus username? Tap on your full name in the Settings menu to see this view pictured above.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="dCc3Bu"&gt;After that’s entered, hit “Save”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RXWg5x"&gt;That’s the last step! But remember that it’s crucial to have the Virtual Desktop Streamer app open in order for your headset to communicate with your PC. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Virtual Desktop Streamer" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uFCk8sazQ5CJ39c4U4ARWJVRwXA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22220811/streamer.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s what the Virtual Desktop Streamer app looks like. It’s very simple.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="FylPqj"&gt;Open Virtual Desktop on your Quest headset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="tFxMTY"&gt;You should see your PC pop up in the list of available devices to connect to from within the Virtual Desktop app on your Quest or Quest 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oWDSZP"&gt;Once you’ve connected, the Options button (the left Touch controller’s equivalent of the Oculus button) is mapped to open up the top-level menu for Virtual Desktop, as shown in the image below. From there, clicking “Games” will reveal every game that’s installed on your PC. You can simply boot each one from there, and your PC will handle all of the hard work of opening the necessary apps. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Virtual Desktop" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RetcNAlbbLJZGLVlASVqciHC1_U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22220812/virtudaldesktopgames.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;All of the VR-ready games installed on your PC will show up within Virtual Desktop.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="E4ucp4"&gt;If you aren’t happy with the visual fidelity within each game, you’re free to customize some settings that affect latency, refresh rate, and more. Note that you’ll likely get a clearer, more fluid image if your PC is powerful. Your wireless router plays a huge role in delivering a smooth experience, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PNzjSC"&gt;Streaming VR over Wi-Fi certainly isn’t a perfect solution. I play just a few feet away from a Wi-Fi 6-ready router that’s wired directly to my PC via an ethernet switch, yet I still experience the occasional spot of lag and slightly fuzzy image. Though with enough tweaking on the Virtual Desktop app (turning Wi-Fi off on seldom-used tech items never hurts), I think you’ll have a good time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="zU1OZb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Facebook is turning VR into a platform — but some indie devs fear its power","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21455665/facebook-oculus-vr-indie-developers-power-monopoly-concerns"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="L6crr9"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update April 30th, 9:16AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated this post with the steps involved for setting up Air Link for Oculus Quest and Quest 2.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ot7NCR"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; The original article erroneously suggested that internet speed played a role in your ability to use this wireless solution to play your VR games. It’s all handled locally. Also, due to a malfunctioning USB-C port on the author’s PC, they erroneously stated that the USB-C cable included with each Quest 2 couldn’t be used to complete this how-to. A reader pointed out that it will work, and the author confirmed it by using the cable with an OTG adapter. We regret these errors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22218827/oculus-quest-2-wireless-pc-vr-games-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22218827/oculus-quest-2-wireless-pc-vr-games-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-30T09:00:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-30T09:00:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>Roku removes YouTube TV from channel store as dispute with Google escalates</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aq1tMjfCzmPCYzzYmNYMRKoe0rw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69211454/cwelch_20210428_4565_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Fhxoz3"&gt;Roku has pulled YouTube TV from its channel store. The distribution agreement between Roku and Google for YouTube TV has expired as of today — and the two sides haven’t been able to reach a new deal. However, Roku says it is “taking the extra step to continue to offer existing subscribers access to YouTube TV on the Roku platform unless Google takes actions that require the full removal of the channel.” New subscriptions from the YouTube TV app have also been switched off “until an agreement is reached.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Oijh6b"&gt;In an email to customers, Roku warned “it is also important that you do not delete the YouTube TV app as it will not be available for download to Roku devices.” The regular YouTube app is unaffected by this situation and remains freely available on Roku devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="68iHaA"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/26/22403740/roku-youtube-tv-google-standoff-competition-negotiations-contract"&gt;Roku has accused Google&lt;/a&gt; of seeking unfair terms that would adversely affect streaming competitors and benefit the YouTube suite of apps. Google has also asked for deeper access to Roku customer data than other services, Roku claims, and is pushing Roku to adopt new hardware requirements; presumably the company is aiming to get AV1 supported in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qipS6m"&gt;“We have only asked Google for four simple commitments,” Roku said in a new statement today. “First, not to manipulate consumer search results. Second, not to require access to data not available to anyone else. Third, not to leverage their YouTube monopoly to force Roku to accept hardware requirements that would increase consumer costs. Fourth, not to act in a discriminatory and anticompetitive manner against Roku.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dXilMH"&gt;Earlier this week, Google accused Roku of abusing its strong position in the streaming hardware market. “Roku often engages in these types of tactics in their negotiations. We’re disappointed that they chose to make baseless claims while we continue our ongoing negotiations,” a Google spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; on Monday. “All of our work with them has been focused on ensuring a high quality and consistent experience for our viewers. We have made no requests to access user data or interfere with search results. We hope we can resolve this for the sake of our mutual users.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nqMiQ3"&gt;Google today &lt;a href="https://blog.youtube/news-and-events/update-our-youtube-tv-members-roku/"&gt;followed that up with a blog post,&lt;/a&gt; stating that “our initial conversations started with Roku simply to renew the current terms of their ongoing deal with YouTube TV, which has been in place for several years. Our offer to Roku was simple and still stands: renew the YouTube TV deal under the existing reasonable terms.” Google claims that Roku used the opportunity to also “renegotiate a separate deal encompassing the YouTube main app, which does not expire until December.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YHFEDT"&gt;One bullet point really does sound like Google wants Roku to get on board with the AV1 codec:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="NmVWOd"&gt;Our agreements with partners have technical requirements to ensure a high quality experience on YouTube. Roku requested exceptions that would break the YouTube experience and limit our ability to update YouTube in order to fix issues or add new features. For example, by not supporting open-source video codecs, you wouldn’t be able to watch YouTube in 4K HDR or 8K even if you bought a Roku device that supports that resolution. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="YE6l2r"&gt;The takeaway is that we’re witnessing a more online, digital version of the carriage disputes that are so common between cable providers and content providers. Both companies are choosing their words extremely carefully. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jb73KE"&gt;Roku has insisted it’s not demanding more money from Google, and its email to customers — sent out at 8AM ET this morning — says “we cannot accept Google’s unfair and anticompetitive requirements that would allow for the manipulation of your search results, impact the usage of your data, and ultimately cost you more.” Google’s stance is that it “can’t give Roku special treatment at the expense of users,” and it’s reiterating that there have been no requests to change search or for special access to user data. “This claim is baseless and false,” Google said in its post. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zZ9c2B"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update April 30th 12PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; The article has been updated with new information from a blog post published by Google / YouTube.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22411711/roku-removes-youtube-tv-channel-store"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22411711/roku-removes-youtube-tv-channel-store</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-30T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-30T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Solar flare: why Tesla’s price hike has customers seeing spots</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9eTt3NtZIV57WxuKJjLItbY19Ek=/0x73:1040x766/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69211368/3558a860_8c1c_425b_8760_8766d441ae27.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Elon Musk says ‘significant mistakes’ were made in how Tesla calculates solar roof costs. Customers are irate&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="hVuaWG"&gt;Gene Frakes, an electrician and skydiving instructor who lives outside of Rockford, IL, became a Tesla Energy customer after watching &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f_GHVSL35-k&amp;amp;t=251s"&gt;a video of snow effortlessly sliding off one of the company’s new solar roofs&lt;/a&gt;. It was just the proof he was looking for that Tesla’s innovative glass roof tiles with embedded solar cells would work just as well in snowy climates as they do in sunnier parts of the country like California. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XAybtQ"&gt;“That was impressive,” Frakes, 50, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Upop4"&gt;But his excitement quickly faded after he received an email from Tesla informing him that the original estimate for the 10.58kW project would be increasing to $53,649 from $34,743 — a 54 percent jump. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BNTrjL3q8IBRiF46jokPvCIp4bQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22478663/iMarkup_20210412_174014.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gene Frakes could hardly believe it when Tesla told him it was raising the price of his solar roof by 54 percent.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LuLZNi"&gt;“It seems so incorrect that I could hardly believe it,” Frakes said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D2CXri"&gt;Frakes wasn’t the only one left sun-kissed by Tesla’s massive price increase. In early April, notices started going out to customers awaiting installation of their Tesla solar roofs that their prices would be going up, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/12/22380057/tesla-solar-roof-price-increase-contract-amount"&gt;sometimes by as much as 100 percent&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; spoke to 11 Tesla solar roof customers around the country who have canceled or are considering canceling their orders. They are commiserating with each other in chat groups, airing their grievances online, and &lt;a href="https://www.change.org/p/tesla-elon-musk-or-tesla-should-honor-signed-contracts-and-pricing-for-solar-roof-customers-with-some-waiting-over-a-year"&gt;launching petitions&lt;/a&gt; to raise awareness about the issue. Some are even considering filing a class action lawsuit against Musk’s company.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ghXkFu"&gt;Tesla offers two solar products: conventional solar panels, which are installed over a customer’s existing roof; and the solar roof, which replaces the current roof slats with ones capable of soaking up the sun’s rays and transforming it into energy. The solar roof is designed to look like asphalt, slate, and Spanish barrel tiles to fit the style of each home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eyeHH1"&gt;It would later be revealed that the company had underestimated the complexity of some of the roofs. Tesla CEO Elon Musk admitted as much in an earnings call on April 26th, saying that the company had made “significant mistakes” in how it calculates the installation costs. Tesla tried to soften the blow by offering some aggrieved customers free Powerwall home batteries if they renewed their orders. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zKCCAT"&gt;But it may not work. Even before the price increases, solar roof customers were filing lawsuits claiming Tesla had destroyed their credit rating by reporting loans they never requested. The price increases are the latest self-inflicted wound that has caused Tesla’s once vaunted solar business, which it originally acquired in 2015, to lose market share as more companies get involved and the price of solar drops nationwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M-Iy2T-lIPXjMkjdqRTIYjGHt64=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22478645/0x0_Solar_Roof_17.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Tesla&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="j0F2eH"&gt;In early March, everything was going well for Amr Kader, an OB-GYN from East Greenwich, RI, and his solar roof project. He’d taken out two loans and started paying down the premium. And he had received the necessary permits from his utility company and the local township. Kader, who also owns a Tesla Model Y, was excited about adding another Tesla product to his lifestyle.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6ZzFbt"&gt;But days before the project was set to begin, he received word from Tesla that it would be rescheduled for late April. After that, he was told his project would be delayed indefinitely due to the company’s inability to secure an installation crew in Rhode Island. After some back-and-forth, Tesla informed Kader that it would also be raising his price by $3,000, or 30 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="kjjT5y"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“abandonment of contract, extortion and deliberate misguidance and misinformation”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="N8lZ6O"&gt;Kader was incensed. He filed a complaint with the state attorney general’s consumer division, accusing Tesla of “abandonment of contract, extortion and deliberate misguidance and misinformation.” He also has been talking to a lawyer about filing a lawsuit against the company, and hopes to see Tesla’s license suspended or revoked in his state. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fZnKAU"&gt;As for his own order, Kader’s initial reaction was to dig in his heels. “I did not cancel my signed contract and made it clear I am not canceling,” he said. But ultimately he decided it wasn’t worth the effort and informed Tesla he wouldn’t be moving forward with the project. And he began shopping around for other, cheaper solar roof products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PY18Mp"&gt;“Honestly, I wouldn’t trust them installing my roof even if they would honor the original contract,” he said. But the Model Y in his driveway serves as a constant reminder of the whole debacle.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="30V3S0"&gt;“It definitely made me feel not proud any more of riding my Tesla car,” Kader admitted, “[and] advertising for them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Tesla’s Patient Superfans Are Willing To Pay Up For Solar Roofs" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nJlVaJxHqKJVRxU_71StHRvGo5U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22478650/1201885701.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Getty&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;On paper, Tesla’s energy division seems to be booming. But the division has never been profitable.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="DZTw8I"&gt;On paper, Tesla’s energy division seems to be booming. The company said it installed 92 mega-watts (MW) of solar energy in the first quarter of 2021, more than twice as much as the first quarter of 2020 — its strongest quarter in two-and-a-half years. Tesla generated $494 million in sales on its solar roofs, including storage products like the Powerwall battery. For all of 2020, Tesla installed 205 MW of solar energy, an 18 percent increase compared to 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="apN9rg"&gt;In the earnings call, Musk claimed that demand for Tesla’s solar roofs “remains strong.” But overall, the division is unprofitable and the company has gone from the biggest rooftop solar installer in the US to a distant second in recent years, falling behind San Francisco-based Sunrun. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UF487d"&gt;Tesla’s solar ambitions date back to 2015, when it acquired SolarCity, a company owned by Musk’s cousin. A year later, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/10/28/13463236/tesla-solar-roof-battery-new-elon-musk"&gt;Musk unveiled the solar roof&lt;/a&gt; on the former &lt;a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2019/08/how-elon-musk-gambled-tesla-to-save-solarcity"&gt;set of &lt;em&gt;Desperate Housewives&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, claiming that the roofs would look “as good or better” than conventional roofs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="njtnvs"&gt;&lt;q&gt;almost from the beginning, the deal proved to be a thorn in Musk’s side&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Atp3xV"&gt;But almost from the beginning, the deal proved to be a thorn in Musk’s side. Critics called it a “bailout” of the struggling SolarCity, which had piled up massive amounts of debt over the years. A number of Tesla shareholders sued Musk over the deal, alleging he overvalued SolarCity and did not properly recuse himself from the deal. &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-tesla-solarcity-lawsuit/tesla-directors-settle-isolating-musk-as-solarcity-trial-looms-idUSKBN1ZT2HF"&gt;Tesla’s board of directors settled the suit&lt;/a&gt; last year without Musk, leaving the CEO the lone defendant in the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xBkwYL"&gt;It’s also seen its share of the market slip. Tesla has fallen far behind Sunrun, which is the largest installer of solar panels in the US. It’s so far behind, Wall Street analysts barely pay attention to the company’s reports on its energy division, Wedbush’s Dan Ives said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ahL0it"&gt;“The Street doesn’t really assign a value to Tesla’s solar business,” Ives said, “because it’s relatively unproven thus far.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AVrHvd"&gt;“It’s been choppy to say the least,” Ives added, “since Tesla has really focused on solar the last few years. It’s between competition, pricing, and execution issues. I think they’ve gotten some upward momentum over the last nine to 12 months, but it’s definitely been more of a black eye on the overall Tesla story.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wUfLQj"&gt;Tesla’s decision to jack up prices on its solar roof customers also flies in the face of the trend of falling prices for solar installations overall, said Seth Blumsack, professor of energy and environmental economics at Penn State. The price of conventional solar panels that are installed on top of a customer’s roof — which are different from Tesla’s solar roof — have gone down 90 percent over the last decade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BiuUg9"&gt;“The pace of these cost declines has been just even beyond what even a lot of experts had predicted,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="EB8Nu5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The pace of these cost declines has been just even beyond what even a lot of experts had predicted”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YtJ8Ok"&gt;And the pace of installations have been growing, to the point where they are about 13 times greater than they were a decade ago, according to the Solar Energy Industries Association. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8Ypwkt"&gt;That said, it’s not unheard of for energy companies trying to introduce a new technology to the market to underestimate the initial costs, Blumstack said. If enough customers “bite the bullet” and decide to absorb the cost increases, that could send a signal to Tesla’s competitors on the direction this technology is going. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zx9kA7"&gt;“It’ll be interesting to see if they’re able to start driving the costs of solar roofs down the same way that we have seen the cost of traditional solar panels decline,” Blumsack said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ks0AqD"&gt;A spokesperson for Tesla did not respond to a request for comment, which isn’t surprising considering the company has eliminated its public relations department and hasn’t responded to a request for comment in over a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Solarglass Roof" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OTGXOVDFBa6NlkXW4if5a679ASc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22478660/1199455787.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Smith Collection / Gado / Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Close-up of Solarglass Roof, a roof shingle with integrated solar panels, from Tesla Energy, a division of Tesla Motors, on Santana Row in the Silicon Valley, San Jose, California, January 3rd, 2020.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="H5IClV"&gt;Texas resident Wissam Mehio is not one of those customers willing to “bite the bullet.” He promptly canceled his order after Tesla informed him that it would be increasing his price to $104,000 from the previous estimate of $69,000. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hZ3Sjt"&gt;“Tesla was so happy to see me go, my $100 [deposit] was refunded to my credit card less than 24 hours later,” he laughed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SiOUOg"&gt;It was particularly disappointing given how Mehio had started telling friends how proud he was about his new “beautiful solar roof.” He even expected a little price increase, and had budgeted an extra $5,000-10,000 for it, given that Tesla had said that the price it gave him was an estimate and would likely change once an onsite assessment is done. But slamming him with a 50 percent increase before coming out for the onsite assessment made canceling a “no-brainer,” Mehio said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="xT99ka"&gt;“With such a move, I feel Tesla Energy wants to transition back from ‘solar for everyone’ to ‘solar for those who don’t count their money,’” he added. “No hard feelings, but I’m out.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22410075/tesla-solar-roof-price-increase-customer-reactions"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22410075/tesla-solar-roof-price-increase-customer-reactions</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-30T08:43:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-30T08:43:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to buy the new iPad Pro with the M1 processor</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="iPad Pro 2021" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q9GZIA0Gfi4WQPK-l2mCpNu-xOw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69159356/ipadpro2021lede.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new iPad Pro&lt;/em&gt; | Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GUYWLh"&gt;Apple announced a 2021 refresh to its iPad Pro lineup, which now includes the same powerful and efficient M1 processor that’s in its MacBook Air, Pro, and Mac mini computers. Both the new 11-inch and 12.9-inch models will feature the chip, as well as a Thunderbolt port and optional 5G support. The display on the larger tablet has received a particularly big boost, jumping to a Liquid Retina XDR Mini LED screen. My colleague Monica Chin has gone deeper on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22385675/apple-ipad-pro-m1-chip-specs-features-price"&gt;more of this year’s big improvements&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iB5ppe"&gt;If you have your eye on the new iPad Pro, preorders begin today, April 30th, with shipping beginning the week of May 21st. Preorders are available at several retailers, including Apple’s direct website and Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="IcpI9v"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The colorful M1 iMac, Mini LED iPad Pro, and refreshed Apple TV 4K are available to preorder now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22409463/apple-m1-imac-ipad-pro-apple-tv-4k-preorders-price-release-date"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="24HsU8"&gt;Where to buy the 11-inch M1 iPad Pro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="euCrDs"&gt;The 11-inch iPad Pro starts at $799 for 128GB of storage and Wi-Fi connectivity. The model with LTE and 5G support costs $200 more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FRO1s7"&gt;If you are looking for this specific model, you can buy it at &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/435031/7613?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-ipad%2Fipad-pro&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Apple’s direct website&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-11-inch-Wi-Fi-128GB/dp/B08637NV8M?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1636248-REG%2Fapple_mhqr3ll_a_11_ipad_pro_wi_fi.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1739232056163661547#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-ipad-pro-11-inch-wi-fi-only%2F-%2FA-82866372%3Fpreselect%3D77616907%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;subid1=WhereToOrderM1iPadPro04302021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iArXoZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10456970"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="27UT4W"&gt;Where to buy the 12.9-inch M1 iPad Pro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="rHZnHK"&gt;If you want the big 12.9-inch iPad Pro, that model starts at $1,099 and comes with 128GB of storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w4b5Km"&gt;The high-end M1 iPad Pro is available for preorder at &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/435031/7613?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-ipad%2Fipad-pro&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-12-9-inch-Wi-Fi-128GB/dp/B0863D15R6?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1636228-REG%2Fapple_mhnf3ll_a_12_9_ipad_pro_wifi.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1739232031086405668#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-ipad-pro-12-9-inch-wi-fi-only%2F-%2FA-82866370%3Fpreselect%3D80601874%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;subid1=WhereToOrderM1iPadPro04302021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="UWdJ8G"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10456977"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="qGFHmp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple announces thinner iMac with M1 chip and bright colors","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394034/apple-new-imac-m1-chip-colors-design-specs-price-release-date"},{"title":"Apple debuts $29 AirTag, a new Tile-like item tracker","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/20844326/apple-airtags-bluetooth-tracker-keys-tile-features-price"},{"title":"Apple announces new Apple TV 4K","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22386298/apple-tv-4k-a12-bionic-price-features-release-date"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="bPQbD3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394227/apple-ipad-pro-2021-how-where-to-buy-preorder-link"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394227/apple-ipad-pro-2021-how-where-to-buy-preorder-link</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-30T08:30:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-30T08:30:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>The colorful M1 iMac, Mini LED iPad Pro, and refreshed Apple TV 4K are available to preorder now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An image showing all seven colors of the new iMac: green, yellow, orange, pink, purple, blue, and silver." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0rtwDK7ce854Oqg-tIjyJow3Ic4=/168x0:1977x1206/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69211243/apple_new_imac_spring21_hero_04202021_Full_Bleed_Image.jpg.medium_2x.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zVUzXt"&gt;Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394034/apple-new-imac-m1-chip-colors-design-specs-price-release-date"&gt;colorful new M1-powered iMacs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22385675/apple-ipad-pro-m1-chip-specs-features-price"&gt;refreshed iPad Pros&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22386298/apple-tv-4k-a12-bionic-price-features-release-date"&gt;updated Apple TV 4K&lt;/a&gt; (with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/18277449/apple-tv-remote-new-design-4k-features-price-release-date"&gt;not-terrible-looking remote&lt;/a&gt;) are now &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1043467/7613?subId1=VergeColorfulMacs043021&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-ipad%2Fipad-pro"&gt;all available to preorder today&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1043467/7613?subId1=VergeColorfulMacs043021&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-tv%2Fapple-tv-4k"&gt;Apple’s website. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZKghJ5"&gt;The company says that the new products will be delivered starting on May 21st —at least for the first wave of orders, although that timing will certainly slip as stock sells out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bn5giu"&gt;Customers interested in &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1043467/7613?subId1=VergeColorfulMacs043021&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-mac%2Fimac"&gt;buying the new iMac&lt;/a&gt; should take note that only some of the color schemes will be available in stores: green, pink, blue, and silver models will be sold in-person at Apple Store locations, but the full seven-color spectrum will only be offered through Apple’s website, at least for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="pG1SBW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10474574"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RIuuCz"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1043467/7613?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-ipad%2Fipad-pro%2F12.9-inch-display-128gb-space-gray-wifi"&gt;new iPad Pro &lt;/a&gt;also features Apple’s new M1 processor (the same as the iMac and last falls updated MacBooks), in addition to an upgraded ultra-wide angle camera for better video calls. Additionally, the larger 12.9-inch model will feature a new Mini LED display, which promises a far brighter and more accurate screen experience — at the cost of a $100 price increase over the 2020 model. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CpLbLU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10456970"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="7VWyXn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10456977"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BGx6Iy9UvD77g1r7uSQJtT6KIzo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22479128/Screen_Shot_2021_04_29_at_4.31.13_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ICQOxQ"&gt;Also of particular note: in addition to the preorders for the updated Apple TV 4K, preorders have also opened for &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1043467/7613?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FMJFM3LL%2FA%2Fsiri-remote"&gt;the standalone $59 Siri Remote&lt;/a&gt; for existing Apple TV HD and Apple TV 4K (first-gen) owners looking to replace the infamous first-generation Siri Remote with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/18277449/apple-tv-remote-new-design-4k-features-price-release-date"&gt;(hopefully) better new design&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iujnaU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10474579"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="W4Vwzt"&gt;Alongside the preorders for the new Apple products, the first wave of last week’s AirTag and purple iPhone 12 and 12 mini devices should be arriving to both customers and in Apple Stores starting today. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22409463/apple-m1-imac-ipad-pro-apple-tv-4k-preorders-price-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22409463/apple-m1-imac-ipad-pro-apple-tv-4k-preorders-price-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
