<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-17T09:03:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-17T09:03:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-17T09:03:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>Intel puts Apple’s ‘I’m a Mac’ guy into new ads praising PCs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uLT12mJPm7oEwJ0bBp5O7qEk-1o=/200x0:2360x1440/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68980460/LDTTUmg.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kMO1fM"&gt;Intel has hired Apple’s former “I’m a Mac” actor Justin Long to create new ads praising PCs. Long starts each commercial with “Hello I’m a... Justin,” with the typical white background you’d find on Apple’s Mac vs. PC ads from the 2000s. Naturally, the ads focus on Mac vs. PC again, with Long mocking Apple’s Touch Bar, &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/WfHplU5fatE"&gt;lack of M1 multiple monitor support&lt;/a&gt;, and the “&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/rvDDC6ktCUg"&gt;gray and grayer&lt;/a&gt;” color choices for a MacBook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0THmCs"&gt;One even &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/9gtRRMd2_UI"&gt;goes all-in&lt;/a&gt; on Apple’s lack of touchscreens in Macs or 2-in-1 support by mocking the fact you have to buy a tablet, keyboard, stylus, and even a dongle to match what’s available on rival Intel-based laptops. &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/8HebkohrCns"&gt;Another ad&lt;/a&gt; also points out that “no one really games on a Mac.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PaSRqw"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9gtRRMd2_UI?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="X5HdBA"&gt;The return of Justin Long in Mac vs. PC ads for Intel comes just months after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/10/21558977/apple-pc-guy-classic-m1-performance-john-hodgman"&gt;Apple brought back actor John Hodgman&lt;/a&gt; to reprise his role as the PC guy from Apple’s “I’m a Mac, and I’m a PC” ad campaign. While Apple kept its reprisal limited to the company’s keynote to introduce Arm-based M1 MacBooks, Intel has gone a step further and revived this for full commercials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3GidON"&gt;Intel is clearly ready to battle Apple’s first chips with marketing, but we’re still waiting for the company to respond with its own silicon advances. Intel has only &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/8/22272041/intel-apple-macbook-m1-performance-benchmarks-processors"&gt;produced benchmarks&lt;/a&gt; so far. Intel’s new CEO, Pat Gelsinger, has also already made it clear that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22232554/intel-ceo-apple-lifestyle-company-cpus-comment"&gt;Intel has to beat Apple in the future&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22335654/intel-mac-guy-new-ads-commercials-pc"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22335654/intel-mac-guy-new-ads-commercials-pc</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-17T09:01:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-17T09:01:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>How a metal with a memory will shape our future on Mars</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ey5U69BFx4KV62u4wPNVr7Js-tg=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68980439/Textless_Thumb_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zIpUSh"&gt;A rover on the Moon has metal wheels that can flex around rocky obstacles, then reshape back to their original form. On Earth, surgeons install tiny mesh tubes that can dilate a heart patient’s blood vessels all on their own, without mechanical inputs or any wires to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9yEjcK"&gt;These shape-shifting capabilities are all thanks to a bizarre kind of metal called nitinol, a so-called shape-metal alloy that can be trained to remember its own shape. The decades-old material has become increasingly common in a wide range of everyday applications. And in the next decade, the metal will face its most challenging application yet: a sample return mission on Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZfvKxU"&gt;Nitinol, made of nickel and titanium, works its magic through heat. To “train” a paper clip made of nitinol, for example, you heat it at 500 degrees Celsius in its desired shape, then splash it in cold water. Bend it out of shape, then return the same heat source, and the metal will eerily slink back into its original form. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VEn9YC"&gt;The temperature that triggers nitinol’s transformation varies depending on the fine-tuned ratio of nickel to titanium. Engineers can tweak the metal to adapt to a wide array of conditions, making it a key tool in places where complex mechanics won’t fit, like the blood vessels surrounding a human heart or a hinge that positions a solar panel by responding to the sun’s heat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="djnD67"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; spoke with engineers at NASA’s Glenn Research Center to see how nitinol will play a role in a mission to retrieve humanity’s first cache of pristine Martian soil samples — the second leg of a Mars mission campaign led by NASA and the European Space Agency. Check out the video above to see how and to see nitinol in action. (We promise, it’s not CGI.)&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22334611/nitinol-metal-shape-memory-alloy-mars-nasa"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22334611/nitinol-metal-shape-memory-alloy-mars-nasa</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-17T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-17T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Zack Snyder’s Justice League remains overshadowed by its social media campaign</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4arTgYtG7ldfkzKXAuIpehJHK3w=/0x84:2000x1417/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68980353/snyder_jl.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KsZiPh"&gt;On March 18th, a four-hour version of director Zack Snyder’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/14/22278944/zack-snyder-justice-league-official-premiere-trailer-hbo-max"&gt;original vision for &lt;em&gt;Justice League&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;will hit HBO Max. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0HGTuA"&gt;Early reviews are mostly littered with praise for the movie, calling it a win for fans of Snyder’s other superhero films (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/3/23/11294512/batman-vs-superman-dawn-of-justice-review-movie-spoilers"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Batman v Superman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/6/10/4412958/man-of-steel-review"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Man of Steel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Others acknowledge that, hey, at least it’s better than the original film released in 2017, which was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/20/21263044/justice-league-snyder-cut-warnermedia-hbo-max-zack-ben-affleck-henry-cavill-gal-gaot-streaming"&gt;spliced together by Joss Whedon&lt;/a&gt; after Snyder had to step back from the project to cope with the sudden death of his daughter. Whether the movie lives up to people’s expectations or not, the very existence of it — the marketing behind it, what it represents to fandom as a whole — is a turning point for online fandom. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vcvok2"&gt;A quick reminder of what the last four years have consisted of from various corners of the internet: after &lt;em&gt;Justice League &lt;/em&gt;came out in 2017, Snyder fans immediately took up a petition asking Warner Bros. to &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2018/1/10/16873696/justice-league-zack-snyder-directors-cut-conspiracy-theory"&gt;release an alternate of the film&lt;/a&gt; — the true version they called the Snyder Cut. Over the years, calls for Warner Bros. to take action have grown, as has the fandom. Billboard signs in Times Square, bus ads in San Diego during Comic-Con, and small demonstrations outside Warner Bros.’ headquarters in Burbank all existed in an attempt to rally WarnerMedia executives into giving them the version of &lt;em&gt;Justice League &lt;/em&gt;they were promised through setups in &lt;em&gt;Man of Steel, Batman v Superman, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/6/2/15728630/wonder-woman-review-gal-gadot-dc-extended-universe-patty-jenkins"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wonder Woman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;and more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="qTB2D7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It took them a long time, the people who really wanted to be productive in this moment, to realize that they’re going to get judged by [negative] actions also.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fJujHJ"&gt;Like any massive faceless group centering their online personas on one particular &lt;em&gt;thing &lt;/em&gt;or person, the Snyder Cut fandom (or the #ReleaseTheSnyderCut collective, as they became known) was a mixture of positives and negatives. The positive aspects are inspiring. Together, the group has raised hundreds of thousands of dollars &lt;a href="https://screenrant.com/justice-league-snyder-cut-suicide-prevention-fundraiser/"&gt;for suicide prevention awareness&lt;/a&gt;, a cause close to Snyder’s heart after his daughter’s death. A fandom rooted in a specific director spawned some genuinely thoughtful social media campaigns. There’s no denying that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lAC3Iu"&gt;It’s also impossible to ignore the negatives. Critics and reporters received &lt;a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/hollywood/2020/05/is-releasing-the-snyder-cut-a-victory-for-toxic-fandoms"&gt;countless death threats and vile slurs&lt;/a&gt; all because they expressed disinterest in a Snyder Cut or called Snyder’s other work bad. Warner Bros. and DC Comics executives like Geoff Johns and former Warner Bros. CEO Kevin Tsujihara were &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/spoki83/status/1175052064856203267"&gt;lambasted by Snyder fans&lt;/a&gt; to the point that Johns seemingly stopped using Twitter altogether. When new Warner Bros. CEO Ann Sarnoff joined the company, her Twitter mentions were full of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/i/events/1143554460674875394?lang=en"&gt;people demanding the Snyder Cut&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YpsjKs"&gt;“It took them a long time, the people who really wanted to be productive in this moment, to realize that they’re going to get judged by [negative] actions also,” Sean O’Connell, a journalist and author of &lt;em&gt;Release the Snyder Cut&lt;/em&gt;, a book detailing the campaign over the last four years, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “The Snyder movement doesn’t have a really strong hold on policing the people in their movement who continue promoting that negativity.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="yDqRj9"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s in some ways fun to surf the wave of a cultural phenomenon. In other ways it’s terrifying and horrible.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IVzhPx"&gt;Even with critics, academics, and journalists calling out the toxic parts of the fandom, there were some members within the group who only seemed incentivized by ongoing acknowledgment and less-than-subtle encouragement from Snyder himself. The director recently &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/14/movies/zack-snyders-rough-and-tumble-ride-with-justice-league.html"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that “it’s in some ways fun to surf the wave of a cultural phenomenon,” adding that “in other ways it’s terrifying and horrible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4dkpNl"&gt;Snyder Cut fans are far from the only fan base with a toxic cloud hanging over parts of it. &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; is a &lt;a href="https://www.esquire.com/entertainment/movies/a25617513/toxic-star-wars-fans/"&gt;perfect example&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;The Last Jedi &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.denofgeek.com/movies/rian-johnson-star-wars-fans-mistake/"&gt;director Rian Johnson&lt;/a&gt;, alongside actors &lt;a href="https://www.gq-magazine.co.uk/culture/article/john-boyega-interview-2020"&gt;John Boyega&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2018/6/5/17429196/kelly-marie-tran-instagram-deleted-harassment-star-wars-rose-last-jedi"&gt;Kelly Marie Tran&lt;/a&gt;, received hordes of harassment from bitter &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; viewers. Boyega and Johnson publicly fought back against trolls, while Tran decided after some time to leave social media platforms like Instagram for her own mental health. At the time, Lucasfilm executives didn’t say anything publicly, nor did any of the official &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; social media accounts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A5rr89"&gt;One of the biggest changes that has come about in an internet-first, social media-dominant world is that fans of massive properties feel closer to talent, executives, and companies than ever before. In turn, companies are trying to figure out how to navigate extremely loud voices on increasingly global platforms. Universal leaned into the &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/travisbean/2020/02/05/justiceforhan-the-unshakable-allure-of-the-most-compelling-fast--furious-character/?sh=78757b363b2e"&gt;#JusticeForHan hashtag&lt;/a&gt; when marketing its upcoming &lt;em&gt;F9&lt;/em&gt;, a popular fan-driven movement. Sony reworked the overall tone for &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/heat-vision/welcome-to-the-multiverse-studios-lean-into-fan-demand"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Venom &lt;/em&gt;after the first trailer&lt;/a&gt; failed to garner hype from Marvel fans. And perhaps most notably, Paramount completely redesigned its &lt;a href="https://www.indiewire.com/2019/11/sonic-redesign-cost-paramount-five-million-1202190493/"&gt;CGI version of Sonic the Hedgehog&lt;/a&gt; after the first trailer led to immediate negative reaction from fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RzARLQ"&gt;Parts of the Snyder Cut fandom have drawn direct comparisons to what happened with BioWare’s &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect 3 &lt;/em&gt;in 2012&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;After the game’s ending drew heavy criticism from fans, BioWare released an alternate ending to try to smooth over a vocal part of the fan base. The DLC was called &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect: Extended Cut, &lt;/em&gt;and it became an example of corporations giving in to social media pressures.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="CQ4Ux0"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I don’t think that studios and corporations are going to make decisions going forward to placate fans on social media because that’s a risky gamble”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NQOjrg"&gt;“It’s such a slippery slope,” O’Connell says. “I don’t think that studios and corporations are going to make decisions going forward to placate fans on social media because that’s a risky gamble. At the same time, this entire DCEU experiment, to me, has been reactionary to the studio’s detriment. They started chasing the Marvel model instead of just believing in whatever Nolan had started and what Snyder tried to continue.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BYA4MA"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T has arguably leaned into the Snyder fandom the most as it tries to garner more attention and subscribers for its new HBO Max streaming service. After years of Warner Bros. repeatedly not saying anything about rereleasing a version of the film in theaters, the announcement of Snyder’s &lt;em&gt;Justice League &lt;/em&gt;on HBO Max came with AT&amp;amp;T’s &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ATT/status/1357080058356092929"&gt;official Twitter account&lt;/a&gt; celebrating a prickly fandom. This hasn’t stopped other Snyder fans from already replying to other AT&amp;amp;T tweets with pleas to #RestoreTheSnyderUniverse, demanding the director be given another shot at creating his entire superhero world, something current DC Films head Walter Hamada has no intention of doing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z3nc0K"&gt;The Snyder Cut is, according to several reviews, much better than the original. It exists as a testament to having a director see their entire project through from beginning to end. But #ReleaseTheSnyderCut is not the same as Zack Snyder’s &lt;em&gt;Justice League&lt;/em&gt;, and there is a reason why WarnerMedia is releasing it as a four-hour film with effectively no oversight on HBO Max instead of rereleasing it in theaters (even with the pandemic) and spending $100 million on marketing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RuPfcP"&gt;It is, as Snyder told &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, a “social experiment.” The problem with an experiment is that no one knows what that means two years, five years, or three decades from now. O’Connell doesn’t believe this would have happened if Warner Bros. waited another year or HBO Max hadn’t launched. It’s a moment to appease fans and drive subscribers to a platform that WarnerMedia CEO Jason Kilar consistently refers to as the future of the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iMP40G"&gt;“It’s the culmination of this entire experience: I fought and used the hashtag #ReleaseTheSnyderCut, and it’s in my world, in my computer, on my TV, in my house,” Snyder said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hMX6xk"&gt;That’s Zack Snyder’s &lt;em&gt;Justice League&lt;/em&gt;. The #ReleaseTheSnyderCut fandom isn’t suddenly going to disappear, as my colleague &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/22327290/snyder-cut-hbo-max-release"&gt;Joshua Rivera wrote at &lt;em&gt;Polygon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. For both the positive campaigners who are happy to finally have Snyder’s version available to watch and the negative spouting trolls who can claim victory on social media and continue fighting with people, they got what they wanted. Their tactics worked. One of the largest corporations in the United States gave in to demands from anonymous people. That’s not something people forget, and it only incentivizes a very specific type of action further. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3toK9X"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22334362/zack-snyder-justice-league-fandom-release-cut-star-wars-twitter"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22334362/zack-snyder-justice-league-fandom-release-cut-star-wars-twitter</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-17T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-17T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>AMD Radeon RX 6700 XT review: Nvidia wins this round</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Unless AMD actually sells them for $479, of course&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="N6AcfM"&gt;AMD and Nvidia are pretending they live in a fantasy world, one where you can buy a state-of-the-art graphics card for under $700. Heck, a fantasy world where you can buy a new AMD GPU &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt; — though AMD has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22310653/amd-radeon-rx-6700-xt-price-release-date-availability-gpu-graphics"&gt;repeatedly&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227040/nvidia-amd-gpu-shortage-rtx-3080-3070-3060-ti-3090-rx-6800-xt"&gt;promised&lt;/a&gt; it would stock additional RX 6800 and RX 6800 XT graphics cards at its website for $579 and $649 respectively, I’ve seen no evidence the company has &lt;em&gt;ever&lt;/em&gt; replenished those supplies since those cards first debuted four months ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GOvtFb"&gt;Today, the company’s launching a GPU that might change that: the $479 Radeon RX 6700 XT. AMD tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; it will have “significantly more GPUs available.” If that’s true — if this is the moment the clouds part, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299505/nvidia-earnings-q4-2021-quarterly-gpu-shortage-revenue"&gt;the GPU shortage&lt;/a&gt; recedes, and you can actually buy a RX 6700 XT for $479 for even a limited time — you absolutely should. It’s a solid performer at 1440p.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6VTUyF"&gt;But amusingly, in the fantasy world where we’re pretending a $400 GeForce RTX 3060 Ti and $500 RTX 3070 still exist, the RX 6700 XT actually feels outgunned. It’s not the clear-cut Nvidia competitor you might have hoped for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2jd13M"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10396725"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IRYcDy"&gt;The AMD Radeon RX 6700 XT comes with a simple pitch: a way to max out your 2560 x 1440 monitor with the latest games at maximum settings, all for $100 less than the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21572796/amd-radeon-rx-6800-review-4k-gaming-test-benchmarks"&gt;RX 6800 I reviewed late last year&lt;/a&gt;. If that sounds familiar, that’s because it’s the same playbook Nvidia used last fall, where its $400 RTX 3060 Ti undercut the $500 RTX 3070 by the same amount. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jueU5v"&gt;So in our fantasy world where those prices held, this would be the lay of the land:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="EagLx8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10396733"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RgzoPp"&gt;Given those prices, I’d expect a $480 AMD card to soundly thrash a $400 Nvidia card. (That’s what the $580 Radeon RX 6800 did to the $500 RTX 3070, after all.) I’d also expect it to be within spitting distance of the $500 Nvidia card if there were only a $20 bill between the two. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dZbm9p"&gt;But running AMD’s card through my 15-game gauntlet on my own 1440p monitor, AMD’s new card sometimes lost to Nvidia’s 3060 Ti — sometimes by a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; — and it can even lose to Nvidia’s vanilla $329 RTX 3060 in tests where I had ray tracing turned on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zg5RUF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10396748"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SaobMd"&gt;As you’ll see in the chart above, AMD does notch some wins, and in many cases lives up to its promise of maxed settings at 1440p. &lt;em&gt;Shadow of the Tomb Raider&lt;/em&gt; looks glorious on my G-Sync / FreeSync monitor at an average 105 frames per second with all the eye candy turned up, and the difference between 120 frames and 114 frames in &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Warzone&lt;/em&gt; at max settings (probably) isn’t worth quibbling about. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XLW6Iu"&gt;With a beefier processor, you should be able to get 60+ frames per second in a maxed-out &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; experience, too — I’m still testing with my old Core i7-7700K, which is more than good enough for most of the games on this list (&lt;em&gt;SotR&lt;/em&gt; shows I’m 100 percent GPU-bound), but a few titles like &lt;em&gt;Microsoft Flight Simulator&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk&lt;/em&gt; are still &lt;a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/news/cyberpunk-2077-cpu-scaling-benchmarks"&gt;notoriously CPU limited&lt;/a&gt; and more cores could help. As another example, my colleague Tom Warren saw identical framerates to me in &lt;em&gt;Watch Dogs: Legion&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Metro Exodus&lt;/em&gt; pairing the 6700 XT with a far newer Intel chip, but slightly higher in &lt;em&gt;Assassin’s Creed Valhalla&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AltwJ3XkfCRXElV9GHBI0SURoFU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22374455/twarren_210315_4475_00013.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Is that a 3060 Ti or 3070 on the left? Both can beat the RX 6700 XT in some games.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="in6KWJ"&gt;But look at &lt;em&gt;Valheim&lt;/em&gt;. Look at &lt;em&gt;Assassin’s Creed Odyssey&lt;/em&gt;. Look at &lt;em&gt;Control&lt;/em&gt;.  How is AMD underperforming or merely tying these lower tier cards? Things aren’t any rosier at 4K resolution, in case you’re wondering: while I still recommend Nvidia’s 3070 for entry-level 4K, the 6700 XT just doesn’t have the same oomph. In games like &lt;em&gt;Control&lt;/em&gt; and&lt;em&gt; Metro Exodus&lt;/em&gt;, I had to drop the settings to a comparatively dull “low,” where the 3070 managed to play those games at 4K and medium-spec without trouble. And of course, AMD doesn’t yet have a DLSS competitor if you’re a fan of AI-upscaled resolution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cvfSnC"&gt;It’s not like AMD is winning in any other particular way, either. While I’m actually fond of the company’s new two-slot design (clearly inspired by&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=1969%2Bcharger%2Brt%2Brear&amp;amp;source=lnms&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjVxqzNv4ztAhXJsJ4KHbkpCaQQ_AUoAXoECBQQAw&amp;amp;biw=1200&amp;amp;bih=1777"&gt; a certain late 1960s muscle car&lt;/a&gt;) and I don’t hugely mind going from three to two axial fans, the RX 6700 XT is just as chunky and nearly as power-hungry as the RX 6800 (230W vs. 250W) without as much to show for it. AMD still recommends a 650W power supply, a pricey proposition for those of us with tall PC cases, and you’ll need both 6 and 8-pin PCIe connectors, while Nvidia’s comparable cards make do with a single 8-pin. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8kiOBLQ3flrIWMtImp0I69blrdI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22374449/twarren_210315_4475_0005.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Vcrrcpbz4HalOrdEwvo9-QUdIWw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22374450/twarren_210315_4475_0006.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gQpmQfk4LLNpRa_e4m36AivCga0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22374448/twarren_210315_4475_0004_2.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lRnQeCNMwvvuK3vPKuycTSzSQaI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22374451/twarren_210315_4475_0008.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6Chll8"&gt;I also saw the 6700 XT hit 89 degrees Celsius on one occasion. While I don’t have enough evidence to say that’s a problem, I’ve yet to see Nvidia’s 3070 cross 82 degrees C even with my case fans unplugged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8VIk7M"&gt;But as I alluded to in my intro, very little of this will matter if you can actually find this card for $479. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WHlnePW2WpajvPbofLSfv8nP4U0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22374453/twarren_210315_4475_00011.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;All modern AMD and Nvidia cards have plenty of display support, with one HDMI 2.1 and three DisplayPorts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ciJ1Ut"&gt;In December, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/6/22155611/price-ps5-xbox-series-x-nvidia-rtx-3080-3070-3090-3060-amd-rx-6800-xt-scalpers-ebay"&gt;I reported&lt;/a&gt; that the true street price of a $399 Nvidia RTX 3060 Ti was actually $675, and that the street price of an $499 RTX 3070 was actually $819. Those were the average prices people actually paid on eBay that month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8oiYcE"&gt;If you think that sounds unbelievable, hear this: the street price of the RTX 3060 Ti and RTX 3070 are now approaching $1,200 &lt;em&gt;each&lt;/em&gt;. People are paying triple for what should have been Nvidia’s bang-for-the-buck graphics card now, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22300659/nvidia-geforce-rtx-3060-review"&gt;the launch of a “$329” RTX 3060&lt;/a&gt; didn’t slow that &lt;em&gt;at all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T08V99"&gt;To me, this indicates two things: First, AMD probably isn’t going to be able to make anywhere near enough RX 6700 XTs to hit anywhere near that $479 price for the vast majority of buyers, even if it produces “significantly” more cards. I wouldn’t expect today to play out any differently than &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301391/nvidia-rtx-3060-launch-supply-demand-newegg-shuffle"&gt;any previous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2020/10/29/21539965/nvidia-rtx-3070-preorders-sold-out-micro-center-best-buy-newegg"&gt;GPU launch&lt;/a&gt; since the pandemic began. It’s a well-established pattern now. Second, none of these fantasyland prices will necessarily keep the RX 6700 XT from being a hit if the supply is there. As you can see from the similar street prices for the 3060 Ti and 3070, the market has a way of balancing prices out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="xwIPm1"&gt;If you miraculously see this card for its list price, buy it, because you won’t get anything better for anywhere near that price in the near future. But it feels inferior to every Nvidia GPU that can compare — and I wouldn’t trade my 3060 Ti for one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="yVOzcZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"AMD Radeon RX 6800 review: entry-level 4K","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21572796/amd-radeon-rx-6800-review-4k-gaming-test-benchmarks"},{"title":"AMD Radeon RX 6800 XT review: AMD is back in the game","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21571414/amd-radeon-rx-6800-xt-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/3/17/22334662/amd-radeon-rx-6700-xt-review-gpu-graphics-card"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/3/17/22334662/amd-radeon-rx-6700-xt-review-gpu-graphics-card</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-17T08:34:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-17T08:34:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>Uber’s new minimum wage policy in the UK doesn’t meet the law, say case claimants</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Uber logo against a dark background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/77ezcyZork854gIO0WFEFjvpuwo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68980295/acastro_180927_1777_uber_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wtD6zB"&gt;Yaseen Aslam and James Farrar, the two lead claimants in the successful tribunal that fought Uber for employee rights in the UK, say the company is continuing to flout the law. After it lost a final appeal with the UK’s Supreme Court &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/21330906/uber-uk-supreme-court-employee-rights"&gt;in February&lt;/a&gt;, Uber announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334771/uber-uk-drivers-workers-benefits-employees-decision"&gt;yesterday&lt;/a&gt; it would give its 70,000 drivers minimum wage, holiday pay, and pensions. But Aslam and Farrar say the details of Uber’s new policy mean it’s still short-changing workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uglw5K"&gt;The issue is that Uber has only &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001543151/000155278121000124/e21143_ex99-1.htm"&gt;committed&lt;/a&gt; to paying drivers at least minimum wage for the time “after accepting a trip request.” This, says Aslam and Farrar, contradicts the Supreme Court ruling, which found that working time for Uber drivers included any period when individuals were logged in to the company’s app and waiting in the right area for fares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="kq1Y16"&gt;&lt;q&gt;UK Uber drivers will only be paid minimum wage after accepting fares&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ygZLUI"&gt;As the justice of the Supreme Court, Lord Leggatt, stated in a &lt;a href="https://www.supremecourt.uk/watch/uksc-2019-0029/judgment.html"&gt;summary&lt;/a&gt; of the ruling: “The judgement also upholds the finding of the employment tribunal that for the purposes of the legislation, the claimants’ working time was not limited, as Uber had argued, to periods when they were actually driving passengers to their destinations. It also included any period when the driver was logged into the Uber app in the relevant territory and was ready and willing to accept trips.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2cgkqD"&gt;Speaking to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, Aslam said the language in the Supreme Court ruling was clear, and Uber’s response showed it would continue to try to bend the law to its advantage. “It’s just a cheap PR trick,” he said of the decision. “If I’m working 10 hours, but only have passengers on board for three hours, I’m only getting paid for those three hours.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z8el0R"&gt;Farrar added: “The Supreme Court was asked to decide two things: if we are workers and when we are workers. These were the decisions it had to make and Uber is in clear violation of them. We can’t accept it and we won’t accept it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NQdB3t"&gt;Uber did not respond to requests for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Uber’s Latest Court Date Gives Gig Economy Its Biggest Test" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M4s1CCqG15VQdVusGl1OCBd5q7Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22376997/1055482772.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Getty&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yaseen Aslam (left) and James Farrar (right) were part of a small group of Uber drivers who brought a case against the company in 2015. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="iAJEjz"&gt;It’s not clear how much time Uber drivers spend on average waiting for fares, and thus how much potential income has been lost through the company’s new policy. Farrar and Aslam say that drivers will lose out on 40 to 50 percent of a possible wage increase. A &lt;a href="https://laborcenter.berkeley.edu/the-uber-lyft-ballot-initiative-guarantees-only-5-64-an-hour-2/"&gt;2019 study&lt;/a&gt; by the University of California, Berkeley, found that US Uber and Lyft drivers spent roughly a third of their working day logged in to the app and waiting for fares. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SKlyO3"&gt;Aslam said Uber’s new policy is crafted to ensure it won’t lose a key advantage versus traditional taxi firms: creating an abundance of drivers who respond quickly to customers without paying for their downtime. “It costs Uber next to nothing to operate in cities,” says Aslam. “All the liabilities — the running costs and expenses of maintaining a vehicle — are shifted over to the driver. So the more drivers they have on the platform, the better it is for them: it doesn’t cost them anything but creates more availability for customers.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FYs4YH"&gt;If Uber had to pay drivers for time spent waiting for requests from passengers, it would lose this advantage. It’s for reasons such as this that &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/ubers-is-based-on-regulatory-arbitrage-2017-9?r=US&amp;amp;IR=T"&gt;critics of the company&lt;/a&gt; say it doesn’t offer any significant technological innovations at all. It simply extracts extra value from workers by exploiting loopholes in countries’ legal systems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EeFjHn"&gt;What’s not clear is what happens next from a legal perspective. Aslam says it’s up to the UK government to enforce the Supreme Court ruling, but he also says London’s transport regulator, Transport for London (TfL), should take responsibility. “TfL has the power to protect workers but they don’t want to get involved,” he says. Farrar added: “It should have been government enforcing this all the way back to the original case, rather than expecting precarious workers to bring complicated litigation all the way to the Supreme Court.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="TOr745"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s regrettable that Uber hasn’t done the right thing entirely.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1KaTbB"&gt;Paul Jennings, a partner at the London law firm Bates Wells, who represented Aslam and Farrar in their original employment tribunal, said that the discrepancy between Uber’s new policies and the Supreme Court ruling was clear and that the government should act. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jDY3Mm"&gt;“The idea that drivers are only working when they have a passenger in the car is not consistent with the judgement,” Jennings told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “It’s regrettable that Uber hasn’t done the right thing entirely.” He added compliance could be enforced without additional litigation, but that the latter might be necessary to “reinforce the judgement.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1iW0qh"&gt;Overall, Aslam and Farrar say they are pleased that Uber has been forced to change its policies but are disappointed their fight is not yet over. “We suffered financially and mentally. But we’re not delighted. What we’re getting is a bone chucked at us,” says Aslam. “It’s never going to stop, we know that. This is Uber.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="omZgCE"&gt;Farrar added that despite the time and resources they’d committed already, the pair was happy to keep on fighting: “Me and Yaseen, we latch on and we don’t let go.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22335554/ubers-uk-minimum-wage-decision-employee-rights-flouting-law"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22335554/ubers-uk-minimum-wage-decision-employee-rights-flouting-law</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-17T04:25:27-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-17T04:25:27-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung says it might skip the Galaxy Note this year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Samsung Galaxy Note 20" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WXUBlu67qThdoqzNvjiUniBOhqs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68979722/dbohn_201004_4226_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dieter Bohn / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="A1PW2J"&gt;Samsung has warned that it might not be able to ship a Galaxy Note phone in 2021 after all, citing difficulties in launching two flagship phones in one year, in comments at its annual shareholders meeting &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-17/samsung-warns-of-serious-imbalance-in-the-chips-industry"&gt;reported on by Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y3IGzu"&gt;“[The] Note series is positioned as a high-end model in our business portfolio,” said mobile chief DJ Koh. “It could be a burden to unveil two flagship models in a year so it might be difficult to release [a] Note model in 2H. The timing of [the] Note model launch can be changed but we seek to release a Note model next year.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HcbvgQ"&gt;The comments came as Samsung sounded the alarm about a global semiconductor shortage, saying that its business will likely be affected next quarter. The potential delay or cancellation of a 2021 Galaxy Note is apparently separate, however; Koh says it’s more about streamlining the lineup, according to Bloomberg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="0euKFz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Samsung Galaxy Note 20 review: stylus tax","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21506471/samsung-galaxy-note-20-review-price-stylus"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="C0ofMo"&gt;The release of a Galaxy Note this year was already far from a sure thing. Samsung had indicated plans to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22175769/samsung-stylus-galaxy-phones-s21-foldable"&gt;bring its key stylus feature to more phones&lt;/a&gt; in the Galaxy lineup, sparking speculation that the line may come to an end. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22177972/galaxy-note-21-still-happening-yonhap"&gt;A Yonhap report&lt;/a&gt;, however, said that Samsung was still preparing to release a new Note phone in 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3kweW2"&gt;Samsung declined to comment to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; on the existence of this device at the time, reiterating its plans to “bring some of the most beloved features of the Galaxy Note to more device categories in 2021.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22335502/galaxy-note-2021-delay-canceled-samsung"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22335502/galaxy-note-2021-delay-canceled-samsung</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T21:39:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T21:39:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>The PS5 is getting DVR support in Japan this year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y0B4mZvfzrZuGjcFjI3AN9d2Qec=/0x0:2163x1442/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68978911/nasne.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HdP8Qn"&gt;Sony has announced that the PlayStation 5 will get DVR functionality in Japan by way of a new app that’ll work with its Nasne tuners. The app will be called Torne (pronounced &lt;em&gt;to-ru-ne&lt;/em&gt;) and should be available later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vsEWLF"&gt;Torne was originally a TV tuner add-on for the PS3 that was released in 2010 and allowed you to save broadcast shows to your console’s hard drive and transfer them to a PSP or PS Vita. It was followed by Nasne, which added its own storage and worked more like a NAS drive, with the recordings available through a mobile app. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DoRqKR"&gt;Sony stopped selling Nasne in 2019, but last year Japanese peripheral manufacturer Buffalo announced that it’d take over the product and release Buffalo-branded versions, with the first models set to ship this spring. The new Nasne still looks like a PS3, just with a Buffalo logo on it; Buffalo is doubling the internal storage to 2TB, however, and tripling external storage capability to 6TB. It’ll go on sale later this month for 29,800 yen (~$270).&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22335149/ps5-nasne-dvr-app-japan-release-buffalo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22335149/ps5-nasne-dvr-app-japan-release-buffalo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T20:44:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T20:44:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple just gave Russia a spot on the iPhone to advertise its favorite apps to its citizens</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pM2WG3NS0H7dkbe0LJ91Bm-c8cQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68978734/acastro_180130_1777_0005.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="NkHvcU"&gt;Starting April 1st, users setting up a new iPhone in Russia will see a screen that allows them to automatically install apps that are officially sanctioned by the Russian government, in compliance with Russian law (&lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-iphone-ipad-mac-russia-apps-preinstall-144255015.html"&gt;via Engadget&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ptFlOo"&gt;The law in question &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/3/20977459/russian-law-pre-installed-domestic-software-tvs-smartphones-laptops"&gt;was passed back in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, and requires smartphones, tablets, laptops, desktops, and smart TVs sold in Russia to come pre-installed with specific apps made by Russian companies by April 1st, &lt;a href="https://www.vedomosti.ru/technology/articles/2021/03/15/861564-iphone-soft"&gt;according to Russian news site &lt;em&gt;Vedomosti&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. (The law was originally set to go into effect in July 2020, but was pushed back to April 2021). &lt;em&gt;Vedomosti&lt;/em&gt; also says that apps won’t be installed if users don’t want them. Apple confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that it will comply with the law by giving the users the option to install the apps when activating the phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XRBCqS"&gt;Which apps are specifically going to be offered to users remains unclear, though &lt;em&gt;Vedomosti&lt;/em&gt; cites a government services app, and apps from Russian companies including Yandex, Mail.ru, and Kaspersky Lab. The government seems to be aware that it might be problematic to favor specific apps, and is planning to expand its list over time: “The Ministry is not at all interested in seeing popular apps included in the mandatory pre-installation list take dominant positions. If alternatives emerge on the market, prove interesting to users and gain popularity quickly, they will be included in this selection and also offered for pre-installation,” a Russian official told &lt;em&gt;Vedomosti.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2DEOsL"&gt;Apple has historically kept tight control over the iPhone’s setup process, and that appears to now be changing, if only in one market. While Apple has previously made changes to stay on the side of local laws — it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/27/20985762/apple-maps-weather-apps-crimea-russia-territory"&gt;changed maps&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/31/17803638/apple-watch-pride-face-russia-block"&gt;blocked pride watch faces&lt;/a&gt; in Russia, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/18/17587304/apple-icloud-china-user-data-state-run-telecom-privacy-security"&gt;now stores iCloud data on state-run servers in China&lt;/a&gt; — this may be one of the more dramatic changes, as it affects a screen that every user will see when they set up their iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XOLofx"&gt;Apple has slowly been allowing users to change how iOS works out of the box, with the ability to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21301478/apple-ios-14-default-apps-browser-email-changes-features-report"&gt;change some default apps in iOS 14&lt;/a&gt;, but now it’s given a small amount of control over the setup process to the Russian government, too. As the company faces &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/16/21292651/apple-eu-antitrust-investigation-app-store-apple-pay"&gt;legal challenges from the EU&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/interface/2020/6/17/21292983/apple-spotify-antitrust-hey-email-congress-house-judiciary-tim-cook"&gt;US over antitrust&lt;/a&gt;, and over &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/13/18263453/spotify-apple-app-store-antitrust-complaint-ec-30-percent-cut-unfair"&gt;giving its competitors a level playing field&lt;/a&gt;, we may see Apple having to give over some more control to governments if it wants to sell its phones to their citizens — though it probably won’t be compelled to ask users if they want to install Spotify at setup. Probably.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334641/apple-follows-russian-default-apps-law-setup-screen-options-user"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334641/apple-follows-russian-default-apps-law-setup-screen-options-user</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T20:36:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T20:36:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Cricut promises unlimited lifetime uploads for existing crafting machines after user backlash</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ucVZNCoR9AXuDUHalhOpFmucaYk=/73x0:1113x693/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68978716/Screen_Shot_2021_03_16_at_3.22.55_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Cricut&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="z12izD"&gt;Cricut is changing its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22332212/cricut-crafting-machine-design-space-upload-limit"&gt;recently announced plan to require a subscription&lt;/a&gt; to get the full use of its crafting machines for precisely cutting paper and other materials. Following backlash from crafters and fans who rely on its machines, &lt;a href="https://inspiration.cricut.com/a-letter-to-the-cricut-community-from-ashish-arora-cricut-ceo/?fbclid=IwAR2nc73QTwCyEhdw0ihhsPdDrAMIlGlq0gMJk2SvuOeVefA6IFvQXts7a6M"&gt;Cricut CEO Ashish Arora apologized for the decision&lt;/a&gt;, and announced that the company will postpone the requirement for a subscription and give unlimited uploads to all users with a registered Cricut device purchased before December 31st, 2021 — for the lifetime of their machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uwzw2c"&gt;Without an upload limit, crafters will be able to use Cricut and its required Design Space app as usual. They can create designs in the app or third-party software like Procreate, and then format it to be cut out of materials like paper, fabric, vinyl, and even wood using a Cricut machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OebFvD"&gt;Prior to this change, Cricut was planning on requiring a $9.99 per month / $95.88 per year Cricut Access Standard plan or a Premium plan for $118.88 per year to keep unlimited uploads. Owners who didn’t pay would be limited to 20 uploads per month, which many creators, who often favor starting Cricut projects in other apps and uploading them into Design Space, were worried would make the device unusable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sO9Exy"&gt;Arora says that people who buy a resold Cricut machine can also get unlimited lifetime uploads, provided the new owner creates a Cricut account and connects their machine before the end of 2021. Arora says the company is also considering options for educational or maker space settings that might burn through 20 uploads quickly, but had no specifics to share other than a general promise that nothing will change before the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GBOZYU"&gt;While in an ideal world a machine that can cost up to $399 wouldn’t ever need a subscription, Cricut has at least listened to the concerns of its current customers and offered them what seems like a pretty good compromise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CJLwcJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PP5LUV"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334798/cricut-postpones-subscription-unlimited-uploads"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334798/cricut-postpones-subscription-unlimited-uploads</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T19:55:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T19:55:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Elon Musk won’t sell his NFT song after all</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Billionaire Elon Musk Receives Axel Springer Award" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aTuSByLXDQ5PqH2RZaNL0TzF-oc=/0x0:3909x2606/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68978575/1229901655.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;div id="xYYRLM"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Actually, doesn’t feel quite right selling this. Will pass.&lt;/p&gt;— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1371969967176957956?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3iC9s0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/3/16/22335019/elon-musk-not-selling-techno-house-nft-song"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/3/16/22335019/elon-musk-not-selling-techno-house-nft-song</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
