<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-10T16:01:05-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-10T16:01:05-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-10T16:01:05-05:00</updated>
    <title>Disney’s new hockey deal will see over 1,000 NHL games stream on ESPN Plus</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Winnipeg Jets v Toronto Maple Leafs" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2b39uX6l5hPd81ou3Okebe4gDDw=/0x6:4200x2806/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68944447/1306372719.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Claus Andersen/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2nzi3W"&gt;Disney and the NHL have just signed a massive new TV rights deal for the next seven years that will see ESPN and ESPN Plus become key places to watch and stream hockey games, starting with the upcoming 2021-2022 season. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XcQRhB"&gt;It’s the first time that ESPN will offer NHL hockey games since its previous deal expired in 2005, and this time streaming — particularly, ESPN Plus streaming — is a huge part of that deal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sZjtZh"&gt;ESPN Plus is effectively replacing NHL.TV as the NHL’s out-of-market streaming service, with over 1,000 games each season available for fans to stream. ESPN and ABC will also get 25 exclusive national regular-season games each season, while 75 games a year will be exclusive to ESPN Plus and Hulu. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cGXckr"&gt;Additionally, ABC will get exclusive rights to the Stanley Cup Final for four of the seven years, with the option to simultaneously broadcast those finals games on ESPN Plus and other linear ESPN networks. Furthermore, ABC and ESPN together will get to broadcast half of the NHL playoffs each season, too. (Specifically, Disney’s networks will get one of the Conference Final series and half of all the first round and second round games each year.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Popl2M"&gt;The new NHL deal marks one of the biggest expansions yet for ESPN Plus when it comes to offering live sports from one of the major North American leagues, and it instantly makes the service a must-have for hockey fans across the US. The NHL deal will also offer a new wave of live sports on Hulu, thanks to the 75 games that will be exclusively broadcast on Hulu and ESPN Plus (which, unlike the other ESPN Plus games, will be available to all Hulu subscribers whether they subscribe to ESPN Plus or not).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GlX5jc"&gt;The news comes just as Disney is &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/digital/news/espn-plus-launches-hulu-1234927368/"&gt;rolling out a larger integration&lt;/a&gt; for ESPN Plus subscribers to be able to access that additional sport content within Hulu itself, which should help make it even easier for subscribers of both of those services to find the newly added NHL games when they debut this fall. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zpkkoM"&gt;ESPN Plus alone costs $5.99 per month, or it can be bundled alongside Hulu with ads and Disney Plus for $13.99 per month. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323789/disney-nhl-deal-espn-plus-stream-abc-hockey-sports"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323789/disney-nhl-deal-espn-plus-stream-abc-hockey-sports</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-10T16:00:06-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-10T16:00:06-05:00</updated>
    <title>I guess I have to watch ads everywhere on my $1,500 LG TV now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/B9a-td2wJMV9A1q2HrIMY3G_-Sc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68944432/DSCF3184.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2nSl5e"&gt;This afternoon, I was updating the streaming apps on my 2020 LG CX OLED TV, something I do from time to time, but today was different. Out of nowhere, I saw (and heard) an ad for Ace Hardware start playing in the lower-left corner. It autoplayed with sound without any action on my part. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ltzf2Q"&gt;Now I’m fully aware that it’s not unusual to see ads placed around a TV’s home screen or main menu. LG, Samsung, Roku, Vizio, and others are all in on this game. We live in an era when smart TVs can automatically recognize what you’re watching, and TV makers are building nice ad businesses for themselves with all of the data that gets funneled in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="l78Tro"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Just got served a legit commercial while updating the apps on my LG OLED TV.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This isn’t the future I signed up for. &lt;a href="https://t.co/TmQflsCxsl"&gt;pic.twitter.com/TmQflsCxsl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Chris Welch (@chriswelch) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/chriswelch/status/1369733357756686349?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="f05LaU"&gt;But this felt pretty egregious even by today’s standards. A random, full-on commercial just popping up in LG’s app store? Is there no escape from this stuff? We’re just going to cram ads into every corner of a TV’s software, huh? Imagine if an autoplay ad started up while you were updating the apps on your smartphone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p4rsTQ"&gt;The Ace spot wasn’t particularly annoying — it was over in 15 seconds — nor did it feel targeted at me or creepy. It’s really the placement that feels like a step too far. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MwP49d"&gt;This stuff can come off as invasive, but it’s also partially what’s steadily brought the prices down on even high-end TVs. I got this 55-inch CX on sale for like $1,400, and it’s pretty much the best TV on the market for next-gen gaming. But even if this beautiful panel came cheaper than it might have &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; ads plastered in random places, the level of ad infiltration on display here is still disheartening to see. LG recently announced it will be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22223767/lg-webos-6-tv-software-oled-qned-lcd-redesign"&gt;licensing webOS to other TV brands&lt;/a&gt;, so maybe the company is trying to see how far it can push things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qD3h9b"&gt;I guess I can always cut the TV’s internet connection and stick to a streaming stick or my Xbox Series X if the autoplay commercials keep popping up everywhere. Or maybe I can opt out of a setting somewhere to end the barrage. Some people aren’t bothered by this stuff, but if you are, check out &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/YouShouldKnow/comments/gn7fw5/ysk_if_you_own_a_samsung_smart_tv_that_has_ads/?utm_medium=android_app&amp;amp;utm_source=share"&gt;this excellent Reddit thread&lt;/a&gt;, which can help you fight back and block some of the domains that these TVs phone home to for their ads. A lot of people on Twitter also &lt;a href="https://pi-hole.net/"&gt;pointed me to Pi-hole&lt;/a&gt; as a fix. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/3/10/22323790/lg-oled-tv-commercials-content-store"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/3/10/22323790/lg-oled-tv-commercials-content-store</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-10T15:51:09-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-10T15:51:09-05:00</updated>
    <title>Gnosia is like a single-player Among Us for the Switch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4Ns2e_IP3H-aElBO-R0vZQcXKhA=/100x0:1180x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68944339/01.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xODgVb"&gt;Deduction games like &lt;em&gt;Among Us &lt;/em&gt;are exciting in part because of the human element — finding those signs that someone is lying, or doing your best to conceal your true identity while everyone scrutinizes you. The experience changes dramatically depending on who you’re playing with and how committed they are to their role. That’s what makes G&lt;em&gt;nosia&lt;/em&gt; so intriguing. The core idea is the same, as you’re either trying to suss out who the enemy is or disguise yourself as one. But there’s a huge difference: in &lt;em&gt;Gnosia&lt;/em&gt; you play entirely by yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P9NMZv"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gnosia&lt;/em&gt; is probably best described as a deduction game transformed into a visual novel. You play as a crew member on a spaceship, one that has been infected by an alien race known as the gnosia. While everyone looks human (well, except for the talking dolphin), one or more is actually an alien who wants nothing more than to kill the rest of the crew. The gnosia only attack at night, and each day the crew will hold a vote on who is most suspicious; the person chosen will then be placed in a cold sleep in hopes of preventing a death. This process continues until either the threat has been eliminated or the gnosia take over the ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vgQwlS"&gt;So how do you figure out if a computer-controlled character is lying? These voting sequences make up the heart of &lt;em&gt;Gnosia&lt;/em&gt;, and they consist of a lot of dialogue. Before actually voting, everyone will voice their opinions and concerns. Some of the crew will have specific roles — like a doctor who can tell if someone is actually a gnosia — but of course they could be lying about that as well. Your job is to pay close attention to what people say, as well as how often, to figure out the truth. Are they constantly trying to divert blame elsewhere? Are they suspiciously quiet? At the same time, you have to be careful not to draw too much attention to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4KNCtW-TRsWyGrvqswMwSCNkRuM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22360142/03.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="QUMDuF"&gt;One of the more interesting narrative twists employed by developer Petit Depotto in &lt;em&gt;Gnosia&lt;/em&gt; is that you and the rest of the crew relive the same day over and over. The variables change each loop, including your own, essentially randomizing things. Sometimes you’re aiming to save everyone, other times you’re plotting as a gnosia. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JzpXiJ"&gt;On the one hand, this leads to a lot of repetition. You’ll be reading through the same lines of dialogue regularly and living through essentially the same day more than 100 times. But the game does a good job of slowly introducing new elements to make things interesting. It’ll take many loops before you have the ability to calm everyone with some small talk or form alliances with other characters. Eventually, more roles are introduced, including a second alien type bent on destroying the universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qoRO22"&gt;The loop mechanic can get tedious, but it’s also integral to the story the game is trying to tell. Every time you start over, you learn just a little bit more about the characters, the gnosia, and the mystery of the loop itself. At a certain point I stopped even trying to “win” during the votes and instead experimented with new techniques in hopes of uncovering more clues. There’s even some RPG-like progression, as you can improve your skills across loops; I focused primarily on stealth and charisma, so that people wouldn’t notice me much but would always listen to me when they did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e5No4v"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gnosia&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t quite replicate the experience of playing with real people, but it’s not really trying to. Instead, the game uses the framework of social titles like &lt;em&gt;Among Us&lt;/em&gt; as a frame for its sci-fi horror story. After about 20 loops, I was hooked and pushing forward through the same routine like a detective in search of any clue I could find. And if I fail? Well, there are plenty of more chances to try again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mjeZI1"&gt;&lt;small&gt;Gnosia &lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;is available now on the Nintendo Switch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22323251/gnosia-review-nintendo-switch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22323251/gnosia-review-nintendo-switch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-10T15:38:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-10T15:38:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>A YouTuber has already posted a full Galaxy A52 5G unboxing</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SefcI2MdrvWvu0FJjNfLlRMxlOs=/267x0:1842x1050/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68944216/galaxya52_unboxing_leak.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;New A-series phones, including the A52 5G seen here, are expected to debut on March 17th. | Image: Moboaesthetics&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1uGRyb"&gt;The Galaxy A52 5G will likely be announced next week at &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/9/22322232/samsung-galaxy-a52-a72-unpacked-event-awesome"&gt;Samsung’s second Unpacked event&lt;/a&gt; of the year, but thanks to an &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/gKPSqrWtAKc"&gt;early unboxing&lt;/a&gt; video &lt;a href="https://www.gsmarena.com/samsung_galaxy_a52_5g_appears_in_unboxing_video-news-48142.php"&gt;spotted by &lt;em&gt;GSMArena&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we won’t have to wait that long to see it in action. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vcfms9"&gt;The upcoming midrange device has been subject to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278488/samsung-galaxy-a52-a72-leak-90hz-refresh-rate-screen"&gt;plenty of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22309330/samsung-galaxy-a52-5g-security-updates-leak"&gt;leaks&lt;/a&gt; over the past few weeks, and the video from YouTuber &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCh1fruDeJL4QcVgFUULX_cQ"&gt;Moboaesthetics&lt;/a&gt; seems to confirm many of them. The device in the video matches up with previously leaked renders and appears to be fully functional. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sbnzcg"&gt;Specs featured in the lengthy video include a 64-megapixel main camera with OIS, a 120Hz display, IP67 dust and water resistance, under-screen fingerprint sensor, and a 4,500mAh battery. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22230868/samsung-galaxy-s21-storage-microsd-support-slot"&gt;Unlike the S21 series&lt;/a&gt;, there’s a microSD card slot for memory expansion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dQsP3w"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gKPSqrWtAKc?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tolgqU"&gt;The A52 5G and also-rumored A72 5G are both expected to be accompanied by cheaper non-5G variants with other slightly downgraded specs, like a 90Hz screen rather than 120Hz. All told, they’re shaping up to look like highly competitive midrange phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YAegLA"&gt;Samsung has not confirmed exactly what it’s announcing at next week’s event, but given the appearance of this video and the recent leaks, it seems certain that the A52 5G will be making its debut soon.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323557/samsung-galaxy-a52-5g-leak-video-unboxing"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323557/samsung-galaxy-a52-5g-leak-video-unboxing</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-10T15:25:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-10T15:25:24-05:00</updated>
    <title>Valorant pro Sinatraa suspended following sexual assault allegations</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Sinatraa" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bx_xPbUJJpXSxw6varJaBfUkAD8=/58x0:901x562/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68944072/unnamed.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Robert Paul / Blizzard Entertainment&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="I5E1RK"&gt;Jay “Sinatraa” Won, one of the biggest names in competitive &lt;em&gt;Valorant&lt;/em&gt;, has been suspended from the game and by his team following accusations of sexual assault. In a statement &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cIe0h/status/1369497186740928512"&gt;posted on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;, Cleo Hernandez posted a lengthy account of her nine-month-long relationship with Won, detailing a disturbing history of physical and emotional abuse, supported by audio recordings and screenshots of messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A5dxGJ"&gt;“I have avoided talking about any aspects of me and Jay’s relationship for over a year,” Hernandez wrote. “I never spoke about it mostly because this is horrifying, and also because I’ve seen the way women in our community are treated when they try to talk about being hurt by prominent figures.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="XOTM5o"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Gaming can’t fix its abuse problem one person at a time","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21307560/gaming-abuse-harassment-systemic-ubisoft-chris-avellone"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wVPK4m"&gt;Won is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/6/20950550/sinatraa-interview-overwatch-league-mvp-san-francisco-shock-e-sports"&gt;a former &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League MVP&lt;/a&gt; who &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/28/21240497/overwatch-league-sinatraa-leaving-sf-shock-valorant"&gt;made the switch to &lt;em&gt;Valorant&lt;/em&gt; last year&lt;/a&gt;. Since Hernandez’s accusations, developer Riot has suspended Won from the game, stating that he won’t be participating in the &lt;em&gt;Valorant&lt;/em&gt; Champions Tour competition that’s slated to take place this weekend. “We are aware of the current situation regarding Jay Won and have launched an investigation,” Alex Francois, Riot’s global head of competitive operations, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/valesports_na/status/1369711283197472769"&gt;said in a statement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZIVB4j"&gt;Simiarly, Won’s team, Sentinels, has launched its own investigation and suspended the player. “While the investigation is pending, he is suspended from the team,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sentinels/status/1369717636553183238"&gt;Sentinels said in a statement&lt;/a&gt;. “We will provide a further update once the investigation has concluded.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HZEJ4N"&gt;Won has yet to release a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323695/jay-sinatraa-won-valorant-suspended-sexual-assault-allegations"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323695/jay-sinatraa-won-valorant-suspended-sexual-assault-allegations</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-10T15:18:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-10T15:18:16-05:00</updated>
    <title>YouTube’s search bar is spacing out in many web browsers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e-xnAZL7eBG_Jd2YnUS4U-bO5jU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68944035/acastro_180403_1777_youtube_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3FtxzF"&gt;So this is a weird one: depending on the browser you’re using, your space bar may not work in the YouTube.com search bar. Pressing it makes absolutely nothing happen, so your YouTube searches end up being one long string of words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eWb5EZ"&gt;This bug appears to show up on the desktop site when you’re using a browser that &lt;em&gt;isn’t &lt;/em&gt;based on Chrome. Firefox wouldn’t take spaces in Windows, macOS, or even Android if you request the desktop version of the website. It seems to work with Safari on iPhones, but it &lt;em&gt;doesn’t&lt;/em&gt; work on Safari on iPad — probably because iPads request the desktop site, too. Asking for the mobile version immediately fixed it there, and requesting the desktop site on an iPhone immediately broke spaces. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yxO3If"&gt;The good news is that the lack of spaces probably won’t make your YouTube experience any different — it’s very good at understanding your intent even on long, relatively obscure searches with a bunch of words smashed together.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Uc_-A8Cw3uRxM_L_wNGgwH1Hyh4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22360288/Screen_Shot_2021_03_10_at_11.12.59_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bravo, YouTube search algorithm.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="s00fKw"&gt;The bad news is there’s another, &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; more annoying bug: if you’re trying to watch a video and type in the search bar at the same time, your keystrokes may end up acting as shortcuts. Pressing the space bar won’t do anything in the search bar, but it will pause your video. Your “T” might show up in the search bar, but it also switched my video into theater mode. (Help!)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mHusqasoK2f1jz8XBtrGrn3z3cs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22360387/YTBug_Animated_Image__Large_.gif"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Typing in the search bar can make many awful things happen on your screen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="sKc0cx"&gt;YouTube did not immediately respond to a request for comment — hopefully because it’s busy working on a fix. For the moment, Google’s own Chrome browser (and YouTube app) are there if you need a YouTube fix.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323716/youtube-search-bar-space-bug-safari-firefox-chrome"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323716/youtube-search-bar-space-bug-safari-firefox-chrome</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-10T15:02:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-10T15:02:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter plans to let anyone start hosting Twitter Spaces in April</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/S5P447vkdEduAUvaItqhhjPqGHk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68943924/acastro_200715_1777_twitter_0004.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OTOJn4"&gt;If you opened your phone this morning to see a Twitter app update, you might have been excited — and then confused — to see an advertisement for Twitter Spaces, the audio chat rooms that the social network &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22309629/twitter-launches-spaces-android-ios-audio-clubhouse"&gt;recently launched to compete with the similar Clubhouse app&lt;/a&gt;. “Introducing Spaces,” the iOS update says, promising that “Now you can Tweet and Talk.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dc1IA8"&gt;But while you won’t actually find the ability to create a new Space unless you’re one of a select few, the company now says it’s planning to launch Spaces to everyone next month.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Mh2xxJEdDyxU5s8NVZhXuhoUSYU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22360580/Image_from_iOS__1_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot by The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The iOS update note.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="JLCapr"&gt;Amusingly, we overheard the news &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSpaces/status/1369719689958592520"&gt;in a Twitter Space itself&lt;/a&gt;, hosted by the company. Twitter’s plans aren’t set in stone, but the gist is that they’re trying to get the product into a state where anyone can host a Twitter Space starting in April. April is the goal. In the meanwhile, users on both iOS &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22309629/twitter-launches-spaces-android-ios-audio-clubhouse"&gt;and Android&lt;/a&gt; can both join and talk in existing Spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eqtymI"&gt;Twitter Spaces are just one of an array of new features the typically feature-resistant company has announced in the past few months, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22319527/twitter-kayvon-beykpour-interview-consumer-product-decoder"&gt;we’ve got a wide-ranging interview with Twitter product head Kayvon Beykpour&lt;/a&gt; where he discusses the whole set, including the company’s Snap and Instagram-like disappearing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21573380/twitter-fleets-launch-stories-spaces-future"&gt;Twitter Fleets&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301375/twitter-super-follows-communities-paid-followers"&gt;Super Follows&lt;/a&gt; where you can pay to subscribe to extra Twitter content from your favorite creators — a business which reminds us of platforms like Substack and OnlyFans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="3aGnUW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Twitter is reinventing itself: an interview with Kayvon Beykpour","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22319527/twitter-kayvon-beykpour-interview-consumer-product-decoder"},{"title":"Twitter says it’ll eventually let people natively record their Spaces","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/9/22321158/twitter-spaces-record-conversation-kayvon-beykpour"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323767/twitter-spaces-april-release-date-plan"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323767/twitter-spaces-april-release-date-plan</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-10T14:05:29-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-10T14:05:29-05:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook moves to dismiss the US government’s antitrust case</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GShPB6KxOkkd1PSRmHU8it9489U=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68943495/acastro_180828_1777_facebook_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Todebl"&gt;In two motions filed Wednesday, Facebook called on the courts to dismiss a pair of &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/03/motions-to-dismiss-ftc-state-ag-lawsuits/"&gt;sweeping competition cases&lt;/a&gt; brought on by the federal government and a coalition of states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="47IWqV"&gt;The Federal Trade Commission and a group of state attorneys general &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22158483/facebook-antitrust-lawsuit-anti-competition-behavior-attorneys-general"&gt;filed separate lawsuits&lt;/a&gt; against Facebook last December accusing the tech giant of engaging in anti-competitive behavior. The two lawsuits make similar claims, alleging that Facebook bought Instagram and WhatsApp in order to squash the threat the two apps posed to the company’s business. Additionally, the attorneys general accused Facebook of using its market dominance to stifle the growth of competing services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HWvO0S"&gt;The FTC’s case also calls for the courts to unwind Facebook’s acquisitions of Instagram and WhatsApp into separate companies once again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9nP3qf"&gt;In Facebook’s motion to dismiss the cases, it claims the lawsuits allege that the two nascent apps were “potential” competitors, rather than a pressing and actual threat to Facebook’s business. The FTC declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="adziuj"&gt;“Facebook is wrong on the law and wrong on our complaint,” New York Attorney General Letitia James said in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; Wednesday. “We are confident in our case, which is why almost every state in this nation has joined our bipartisan lawsuit to end Facebook’s illegal conduct. We will continue to stand up for the millions of consumers and many small businesses that have been harmed by Facebook’s unlawful behavior.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="cJtJHF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“These complaints do not credibly claim that our conduct harmed either”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="X7TcAN"&gt;“Antitrust laws are intended to promote competition and protect consumers,” Facebook said in a blog post Wednesday. “These complaints do not credibly claim that our conduct harmed either.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZKMeaB"&gt;Because the FTC cleared the Instagram and WhatsApp acquisitions at the time, Facebook also argues that the commission doesn’t have sufficient grounds to reverse that decision. “Facebook is aware of no comparable, much less successful, challenge by the FTC to a long-completed acquisition that the FTC itself cleared,” Facebook’s filing reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FUEwHP"&gt;Facebook is at the center of a series of antitrust investigations brought on by the federal government, states, and Congress. Last month, the House Judiciary Committee’s subcommittee on antitrust held its first hearing on tech dominance after a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/29/21335706/antitrust-hearing-highlights-facebook-google-amazon-apple-congress-testimony"&gt;16-month probe&lt;/a&gt; into companies like Amazon, Apple, Facebook, and Google. That investigation prompted a report from Democrats calling for structural remedies to Facebook’s business, potentially leading to a breakup. The hearing marked &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301453/antitrust-facebook-google-amazon-apple-reform-cicilline-buck"&gt;the last leg of the committee’s work&lt;/a&gt;, holding a second series of hearings on how to reform US antitrust law as it’s applied to tech companies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wT6K2Q"&gt;Committees in both the House and Senate plan to hold hearings this week, and new legislation is expected to land before the end of spring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M7REh2"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated 3/10/21 at 3:12PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Included a statement from New York Attorney General Letitia James.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323642/facebook-antitrust-ftc-states-new-york-dismiss-instagram-whatsapp-acquisition"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323642/facebook-antitrust-ftc-states-new-york-dismiss-instagram-whatsapp-acquisition</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-10T14:04:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-10T14:04:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apex Legends is out on the Switch, but it’s missing a key feature: cross-progression</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UcRONyLSx4Plg6Fx7O7m_QQb7vo=/200x0:2339x1426/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68943479/Screen_Shot_2021_03_10_at_1.29.42_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gMpowt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/apex-legends-switch/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the latest major cross-platform Switch port. After years of availability on Xbox, PlayStation, and PC, EA has finally brought the battle royale shooter to Nintendo’s handheld console, adding a fresh wave of players to the mix and a new, on-the-go option for existing &lt;em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;/em&gt; fans. But there’s a glaring issue with the Switch port: right now, there’s no cross-progression, making the Switch port effectively a nonstarter for dedicated players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="UvCY7t"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apex Legends won’t dethrone Fortnite, but there’s still nothing like it","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286834/apex-legends-review-ps4-xbox-pc-fortnite-battle-royale"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="hqFu5W"&gt;At launch, the new Nintendo Switch version of &lt;em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;/em&gt; offers cross-platform gameplay — meaning that you can play with and against players on Xbox, PlayStation, and PC in addition to other Switch players. But any progress or purchases that players have made on those other platforms won’t carry over. Effectively, &lt;em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;/em&gt; players on the Switch are starting from scratch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7VJgjq"&gt;Despite the “Season 8” branding that covers &lt;em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;/em&gt;, there’s no continuity for players on the Switch version — so much so, that players have to replay the tutorial before they’ll actually be able to drop into a full match. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ueN7ZJ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/03/feature_panic_button_and_respawn_on_the_challenge_of_bringing_apex_legends_on_switch"&gt;In an interview with &lt;em&gt;Nintendo Life&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Chad Grenier (Respawn’s game director for &lt;em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;/em&gt;) said that cross-progression is planned for the future, but with the caveat that “we’re a ways out from being able to offer that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="UtfKH7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We’re a ways out from being able to offer [cross-progression].”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qnsqcz"&gt;Grenier explains that there are a mix of issues preventing Respawn from offering cross-progression, with contractual, legal, and technical problems that need to be sorted out. “It’s a complex challenge of multiple accounts existing for various users that we have to resolve or merge, there are legal and contractual things to navigate with purchasing on other platforms and having those carryover and also some technical challenges.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="khN8SN"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;/em&gt; is by no means the first mainstream game to run into this issue. Unfortunately, the lack of cross-progression is more common than not for most cross-platform games, both on the Switch and on other platforms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bKvqrT"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/17/20919715/overwatch-switch-port-review-impressions-blizzard-nintendo-game"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, for example, has been struggling with the lack of cross-platform progression and gameplay for years, despite the emphasis that Blizzard puts on cosmetic content unlocks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TU0P99"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Control&lt;/em&gt; has been ported to plenty of platforms since its launch, including Amazon’s Luna, a cloud-based version for the Nintendo Switch, and a next-gen version for PS5 and Xbox One. But there’s no crossover for saves between those titles — if you started &lt;em&gt;Control&lt;/em&gt; on a PS4, then that’s where your save is stuck forever, even if you want to try streaming it from an internet service or playing with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22260905/control-ps5-next-gen-hands-on-preview"&gt;fancier graphics on a next-gen console&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kdvLQV"&gt;Obviously, there are real technical and legal issues here. &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt;’s skins are heavily tied to its loot box economy, which are all purchased through the platform-specific stores, which can complicate things. &lt;em&gt;Control&lt;/em&gt;’s lack of next-gen saves are tied to updates to the game engine that prevented Remedy from offering continuity for existing players. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5nUz9S3s0CI20SFYnad4YhCcKKo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22360105/Screen_Shot_2021_03_10_at_1.29.37_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="g2k53l"&gt;But there’s also a wealth of games in 2021 that show that a better way is possible. &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/21/21332925/rocket-league-free-to-play-psyonix-epic-game-store-steam"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rocket&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;League&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are the gold standard here: simply log into Epic’s free-to-play games on your platform of choice, and all your stuff is there waiting for you. You can play with friends on any platform (well, except iOS), from any platform, with all of your skins, emotes, items, and unlocks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ezJFOA"&gt;And even recent Ubisoft games have added cross-play and cross-progression through &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/21/21527273/ubisoft-connect-crossplay-cross-saves-watch-dogs-legion"&gt;Ubisoft Connect&lt;/a&gt;, letting players start playing sprawling RPGs like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/12/21319059/assassins-creed-valhalla-hands-on-preview-pc-xbox-one-ps4-gameplay-ubisoft-rpg"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Assassin’s Creed Valhalla&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on one system and continue on another. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lnv9bR"&gt;In 2021, offering cross-progression and cross-play is increasingly becoming table stakes for major games. With massive titles that can take dozens, if not hundreds of hours of players’ time, locking down progression to a single console or platform just doesn’t make sense. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="gJOQ0j"&gt;&lt;q&gt;When in-game items are the whole point, it’s essential to make them available everywhere&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rZXWmW"&gt;And that’s doubly true for free-to-play games like &lt;em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;/em&gt;, which live or die on the strength and size of their multiplayer community and the money that they can make off selling cosmetic items. When your game is free to download on any platform, it’s critical that the time and money that players invest into getting those digital rewards be consistent across those platforms, because the collection of those items is the main reward structure of those games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UwI0ty"&gt;Bungie figured that out a while ago, back when it transitioned &lt;em&gt;Destiny 2&lt;/em&gt; to a free-to-play title — it now&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;allows players to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/22/20828271/destiny-2-how-to-cross-save-game-pc-xbox-ps4-steam-battlenet"&gt;sync their in-game items&lt;/a&gt; to whatever platform they’re playing on (even if Bungie is still working out cross-platform gameplay). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q3gaQj"&gt;The whole point of putting a game like &lt;em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;/em&gt; on the Switch is to offer players another avenue to play the game. Sure, it may attract some new players, but for many others it’s a way to spend even more time with a game they already love. But by locking things like hero characters or items that players have painstakingly unlocked through time or money to a single platform, the game is still stuck in an outdated model of game design. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TWnBbZ"&gt;Players have a finite amount of time. And why would you open up &lt;em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;/em&gt; to unlock all your old gear again when you pick up your Switch when you could make progress on your &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; battle pass — a far more substantial unlock that isn’t tethered to a single system — instead? &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323591/apex-legends-switch-port-cross-progression-purchases-fortnite"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323591/apex-legends-switch-port-cross-progression-purchases-fortnite</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-10T13:58:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-10T13:58:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>Don’t invest in SPACs just because of celebrity endorsements, SEC says</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Shaq wearing Magic Leap One headset" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/z-eQTLRNW4O66hvYItDNGdy7dWY=/69x0:980x607/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68943386/Screen_Shot_2018_02_13_at_7.55.37_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.recode.net/2018/2/9/16997086/how-to-watch-live-livestream-rony-abovitz-magic-leap-adam-silver-nba-augmented-reality-code-media" target="_blank"&gt;Recode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mnNtav"&gt;Today, the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) has found the growing trend of celebrity-endorsed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21502700/spac-explained-meaning-special-purpose-acquisition-company"&gt;special purpose acquisition companies (SPACs)&lt;/a&gt; dangerous enough &lt;a href="https://www.investor.gov/introduction-investing/general-resources/news-alerts/alerts-bulletins/investor-alerts/celebrity"&gt;to warn investors in a new statement&lt;/a&gt;: just because a celebrity is participating in or endorsing a SPAC, doesn’t mean you should invest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xf483W"&gt;The terminology can be complicated, but the SEC’s advice is fairly simple. Like if any stranger recommended you invest in a business (in this case, one trying to merge with other companies to take them public), there are a lot of unknowns that should be accounted for. “Celebrities, like anyone else, can be lured into participating in a risky investment,” writes the SEC’s Office of Investor Education and Advocacy. Celebrities, many already being wealthy and successful, “may be better able to sustain the risk of loss.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="UzGGJO"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Celebrity endorsements don’t make investments any safer&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YEb5XP"&gt;Additionally, as part of the deal to be an initial investor or sponsor for a SPAC, celebrities might have economic arrangements that are different from the average shareholder. As much as I’d want to trust Papa John’s board member and basketball star Shaquille O’Neal’s choice in acquiring a specific “audience aggregation platform” (something &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/korihale/2020/10/20/shaq-moves-into-spacs-with-former-disney-execs--mlk-jrs-son/?sh=41ae8a7c6c77"&gt;he’s apparently looking to get into&lt;/a&gt;), he might be earning far more than you or I ever will off our likely riskier investments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kLYyYK"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;“The rapid increase in the volume of SPACs represents a significant change and we are taking a hard look at the disclosures and other structural issues surrounding SPACs,” said John Coates, Acting Director of the SEC’s Division of Corporation Finance. &lt;a href="https://t.co/3SYLtF2ehj"&gt;https://t.co/3SYLtF2ehj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— SEC_News (@SEC_News) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SEC_News/status/1369669846670209027?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="snBBtf"&gt;The timing for this warning (noted in the tweet above) is directly connected to the exponential growth in the interest in SPACs, from bringing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266661/genetic-health-23andme-public-spac-richard-branson"&gt;23andMe public&lt;/a&gt; to basically swallowing every &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/28/22247942/faraday-future-spac-merger-public-psac-property-solutions-nasdaq"&gt;electric&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22268085/lucid-motors-spac-merger-public-nyse-cciv-deal-air-sedan"&gt;vehicle&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/18/21374272/canoo-ev-startup-spac-ipo-reverse-merger"&gt;startup&lt;/a&gt; you’ve heard of. The SEC has seen fit to step in to warn investors and caution celebrities in these kinds of situations in the past, specifically requiring stars to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/2/16597870/sec-warns-celebrities-endorsement-ico-cryptocurrency"&gt;disclose how much they’re compensated&lt;/a&gt; to advertise cryptocurrency initial coin offerings (ICOs). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lj3guA"&gt;SPACs aren’t going away, and in a culture where many wealthy celebrities are also wealthy investors — or where investors like Chamath Palihapitiya &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/when-spac-man-chamath-palihapitiya-speaks-reddit-and-wall-street-listen-11615006818"&gt;can wield celebrity-like influence&lt;/a&gt; over &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/03/05/chamath-palihapitiya-sells-virgin-galactic-spce-stake.html"&gt;a company and its accompanying value&lt;/a&gt; — seeing past the glamour and bluster is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JUpwaQ"&gt;“Even if a celebrity is involved in a SPAC, investing in one may not be a good idea for you. Before investing, always do your research,” writes the SEC. We all want, nay, &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to be friends with Shaq, but that doesn’t mean our money needs to.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323357/sec-warning-celebrity-spac-endorsements-invest"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323357/sec-warning-celebrity-spac-endorsements-invest</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
