<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-11-08T03:05:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-08T03:05:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-08T03:05:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Disney Plus is giving away a month for $2 for new and returning streamers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="disney+" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4f0UTZVCE9p-7y31DnJ7D2FdVUk=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70110670/disneyplus.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Disney&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="82aoGs"&gt;Disney Plus is offering a pretty killer deal for streamers who may have left or have yet to try its service. For new and eligible returning subscribers, one month of Disney Plus will cost just $2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MCiAtt"&gt;The offer is one of several promotions the service has announced as part of its anticipated &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686598/disney-plus-day-shang-chi-streaming-free"&gt;Disney Plus Day&lt;/a&gt; event taking place November 12th. In addition to offering a month of its service to eligible users for dirt cheap, subscribers can take advantage of special perks at its parks on Disney Plus Day. The perks include early entry to parks 30 minutes before opening at the Walt Disney World Resort and Disneyland Resort, as well as free Disney PhotoPass photo downloads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="69B6gH"&gt;On the retail front, new merch will hit ShopDisney from across Disney franchises, including Marvel, Pixar, and Star Wars. Disney Plus subscribers can also take advantage of free shipping in the US and Europe from November 12th to November 14th. Disney &lt;a href="https://books.disney.com/"&gt;ebooks&lt;/a&gt;, meanwhile, will be discounted to just $1 through November 17th. And the company is teaming up with Target to offer special giveaways when subscribers sign up in-store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SroxE2"&gt;Disney is also partnering with Funko for 10 percent off Disney Plus products with the code DISNEYPLUSDAY. (The same code can be used at WizKids for a 5-percent discount on Disney products, which will ship with a Marvel-themed gift, from November 8th through November 14th.) Plus, New Star Wars Funko products will be made available at BringHometheBounty.com beginning at 6AM PT on November 12th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z1H0b0"&gt;In addition, participating AMC theaters will screen surprise Disney movies from November 12th through November 14th for $5 per ticket. You won’t know what you’re seeing until the show begins, and each screening will include a surprise short. Special concessions and a Disney Plus poster are included with the ticket price. More than &lt;a href="https://www.amctheatres.com/disney-plus-day-surprise-screenings-weekend"&gt;200 AMC theaters&lt;/a&gt; will be participating. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YUXBmc"&gt;Lastly, it wouldn’t be an event in 2021 with some kind of NFT shenanigans, would it? Disney is partnering with VeVe to offer special NFTs of golden statues of characters from across the Disney family of brands and franchises, including &lt;em&gt;The Simpsons&lt;/em&gt;. The NFT series launches November 7th, and an “ultra-rare” collectible will become available on Disney Plus Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0JlIpT"&gt;Following the one-month $2 promotional pricing, Disney Plus will cost its regular $8 per month. So if you plan to swipe the service on the cheap and then bail, remember to set a reminder to cancel your subscription before it quadruples in price.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22766153/disney-plus-day-2-subscription-amc-theaters"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22766153/disney-plus-day-2-subscription-amc-theaters</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-07T17:56:54-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-07T17:56:54-05:00</updated>
    <title>New Trailers: The Power of the Dog, Moonfall, Morbius, The Book of Boba Fett and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EGCInu9HhH3vpe3xK88Xo-R2W_U=/164x0:1517x902/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70109429/benedict_1.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Benedict Cumberbatch stars in The Power of the Dog, coming to Netflix December 1st. | &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LRDPo0CHrko&amp;amp;ab_channel=Netflix" target="_blank"&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="cuZnlN"&gt;I have noticed this irritating thing where more and more trailers have a scene to introduce the trailer. It is already an introduction! You are wasting precious seconds telling me what I’m about to see instead of just showing me! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="osY1WB"&gt;OK end rant. I finished my (late) binge of &lt;em&gt;Maid&lt;/em&gt; on Netflix and am now really interested to read the book. It may have been one of the most realistic descriptions of poverty I’ve ever seen, where even the smallest setback can have a devastating effect, and you’re painfully aware of every penny you earn and where it’s going to go before you even get paid. Also &lt;em&gt;The Morning Show&lt;/em&gt; finally had a good, return-to-form episode with Ruthless Cory, Spiraling Chip, and Awful Alex each at their peak. The best scene, though, belonged to Mia (Karen Pittman) as she tried to make sense of the episode’s big event on a personal level. More of her, please, show (although with two episodes left in the season and Alex just back from Italy and breathing on and hugging everyone... maybe not?). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rPTZRQ"&gt;This week’s trailers: The baddies take center stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="coIN3K"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="g6CkLl"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LRDPo0CHrko?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="BxDyAV"&gt;The Power of the Dog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="FXtWWN"&gt;Benedict Cumberbatch plays a mean cattle rancher who bullies his brother, his sister-in-law, and her son in this absolutely gorgeous-looking movie directed by Academy Award winner Jane Campion which is based on the 1967 novel of the same name by Thomas Savage. The movie is already generating (I know, but it &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/10/07/movies/2022-oscar-contenders.html?searchResultPosition=1"&gt;really is&lt;/a&gt;) Oscar buzz for Cumberbatch and for Kirsten Dunst. Along with Cumberbatch, Dunst, Jesse Plemons, and Kodi Smit-McPhee star in &lt;em&gt;The Power of the Dog&lt;/em&gt;, which comes to theaters on November 17th and Netflix on December 1st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="26KQJH"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="P55rbK"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rOJ1cw6mohw?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="RFRKiI"&gt;The Book of Boba Fett &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="5Rvf3z"&gt;“Every galaxy has an underworld” is this series’ tagline and hell yeah it does let’s go. The &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;long&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;-awaited series on the &lt;em&gt;Star Wars &lt;/em&gt;movies’ most popular villain (note that the first thing we hear in the trailer is: “I am not a bounty hunter”) is almost here, and this first trailer should do plenty to whet fans’ appetites. We got our first look at the series in a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=afuXMQQHr8A&amp;amp;ab_channel=StarWarsCoffee"&gt;post-credit scene&lt;/a&gt; from the finale of the second season of &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt;, where Fett kills Bib Fortuna and takes the throne once occupied by his late employer Jabba the Hutt. The loyal Fennec Shand sits at his side. The new trailer shows Fett trying to negotiate with some of Jabba’s former associates: “Jabba ruled with fear. I intend to rule with respect.” Bring on the wretched hive of scum and villainy! Temuera Morrison and Ming-Na Wen star in &lt;em&gt;The Book of Boba Fett&lt;/em&gt;, which comes to Disney Plus on December 29th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="keim8k"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="afXIdW"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xx97DuHGr2o?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="fIxrGU"&gt;Moonfall &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="7MXe4N"&gt;Maybe this movie will be good! Big, loud, disaster &lt;a href="https://www.rogerebert.com/cast-and-crew/roland-emmerich"&gt;movies directed by Roland Emmerich&lt;/a&gt; are ... well they are big and loud and usually very popular. The premise here is that the guys on the Apollo 11 moon landing in 1969 found something sinister that has been kept hidden for 50 years but now it’s like, out? And the moon is going to … fall? And also it’s hollow and there is something in there? Anyway it will all be Very Bad for Earth and, the Only One Who Can Save Us All is Halle Berry (that tracks, actually). She stars along with Patrick Wilson, John Bradley, and Donald Sutherland (who is apparently playing The Voice of Doom) in &lt;em&gt;Moonfall&lt;/em&gt;, which hits theaters February 4th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="sDxru7"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oZ6iiRrz1SY?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="U1ikfn"&gt;Morbius&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="1hKUKc"&gt;Maybe &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; movie will be good! It’s been almost two years since we last saw a trailer for this movie about a lesser-known Spiderman antihero and I think &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/13/21062568/morbius-trailer-jared-leto-marvel-sony-pictures-venom-michael-keaton-vulture"&gt;our review&lt;/a&gt; of the first trailer back in January 2020 holds up pretty well. Dr. Michael Morbius has a blood ailment he has to find a cure for and accidentally turns himself into a sort-of vampire with perfect abs “and some form of bat radar” (literally a quote from the trailer) and he can also sort of fly, plus he needs to drink blood. OK, cool. Jared Leto, Matt Smith, Adria Arjona, Jared Harris, Al Madrigal, and Tyrese Gibson star in Morbius, which comes to theaters in January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IsgIqX"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is also a new trailer&lt;/strong&gt; for &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IQqqAWMIIAQ&amp;amp;ab_channel=SonyPicturesEntertainment"&gt;Resident Evil: Raccoon City&lt;/a&gt; which I will link here but decided not to embed because it’s pretty gruesome throughout. It comes to theaters November 24th. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/7/22766931/new-trailers-power-of-the-dog-moonfall-morbius-boba-fett-disney-netflix"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/7/22766931/new-trailers-power-of-the-dog-moonfall-morbius-boba-fett-disney-netflix</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-07T16:41:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-07T16:41:01-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google explains why the Pixel 6’s fingerprint scanner may be sluggish</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Google Pixel 6" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/60P-QuB0BsysdDpovEEVCaBlJFE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70109224/pixel6.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MzeGYN"&gt;There’s a lot to rave about with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22731034/google-pixel-6-pro-price-specs-features-release-date-hands-on"&gt;the Google Pixel 6 and 6 Pro&lt;/a&gt;, but their fingerprint scanners are not among those things. Since the Pixel 6 release in October, &lt;a href="https://www.tomsguide.com/opinion/google-pixel-6-fingerprint-sensor-is-the-weakest-part-of-a-killer-android-phone"&gt;users have been complaining&lt;/a&gt; about its sluggish, unreliable fingerprint scanner that makes the phone a hassle to unlock. Google has finally responded to those complaints, and while it provided an explanation, it didn’t really offer any solid solution (via &lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/google-pixel-6-slow-fingerprint-sensor-195023475.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Engadget&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wMFFdB"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We're sorry for the hassle. The Pixel 6 fingerprint sensor utilizes enhanced security algorithms. In some instances, these added protections can take longer to verify or require more direct contact with the sensor. Try troubleshooting steps: &lt;a href="https://t.co/uTbifE5Uyo"&gt;https://t.co/uTbifE5Uyo&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks. ^Levi&lt;/p&gt;— Made By Google (@madebygoogle) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/madebygoogle/status/1457043416139898881?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 6, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qr3erX"&gt;In a reply on Twitter, Google attributes the issue to the “enhanced security algorithms” that the Pixel 6’s fingerprint scanner uses. Google says that these security measures can make your fingerprint “take longer to verify or require more direct contact with the sensor.” It then provides a link to a &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/answer/6285273"&gt;Google support page&lt;/a&gt; that really doesn’t offer much help, besides suggesting to ensure your fingers are clean and that you’re using a finger that you’ve registered with the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gAQi4k"&gt;Replies from other Twitter users suggest that it may be a hardware issue. The Pixel 6 uses an under-the-screen optical fingerprint scanner instead of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22223494/qualcomm-ultrasonic-fingerprint-reader-samsung-galaxy-s21-announcement"&gt;a fast ultrasonic one&lt;/a&gt; like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22252460/samsung-galaxy-s21-review-price-camera-processor"&gt;Samsung Galaxy S21&lt;/a&gt;, which some users say could be the reason behind the sensor’s poor performance. But as noted by &lt;em&gt;Engadget&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Android/comments/qoayk3/made_by_google_the_pixel_6_fingerprint_sensor/"&gt;other users on Reddit&lt;/a&gt; say that the optical fingerprint scanner works fine on their OnePlus phones, possibly indicating a software issue specific to the Pixel 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pj9cqD"&gt;For now, it looks like there’s no clear solution to the Pixel 6’s finicky fingerprint scanner, and Google’s answer is vague at best. There’s no telling whether Google can patch the issue in a software update, or if the scanner’s so-called “enhanced” security system really is picky when it comes to prints. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; reached out to Google with a request for comment but didn’t immediately hear back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HgkZVa"&gt;Until Google decides to resurrect face unlock, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/17/20919390/google-pixel-4-face-unlock-eyes-closed-privacy-eye-contact"&gt;which had its own security flaws&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll just have to resort to typing in your PIN. Otherwise, the Pixel 6 will test your patience as you try to scan your fingerprint over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="xfcEGg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Google’s Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro are bigger, better, and smarter","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22750387/google-pixel-6-pro-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/7/22768853/google-explains-pixel-6-fingerprint-scanner-unreliable"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/7/22768853/google-explains-pixel-6-fingerprint-scanner-unreliable</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-07T15:34:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-07T15:34:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>SpaceX Crew-3 launch delayed again, this time to November 10th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4FpIRwmZL9nF5w2sU4GTJT0zQuI=/339x0:4116x2518/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70109011/51634067771_6e46bf9d92_o.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;SpaceX’s Falcon 9 rocket and Crew Dragon&lt;/em&gt; | Image: NASA / Joel Kowsky&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HsxmOa"&gt;The SpaceX Crew-3 mission to the International Space Station has been delayed again, this time to November 10th at 9:03PM ET, &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/commercialcrew/2021/11/07/nasa-spacex-adjust-crew-2-station-departure-date/"&gt;NASA said Sunday&lt;/a&gt;. Although NASA had originally planned to have a changing of the guard with the Crew-2 astronauts greeting the Crew-3 team before Crew-2 departed, the space agency has decided to return the Crew 2 to Earth first, pushing that mission from Sunday to Monday, November 8th at 2:05PM ET, because of weather concerns. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nmpd0O"&gt;Wednesday so far has an 80 percent chance of favorable weather for liftoff, SpaceX noted in a tweet on Sunday. If all goes to plan the craft will take off from Kennedy Space Center in Florida, and dock with the ISS at about 7:10PM ET on November 11th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="IFkpwZ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Following Crew-2’s return to Earth, Falcon 9 will launch Dragon’s third long-duration crew mission to the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Space_Station?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Space_Station&lt;/a&gt; as soon as Wednesday, November 10; weather forecast is 80% favorable for liftoff &lt;a href="https://t.co/xOFGVw3fOP"&gt;pic.twitter.com/xOFGVw3fOP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— SpaceX (@SpaceX) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SpaceX/status/1457375316003880963?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BFPCCc"&gt;After it was originally scheduled for an October 31st launch, the Crew-3 has seen several delays, for weather concerns, and once for a “minor medical issue” with one of the crew members. . Four astronauts—NASA’s Thomas Marshburn, Raja Chari, and Kayla Barron, and the European Space Agency’s Matthias Maurer— will travel aboard SpaceX’s Crew Dragon spacecraft to begin a six-month stay in orbit on the ISS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BHPU31"&gt;Crew-3 is the third operational crewed flight for SpaceX as part of NASA’s Commercial Crew Program, which uses private craft to bring NASA astronauts to and from the ISS. If it ever launches, it will be the fifth time Space X has sent people to orbit aboard its Crew Dragon; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/30/21269703/spacex-launch-crew-dragon-nasa-orbit-successful"&gt;SpaceX launched two NASA astronauts to the ISS&lt;/a&gt; in May 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QcT0EO"&gt;NASA’s livestream coverage of the launch will be available &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=21X5lGlDOfg"&gt;on YouTube&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/nasalive"&gt;on the agency’s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2yAe7n"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d4ra4r"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nhlgyT"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/7/22768771/spacex-crew-3-launch-delayed-november-10th-nasa"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/7/22768771/spacex-crew-3-launch-delayed-november-10th-nasa</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-07T14:37:32-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-07T14:37:32-05:00</updated>
    <title>Elon Musk polls his Twitter followers, and a majority votes he should sell 10 percent of his Tesla stock </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="GERMANY-US-POLITICS-ELECTION-ECONOMY-TESLA" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cyzGx3raWrRYNjc3325O1p_XkrE=/0x152:3678x2604/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70108047/1234651136.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Elon Musk polled his Twitter followers | Photo by PATRICK PLEUL/POOL/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JchOSd"&gt;Tesla CEO and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22163361/elon-musk-billionaire-richest-world-jeff-bezos-tesla-stock-spacex"&gt;wealthiest&lt;/a&gt; person in the world Elon Musk tweeted out a poll Saturday, asking his Twitter followers whether he should sell 10 percent of his stock in the automaker, ostensibly to pay more tax. When the poll closed Sunday afternoon, 57.9 percent of more than 3.5 million participants had voted “yes,” and 42.1 percent voted “no.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="coNDYE"&gt;“Much is made lately of unrealized gains being a means of tax avoidance, so I propose selling 10% of my Tesla stock,” Musk &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1457066048944066565?s=20"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; Saturday. He said in a subsequent tweet that he’d abide by the results of the poll “whichever way it goes.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5dcmVn"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I will abide by the results of this poll, whichever way it goes&lt;/p&gt;— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1457066048944066565?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 6, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QPNAbf"&gt;Musk had been a vocal critic of a &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/how-the-billionaires-income-tax-would-work-11635325201?mod=article_inline"&gt;proposal to tax unrealized gains&lt;/a&gt; on publicly traded assets for some of the wealthiest Americans. Under the &lt;a href="https://www.finance.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/Billionaires%20Income%20Tax%20-%20One%20Pager.pdf"&gt;proposal&lt;/a&gt; by Sen. Ron Wyden (D-Oregon), if assets increased in value, even if the person didn’t sell the assets, the person would have to pay taxes on the unrealized gain. It would basically end the tax loophole that lets billionaires defer capital gains taxes indefinitely, while still being able to borrow against that wealth. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IMidhq"&gt;“Eventually, they run out of other people’s money and then they come for you,” Musk &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1452792781726961668"&gt;tweeted in October&lt;/a&gt;, in response to a tweet expressing concerns about the proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BYvF1I"&gt;Wyden responded to Musk’s idea, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RonWyden/status/1457110175932846080?s=20"&gt;tweeting&lt;/a&gt; on Saturday: “Whether or not the world’s wealthiest man pays any taxes at all shouldn’t depend on the results of a Twitter poll, It’s time for the Billionaires Income Tax.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t1PfxF"&gt;Saturday was also not the first time Musk has floated the idea of selling off some Tesla stock. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HZP67-DECVw&amp;amp;ab_channel=Recode"&gt;Musk told journalist Kara Swisher at Code Conference&lt;/a&gt; in September that he planned to sell a big chunk of his Tesla stock options before they expired. “I have a bunch of [stock] options that are expiring early next year, so that’s a huge block of options we’ll sell in Q4,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qnW8ZV"&gt;Swisher asked if he was surprised by how much Tesla’s stock had gone up. “I have gone on record and said I think [Tesla’s] stock price is too high, in my opinion,” Musk added later. “What am I supposed to do? I’m not the one making it go up.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gTbnZh"&gt;ProPublica journalist &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/eisingerj/status/1457099957635272707?s=21"&gt;Jesse Eisinger pointed out on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; that the third tweet in Musk’s Saturday thread — “Note, I do not take a cash salary or bonus from anywhere. I only have stock, thus the only way for me to pay taxes personally is to sell stock”— appeared to confirm the news site’s reporting on how &lt;a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/the-secret-irs-files-trove-of-never-before-seen-records-reveal-how-the-wealthiest-avoid-income-tax"&gt;the ultra-wealthy avoid paying income taxes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="QHjEBm"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Note, I do not take a cash salary or bonus from anywhere. I only have stock, thus the only way for me to pay taxes personally is to sell stock.&lt;/p&gt;— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1457067398712942592?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 6, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QheKCL"&gt;“Thank you for confirming our story: That for the ultra wealthy income taxes are essentially voluntary,” Eisinger tweeted, noting that Musk had previously called the story “misleading.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hIjOQY"&gt;As of Sunday afternoon, Musk had not commented on the poll results. We’ll update this post if he does. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FBAtbo"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: November 7th, 2:37PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Adds final result of Musk’s Twitter poll&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/7/22768364/elon-musk-poll-twitter-tesla-10-percent-billionaires-capital-gains-tax"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/7/22768364/elon-musk-poll-twitter-tesla-10-percent-billionaires-capital-gains-tax</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-07T14:11:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-07T14:11:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft says it will end OneDrive updates to Windows 7 and 8 in March</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9v0GGeYwWNwjU89uuuO3ff1UXR8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70108787/acastro_180226_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9RtmAN"&gt;Microsoft says OneDrive users on Windows, 7, 8, or 8.1 will be unable to sync their content to the cloud starting on March 1st, 2022, according to a blog &lt;a href="https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/microsoft-onedrive-blog/end-of-support-for-onedrive-desktop-application-on-windows-7-8/ba-p/2929066"&gt;post on its Tech Community forum&lt;/a&gt;. OneDrive will also no longer receive updates if it’s running on a system that doesn’t have Windows 10 or Windows 11 installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rTDgN2"&gt;Files will still be accessible from the OneDrive app no matter what version of Windows you’re using — they’ll just no longer automatically upload to the cloud. To avoid any issues with OneDrive, Microsoft recommends upgrading to a newer version of Windows before March of next year. As for systems that aren’t able to run Windows 10 or Windows 11, Microsoft says that users can still back up their files by uploading them to the OneDrive web app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n2zOco"&gt;In addition to halting updates and the ability to sync, &lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/office/onedrive-sync-app-no-longer-supported-on-windows-7-8-or-8-1-a3bd41c7-5f82-42c3-aa46-de782581be2a"&gt;OneDrive on Windows 7, 8, and 8.1 will lose support on January 1st&lt;/a&gt;. According to Microsoft, the reason for the change is “to focus resources on new technologies and operating systems, and to provide users with the most up-to-date and secure experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zYxPfl"&gt;The lifecycle for &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/lifecycle/products/windows-8"&gt;Windows 8 ended in 2016&lt;/a&gt;, with Microsoft halting mainstream support for &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/lifecycle/products/windows-81"&gt;Windows 8.1 in 2018&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/14/21065122/microsoft-windows-7-end-of-support-lifecycle-millions-pcs"&gt;Windows 7 in 2020&lt;/a&gt;. Now that Microsoft is planning to&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22533018/microsoft-windows-10-end-support-date"&gt; end support for Windows 10 in 2025&lt;/a&gt;, it might be time to start preparing for a Windows 11 upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="gaE4IR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Windows 11 review: A familiar home that’s still being renovated","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22708762/microsoft-windows-11-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/7/22768667/onedrive-windows-7-8-stop-syncing-cloud-march"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/7/22768667/onedrive-windows-7-8-stop-syncing-cloud-march</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-07T12:53:34-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-07T12:53:34-05:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix will reportedly make games available via the App Store on iOS</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7ro84Ro2U8gA3HdKD5gpspEoUVI=/81x0:879x532/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70108589/Screen_Shot_2021_11_02_at_1.24.40_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uKpxIa"&gt;Earlier this month, Netflix officially got into gaming by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759628/netflix-games-global-rollout-mobile-android-devices"&gt;rolling out a mobile game service for Android users&lt;/a&gt;. While Netflix says that it's working on an iOS version of the service, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;tech reporter Mark Gurman says that Apple’s App Store policies will prevent Netflix from making games available from its app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4RS4ih"&gt;Apple bars third-party apps from functioning as a hub for games, which has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/18/20912689/apple-cloud-gaming-streaming-xcloud-stadia-app-store-guidelines-rules"&gt;become a point of contention with cloud gaming services&lt;/a&gt; like Xbox Cloud Gaming, Nvidia GeForce Now, and Google Stadia. Cloud gaming services can only get around this by offering their games through a web app, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/23/22589398/facebook-cloud-gaming-web-app-launch-apple"&gt;just like Facebook has already done&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="RUev3O"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Apple will need to change its rules or grant Netflix an exemption”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Fsebeq"&gt;According to Gurman’s latest &lt;em&gt;Power On&lt;/em&gt; newsletter, Netflix will tiptoe around Apple’s rules by making its games available via the App Store. This means that games won’t be downloadable or playable from the Netflix app — you’ll only be able to launch them from there. The service currently functions in this way on Android; the games are neatly packaged in a dedicated tab on the Netflix app, but are downloaded individually from the Google Play Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vWXEa6"&gt;While this setup is fine, it isn’t ideal for an all-in-one gaming service. Users should be able to download and play games from within the service itself. That’s why Gurman predicts that Netflix will eventually bring its games to the cloud. Again, this would work fine for Android, but Apple’s policies make it nearly impossible for cloud gaming to thrive, forcing services to settle for measly web apps. If and when Netflix decides to embrace cloud gaming, it’s unclear what will happen to the service on iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Dm6jE"&gt;“Apple will need to change its rules or grant Netflix an exemption,” Gurman says. “That leaves the ultimate success of Netflix’s service in the hands of Apple, a longtime partner but also a growing rival.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/7/22768521/netflix-reportedly-make-games-available-app-store"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/7/22768521/netflix-reportedly-make-games-available-app-store</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-07T11:52:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-07T11:52:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>Forza Horizon 5 will add on-screen sign language interpreters in a post-launch update</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/U3b6UY8gBmOahTeoULjND-AMUF8=/295x0:1587x861/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70108394/forza_screen_cap.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Forza Horizon 4 will add sign language interpreters to cut scenes in a post-launch update | &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o450zdpHZ7U&amp;amp;t=259s&amp;amp;ab_channel=Forza" target="_blank"&gt;Playground Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="NoX385"&gt;The developers of &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt; are planning to add on-screen sign language interpreters who would appear in a picture-in-picture display during the game’s cutscenes. The feature won’t be available when the game launches worldwide on November 9th, but Playground Games creative director Mike Brown wrote in a blog post on Xbox Wire that it would be “coming soon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="722oTq"&gt;“We’re constantly listening to the community to make &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt; an inclusive experience for everyone to enjoy,” Brown &lt;a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2021/11/04/gaming-for-everyone-the-accessibility-features-of-forza-horizon-5/"&gt;said in a blog post on Xbox Wire&lt;/a&gt;. “With this in mind, the team is excited to share we are also working on American Sign Language (ASL) and British Sign Language (BSL) support for cinematics in &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt;.” He didn’t offer an exact release date for the feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hvTjoX"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt; will have several other accessibility features available at launch. They include a game speed modification setting to play at reduced speeds when playing off line, a high contrast mode, a color blindness mode, customizable subtitles, a screen reader narrator who reads aloud text, buttons, and other game elements, and the ability to disable moving backgrounds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dU4bNG"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/o450zdpHZ7U?rel=0&amp;amp;start=259" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="935CuW"&gt;“We want everyone in the world to be able to experience our game, and with more than an estimated 400 million gamers with disabilities across the globe, it is vital that all players be able to tailor their gameplay in a way that works best for them,” Brown wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="86DI0q"&gt;Forza Horizon 5 launches November 9th on Xbox Series X / S, Xbox One, and PC. Those who bought the Premium Edition or Premium Add-Ons Bundle got access to play the game starting November 5th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="DZAfEJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Forza Horizon 5 is the perfect portable Xbox game","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22762183/forza-horizon-5-perfect-portable-xbox-game-series-x-s-pc-steam"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/7/22768466/forza-horizon-5-on-screen-sign-language-interpreters-cutscenes-xbox"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/7/22768466/forza-horizon-5-on-screen-sign-language-interpreters-cutscenes-xbox</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-07T11:03:43-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-07T11:03:43-05:00</updated>
    <title>Go read this report about how GM’s deal with Rivian fell apart</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jc0W4_cDOysbz7UXq2tywmIIpVg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70108250/mclark_210923_4776_0008.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Mitchell Clark / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2w4UOs"&gt;A little over two years ago when Rivian’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/transportation/2021/9/28/22697309/rivian-r1t-electric-truck-test-drive-off-roading-camp-tested"&gt;all-electric vehicles&lt;/a&gt; were still just blueprints, American carmakers Ford and GM were itching to invest. Fast-forward to the present, and Ford wound up becoming &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/23/22590848/rivian-raise-amazon-ford-new-factory-ipo-electric-pickup"&gt;one of Rivian’s biggest partners alongside Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. What most people may not realize, however, is that Ford nearly lost its spot to GM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cR456n"&gt;This &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/how-ford-won-the-race-for-rivian-11636171218"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; report&lt;/a&gt; describes some of the clandestine dealings in cinematic detail, and explores how Rivian CEO RJ Scaringe’s bond with Joe Hinrichs, Ford’s former president of global operations, became the foundation of Ford’s investment in the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hsHR4P"&gt;According to the&lt;em&gt; WSJ&lt;/em&gt;, Hinrichs first met with Scaringe in 2018. But because Ford had just missed its earnings targets, it wasn’t ready to invest in Rivian. This left room for GM, which had already started working on its electric vehicles, to slide in. However, &lt;em&gt;The WSJ &lt;/em&gt;says that leaders at Rivian remained skeptical of a deal with GM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HwjjJt"&gt;In 2019, Hinrichs met with Scaringe just after Amazon invested $700 million in Rivian. Hinrichs tried convincing him to reconsider a deal with Ford, after Scaringe said his company was on the verge of a deal with GM. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="Qs9WGf"&gt;Sensing hesitancy about GM, Mr. Hinrichs said he urged the young executive to reconsider. ‘Just because you got engaged to someone doesn’t mean you need to marry them,’ Mr. Hinrichs said he told Mr. Scaringe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="TUXBJ6"&gt;Hinrichs gave Scaringe yet another chance to talk — both of them happened to have meetings in Seattle, and Hinrichs offered to give Scaringe a ride back to Detroit in Ford’s Gulfstream jet. Scaringe still had yet to seal a deal with GM, and during the flight, Hinrich and Scaringe laid out a deal. When they landed, Hinrichs helped Scaringe stay out of sight of nearby GM executives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="tv0qWh"&gt;As the plane taxied toward a hangar used by both Ford and GM, executives on board spotted another jet outside the hangar with two GM-made black Cadillac Escalades waiting nearby. Mr. Hinrichs said he sensed Mr. Scaringe didn’t want to be seen by GM executives, so Mr Hinrichs requested that a Lincoln Navigator be pulled alongside the plane. When the door opened, Mr. Scaringe dashed down the plane’s steps and into the Navigator, keeping his head down as Mr. Hinrichs loaded their luggage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Fvlmns"&gt;Ford and Rivian’s talks continued overnight, and the two companies reached a deal at 4AM, according to the&lt;em&gt; WSJ&lt;/em&gt;. In April 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/24/18514031/ford-electric-pickup-truck-ev-startup-rivian-tech"&gt;Ford announced that it would invest $500 million&lt;/a&gt; in the startup — it has since invested a total of $1.2 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jUug2t"&gt;The stories of how deals come together don’t always have as many twists and turns as the stories of how deals fall apart. This great &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/how-ford-won-the-race-for-rivian-11636171218"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; piece&lt;/a&gt; has a little of both, and it’s a fascinating read. Go check out the dramatic tale, that has all the makings of a movie — or a really captivating novel.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/7/22768373/go-read-this-gm-deal-ford-rivian-fell-apart"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/7/22768373/go-read-this-gm-deal-ford-rivian-fell-apart</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-06T22:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-06T22:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix’s Arcane is a slick and exciting intro to League of Legends</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eEY9sMVp5sF8cH4Pqbx5wSSAxd8=/240x0:1545x870/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70106449/Vi_fight.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TWXeqg"&gt;For years, fans have been wondering just when the heck &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; developer Riot would make an animated series. It seemed inevitable. The studio previously created stunning animated shorts to promote everything from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/24/21336218/league-of-legends-yone-anime-cinematic-riot-games"&gt;new characters&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22700154/league-of-legends-world-2021-anthem-music-video"&gt;esports tournaments&lt;/a&gt;. And with an increasing focus on expanding &lt;em&gt;League&lt;/em&gt;’s storytelling — something that’s tough to do within the confines of a team-based strategy game — a show made a whole lot of sense. Now, it’s real, with a nine-episode series called &lt;em&gt;Arcane&lt;/em&gt;. The best part: not only is it a lot of fun, but you don’t have to know anything about &lt;em&gt;League&lt;/em&gt; to get into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uTbT6U"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Arcane&lt;/em&gt; is set (mostly) in a city called Piltover early on, which is on the verge of a big change that could impact the entirety of the fantasy realm of Runeterra: a pair of scientists are figuring out a way to harness the dangerous power of magic to use in everything from weapons to tools to transportation. Amidst this backdrop, the show follows a handful of characters throughout the city. Things start out with a street kid named Vi leading a small gang to a big score, heading to the upper reaches of the city to steal some expensive-looking gadgets. The heist, naturally, goes bad and ends with some exploding crystals. The perspective then shifts to the likes of the aforementioned scientists and an underworld kingpin with lots of scars and a big grudge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gf5rGf"&gt;What’s great about &lt;em&gt;Arcane&lt;/em&gt;’s fantasy-meets-steampunk world is that it’s pretty easy to understand. The show doesn’t waste time with big lore dumps, nor does it expect you already know who these characters are. Vi, for instance, is one of &lt;em&gt;League&lt;/em&gt;’s most popular characters, but the show serves mostly as an origin story for her and a few others. For fans, it’s a cool chance to see how some of these characters came to be — you even learn about Vi’s iconic gauntlets — but for everyone else, you’re being introduced to interesting people at a pivotal point in their lives. No prior knowledge necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="irZkb1"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3Svs_hl897c?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Hh1r2b"&gt;It helps that the story is relatively straightforward. There isn’t anything about &lt;em&gt;Arcane&lt;/em&gt; that I would call new or revolutionary. It’s a fairly typical fantasy tale that just happens to be really well done. The villains are intimidating, the would-be heroes are messy and relatable, the action is extremely satisfying to watch, and everything moves at a brisk pace. The best thing &lt;em&gt;Arcane&lt;/em&gt; has going for it is just how stylish it looks. Each frame looks like a gorgeous piece of hand-painted concept art; in motion, it’s like nothing I’ve ever seen. It’s also a world that feels lived-in and fully realized. The slums of Piltover have a toxic green look to them (police officers even wear masks when they venture in), while the upper levels are bright, airy, and luxurious. I especially loved all of the strange mechanical creations that help keep the city alive and bustling. What I’m saying is, after watching the first few episodes, I want an &lt;em&gt;Arcane&lt;/em&gt; art book ASAP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w4ZjAK"&gt;One of the more interesting things about the show is how it’s being released. It’s not an all-you-can-watch binge-fest, nor are episodes dropping weekly. Instead, &lt;em&gt;Arcane&lt;/em&gt; uses something of a hybrid format. The nine episodes are divided into chapters and are being released as three-episode bundles over the course of three weeks. (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22579993/fear-street-netflix-horror-trilogy-summer-movie"&gt;It’s reminiscent of Netflix’s experimental &lt;em&gt;Fear Stree&lt;/em&gt;t trilogy of horror movies&lt;/a&gt;.) For the first chapter, at least, it works well because the three episodes have their own clear arc, while episode four picks up some time later, though that’s as far as I’ve watched so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iEyNC8"&gt;Early on,&lt;em&gt; Arcane&lt;/em&gt; walks a fine line. It’s both a tribute and an introduction to a vast fantasy realm that’s been around for a decade and has millions of existing fans. Those viewers will find a story with some exciting Easter eggs and a deeper look at characters that have been around for ages. Everyone else is in for a surprisingly thrilling adventure that doesn’t skimp on style. Really, the most jarring thing for newcomers might be if they’re inspired to play &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; itself, which is decidedly lacking in the style and speed that make the show work so well.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22763818/netflix-league-of-legends-arcane-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22763818/netflix-league-of-legends-arcane-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
