<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-14T14:03:43-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-14T14:03:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-14T14:03:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>iPhone 13 Pro and Pro Max announced with high refresh rate 120Hz displays</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KT2X-gvGS17lneGO-3UDXAvi8Fs=/147x0:1737x1060/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69857534/bHfOSj7.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1paZ9b"&gt;Apple has officially announced the high-end part of the iPhone 13 lineup: the iPhone 13 Pro and 13 Pro Max. It’s got a faster A15 Bionic chip, three all new cameras, and an improved display with up to a 120Hz ProMotion high refresh rate display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xtNAGq"&gt;This is the third year Apple is splitting its flagship phone lineup into regular and “Pro” devices. Last year, however, many reviewers noted that there wasn’t much of a difference between the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21524288/apple-iphone-12-pro-review"&gt;iPhone 12 Pro&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21522988/iphone-12-review"&gt;iPhone 12&lt;/a&gt;. Yes, the 12 Pro had an extra telephoto camera, lidar sensor, and more RAM and base storage, but its basic design, processor, 5G capabilities, and OLED display were all similar, if not identical, to the regular iPhone 12. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hwZ1UV"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing… we’re adding more to this post, but you can follow along with our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22436135"&gt;&lt;em&gt;iPhone 13 and Apple Watch event live blog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; to get the news even faster.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22666884/iphone-13-pro-max-specs-price-release-date-cameras"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22666884/iphone-13-pro-max-specs-price-release-date-cameras</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-14T13:46:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-14T13:46:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>iPhone 13 announced with redesigned camera array and smaller notch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xsB-LBOr9G4ouVpZhig85sRirt0=/136x0:1525x926/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69857392/Screen_Shot_2021_09_14_at_1.39.54_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CkNTNs"&gt;Apple’s iPhone 13 has officially arrived — the baseline, most mainstream model that will set the bar for Apple’s 2021 phone lineup. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3FkoaW"&gt;As with last year, the entry-level iPhone 13 will come in two versions: the 6.1-inch “regular” model and the smaller 5.4-inch iPhone 13 Mini. The screen is still an OLED panel, the sides still aluminum sandwiched between two slabs of glass. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="inA1I2"&gt;Pricing starts at $799 for the iPhone 13 and $699 for the smaller iPhone 13 Mini. Storage options for this year’s models have been bumped up, with Apple offering 128GB, 256GB, and 512GB configurations for the two models. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ikW79s5y-RaBDX8CAEJJHBCIuss=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22850282/Screen_Shot_2021_09_14_at_1.41.05_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="xtBs1l"&gt;There’s not much in the way of radical new features or changes here; instead, the iPhone 13 is closer to Apple’s old “S”-year model of iPhones, offering some refinements and improvements to last year’s design rather than monumental new features. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="frlcut"&gt;Unlike the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21522988/iphone-12-review"&gt;iPhone 12&lt;/a&gt;, which saw a substantial redesign, the iPhone 13 has the same broad look as last year’s model, just with a slimmed-down Face ID notch that’s 20 percent smaller, meaning it’ll take up less space at the top of your phone. It’s not quite the minimal look that hole-punch displays offer on Android, but it’s a nice-looking improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8A6dgF"&gt;There’s also a more powerful processor: the A15 Bionic, which Apple says is faster and more power-efficient than last year’s A14 Bionic chip. It’s still a 5nm chip and still a 6-core CPU (with two new high-performance and four new high-efficiency cores) — but Apple says it’s the “fastest CPU in a smartphone,” up to 50 percent faster than the competition. It also says that graphics are up to 30 percent faster than its competitors (although, it doesn’t specify who it’s comparing to). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WIJvID"&gt;The new iPhone 13 lineup will also offer better battery life: the iPhone 13 Mini will get 1.5 hours more battery life than the iPhone 12 Mini, while the larger iPhone 13 should get up to  2.5 hours more battery life compared to the iPhone 12, thanks to bigger batteries, better performance from the A15 Bionic, and additional software improvements and optimizations. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DusYFhdF-o9khj_qW4kSDgZQ2io=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22850280/Screen_Shot_2021_09_14_at_1.51.10_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="oZS6Ik"&gt;The biggest change actually comes in the form of trickled-down camera technology from last year’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21555901/iphone-12-pro-max-review"&gt;iPhone 12 Pro Max&lt;/a&gt;: the base iPhone 13 has gotten the same souped-up camera that Apple debuted with its biggest smartphone in 2020, with a physically larger sensor for the wide camera that’s 47 percent bigger than last year, allowing it to capture more light in darker environments with less noise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cj12S7"&gt;The new wide sensor is a 12-megapixel lens with an f/1.6 aperture, while the new 12-megapixel ultrawide camera features a faster f/2.4 lens and 120-degree field of view. The iPhone 13 will also feature the sensor-shift stabilization technology that Apple introduced last year on the 12 Pro Max, which physically moves the wide sensor to reduce vibrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uuXWwk"&gt;Apple also introduced a new “cinematic mode” for video that allows for a rack focus effect to change the focus during a video, which the company showed off in an amusing &lt;em&gt;Knives Out&lt;/em&gt;-style parody. When recording a video, cinematic mode will automatically transition focus while filming in real time, intelligently shifting focus when people enter the frame or glance away from the camera. You’ll be able to manually change focus or lock focus on a particular object for more precise control, too. The front-facing camera will also feature cinematic mode support. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eQ1gNooRRwRVRPeH7FQB8wNsDUA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22850302/lcimg_385816e3_76e0_4fe7_b78e_de8db4c4b292.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dy7G8r"&gt;Apple is also promising improved 5G performance compared to the iPhone 12, with more band support for better international 5G experiences. The company promises the iPhone will support 200 carriers in over 60 countries and regions by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SAEIOL"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing… we’re adding more to this post, but you can follow along with our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22436135"&gt;&lt;em&gt;iPhone 13 and Apple Watch event live blog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; to get the news even faster.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22666802/iphone-13-specs-price-release-date-apple-camera"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22666802/iphone-13-specs-price-release-date-apple-camera</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-14T13:26:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-14T13:26:16-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Apple Watch Series 7 has a brand-new look</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/c3KmOcNdHS14eA3HasoLgaVr8qQ=/74x0:820x497/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69857319/Capto_Capture_2021_09_14_01_24_25_PM.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CojUH9"&gt;The Apple Watch Series 7 looks a little different than &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496141/apple-watch-series-6-review-blood-oxygen-monitor-watchos-7"&gt;its predecessors&lt;/a&gt;. The display now goes virtually to the edge of the case. That means a slick new look for some watchfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="shMhTn"&gt;The bezels around the display are slimmer at just 1.7mm, and the always-on screen mode is 70 percent brighter. Apple claims you can cram 50 percent more text onto the display than the Series 6. The new display also means new ways to interact, with a full keyboard that will support swiping. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W6J4CQGkReba4ZGf-0Jmk7rLl_I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22850197/lcimg_5ab83a83_d836_4e82_b8f5_f6ccdf0eee9f.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Series 7 on the right isn’t that much larger, but it should feel bigger, thanks to much smaller bezels.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="O6YXWO"&gt;There’s a whole new set of watchfaces to take advantage of the larger screen, including a more modular watchface. And a bigger display doesn’t mean it’s more delicate: Apple claims it’s crack resistant and now has an IP6X rating, which means it should be able to take a dunk in the sand at the beach a little better than it will the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F4vtU0"&gt;The small Apple Watch went from 40mm to 41mm and the big Watch from 44mm to 45mm. That makes these watches the largest Apple Watches to date. In fact, the small Apple Watch is now just 1mm smaller than the largest one &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/9/9/6125873/apple-watch-smartwatch-announced"&gt;introduced back in 2014&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P6KnQz"&gt;Like the Series 6, the new Series 7 will &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/watch/battery/"&gt;offer up to 18 hours of battery life&lt;/a&gt; and include a charger that charges via USB-C instead of USB-A. The aluminum variation will come in five colors total, the usual black, gold, blue and red, plus a dark green that feels in sync with the rugged new support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D1xWcN"&gt;Besides the refreshes to the premium Apple Watch, Apple’s also added some new features to Watch OS 8. Outdoor cycling will now have better support and should automatically pause the workout when you stop at a light or just to catch a break. Fall support will now also appear in workouts, so if you wreck your bike or trip up badly during a brutal HIIT workout the watch will be able to contact emergency services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mbBblG"&gt;The Watch Series 3 is sticking around and starting a $199 and the Watch SE will be available for $279, while the new Series 7 will start at $399.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kE4koI"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing… we’re adding more to this post, but you can follow along with our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22436135"&gt;&lt;em&gt;iPhone 13 and Apple Watch event live blog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; to get the news even faster.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22667395/apple-watch-series-7-price-specs-redesign-announcement"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22667395/apple-watch-series-7-price-specs-redesign-announcement</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Cranz</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-14T13:14:27-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-14T13:14:27-04:00</updated>
    <title>All-new iPad Mini announced with 5G, USB-C, and larger 8.3-inch display</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wQ-Fh3V_HHaNuR5iECA4AxONDP8=/141x0:1640x999/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69857249/lcimg_7b04f92e_6e3b_4b04_83c7_9381b0d97513.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="atJv07"&gt;Apple has announced its all-new iPad Mini. It features a new enclosure with narrower bezels and rounded corners. The big news is that it’s larger than the iPad Mini 5 with an 8.3-inch display (up from its predecessor’s 7.9-inch panel), making the device even more viable as a driver for multitasking or schoolwork. Apple says the screen can reach 500 nits of brightness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tHmNxr"&gt;The iPad Mini is currently Apple’s smallest tablet, even with the bump in size. Apple was rumored to have been considering a Mini LED display on the new iPad, similar to that of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395449/apple-ipad-pro-2021-liquid-retina-xdr-mini-led-explainer"&gt;largest iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt;. Those appear to have missed the mark; the new Mini sports a regular Liquid Retina display.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ncuFA65v4fZQrYnuxxe0gdDFiPU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22850183/lcimg_90987419_14bd_47ba_b425_5984e2255904.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ILSQY3"&gt;The iPad Mini’s design has remained largely consistent since its 2012 debut. The new model is something of a shake-up to the traditional build, featuring slimmer bezels than the iPad Mini 5 and new color options. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uuGneI2Uk0jgQWaEf6z1WGpmsjk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22850179/lcimg_29dd1c6f_2141_4080_b52a_db12ce0673ef.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="RMePML"&gt;The new tablet also features a USB-C port, Touch ID (no Face ID), a new speaker system with stereo in landscape mode, and upgraded 12MP cameras on the front and back, including a shooter with True Tone flash and 4K video recording on the back and a new 12MP ultrawide camera on the front, which will support Apple’s Center Stage feature. It also supports Wi-Fi 6 and 5G (with download speeds up to 3.5 gigabits per second) as well as the second-generation Apple Pencil, which attaches magnetically to the side of the chassis.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lrFZnbsShiYFufYnN6IyTrtvz_8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22850192/lcimg_86345a67_53a1_4376_92b6_933c3d884fcd.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are new slim covers, but no mention of a keyboard cover.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="qhemxg"&gt;The enclosure also incorporates 100 percent recycled aluminum; the solder of the main logic board includes 100 percent recycled tin, and the enclosure magnets are 100 percent rare earth elements. Apple claims you can expect 40 percent faster CPU performance and 80 percent faster GPU performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f6lIdp"&gt;The new iPad Mini is up for preorder today and will be available next week starting at $499.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qKalAJ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing… we’re adding more to this post, but you can follow along with our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22436135"&gt;&lt;em&gt;iPhone 13 and Apple Watch event live blog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; to get the news even faster.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="rYclx8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Apple Watch Series 7 has a brand-new look","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22667395/apple-watch-series-7-price-specs-redesign-announcement"},{"title":"Apple announces new entry-level iPad with A13 Bionic chip","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22672438/ipad-2021-new-price-specs-release-date-apple-a13-chip"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22667216/ipad-mini-6-price-specs-release-date-features-apple"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22667216/ipad-mini-6-price-specs-release-date-features-apple</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-14T13:09:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-14T13:09:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple announces new entry-level iPad with A13 Bionic chip</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/emMeRePA-FWf8weLeznyupOdvsc=/141x0:1640x999/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69857219/lcimg_06408afc_ebbc_4bcf_a6a4_db043132841a.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YIQyWB"&gt;Apple has just announced the latest version of its most popular tablet: the standard iPad. This new model is the ninth generation of the iPad that first debuted in 2010, and it features a new processor called the A13 Bionic. Additionally, there’s a new 12-megapixel front camera that supports the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395325/ipad-pro-pan-zoom-video-conferencing-microsoft-teams"&gt;Center Stage feature&lt;/a&gt; that debuted with the iPad Pro last year. The rest of the 9th Gen iPad will look very familiar to anyone who has seen an iPad in the past few years, complete with the same home button, bezels, single rear camera, and Lightning port we’ve seen before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A9GfH4"&gt;Apple says the new processor is 20 percent faster than the one in the outgoing model. The 10.2-inch display is the same size and resolution as before, but it now supports the True Tone feature that automatically adjusts the screen’s color temperature to ambient lighting.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IVyTLKRSkH9TzQrHmXU7mL_wRAo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22850102/lcimg_f2245adc_fcad_44a9_9744_ee7dfc6b75b9.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 9th Gen iPad supports the first-generation Apple Pencil.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="KeYlTE"&gt;The latest iPad will ship with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22463812/apple-ipados-15-features-productivity-release-date"&gt;iPadOS 15&lt;/a&gt;, which was announced earlier this year and includes enhancements to the iPad’s homescreen, app organization, and multitasking features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mx1lPy"&gt;The base-model iPad is the one most people gravitate toward, as it’s the most economical model in the lineup. This year, Apple has bumped the base storage to 64GB and kept the starting $329 price the same. The iPad is also compatible with the first-generation Apple Pencil and the Apple Smart Keyboard. It will be available in silver or space gray and can be ordered starting today, September 14th, with deliveries expected for next week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9SgXDy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing… we’re adding more to this post, but you can follow along with our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22436135"&gt;&lt;em&gt;iPhone 13 and Apple Watch event live blog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; to get the news even faster.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22672438/ipad-2021-new-price-specs-release-date-apple-a13-chip"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22672438/ipad-2021-new-price-specs-release-date-apple-a13-chip</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-14T12:55:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-14T12:55:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>Valve’s Steam Deck is now real enough to send to developers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ch22_lsJ3X-eOpfNasIolM95vXY=/69x0:1131x708/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69857060/f6b29587c2ae8bbc1d66b83d7d0378febd6f6582.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Valve&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QOcVAH"&gt;Valve’s foray into video game handhelds, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578783/valve-steam-deck-gaming-handheld-pc"&gt;the Steam Deck&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1675180/view/2963920750895461227"&gt;has started shipping out to developers&lt;/a&gt;. The company opened up requests for early versions of the device &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/steam-deck-dev-kits/"&gt;on September 2nd&lt;/a&gt; to developers, and now it seems like those devices are heading out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GTgpkJ"&gt;The Steam Decks shipping out are “engineering verification test builds” according to Valve, and are “functionally identical” to the version of the device that will be shipped to customers. As Valve explains: “the dev-kit program gives us the chance to guide game developers through the process of getting their games on Steam Deck while also continuing to gather their feedback as we prepare for the official launch at the end of the year.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5VTk3CQOurgnwYNZnGjJa3b8VH8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22849898/6348ca171b7eace23027e4a513748c9f12900320.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Valve&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steam Decks preparing to ship.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="k3ignX"&gt;Valve &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578783/valve-steam-deck-gaming-handheld-pc"&gt;first introduce the Steam Deck in July&lt;/a&gt; with the promise of an easy transition to the device’s Linux software thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.protondb.com/"&gt;the Proton compatibility layer&lt;/a&gt;. Sending out dev kits allows developers to experiment with that, and also makes the Steam Deck that much more real for anyone who might feel anxious &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/18/22579747/valve-steam-deck-steam-machines-editorial"&gt;about Valve experimenting with hardware again&lt;/a&gt;. Our experience with the Steam Deck &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22612886/valve-steam-deck-handheld-gaming-pc-hands-on-preview"&gt;was largely positive during our hands-on&lt;/a&gt;, and now developers will have a chance to try the device for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EE6hkj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22673732/valve-steam-deck-dev-kits-shipping"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22673732/valve-steam-deck-dev-kits-shipping</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-14T12:43:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-14T12:43:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>Tonal will offer Peloton-like live classes starting in October</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XO_40FHCRWYX_6S1Tp4-4N96laY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69857012/akrales_190725_3568_0138.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kK0V9L"&gt;Tonal, which offers an at-home connected strength training machine, is adding to its library of on-demand exercise programs by introducing a Peloton-like live classes service called Tonal Live. Classes start streaming on October 20th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x3ZpGB"&gt;During classes, coaches will give you pacing cues, feedback on your workout, and shoutouts, &lt;a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210914005303/en/Tonal-Announces-Tonal-Live-A-New-Interactive-Workout-Experience"&gt;according to a press release&lt;/a&gt;. The machine’s homescreen and app are also getting a redesign that “allows for the discovery and a schedule of Live workouts, an on-demand library of past Live workouts, and the ability to preview the movements in a workout.” Tonal is also adding a “Social Zone” where users can interact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8ZOEgk"&gt;The addition of live classes fixes a notable gap in Tonal’s offerings. Former &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; staffer Natt Garun criticized the fact that Tonal didn’t offer live classes &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/23/21077238/tonal-review-strength-training-connected-weight-fitness-machine-price"&gt;in her January 2020 review of the machine&lt;/a&gt; and said that the pre-taped sessions could feel overly rehearsed or get stale over time. For Tonal users who might be bored with the currently available classes, live sessions could offer some regular variety to workouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eSNiyi"&gt;Like a Peloton bike, though, a Tonal machine doesn’t come cheap — it costs $2,995 and has a monthly subscription fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Vc94E3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"I trained with Tonal, the ‘Peloton for weightlifting’ ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/23/21077238/tonal-review-strength-training-connected-weight-fitness-machine-price"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22673676/tonal-live-classes-workouts-peloton"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22673676/tonal-live-classes-workouts-peloton</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-14T12:30:09-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-14T12:30:09-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple iPhone 13 and Apple Watch live blog: ‘California Streaming’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Apple Store, San Francisco" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DY10FWtLnPI0keSd-qOy_OISE2A=/0x85:2040x1445/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69856958/IMG_3669.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;On such a winter’s day&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="UsbJQM"&gt;The time has come for yet another iPhone announcement — plus whatever else Apple might have up its sleeve. Sleeve’s the right metaphor, actually, as new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22663715/apple-iphone-13-event-rumors-announcements-california-streaming"&gt;Apple Watches&lt;/a&gt; are expected today in addition to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22663715/apple-iphone-13-event-rumors-announcements-california-streaming"&gt;iPhone 13&lt;/a&gt;. The keynote kicks off online at 10AM PT / 1PM ET and we’ll be live blogging the whole thing right here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OmzoGT"&gt;For the iPhone 13, we expect we’ll see the usual camera improvements and faster processors. The cameras may have a new astrophotography trick. There are also rumors that the notch in the screen that houses the FaceID sensors will be smaller this year — but still much larger than the hole punches we see on Android phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2ab6gJ"&gt;For the watch, we might get the first big design change ever. Apple may be dropping the rounded, lozenge shape in favor of flatter sides that match the design of the newer iPhones and iPads. Bigger screens and better batteries are also rumored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7uYnZU"&gt;What else? Probably some AirPods. Maybe some iPads. We doubt there will be Macs. But Apple has a lot of product lines that are potential candidates for updates — not to mention new versions of its operating systems to get out the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HjVCcH"&gt;We’ll be covering it all, right here. Tune in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="VxJJwt"&gt;iPhone 13 live blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="Ujrleu"&gt;&lt;div class="live-center-embed" data-src="https://livecenter.norkon.net/frame/voxmedia/16621/vox"&gt;&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;(function(n){function c(t,i){n[e](h,function(n){var r,u;if(n&amp;&amp;(r=n[n.message?"message":"data"]+"",r&amp;&amp;r.substr&amp;&amp;r.substr(0,3)==="nc:")&amp;&amp;(u=r.split(":"),u[1]===i))switch(u[2]){case"h":t.style.height=u[3]+"px";return;case"scrolltotop":t.scrollIntoView();return}},!1)}for(var t,u,f,i,s,e=n.addEventListener?"addEventListener":"attachEvent",h=e==="attachEvent"?"onmessage":"message",o=n.document.querySelectorAll(".live-center-embed"),r=0;r&lt;o.length;r++)(t=o[r],t.getAttribute("data-rendered"))||(u=t.getAttribute("data-src"),u&amp;&amp;(t.setAttribute("data-rendered","true"),f=n.ncVizCounter||1e3,n.ncVizCounter=f+1,i=f+"",s="nc-frame-c-"+i,t.innerHTML='&lt;div style="position: relative; height: 300px; border: none;" id="'+s+'"&gt;&lt;iframe src="'+u+"?"+i+'" style="position: absolute; left: 0; top: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;',c(t.firstChild,i)))})(window);&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ZP21SS"&gt;Watch the Apple keynote&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="IwUseW"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EvGOlAkLSLw?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22672094/apple-event-iphone-13-live-blog-news-announcements"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22672094/apple-event-iphone-13-live-blog-news-announcements</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
      <name>Nilay Patel</name>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-14T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-14T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Razer’s Wolverine V2 Chroma is an elegant, customizable wired controller</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Razer Wolverine V2 Chroma" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9HXUZwvCL8ljeIyBRlnKHty4Fd8=/1x0:5566x3710/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69856798/wolverinev2chroma1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Razer&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aWNa1N"&gt;A year after the launch of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/19/21571482/razer-wolverine-v2-xbox-series-x-s-controller-pc-wired-elite-trigger-stops-price-features"&gt;Razer’s $100 Wolverine V2 Xbox controller&lt;/a&gt;, today the company has announced a $150 version with more features called the Wolverine V2 Chroma. The new name is a giveaway to one of the additions: a strip of Chroma RGB lighting near each of the two grips that can be programmed to your liking via its accessory companion app on an Xbox or PC. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zmj7bu"&gt;This controller is actually replacing the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2017/8/24/16198780/razer-xbox-one-pc-pro-game-controller-price-availability"&gt;Wolverine Ultimate that was released in late 2017&lt;/a&gt;. Like the older controller, the Wolverine V2 Chroma has swappable thumb sticks like those included with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/31/20926499/microsoft-xbox-elite-wireless-controller-series-2-review-price-specs-features"&gt;Xbox Elite controllers&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/17/22627413/scuf-instinct-pro-microsoft-xbox-controller-wireless-series-x-s-one-pc-features-price"&gt;Scuf’s Instinct&lt;/a&gt;, trigger stops to shorten the throw of triggers, and six remappable macro buttons (including four paddles on the back) that can be customized.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Razer Wolverine V2 Chroma" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lXOiW3PZr20AmNdpathy3KFqWlQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22840549/wolverinev2chroma3.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Razer&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The analog stick covers are swappable, though the d-pad is not.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LuUkxM"&gt;There are a few improvements over its predecessor. For example, the Wolverine V2 Chroma’s LED implementation definitely looks better, and I prefer its shape and overall design over the older model. It also gets points for using USB-C instead of the Ultimate’s Micro USB port and for having the same offering of buttons as Microsoft’s latest Xbox controller. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="DPMxHL"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The older Wolverine Ultimate offers a little more customization&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BXgjgb"&gt;But the newer controller isn’t superior in every way. The older Wolverine Ultimate offers a little more customization for a lower price (currently $129.99). Namely, its D-pad can be swapped. Also, the Ultimate doesn’t require software to remap its button, instead letting you do it right from the controller. It’s not a deal-breaker, but you might prefer that solution as opposed to downloading software.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Razer Wolverine V2 Chroma" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uo3bN27M5iiTiiG4-2FGMl-kjr8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22840534/wolverinev2chroma2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Razer&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wolverine V2 Chroma has six macro buttons in total, which are programmable through Razer’s accessory app for Windows 10 and Xbox.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SBTojE"&gt;All said, this is a fairly minor upgrade over the Wolverine V2, though there’s enough that’s new and worthwhile here that you might be interested. On the other hand, you might find yourself content with either buying or hanging onto the older Wolverine Ultimate.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22666452/razer-wolverine-v2-chroma-xbox-pc-wired-controller-price-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22666452/razer-wolverine-v2-chroma-xbox-pc-wired-controller-price-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-14T10:41:47-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-14T10:41:47-04:00</updated>
    <title>The investigation into Tesla Autopilot’s emergency vehicle problem is getting bigger</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Tesla Motors Inc. Tests Self-Driving Technology" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/q_1MBbnUG-EL4t3dk_Ams4hhG2s=/0x0:4000x2667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69856289/494411536.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FvbUMx"&gt;The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration is requesting advanced driver assist data from 12 automakers as it seeks to expand &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22626819/tesla-autopilot-crash-emergency-vehicle-probe-nhtsa"&gt;its investigation into Tesla’s Autopilot&lt;/a&gt;. The government is probing a dozen incidents involving Teslas crashing into emergency vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="juy2nN"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.autonews.com/regulation-safety/nhtsa-seeking-driver-assist-data-12-automakers-tesla-autopilot-probe"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Automotive News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the agency’s Office of Defects Investigation sent letters to a dozen major automakers, including Ford, General Motors, Toyota, and Volkswagen, requesting information regarding their Level 2 driver assist systems, in which the vehicle can simultaneously control steering, braking, and acceleration under specific circumstances. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="K89fIm"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Automakers are being asked to provide the number of vehicles with Level 2 systems that have been manufactured in the US&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MsmmAi"&gt;Automakers are being asked to provide the number of vehicles with Level 2 systems that have been manufactured in the US, as well as the total number of miles covered with those systems engaged and a recent list of any changes or updates. NHTSA is also requesting customer complaints, field and crash reports, and any lawsuits related to the Level 2 systems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="elOJdR"&gt;
&lt;p style=" margin: 12px auto 6px auto; font-family: Helvetica,Arial,Sans-serif; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; font-size: 14px; line-height: normal; font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; -x-system-font: none; display: block;"&gt;   &lt;a title="View NHTSA Ford letter on Scribd" href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.scribd.com%2Fdocument%2F525253207%2FNHTSA-Ford-letter%23from_embed&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F14%2F22673497%2Ftesla-nhtsa-autopilot-investigation-data-ford-gm-vw-toyota" style="text-decoration: underline;" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;NHTSA Ford letter&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a title="View ahawkins8223's profile on Scribd" href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.scribd.com%2Fuser%2F112638498%2Fahawkins8223%23from_embed&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F14%2F22673497%2Ftesla-nhtsa-autopilot-investigation-data-ford-gm-vw-toyota" style="text-decoration: underline;" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ahawkins8223&lt;/a&gt; on Scribd&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe class="scribd_iframe_embed" title="NHTSA Ford letter" src="https://www.scribd.com/embeds/525253207/content?start_page=1&amp;amp;view_mode=scroll&amp;amp;access_key=key-S1do6EeqCFh831ddBaLR" data-auto-height="false" data-aspect-ratio="0.7729220222793488" scrolling="no" id="doc_14587" width="100%" height="600" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="27HKxj"&gt;The data request comes less than two weeks after NHTSA sent an order to Tesla to provide data on the operation of its Autopilot system, including details on which of its sold vehicles are equipped with Autopilot as well as the system’s operating parameters. The agency’s investigation into Tesla could have wide-ranging implications for Tesla, which has pushed the boundaries in releasing experimental software to untrained customers in order to advance its vision of autonomous driving. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zyzjza"&gt;NHTSA’s investigation covers an estimated 765,000 Tesla vehicles that were released from 2014 through 2021. The agency is looking into 12 crashes in which Tesla owners using the company’s Autopilot features have crashed into stationary emergency vehicles, resulting in 17 injuries and one fatality. Most of these incidents took place after dark, with the software ignoring scene control measures including warning lights, flares, cones, and an illuminated arrow board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DgmYMg"&gt;Tesla has until October 22nd to hand over the data. US-based automakers like Ford, GM, and Stellantis have until November 3rd, and all other car companies, like Toyota, Subaru, Nissan, and Honda, have until November 17th. Automakers that fail to respond could face civil penalties of up to $115 million. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22673497/tesla-nhtsa-autopilot-investigation-data-ford-gm-vw-toyota"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22673497/tesla-nhtsa-autopilot-investigation-data-ford-gm-vw-toyota</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
