<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-12T08:30:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T08:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T08:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netgear’s new mesh Wi-Fi 6E router costs $1,500</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pe8GRwvemgM9AFG5vz13t4vDjv8=/165x0:2835x1780/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69983432/Orbi_WiFi_6E_2.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Netgear launches the first quad band Wi-Fi 6E mesh system.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XdzxPB"&gt;Just when you were starting to think about upgrading to a Wi-Fi 6 router, Wi-Fi 6E is here. And it’s expensive. Netgear announced its newest entry into the 6E foray today, the Orbi Quad-B and Mesh WiFi 6E RBKE960 series. This is the first quad-band Wi-Fi 6E mesh offering, but not the first Wi-Fi 6E mesh router (the $1,200 &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.linksys.com%2Fus%2Fwhole-home-mesh-wifi%2Flinksys-atlas-max-6e-tri-band-mesh-wifi-6e-system-3-pack%2Fp%2Fp-mx8503%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F12%2F22716979%2Fnetgear-orbi-quad-band-wi-fi-6e-mesh-router-release-date-specs-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Linksys Atlas Max 6E&lt;/a&gt; took that honor earlier this year). Featuring a 2.4 GHz band, two 5GHz, and a brand spanking new 6GHz band, this $1,500 system also supports four different networks out of the box, including one designed exclusively for your insecure smart home devices. And if that doesn’t get you excited, they’re also releasing a limited-edition color… black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rGPXL_a7o95AM_ChvP6B_s9asLY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22911341/Orbi_WiFi_6E_3.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Netgear&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new Orbi router is larger than most of its mesh competitors and also a lot more expensive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SwCbCs"&gt;This incredibly expensive setup ($500 more than &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.netgear.com%2Fhome%2Fwifi%2Fmesh%2Frbk852%2F%3Futm_source%3Dpepperjam%26utm_medium%3Daffiliate%26utm_campaign%3D21181%26clickId%3D3720363108&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F12%2F22716979%2Fnetgear-orbi-quad-band-wi-fi-6e-mesh-router-release-date-specs-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Orbi’s already pricey tri-band Wi-Fi 6 option&lt;/a&gt;) supports multi-gigabit internet. Netgear claims that even if your home doesn’t have many Wi-Fi 6E clients (which it won’t), you’ll see increased speeds of up to 30 percent due to the significant number of radios crammed in (each band has 4 x 4 MIMO support and the system is rated AXE11000), plus the upgraded antenna designs. This thing is stacked. It’s also large. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gR5Qy1"&gt;“It’s a complex product and therefore challenging to get all this technology into a smaller form factor,” Ravindra Bhilave, director of product management at Netgear, told me during a briefing ahead of the announcement. Where its competitors such as Nest and Eero have more discreet, compact designs, Netgear is sticking with Orbi’s loud and proud look. At one stage, Netgear even decided to step backward in the design evolution process of the router by releasing a black version. I have clearly wasted countless hours complaining that black (and, to be fair, white) plastic boxes do not look good in most homes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e7VyGJHY_AGj4Fa_8URCj5Nqobc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22911292/Orbi_WiFi_6E_5.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A limited-edition black version of the Orbi quad-band Wi-Fi 6E router will not cost more.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="PqEQur"&gt;But hey — if this thing can do all it says it can and keep my son’s Xbox online while I Zoom, my husband watches &lt;em&gt;Squid Game&lt;/em&gt; on Netflix, and my daughter hits &lt;em&gt;Rec Room&lt;/em&gt; on the Oculus, it could be neon purple for all I’d care. Wi-Fi is the backbone of the smarthome and any upgrade to it is generally appreciated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0F47l6"&gt;The ability to set up a separate smart home network on this Orbi system is also an intriguing proposition, although how it will actually be executed remains to be seen. Netgear tells me the transition between networks will be “seamless.” So, if your phone is on the regular network and you’re trying to control devices on the smart home network, there won’t be any issues. That’s a problem people run into when trying to use a Guest Network as a smart home network as guest networks are designed to be sealed off from everything else, which can cause communication issues. Netgear also pointed out that smart home devices are often “not friendly with band-steering,” and this dedicated network can make sure devices stay on one band.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WIf2uv"&gt;Orbi is consistently highly rated for reliability and performance, even if it doesn’t blend in with the home decor as well as a Plume or offer double duty as a smart speaker like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/4/20946586/google-nest-wifi-review-mesh-router-price-specs-features"&gt;Nest&lt;/a&gt; or a smart home hub as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22193059/eero-pro-6-review-mesh-router-wifi-6-test-speeds-network"&gt;Eero&lt;/a&gt; can. But do you need Wi-Fi 6E? Do you need to spend $1,500 for better Wi-Fi? Not now, no. But in a couple of years you might wish you had. So, if you’re in the market for a new router, it could be worth considering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q6tJ2Q"&gt;The reason is that Wi-Fi 6E brings with it a whole new band — 6GHz. This delivers more spectrum to handle multi-gigabit speeds on compatible phones and laptops (a handful of which currently support it). There’s lots more to love about Wi-Fi 6 (read our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/23/21231623/6ghz-wifi-6e-explained-speed-availability-fcc-approval"&gt;in-depth explainer for all the details&lt;/a&gt;), and the Orbi system even has its own 6E network, which you can set up just for those devices. Netgear opted not to use 6GHz as the dedicated backhaul, as Linksys did with limited success based on our early testing. Instead, it uses the second 5GHz band. Bhilave says the team made this choice as 5GHz has better range than 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GQ4QZ5"&gt;Other specs include an upgraded WAN port (for your incoming internet connection) that now supports up to 10 gigabits, an additional 2.5-gigabit port on the router, plus three other ethernet ports on each device, so you can hardwire all your TVs. The satellites also support wired backhaul, like other Orbi systems. Netgear says its three-pack covers up to 9,000 square feet, and you can expand it further for $599 per satellite. The Orbi Quad-Band Mesh WiFi 6E System RBKE963 can be preordered today in the US and UK on Netgear.com and comes to other regions as WiFi 6E is approved. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OEEmJi"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22716979/netgear-orbi-quad-band-wi-fi-6e-mesh-router-release-date-specs-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22716979/netgear-orbi-quad-band-wi-fi-6e-mesh-router-release-date-specs-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T07:54:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T07:54:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>These apps let you customize Windows 11 to bring the taskbar back to life</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A user types on the Surface Pro 8 keyboard. The screen displays Microsoft Teams on a blue and white background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9yXlkNEcyk8o6ijkMEpp4YKCrcI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69983271/bfarsace_211004_4777_0011.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Windows 11 taskbar.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tZxuLn"&gt;I’m not the only one who &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22673266/microsoft-windows-11-taskbar-features-missing-design-changes"&gt;hates the new Windows 11 taskbar&lt;/a&gt;, and now third-party developers are coming to the rescue with apps that bring back some of the features missing in Microsoft’s latest OS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SOZTTz"&gt;Microsoft removed basic taskbar functionality in Windows 11, like displaying the time and date on multiple monitors, moving the taskbar to the top of the screen or sides, and even small things like altering its height and having small icons. It has angered many Windows users, and most of the top feedback in Microsoft’s Windows Insider program was related to the taskbar changes before Windows 11 debuted last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="k7PQ7L"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Stardock is releasing Start11 today, which offers a lot of customization for the Windows 11 Start menu and taskbar &lt;a href="https://t.co/pn7NcRBQuK"&gt;https://t.co/pn7NcRBQuK&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/Lrstn0v8mp"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Lrstn0v8mp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Tom Warren (@tomwarren) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/1446133458678341647?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zjVYl6"&gt;Stardock’s new &lt;a href="https://www.stardock.com/products/start11/"&gt;Start11 app&lt;/a&gt; primarily focuses on allowing you to change the Start menu back to classic styles, but there’s also a lot of taskbar customization, too. You can change the taskbar size, its position across multiple monitors, and even what’s shown when you right-click on the bar. If you’re a fan of having Task Manager anywhere you right-click on the Windows 11 taskbar, you can bring it back with Start11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nRil8L"&gt;While drag and drop still isn’t supported with Start11, the only thing that’s really missing is the ability to show the clock on multiple monitors. Thankfully, another third-party app, &lt;a href="https://github.com/martinet101/ElevenClock"&gt;ElevenClock&lt;/a&gt;, saves the day. ElevenClock puts the time and date on multiple monitors, a feature that is strangely missing in Windows 11.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/opL21gbYPxQVlyxWOAmvY4T3nJU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22920267/CQU4KrA.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;ElevenClock brings the time and date to every taskbar in Windows 11.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="S77uqE"&gt;Windows 11 users shouldn’t really need to resort to third-party apps just to bring back basic taskbar functionality that has existed in Windows for decades, but until Microsoft addresses this area of feedback there are at least some workarounds available. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A6I5v5"&gt;Microsoft hinted at potential changes to the taskbar last month. “As with every experience in Windows 11, we’re constantly listening and learning, and welcome customer feedback that helps shape Windows,” said a Microsoft spokesperson in a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22673266/microsoft-windows-11-taskbar-features-missing-design-changes"&gt;statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; in September&lt;/a&gt;. “Windows 11 will continue to evolve over time; if we learn from user experience that there are ways to make improvements, we will do so.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="YxizxN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to customize your Windows 11 taskbar ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22688307/windows-11-microsoft-taskbar-how-to"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722202/microsoft-windows-11-taskbar-customize-apps-start11-elevenclock"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722202/microsoft-windows-11-taskbar-customize-apps-start11-elevenclock</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T07:43:07-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T07:43:07-04:00</updated>
    <title>This bipedal robot uses propeller arms to slackline and skateboard</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kRPiwnspZvjY0S06x4_DqlU_JBQ=/143x70:1121x722/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69983259/Screen_Shot_2021_10_12_at_12.30.30_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;LEONARDO can fly and walk thanks to bipedal legs and propeller arms. &lt;/em&gt; | Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.caltech.edu/about/news/leonardo-the-bipedal-robot-can-ride-a-skateboard-and-walk-a-slackline" target="_blank"&gt;Caltech Aerospace Robotics and Control Lab&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/scirobotics.abf8136" target="_blank"&gt;Science Robotics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="487ZN6"&gt;When it comes to judging how cool robots are, I deploy a simple but reliable heuristic: can I imagine this machine appearing in the &lt;em&gt;Metal Gear Solid&lt;/em&gt; franchise? With LEONARDO, a &lt;a href="https://www.caltech.edu/about/news/leonardo-the-bipedal-robot-can-ride-a-skateboard-and-walk-a-slackline"&gt;bipedal robot with propellers for arms&lt;/a&gt;, I can not only imagine it, I’m pretty sure it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;em&gt;MGSV&lt;/em&gt;. From the bubble head to the uncannily precise movements, it’s just a very cool robot, which I can also imagine being used to infiltrate mercenary basecamps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="JHmp69"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Just like a bird, LEONARDO can both walk and fly&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CaASVg"&gt;LEONARDO is a pleasingly choppy acronym for “LEgs ONboARD drOne” — the product of those linguistic geniuses in Caltech’s Aerospace Robotics and Control Lab. You may have seen an earlier iteration of the bot &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2019/10/7/20903112/leonardo-drone-bipedal-robot-balance-propellers-video"&gt;back in 2019&lt;/a&gt; (when, amazingly, LEONARDO stood for “LEg ON Aerial Robotic DrOne” instead), but its design and capabilities have since been upgraded, adding railguns and tactical nukes. Oh, no, sorry, that’s &lt;em&gt;Metal Gear Solid &lt;/em&gt;again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="99NXic"&gt;According to an interview with Caltech’s Professor Soon-Jo Chung &lt;a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/bipedal-drone-robot-caltech"&gt;at &lt;em&gt;IEEE Spectrum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, 2021’s LEO (for short) has been re-built from scratch, with lighter legs, double the number of propellers, and a new integrated design that places the battery and electronics onboard. The bot is now 75cm tall (2.5 feet), weighs 2.5kg (5.5lbs), and can fly at speeds of up to 3m/s. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xbtKkq"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/h3bkvVXsVFM?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QmY1cw"&gt;The interesting thing about LEO, of course, is its hybrid design: it can both fly and walk. These aren’t distinct modes of travel, either, as the propellers help stabilize the robot during tricky bipedal movements. The end-result is that the bot can not only hop and walk but skateboard and slackline, skills that are beyond the remit of this particular biped. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4pIrTE"&gt;This multimodal approach means that LEO would, potentially, be able to move through environments that challenge other bots. Soon-Jo Chung tells &lt;em&gt;IEEE Spectrum&lt;/em&gt; that one potential application is in high-altitude environments, like inspecting high voltage lines or tall bridges. “In such applications, conventional biped robots have difficulties with reaching the site, and standard multi-rotor drones have an issue with stabilization in high disturbance environments,” says the professor. LEO, of course, can do both. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ChHq6V0JXV-LLRunEQjIAnZ2W_Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22920262/Screen_Shot_2021_10_12_at_12.32.07_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Caltech&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A render of an imagined future version of LEONARDO with a yellow exterior. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="98dKWV"&gt;You won’t be seeing LEO tackle these problems in the near-future, though. It’s still very much a research project, and there are a number of design challenges before LEO could be put to commercial use. Foremost among these is perhaps battery life, as the bot can only currently operate for 100 seconds of flight or 3.5 minutes of walking before it needs to have a sit down and recharge. I’m much the same myself, but thankfully I don’t have a job inspecting high-altitude power lines either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i913xC"&gt;For more information on LEO, you can check out this &lt;a href="https://www.caltech.edu/about/news/leonardo-the-bipedal-robot-can-ride-a-skateboard-and-walk-a-slackline"&gt;blog post from Caltech&lt;/a&gt; or a &lt;a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/scirobotics.abf8136"&gt;paper on the machine&lt;/a&gt; published in &lt;em&gt;Science Robotics.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722179/bipedal-robot-propeller-arms-leonardo-caltech-slackline-skateboard"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722179/bipedal-robot-propeller-arms-leonardo-caltech-slackline-skateboard</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T06:44:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T06:44:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>US PC market declines due to supply issues just as Windows 11 launches</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Best Laptops 2020: Microsoft Surface Laptop 3" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SM7-uuPNHxHexzHQAN2pzPA4jxM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69983024/akrales_190930_3689_0135.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2BbgRm"&gt;The US PC market has declined during the recent quarter, due to pandemic-related supply issues. It’s the first time the US PC market has declined since the pandemic began causing lots of people &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225356/pc-sales-shipments-2020-growth-idc-canalys-remote-work"&gt;to rush out and buy new PCs&lt;/a&gt; over the past 18 months. Overall, &lt;a href="https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2021-10-11-gartner-says-worldwide-pc-shipments-grew-1-percent-in-third-quarter-of-2021"&gt;Gartner&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.idc.com/getdoc.jsp?containerId=prAP48301621"&gt;IDC&lt;/a&gt; analysis both suggest the worldwide PC market grew in Q3, but at a slower rate than we’ve seen during the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hFc5NN"&gt;Gartner says “consumer and educational spending began to shift away from PCs to other priorities,” during the quarter, leading to less demand for PCs. That’s illustrated best by a 17 percent drop in Chromebook shipments, which Gartner has included in its traditional PC shipments for the first time ever this quarter. Both IDC and Gartner report 84.1 million shipments of PCs in Q3, while IDC puts the number at 86.7 million.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/z-UzlfJN2DsiQ72rpq_cUTrQdco=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22900781/bfarsace_211004_4777_0043.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft just launched new Surface devices.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7G4j8k"&gt;IDC and &lt;a href="https://canalys.com/newsroom/global-pc-market-grows-5-percent-in-q3-2021"&gt;Canalys&lt;/a&gt; both point towards pandemic-related supply issues. “The PC industry continues to be hampered by supply and logistical challenges and unfortunately these issues have not seen much improvement in recent months,” says Jitesh Ubrani, research manager for IDC’s mobile and consumer device trackers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zBp5U8"&gt;These supply issues appear to have impacted laptops more than desktops, with both Gartner and Canalys highlighting stronger desktop PC growth. “These component shortages are expected to persist into the first half of 2022,” says Gartner, after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22701878/xbox-phil-spencer-supply-constraints-2022"&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632047/nvidia-gpu-supply-rtx-30-series-constraints-2022"&gt;Nvidia&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22385240/tsmc-chip-shortage-2022-intel-ceo-earnings-graphics-cards-cpus-gpus"&gt;TSMC&lt;/a&gt; have all warned about industry chip shortages continuing well into 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zq8zJk"&gt;The shortages and US PC market performance comes just as Microsoft has launched Windows 11. The software giant started shipping Surface devices &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22709166/microsoft-windows-11-release-download-available"&gt;equipped with Windows 11&lt;/a&gt; last week, alongside laptops from OEMs like Asus, Lenovo, and HP. Other PC makers like Acer, Dell, and Samsung will also be releasing new Windows 11 devices soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iYJk1e"&gt;The shortages could make it more difficult to find a Windows 11 PC during this holiday season, with supply chain issues affecting Wi-Fi modules, power management circuits, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722151/us-pc-market-decline-supply-issues-windows-11-launch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722151/us-pc-market-decline-supply-issues-windows-11-launch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T06:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T06:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>8BitDo’s Xbox media remotes are cute and cheap</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UmLsUTnSeuiJOe-iV4SIQJkTCWs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69983005/DSCF7774.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The white version of the 8BitDo Media Remote for Xbox is very compact.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9a7ABC"&gt;For some reason, Microsoft doesn’t make a media remote for its Xbox Series consoles. There was a first-party option for the Xbox One, which should work well enough with the S and X (as most Xbox One accessories do), but it appears to have been discontinued. Perhaps it’s a casualty of Microsoft’s more recent &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/7/29/9064527/microsoft-xbox-one-entertainment-features-future"&gt;focus on gaming over TV and entertainment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OiiGAS"&gt;Anyway, here’s renowned controller maker 8BitDo with a couple of officially licensed remotes designed for the new Series consoles. I’ve been using them with my Series X and One X, and I’ve found they do a good job at an affordable price, as long as they’ll work with your setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9lpGiK"&gt;There are two versions of the Media Remote for Xbox, as 8BitDo calls it: a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09B2R2GRM?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$24.99 “Long Edition”&lt;/a&gt; black model with a numpad, and a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09B2SYWH9?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$19.99 white “Short Edition”&lt;/a&gt; without. Both have a compact, comfy soapbar-style design with responsive, clicky buttons, including all the ones you’d use to navigate the Xbox interface with a game controller. They each run off two included AAA batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uB5kOT"&gt;I’m not really sure why you’d want the numpad on the longer black version, unless you’re still living Microsoft’s original dream of the Xbox One as an all-in-one TV hub. It does have a few extra buttons for features like closed captioning, but that won’t do anything for you if you’re mainly planning on using it for streaming apps like Netflix. Still, the option is there if you want it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/S1ivOS1dkPimN0AuBxHkCYeFaB4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22920188/DSCF7776.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The black version of the 8BitDo Media Remote for Xbox adds a numpad and a few extra buttons.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="x9Dn3X"&gt;I prefer the white version myself in use — it’s easy to reach all the buttons without moving your thumb around. But I’d favor this size in black, both to match the Xbox aesthetic and to stand out less in a dimmed living room. In a nice touch, both models have backlit buttons that activate when you pick up the remote and turn off after a few seconds, so they’re equally usable in darker situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jn8zPd"&gt;The remotes use infrared, which has its pros and cons. They require line of sight to the Xbox console, which wasn’t a problem with the One X in my living room but did cause issues with my Series X, since it’s placed out of sight. Given the Series X’s chunky vertical design, some owners may not have been able to place it within plain sight of their couch, so that’s something to keep in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UpsKam"&gt;Using infrared, however, does have the advantage of requiring no pairing or setup. I could use both remote models with both of my Xbox consoles right away. And I know better than to promise that HDMI-CEC will work reliably for your particular setup, but at least for me, it has. I can turn my TV and consoles on with the Xbox button on the remote, as well as adjust the TV’s volume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6SdLpp"&gt;If your Xbox is your primary streaming device and you’re okay with IR, I think it’s worth picking up one of 8BitDo’s Media Remotes. Like most of the company’s products, these are well-designed little gadgets that make using your console more enjoyable. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722115/8bitdo-xbox-media-remote-review-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722115/8bitdo-xbox-media-remote-review-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T06:15:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T06:15:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google says it’s dropping Material Design components on iOS in favor of Apple’s UIKit</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_d2JPeeoLspqwU5NWsblSUfPouE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69982999/acastro_210121_1777_google_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EtzZAf"&gt;Google is phasing out its use of Material Design user interface components for its iOS apps in favor of leaning more on Apple’s own UIKit. The company says the result of the switch should be less work for its iOS development team, but, more importantly, it’s likely the change will mean that Google’s iOS apps will feel less like interlopers on Apple devices. Instead of obeying Android’s UI conventions, they should look and feel more like they belong on iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KZafr9"&gt;The change was &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/featherless/status/1446151509549387781"&gt;announced on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; by Jeff Verkoeyen, engineer lead for Google Design on Apple’s platforms. I recommend reading the full thread if you’re interested, but Verkoeyen says his team “shifted the open source Material components libraries for iOS into maintenance mode” earlier this year. Material Design is Google’s in-house set of design conventions, which it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/6/25/5841044/material-design-new-google-interface-2014"&gt;introduced in 2014&lt;/a&gt; in order to unify the look and feel of its apps and services across mobile devices, Chrome OS, and the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8w0gsG"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This year my team shifted the open source Material components libraries for iOS into maintenance mode. Why?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A  ...&lt;/p&gt;— Jeff Verkoeyen (@featherless) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/featherless/status/1446151509549387781?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="lRkPxb"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This evolution of how we approach design for Apple platforms has enabled us to marry the best of UIKit with the highlights of Google's design language.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The result? Many custom components simply aren't needed anymore. And the ones that are, they now get more attention and focus.&lt;/p&gt;— Jeff Verkoeyen (@featherless) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/featherless/status/1446151524934107137?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="Dyg4Zp"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;The time we're saving not building custom code is now invested in the long tail of UX details that really make products feel great on Apple platforms. To paraphrase Lucas Pope, we're "swimming in a sea of minor things", and I couldn't be more excited about this new direction.&lt;/p&gt;— Jeff Verkoeyen (@featherless) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/featherless/status/1446151530508398596?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wzR3QC"&gt;Verkoeyen said Google developed its own Material Design components for iOS, but, over time, found that these have been “slowly drifting further and further from Apple platform fundamentals because those fundaments were also evolving year over year.” Instead of creating work for itself by filling those gaps, Verkoeyen says Google has now decided to use Apple’s own UIKit for it iOS apps. He notes that doing so will “result in much tighter integrations with the OS than what we can reasonably achieve via custom solutions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6phvRk"&gt;Verkoeyen’s phrasing is somewhat oblique here, but many are &lt;a href="https://sixcolors.com/link/2021/10/googles-apps-to-embrace-ios-on-ios/"&gt;interpreting&lt;/a&gt; the thread — including that mention of “tighter integrations” — as meaning that Google’s iOS apps will, in the future, follow more of the design conventions of Apple’s mobile OS. That might mean using fewer custom buttons that look like they belong on Android, for example. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yCt1qG"&gt;As long-time Apple journalist Jason Snell &lt;a href="https://sixcolors.com/link/2021/10/googles-apps-to-embrace-ios-on-ios/"&gt;commented&lt;/a&gt;: “This is good news. It’s good for Google’s developers, who no longer have to build that custom code. And more importantly, it’s good for people who use Google’s apps on iOS, because with any luck they’ll be updated faster, work better, and feel more like proper iOS apps, not invaders from some other platform.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dp3l8A"&gt;The proof of the pudding is in the eating, though, and until Google actually starts updating it iOS apps over the coming years, we won’t really know how it plans to marry the two design approaches. Let’s hope it does the right thing, and just makes things easiest for users. We will see.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722130/google-ios-app-material-design-components-uikit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722130/google-ios-app-material-design-components-uikit</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T06:09:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T06:09:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft says it mitigated the largest DDoS attack ever recorded </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/I4J8yKVi9yzatcHIyDsC0QLci1E=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69982991/acastro_180507_1777_microsoft_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GBoJT8"&gt;Microsoft says it was able to mitigate a 2.4Tbps Distributed Denial-of-Service (DDoS) attack in August. The attack targeted an Azure customer in Europe, and was 140 percent higher than the highest attack bandwidth volume Microsoft recorded in 2020. It also exceeds the peak traffic volume of 2.3Tbps, the previous largest attack, which was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/18/21295337/amazon-aws-biggest-ddos-attack-ever-2-3-tbps-shield-github-netscout-arbor"&gt;directed at Amazon Web Services&lt;/a&gt; last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8X1mcN"&gt;Microsoft says the attack lasted more than 10 minutes, with short-lived bursts of traffic that peaked at 2.4Tbps, 0.55Tbps, and finally 1.7Tbps. DDoS attacks are typically used to force websites or services offline, thanks to a flood of traffic that a web host can’t handle. They’re usually performed through a botnet, a network of machines that have been compromised using malware or malicious software to control them remotely. Azure was able to stay online throughout the attack, thanks to its ability to absorb tens of terabits of DDoS attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V_rnv7wGdYm8wYIiso4vTPFN6gg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22920213/ac2a83f9_1eff_4b83_8d05_2f83d99c5b4e.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The attack on Azure lasted more than 10 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Hqsn1V"&gt;“The attack traffic originated from approximately 70,000 sources and from multiple countries in the Asia-Pacific region, such as Malaysia, Vietnam, Taiwan, Japan, and China, as well as from the United States,” &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fazure.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fblog%2Fbusiness-as-usual-for-azure-customers-despite-24-tbps-ddos-attack%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F12%2F22722155%2Fmicrosoft-azure-biggest-ddos-attack-ever-2-4-tbps" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;explains Amir Dahan&lt;/a&gt;, a senior program manager for Microsoft’s Azure networking team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2xYboU"&gt;While the number of DDoS attacks have increased in 2021 on Azure, the maximum attack throughput had declined to 625Mbps before this 2.4Tbps attack in the last week of August. Microsoft doesn’t name the Azure customer in Europe that was targeted, but such attacks can also be used as cover for secondary attacks that attempt to spread malware and infiltrate company systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jgwwyk"&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) previously held the record for the largest mitigated DDoS attack, a 2.3Tbps attempt that leapfrogged the previous 1.7Tbps record held by NetScout Arbor in March 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722155/microsoft-azure-biggest-ddos-attack-ever-2-4-tbps"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722155/microsoft-azure-biggest-ddos-attack-ever-2-4-tbps</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T06:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T06:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Tile refreshes its Mate, Pro, Slim, and Sticker trackers with better range, louder volume, and improved water resistance</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6a2fPRgTz4vRiyK9GUqH3AAd_gI=/0x2:7952x5303/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69982970/Black_Pro_Sticker_Combo.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The new Tile Pro, Tile Slim, and Tile Sticker trackers | Image: Tile&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8Xjt0K"&gt;Tile is refreshing its entire product lineup today with brand new hardware for its Tile Mate, Tile Pro, Tile Slim, and Tile Sticker Bluetooth trackers. All four trackers are getting sleeker, updated designs, with improvements to both tracking range, volume, and water resistance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ro8GXg"&gt;The regular $24.99 Tile Mate is getting its biggest change in years, with a more rounded shape and design and a new black color option (in addition to the standard white). Range is being increased from 200 feet to 250 feet, the volume of the ring is now louder when you’re trying to locate it, and the water resistance has been upgraded to an IP67 rating. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9fEK0M"&gt;Battery life is also longer on the new Mate — three years, instead of the single year offered on the previous model — although it comes with the tradeoff that the battery is no longer user-replaceable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/B-9TdH-pjYzc-rTlT4om4HClseY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22911367/BW_Mates_Keys.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Tile&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The refreshed Tile Mate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ItET26hB6vN1R3FBf9WSxCDTUe4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22911375/Slim_Wallet.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Tile&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The refreshed Tile Slim&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XM1qaA"&gt;The $34.99 wallet-sized Tile Slim is also getting similar upgrades to the Mate: a new design that fits in with the other new Tiles, a boosted 250-foot range (from 200 feet), a louder ring, and IP67 water resistance (although, unlike the old Mate, the old Slim was already waterproof, so that’s not as big a change). It also maintains its built-in battery, which, like the Mate, lasts approximately three years before needing replacement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DIxTGW"&gt;The $34.99 Tile Pro is also getting a new design, which should help better distinguish it from the regular Tile Mate. The new model has a more rectangular appearance that fits better on a keyring than the old square shape. And like the regular Mate, the updated Pro is also more water-resistant, with a new IP67 rating (compared to the IP55 rating on the old Pro, which only protected against “&lt;a href="https://tileteam.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360009916693-Tile-Pro-2020"&gt;splashes or a quick drop in water&lt;/a&gt;”). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="bikEOe"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Improvements all around&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PTU2Nb"&gt;Some parts of the Pro are the same as the previous model: it still has the longest range of any Tile tracker (400 feet), and it’s keeping the replaceable battery (which lasts about a year before you’ll have to swap it out).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gv4sXu"&gt;Lastly, there’s the $29.99 Tile Sticker, which is getting its first update since it was first released. The new model has dramatically better range (250 feet, compared to 150 feet on the old model), better battery life (three years off the non-replaceable battery, up from two years before), and a louder ring. And like the other new models, the new Sticker also has IP67 water resistance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Myr-zWOnGy_yIkpH7-0LnQKjok0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22911379/Black_Pro_Backpack.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Tile&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The refreshed Tile Pro&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ueLa4wlTc4zjTVoyNZd-0LbumIA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22911385/Sticker_Remote.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Tile&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The refreshed Tile Sticker&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KH4ShE"&gt;Tile is also rolling out a new Lost and Found feature on the Mate, Pro, and Slim trackers: the new models now feature a QR code on the back, which can be scanned by anyone who finds a Tile tracker out in the world but isn’t already a Tile user. When the lost tracker is found, scanning it will pop up your contact information so that you can coordinate getting your stuff back. (The feature isn’t available on the Sticker due to size constraints in printing the QR code.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WkMHQU"&gt;It’s not quite on the same level as Apple’s AirTags or Samsung’s SmartTags, both of which can leverage Apple and Samsung devices that belong to users who don’t actually own trackers as part of the companies’ Bluetooth networks, but Lost and Found should help expand Tile’s usefulness even when found by a non-Tile customer. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R-gaPNca4-NbBlXUGn1BvqdCKfY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22911360/tile.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Tile&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Tile’s new QR-code powered Lost and Found feature&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ASH5sV"&gt;Additionally, Tile also announced a new safety feature, called “Scan and Secure,” that it’ll be rolling out in early 2022. Once it’s available, Scan and Secure will allow anyone to download the Tile app and use it to scan and detect nearby devices and notify you if there are any unknown Tiles nearby. The goal is to make it harder for someone to use Tiles for malicious tracking purposes (Apple and Samsung both offer similar safety features with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/3/22516178/apple-airtags-tracking-devices-update-play-sound-privacy-android-app"&gt;AirTags&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22392924/samsung-smartags-tracker-bixby-privacy-smartthings"&gt;SmartTags&lt;/a&gt;), and Tile is working with the National Network to End Domestic Violence on development and design of the feature. Users who install the Tile app to scan for devices won’t be part of Tile’s finding network, either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fuuM7i"&gt;Noticeably missing from Tile’s announcement is the addition of ultra-wideband radio technology for more accurate localized tracking, something that its AirTag and SmartTag Plus competitors both have offered for months. But Tile has an answer for that, too, in the form of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22480911"&gt;newly announced Tile Ultra&lt;/a&gt;, which will bring UWB-powered AR tracking to the lineup in early 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NqDB1y"&gt;The four new Tile trackers are available starting today from Tile’s website and a variety of retailers, including Amazon, Costco, Best Buy, and Target. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="riFIo8"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22716868/tile-mate-pro-slim-sticker-trackers-update-range-volume-water-resistance"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22716868/tile-mate-pro-slim-sticker-trackers-update-range-volume-water-resistance</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T06:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T06:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Tile Ultra takes on AirTags with UWB-powered AR tracking, coming early 2022</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SKvpG8MLiuG_48l5V52C10xDf40=/162x0:1761x1066/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69982973/Screen_Shot_2021_09_20_at_12.19.29_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="J32oab"&gt;Tile has officially announced its first ultra-wideband (UWB) tracking tag, the Tile Ultra, coming in 2022 and which Tile claims is the first tracking tag from any company to offer UWB support on both Android and iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bd495K"&gt;Tile isn’t giving any information on price or a release date beyond “early 2022,” but it did provide an early preview of what the Ultra will look like and how it’ll work. From the outside, the Ultra looks similar to the newly updated Tile Pro, with a rounded, rectangular shape and a built-in key ring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CLzy7N"&gt;But on the inside, in addition to using Bluetooth radios to leverage Tile’s network of devices to discover the rough location of an object, the Tile Ultra (similar to Apple’s AirTag and Samsung’s SmartTag Plus) can then use its UWB radio to offer more accurate location abilities, even if your tag is behind a shelf or under a couch. The Ultra will also offer an augmented-reality mode to easily directly you straight to your missing tracker. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rrOd58r4A6vJgMLZiSzAzKVfcrY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22911325/UWB_AR.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="gyTfgW"&gt;The new Ultra tag comes as Tile is also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22480909"&gt;announcing refreshed versions&lt;/a&gt; of the rest of its tracking tag lineup (the Mate, Pro, Slim, and Sticker), which have been updated with sleeker designs, louder volume, and improved water resistance. Those four new models, unlike the Ultra, are available today. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22716870/tile-ultra-bluetooth-tracker-uwb-ar-early-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22716870/tile-ultra-bluetooth-tracker-uwb-ar-early-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T05:42:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T05:42:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft transforms the Windows Subsystem for Linux into a Windows 11 app</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/o58ybIDIzGAnz7f6c-Ugiz6yXQ8=/0x20:1219x833/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69982908/windowslinux.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BfN9KY"&gt;Microsoft has transformed the Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL) into an app that you can simply download and install from the Microsoft Store on Windows 11. A preview version of the app is &lt;a href="https://aka.ms/wslstorepage"&gt;available right now&lt;/a&gt;, allowing Windows 11 users to install Windows Subsystem for Linux without having to head into add / remove programs and selecting WSL as an optional inbox component for Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6wsACm"&gt;This separate app will now be serviced through the store, which means Microsoft can update WSL independently from Windows, allowing WSL users to “get the latest WSL updates and features faster, and without needing to modify your Windows version.” While there are no new changes with this Store app version just yet, it does mean that future updates can appear without needing to wait for a bigger Windows release or update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WHqlCs"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nVxYFMa1ltM?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="t7OkmM"&gt;Microsoft &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22396018/microsoft-windows-10-linux-gui-apps-task-manager-app-throttling-features"&gt;enabled Linux GUI apps on Windows 10&lt;/a&gt; for developers last year, and features like this will be available immediately in the Microsoft Store in the future. It appears that this Microsoft Store app for WSL will only work on Windows 11, though. Microsoft doesn’t mention Windows 10 &lt;a href="https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/a-preview-of-wsl-in-the-microsoft-store-is-now-available/"&gt;in its blog post&lt;/a&gt;, suggesting that you’ll need to update to benefit from the Microsoft Store app. It’s good news for Windows 11 users though, especially those in enterprise environments where it often takes slightly longer to get the latest Windows versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nUE5Lp"&gt;Microsoft will still support the inbox version of WSL so you can run them side by side, and aims to move Windows 11 users over to the Microsoft Store version eventually. “Our goals are to make WSL in the Microsoft Store the best way to install and use WSL, as you’ll be able to get the latest updates fastest through that route, and in the long term we’d like to move WSL users to use the store version,” &lt;a href="https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/a-preview-of-wsl-in-the-microsoft-store-is-now-available/"&gt;explains Craig Loewen&lt;/a&gt;, a program manager for the Windows developer platform.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722146/microsoft-windows-subsystem-for-linux-app-windows-11-microsoft-store"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722146/microsoft-windows-subsystem-for-linux-app-windows-11-microsoft-store</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
