<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-08-06T14:59:44-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-06T14:59:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-06T14:59:44-04:00</updated>
    <title>Razer will let you sign up to beta test its RGB face mask</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Sb8fAZsq82C-U1WctXeS9vpu5hs=/63x0:1530x978/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69689974/Screen_Shot_2021_08_06_at_11.01.44_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Razer&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mW1VJT"&gt;Razer &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Razer/status/1423660327762374662?s=20"&gt;announced today&lt;/a&gt; that its lit-like-a-gaming-PC N95 mask has a new name and a beta program set up ahead of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22524990/razer-hazel-mask-first-launch-early-fourth-quarter-2021-drops"&gt;the planned fourth quarter launch&lt;/a&gt;. The futuristic-looking &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22221344/razer-project-hazel-n95-respirator-mask-coronavirus-chroma-rgb-concept"&gt;Project Hazel&lt;/a&gt; has been christened the Razer Zephyr, and you can sign up to be a beta tester &lt;a href="https://razer.a9yw.net/c/482924/642901/10229?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.razer.com%2Fcampaigns%2Froad-to-zephyr%23signup&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;right now on Razer’s site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oYeszY"&gt;Razer has not provided any additional information on the timing of the Zephyr’s release or when beta testers can expect to receive their masks. Based on &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RMKIkNo-QMg&amp;amp;t=22s"&gt;the video Razer shared alongside its announcement&lt;/a&gt;, beta testers might get a different mask design from what’s been shared up until this point. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kVIsG6"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RMKIkNo-QMg?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=22&amp;amp;start=22" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="msCkpD"&gt;The Zephyr seems a tad wider and rounder than Razer’s original Project Hazel, and there’s a grille at the bottom of the mask that’s a lot more visible than previous images and photos have shown. It might be for additional ventilation or to assist in voice amplification, but it definitely wasn’t featured in Razer’s earlier concepts for the face mask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZYVE6C"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; has reached out to Razer for more details on the beta program and any possible design changes that will ship alongside the Zephyr beta.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6fFKdKiVlkTC6gQz3yBL1xdRRSQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22766767/zephyr_teaser_1500x1000_gallery3.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Razer&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Zephyr on a real human face. Note the bottom grille.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KR6GOMeCKt3NTuyN5VZqV75liN4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22399320/QTPjtwr.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Razer&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The original Project Hazel design.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6hVXwt"&gt;We should have a better idea about the design once masks actually make it into beta testers’ hands, but the announcement of the program in the first place does make the Zephyr that much more real. Considering the project went from a fun CES concept to a real thing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22221344/razer-project-hazel-n95-respirator-mask-coronavirus-chroma-rgb-concept"&gt;Razer was intent on making&lt;/a&gt;, every step pushes this mask further from vaporware. Whether it’s actually affordable, enjoyable, or practical to wear is an entirely separate issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="emT4kL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"CDC reinstitutes mask recommendations for some vaccinated people ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22595945/cdc-mask-recommendations-vaccinated-delta"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="LbZyho"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22613139/razer-zephyr-n95-rgb-mask-project-hazel"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22613139/razer-zephyr-n95-rgb-mask-project-hazel</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-06T14:35:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-06T14:35:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>The FCC finally made a new broadband map of the US</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wS0eUSzhJ-Rxjc9F9g3aolzq1ms=/184x0:1750x1044/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69689876/Screen_Shot_2021_08_06_at_9.06.49_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: FCC&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mVdH0R"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.fcc.gov/document/fcc-launches-new-mobile-broadband-map"&gt;The Federal Communications Commission has launched&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;a href="https://fcc.maps.arcgis.com/apps/webappviewer/index.html?id=6c1b2e73d9d749cdb7bc88a0d1bdd25b"&gt;new map&lt;/a&gt; designed to show consumers what kind of cellular coverage they can expect in a given area from AT&amp;amp;T, T-Mobile, US Cellular, and Verizon. It’s been a long time coming, and it looks like an improvement over the agency’s past attempts to show gaps in the nation’s broadband coverage, which were &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/24/17882842/us-internet-broadband-map-isp-fcc-wireless-competition"&gt;woefully inadequate and inaccurate&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7eTcDY"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; editor-in-chief Nilay Patel &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/reckless/status/1423671191210954752?s=20"&gt;pointed out on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, it shouldn’t have taken this long for this map to be available. The &lt;a href="https://www.commerce.senate.gov/2020/3/bill-to-improve-broadband-data-maps-signed-into-law"&gt;law requiring that these maps be made&lt;/a&gt;, known as the Broadband Deployment Accuracy and Technological Availability (DATA) Act, was signed in March 2020, and the lack of details about broadband coverage has created confusion about the so-called digital divide for years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sL7XuU"&gt;It’s also worth noting that the map isn’t based on data that the FCC collected or crowdsourced. FCC acting chairwoman Jessica Rosenworcel said in a news release that the data was provided by the carriers who don’t have a great reputation for having the most accurate picture &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22177154/us-internet-speed-maps-competition-availability-fcc"&gt;of where they do and don’t provide broadband&lt;/a&gt; (though the FCC is working on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/22/22345533/fcc-broadband-data-collection-program-fix-the-internet"&gt;getting a better picture of home internet availability&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Consumer Reports&lt;/em&gt; are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22574103/internet-bill-equity-verge-consumer-reports-partnership"&gt;working on examining how cost-effective broadband is&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8Xj9r3k-UzIq5KRkXH20J0jatkc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22766633/FCC_Map_Vs.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The FCC’s map (left) versus T-Mobile (right, top), AT&amp;amp;T (right, middle), and Verizon’s (right, bottom).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="w05RVM"&gt;The interactive map lets users select which carrier’s coverage map they want to see, and it provides information about LTE coverage, voice coverage, or both. The FCC says the map is the work of its Broadband Data Task Force. The map is fairly user-friendly; instead of having to flip between &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fcoverage%2Fcoverage-map&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F8%2F6%2F22613096%2Ffcc-cellular-broadband-voice-availability-map-data" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;T-Mobile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.att.com/maps/wireless-coverage.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.verizon.com/coverage-map/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Verizon’s&lt;/a&gt; coverage maps, users can see all of the data in one place, overlaid on top of each other. The map also provides a distinction between data availability and voice availability — which is useful, as being able to make a call and being able to get online are obviously two very different things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ylnplN"&gt;One big thing the map is missing is data about 5G coverage, or really any indicator of what kind of speeds users can expect. &lt;a href="https://www.fcc.gov/news-events/notes/2021/08/06/new-mobile-map-preview-whats-come"&gt;In a note about the map’s launch&lt;/a&gt;, Rosenworcel says the network has to provide at least 5Mbps down and 1Mbps up to qualify as 4G data coverage. If one carrier provided an area with 100Mbps speeds and another provided 10Mbps speeds, that could be difficult to distinguish on the map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="4ogxZB"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Data for the map is provided by the carriers&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="juNEm2"&gt;Rosenworcel also admits that this map is only a first step in the FCC’s work to improve the information available to consumers, but it’s an important one. It at least lets consumers know the minimum of what they should expect in a given area and gives them the tools to make more informed decisions about their cellular provider.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22613096/fcc-cellular-broadband-voice-availability-map-data"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22613096/fcc-cellular-broadband-voice-availability-map-data</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-06T13:26:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-06T13:26:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>SEC charges crypto exchange execs for the first time over unregistered token sales</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YPzBdfjvxe1NVLbgdld5glD_SGE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69689495/GettyImages_1230723516.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An employee wearing a protective face mask inspects Sapphire Technology Ltd. AMD graphics processing units (GPU) at the Evobits crypto farm in Cluj-Napoca, Romania, on Wednesday, Jan. 22, 2021. The world’s second-most-valuable cryptocurrency, Ethereum, rallied 75 percent this year, outpacing its larger rival Bitcoin.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Akos Stiller / Bloomberg via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MWEKOa"&gt;The Securities and Exchange Commission issued &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2021-145"&gt;its first charges&lt;/a&gt; against the decentralized finance industry Friday, accusing two people of illegally selling over $30 million of securities in unregistered offerings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pE6tlB"&gt;The SEC’s Friday order found that two executives from the Blockchain Credit Partners company used the Ethereum blockchain to sell cryptocurrencies to investors while misleading them about the company’s profitability. Specifically, investors purchased cryptocurrencies using digital assets like ether. The company then promised to pay investors over 6 percent in interest and that the funds would go toward physical investments like car loans to create additional income. The SEC determined that these “real-world” investments wouldn’t generate the income advertised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="EG3zWd"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Full and honest disclosure remains the cornerstone of our securities laws”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2Rzvh0"&gt;“Full and honest disclosure remains the cornerstone of our securities laws – no matter what technologies are used to offer and sell those securities,” Gurbir S. Grewal, SEC Enforcement Division director, said in a statement Friday. “This allows investors to make informed decisions and prevents issuers from misleading the public about business operations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JFN6po"&gt;Friday’s charges against the company come as the federal government is preparing to issue new regulations for the decentralized finance and cryptocurrency markets. Earlier this week, SEC Chair Gary Gensler &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608096/cryptocurrency-bitcoin-sec-gary-gensler-regulation"&gt;called on Congress&lt;/a&gt; to grant the agency more authority in regulating cryptocurrency, lending, and platforms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tbbsME"&gt;“If we don’t address these issues, I worry a lot of people will be hurt,” Gensler said on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hHXhFL"&gt;Congress has so far failed to give the SEC more authority in the cryptocurrency market, opting this week to include language in the bipartisan infrastructure package focusing on taxation of digital assets. On Sunday, Senate negotiators reached a $1 trillion infrastructure deal, including language that would require cryptocurrency brokers to report transactions on their tax returns. But the definition of “broker” was vague and could potentially open miners up to greater taxation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MAWGJI"&gt;It’s unclear &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22612663/infrastructure-bitcoin-tax-blockchain-proof-of-work-stake-ethereum"&gt;how cryptocurrency will fare&lt;/a&gt; under the new infrastructure bill. There are dual amendments in the Senate looking to clarify the language. An amendment authored by Sens. Ron Wyden (D-OR), Cynthia Lummis (R-WY), and Pat Toomey (R-PA) would exempt miners. Another amendment from Sen. Mark Warner (D-VA) has gained more popularity amongst lawmakers, but cryptocurrency advocates fear it would hurt the industry by creating uneven reporting requirements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DnGF7v"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OiBAuT"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22613195/sec-cryptocurrency-blockchain-gensler-charge-illegal-fraud-tokens"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22613195/sec-cryptocurrency-blockchain-gensler-charge-illegal-fraud-tokens</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-06T13:07:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-06T13:07:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>The best laptop you can buy in 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Dell XPS 13, Dell XPS 15, HP Elite Dragonfly, Surface Laptop 3, MacBook Pro, and Lenovo Yoga C740." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/C554ZjlwY7R1hgqzx9H7bhxKvWA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66770456/VRG_4013_Best_Laptop_Grid.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: William Joel/The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The best laptops for you, from ultraportables to high-powered editing machines&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="DsiiFD"&gt;The best laptop of 2021 can come with a variety of brands, prices, and features. Here, we’ve got the rest of the best laptops, Windows 10 business notebooks, gaming rigs, Chromebooks, laptops for school, and 2-in-1 convertibles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lfv5g0"&gt;Our current pick for the best laptop of 2021 is the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"&gt;MacBook Air&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a device that does just about everything right. While it’s certainly not a perfect device, there are no major flaws. It’s a great pick for productivity, browsing, and even light gaming. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SNThzL"&gt;We live in a world where smartphones are ubiquitous, tablets are commonplace, and even smartwatches are a thing that people talk about on the regular. But throughout all of these advances, the humble laptop has persevered — and for good reason. When it comes time to work, whether that's editing photos, writing a lot of emails, composing documents, or staying in touch with colleagues and family, we’re here with our top picks to help you find the best laptop for the job. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="31HnuI"&gt;It's getting harder to buy a bad laptop, but what separates the best laptop of 2021 from good laptops is how they balance power, efficiency, portability, and comfort. The top laptop should have a fantastic keyboard and trackpad — after all, those are the two biggest reasons you'd choose a laptop over a smartphone or tablet. Its display should be easy on the eyes, bright, and sharp enough that you aren't distracted by jagged edges and visible pixels. It should be powerful enough for most anything short of intensive video editing and advanced gaming. It should be easy to carry around from place to place, and it should be able to last all day without needing to be plugged in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3hnoYs"&gt;In our view, the best laptop for budget shoppers is the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21319378/hp-envy-x360-2020-amd-review-price-specs-features"&gt;HP Envy x360 13&lt;/a&gt;. For a sub-$1,000 price, it delivers performance on par with much more expensive laptops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7ABV8A"&gt;Our other picks for the best laptops, Chromebooks, and 2-in-1s of 2021 include the Asus ROG Zephyrus G14, the MacBook Pro 16, and the HP Elite Dragonfly. Check out the full list of best laptop picks below or our roundup of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22295181/best-gaming-laptop"&gt;best gaming laptops&lt;/a&gt;, if you’re looking for a powerful machine that doesn’t sacrifice portability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="4mn8ET"&gt;Best Laptops 2021&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="GJnOwH"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Laptops 2020: Apple MacBook Air" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cT9WoMfWteu_VLQY3timVCW362k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22046471/vpavic_4291_20201113_0411.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Apple MacBook Air is the best laptop of 2020.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="oTToOm"&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"&gt;MacBook Air (late 2020)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="rE8ByG"&gt;The best laptop of 2021&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="qIDMjX"&gt;The late-2020 MacBook Air, powered by Apple’s M1 processor, is the best laptop you can buy. The base model, which includes 8GB of RAM and 256 GB of storage, starts at $999. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GYCzY0"&gt;Appearance-wise, this laptop has a lot in common with the Intel-powered MacBook Air that Apple released earlier this year, including the same 2560 x 1600 screen, Touch ID, 720p webcam, fingerprint sensor, and scissor-switch keyboard. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iDDWFN"&gt;But the new processor is the star of the show here; it’s fast. In our testing, it handled intense photo- and video-editing workloads better than almost any Intel-powered laptop we’ve tried this year. It was also able to run &lt;em&gt;Shadow of the Tomb Raider&lt;/em&gt; at close-to-playable frame rates, which is quite a feat for integrated graphics. At launch, these apps hadn’t yet been optimized for the M1 processor and were running through Apple’s Rosetta 2 translation layer — but they still worked fine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ACwNY3"&gt;And the processing power didn’t even weigh down the battery life: we got between eight and 10 hours of sustained work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XZkaRR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10220133"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8eGPnz"&gt;Another benefit of the M1 processor is that it enables the MacBook Air to run iPhone and iPad apps natively on macOS. As of this writing, there still isn’t a huge selection of mobile apps available, and some that have been released aren’t quite optimized for the laptop screen. Still, it’s a benefit we can look forward to as time goes on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NjPO8F"&gt;Overall, there’s no reason that a general-use customer shouldn’t consider the MacBook Air. It’s a reliable device with excellent performance, as well as the excellence in build quality for which Apple is known. Power users who need a MacBook Pro probably know who they are; the Air should be fine for everyone else. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="L8pJhA"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Laptop 2021: HP Spectre x360 14" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VXu0jcRLvUdGZwwpjg3vvbG1mn4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22279295/mchin_190429_4395_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by MonicaChin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The HP Spectre x360 14 is one of the best convertible laptops you can buy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="O7mXrt"&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22264792/hp-spectre-x360-14-laptop-stylus-oled-review-price-specs-features"&gt;HP Spectre x360 14&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="N7xEV5"&gt;The best Windows laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="4nwIVn"&gt;It’s hard to come up with a single complaint about the Spectre x360 14. It’s a drop-dead gorgeous machine with a sturdy build and a premium look and feel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xL3xF1"&gt;But the Spectre x360 14 isn’t just pretty to look at: it’s also a pleasure to use as a daily work driver. Intel’s latest 11th Gen processors and Iris Xe integrated graphics deliver snappy performance with no slowdown or freezes that we observed. And we got an average of 10 hours of battery life out of the device — one of the best results we’ve ever seen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yfMa1S"&gt;On the outside, the Spectre includes a roomy 3:2 display, and if FHD resolution doesn’t suit your fancy, there are OLED and 1,000-nit options available. There’s even a packaged stylus, which attaches magnetically to the side of the Spectre — handy if you’re using the device as a tablet. Pretty much every other aspect of this laptop, from its comfortable keyboard and smooth touchpad to its bass-heavy audio and practical port selection, rivals or exceeds the best convertibles on the market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xxTNW9"&gt;Such an exceptional package of features doesn’t come cheap, and many customers will find everything they need in a less expensive product. But the Spectre x360 14 is the new gold standard of Windows convertibles. Overall, it’s the best Windows laptop you can buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ewzfR6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10340665"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="yswF9z"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Laptop 20201: LG Gram 17" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GfTxqQBd93C-ef4Dw31UfHEVW_I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22411713/cfaulkner_20210326_4491_0006.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The LG Gram 17 is the lightweight 17-inch laptop to buy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SoHxJX"&gt;3. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22364183/lg-gram-17-2021-intel-11th-gen-iris-xe-graphics-performance-battery-review"&gt;LG Gram 17 (2021)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="aOmcws"&gt;The best laptop in 2021 for big-screen fans&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="ovDneV"&gt;Even if you’ve used a light laptop before, it’s difficult to explain how light the LG Gram 17 is. It has a massive 17-inch display, but it’s somehow only three pounds. Picking it up messes with your mind; you feel like you’re not holding anything. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AbftFc"&gt;But the Gram 17’s weight isn’t the only standout feature. It also has some of the best battery life you can get, lasting over 12 hours in our testing. Add a great keyboard, a solid port selection, quiet fans, and a fast processor, and there’s very little not to like about this device. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BvoTCC"&gt;Not everyone needs a 17-inch display, and many folks who do are looking for a heavier-duty workstation that probably doesn’t get moved very often. But if you’d just really like a large screen for your daily office work and Netflixing, you’re the target demographic for this machine. It’s a niche, but truly impressive device without much real competition in today’s market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kJHRXY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10498451"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="VSwm66"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Laptops 2020: HP Envy x360 13" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-3n_PDQBp_EOIUDusfA7A_LYGZA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/20069599/mchin_200705_4086_0006.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photography by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The HP Envy x360 is the best laptop you can buy for under $1,000.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="7dLyUJ"&gt;4. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21319378/hp-envy-x360-2020-amd-review-price-specs-features"&gt;HP Envy x360 (2020)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="IOuDKK"&gt;The best budget laptop in 2021&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="6ONzJr"&gt;You don’t need to spend $1,000 to get a laptop that looks and feels premium. The HP Envy x360 2020 is the best budget laptop you can buy, thanks to its sturdy and compact build, chic convertible design, and excellent performance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5TwdF5"&gt;Part of what makes the Envy so great is that HP has ported over a number of elements from its excellent 2019 flagship, the Spectre x360, including the thin-and-light chassis and nearly bezel-free display with an 88 percent screen-to-body ratio. The touchscreen (which supports HP’s MPP2.0 pen) is bright and looks great. (You can choose a 300-nit, 400-nit, or 1,000-nit panel). And HP has added a row of convenient hotkeys to the keyboard, including kill switches for the microphone and webcam. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xRbztF"&gt;But the most exciting feature is inside: the new Envy x360 is powered by AMD’s Ryzen 4000 series. The Ryzen 5-4500U in my model did an outstanding job with a fairly heavy load of multitasking. And AMD’s integrated Radeon graphics delivered good gaming performance comparable to what you’d expect from a lower-powered discrete GPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="UnaYvt"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9505904"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="oZ6G0O"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Laptops 2020: Apple MacBook Pro (late 2020)" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OP4WWFrMJ2y3hRwBn6-2rHM2r-c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22038539/akramer_201113_4290_0022.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Alexander Kramer for The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 13-inch MacBook Pro is a refreshed MacBook Pro for modern customers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3k1xVZ"&gt;5. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review"&gt;MacBook Pro 13 (late 2020)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="lYrZ3f"&gt;The best MacBook Pro for everyday users&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="yUbRrT"&gt;If you’re looking to buy an M1 MacBook for heavier workloads, you’ll want to look at the late-2020 MacBook Pro. It starts at $1,299, which is $300 more than the late-2020 MacBook Air. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gNImzP"&gt;The MacBook Pro has a slightly different design and look than the Air, as well as a few additional features like the Touch Bar. But the two have the same processor. The main difference is that the Pro includes a fan (the Air is fanless), which means it can sustain heavy workloads for a longer period of time without needing to throttle its performance. But you won’t notice much of a performance difference between the two MacBooks unless you’re routinely pushing heavy tasks for long periods of time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="USngRn"&gt;If that’s you, though, go for the Pro. We were able to run a number of hefty Premiere Pro exports and didn’t see a dip in times. The Pro also achieved a significantly higher score than the Air in a 30-minute loop of Cinebench R23; the scores were closer together after a single run. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="YY6PlN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10220169"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="9bGBKN"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Laptops 2020: Dell XPS 13 2-in-1" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/t2jDTEOcLfPOaz5wvoUW7fiKiWg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22048783/mchin_190211_4302_0012.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Dell XPS 13 2-in-1 is the best convertible you can buy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="NKt5f4"&gt;6. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21575308/dell-xps-13-2-in-1-2020-review-tiger-lake-specs-price-features"&gt;Dell XPS 13 2-in-1&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Ucqsb1"&gt;A great 2-in-1 laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="iLNMXR"&gt;If you’re looking for a convertible laptop that does just about everything right, we recommend Dell’s latest XPS 13 2-in-1. It features a sturdy and well-made chassis, a nearly bezel-free 16:10 touch display, and Intel’s newest 11th Gen processors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dghfZI"&gt;The base model, for $1,099, includes a Core i3-1154G4, 8GB of RAM, a 1920 x 1200 display, and a 256GB SSD. You can spec that up to a 3840 x 2400 display, a Core i7-1165G7, 32GB of RAM, and a 1TB SSD. There are various add-ons as well: you can pay $50 extra for a white model and $60 to upgrade to Windows 10 Pro. Basically, there’s something for everyone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BEAGgI"&gt;Dell has made a few minor tweaks to the 2-in-1 since last year’s model. The webcam now supports Windows Hello, and the RAM and microSD reader have been upgraded. But the exciting news is the new chip and, in particular, Intel’s new integrated graphics. The XPS 13 2-in-1 did a better job than any 10th Gen laptop with an iGPU on our Adobe Premiere Pro export test. And you can even play some games on this thing: it broke 60fps on &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt;, and even managed 36fps on &lt;em&gt;Shadow of the Tomb Raider&lt;/em&gt; at its lowest settings. That’s an improvement over the results we saw from 10th Gen systems, and it also beats some 11th Gen systems (including the clamshell Dell XPS 13). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="izx3w7"&gt;Of course, it’s not perfect. The port selection is limited (as is customary for modern XPS models) and the keyboard is a bit flat for my taste. But overall, the 2-in-1 excels on the fundamentals: build quality, display, performance, and battery life. What more could you want?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="woXzPz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10220219"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="H5F8sd"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Laptops 2020: Dell XPS 13 (late 2020)" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DlGu9NcyOGiBmZH9uk0wUADgPx0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22007661/mchin_190124_4274_0004.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Dell XPS 13 is one of the best laptops of 2020.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Ncv6I8"&gt;7. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21546784/dell-xps-13-late-2020-review-design-specs-price-features"&gt;Dell XPS 13 (late 2020)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="w7TWDY"&gt;The best laptop for college&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="6xPrkB"&gt;The Dell XPS 13 is a compact and reliable laptop. Its beautiful chassis, excellent 16:10 display, and great performance make it an excellent choice for general-purpose users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ik0URk"&gt;This late-2020 model comes with Intel’s new Tiger Lake processors, from a Core i3-1154G4 up to a Core i7-1165G7. It starts at $999, so it’s a bit cheaper than the 2-in-1. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MZCO5H"&gt;My review unit (an i7 model) blew through the work tasks I needed it to do without any slowdown or heat. It did quite well, and handily beat its 10th Gen predecessor in both gaming and media work. It didn’t do as well as the XPS 13 2-in-1, which is why that model is ranked higher on this list. But if you like the look and feel of the XPS 13 and would prefer a clamshell model (or need a bouncier keyboard), this XPS is still a great option. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uN3gSr"&gt;There’s an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22528646/dell-xps-13-oled-2021-review-screen-specs-price"&gt;OLED model&lt;/a&gt; of the XPS 13 as well, which costs $300 more than the FHD model. This model has worse battery life, but does deliver a stunning picture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="LcZHL9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10220250"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="PzHMkm"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Laptop 2021: Asus Zephyrus G15" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FOls4hR6yunICRTjJJFN-zK9XjI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22341889/akrales_210226_4440_0022.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales/ The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The Asus Zephyrus G15 is the best gaming laptop you can buy.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="rLlXNY"&gt;8. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/30/21197761/asus-rog-zephyrus-g14-review-gaming-laptop-specs-features-price"&gt;Asus ROG Zephyrus G15&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="nxYz9i"&gt;The best gaming laptop in 2021&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="2eqQM4"&gt;At just over four pounds, the Zephyrus G15 is one of the lightest 15-inch gaming laptops you can buy. But you’re not compromising performance for that portability. The G15 is powered by the top mobile chips AMD and Nvidia have to offer, and pairs thim with a fast 165Hz QHD display. In our testing, the system was able to handle even the toughest AAA titles at QHD resolution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SxthwN"&gt;Almost everything else about the G15 is great too: the audio sounds good, the keyboard and touchpad are some of the best on the market, the port selection has just about everything you’d need, and the battery can last over eight and a half hours to a charge. If you’re looking for a high-powered gaming machine that also works great as a daily driver, the Zephyrus G15 should be at the top of your list. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kJ5hNb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10385239"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="wfabqO"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Laptop 2021: ThinkPad X1 Nano" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-UJ9eqFis-TjN1Cukkv-3CVFFyo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22366104/akrales_210305_4459_0032.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The ThinkPad X1 Nano is a lightweight laptop for business travelers.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="m9IrEq"&gt;9. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22335874/lenovo-thinkpad-x1-nano-laptop-windows-business-intel-review-price-specs"&gt;Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Nano&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="TA1Mem"&gt;The best laptop for business travel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="XTubRZ"&gt;In many ways, the ThinkPad X1 Nano is a run-of-the-mill ThinkPad. It’s got a solid sturdy chassis, discrete clickers, a physical privacy shutter, a red TrackPoint in the middle of the keyboard, and all kinds of business-specific security and management features. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WdGWMd"&gt;But the Nano is special because it’s the lightest ThinkPad Lenovo has ever made. It’s also one of the lightest laptops you can buy, at just 1.99 pounds. You’re not sacrificing performance to get that mindblowing weight: The Nano kept up with our heavy testing workloads without any fan noise or noticeable heat. If you’re looking for a reliable business laptop that will feel like nothing in your briefcase, this is the one for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TxKHkC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10498483"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="yQ8lEM"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Laptops 2020: Asus ROG Zephyrus G14" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NKgtx_4xZAjnNx7xRifo47bgVlw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19855768/awhite_200319_3954_6.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Avery White for The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Asus ROG Zephyrus G14 is a brilliant gaming laptop.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="JUpNYn"&gt;10. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/30/21197761/asus-rog-zephyrus-g14-review-gaming-laptop-specs-features-price"&gt;Asus ROG Zephyrus G14&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="pLq6K9"&gt;The best 14-inch gaming laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="FBMA49"&gt;The Zephyrus G14 is an astonishingly powerful gaming laptop for a low price (relative to other notebooks with comparable hardware). It pairs AMD’s new Ryzen 9 4900HS with an Nvidia RTX 2060 Max-Q GPU and a 120HZ display, and it can run demanding games at their highest settings without a problem. It’s also quite light for such a powerful laptop, weighing just over 3.5 pounds. Its battery life is also impressive for a gaming rig; we got almost nine hours of multitasking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cWOpxK"&gt;But you don’t need to be a gamer to appreciate the Zephyrus G14. It’s also a great notebook for business and everyday multitasking with a unique retro design. Plus, the keyboard and touchpad are exceptional and quiet enough not to bother officemates. On the flip side, if you need to use your laptop for videoconferences, the G14 would not be a great choice, as it lacks a webcam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="VEeU1O"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9505867"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="Mj8xj4"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Laptops 2020: Apple MacBook Pro 16-inch" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/67n9Ccapbp52oZ-JCjWEhCCzG8s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19395185/vpavic_191118_3800_0058.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The MacBook Pro is an excellent laptop for video editing. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="HfyKBe"&gt;11. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/21/20974649/apple-macbook-pro-16-inch-laptop-review-keyboard-test-specs-price-features"&gt;MacBook Pro (16-inch, 2019)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="2WSPjS"&gt;A great choice for Mac power users&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="TfAFYg"&gt;The 16-inch MacBook Pro is the best Apple laptop for power users. Apple dealt with the biggest complaints that people have historically had about MacBook Pros, and if you can stomach the price, there’s not a lot else to complain about. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cIH5ZZ"&gt;Most importantly, the keyboard is good again. The keys have a full millimeter of travel, and while the typing experience isn’t exceptional, it’s a world away from the maligned butterfly keyboard of MacBooks past. It’s fairly quiet, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hjExSY"&gt;This MacBook also features the best sound you’ll find on a laptop. Apple has crammed three speakers into each side, including two woofers. The result is balanced audio with audible bass and great stereo separation. For those who need a laptop that can crank through editing video, working with multiple audio tracks, or processing large batches of photos, the 16-inch MacBook Pro is the king of the hill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2cuRvu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9505885"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="LqrBux"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Laptops 2020: HP Elite Dragonfly (2020)" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xYuQyOzRJyiif2SGm9W6UBSqfUc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19951340/akrales_200507_4005_0212.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The HP Elite Dragonfly is a great business laptop.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="XU9ktC"&gt;12. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/9/21247274/hp-elite-dragonfly-2020-review-tile-test-specs-price-features"&gt;HP Elite Dragonfly&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="t0EL7n"&gt;The best business laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="MrOD1p"&gt;If you’re a business professional and money is no object for you or your company, you can’t do better than the HP Elite Dragonfly. The 2020 model is the first Dragonfly that features HP’s super-secure SureView Reflect technology, which tints the screen so that snoops can’t see what you’re doing while you’re working in public. When it’s not tinted, the display gets quite bright (over 700 nits) and has great viewing angles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OzVcoU"&gt;The new Dragonfly is also the first laptop to include a built-in Tile tracker. That means if you lose the device, you can use the Tile smartphone app to set off an alarm (if it’s in Bluetooth range) or locate it anywhere in the world using Tile’s crowd-finding network. The tracker can work for a limited time even when the laptop is off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yXS6n7"&gt;Almost everything else about the Dragonfly is good; it has some of the best battery life of any laptop on the market (we got over 11 hours), a sleek and stunning 2-in-1 design, and an exceptional keyboard. Plus, it incorporates sustainable material, including ocean-bound plastics and recycled DVDs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IEHKpz"&gt;The Dragonfly is pricey, and there are cheaper business laptops that will suit the needs of most professionals just fine. But if you’re looking for the best of the best, it’s the unambiguous winner. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="QuxuHo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9505910"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="Vr5Tg8"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Laptops 2020: Lenovo Chromebook Duet" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M79QGj6leDzJdmoI3tnqqQRv7Cc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19978535/mchin_200512_4018_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Lenovo Chromebook Duet is a great option for budget shoppers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="MIUCfV"&gt;13. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21262694/lenovo-chromebook-duet-review-tablet-chromebook-chrome-os-price"&gt;Lenovo Chromebook Duet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="WpIKDR"&gt;The best laptop for students&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="5khaPj"&gt;Lenovo’s Chromebook Duet is a great convertible laptop for kids, or anyone who wants a reliable secondary driver for browsing and games. It’s a nice-looking, well-made 10-inch device that comes with a detachable keyboard and kickstand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FV5DZN"&gt;The Duet is tailor-made to be used around the house and on the go, weighing just 2.03 pounds and delivering over 11 hours of battery life. Its MediaTek processor isn’t designed to shoulder heavy loads, but it’s just fine for browsing in a couple tabs, watching Netflix, or playing Android games — it even handles photo editing pretty well. The Duet also features a new “tablet mode” for Chrome OS, which supports an Android-inspired gesture navigation system and a unique Chrome layout optimized for tablet use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XiBrWO"&gt;The Chromebook Duet is an absolute steal for its low price, and is the Chromebook to buy if you’re on a tight budget. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GSFbIW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9505920"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="hvT0ep"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Laptop 2021: Razer Book 13" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fe8-f1VUQmxBbLTr9bDvEZgu_z4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22290553/akrales_210203_4381_0116.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Razer Book 13 proves that Razer is cut out for more than just gaming rigs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="g8zMV8"&gt;14. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22287698/razer-book-13-review-design-specs-price-features"&gt;Razer Book 13&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sky6IZ"&gt;A stylish, powerful productivity laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="1AVfKp"&gt;Razer is best known for its gaming laptops, but the company is making a big splash in the business and productivity space with its new Razer Book 13. At 0.6 inches thick and 3.09 pounds, the Book 13 is a portable workstation with a gorgeous and sturdy aluminum build. It features a good port selection including Thunderbolt 4, USB-A, HDMI 2.0 and a microSD slot, and it’s one of very few non-gaming laptops out there to come with a per-key RGB keyboard. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cAI01n"&gt;On the inside, this laptop is even more impressive. Its powerful chip did better than any other Windows laptop of its size on our Premiere Pro media export test. And while the Book 13 isn’t a gaming laptop, it delivers some of the best gaming performance I’ve ever seen from integrated graphics — it can even run &lt;em&gt;Shadow of the Tomb Raider&lt;/em&gt; over 30fps. While the Razer Book 13’s high price means it won’t be ideal for everyone, it’s still an outstanding laptop all around, combining a high-quality chassis with powerful productivity performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="DRST2I"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10375007"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="eEK1Gs"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Laptop 2021: Lenovo Yoga 9i" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2vNNkwrX84kygHr3-kitt7jV-UY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22651293/akrales_20210609_4596_0120.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Lenovo Yoga 9i is a portable entertainment machine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="zaTcIA"&gt;15. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22569871/lenovo-yoga-9i-14-inch-laptop-review"&gt;Lenovo Yoga 9i&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="DdByBe"&gt;The best multimedia laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="3TMlQz"&gt;Most thin and light laptops share one significant weakness — thin, tinny audio. That’s not the case with the Lenovo Yoga 9i. This 14-inch convertible has a rotating soundbar in its hinge, meaning that no matter how it’s positioned, the speakers face outwards. You can expect clear, booming sound whether you’re using the 9i in tablet, tent, or clamshell mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bd1MYR"&gt;There’s a lot more to like as well. You get an excellent 1080p touch display and a built-in stylus for easy artwork and note-taking. The 11th-Gen processors deliver satisfactory performance and all-day battery life. The audio quality, screen, and convertible form factor all add up to an unbeatable machine for multimedia entertainment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JHuWqw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10689258"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="LWsjh3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="AOUkel"&gt; Related:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lcntiD"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Samsung Galaxy Book Pro and Pro 360 first look: OLED for $999|101876" data-volume-uuid="22d4ac801" data-volume-id="101876" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-248" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21250695/best-laptops"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21250695/best-laptops</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-06T13:00:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-06T13:00:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>Valve Steam Deck hands-on: the Nintendo Switch of PC gaming</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W0oPJASTsfRe4c8OXQfF_IoDL0A=/0x0:1620x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69689351/STEAMDECK_THUMB_Textless.8.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Reservations are already sold out through mid-2022&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="IOVusn"&gt;I have held the Steam Deck, and I’m nearly a believer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p-large-text" id="Fl49DU"&gt;Not quite, but I like what I see. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sBOuVy"&gt;Three weeks after PC gaming giant &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578783/valve-steam-deck-gaming-handheld-pc"&gt;Valve surprise-announced its own $400 portable game console&lt;/a&gt;, I flew to the company’s headquarters in Bellevue, Washington, for a whirlwind tour of the company’s latest prototypes — and a chance to compare them to the Nintendo Switch and an earlier AMD-powered handheld gaming system, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/1/18/22237379/aya-neo-gpd-win-3-nintendo-switch-gaming-pc-handheld-specs-comparison"&gt;the Aya Neo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xaJj4h"&gt;I logged in with my Steam account, picked up &lt;em&gt;The Witcher 3&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Control &lt;/em&gt;right where I left off weeks or months ago on my desktop gaming PC, and chewed through a few demons in &lt;em&gt;Doom Eternal&lt;/em&gt; with thumbsticks, precision touchpads, and gyroscopic aiming. While I didn’t get answers to burning questions like how seamlessly you can install your own games, how the model with slower eMMC storage works, or how well it works outdoors, I was absolutely able to feel how comfortable this portable might be and how much power it has on tap. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4ZZRVe"&gt;Going in, we knew to expect performance far ahead of a Nintendo Switch but not nearly that of a next-gen game console &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578917/valve-steam-deck-nintendo-switch-xbox-series-x-ps5-spec-comparison"&gt;since the Steam Deck has slightly less than half the raw graphical muscle&lt;/a&gt; of even Microsoft’s entry-level Xbox Series S. But since it only has to power 720p gaming, not 1440p or even 1080p, you may get a surprising amount of bang for your four hundred bucks: I was able to turn up demanding sections of &lt;em&gt;The Witcher 3&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Control &lt;/em&gt;to medium spec without feeling uncomfortable. That’s a full graphical tier higher than the founder’s edition Aya Neo, where I’m typically playing those games on lowest settings and sometimes still bogging down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Nintendo Switch atop a Steam Deck, showing its similar design and array of ports." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VkAJ9fDcfINBpd4Mb5WPvDbXCH4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22766268/shollister_210805_4698_0010.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nintendo Switch atop a Steam Deck, showing its similar design and array of ports.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UoBJ6Y"&gt;What I didn’t necessarily envision when I walked into Valve’s lobby: just how gigantic the Steam Deck looks next to a Nintendo Switch — and yet, how much more comfortable it is to hold. While it just barely fits into a deep cargo pants pocket (if you can call “bulges out in every direction” a fit), I now believe Valve when it says the Deck was sculpted for long play sessions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="srpqhS"&gt;The first time I picked it up, it felt like my fingers just melted into its grips and grooves, placing every control at my fingertips — including far meatier joysticks and a deeper, softer throw to its triggers than the stiff, clicky controls I’ve come to expect from the Switch and Switch-like PC competitors. I’m not sure I’m a fan of the smooth, flat-topped joysticks, though. Even though you can do some awesome gyroscopic aiming by leaving your finger on the hidden capacitive sensor there, you can already pull that same trick with the precision touchpad, and I’m not sure it’s worth the trade-off in joystick grippyness. I’d need to test more, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Close-up of the Steam Deck’s large grip jutting out, showing its rear buttons as well" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XJg2cU_YU4_m7Tvwo_EsHF93ocY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22766267/shollister_210805_4698_0008.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Those grips.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GgbqDL"&gt;While I immediately noticed the extra half-pound of weight compared to the Switch, it didn’t bug me during my brief session. The Deck may be heavier, but these prototypes seem light for their size, with a slightly hollow feeling that — come to think of it — might be polarizing. I wonder if Valve will keep it that way and if the screen finish and the plastics might improve. Indoors, I didn’t really have a clear preference between Valve’s glossy screen and the premium etched anti-glare treatment — since what you gain in anti-glare you lose in vibrancy — and I spotted a few scratches on the chassis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8kR22M"&gt;I also definitely felt some heat and battery drain, with one unit that was plugged in at the beginning of our session nearly dead after an hour and a half. Since Valve promised four hours of real-world battery life playing &lt;em&gt;Portal 2&lt;/em&gt; and up to eight hours with less demanding fare, I imagine that’s not normal. Valve couldn’t say what will specifically change between these EV2 developer units and final, but that build quality is still being improved. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pyAKA1"&gt;(Valve told us after publish that these units just came out of a previous 1.5 hour session with a different group of journalists, which would definitely help explain that, and it’s true that the very first photo I shot of the Steam Deck at the beginning of my session showed a battery indicator that wasn’t completely topped off.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bg1Mxx"&gt;And Valve was upfront that it’s definitely still working out some software bugs, like the occasional freeze or how &lt;em&gt;Prey&lt;/em&gt; suddenly decided I was going to have a mouse cursor atop my screen in the middle of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nVu15SNm6Lu4rjJDCKCCW_VJmmE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22766266/shollister_210805_4698_0007.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The flat top on that joystick hides a capacitive sensor, so the Deck knows when your thumb is there.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1eOGpD"&gt;There’s a lot I really wasn’t able to do in an hour and a half at Valve’s HQ yesterday, like dig in deep on the new SteamOS (though I do like how much more streamlined it looks and how you can easily see which games you’ve got on an SD card and the internal drive), try any online or multiplayer gaming, or hook it up to a bigger monitor. The team also wouldn’t let us tear it down — I asked! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LvmWnF"&gt;But I was able to get some partial answers to some lingering questions and a promise that this won’t be the last look at the Steam Deck ahead of its late-2021 / early-2022 launch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yIApwt"&gt;As one example, Valve says it’s planning to produce its own video to explain exactly what it means to open up the Steam Deck and access the internals, because that’s definitely a thing the company’s planning to let you do. (It has Philips-head screws.) We’d already heard &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22589033/valve-steam-deck-pc-screen-performance-target-30hz-gameplay-upgradeable-ssd"&gt;you can swap the SSD&lt;/a&gt;, but reparability is very much on the company’s mind as well. Valve’s Greg Coomer says the company has a complete set of nuanced answers to your burning questions there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XzvXiG"&gt;You might also remember that Valve plans to offer a docking station for the Steam Deck to easily output to a TV, and while that’s still in the works, the team says it’s hoping to ship that alongside the portable. It’s possible you might be able to order one alongside the Deck, though not for certain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="This small wedge is not the dock, just a little stand Valve mocked up." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1_jfOT2tYkbw-qtOIhW3jsW78ts=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22766264/shollister_210805_4698_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This small wedge is not the dock, just a little stand Valve mocked up.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="i38KBD"&gt;You’ll be able to browse websites from the Steam Deck, adding icons for your favorites to your Steam library the same way you can technically add any generic Windows app to the Steam launcher today. And while Valve isn’t promising it for sure, the team says it’s “in active discussions” with anti-cheat makers about getting compatibility with Proton, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578879/valve-steam-deck-handheld-pc-windows-support"&gt;unlocking games like &lt;em&gt;Apex Legends, Destiny 2, Fortnite, PUBG&lt;/em&gt;, and others that won’t run&lt;/a&gt; without that anti-cheat software. “We think we’re going to have that for launch,” said Valve’s Erik Peterson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jj8Krt"&gt;The precision touchpads still have the same kind of quirky, audible haptic feedback as they did in the Steam Controller. “We haven’t tried to make them play songs, but I’m sure you could if you tried,” said one Valve team member. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cJyLtr"&gt;With games that rely on the Vulkan API for graphics performance, Valve will be pre-compiling the shaders and including them when you first download and install game files, which could speed up first-time game launches. In this prototype phase, that can take a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="zVO3px"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Why the Steam Deck won’t&amp;amp;nbsp;flop&amp;amp;nbsp;like Valve’s Steam Machines","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/18/22579747/valve-steam-deck-steam-machines-editorial"},{"title":"Valve’s new Steam Deck can run Windows and turn into a handheld Xbox","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578879/valve-steam-deck-handheld-pc-windows-support"},{"title":"How does Valve’s Steam Deck compare to the Nintendo Switch, Xbox Series X, and PlayStation 5?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578917/valve-steam-deck-nintendo-switch-xbox-series-x-ps5-spec-comparison"},{"title":"Valve’s Steam Deck: all the news about the new gaming handheld","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22579493/valve-steam-deck-gaming-handheld-pc"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="MBFJ0F"&gt;The team brushed off questions about whether Valve would bring any new games to the Steam Deck or whether it’s going to be profitable — “We’re not going to dive into this and lose a bunch of money” — but they did &lt;em&gt;strongly&lt;/em&gt; suggest to me that they wouldn’t make any games exclusive to portables the way they made &lt;em&gt;Half-Life: Alyx&lt;/em&gt; exclusive to VR, saying they don’t think about the Steam Deck’s inputs the same way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G70Bzr"&gt;While the team believes some game manufacturers might specifically optimize their controls for portables, Valve says it didn’t design the Steam Deck in terms of giving the player &lt;em&gt;hands, &lt;/em&gt;even though the Deck has buttons under eight of your fingers and can sense your thumb position. It was more about having more buttons for PC gamers and developers to map, and one team member brought up how the Xbox Elite controller gives you extra paddles so you don’t have to take your fingers off the sticks. “It’s more about quality of inputs and quantity of inputs,” said one team member.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="ehx7mW"&gt;But Coomer did light up when I suggested maybe we could see the Steam Deck’s custom APU in a standalone VR headset, like the Oculus Quest. He said he loved the question. “We’re not ready to say anything about it, but it would run well in that environment, with the TDP necessary... it’s very relevant to us and our future plans,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UZPXzz"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0l1oEL"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, 2:22PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Valve tells us the reason we saw low battery life was because of an earlier group briefing, so they weren’t at full charge when we began. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IxCEZm"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;We played Doom Eternal, not Doom Ultimate, which would be &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://doomwiki.org/wiki/The_Ultimate_Doom"&gt;&lt;em&gt;a far less impressive showing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dm7Nd0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22612886/valve-steam-deck-handheld-gaming-pc-hands-on-preview"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22612886/valve-steam-deck-handheld-gaming-pc-hands-on-preview</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-06T12:31:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-06T12:31:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>Vergecast: Pixel 6 preview and Apple’s new system for detecting illegal imagery </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Google Pixel 6 Pro" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0R4-IhzTNf9lWDuwVvcHhRLUC88=/162x0:1935x1182/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69689141/Google_Pixel_6_Pro__Alt_Angle_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7pDclY"&gt;Every Friday, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; publishes our flagship podcast, &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/the-vergecast"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, where co-hosts Nilay Patel and Dieter Bohn discuss the week in tech news with the reporters and editors covering the biggest stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="O8bf3R"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/1f065kY3QYR0aeHqCvDOLI" width="100%" height="232" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ht2RNv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iinfZk"&gt;This week on &lt;em&gt;The Vergecast,&lt;/em&gt; Nilay and Dieter start the show with &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; managing editor Alex Cranz to discuss Google’s surprise preview of its next phone — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605094/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-specs-ai-ml"&gt;the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro &lt;/a&gt;— along with a new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609924/pixel-6-google-tensor-soc-chip-cpu-gpu-samsung-apple"&gt;custom-designed Tensor processor&lt;/a&gt;. The crew gives their first impressions of Google’s take on an “ultra high end” phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UxWWrE"&gt;In the second half of the show, &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; policy editor Russell Brandom reports back from a briefing call with Apple about its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611721/apple-csam-child-abuse-scanning-hash-system-ncmec"&gt;new system meant to detect child abuse imagery&lt;/a&gt; by scanning photos stored on iPhones and iCloud. The &lt;em&gt;Vergecast&lt;/em&gt; crew discusses how secure this method is and the precedent it sets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Wbgi9"&gt;You can listen to the full discussion here or in your preferred podcast player. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T0QadN"&gt;Stories discussed in this episode: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="hh0hZv"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22600423/vaccine-mandates-federal-state-google-facebook"&gt;Vaccine carrots only got us so far — now, it’s time for sticks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9Ozz0x"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609757/new-york-auto-show-2021-canceled-delta-variant-covid"&gt;New York Auto Show canceled as delta variant spreads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="inlXF5"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22607882/key-to-nyc-pass-covid-vaccine-proof-new-york-city"&gt;NYC’s Key vaccination requirement for indoor dining can be met with an app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xkCLcM"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22610865/yelp-vaccination-policies-businesses-staff-customers"&gt;Yelp will let businesses list their vaccination policies&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dAlm3v"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611045/moderna-third-shot-covid-19-vaccine-booster-delta-variants-coronavirus"&gt;Moderna says a third shot of its COVID-19 vaccine may be needed to protect against variants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="z0hdw5"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605094/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-specs-ai-ml"&gt;This is the Pixel 6, Google’s take on an ‘ultra high end’ phone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qFESgP"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609924/pixel-6-google-tensor-soc-chip-cpu-gpu-samsung-apple"&gt;Google’s Tensor chip is only the first step toward truly great Pixel phones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kJUWJv"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611305/apple-scan-photos-iphones-icloud-child-abuse-imagery-neuralmatch"&gt;Apple will reportedly scan photos stored on iPhones and iCloud for child abuse imagery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qhjC1g"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611721/apple-csam-child-abuse-scanning-hash-system-ncmec"&gt;Apple reveals new efforts to fight child abuse imagery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="58fBKM"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22609444/google-nest-cam-indoor-floodlight-doorbell-price-specs-news"&gt;Google’s new Nest cameras and doorbell have lower prices and more smarts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0cv6zz"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608812/oppo-next-generation-under-screen-camera-tech-announced"&gt;Oppo announces ‘next-generation’ under-display selfie camera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="iQ3Qmf"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611234/apple-airpower-wireless-charger-working-prototype"&gt;Here’s a closer look at Apple’s canceled AirPower wireless charger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hYC4IN"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22607730/apple-mac-pro-amd-radeo-pro-gpu-options"&gt;Apple updates Mac Pro GPUs with new AMD Radeon options&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3JFaNO"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22607386/apple-magic-keyboard-touch-id-standalone-seperate-price-release-date-m1-chip"&gt;You can get a Touch ID-equipped Magic Keyboard without buying a whole iMac now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="V1keRL"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/30/22602017/elon-musk-tim-cook-apple-ceo-demand-tesla-acquisition"&gt;Elon Musk and Apple deny wild story that he tried to replace Tim Cook &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="glNVAR"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609564/facebook-reality-lab-reverse-passthrough-vr-prototype-research-siggraph"&gt;Facebook can project your eyes onto a VR headset, and it’s exactly as uncanny as it sounds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="27TO7M"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609944/nyt-crossword-puzzle-puz-file-format"&gt;NYT crossword puzzle no longer works in third-party apps, crosses puzzle solvers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="XzmJaw"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609212/hbo-max-podcast-exclusive-batman-audio-jeffrey-wright"&gt;HBO Max is getting its own exclusive podcasts, starting with Batman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RSxlTb"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608577/att-directv-tpg-deal-u-verse-att-tv-new-company"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T has officially spun off DirecTV, which is now its own business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="C5FP2t"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608265/t-mobile-sprint-lte-network-shutdown-2022"&gt;T-Mobile confirms it will shut down Sprint’s LTE network next year&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="ZUgT6H"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"The Vergecast","description":"The podcast you need to make sense of the week in tech news","label":"Subscribe","url":"https://pod.link/430333725"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22613001/pixel-6-preview-apple-iphone-csam-detection-vergecast-podcast-461"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22613001/pixel-6-preview-apple-iphone-csam-detection-vergecast-podcast-461</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Marino</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-06T12:01:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-06T12:01:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple VP acknowledges concerns about new scanning feature in internal memo</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VSGhQl7q43Qpftf2KZ6WSgH_o0I=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69688995/acstro_190902_apple_event_0004.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OrjUON"&gt;Apple’s &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fchild-safety%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F8%2F6%2F22612934%2Fapple-vp-memo-concerns-privacy-new-scanning-photos-images-ios" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;forthcoming feature&lt;/a&gt; that will scan iOS devices for images of child abuse is an “important mission,” a software vice president at the company wrote in an internal memo. First reported by&lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/08/06/apple-internal-memo-icloud-photo-scanning-concerns/"&gt; &lt;em&gt;9to5 Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the memo by Sebastian Marineau-Mes acknowledges that the new protections have some people “worried about the implications” but that the company will “maintain Apple’s deep commitment to user privacy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8Ig9yv"&gt;As part of its Expanded Protections for Children, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611721/apple-csam-child-abuse-scanning-hash-system-ncmec"&gt;Apple plans to scan images&lt;/a&gt; on iPhones and other devices before they are uploaded to iCloud. If it finds an image that matches one in the database of the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children (NCMEC), a human at Apple will review the image to confirm whether it contains child pornography. If it’s confirmed, NCMEC will be notified and the user’s account will be disabled. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3HB3oD"&gt;The announcement raised concerns among privacy advocates who questioned how Apple could prevent the system from being exploited by bad actors. The Electronic Frontier Foundation &lt;a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2021/08/apples-plan-think-different-about-encryption-opens-backdoor-your-private-life"&gt;said in a statement&lt;/a&gt; that “it’s impossible to build a client-side scanning system that can only be used for sexually explicit images sent or received by children” and that the system, however well-intended, “will break key promises of the messenger’s encryption itself and open the door to broader abuses.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7BFvDx"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;, Marineau-Mes wrote in the memo that the project involved “deep cross-functional commitment” across the company that “delivers tools to protect children, but also maintain Apple’s deep commitment to user privacy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uGfQad"&gt;Apple did not immediately reply to a request for comment Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22612934/apple-vp-memo-concerns-privacy-new-scanning-photos-images-ios"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22612934/apple-vp-memo-concerns-privacy-new-scanning-photos-images-ios</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-06T11:57:07-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-06T11:57:07-04:00</updated>
    <title>Fires are growing worse at night</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="California wildfire continues" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/90ETo9H41r6YZJL36h9EbyUgEE8=/8x0:4928x3280/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69688923/1234478675.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Flames rise during Dixie Fire near Chico in Greenville, California, United States on August 5, 2021.&amp;nbsp; | Photo by Neal Waters / Anadolu Agency via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uZUxIR"&gt;The nights have gotten hotter and drier in the Western US, which is making it harder to stop wildfires. Fires burn later into the night and pick back up earlier in the morning than they used to, firefighters say. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vltxeY"&gt;New research backs up what firefighters have seen and finds that there’s been a pretty dramatic shift in the night air in just the past few decades. The night air’s drying power, or vapor pressure deficit, has risen sharply in the past 40 years — as much as 50 percent above the previous average in the 1980s in the southern Sierra Nevada. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XWB95g"&gt;“I was surprised—it’s unusual to see geophysical data change that dramatically,” Andrew Chiodi, a research scientist at the University of Washington, said in a &lt;a href="https://news.agu.org/press-release/dryer-warmer-night-air-is-worsening-some-western-wildfires/"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; yesterday. Chiodi was the lead author of the new research recently published in the j&lt;a href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021GL092830"&gt;ournal &lt;em&gt;Geophysical Research Letters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="FhQXpX"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Nighttime is an important time in fire management.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eLvgkV"&gt;Hot, dry weather parches the landscape, creating more fuel to feed fires. In the evening in the Western US, temperatures traditionally get a little cooler and humidity rises. Vegetation soaks up some of that moisture, making it a less volatile fuel for wildfires. That would give firefighters a little bit of a breather at night or &lt;a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/one-climate-change-wildfire-risk-lurks-in-the-dark/"&gt;an opportunity to get ahead&lt;/a&gt; of the blaze while it moves at a slower pace.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FkqK3g"&gt;“Nighttime is an important time in fire management. When fires die down at night it gives firefighters a chance to rest, move equipment and strategize,” Chiodi said. But they’re losing that advantage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iQ3ZiW"&gt;During the evening of August 4th, the Dixie Fire &lt;a href="https://www.fire.ca.gov/incidents/2021/7/14/dixie-fire/?fbclid=IwAR0wm041z9XtBh_4VCdMDR36CRfFw-4_gTJr7I2KUjSvDO77PJZagqMQZX0"&gt;grew explosively overnight&lt;/a&gt;. The inferno &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/fires-environment-and-nature-california-13faa6976260a4a9e10906c70b4ed2d0"&gt;destroyed&lt;/a&gt; much of the town of Greenville, a community that dates back all the way to California’s Gold Rush. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PG4iqI"&gt;“We lost Greenville tonight,” local Rep. Doug LaMalfa (R-CA) said as he held back tears in a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/watch/?v=423084935691083"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; posted to Facebook on August 5th. “There’s just no words.” The fire stayed active — and “very active” in some parts — overnight again on August 5th and was still &lt;a href="https://www.fire.ca.gov/incidents/2021/7/14/dixie-fire/?fbclid=IwAR0wm041z9XtBh_4VCdMDR36CRfFw-4_gTJr7I2KUjSvDO77PJZagqMQZX0"&gt;just 35 percent contained&lt;/a&gt; as of August 6th morning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qgRgub"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I'd say the majority of downtown Greenville is completely destroyed. All I see standing on the main st. Is a dollar general. My heart is broken for this beautiful little town. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/dixiefire?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#dixiefire&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/G8kVMZdanF"&gt;pic.twitter.com/G8kVMZdanF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Stuart Palley (@stuartpalley) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/stuartpalley/status/1423162562397437962?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 5, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KP3S8P"&gt;LaMalfa has a history of &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2018/jul/31/california-wildfire-climate-change-carr-fire"&gt;skepticism on climate change&lt;/a&gt;. But &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/7/25/22592004/wildfires-climate-change-reconciliation-bill"&gt;evidence is piling up&lt;/a&gt; showing that California’s fire seasons are growing longer and more intense as the world heats up. &lt;a href="https://climate.nasa.gov/blog/3066/the-climate-connections-of-a-record-fire-year-in-the-us-west/"&gt;2020 smashed the record&lt;/a&gt; for the most land burned in a single season, more than doubling the previous record. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5N6BYk"&gt;“We’re seeing truly frightening fire behavior ... We have a lot of veteran firefighters who have served for twenty, thirty years and have never seen behavior like this,” said Plumas National Forest supervisor Chris Carlton during an August 5th &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/plumascountysheriff/"&gt;evening update&lt;/a&gt; on the Dixie Fire, which he described as “extreme.” “We really are in uncharted territory around some of these extreme large fires,” Carlton said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="edP0MX"&gt;While there are other factors at play that researchers still don’t fully understand, climate change is also playing a role in making fires more devastating at night. &lt;a href="https://oehha.ca.gov/epic/changes-climate/annual-air-temperature"&gt;Average temperatures in California&lt;/a&gt; have risen faster than the global average. There’s been an even steeper rise at night than during the day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fh94t9"&gt;Nights are actually getting hotter &lt;a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/gcb.15336"&gt;across much of the world&lt;/a&gt;. There are apocalyptic images of a &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/europe-middle-east-fires-environment-and-nature-turkey-95c9f86c10d315c94b73f32c965f6853"&gt;coal-fired power plant flaming&lt;/a&gt; in the night — on the same evening that the Dixie Fire tore through Greenville — as Turkey battles catastrophic blazes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="7qEWhb"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Apocalyptic scenes from Turkey’s Milas where wildfires are burning a coal based thermal plant &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;People are concerned that the coal also would cause further air pollution and a separate environmental disaster&lt;a href="https://t.co/YEd98kW5Ow"&gt;pic.twitter.com/YEd98kW5Ow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ragıp Soylu (@ragipsoylu) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ragipsoylu/status/1423012967919071233?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 4, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="b6PB25"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22612874/wildfires-worse-night-hot-dry-california-us-west"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22612874/wildfires-worse-night-hot-dry-california-us-west</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-06T11:36:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-06T11:36:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google considered buying ‘some or all’ of Epic during Fortnite clash, court documents say</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bbHLGhzaAhz_-B_9bEMD4CbvBCg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69688800/acastro_20200818_1777_epicApple_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LrXeKy"&gt;Google considered buying Epic Games as the companies sparred over Epic’s &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; Android app, according to &lt;a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.cand.364325/gov.uscourts.cand.364325.159.5.pdf"&gt;newly unsealed court filings&lt;/a&gt;. Last night, Google lifted some of its redactions in Epic’s antitrust complaint against Google, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22583467/epic-fortnite-google-play-store-lawsuit-amended-complaint-filed"&gt;Epic amended and refiled&lt;/a&gt; last month. The complaint still omits many details about Google’s dealings with specific companies, but the new details reflect internal Google communications about competition on the Android platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="INWwJm"&gt;Epic claims Google was threatened by its plans to sidestep Google’s official Play Store commission by distributing &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; through other channels, and in an unredacted segment, it quotes an internal Google document calling Epic’s plans a “contagion” threatening Google. Here’s Epic’s description of the situation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="CPWveA"&gt;Google has gone so far as to share its monopoly profits with business partners to secure their agreement to fence out competition, has developed a series of internal projects to address the “contagion” it perceived from efforts by Epic and others to offer consumers and developers competitive alternatives, and has even contemplated buying some or all of Epic to squelch this threat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="fS8Kau"&gt;The internal messages discussing that possibility remain secret, and the complaint doesn’t indicate that Google ever reached out to Epic with these plans. It also doesn’t give a timeframe for the discussion — although it presumably happened after Epic started its plans to launch &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; on Android in 2018. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1423677740851531781"&gt;In a tweet&lt;/a&gt; after this article’s publication, Epic CEO Tim Sweeney said the plan “was unbeknownst to us at the time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="HATbtk"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This was unbeknownst to us at the time, and because of the court’s protective order we’re just finding out now about Google’s consideration of buying Epic to shut down our efforts to compete with Google Play.&lt;a href="https://t.co/HSS1edUrQm"&gt;https://t.co/HSS1edUrQm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Tim Sweeney (@TimSweeneyEpic) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1423677740851531781?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 6, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vptrsW"&gt;Epic has also alleged that Google offered it a “special deal” to launch &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; on the Play Store. In another unsealed section, the complaint describes a Google Play manager reaching out to Epic about its plans to sideload &lt;em&gt;Fortnite &lt;/em&gt;— and apparently admitting that sideloading is a “frankly abysmal” experience in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="a7s2R3"&gt;One manager contacted Epic’s Vice President and Co-Founder to gauge Epic’s interest in a special deal and, among other things, discussed “the experience of getting &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; on Android” via direct downloading. The manager’s call notes state that she viewed direct downloading &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; as “frankly abysmal” and “an awful experience”, and that Epic should “worry that most will not go through the 15+ steps.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Jtn6co"&gt;Another section says that “staff members have acknowledged internally that the difficulty Google imposes on consumers who wish to direct download leads to a ‘[p]oor user experience,’ in that there are ‘15+ steps to get app [via sideloading] vs 2 steps with Play or on iOS.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iXsgkm"&gt;Overall, “Google understands that the myriad barriers it erects to direct downloading have the effect of protecting its app distribution monopoly and limiting developers’ ability to distribute their apps,” Epic alleges in its complaint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="7VDskJ"&gt;In an internal document titled “Response to Epic”, a Google employee explained that the “install friction” associated with direct downloading was “not only a bad experience” for users but that Google knew “from its data that it will drastically limit [Epic’s] reach”. The document goes on to explain that “[f]uture [&lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;] updates will be challenged re: targeting, update experience via web”; that the direct downloading approach was “most associated with malicious apps”, which would be “incompatible with [Epic’s] brand/demographics”; and that “[t]he approach will create significant user confusion, since [Google Play] will still attract [billions] of users who will search for &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; and run into deadends that aren’t clear how to resolve”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="cFM5Yg"&gt;Epic’s lawsuit was recently linked with a much bigger &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22567532/google-play-store-antitrust-lawsuit-state-ag-app-fees"&gt;state antitrust complaint against Google&lt;/a&gt;. Like Epic, a group of state attorneys general alleges that Android is much less open than Google claims, saying it cuts create deliberate barriers — including Android phone features and deals with phone makers — to restrict third-party app stores and discourage downloading apps directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="zK36MC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Google has called Epic’s lawsuit “meritless”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uqMigR"&gt;Google also removed some redactions in &lt;a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.cand.364325/gov.uscourts.cand.364325.159.3.pdf"&gt;the state complaints&lt;/a&gt;, mostly relating to its internal descriptions of how Android works. In a 2017 presentation about Amazon’s App Store, for instance, Google apparently noted that “if we were honest we would admit that most users and developers aren’t consciously ‘choosing’ they are going with the default.” And in 2019, it referred to Apple and Android as “new closed internet ecosystems” that “centralized content distribution via app stores… [and] payments via app store services” — although the larger context of those remarks isn’t clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wegBHb"&gt;Google has strongly denied the claims in both suits. “The open Android ecosystem lets developers distribute apps through multiple app stores. For game developers who choose to use the Play Store, we have consistent policies that are fair to developers and keep the store safe for users,” it said in a previous comment on Epic’s amended filing. “While &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; remains available on Android, we can no longer make it available on Play because it violates our policies. We will continue to defend ourselves against these meritless claims.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IsJN2R"&gt;Epic filed lawsuits against both Apple and Google last year after it introduced a new &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; payment system that sidestepped their payment systems and in-app purchase commissions, leading both companies to kick &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; off their mobile stores. (&lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; is still available on Android devices via sideloading.) Epic’s case against Apple went to trial in May and is currently awaiting a ruling from the court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ecDgiT"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update August 6th, 1:10PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added statement and tweet from Epic CEO Tim Sweeney.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22612921/google-epic-antitrust-case-court-filings-unsealed"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22612921/google-epic-antitrust-case-court-filings-unsealed</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-06T10:13:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-06T10:13:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>New Bitcoin tax plans could stifle greener blockchain tech</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/J_DbxJX6oXJJeyM3-xmBU1CfR14=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69688305/jbareham_180313_1777__bitcoin_cryptocurrency_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hGrtts"&gt;Ongoing efforts to pass a bipartisan infrastructure bill could reshape the cryptocurrency world, as lawmakers debate new tax-reporting requirements on various parts of the blockchain system. &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2021/08/06/crypto-bitcoin-infrastructure-senate/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; is reporting&lt;/a&gt; that, on Thursday, Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen directly lobbied lawmakers to keep stronger cryptocurrency tax provisions in the infrastructure bill. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f4g880"&gt;It’s a sign of how committed the White House is to bringing cryptocurrency into the broader tax-reporting system, even as the details of the new requirements threaten to upset the delicate political balance of the infrastructure plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="c7xhHI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A broad new requirement on cryptocurrency brokers&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ehXjZp"&gt;From the beginning, the drafters of the bipartisan infrastructure framework hoped to offset the rush of new spending with $28 billion in new cryptocurrency taxes (levied over 10 years). Broadly, the tax proposals have been uncontroversial — but the details of who will bear the burden of reporting transactions have been maddeningly difficult to agree upon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bzLslD"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605917/senate-negotiators-bipartisan-infrastructure-broadband-electric-vehicles-cryptocurrency"&gt;The initial bill text released on Saturday&lt;/a&gt; placed a broad new requirement on cryptocurrency brokers to report transactions as part of their tax returns, similar to existing requirements for trading conventional assets. But the original text left the definition of a “broker” vague, potentially extending to wallet developers or miners. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WarTYF"&gt;An amendment from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/24/17606974/oregon-senator-ron-wyden-interview-internet-section-230-net-neutrality"&gt;Sens. Ron Wyden (D-OR)&lt;/a&gt;, Cynthia Lummis (R-WY), and Pat Toomey (R-PA) would explicitly exempt miners from any reporting requirements, but the amendment has yet to pass. More recently, a group of lawmakers led by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/5/18056610/facebook-mark-warner-congress-cambridge-analytica"&gt;Sen. Mark Warner (D-VA)&lt;/a&gt; has offered a slightly harsher compromise, which has gained more support in Congress but left many cryptocurrency advocates uncomfortable. In particular, advocates are concerned that the uneven reporting requirements in the Warner amendment could lead to a lasting split between different blockchain technologies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="GT9Yke"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“This is no way to make policy.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vcDiYe"&gt;Most cryptocurrency still relies on proof-of-work blockchains like Bitcoin, which require energy-intensive mining to certify new entries on the blockchain. But a new model of blockchain would allow miners to certify blocks by staking a certain amount of currency (hence “proof-of-stake”), thus allowing for faster and more complex transactions. Proof-of-stake blockchains are still less popular, but some larger coins (&lt;a href="https://electriccoin.co/blog/should-zcash-switch-from-proof-of-work-to-proof-of-stake/"&gt;most notably Zcash&lt;/a&gt;) are actively considering a switch to the new mode. Ethereum is &lt;a href="https://www.bitcoinsuisse.com/eth-2-faq"&gt;in the process of launching&lt;/a&gt; its own staked blockchain, called Ethereum 2.0 or ETH2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EsdTZ1"&gt;The Warner amendment defines “broker” to include proof-of-stake miners but not proof-of-work miners, due to the additional complexity and financial flexibility of proof-of-stake mining. But cryptocurrency groups worry that the additional regulatory burden will drive coins away from proof-of-stake systems, stifling the new innovation before it has a chance to take hold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qM9BRI"&gt;“The language in the new amendment enshrines one of many competing technologies in law,” Coin Center’s Neeraj Agrawal told&lt;em&gt; The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “It is the government picking a winner on an otherwise competitive field. And worst of all, tech policy of this magnitude is being done as last minute tax provision buried in a massive must-pass infrastructure bill. This is no way to make policy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M8t84v"&gt;The split is particularly divisive given the intense energy demands of proof-of-work mining, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22373524/cryptocurrency-climate-accord-bitcoin-carbon-footprint"&gt;a long-standing sore point for cryptocurrency&lt;/a&gt; that many had hoped proof-of-stake systems would address. In a tweet Thursday night, Sen. Wyden criticized the Warner amendment through the lens of climate policy, calling it “a government-sanctioned safe harbor for the most climate-damaging form of crypto tech.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5GfzNj"&gt;Most Bitcoin groups, including Coin Center, are now pushing for the Wyden amendment as the least damaging option, despite the White House’s lobbying. “This will not happen without your elected reps hearing from you,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/brian_armstrong/status/1423044785166864390"&gt;said Coinbase CEO Brian Armstrong&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter. “Please contact your senators and ask them to support the amendment.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22612663/infrastructure-bitcoin-tax-blockchain-proof-of-work-stake-ethereum"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22612663/infrastructure-bitcoin-tax-blockchain-proof-of-work-stake-ethereum</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
