<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2020-12-01T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-01T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-01T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Qualcomm’s new Snapdragon 888 processor will power the Android flagships of 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dHGWnY3DYG6pWSxWMVrDfyD_tRg=/0x0:4936x3291/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68042714/Snapdragon_888_Front_Chip_in_Studio__1_.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Y47fNj"&gt;Qualcomm has officially announced the Snapdragon 888 at its Snapdragon Tech Summit, offering a first look at its next-generation flagship smartphone processor. The 888 will power the next wave of 2021 Android flagships from companies like Samsung, OnePlus, LG, Sony, and more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1zmJfw"&gt;In a first for the company’s top-of-the-line 8-series chipsets, the Snapdragon 888 is making a big improvement for 5G: it’ll finally offer a fully integrated 5G modem, unlike last year’s Snapdragon 865 (which required that manufacturers include a separate modem chip inside the cramped interior of a modern smartphone).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OybY60"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The future of Android flagships is here&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="z9hHpK"&gt;The Snapdragon 888 will feature &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/19/21142381/qualcomm-x60-modem-5g-phones-faster-power-efficient-5nm-carrier"&gt;Qualcomm’s X60 modem&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.qualcomm.com/products/snapdragon-x60-5g-modem"&gt;announced earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;, which jumps to a 5nm process for better power efficiency and improvements for 5G carrier aggregation across the mmWave and sub-6GHz bands of the spectrum. Between the new 5nm architecture and the power efficiency gains from an integrated modem, the new chip looks to offer some substantial battery improvements when it comes to 5G. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BvxQx3"&gt;In addition to the 5G improvements, Qualcomm also teased several other advances coming to the Snapdragon 888, including the company’s sixth-gen AI Engine (running on a “redesigned” Qualcomm Hexagon processor), which promises a big jump in performance and power efficiency for AI tasks. The Snapdragon 888 also will feature the “most significant upgrade in Qualcomm Adreno GPU performance,” though specifics on what kind of improvements are coming have yet to be announced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="58DDc6"&gt;Lastly, Qualcomm previewed new photography features that the Snapdragon 888 will enable, including the ability to shoot roughly 120 photos per second at 12-megapixel resolution, thanks to the updated ISP (which is up to 35 percent faster). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4He7pw"&gt;Per Qualcomm’s usual practice, today’s announcement is just a first look at the Snapdragon 888. A more comprehensive overview of the specs and improvements being offered with this year’s chipset will arrive in the Snapdragon Tech Summit’s second day of keynotes, on December 2nd. And given Qualcomm’s near-total dominance when it comes to providing chips for almost every major smartphone in the US, the debut of the Snapdragon 888 isn’t just a first look at Qualcomm’s latest advances: it’s a preview of what to expect from phones like Samsung’s Galaxy S21 lineup and other top Android phones for 2021, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1vcAwx"&gt;We’ll have additional details on the Snapdragon 888 tomorrow as the summit continues, so check back for more information soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uwtJRk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hZVcYT"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21678359/qualcomm-snapdragon-888-processor-first-look-5g-performance-ai-photography"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21678359/qualcomm-snapdragon-888-processor-first-look-5g-performance-ai-photography</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-01T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-01T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Nest Thermostat review: more simple than smart</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Google’s budget thermostat is inexpensive but limited&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="Yny6lM"&gt;Ten years ago, Nest introduced its first smart thermostat, the Nest Learning Thermostat, and showed the world what a smart thermostat is capable of. You can use it to automatically program your thermostat’s schedule, control it with your smartphone or a voice assistant, integrate it with other smart devices in your home like smoke detectors, and have it adjust itself for when you’ve left the house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X0dpdD"&gt;The company’s latest model, the simply named $129.99 Nest Thermostat, does away with a lot of the more advanced features in favor of a simpler, more basic design and feature set. But while Google’s goal is to appeal to those who haven’t yet upgraded their ancient programmable thermostat, it’s stripped out a lot of what makes a connected thermostat smart to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="J9XMaa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:9740071"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mfhiRk-6tKSE5LBu_ApoSrHWuxE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22053786/dseifert_201115_4301_0002.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can control a handful of functions on the thermostat itself, but most settings are found in the Google Home smartphone app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="KS4uKi"&gt;The most obvious thing Google did was change the design and functionality of the thermostat itself. The Nest Thermostat doesn’t have the signature rotating ring of Nest’s prior models. Instead, you use a touch strip on the right side to adjust temperature and navigate the interface. The touch strip works fine, and the thermostat will emit an audible click as you swipe up or down, but it’s far less satisfying to use than the dampened ring on the Nest Learning Thermostat. I do prefer it to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/3/18646398/ecobee-smartthermostat-review-alexa-announcement-price-specs-features"&gt;Ecobee’s clumsy touchscreen&lt;/a&gt;, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vklN4D"&gt;Also different are the materials: the Nest Thermostat is made entirely of plastic that you can get in four different colors, as opposed to the metal finishes of the older models. Aesthetics are certainly a personal preference, but I like the look of the brushed metal of the older Nest models much better. It’s clear that Google’s changes here were to bring the price down and make it more accessible than the flagship model that retails for $250 (though it can be found on sale quite regularly). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FuleJO"&gt;The front of the Nest Thermostat has a mirrored finish, with a display that shines through it when you are in front of the thermostat or interacting with it. This is not a touchscreen — all interaction on the thermostat is done through the touch strip — and most of the time, it just sits there on the wall not displaying anything. I was concerned that this mirrored finish would get quite dusty, but in the few weeks I’ve been testing the Nest Thermostat, it’s stayed clean.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4nZL8QVPk1WxC7vOwPmPlblvLhI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22053783/dseifert_201115_4301_0004.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nest’s signature rotating ring has been replaced by a touch strip on the right side.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="EEtNKi"&gt;When the screen is on, it looks like information is just floating on the mirrored front, a neat effect. It will tell you what the thermostat is currently set to, what temp it’s reading, and whether it is running the heating or cooling systems to adjust the climate in your home. Tap the side, and you can scroll through the menus to adjust modes, set a hold temperature, and view other settings, though most of the adjustments to scheduling and such are handled through the Google Home app on your smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gAlcM6"&gt;The mirrored finish is unbroken, thanks to Google’s use of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/9/30/21496318/google-soli-radar-motion-sense-rick-osterloh-pixel-5"&gt;radar-based Soli technology&lt;/a&gt; to detect your presence instead of a more traditional motion sensor. But if you look at it from the right angle, mostly from the left side, you can see where the square display is centered under the mirrored panel, breaking the illusion a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XP0irY"&gt;The Nest Thermostat doesn’t support a number of advanced features found on the higher-end model, including FarSight, which lets you see the current temp or other info from across the room. In practice, this wasn’t a problem in my home. The Nest was still able to detect my presence and light up even when I was 10 or more feet away from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zxN-ss4EkLC6BS4LqcACeIPHa3g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22053781/dseifert_201115_4301_0006.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Installing the Nest Thermostat only takes a few minutes, but you’ll have to buy the backing plate separately.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DxY-sECWccEptaLJVFhKdJQXuaA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22053780/dseifert_201115_4301_0007.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nest Thermostat uses AAA batteries instead of a built-in rechargeable one.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CG9gei"&gt;Installing the Nest Thermostat is very similar to prior models, and Google does a good job of walking you through the process with video tutorials in the app. Certain creature comforts, such as the included screwdriver, have been dropped for this model, and most frustrating of all, it doesn’t come with a backing plate to cover up the holes in the wall from your old thermostat. To get one of those, you’ll need to shell out another $15. (Older models always included it in the box.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="05VSmK"&gt;The Nest Thermostat doesn’t use the rechargeable lithium battery as other models, instead relying on two AAA batteries that Google says will last up to two years. Google also says it does use the same trickle power feature to draw energy from the HVAC system as the older model, which likely helps extend the life of those two batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3kZKNq"&gt;In all, it takes about 15 minutes to install and set up the Nest Thermostat, though you can also pay a professional to do it for you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gI1PN7fnY618Nd9YOK1eeT-ByJA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22128239/nest_thermostat_programming_3up.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Programming the Nest Thermostat is handled through the Google Home app and is very similar to a traditional programmable thermostat.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fr7qem"&gt;Set up and control of the Nest Thermostat is handled entirely through the Google Home app; you can’t do anything with it in the old Nest app. That may be frustrating for existing Nest customers looking for a single place to monitor all of their devices, but for most new owners, it doesn’t matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V1bQ0j"&gt;Scheduling the Nest Thermostat is significantly different than how older Nest models work. Instead of relying on the thermostat to determine your patterns and automatically schedule itself, you are prompted to choose temperatures and time blocks when you set it up. This is very similar to how a traditional programmable thermostat works: you put in what times you’re home, what times you aren’t, and when you go to bed, and then set temps for each respective mode. You can also add custom time blocks for more granular controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZwdWHE2JHNPzsKFhdN2C0b_AJo4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22128242/Screenshot_20201129_114255_Home.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can view stats on your system’s usage and efficiency through the app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Wxk6ys"&gt;This method will be very familiar to those coming from an old programmable thermostat, but it makes the Nest Thermostat feel quite limited and dumb compared to other smart thermostats. For example, it will not adapt itself if your schedule happens to deviate from your programming because you’re home at a different time than usual. Right now, we are home a lot more than we typically are, thanks to pandemic-related lockdowns, but the Nest Thermostat sticks to its programmed schedule no matter what.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gU00QL"&gt;The Nest Thermostat does have the ability to go into its energy-saving Eco mode when you aren’t home by using its own presence detection, geolocation on your phone, or a combination of the two. If the system doesn’t see any activity for an hour and your phone location is reporting that you’re not home, it will automatically switch to the Eco preset to save energy. It’s odd that it can’t do the opposite for when you are home unexpectedly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rEVJ9A"&gt;Another area where the Nest Thermostat is inferior to other models is in support for remote sensors. It just doesn’t support them; the only temperature it will set itself to is what it reads from its wall-mounted position. Both the Nest Learning Thermostat and Ecobee line of thermostats can adjust the system based on sensors elsewhere in the home, which provides much more flexibility and control over the climate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7F0aWo"&gt;The Nest Thermostat isn’t completely dumb. In addition to the smartphone control, you can use either the Google Assistant or Amazon’s Alexa to adjust the thermostat via voice. It also has built-in energy-saving and comfort features from the other Nest models, including the ability to preheat or cool the home before a scheduled time block starts or circulating the air with the fan to more efficiently use air conditioning. It will also tell you how long it will take the system to reach your selected temperature and will award leaf icons when you program it efficiently — though in my home, the only way to get a leaf was to set it uncomfortably cool or warm. It will also prompt you to change filters and do other maintenance to keep the system running efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dkjO2iH55XPgihgwBa32MIZExIA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22053785/dseifert_201115_4301_0003.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nest Thermostat works with most HVAC systems.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="QkUw4s"&gt;In all, the Nest Thermostat is a fine connected thermostat that lets you program and control it with your phone easily. It also can save you money on your heating and cooling bills, thanks to its Eco modes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="PL2DNB"&gt;But it also feels like a smart thermostat from years ago and isn’t as helpful or flexible as other options, even within Nest’s own lineup. The main appeal for the Nest Thermostat is its price: at $130 and even less if you have a rebate available from your local power company, it’s a much easier pill to swallow than Nest’s fancier models or even Ecobee’s options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="Ic6PS8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9740182"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JoYFrE"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21725036/google-nest-thermostat-2020-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21725036/google-nest-thermostat-2020-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-01T09:54:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-01T09:54:01-05:00</updated>
    <title>The best Cyber Monday deals that are still happening</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/A7Lr5YMWFblzi49LBJtVT60pcb8=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68042448/4311_Cyber_Monday_Still_Get.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7QychB"&gt;Cyber Monday may be a thing of the past, but some of its best deals are still happening. Many retailers will keep some of them going a little longer this week, now dubbed “Cyber Week.” Between now and the winter holidays, you can expect the non-stop barrage of deals to slow down a bit. However, in an effort to keep you coming back to snag those last-minute gifts, some stores may reintroduce this year’s best deals at a moment’s notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ypw7fr"&gt;Below, you’ll find a few good deals on wireless noise-canceling headphones, earbuds, video games, and more. If you like where a price is at, it may be a good idea to make a purchase now, as these deals could end any moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qHCSuC"&gt;We’ll be doing our best to keep this post updated during Cyber Week, including adding new deals when they arrive, and striking through expired deals. And if you’ve been around these parts before and are just looking for what’s new, you’ll find those deals at the top of the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="X2yB5s"&gt;Latest Deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="0jzSZj"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08KB5FBH8/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The Nintendo Switch console that includes yellow and blue Joy-Con controllers&lt;/a&gt;, along with &lt;em&gt;Fortnite &lt;/em&gt;and 2,000 V-Bucks is available at Amazon for $300.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yjWMLx"&gt;AirPods Pro are back down to $190 at Woot, matching the deal we saw just before Black Friday. Woot guarantees that your order will arrive before Christmas on December 25th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="izeuIq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="FHs7p6"&gt;If you missed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/30/21725110/samsung-galaxy-buds-live-earbuds-cyber-monday-deal"&gt;Woot’s incredible deal on the Galaxy Buds Live&lt;/a&gt;, don’t worry, &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1602829-REG%2Fsamsung_sm_r180nzkaeue_galaxy_buds_live_mystic.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo has the wireless earbuds on sale for $120&lt;/a&gt; in black and bronze. It is not the lowest we have seen these bean-shaped earbuds for, but still an incredible deal. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Samsung-Wireless-Cancelling-Charging-Included/dp/B089B658NP?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; also has the Galaxy Buds Live on sale starting at $129, and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1722751386730213452" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; has the earbuds for $130.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="mv6joD"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Yakuza: Like a Dragon&lt;/em&gt; rereleased earlier this month and during Black Friday and Cyber Monday, the game was marked down to $40 on &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1725320389421352585" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;PS4&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1725320376438453805" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xbox&lt;/a&gt;, the latter providing you a free copy on Xbox One and the Xbox Series X / S if you own one of Microsoft’s next-gen consoles. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="CTVkXY"&gt;The best Cyber Week deals on headphones&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="nVQWTC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9523565"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="IGq3Xa"&gt;Sony’s WH-XB900N noise-canceling headphones are &lt;s&gt;$118&lt;/s&gt; $148 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07RM8WQ8G?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724683993194110376" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; (usually $248)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="QgqWE5"&gt;Even more affordable yet, the Sony WH-CH710N noise-canceling headphones are just &lt;s&gt;$88&lt;/s&gt; $98 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B085RQYX5Z?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724686850701604233" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; (usually $200)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="VqxzjQ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9586877"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="TZ3ddR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9625639"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="EEt4eK"&gt;The Sennheiser Momentum Wireless noise-canceling headphones are $350 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sennheiser-Momentum-Cancelling-Headphones-Functionality/dp/B07VW98ZKG?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724685151178098131" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, knocking $50 off the normal price&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="556ewp"&gt;Shure’s Aonic 50 noise-canceling headphones are $300 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Shure-Cancelling-Headphones-Studio-Quality-Technology/dp/B084S1CYKF?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;s&gt;and &lt;/s&gt;&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724686048381502302" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;s&gt;Best Buy&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — a whole $100 off their usual price&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="MEBNrd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="vDOnQN"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B088KTR418/?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Beats Powerbeats Pro in the lava red and spring yellow colors&lt;/a&gt; are &lt;s&gt;$160&lt;/s&gt; $150, down from their usual $200 asking price at Amazon. &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724949373602313118" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy is selling&lt;/a&gt; the moss color, as well as the spring yellow and lava red colors for $160.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="AabqD1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9625438"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="NH77ke"&gt;Jabra’s previous-generation Elite 65t are still a great starter set of wireless earbuds, and they’re pretty cheap at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B077ZGRVRX/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;s&gt;and &lt;/s&gt;&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724674752881417758" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;s&gt;Best Buy&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Normally $120, they’re $70.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="vDyFFd"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PYLT6DN/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple’s AirPods with a wireless charging case costs $140&lt;/a&gt;, which is officially the lowest price. These have been selling for $150 throughout Black Friday, but this early Cyber Monday deal is live now at Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="RKWtd7"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9507432"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="Sby1pO"&gt;You can snag a set of &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08LYZJ868?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Echo Buds&lt;/a&gt;, which also sound good and have Bose noise reduction technology. They cost $80, down from $130, and you’ll get a six-month subscription to Amazon Music Unlimited.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="8qREFt"&gt;The Galaxy Buds Plus dropped another $10 at Amazon, down to $100 from their original $150 price. Other retailers have joined Amazon at $100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Puasru"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9581901"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="MlbiD6"&gt;Also at $80 are 1More’s ColorBuds, a solid set of wireless earbuds that pop with color. These are normally $100, and you can get this deal through &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fusa.1more.com%2Fproducts%2Fcolorbuds-true-wireless-in-ear-headphones-ess6001t%3F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21583109%2Fafter-cyber-monday-post-tech-deals-games-headphones-gadgets#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;1More&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SxcjKC"&gt;The best Cyber Week deals on streaming services&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ADDd8D"&gt;For new and returning customers (who haven’t subscribed in the last three months and who haven’t taken advantage of last year’s promo), &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/click?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;offerid=763711.10&amp;amp;type=3&amp;amp;subid=0&amp;amp;u1=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;you can get on Hulu’s ad-supported streaming plan for just $1.99 per month for a full year&lt;/a&gt;. After that, your monthly rate goes back up to $5.99. This deal was supposed to end earlier this morning, but the landing page is still up for the promotion.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-dWNygU5BvtSAr-oTD7b-MNg6y0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21924542/DSCF2108.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="HXGunt"&gt;If you &lt;a href="https://tv.youtube.com/welcome/"&gt;subscribe to YouTube TV by December 31st&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll get a free Chromecast with Google TV.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="8Au2Mj"&gt;1Password is offering an exclusive  offer to readers of &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; until Thursday, December 3rd. You can save 50 percent each month on the cost of a family subscription (up to five people, and &lt;em&gt;not &lt;/em&gt;restricted to a single household) to 1Password’s services, &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/am/sid/verge/https://1password.com/promo/black-friday/the-verge/?SID=___vg__e_21445064__r_theverge.com/author" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;costing $2.50 per month&lt;/a&gt; for up to one year. After that year is up, you’ll be charged the regular $5 per month rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="IzFZGl"&gt;The best Cyber Week deals on TVs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="mVqZ85"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9733779"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="b3Lzst"&gt;The best Cyber Week deals on laptops&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="l8F85p"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724673736170934495" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;HP’s Envy x360 13 2-in-1&lt;/a&gt; is $750 at Best Buy (usually $1,000)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="d7SFHu"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=44583&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fp%2F34-725-086%3Fitem%3D34-725-086%26Tpk%3D34-725-086%3Fcm_sp%3DBlackFriday-_-eflyer-_-2020-_-1123-1127%26nm_mc%3DAFC-RAN-COM%26cm_mmc%3DAFC-RAN-COM%26utm_medium%3Daffiliates%26utm_source%3Dafc-Vox%2BMedia%26AFFID%3D3430747%26AFFNAME%3DVox%2BMedia%26ACRID%3D1%26ASUBID%3Dverge%26ASID%3D%26ranMID%3D44583%26ranEAID%3D3430747%26ranSiteID%3DnOD_rLJHOac-ZkMmnmwefQB3TBnzfVQidA&amp;amp;u1=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The Gigabyte Aorus 5 gaming laptop&lt;/a&gt; with a six-core Intel Core i7 processor, the RTX 2060, and 16GB of RAM is &lt;s&gt;$1,050&lt;/s&gt; $1,200 with a rebate card at Newegg (usually $1,300)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="19wnN6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9624587"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="0LVkI6"&gt;The Acer Aspire 5 is a solid budget laptop with an 11th Gen Core i5-1135G7 processor, 8GB of RAM and a 512GB SSD. &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=44583&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Facer-a515-56-56dj%2Fp%2FN82E16834316938%3FItem%3DN82E16834316938%26Tpk%3D34-316-938%3Fcm_sp%3DBlackFriday-_-eflyer-_-2020-_-1123-1161&amp;amp;u1=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;It costs $550 at Newegg&lt;/a&gt;, down from $650.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="rojR4F"&gt;The best Cyber Week deals on smart speakers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="69XMDC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9508352"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="kX6U64"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9607515"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="tqFtlZ"&gt;If you want &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07XJ8C8F7/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the new spherical Echo Dot with a digital clock embedded in the fabric&lt;/a&gt;, that one costs $39 at Amazon. It’s normally $60. Stock seems to be running low for this model, as it’s currently set to restock in an extremely vague “three to six months”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7KWZwX"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B084J4MJCK/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The new (and adorable) Kids Edition Echo Dot&lt;/a&gt; is $39. It normally costs $60.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y53nZZLH59Xl8UsLsNFj5wefzeE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21935903/dseifert-nest-audio-4225-1.0.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LKFS2j"&gt;Google’s latest Nest Audio speakers are available as a duo for $170, knocking $20 off the usual price for buying two together. These can be paired for a stereo arrangement for music and podcasts, and at some point, you’ll be able to use them as a home theater setup with Chromecast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0pVsi9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9503894"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="m97eaJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9736399"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="8HKZt7"&gt;The best Cyber Week deals on smart displays&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="K1Jknn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513095"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="bfrAso"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9573987"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cog6wX"&gt;Google’s Nest Hub smart displays are great if you like to watch YouTube, or have a big Google Photos library you want to show off on their screens. The smallest Nest Hub starts at $50, though only the larger Nest Hub Max can make video calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kDtUQC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9625445"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="dZw6p6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9625470"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sDfeFB"&gt;The best Cyber Week deals on phones&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="PWA2mq"&gt;At the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oneplus.com%2Foneplus-8%3Ffrom%3D8&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21583109%2Fafter-cyber-monday-post-tech-deals-games-headphones-gadgets#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;OnePlus site&lt;/a&gt;, you can get the standard OnePlus 8 for $200 off its usual price, costing $599. &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1581337-REG%2Foneplus_5011100963_8_256gb_smartphone_interstellar.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21583109%2Fafter-cyber-monday-post-tech-deals-games-headphones-gadgets#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt; is actually offering a slightly bigger price cut of $230 off. This phone shares a few similarities to the 8 Pro, like the Snapdragon 865 processor, 12GB of RAM, and 256GB of storage. Though, it doesn’t have wireless charging and its camera array doesn’t quite stack up as favorably. Also, it has a 90Hz refresh rate display compared to 120Hz on the 8 Pro, and the display itself is smaller (about 6.5 inches versus 6.8 inches).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="juEMEl"&gt;Speaking of the OnePlus 8 Pro, Amazon recently knocked an extra $50 off the Black Friday sale price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="oVbnF2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9628882"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xBBpZQ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://fi.google.com/about/phones/pixel-4a-5g"&gt;The Pixel 4A with 5G is $200 off when new customers&lt;/a&gt; purchase it through the Google Fi MVNO service, resulting in a $299 final price. If you’re an existing Google Fi subscriber, you can upgrade to the 4A with 5G and get $150 off, knocking the price down to $349. Not bad, considering that’s the same price as the standard Pixel 4A that doesn’t have 5G support.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The rear of the iPhone 12 is glossy and it picks up both fingerprints and micro-scratches fairly easily. Use a case." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Su01ArTK53SDrAwX-UxIWv9wQXw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21973515/vpavic_4243_20201017_0103.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="nEDMCh"&gt;Until December 7th, Visible (owned by Verizon, operating on Verizon LTE) will give you a complimentary set of AirPods Pro &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.visible.com%2Fapple&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21583109%2Fafter-cyber-monday-post-tech-deals-games-headphones-gadgets#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;with the purchase of any phone in the iPhone 12 series&lt;/a&gt;. The catch is that you’ll need to buy the phone and port your number to a new line in the same transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-dWNygU5BvtSAr-oTD7b-MNg6y0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21924542/DSCF2108.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="mzehHA"&gt;The best Cyber Week deals on streaming devices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="8hVivI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9550519"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="RTqS9V"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07ZZVX1F2/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The standard Amazon Fire TV Stick&lt;/a&gt; with a more capable Alexa Remote is $28 (usually $40)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0XlwIm"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B079QHML21/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The Amazon Fire TV 4K Stick&lt;/a&gt; with Dolby Atmos and 4K HDR support is $30 (usually $50)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NO0c9f"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07KGVB6D6?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The high-end Amazon Fire TV Cube&lt;/a&gt; that supports 4K HDR, Dolby Atmos, and can handle voice queries from across the room is $80 (usually $120)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="XbEvvg"&gt;The best Cyber Week deals on tablet accessories&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3Ovbhy14PfmPVfO23bHYgZBG-IE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19868722/DSC00765.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Brydge Pro Plus keyboard has an integrated trackpad, so you don’t need to use the touchscreen (or, at least as much)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="cA2Ing"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0865JB97F/?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Brydge’s Pro Plus keyboard with a trackpad built-in for the 11-inch iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt; (2018 or 2020 versions) is $140, down from its usual $160 price. The 12.9-inch version is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0865KQ772/?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;back in stock at Amazon, costing $160&lt;/a&gt; instead of $180.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="18aWEh"&gt;If you don’t need a trackpad with your keyboard, the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B089H2P9T5/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Brydge Pro for 12.9-inch iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt; models costs $100, down from $170. The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B089H1RFGP/?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;11-inch version&lt;/a&gt; is the same price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="4yFMtD"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07HXH6NWN/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Brydge keyboard made for 10.5-inch iPads&lt;/a&gt;, including the seventh and eight generation iPad, the previous-generation iPad Air and iPad Pro models, is $70 off. You can snag one for $60.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wOlFwc"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08CWLKWK6/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Brydge Go Plus&lt;/a&gt;, made for the Surface Go, is $100 ($40 off)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="IE0Ggl"&gt;The best Cyber Week gaming deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="HbWH7w"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9734577"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="wRyarN"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=vergeevergreen&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fplaystation-4%2Fgames%2Fproducts%2Ffifa-21%2F11102805.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;FIFA 21&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;s&gt;$27&lt;/s&gt; $25 at GameStop&lt;/a&gt; (usually $60), the lowest it’s been. If you buy the PS4 version and upgrade to the PS5, you will receive the next-gen version free of charge until &lt;em&gt;FIFA 22&lt;/em&gt; releases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="deOfEL"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=%5B%5Dvg%5Be%5D21335511%5Br%5Dgoogle.com%5Bt%5Dw%5Bd%5DD&amp;amp;murl=https://www.gamestop.com/video-games/playstation-4/games/products/madden-nfl-21/11100040.html?condition=New" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Madden NFL 21&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;s&gt;$27 &lt;/s&gt;$25 at GameStop&lt;/a&gt;, the lowest price ever. If you buy the PS4 version and upgrade to the PS5, you will receive the next-gen version, free of charge until &lt;em&gt;Madden 22&lt;/em&gt; releases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="tFrmRF"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Last of Us Part II&lt;/em&gt; is $30 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Last-Us-Part-II-PlayStation-4/dp/B07DJRFSDF?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724704923555918277" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=%5B%5Dvg%5Be%5D21335511%5Br%5Dgoogle.com%5Bt%5Dw%5Bd%5DD&amp;amp;murl=https://www.gamestop.com/video-games/playstation-4/games/products/the-last-of-us-part-ii/11097389.html?condition=New&amp;amp;utm_source=rakutenls&amp;amp;utm_medium=affiliate&amp;amp;utm_content=Vox+Media&amp;amp;utm_campaign=10&amp;amp;utm_kxconfid=tebx5rmj3&amp;amp;cid=afl_10000087&amp;amp;affID=77777&amp;amp;sourceID=nOD_rLJHOac-irigNeksZCfbBzWuPDGVBA" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GameStop&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FThe-Last-of-Us-Part-II-Sony-PlayStation-4-711719519102%2F839659063&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; (usually $60).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CIRS2nq9_g7OClmscCMMBCEx1O8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/20081553/akashima_flowers_1.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The landscapes in Ghost of Tsushima are serene&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="NloLjX"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Ghost of Tsushima&lt;/em&gt; is $40 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Ghost-Tsushima-PlayStation-4/dp/B08BSKT43L?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724705099506154974" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=vergeevergreen&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fplaystation-4%2Fgames%2Fproducts%2Fghost-of-tsushima%2F11100913.html%3Fcondition%3DNew%26utm_source%3Drakutenls%26utm_medium%3Daffiliate%26utm_content%3DVox%2BMedia%26utm_campaign%3D10%26utm_kxconfid%3Dtebx5rmj3%26cid%3Dafl_10000087%26affID%3D77777%26sourceID%3DnOD_rLJHOac-O6N4GllPS.zG14ufVN1tUQ" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GameStop&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FGhost-of-Tsushima-Sony-PlayStation-4%2F902309293&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; (usually $60)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nvX5uA"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=%5B%5Dvg%5Be%5D21335511%5Br%5Dgoogle.com%5Bt%5Dw%5Bd%5DD&amp;amp;murl=https://www.gamestop.com/video-games/playstation-4/games/products/nba-2k21/11103262.html?condition=New&amp;amp;utm_source=rakutenls&amp;amp;utm_medium=affiliate&amp;amp;utm_content=Vox+Media&amp;amp;utm_campaign=10&amp;amp;utm_kxconfid=tebx5rmj3&amp;amp;cid=afl_10000087&amp;amp;affID=77777&amp;amp;sourceID=nOD_rLJHOac-jiYyuc8u_zbu8bOooUIYsQ" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;NBA 2K21&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;s&gt;$30&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/a&gt; $25 (usually $60), the lowest price we’ve seen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rXo1nG"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Watch Dogs Legion&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;s&gt;$30&lt;/s&gt; $37 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Watch-Dogs-Legion-PlayStation-4-Standard/dp/B07SJ2T3CW?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and $40 at &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FWatch-Dogs-Legion-Xbox-Series-X%2F552057007&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;  (usually $60). If you buy the Xbox One version and upgrade to that console’s successor, you will receive the next-gen version free of charge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="TvGydM"&gt;The best Cyber Week deals on PC tech&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Brydge" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P-EOHcL79LRDjbPa_kdzi20-3zc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21712488/W_Touch___W_Type.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Brydge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The W-Type keyboard next to the W-Touch wireless trackpad&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="W4BrrQ"&gt;For the first time, Brydge has discounted its &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08D6XQX14/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;W-Touch standalone trackpad&lt;/a&gt; for Windows 10. Normally $100, it’s down to $70.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="KTKnrb"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08D6XS52J?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;W-Type wireless, full-sized Bluetooth keyboard&lt;/a&gt; is discounted by $20, bringing the price down to $40.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ekCZCJ"&gt;Samsung’s 2TB 970 Evo Plus NVMe SSD is $250 at Newegg &lt;s&gt;and Best Buy&lt;/s&gt;, beating the lowest price by about $40. A PCIe 3.0 M.2 SSD like this will fit in only certain kinds of motherboards (so check before you buy).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="SBMmrh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9581101" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_square_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="J1aM8G"&gt;For an even faster M.2 drive that’s actually capable of delivering quicker read/write speeds for both PCIe 3.0 and motherboards with PCIe 4.0 support, Samsung’s 500GB 980 Pro NVMe SSD is $120 (usually $150) at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08GL575DB?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="nXAomD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9736457"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="OEqXx2"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B081D8TPZZ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The all-black HyperX Cloud Alpha S wired gaming headset&lt;/a&gt; is $100 at Amazon, down from its usual $130 price.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="kMtSoC"&gt;The best Cyber Monday deals on mesh Wi-Fi routers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="HepWLc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9603453"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="sFtw50"&gt;Google’s Nest Wifi mesh routers are steeply discounted, starting with the single unit that’s $135 instead of $169 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07YMKD6SM?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and $139 at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724592195825667221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gExQm3"&gt;The best Cyber Week deals on misc. tech&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="pectet"&gt;A number of retailers are selling the DJI Osmo Action for $199, a discount of about $50 from its regular price. The Osmo Action is similar to GoPro’s line of action cameras, and comes with both front and rear facing screens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="oxTsVA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9738122"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="1URx75"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="XSLdjY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21583109/after-cyber-monday-post-tech-deals-games-headphones-gadgets"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21583109/after-cyber-monday-post-tech-deals-games-headphones-gadgets</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-01T09:51:53-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-01T09:51:53-05:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung rumored to discontinue Galaxy Note line, add stylus support to 2021 Galaxy S and Z Fold</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Samsung Note20 smartphone" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VwJHtx68dVO66jyKz49HEDxIQUQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68042605/dbohn_200817_4133_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dieter Bohn / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="U09Ahm"&gt;Samsung will reportedly discontinue its Galaxy Note phone line in 2021, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-samsung-elec-smartphone-idUSKBN28B3U5"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, as the company contends with falling demand for pricey smartphones caused by the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic. Instead, the company is set to focus on its flagship Galaxy S lineup of phones, while Samsung’s foldable phones (like the Z Flip and Z Fold) will take the place of the Galaxy Note as Samsung’s more experimental premium devices, complete with an optional stylus accessory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fBBCwD"&gt;The idea that Samsung would stop selling the Galaxy Note line of phones in favor of the Galaxy S models makes a lot of sense. In the earlier years of the Note, the two lines of phones were distinct: the Galaxy S models were smaller, more mainstream devices, while the comparatively massive Note lineup hewed closer to a tablet, complete with the iconic stylus that helped set it apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="U0rMBr"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Note’s success in popularizing big-screened phones may have been its undoing&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8aECpr"&gt;But the Note’s success in popularizing big-screened phones may have proved to be its undoing. When the original Galaxy Note was introduced in 2011, its then-massive 5.3-inch display let it tower over other phones, like the 4.3-inch Galaxy S II that Samsung had released in 2011. But fast-forward to 2020, and phones like the Galaxy S20 Ultra and Galaxy Note 20 Ultra are effectively competiting against each other for the same audience, with far more similar specs, screen sizes, and functionality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cXfvlh"&gt;In an era where Samsung is already developing and shipping cheaper smartphones in mere months — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/23/21451701/samsung-galaxy-s20-fe-price-release-date-specs-features"&gt;like the Galaxy S20 FE&lt;/a&gt;, which released earlier this year to directly respond to consumer demand for a lower-cost midrange phone that still offered some of Samsung’s more premium features — it’s hard to justify the existence of a second lineup of flagships. That’s especially true when the only real outlier that sets the Note apart today is the stylus, something that Samsung appears to be trickling down to the standard Galaxy S lineup in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="V4d1ej"&gt;&lt;q&gt;In a world of giant smartphones, the Note doesn’t stand out anymore&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="EPhDgg"&gt;The other factor is the Galaxy Note lineup just isn’t that special anymore. In prior years, Samsung used the Note to experiment with some of its bolder and more interesting new innovations and design changes. For instance, the Note lineup helped popularize the edge display and featured larger swappable batteries, an IR blaster, the removal of the microSD card slot, and several generations of influential Galaxy hardware design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yDfYCB"&gt;But its role of Samsung’s futuristic test platform has been wholly usurped by foldable phones like the Galaxy Z Fold, which promise meaningfully bigger screens than the traditional Galaxy S and Note lineups and the kind of bold new hardware that used to be the calling card of the Note. Add a stylus — which Samsung is reportedly planning to offer as an optional accessory — and the Z Fold lineup is a practically perfect heir to the Note lineup’s unique strengths&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Whw2I7"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21754983/samsung-galaxy-note-21-2021-smartphone-discontinued-stylus-s21-foldable-rumor"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21754983/samsung-galaxy-note-21-2021-smartphone-discontinued-stylus-s21-foldable-rumor</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-01T09:50:50-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-01T09:50:50-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best Kindle deals right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VfQnBwLbLIeiZEVOPMuNUumuNok=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67715739/akrales_190723_3560_0016.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MyfWR7"&gt;When it comes to finding a device to use to read your ebooks, you have a few options to choose from. You can always buy a tablet or simply use your smartphone, but those devices are multipurpose and can be used for a ton of things, like surfing the web or doom-scrolling through Twitter. If you are looking for something to strictly read books, e-readers, while a niche piece of tech, are designed to store all of your books in a virtual library with no other functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pDKHVT"&gt;Amazon has dominated the space for years with its Kindle products. Right now, there are three Kindle models you can choose from, each with pros and cons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JRHBaM"&gt;Below, we’ve listed each of the current Kindles available for purchase. Sometimes, there isn’t a deal for one or, in some instances, all of the products. In that case, we’ve mentioned the most recent sale price so you know when is a good time to buy the e-reader at a discounted rate. But most of the time, there’s some deal going on. Whether you’re looking for a new model or to grab a bundle that includes a few extras, these are the best Kindle deals right now.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pkAGJ6iYjGrpA-YsqWJjBBYbkTY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16018841/akrales_190408_3351_0016.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kindle (2019).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="jqPttv"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/4/10/18302177/amazon-kindle-base-model-low-resolution-screen-backlight-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kindle (10th Generation)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="mXAcFi"&gt;This is Amazon’s most affordable e-reader, usually costing $90. Released in 2019, this base Kindle model includes a front light, comes in one storage configuration of 8GB, and comes with or without ad support. Despite including the same 167ppi resolution as its predecessors, this model has a slightly higher contrast than earlier models. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pIAlEv"&gt;Right now, you can buy the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Essentials-including-Amazon-Printed-Adapter/dp/B08C6NDPFM/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=vergereviews-20&amp;amp;linkId=08c9fedb17174c7a7fe940944cd78418&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kindle Essentials Bundle&lt;/a&gt;, which is $120 ($15 off its usual price), and it includes a printed cover and a power adapter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="RkX3DN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9552432"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fux5e_2NAD_6n9O0DpRG1PE85p0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19266309/_DSC4246_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kindle Kids Edition.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ze80m8"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/10/7/20902588/kindle-kids-edition-amazon-bundle-young-e-reader-case-replacement-program-freetime"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kindle Kids Edition (2019)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="JypT34"&gt;The entry-level Kindle and Oasis models were not the only ones that received a refresh in 2019, Amazon also announced and released a Kindle Kids Edition Bundle, which provides age-appropriate content for younger readers who prefer digital books for $109 ($20 more than the base Kindle). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6LlYfl"&gt;The Kindle Kids Edition consists of five items: the device, a case, a two-year extended replacement guarantee (in the event the device breaks), and one year of Amazon’s FreeTime Unlimited service. The latter is the biggest selling point of this device, as it allows parents to grant access to a digital library of kid-friendly books like &lt;em&gt;Percy Jackson&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The Hobbit &lt;/em&gt;at no additional cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N7AYlh"&gt;Right now, Amazon is offering the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/All-new-Essentials-including-Protector-Adapter/dp/B07XW24MVK?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kindle Kids Edition Essentials Bundle, which is $128&lt;/a&gt; and includes all of the things previously mentioned above, plus a power adapter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3DEvBp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9552664"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7Ui-7fZF-JF49zi7F7FaH9eYRUY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13391945/akrales_181101_3056_0332.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kindle Paperwhite (fourth-generation).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="t6m9om"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/7/18065960/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-2018-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kindle Paperwhite (Fourth Generation)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="P1C5xu"&gt;Amazon released the fourth-generation Kindle Paperwhite in 2018. Starting at $130, the Paperwhite comes in three different configurations: 8GB Wi-Fi, 32GB Wi-Fi, and a second 32GB model that drops the ads from the lock screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qneu65"&gt;The Paperwhite features a six-inch, pin-sharp backlit display, which is the main reason to get one over the base Kindle. The 2018 model added a few useful features normally found on Amazon’s flagship reader, the Oasis, such as water resistance and Audible audiobook support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bJrHrN"&gt;Amazon has knocked $20 off its Kindle Paperwhite Essentials Bundle, which includes either an &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07HKWNVSD/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=vergereviews-20&amp;amp;linkId=261395a0382ce2c0aecf3c9f9e099dcc&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;8GB&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07HKX97CR/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=vergereviews-20&amp;amp;linkId=3a5cb4645a5b1f86f9b8e704cc584654&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;32GB&lt;/a&gt; Paperwhite (with ads), plus a leather cover and a power adapter. If you are a fan of &lt;em&gt;The Hunger Games&lt;/em&gt; book series, the e-commerce giant has four bundles that include the Paperwhite (with ads) and exclusive covers designed by the series’ author, plus a power adapter for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kindle-Paperwhite-Bundle-including-Ad-Supported/dp/B087NMH2F7?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$160 if you buy the 8GB&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kindle-Paperwhite-Bundle-including-Ad-Supported/dp/B087NM77FC?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$190 if you buy the 32GB&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vOUHwk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9552401"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/50C1xWX4q-mLYmoXmHAKkoXLX1s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/18329976/akrales_190723_3560_0055.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kindle Oasis.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="X5jbTU"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/24/20707619/amazon-kindle-oasis-2019-e-reader-review-price-specs-features-display"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kindle Oasis (Third Generation)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="IByP4u"&gt;The Kindle Oasis is the most expensive of the lineup, starting at $250. The device comes in two storage configurations: 8GB or 32GB, and like the other models, you can get the product with or without ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1AvXZM"&gt;The Kindle Oasis 2019 model looks very similar to its previous model. It still maintains its waterproof, seven-inch, 300ppi E Ink display and supports Audible audiobooks by connecting to Bluetooth. Yet, the biggest change to the Kindle Oasis 2019 is that it can adjust the color temperature to a yellow-toned display, making it easier to read at night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oxP7sb"&gt;In the past, we have seen the Kindle Oasis go down to as low as $200 if you get the 32GB model, which is the lowest it has ever been for that configuration to date. While there are no deals on just the Oasis itself, Amazon is currently offering an Essentials Bundle for $30 off its normal price. You can get either the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B087YZGRGQ/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=vergereviews-20&amp;amp;linkId=e940143295b150503dca7aa3985b2fd5&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;8GB&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B087Z7Z3DF/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=vergereviews-20&amp;amp;linkId=7b5fe424246439c89a69b3302267e073&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;32GB&lt;/a&gt;, and it will also include a leather cover, a power adapter, plus three months of Kindle Unlimited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="hPPu8s"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9552599"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21539047/best-amazon-kindle-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21539047/best-amazon-kindle-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-01T09:41:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-01T09:41:24-05:00</updated>
    <title>YouTube’s top trending video of 2020 is a powerful Dave Chappelle Netflix special</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DkyEP9uEn8Z6KTNw-rtCAq44lPs=/93x0:2468x1583/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68042570/chappelle.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="h3Ysm3"&gt;YouTube has released its annual top trending videos list of 2020, and the list reflects a year dominated by shifts in behavior brought on by the pandemic, civil unrest, and a heated political environment leading up to the US election. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1toBsk"&gt;The top trending video of 2020 was &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fculture%2Fon-television%2Fdave-chappelles-rough-cut-humorlessness-in-846&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21755000%2Fyoutube-top-trending-videos-2020-dave-chappelle-netflix#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Dave Chappelle’s &lt;em&gt;8:46&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a 27-minute stand-up special that was filmed at a socially distanced event in Ohio where the comedian lives. Netflix dropped the surprise special on June 12th, amid ongoing protests dedicated to fighting racism and police brutality around the world in the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21355121/new-civil-rights-movement-police-brutality-protests-film-videos-black-lives-matter"&gt;wake of George Floyd’s death&lt;/a&gt;. The special was praised by critics and other public figures for its honesty about America’s ongoing issues with racism. The title of the special, &lt;em&gt;8:46&lt;/em&gt;, references the length of time Minneapolis police officer Derek Chauvin kept his knee &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21378157/police-brutality-violence-recording-videos-black-lives-matter-consequences"&gt;pressed on Floyd’s neck&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kje140"&gt;“More than anything else, it sets the tone for how there was this thing that was happening in culture and in the world, and how people created content that reflected this moment that was happening,” Earnest Pettie, an analyst on YouTube’s culture and trends team, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Viewers swarmed to it.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eOPOSb"&gt;That’s true with other videos found on the list as well. The second top trending video of the year is &lt;em&gt;Saturday Night Live&lt;/em&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://www.vulture.com/2020/10/watch-saturday-night-live-cold-open-starring-jim-carrey.html"&gt;first debate cold open&lt;/a&gt; that focused on the presidential election. The open featured Alec Baldwin as President Donald Trump and Jim Carrey as President-elect Joe Biden. Despite the video only being published on YouTube in early October, it quickly became one of the most shared videos, according to Pettie. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="s4Xt8q"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The Top Trending list is an accurate reflection of what people are actually into, and talking about and sharing with each other.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FIzz2F"&gt;Elsewhere, signs of what was happening in other parts of 2020 culture can be found on the list, too. Both &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/22/21571189/charli-damelio-100-million-tiktok-followers"&gt;Charli and Dixie D’Amelio&lt;/a&gt;, two of TikTok’s most popular creators, made the top 10 list for breakout stars on YouTube. Also on the list is Chloe Ting, an exercise influencer who became extremely popular at the &lt;a href="https://www.elle.com/culture/a33635518/chloe-ting-teenage-girls-and-the-quest-for-flat-abs-in-lockdown/"&gt;beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic&lt;/a&gt; in the United States when people were trying to find ways to work out at home. Corpse Husband, a YouTuber who &lt;a href="https://www.insider.com/corpse-husband-face-reveal-aoc-real-name-look-like-youtuber-2020-11"&gt;picked up quite a bit of attention&lt;/a&gt; after one of his songs went viral on TikTok and he streamed &lt;em&gt;Among Us &lt;/em&gt;with some fellow big-name YouTube creators and public figures (AOC, Toast, James Charles), also made the list. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZPQBvg"&gt;Some of the names are also recognizable to people keeping up with the YouTube community. MrBeast, Jeffree Star, NikkieTutorials, Dude Perfect, and David Dobrik all created some of the year’s top trending videos. What remains unclear from this year’s list is how many people watched those videos — just because a video is counted as a top trending title doesn’t necessarily mean it’s the most watched. YouTube’s team wanted to focus on “a variety of ways that people interact” with what they’re watching, Pettie said. Unlike former years, YouTube also doesn’t have any plans to release a Most Viewed list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JSpOBW"&gt;“The Top Trending list is an accurate reflection of what people are actually into, and talking about and sharing with each other,” Pettie said. “This is what we feel is an excellent representation of the year.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XdBQld"&gt;The full list of Top Trending 2020 titles can be read below. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dFfdgY"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TOP TRENDING VIDEOS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9azWVB"&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3tR6mKcBbT4"&gt;8:46 - Dave Chappelle&lt;/a&gt; - Netflix is a Joke&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="82vKka"&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Wsije1KetVw"&gt;First Debate Cold Open&lt;/a&gt; - Saturday Night Live&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NlnZ4U"&gt;3. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w4Ro3SsYT5s"&gt;We Broke Up&lt;/a&gt;. - jeffrreestar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="svneAy"&gt;4. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=erQ_9yEz0ls"&gt;I Bought The World’s Largest Firework ($600,000)&lt;/a&gt; - MrBeast&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OAG6oh"&gt;5. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QOOw2E_qAsE"&gt;I’m Coming Out.&lt;/a&gt; - NikkieTutorials &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ciWzFV"&gt;6. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tylNqtyj0gs"&gt;Minecraft Speedrunner VS 3 Hunters GRAND FINALE&lt;/a&gt; - Dream&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="79fuFC"&gt;7. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LCNdTLHZAeo"&gt;Ricky Gervais’ Monologue - 2020 Golden Globes&lt;/a&gt; - NBC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BI2cU6"&gt;8. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eZUKSxE2UZg"&gt;Quarantine Stereotypes&lt;/a&gt; - Dude Perfect&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="koBro4"&gt;9. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F5pgG1M_h_U"&gt;Some Good News with John Krasinski Ep. 1&lt;/a&gt; - SomeGoodNews&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rVOZht"&gt;10. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hWzccW4TQkg"&gt;We Can’t Believe This Happened&lt;/a&gt; - David Dobrik&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dq725M"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9GsiZa"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TOP BREAKOUT CREATORS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JNl6iB"&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/DreamTraps"&gt;Dream&lt;/a&gt; (12.5 Million Subscribers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="beGPIw"&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW0wEGsLzmIgvQDOXgaz4vg"&gt;Tiko&lt;/a&gt; (5.21 Million Subscribers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uvpnib"&gt;3. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/ChloesAddiction"&gt;Chloe Ting&lt;/a&gt; (15.9 Million Subscribers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1hRHi5"&gt;4. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/EddieVR/featured"&gt;EddieVR&lt;/a&gt; (4.86 Million Subscribers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ATqrKl"&gt;5. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCi3OE-aN09WOcN9d2stCvPg"&gt;charli d’amelio&lt;/a&gt; (8.32 Million Subscribers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G22fn7"&gt;6. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/GeorgeeeHDPlays"&gt;GeorgeNotFound&lt;/a&gt; (4.4 Million Subscribers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ULhw1P"&gt;7. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/dixiedamelio/videos"&gt;Dixie D’Amelio&lt;/a&gt; (6.58 Million Subscribers) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HWjwbw"&gt;8. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCFNTq9XKHDNy_1-2lL0kqCg"&gt;Corpse Husband&lt;/a&gt; (4.95 Million Subscribers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jf0xPI"&gt;9. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOe_y6KKvS3PdIfb9q9pGug"&gt;SomeGoodNews&lt;/a&gt; (2.56 Million Subscribers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="24t1U5"&gt;10. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC2sYit3cZ2CuD_8FHYH7O_Q"&gt;Hyram&lt;/a&gt; (3.9 Million Subscribers) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KI9Zns"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uNNrqv"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TOP CREATORS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6jzNFg"&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCX6OQ3DkcsbYNE6H8uQQuVA"&gt;MrBeast&lt;/a&gt; (46.1 Million Subscribers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a557CR"&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/DreamTraps"&gt;Dream&lt;/a&gt; (12.5 Million Subscribers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fNlnUw"&gt;3. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UClQubH2NeMmGLTLgNdLBwXg"&gt;ZHC&lt;/a&gt; (17.1 Million Subscribers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jZoBVa"&gt;4. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCpB959t8iPrxQWj7G6n0ctQ"&gt;SSSniperwolf&lt;/a&gt; (23.1 Million Subscribers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cwik1F"&gt;5. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW0wEGsLzmIgvQDOXgaz4vg"&gt;Tiko&lt;/a&gt; (5.21 Million Subscribers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GuMa8A"&gt;6. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/ChloesAddiction"&gt;Chloe Ting&lt;/a&gt; (15.9 Million Subscribers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lEW9eg"&gt;7. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9DWJ33CMvIseLlyx6hyRnA"&gt;JoshDub&lt;/a&gt; (8.14 Million Subscribers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CQ1Ykb"&gt;8. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCja7QUMRG9AD8X2F_vXFb9A"&gt;The Royalty Family&lt;/a&gt; (10.5 Million Subscribers)	&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZfcFZe"&gt;9. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCw1SQ6QRRtfAhrN_cjkrOgA"&gt;LazarBeam&lt;/a&gt; (17.2 Million Subscribers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m6LYfr"&gt;10. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCucot-Zp428OwkyRm2I7v2Q"&gt;James Charles&lt;/a&gt; (23.9 Million Subscribers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ozNqH1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lRh3rO"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MUSIC VIDEOS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T9hGaP"&gt;1. Future -&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l0U7SxXHkPY"&gt; Life Is Good (Official Music Video) ft. Drake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oWjlW9"&gt;2. 6IX9INE- &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pPw_izFr5PA"&gt;GOOBA (Official Music Video)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uTTog4"&gt;3. Lil Baby x 42 Dugg - &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GErG9femMQk"&gt;We Paid (Official Video)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dVAVGH"&gt;4. NLE Choppa - &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fyIcQ1Xl-rs"&gt;Walk Em Down feat. Roddy Ricch (Official Music Video)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nIFn0F"&gt;5. Cardi B - &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hsm4poTWjMs"&gt;WAP feat. Megan Thee Stallion [Official Music Video]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZnbLmi"&gt;6. DaBaby – &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=83xBPCw5hh4"&gt;ROCKSTAR FT RODDY RICCH [Audio]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2yqPH0"&gt;7. Roddy Ricch - &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UNZqm3dxd2w"&gt;The Box [Official Music Video]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PPB5dN"&gt;8. Drake - &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JFm7YDVlqnI"&gt;Laugh Now Cry Later (Official Music Video) ft. Lil Durk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5EHLeN"&gt;9. YoungBoy Never Broke Again - &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lUmYlsulfYo"&gt;Lil Top [Official Music Video]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5BWSKe"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21755000/youtube-top-trending-videos-2020-dave-chappelle-netflix"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21755000/youtube-top-trending-videos-2020-dave-chappelle-netflix</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-01T09:22:52-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-01T09:22:52-05:00</updated>
    <title>Arecibo Observatory in Puerto Rico collapses as engineers feared</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="PUERTORICO-SCIENCE-ASTRONOMY-OBSERVATORY" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3MJf54RqHCnjAfB4DoYCpE_p-PQ=/0x0:5351x3567/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68042485/1229684803.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Arecibo Observatory prior to the collapse. The 900-ton platform suspended above the dish fell overnight.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Ricardo Arduengo / AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5MHiuY"&gt;The massive Arecibo Observatory in Puerto Rico collapsed in on itself overnight. The catastrophic failure &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/19/21575025/arecibo-observatory-puerto-rico-decommission-structural-collapse-cable-break"&gt;had been predicted by engineers after the telescope suffered two major cable malfunctions&lt;/a&gt; over the last couple of months, risking the integrity of the observatory’s entire structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4Fn0ts"&gt;Pictures of Arecibo surfaced online this morning, revealing that the massive 900-ton platform that is normally suspended above the observatory was no longer there. The National Science Foundation, which oversees Arecibo, confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the platform did come crashing down onto the telescope’s giant 1,000-foot-wide dish. No injuries have been reported, according to the agency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="dIDmnb"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Our top priority is maintaining safety.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lr4EYK"&gt;“NSF is working with stakeholders to assess the situation,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NSF/status/1333772980539691008"&gt;the agency tweeted&lt;/a&gt;. “Our top priority is maintaining safety. NSF will release more details when they are confirmed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="AhfZoh"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="es" dir="ltr"&gt;Ayer fue la última vez que visite esta belleza de lugar. Lamentablemente agonizaba. Aquí imágenes de ayer y hoy. &lt;a href="https://t.co/jWuAwtUc1s"&gt;pic.twitter.com/jWuAwtUc1s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Deborah Martorell (@DeborahTiempo) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DeborahTiempo/status/1333747356605571072?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 1, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LBWFiT"&gt;This catastrophic scenario is something the NSF feared might happen. On November 19th, the agency announced that the remaining cables at Arecibo ran the risk of failing, which could lead to the platform’s collapse. Knowing this was imminent, NSF said it planned to demolish Arecibo in a controlled manner, concluding that there was no safe way to save the observatory. Managers had evacuated the facility and set up a “safety exclusion zone” to keep people away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C2tBMJ"&gt;The collapse comes at the end of a difficult period for Arecibo. In August, the observatory &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/14/21368784/arecibo-observatory-puerto-rico-cable-damage-reflector-dish"&gt;suffered its first major malfunction&lt;/a&gt;, when an auxiliary cable came loose from its socket and fell onto the observatory’s dish, punching a large hole in the structure. At the time, NSF and the University of Central Florida, which oversees day-to-day operations at Arecibo, vowed to investigate the failure and fix the damage in order to get the observatory up and running again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="FFTfIi"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“NSF is saddened by this development.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AdUxBp"&gt;But as engineers were figuring out a path forward for repairs, &lt;a href="https://www.ucf.edu/news/a-second-cable-fails-at-nsfs-arecibo-observatory-in-puerto-rico/"&gt;a second main cable failed on November 6th&lt;/a&gt;. This time, the cable snapped and also fell onto Arecibo’s giant dish, causing damage to other cables nearby. Engineers found that the other cables could not be guaranteed to hold. The NSF concluded that Arecibo would eventually collapse if no actions were taken; they just didn’t know when the collapse might occur. The agency had hoped to demolish the structure before it took place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DD506o"&gt;“NSF is saddened by this development,” the agency &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NSF/status/1333772983316385797"&gt;tweeted about the collapse&lt;/a&gt;. “As we move forward, we will be looking for ways to assist the scientific community and maintain our strong relationship with the people of Puerto Rico.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="PUERTORICO-SCIENCE-ASTRONOMY-OBSERVATORY" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V5SNnvMwGz5vr0SqzXmi6Yy8EAA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22133346/1229684651.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Ricardo Arduengo / AFP via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Damage to the Arecibo Observatory is seen on November 19th after the second cable failure.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pJsUM8"&gt;The NSF’s decision to tear down Arecibo was met with a lot of pushback from fans of the telescope. Arecibo has been a major beacon of opportunity in Puerto Rico as well as an incredible asset for peering into the cosmos. The observatory has been used to identify distant exotic objects like pulsars as well as to listen for mysterious blasts of radio waves coming from the distant Universe. Scientists also used Arecibo in 1974 to send out a picture message out into the cosmos, detailing humanity’s achievements for anyone that might be listening. Arecibo has also made numerous cameos in television and film, including &lt;em&gt;GoldenEye &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Contact.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MJ1TAl"&gt;Not wanting to see the observatory demolished, a Puerto Rican scientist &lt;a href="https://www.change.org/p/united-states-national-science-foundation-nsf-repair-the-arecibo-observatory-do-not-decommission-it?redirect=false"&gt;launched a petition on Change.org&lt;/a&gt; to urge the NSF to repair Arecibo. As of today, the petition has more than 36,000 signatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pHTmxf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dEUCal"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C95Gaf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21754959/arecibo-observatory-platform-collapse-dish-puerto-rico-telescope"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21754959/arecibo-observatory-platform-collapse-dish-puerto-rico-telescope</id>
    <author>
      <name>Loren Grush</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-01T09:07:10-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-01T09:07:10-05:00</updated>
    <title>Reddit reveals daily active user count for the first time: 52 million</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ENxPKWZMM6fEoFdRgB4vOZXqhqI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68042429/acastro_180413_1777_reddit_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="V5gTcJ"&gt;Reddit revealed that it now has 52 million daily users, and the number appears to be growing quickly. Reddit &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/reddit-claims-52-million-daily-users-revealing-a-key-figure-for-social-media-platforms-11606822200"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;that daily usage grew 44 percent year over year for October, a sizable increase on a metric that speaks to just how essential a product it is to its users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IHMqpD"&gt;The number is small compared to other social media rivals, though. Twitter has 187 million daily users, Snap has 249 million, and Facebook has 1.82 billion. But at their larger sizes, none of those services are seeing daily usage grow as rapidly as Reddit. In their most recent quarters, Twitter reported 29 percent year-over-year growth, Snap reported 18 percent, and Facebook reported 12 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v0dmck"&gt;Daily usage of Reddit is being shared for the first time “as a more accurate reflection of our user growth and to be more in-line with industry reporting,” the company told the &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt;. (It is true that social media companies tend to use daily users as their preferred metric; though Twitter, for instance, only switched away from reporting monthly users because that number was dipping, while daily users was growing.) The other reason for the change was to focus on a number that would better help to grow Reddit’s advertising business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kQsH7H"&gt;Reddit has focused on monthly usage in the past. This time last year, the company said it had 430 million monthly users, with 30 percent year-over-year growth. The quick growth has come during a period that Reddit began to iterate more rapidly on its service. It rolled out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/2/17190244/reddit-redesign-begins-rolling-out"&gt;a significant redesign&lt;/a&gt; in 2018 and this year has added features like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/15/21324962/reddit-image-gallery-feature-announced-gifs-imgur"&gt;galleries&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/24/21191119/reddit-poll-post-type-nfl-super-bowl-survey"&gt;polls&lt;/a&gt;. The company has also gotten more serious about cracking down on some of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/29/21304947/reddit-ban-subreddits-the-donald-chapo-trap-house-new-content-policy-rules"&gt;problematic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/30/20891920/reddit-harassment-bullying-threats-new-policy-change-rules-subreddits"&gt;communities&lt;/a&gt; hosted on its site, which should help to make the service friendlier to both advertisers and users overall.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21754984/reddit-dau-daily-users-revealed"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21754984/reddit-dau-daily-users-revealed</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-01T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-01T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Varjo’s dual-resolution VR and AR headsets just got crisper and cheaper</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Varjo XR-3 AR headset" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M2amlROn6TYGua4F9BTbdckRszs=/0x0:1800x1200/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68042322/_S8A0978_scaled.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Varjo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="N2NPmh"&gt;Virtual reality company Varjo, known for its unusual dual-resolution displays, has a new generation of virtual and augmented reality headsets. It’s promising even higher resolution, a wider field of view, and AR with advanced depth mapping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ge5Hgi"&gt;Varjo’s PC-tethered VR-3 and XR-3 both have some of the sharpest screens you’ll find in VR and AR. The headsets use two panels for each eye: a small 1920 x 1920 display in the center of your vision, and a 2880 x 2720 panel for the rest of the screen. That produces an extremely clear image when you’re looking straight ahead and a more standard (albeit still high) VR resolution for your peripheral vision. Earlier Varjo devices used the same strategy with lower-resolution panels; the VR-1 and VR-2 &lt;a href="https://www.roadtovr.com/varjo-vr-2-headset-steamvr-support-hand-tracking-retina-display/"&gt;from 2019&lt;/a&gt;, for instance, had a 1920 x 1080 inner panel and a 1440 x 1600 display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TmKYtx"&gt;The original Varjo screen (which it calls a “bionic display”) had a relatively narrow, boxy field of view, but the VR-3 and XR-3 have expanded that to offer a 115-degree horizontal FOV. That’s higher than the &lt;a href="https://uploadvr.com/valve-index-price-specs/"&gt;fairly expansive Valve Index&lt;/a&gt; and substantially bigger than lower-end consumer headsets. (These headsets typically have closer to 110 degrees of &lt;em&gt;diagonal&lt;/em&gt; FOV, which &lt;a href="https://uploadvr.com/field-of-view-tool-database/"&gt;translates into 100 degrees or less&lt;/a&gt; horizontal.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F5OQda"&gt;The XR-3 and VR-3 use the same screen, and both feature hand and eye tracking, as well as the same 90Hz refresh rate. But the XR-3 also includes cameras and LIDAR sensors that turn it into an AR headset by combining virtual objects with a passthrough video feed. That makes the XR-3 somewhat heavier than the VR-3, at 594 grams compared to 558 grams, plus the weight of a headband that’s supposed to evenly and comfortably distribute that weight. (The recent Oculus Quest 2, a totally self-contained device, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/16/21427947/oculus-quest-2-facebook-vr-headset-price-release-date-preorder-connect"&gt;weighs 503 grams&lt;/a&gt; altogether.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="O6e38h"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The XR-3’s passthrough design is an alternative to typical AR glasses&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DdxbrT"&gt;Varjo’s passthrough AR approach produces a much bulkier product than AR glasses like the Microsoft HoloLens, which project light through a pair of transparent glasses onto the real world. But it also creates much more solid-looking virtual objects, similar to the AR images you’d find on phones and tablets. LIDAR — which Apple incorporated &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/19/21185200/apple-ipad-pro-lidar-sensor-ar-hardware-solution-software-apps-augmented-reality"&gt;into its 2020 iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt; — helps the headset more accurately map the outside world. You might still get some obvious “tells,” like virtual objects’ lighting not matching that of a real room. But better mapping means that physical objects can realistically occlude virtual ones, for instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yaoAiQ"&gt;Varjo still isn’t pitching its headsets to consumers. The XR-3 costs $5,495 and requires a one-year $1,495 Varjo software support subscription. The VR-3 costs $3,195 and requires a similar $795 subscription. But that’s still a major cut from the $9,995 XR-1 and the $4,995 VR-2. The goal is a headset that more businesses and other organizations can afford. The higher resolution, meanwhile, could help with specific use cases. The VR-3 and XR-3’s crisper peripheral vision means that pilots-in-training can glance around at a virtual cockpit and get a clear image, for instance — mimicking how they’d act while flying a real plane. Varjo also promises better color accuracy with the XR-3 cameras, so doctors could get a better look at something like a rash while holding telemedicine sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0ul8O2"&gt;The VR-1, VR-2, &lt;a href="https://www.roadtovr.com/varjo-launches-10000-xr-1-dev-edition-headset-combining-vr-ar-single-package/"&gt;and XR-1&lt;/a&gt; were announced and released within months of each other, and the VR-3 and XR-3 are being released roughly a year later. Varjo doesn’t expect to keep up this tight hardware release cycle. With the screen resolution boost, higher field of view, and other features in place, it’s going to focus on scaling up deliveries and improving performance via software tweaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="25U4ro"&gt;The XR-3 and VR-3 are both available for purchase today, and shipments will start in early 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21720748/varjo-vr3-xr3-vr-ar-dual-resolution-headsets-price-shipping-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21720748/varjo-vr3-xr3-vr-ar-dual-resolution-headsets-price-shipping-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-01T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-01T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Lucid Motors finishes the first phase of its $700 million EV factory in Arizona</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ogvucimTpjGgJfppNDUkUam2WeU=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68042342/Exterior_Casa_Grande.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uATUgn"&gt;Last year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2019/9/27/20887693/lucid-motors-casa-grande-factory-arizona-saudi-arabia"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; published&lt;/a&gt; the first images of Lucid Motors’ planned $700 million electric car factory in Arizona. Now, nearly a year after breaking ground, the company announced that it has finished the first phase of construction and is on schedule to start production of its first vehicle, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/9/21429319/lucid-motors-air-electric-sedan-price-specs-range-reveal"&gt;the luxury Lucid Air sedan&lt;/a&gt;, by spring 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FYYER0"&gt;The first phase of the factory comprises 999,000 square feet of space, with the goal of eventually expanding that to a whopping 5.1 million square feet by 2028. The next phase of construction will begin in early 2021, Lucid says. Initially, the factory will have the capacity to produce 30,000 vehicles a year, with the goal of eventually getting to an annual capacity of 400,000 vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xYxqGm"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Initially, the factory will have the capacity to produce 30,000 vehicles a year&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zU5pIc"&gt;Lucid says it has already produced a “full beta prototype test fleet” and is now transitioning to the construction of “production representative” versions of the Air. The company hopes to expand the factory to begin production of its SUV, codenamed “Project Gravity,” by 2023. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9TZmbB"&gt;Lucid Motors doesn’t own the land; instead, Pinal County &lt;a href="https://www.bizjournals.com/sanjose/news/2019/02/13/lucid-motors-casa-grande-az-factory-lucid-air.html"&gt;bought the more than 500-acre site and will lease it to the EV startup&lt;/a&gt; with the goal of eventually handing it over. Pinal County raised $29.94 million through bonds to buy the land, and Lucid Motors will pay $1.8 million each year in rent, before being given the opportunity to buy the land in five years. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RGdIM5WXG8HFag4rCSj2GL797X4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22131727/Aerial_2.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_S6bhHEW0r8i7EbY1Zk2TbFs6Yk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22131809/Greenfield_1.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="BIRPCu"&gt;The Lucid Air, first revealed last September, will get up to 517 miles of range, can hit a quarter-mile in under 10 seconds, packs over 1,000 horsepower, and will have a base price of $77,400. But Lucid is prioritizing the pricier trim levels in the hopes of replicating Tesla’s strategy of selling a lot of really expensive cars to generate enough cash flow for the more affordable versions. The two most expensive versions of the Air — the $139,000 Air Grand Touring and $169,000 Air Dream Edition — are expected to go on sale in the second quarter of 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ptwWu"&gt;Over the last decade, there’s been a lot of money pouring into the EV startup space, without many new EVs to show for it. One of the major hurdles has been factory construction. Some companies believed they needed to build big, expensive factories, a la Tesla’s Gigafactory, to impress investors and signal their intention to compete with Elon Musk. Others searched for smaller, preexisting factories to lease in the hopes of saving money on capital costs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Td8P4z"&gt;Like many other EV startups, Lucid Motors almost ran out of money as it pursued its plans to build the Lucid Air. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/21/18235019/lucid-motors-electric-suv-ev-saudi-arabia"&gt;It took on loans&lt;/a&gt; from a hedge fund and a Chinese bus company to stay afloat and ultimately received a massive $1 billion lifeline from Saudi Arabia’s Public Investment Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jAqZmApqchIa9iakAqaj-SRADmo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22131810/Int_Paint_shop_01.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21739985/lucid-motors-ev-factory-construction-arizona"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21739985/lucid-motors-ev-factory-construction-arizona</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
