<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-11-12T10:30:08-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-12T10:30:08-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-12T10:30:08-05:00</updated>
    <title>Instagram Reels now have text-to-speech and voice effects just like TikTok </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZDKXIKTetEBuNHy1b2FeSTGDGXo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70132851/acastro_190919_1777_instagram_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5CncBi"&gt;Instagram has added text-to-speech and voice effects to its TikTok competitor Reels, two features TikTok has had for some time. The robotic voice-overs used as narration for videos grew so ubiquitous on TikTok in fact, that voice actor &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22435058/tiktok-voice-sues-unauthorized-usage-text-to-speech"&gt;Bev Standing sued the company in May&lt;/a&gt;, saying it didn’t have permission to use her voice. In September, TikTok &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22701167/bev-standing-tiktok-lawsuit-settles-text-to-speech-voice"&gt;reached a settlement with Standing&lt;/a&gt; that included a licensing agreement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="07PDxQ"&gt;While it’s popular among TikTok creators, more importantly, text-to-speech is a widely used accessibility feature that allows blind people and those with low vision to hear spoken versions of written text. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ilzlba"&gt;To use text-to-speech in Reels, open the Instagram app and go to the Reels camera, record or upload a video, and add text to the video using its text tool. Tap the text bubble to get to the three-dot menu, and select “text-to-speech,” then choose which voice option you want. Then post the Reel as usual. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YVckuW"&gt;If you want to add voice effects to your Reel, which lets you modify audio including a voice-over, after recording a Reel, tap the music note to open the audio mixer, tap “effects” and choose the voice effect you want. Options include “helium,” “giant,” and “robot.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7S5JqOKS6x9n954CS_RzJzndgWE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23008827/voice_effect.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CWHL67OPk_H/" target="_blank"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can add voice effects to Instagram Reels.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="cEBF0C"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/5/21354117/instagram-reels-tiktok-vine-short-videos-stories-explore-music-effects-filters"&gt;Reels launched in 2020&lt;/a&gt;, meant to be a direct competitor to the wildly popular TikTok. Instagram launched a bonus program for creators in July, part of parent company Facebook’s (now Meta) plan to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22577242/facebook-1-billion-payments-creators-2022"&gt;pay $1 billion to creators&lt;/a&gt; through 2022, and has offered creators with high follower counts &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22777899/instagram-reels-bonus-program-35000-dollars-creators-tiktok-competitors"&gt;as much as $35,000 in bonuses to create Reels&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cT5QHn"&gt;Meanwhile, TikTok has evolved its text-to-speech feature with &lt;a href="https://collider.com/scream-ghostface-tiktok-text-to-speech/"&gt;specialized character voices&lt;/a&gt;; on Friday it introduced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22778092/disney-plus-day-tiktok-text-to-speech-voices-characters-marvel"&gt;text-to-speech voices from Disney characters&lt;/a&gt; including Stitch, Chewbacca, Rocket Raccoon, and others. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22778073/instagram-reels-text-to-voice-effects-tiktok-creators"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22778073/instagram-reels-text-to-voice-effects-tiktok-creators</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-12T10:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-12T10:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Invasion’s creepy alien reveal was worth the wait</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Invasion" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/45mkUDYvyjJwkq1vLDS5JPcRWdM=/480x0:3360x1920/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70132841/Invasion_Photo_010508.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GFjmVk"&gt;It took half of a season, but we’re finally here: the aliens have shown themselves in &lt;em&gt;Invasion&lt;/em&gt;. The Apple TV Plus series got off to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22740520/invasion-review-apple-tv-plus"&gt;a slow start&lt;/a&gt; when it debuted in October. The first handful of episodes were tense character drama, focusing on a few characters spread across the globe, each of whom was dealing with some personal issues in addition to the titular attack on the planet. That was all well and good, but the sci-fi elements were so scant that you could blink and miss them. No one even said the word “alien” until episode five. But now that we’re halfway through the season, that’s changed. The latest episode finally shows the creepy off-world invaders, and it has given the show the purpose it needs — along with some scares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4dbcps"&gt;If you haven’t watched the show yet, &lt;em&gt;Invasion&lt;/em&gt; is probably best described as &lt;em&gt;This is Us&lt;/em&gt; mashed up with &lt;em&gt;War of the Worlds&lt;/em&gt;. It takes a big idea — aliens are invading seemingly every part of the world — but explores it through a series of small, intimate stories. There’s a mother learning about an unfaithful spouse, a US soldier on his own in Afghanistan, and a bus full of English teens that crashes in the middle of nowhere, among others. Each of these characters is not only dealing with their own shit but also the early stages of the invasion. No one even knows what’s going on. Amidst power outages, mysterious objects crashing from space, and the occasional synchronized nosebleed, there’s a lot of misplaced blame on “the Russians” or unspecified terrorists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uZFX68"&gt;Viewers, of course, have known all along that it’s aliens. It’s right there in the title of the show. But the hints for the actual characters living through the invasion have been sparse, sporadic, and confusing. Now things are becoming more clear. In episode five, we got a tease of just how strange these invaders might be when a doctor named Aneesha (played by Golshifteh Farahani, whose distraught performance remains a highlight of the show) notices a spiky little blob while stitching up a patient. It’s gross and dangerous-looking. It also seems alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZSdAaW"&gt;It turns out that was just a taste. In episode six, after a brief detour that started out as a hunt for food and ended up as a short-term residency at a field hospital, Aneesha returns to the house her family has been staying in, only to find it empty and boarded-up like something from a zombie movie. Except it’s not empty; &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; is lurking around. You see and hear it in brief, terrifying flashes. The whole house will start to shake unexpectedly. Giant, spider-like legs scurry in the background. At one point, you can see the full creature but as a tiny reflection in a mirror.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="invasion" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/l8WLDrnD0FTv56naoDQp2I_dQKE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23005242/Invasion_Photo_010503.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="UTLTEV"&gt;Like everything else in &lt;em&gt;Invasion&lt;/em&gt;, the build-up is slow and methodical. But it works: it’s almost like a horror movie, one that takes its time before showing the monster in its full, terrifying glory. And the reveal here is wonderful, as you watch a tortuous sequence where the creature terrorizes the family as they attempt to make an escape. Seeing the alien doesn’t take away from its mystery or menace at all. In fact, it just raises more questions about how these spindly black blobs managed to coordinate a planet-wide attack and what exactly it is they want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EW7K68"&gt;What I’m saying is, the slow-burn reveal was worth it. Not only are the aliens unexpected and scary, but their arrival also makes almost every character’s arc more interesting. Before, as engaging as many of the personal stories were, it felt a lot like a bunch of people floundering around during the end of the world. Now there’s some purpose. That’s especially true with Mitsuki Yamato (Shioli Kutsuna), an obsessed Japanese space technician who appears to be the only one close to figuring out what’s going on with the invaders. More than just moving the plot forward, though, the blobby bugs from space have introduced a tangible threat. It’s no longer just some weird stuff going on — it’s a bunch of killer spiders sneaking around every city on the planet for unknown reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dncTTx"&gt;I’m glad I stuck it out to see the aliens. But they do introduce a new problem for &lt;em&gt;Invasion&lt;/em&gt; because now the show has to do it all over again. The first five episodes were a slow build-up that ultimately paid off, but we’re just over halfway through the story at this point, so there’s plenty to go. The reveal worked, but the next test will be seeing if the show can connect all of its many stories into something satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22776188/invasion-apple-tv-plus-episode-6-aliens"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22776188/invasion-apple-tv-plus-episode-6-aliens</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-12T10:10:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-12T10:10:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Hospitals are at a high risk of cyberattacks, but patients don’t realize it</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Health Care Professionals Work On The Frontlines Of COVID-19 Pandemic In Maryland Hospital" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Jl5wVeb1ojKI6UAalNNAzgZYRoM=/0x0:6720x4480/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70132722/1222271719.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Win McNamee/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0RzJeq"&gt;Southern Ohio Medical Center, a not-for-profit hospital in Portsmouth, Ohio, canceled appointments for today and is diverting ambulances after it was &lt;a href="https://myfox28columbus.com/news/local/southern-ohio-medical-center-hit-by-cyberattack"&gt;hit by a cyberattack on Thursday&lt;/a&gt;. It’s part of a series of escalating attacks on healthcare organizations in the past two years — a trend that could have serious consequences for patient care. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YY7qWA"&gt;But while information technology experts are well aware that the risk of cyberattacks that compromise patient data and shut down computer systems is on the rise, patients don’t seem to be, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.armis.com/press-releases/armis-data-highlights-increased-risk-for-healthcare-organizations-as-attack-surface-expands/"&gt;new report&lt;/a&gt; by cybersecurity company Armis. In fact, over 60 percent of people in the general public surveyed in the new report said they hadn’t heard of any cyberattacks in healthcare in the past two years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yG0DMs"&gt;That’s despite a &lt;a href="https://healthitsecurity.com/news/healthcare-cyberattacks-doubled-in-2020-with-28-tied-to-ransomware"&gt;doubling of cyberattacks&lt;/a&gt; on healthcare institutions in 2020, high-profile incidents like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/28/21482304/ransomware-outage-hospital-chain-cybersecurity"&gt;attack on hospital chain Universal Health Services&lt;/a&gt;, and a major &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/29/21540026/cyberattack-ransomware-hospitals-russia-covid"&gt;threat&lt;/a&gt; from groups using the ransomware Ryuk. The magnitude of attacks during the COVID-19 pandemic &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21551050/cyberattacks-hospitals-coronavirus-deadly-tactics"&gt;shocked experts&lt;/a&gt;, who said that ransomware gangs were targeting hospitals more aggressively than they had before. Unlike attacks on banks or schools, which are also common, these attacks have the potential to directly injure people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vmMMt3"&gt;“It crosses a line that I think the entire cybersecurity community just didn’t think was going to get crossed anytime soon,” Caleb Barlow, CEO of cybersecurity consulting firm CynergisTek, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21551050/cyberattacks-hospitals-coronavirus-deadly-tactics"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; last year&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7DsLfE"&gt;The Armis report surveyed 400 IT professionals in healthcare and over 2,000 people in the general public who could potentially be patients at healthcare institutions around the United States. Though the number of people surveyed is small, the findings indicate that members of the public generally aren’t aware of cyberattacks in&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;the healthcare industry unless they have been impacted directly by one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DU6sst"&gt;While 61 percent of potential patients surveyed hadn’t heard of cyberattacks in healthcare in recent years, around a third of respondents said that they’d been the victim of a cyberattack in the health system. Assuming most people in the group that had been victims of a cyberattack had heard of one, only a small percentage of survey respondents &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; heard of attacks in healthcare without being the victim of one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pkm4iY"&gt;“Attacks on hospital systems really aren’t top of mind until they impact you directly,” says Oscar Miranda, chief technology officer for healthcare at Armis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bSFfLY"&gt;The report also zeroed in on a gap between people’s awareness of healthcare cyberattacks and their level of concern about the problem. Around half of people surveyed said that they would switch hospitals if there was a cyberattack, and over 70 percent said they thought attacks could have consequences for their care. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SIqyeY"&gt;Those concerns are warranted: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696097/hospital-ransomware-cyberattack-death-rates-patients"&gt;healthcare organizations say&lt;/a&gt; that ransomware delays procedures for patients and can lead to longer hospital stays. An &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632378/pandemic-ransomware-health-risks"&gt;analysis&lt;/a&gt; from the United States’ Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency also showed that hospitals battling ransomware attacks during the COVID-19 pandemic reached a tipping point associated with excess deaths more quickly than hospitals not dealing with one.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EpyVCw"&gt;Cybersecurity has historically not been a priority for healthcare organizations, many of which don’t have the resources to invest in that area. But the spikes in ransomware attacks on hospitals in the past two years, coupled with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696097/hospital-ransomware-cyberattack-death-rates-patients"&gt;the new research&lt;/a&gt; showing links between cyberattacks and health outcomes, are pushing groups to make changes. In the Armis survey, three-quarters of IT experts said the steady pulse of news about ransomware attacks has led to a push for more investment in cybersecurity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="69M0pr"&gt;“I do believe we’re making strides in finally actually addressing ransomware,” Miranda says. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22776561/hosptial-cyberattack-ransomware-risk"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22776561/hosptial-cyberattack-ransomware-risk</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-12T10:09:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-12T10:09:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla vehicle in ‘Full Self-Driving’ beta mode ‘severely damaged’ after crash in California</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gd5mJv1y0OnQGAmw7RKQzgxcTU0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70132720/tesla_model_y_3597.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VLeOdC"&gt;A Tesla Model Y in “Full Self-Driving” (FSD) beta mode allegedly crashed on November 3rd in Brea, a city southeast of Los Angeles, marking what is likely to be the first incident involving the company’s controversial driver assist feature. No one was injured in the crash, but the vehicle was reportedly “severely damaged.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9y0XGa"&gt;The crash was reported to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, which has multiple, overlapping investigations into Tesla’s Autopilot system. The incident report appears to have been made by the owner of the Model Y. A spokesperson for NHTSA did not immediately respond to a request for comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gcot8N"&gt;According to the report: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="v9sPxq"&gt;The Vehicle was in FSD Beta mode and while taking a left turn the car went into the wrong lane and I was hit by another driver in the lane next to my lane. the car gave an alert 1/2 way through the turn so I tried to turn the wheel to avoid it from going into the wrong lane but the car by itself took control and forced itself into the incorrect lane creating an unsafe maneuver putting everyone involved at risk. car is severely damaged on the driver side.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="RSGGtu"&gt;Tesla’s decision to test its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/26/22693610/tesla-opens-full-self-driving-beta-software-more-customers"&gt;“Full Self Driving” driver assistance software&lt;/a&gt; with untrained vehicle owners on public roads has attracted a massive amount of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22724171/nhtsa-tesla-letters-fsd-beta-autopilot-recall-emergency-vehicles"&gt;scrutiny&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/22/21528508/tesla-full-self-driving-beta-first-reaction-video"&gt;criticism&lt;/a&gt;. Throughout, the company has rolled out — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/24/22743628/elon-musk-tesla-fsd-beta-10-3-rollback-issues-phantom-fcw"&gt;and retracted&lt;/a&gt; — several software updates meant to upgrade the system while also addressing bugs in the software. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OXYour"&gt;There have been many video clips uploaded online showing Tesla owners using FSD beta, with varying degrees of success. Some clips show the driver assist system confidently handling complex driving scenarios, while others depict the car drifting into the wrong lane or making other serious mistakes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Bneq48"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Despite its name, FSD is not an autonomous driving system&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="s3YFum"&gt;Despite its name, FSD is not an autonomous driving system. Drivers are required to stay vigilant, keeping their eyes on the road and their hands on the steering wheel. Vehicles with highly automated driving systems that still require human supervision are classified as Level 2 under the Society of Automotive Engineers’ taxonomy. (Level 5 describes a vehicle that can drive anywhere, under any conditions, without any human supervision.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="48Wwdc"&gt;The US government has taken a renewed interest in Tesla, recently announcing that it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22626819/tesla-autopilot-crash-emergency-vehicle-probe-nhtsa"&gt;investigating incidents involving Tesla cars operating Autopilot that have crashed&lt;/a&gt; into parked emergency vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8dSSz0"&gt;NHTSA is also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22724171/nhtsa-tesla-letters-fsd-beta-autopilot-recall-emergency-vehicles"&gt;seeking more information from Tesla&lt;/a&gt; about the growing public beta test of FSD, the recently launched “Safety Score” evaluation process for entering the program, and the nondisclosure agreements Tesla was making participants sign up until recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zOuZRV"&gt;A spokesperson for Tesla did not respond to a request for comment — nor is it likely they will after disbanding their press department in 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xEyCrn"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22778135/tesla-full-self-driving-beta-crash-fsd-california"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22778135/tesla-full-self-driving-beta-crash-fsd-california</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-12T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-12T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Verge’s 2021 holiday gift guide for creators</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WXRQFaxUfXA-xxP2HtiB-0EhXPs=/0x2:2048x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70132581/Creators.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Richard Parry&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Gifts for the aspiring and established content creators&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="c4X606"&gt;From YouTube to Twitch to TikTok, or everyday photography, videography, and podcasting. To some degree, everyone is a content creator, whether it is a pursuit of a personal passion or for the consumption and streaming by a huge audience. Consequently, the most dedicated creators can also be the most difficult to shop for. What do you get for someone who is just starting out that will be most helpful? Or what about someone that’s a bit further along and more established?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Amzgyl"&gt;If you find yourself shopping for someone in your life that is looking to start something fresh or take their craft to the next level, we have a few gift ideas for you to check out. Like the Sony A6600 ($1,600), some are no small investment but are favored by YouTubers far and wide. Others, like Shure’s MV7 mic ($250), could jumpstart a serious podcast project or be used by a professional. And fun ideas like the IKEA Lanespelare ($25) and Philips Hue Lightstrip kit ($80) could be a great choice for anyone who wants to freshen up the decor in a studio or streaming space, as they look great on-camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="AyaGmb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Verge Holiday Gift Guide 2021","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22759813/holiday-gift-guide-best-tech-gadget-unique-ideas"},{"title":"The Verge’s Favorite Holiday Gifts Under $50","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22748775/holiday-gift-guide-under-50-cheap-tech-gadgets-best-ideas"},{"title":"The Verge’s Guide to Black Friday 2021","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21583092/black-friday-guide-cyber-monday-tech-gadgets"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="bXn2kk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10830492"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iuyFyC"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22746670/holiday-gift-ideas-2021-creators-content-artists-tech-gadgets-creative"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22746670/holiday-gift-ideas-2021-creators-content-artists-tech-gadgets-creative</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-12T09:51:14-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-12T09:51:14-05:00</updated>
    <title>Disney partners with TikTok for official text-to-speech voices from Stitch, Chewbacca, Rocket Raccoon, and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gEdMDnRtQNr-2va3DEXGZIluUnE=/0x129:1102x864/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70132532/Screen_Shot_2021_11_12_at_9.28.44_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KmlF9T"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/disneyplus/status/1459151492586299401"&gt;Disney is teaming up with TikTok&lt;/a&gt; to add official character voices to the popular social media app’s text-to-speech feature, allowing you to have your captions read by &lt;em&gt;Lilo and Stitch&lt;/em&gt;’s Stitch, C-3PO, Chewbacca, a Stormtrooper from &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;, and Rocket Raccoon from &lt;em&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy. &lt;/em&gt;The new character voices are rolling out in the app today as part of the &lt;a href="https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/c/482924/564546/9358?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.disneyplus.com%2Fwelcome%2Fsubscribe-now%3Fcid%3DDSS-Search-Google-71700000058993695-%26irclickid%3DRgfSZFzslxyIRHnyqjWYSydRUkGxmxXflxjQxI0%26irgwc%3D1%26cid%3DDSS-Affiliate-Impact-Content-Vox%2520Media-564546%26gclid%3DCj0KCQiAsqOMBhDFARIsAFBTN3dBoDWJXrDVwzeR5APtVTarczQ4WhI6tkPIVtKwBlFRLhxMopaTyLMaAlj9EALw_wcB&amp;amp;subid1=VergeDisneyPlusDayTikTok111221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Disney Plus Day&lt;/a&gt; promotional holiday celebrating the two-year anniversary of the service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Wp8vXx"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Disney is partnering with TikTok for new themed character test-to-speech voices, a feature that will surely be used only in a mature and appropriate fashion. &lt;a href="https://t.co/3Hz2NPZFor"&gt;pic.twitter.com/3Hz2NPZFor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Chaim Gartenberg (@cgartenberg) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cgartenberg/status/1459166147325173765?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 12, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cRzovU"&gt;Using the voices works similarly to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22594929/tiktok-text-to-speech-how-to"&gt;regular text-to-speech voices&lt;/a&gt; on TikTok; after recording a video, tap the text button on the screen, and type whatever you’d like the text-to-speech voice to read. Then, tap the text-to-speech button (it looks like a head with sound waves coming out of it) to select a voice. But instead of just seeing the usual milquetoast Siri-like presets that TikTok usually offers (the company has five different ones now, after a lawsuit over the original text-to-speech voice earlier this year), you’ll see — at least in theory — the new Disney voices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p1i5GJ"&gt;I say in theory because as part of the promotion, you’ll have to unlock the new Disney voices first by using specific keywords. When I tried it out, I only had the Rocket voice unlocked, but presumably intrepid Disney fans on the internet will figure out how to unlock the other voices quickly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jAPLlI"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;*yells in Chewbacca*    New Text-to-Speech voices ft. some of your favorite characters are available now on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tiktok?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@TikTok&lt;/a&gt;! To unlock them, discover the mystery keywords. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DisneyPlusDay?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#DisneyPlusDay&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/mRwzLsmod3"&gt;pic.twitter.com/mRwzLsmod3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Disney+ (@disneyplus) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/disneyplus/status/1459151492586299401?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 12, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="cTOnCo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to use TikTok’s Text-to-Speech feature","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22594929/tiktok-text-to-speech-how-to"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="ByIQUI"&gt;The Disney collaboration isn’t the first time that TikTok has offered promotional text-to-speech voices: the app &lt;a href="https://collider.com/scream-ghostface-tiktok-text-to-speech/"&gt;previously teamed up with Paramount&lt;/a&gt; to add a &lt;em&gt;Scream-&lt;/em&gt;themed voice that sounded like the villainous Ghostface to coincide with the trailer for the upcoming horror film. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A6grAE"&gt;Disney and TikTok haven’t said how long the new character text-to-speech voices will be available. Fortunately, though, there is literally no way that giving TikTok creators the power to make C-3PO say &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; will backfire in any way as the new text-to-speech voices get used solely in a mature and appropriate fashion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RvxPgF"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rhdzDy"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22778092/disney-plus-day-tiktok-text-to-speech-voices-characters-marvel"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22778092/disney-plus-day-tiktok-text-to-speech-voices-characters-marvel</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-12T09:05:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-12T09:05:47-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Nintendo Switch is back on top in the US after OLED launch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P_u2JmVqzVnMz56CWPxsMiOTtw0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70132329/cfaulkner_210921_4751_0009.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="p9XWUj"&gt;Last month, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22732577/ps5-nintendo-switch-npd-us-sales"&gt;the PS5 ended the Nintendo Switch’s nearly three-year-long reign as the best-selling console in the US&lt;/a&gt;. That proved to be short-lived, however. In October, thanks in large part to the release of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/22711889/nintendo-switch-oled-review"&gt;the new OLED model of the Switch&lt;/a&gt;, Nintendo is back on top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="32BL3z"&gt;According to Nintendo, the Switch sold 711,000 units overall in the US during October, and 314,000 of those were the OLED version. The NPD Group says that these numbers made the Switch the US’s best-selling console that month “in both units and dollars.” (The analyst firm also says that the PS5 remains the top seller in 2021 in terms of dollars, while the Switch is on top when it comes to units sold.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WJSFLC"&gt;“We see this as a strong start for the Nintendo Switch OLED model and a very strong indicator of the performance we can expect as we go into the holiday season,” Nintendo of America president Doug Bowser tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OdMnf7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“If you see it, buy it”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oyNE5Q"&gt;Bowser notes that those October sales numbers are 3 percent lower compared to the same time last year. Earlier this month, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22762933/nintendo-earnings-q2-2021-switch-sales-forecast"&gt;Nintendo cut its overall sales forecast&lt;/a&gt; — it now expects to sell 24 million units globally between April 2021 and March 2022, 1.5 million less than previously forecasted — due to the global chip shortage. And Bowser says that he doesn’t predict those supply issues changing any time soon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="DTNFwi"&gt;These challenges have been facing many industries, and they’ve been going on for quite some time. But we’re working to meet demand for our holiday products, including Nintendo Switch OLED model. I will say things are constantly changing, but we’ve been working across the supply chain — from production to overseas transport to local distribution channels — to make sure we have a steady flow of hardware and games through the holiday cycle. Now, despite all of our efforts, I’d say there’s still a high level of uncertainty. I’d certainly recommend if you see it, buy it this holiday season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QJiiQI"&gt;As you know, in our last earnings report, we did reflect a reduction in our overall number for this year; we took it down about 1.5 million units to 24 million units globally. And that does reflect the outlook and the visibility that we have into the rest of the fiscal year. I will say, the semiconductor components are in short supply, and the future is uncertain. There are no major improvements that we’ve seen on the horizon. So I think the challenges will continue into 2022. We’re going to continue to do our best working with our suppliers to make sure we have the best supply possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="7gUiF1"&gt;Outside of hardware, Nintendo noted that &lt;em&gt;Metroid Dread&lt;/em&gt; — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/6/22710468/metroid-dread-review-nintendo-switch"&gt;which launched alongside the OLED Switch on October 8th&lt;/a&gt; — sold 854,000 units in the US, making it “the best start for any Metroid game ever,” according to Bowser. Meanwhile, &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing: New Horizons&lt;/em&gt; received “a significant spike in people buying the game” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/5/22765536/animal-crossing-new-horizons-2-0-update"&gt;after its final major update&lt;/a&gt;, according to Nintendo, though the company hasn’t released specific numbers on this. &lt;em&gt;New Horizons&lt;/em&gt; is currently the second best-selling Switch game with nearly 35 million units sold globally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cWAGh0"&gt;Bowser also touched on a few other recent and ongoing Nintendo storylines, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="6FOP0a"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/26/22746897/nintendo-switch-online-n64-emulation-quality-bad"&gt;Fan complaints of poor emulation for Nintendo 64 games on Switch Online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="03Gypl"&gt;We’re constantly looking for ways to make our online features and those games better and continuing to add value through more services and more games as we go forward. We take the feedback very seriously, and we’re continuing to look at ways to improve the overall performance. For us, it’s about quality and great content at a great value.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Dkp37L"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/7/22715467/nintendo-joy-con-drift-never-fixed-switch-oled"&gt;The years-long battle against Joy-Con drift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="7sxizI"&gt;As we’ve gone through the first five and a half years of the Nintendo Switch, we’ve observed gameplay, we’ve observed as people have returned units how they’ve worn, and we’ve been making continuous improvements overall to the Joy-Con, including the analog stick. This latest version, Nintendo Switch OLED, has the same updated analog stick that’s now available in the original Nintendo Switch and Nintendo Switch Lite.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="d7wnyH"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22776640/nintendo-switch-oled-sales-october-2021-doug-bowser-interview"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22776640/nintendo-switch-oled-sales-october-2021-doug-bowser-interview</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-12T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-12T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>More than a dozen new titles are coming to Disney Plus today</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AGwIm7iqvaUXCKf_yp9DVSg2_E8=/327x12:1596x858/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70132198/sft1990_cmp_wta_v0162.1048.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Marvel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mSvyl7"&gt;If you’ve been holding off to catch &lt;em&gt;Shang-Chi and The Legend of the Ten Rings&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Jungle Cruise&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;a href="https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/c/482924/564546/9358?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.disneyplus.com%2Fwelcome%2Fsubscribe-now%3Fcid%3DDSS-Search-Google-71700000058993695-%26irclickid%3DRgfSZFzslxyIRHnyqjWYSydRUkGxmxXflxjQxI0%26irgwc%3D1%26cid%3DDSS-Affiliate-Impact-Content-Vox%2520Media-564546%26gclid%3DCj0KCQiAsqOMBhDFARIsAFBTN3dBoDWJXrDVwzeR5APtVTarczQ4WhI6tkPIVtKwBlFRLhxMopaTyLMaAlj9EALw_wcB&amp;amp;subid1=VergeNewDisneyPlusTitles111221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Disney Plus,&lt;/a&gt; today’s the day. More than a dozen films and series are arriving on the service today as part of the service’s Disney Plus Day celebration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gjQKVO"&gt;The event kicks off at 6 AM PT/9 AM ET and will give viewers access to exclusive looks, teasers, trailers, and more. These will be unveiled throughout the morning, and fans will be able to follow along from Disney Plus’s official Twitter, Facebook, and Instagram accounts. In addition, Disney Plus is dumping a veritable truckload of content onto its streaming service today, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="xEbRo3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shang-Chi and The Legend of the Ten Rings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LrYuGn"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jungle Cruise&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DAr1Hw"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Home Sweet Home Alone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fzJEAW"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Olaf Presents&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Ua7cka"&gt;&lt;em&gt;A collection of fan-favorite shorts from Walt Disney Animation Studios&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="YyY5qO"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ciao Alberto &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rO6pWb"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The World According to Jeff Goldblum Season 2 &lt;/em&gt;(Episodes 1-5)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2k1ecF"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Under The Helmet: The Legacy Of Boba Fett &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ByW9yV"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Simpsons In Plusaversary &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fZOuc3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Entrelazados&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qVEF31"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Making of Happier than Ever: A Love Letter to Los Angeles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kgWjLR"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marvel Assembled: The Making of Shang-Chi and The Legend of The Ten Rings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AsfBls"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marvel Studios Legends: Hawkeye&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="F0Ue8h"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enchanted&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xdwRhp"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fSOOBT"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fancy Nancy Season 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="q2tiGm"&gt;Disney Plus Day kicked off with killer promotions for fans of its family of franchises, including Marvel, Star Wars, Pixar, and more. New or returning subscribers, for example, can swipe a subscription for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22766153/disney-plus-day-2-subscription-amc-theaters"&gt;just $2 for a month&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LVjven"&gt;Disney is also partnering with brands like WizKids and Funko for special deals on Disney merch, and the company is unveiling an “ultra-rare” NFT today as well. Throughout the weekend, fans can also catch &lt;a href="https://www.amctheatres.com/disney-plus-day-surprise-screenings-weekend"&gt;surprise screenings&lt;/a&gt; of popular films for $5 a pop at more than 200 AMC theaters nationwide. (You won’t know what you’re watching until the movie starts.) A full rundown of its Disney Plus Day promotions can be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22766153/disney-plus-day-2-subscription-amc-theaters"&gt;found right here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BnTeWk"&gt;Lastly, Disney partnered with IMAX to upgrade a collection of Marvel movies to IMAX’s expanded aspect ratio format on Disney Plus, which will give viewers up to 26 percent more picture during certain scenes. Thirteen Marvel films will get the upgrade, including &lt;em&gt;Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings&lt;/em&gt; and other recent MCU titles like &lt;em&gt;Black Widow&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="plW9yh"&gt;In addition to all of the promotions, Disney also used the faux-holiday as a chance to tease some of its upcoming streaming series, including the likes of &lt;em&gt;Baymax &lt;/em&gt;and a first look image of &lt;em&gt;Hocus Pocus 2.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8aIAn4"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lcYPrMk12zw?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="au9WM1"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;They're already running amok, amok, amok!   &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BetteMidler?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@BetteMidler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SJP?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@SJP&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kathynajimy?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@KathyNajimy&lt;/a&gt; are in production on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/HocusPocus2?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#HocusPocus2&lt;/a&gt;, coming Fall 2022 on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DisneyPlus?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#DisneyPlus&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DisneyPlusDay?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#DisneyPlusDay&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/deTH8HxPjW"&gt;pic.twitter.com/deTH8HxPjW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Disney+ (@disneyplus) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/disneyplus/status/1459169624692387842?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 12, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22776901/disney-plus-day-time-date-new-titles"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22776901/disney-plus-day-time-date-new-titles</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-12T08:57:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-12T08:57:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>The latest Nest Learning Thermostat is $70 off for Verge readers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NPsMvsf_hPsvNIG0tXW7aBeOPtA=/202x0:1272x713/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70132180/nestlearningthermo_screenshot.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iuw3pA"&gt;It’s Friday once again, and two more Fridays from now will be the big one: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/black-friday"&gt;Black Friday&lt;/a&gt;. I bet you’re also thinking to yourselves, “Just where has the time gone?” Well, it’s flying by for all of us, and while our excellent (if I say so myself) &lt;em&gt;Verge Deals&lt;/em&gt; team has been hard at work on our beautiful &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22759813/holiday-gift-guide-best-tech-gadget-unique-ideas"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;Holiday Gift Guide&lt;/a&gt; for you to peruse and adding a bunch of hot &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22759214/black-friday-early-deals-best-headphones-laptops-gaming-tvs-tech-sale"&gt;early Black Friday deals&lt;/a&gt; to shop, we even have some exceptional deals for you today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dUJw51"&gt;First up, we have an exclusive deal on the Google Nest Learning Thermostat (third generation) for &lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;readers. You can &lt;a href="https://shareasale.com/r.cfm?b=1264455&amp;amp;u=1225169&amp;amp;m=83747&amp;amp;urllink=www%2Ewellbots%2Ecom%2Fproducts%2Fgoogle%2Dnest%2Dlearning%2Dthermostat%2D3rd%2Dgeneration&amp;amp;afftrack=VergeDailyDeal111221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;save $70 on the Nest Learning Thermostat at Wellbots&lt;/a&gt;. Use the coupon code &lt;strong&gt;THEVERGENEST &lt;/strong&gt;through December 1st to bring the price of the stainless steel, white, or polished steel finishes all the way down to $179.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IaMVAD"&gt;This is one of the few smart thermostats that lets you set it and forget it, if you choose to. Many other models can allow you to control your home heating and cooling remotely, with extra features like geofencing and optional remote temperature sensors, but few learn from your habits and preferences like this Nest unit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ENuTYR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Google shares its commitment to Matter, promises future interoperability between smart home platforms  ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/21/22738584/google-smart-home-developer-summit-2021-matter-thread"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="jZErbh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9736404"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XuRPpI"&gt;If you’re shopping for a set of true wireless earbuds for an Android phone, it can feel a bit like the Wild West. Samsung’s offerings are frequently discounted, but they might not be everyone’s style. The OnePlus Buds Pro, though, feature a subdued design, solid noise cancellation, and good audio quality at an affordable price. They’re also lightweight — weighing in at just 4.35 ounces per earbud — and they come with a charging case that is actually pocketable, unlike some competing models, like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/3/18292853/beats-powerbeats-pro-true-wireless-earbuds-announced-airpods"&gt;Beats Powerbeats Pro&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eKB0l7"&gt;&lt;a href="https://onepluscom.pxf.io/c/482924/916678/12532?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oneplus.com%2Fproduct%2Foneplus-buds-pro&amp;amp;subid1=vergedailyroundup111221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;OnePlus itself is offering these earbuds for $50 off&lt;/a&gt;, for a best-yet price of $100. That’s a great deal for these earbuds considering that they just came out in September. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22637548/oneplus-buds-pro-review-specs-price-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="k2ESIN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best wireless earbuds to buy right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="LUmkIr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10860138"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hdol61"&gt;Sticking with deals in the realm of audio, but shifting gears just a bit to the world of gaming, the wired Xbox Stereo Headset offers a very budget-friendly option of quality audio for Xbox and PC gamers (or anything else that has a 3.5mm input). It looks a lot like the more &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22325883/microsoft-xbox-wireless-headset-gaming-series-x-s-pc-windows-10-review"&gt;expensive Wireless Stereo Headset&lt;/a&gt;, but it is nearly half the price and you never have to worry about charging it. Normally $60, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B09C2JSK2X/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon currently has it for just $50&lt;/a&gt; — a discount of 17 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wwAoYq"&gt;If you’re looking for something higher end, then we have you covered in our roundup of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549510/best-gaming-headset-wired-wireless-features-specs-price-sound-microphone-test-buy"&gt;the best wired and wireless gaming headsets&lt;/a&gt;, but at this price it’s hard to deny the appeal of a simple product at a great price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WfulKn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10860198"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="irF2iz"&gt;I already mentioned that we were shifting gears to the world of gaming, but now we’re shifting actual gears on real (virtual) cars thanks to this great deal on &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5. &lt;/em&gt;The latest iteration in the open-world driving series landed this week, and it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22762183/forza-horizon-5-perfect-portable-xbox-game-series-x-s-pc-steam"&gt;has a lot to offer on Xbox Series X / S consoles&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5 &lt;/em&gt;is available on Xbox and PC on Xbox Game Pass, but if you prefer physical copies of games, then Walmart and Amazon are helping you out with an early deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="npx3Nf"&gt;Both &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FForza-Horizon-5-Microsoft-Xbox-One-Xbox-Series-X-Physical%2F694914231&amp;amp;subid1=vergedailyroundup111221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Forza-Horizon-Standard-Xbox-One-X/dp/B097MGZ7MY?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; are offering &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5 &lt;/em&gt;for Xbox Series X / S and Xbox One consoles at $51, saving you 15 percent just shortly after the launch of one of Xbox’s hottest new games. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jl4sIM"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10847621"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Xhh6HA"&gt;Over at Amazon’s early Black Friday deals, there are some &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/deal/4998f143?showVariations=true&amp;amp;ref=dlx_early_gd_dcl_img_8_4998f143_dt_sl5_f1"&gt;excellent savings on a variety of Shure microphones&lt;/a&gt;. These include some of the heavy-hitters of the podcast world, like the broadcast-quality SM7B and its newer offspring: the MV7 and MV7X. You probably know the sound of a Shure SM7B even if you’re not an audiophile, as it’s one of the most popular podcast mics in the industry. People often choose it for the darker tones it offers, giving that NPR-like warmth to even nasally voices. Of course, a good EQ and pre-amp can be just as important as the mic itself for high-end productions, especially for the SM7B which is very quiet without a quality interface or in-line boost for added gain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="I3uY3c"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10860971"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3yiT1i"&gt;The Shure SM7B, MV7, and MV7X are all dynamic microphones, so while that means you are best served by talking directly into them — up-close and right into the mic — it also means your voice is isolated, and the background noises or reflections bouncing off of hard surfaces in your room are reduced. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xoPx4i"&gt;All three mics are discounted at Amazon and other retailers like B&amp;amp;H, Adorama, and Best Buy. The Shure SM7B is $359 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Shure-SM7B-Cardioid-Dynamic-Microphone/dp/B0002E4Z8M?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F225820-REG%2FShure_SM7B_SM7B_Cardioid_Dynamic.html%3Fsts%3Dpi%26pim%3DY&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F11%2F12%2F22776977%2Fgoogle-nest-learning-thermostat-oneplus-buds-pro-xbox-headset-mic-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://adorama.rfvk.net/c/482924/51926/1036?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.adorama.com%2Fshsm7b.html&amp;amp;subid1=vergedailyroundup111221"&gt;Adorama&lt;/a&gt; — discounted $40 off its normal price of $399. The MV7, which is newer and simplest to use thanks to its option of direct USB connection, is on sale for $219 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Shure-Microphone-Podcasting-Voice-Isolating-Technology/dp/B08G7RG9ML?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1593379-REG%2Fshure_mv7_k_mv7_mic.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F11%2F12%2F22776977%2Fgoogle-nest-learning-thermostat-oneplus-buds-pro-xbox-headset-mic-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://adorama.rfvk.net/c/482924/51926/1036?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.adorama.com%2Fshmv7k.html&amp;amp;subid1=vergedailyroundup111221"&gt;Adorama&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfY84jNrp1T" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; — $30 off its standard price of $249. Lastly, the newest spinoff of the SM7B, the MV7X, comes in at a savings of $30 for the lowest price of $149 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Shure-Microphone-Podcasting-Voice-Isolating-Technology/dp/B09BZZCGC8?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1658148-REG%2Fshure_mv7x_podcast_xlr_microphone.html%3Fsts%3Dpi%26pim%3DY&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F11%2F12%2F22776977%2Fgoogle-nest-learning-thermostat-oneplus-buds-pro-xbox-headset-mic-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://adorama.rfvk.net/c/482924/51926/1036?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.adorama.com%2Fshmv7x.html%3Forigterm%3Dmv7x%26searchredirect%3Dtrue&amp;amp;subid1=vergedailyroundup111221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Adorama&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfY843TkGNP" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. That’s a lot of mic for the value, though keep in mind that when opting for the high-end SM7B or entry-level MV7X, you need an audio interface for their XLR-only connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ad77UF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"What the experts use: Andrew Marino’s podcasting gear","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21512739/podcast-gear-microphone-daw-electro-voice-shure-adobe"},{"title":"How to get great audio for podcast interviews","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22652143/podcast-interviews-audio-mic-how-to-noise"},{"title":"The best microphones to start podcasting with","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/5/18295732/podcast-microphone-best-top-price-specs-features-rode-blue-shure"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="pmW5Hg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10729885"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="GrThFy"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10860977"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hNQCmQ"&gt;A few more deals to have your eye on&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="SC97sy"&gt;The second-generation Apple AirPods are still available at their all-time low price of &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Charging-Case-2nd-Generation%2F604342441%3Fathbdg%3DL1800&amp;amp;subid1=vergedailyroundup111221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$90 from Walmart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="5PuKWq"&gt;The AirPods Max are &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfY9nhSpo38" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$70 off at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, discounted to $479, and have Best Buy’s Black Friday price guarantee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2D8tLw"&gt;Sony’s ZV-1 video-centric point-and-shoot camera with vlogger accessory kit is &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1566753-REG%2Fsony_sony_zv_1_digital_camera.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F11%2F12%2F22776977%2Fgoogle-nest-learning-thermostat-oneplus-buds-pro-xbox-headset-mic-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$746 off at B&amp;amp;H&lt;/a&gt;, a savings of $150.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JFWndo"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfY9pdtzuHL" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy has many Google Assistant-powered smart devices on discount&lt;/a&gt; for this weekend, including the Nest Mini smart speaker for $25 and the Nest Audio for $60. All of these deals have Black Friday price guarantees. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="eYqzsx"&gt;The Fitbit Charge 5 that recently released is discounted at Best Buy, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfY9slKugI8" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on sale for $130&lt;/a&gt; (a savings of $50).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="Knxo1S"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/11/12/22776977/google-nest-learning-thermostat-oneplus-buds-pro-xbox-headset-mic-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/11/12/22776977/google-nest-learning-thermostat-oneplus-buds-pro-xbox-headset-mic-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-12T07:54:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-12T07:54:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>World’s first USB-C iPhone sells on eBay for $86,001</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OMn_XL__RTecS6p-9n3QoN3_Ueg=/0x0:768x512/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70131929/msedge_8C53o6F5aS.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OXksGg"&gt;A modified iPhone X that has a USB-C port instead of a Lightning port has &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ebay.com%2Fitm%2F165161363347&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F11%2F12%2F22777988%2Fusb-c-iphone-x-lightning-ebay-auction-86001" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;sold on eBay&lt;/a&gt; for the princely sum of $86,001. The phone, which is the work of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722123/first-iphone-usb-c-port-robotics-engineering-student-custom"&gt;robotics engineering student Kenn Pillonel&lt;/a&gt;, can use the physical connector for both charging and transferring data. But Pillonel warns that the buyer &lt;a href="http://vi.vipr.ebaydesc.com/ws/eBayISAPI.dll?ViewItemDescV4&amp;amp;item=165161363347&amp;amp;t=0&amp;amp;category=9355&amp;amp;seller=geeken&amp;amp;excSoj=1&amp;amp;excTrk=1&amp;amp;lsite=0&amp;amp;ittenable=false&amp;amp;domain=ebay.com&amp;amp;descgauge=1&amp;amp;cspheader=1&amp;amp;oneClk=2&amp;amp;secureDesc=0&amp;amp;oversion=f3d3fc33"&gt;shouldn’t use the groundbreaking device as a regular phone&lt;/a&gt;, take it apart, or update the OS — any of which could risk breaking it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J2qoMU"&gt;The fact that the mod has sold for over eighty times its original sale price shouldn’t come as much of a surprise. Although Pillonel has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22759704/usb-c-iphone-hack-mod-open-source-github-repo-ken-pillonel-design-video"&gt;open-sourced his work on the project&lt;/a&gt; in a Github repository containing technical details, CNC instructions, and information on the custom PCB the design uses, actually replicating the modification is no mean feat. Especially since it involves installing extra circuitry into the phone’s chassis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MvNfAL"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FVEQJNRmfDQ?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dWWc7L"&gt;The auction started at just $1, but bidding had reached over $3,000 by the end of its first day, before quickly climbing into the tens of thousands. There were also a couple of much higher bids of around $100,000 that were retracted before the auction came to an end. It attracted a total of 116 bids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RXaW8w"&gt;Although the prototype has now been sold, Pillonel has previously said he intends to continue working to improve elements like the USB-C iPhones’ fast-charging, waterproofing, and adding support for USB-C accessories. With the design open-sourced, and the prototype released into the world, it’s a project that’ll hopefully become a team effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="szUoit"&gt;If you’d like to hear more about Pillonel’s project, check out his appearance on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22772024/vergecast-podcast-usb-c-future"&gt;the Vergecast&lt;/a&gt; this week.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22777988/usb-c-iphone-x-lightning-ebay-auction-86001"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22777988/usb-c-iphone-x-lightning-ebay-auction-86001</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
