<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-08T17:17:19-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-08T17:17:19-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-08T17:17:19-05:00</updated>
    <title>CD Projekt Red is working to settle a class-action lawsuit over botched Cyberpunk 2077 launch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TohRpJ9Iy3WNFOCeJjFJVODvBgY=/30x0:1460x953/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70247073/Cyberpunk2077_The_man_with_the_silver_hand_RGB_en.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Johnny Silverhand in &lt;/em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: CD Projekt Red&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1CbLps"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; developer CD Projekt Red has &lt;a href="https://www.cdprojekt.com/en/investors/regulatory-announcements/current-report-no-43-2021/"&gt;entered negotiations&lt;/a&gt; to settle a class-action lawsuit over the game’s bungled launch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lOhkKl"&gt;There are still a number of outstanding questions about any potential settlement, &lt;a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/21150635-in-chambers-order-re-notice-of-settlement-and-requirements-re-preliminary-approval"&gt;according to court documents&lt;/a&gt;, including all class certification requirements, the proposed allocation plan for the settlement fund, and how the settlement will be administered. In other words, it’s undecided exactly who will be eligible for anything awarded in a settlement or how much those eligible parties may receive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gCybyu"&gt;The plaintiffs in the case must next file a preliminary approval of the settlement or an update on its status by January 13th, 2022. Four lawsuits against the company were compiled into one &lt;a href="https://www.cdprojekt.com/en/investors/regulatory-announcements/current-report-no-27-2021/"&gt;in May&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eQmsu7"&gt;At release (which was almost exactly one year ago), &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22197547/cyberpunk-2077-glitches"&gt;many glitches&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/digitalfoundry-2077-cyberpunk-2077-how-bad-is-last-gen-performance-and-can-it-be-improved"&gt;ran quite poorly on older consoles&lt;/a&gt;. Things were so bad that Sony pulled the game from the PlayStation Store &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22188007/sony-cyberpunk-2077-removed-playstation-store-full-refunds-policy"&gt;within a week&lt;/a&gt;. CDPR has spent much of the year since trying to fix things up with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22627096/cyberpunk-2077-patch-1-3-reset-perks-mini-map"&gt;hotfixes and updates&lt;/a&gt;, and the game eventually returned to the PlayStation Store &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/21/22543298/cyberpunk-2077-playstation-store-ps4-warning"&gt;after more than six months&lt;/a&gt;. The studio also pushed a planned update optimizing &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; for next-gen consoles &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/29/22808038/cd-projekt-red-cyberpunk-2077-next-gen-update-release-date"&gt;into 2022&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="tJP67p"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/21150635-in-chambers-order-re-notice-of-settlement-and-requirements-re-preliminary-approval/?embed=1&amp;amp;responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="(In Chambers) Order Re: Notice of Settlement and Requirements Re: Preliminary Approval (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="905" style="border: 1px solid #aaa; width: 100%; height: 800px; height: calc(100vh - 100px);" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22824847/cd-projekt-red-settle-class-action-lawsuit-cyberpunk-2077-launch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22824847/cd-projekt-red-settle-class-action-lawsuit-cyberpunk-2077-launch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-08T17:12:08-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-08T17:12:08-05:00</updated>
    <title>Instagram head says it’s bringing back the chronological feed</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yxBE7qui038gdQiz00edJnGtcl0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70246745/acastro_190919_1777_instagram_0002.0.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Instagram is working on a chronological feed | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MuDoWa"&gt;During a hearing before a Senate subcommittee on Wednesday, Instagram head Adam Mosseri said the company is working on a version of its feed that would show users' posts in chronological order, unlike its current ranking algorithm that sorts posts based on user preferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1AHzuD"&gt;The company’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/6/3/11853026/instagram-algorithm-feed-global"&gt;algorithmically sorted feed&lt;/a&gt;, introduced in 2016, and then updated in 2017 to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/27/16823118/instagram-recommended-posts-feature-roll-out-now-android-ios"&gt;include recommended posts&lt;/a&gt;, is widely disliked by users who prefer to have their posts and their friends’ posts surface in a timely manner. The current feed uses AI to create what Instagram considers a more personalized feed, based on users’ activity. But it has remained generally unpopular among a vast swath of users, despite the company’s assertions otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vlcBxR"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22816730/mosseri-testimony-instagram-senate-hearing-haugen-child-safety-facebook-meta"&gt;Mosseri appeared before the Senate subcommittee&lt;/a&gt; where he was grilled by senators about child safety issues on the app, prompted in part by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22710371/facebook-whistleblower-congress-hearing-instagram-kids-safety-privacy-blumenthal"&gt;revelations from whistleblower Frances Haugen&lt;/a&gt;, who provided internal documents to &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-facebook-files-11631713039"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/a&gt;that suggested the company was aware its app may be “toxic” for teenagers. “Have some empathy. Take some responsibility,” Sen. Marsha Blackburn (R-TN) chided Mosseri as the hearing wound down.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WnJ4p6"&gt;During his testimony, Mosseri proposed the creation of an “industry body”  that would determine best practices over the handling of children’s data and parental controls to help keep children safe online. The body would receive input from parents, regulators, and civil society, to create universal standards and protections. Mosseri said platforms would need to earn the protections of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21273768/section-230-explained-internet-speech-law-definition-guide-free-moderation"&gt;Section 230&lt;/a&gt; of the Communications Decency Act by following those standards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xaVLRP"&gt;Senators seemed skeptical that such an an “industry body” could be effective. “The time for self-regulation is over,” said Sen. Richard Blumenthal (D-CT), who has called for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/26/22747330/snap-tiktok-youtube-facebook-papers-blumenthal-coppa-kids-child-safety"&gt;online child safety measures&lt;/a&gt; to address concerns about Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="h72kIU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Section 230 is 25 years old, and it’s never been more important","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22268421/cda-section-230-25th-anniversary-reform-stakes-big-tech-internet"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="NpKoa9"&gt;On Tuesday, Instagram rolled out the “Take a Break” feature it started testing last month to users in the US and other English-speaking countries. The opt-in feature prompts users to pause using the app after they’ve been using it for a certain time period. More parental controls over their teenagers’ use of Instagram will be released next year, Mosseri said Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OQYhB8"&gt;“What you’ve suggested so far is underwhelming,” Blumenthal told Mosseri before ending Wednesday’s hearing, referring to Take a Break and the other updates. “That ain’t gonna save kids from the addictive effects ... of your platform.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="10fCHl"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22824609/instagram-chronological-feed-adam-mosseri"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22824609/instagram-chronological-feed-adam-mosseri</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-08T16:09:08-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-08T16:09:08-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple will pay for Jennifer Lawrence to play Elizabeth Holmes in new Theranos film</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Fortune Global Forum - Day 1" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pxoo7k-7HQrQf9OJFIaNGabPaLA=/0x0:2627x1751/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70246655/495430024.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Kimberly White/Getty Images for Fortune&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="L3yGHn"&gt;Apple says it will produce a movie about former Theranos CEO Elizabeth Holmes, with Jennifer Lawrence of &lt;em&gt;Hunger Games &lt;/em&gt;fame in the starring role. The movie, to be directed by &lt;em&gt;Succession&lt;/em&gt; creator Adam McKay, will be based on the bestselling book &lt;em&gt;Bad Blood: Secrets and Lies in a Silicon Valley Startup&lt;/em&gt; by former &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; reporter John Carreyrou. He &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/theranos-has-struggled-with-blood-tests-1444881901"&gt;wrote the first news stories&lt;/a&gt; detailing Theranos’ problems, even as the company and Holmes were being lauded in Silicon Valley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sfmkHy"&gt;Holmes is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22792606/elizabeth-holmes-fraud-witness-stand-surprise"&gt;currently on trial&lt;/a&gt; facing 11 counts of wire fraud and conspiracy to commit wire fraud after it was discovered that Theranos’ blood testing technology didn’t meet the standards it claimed to investors. At the time of its unraveling, Theranos was valued at $9 billion, and Holmes was labeled the youngest self-made billionaire and featured on &lt;em&gt;Fortune’s&lt;/em&gt; 40 under 40 list. Later in 2016, Holmes &lt;a href="https://fortune.com/2016/03/30/most-disappointing-leaders/"&gt;was named&lt;/a&gt; one of the world’s most disappointing leaders. She faces up to 20 years in prison, if convicted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="VO77Ec"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Elizabeth Holmes is on trial for fraud over her time at Theranos ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22684354/elizabeth-holmes-trial-wire-fraud-theranos"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="OJkkmb"&gt;The film is the another confirmed project about the Theranos scandal. Earlier this year, Hulu confirmed that it would be making &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2021/03/amanda-seyfried-elizabeth-holmes-the-dropout-hulu-theranos-kate-mckinnon-1234723500/"&gt;a docuseries&lt;/a&gt; starring Amanda Seyfried.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xaFk7o"&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22824561/apple-theranos-elizabeth-homes-jennifer-lawrence-adam-mckay-bad-blood"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22824561/apple-theranos-elizabeth-homes-jennifer-lawrence-adam-mckay-bad-blood</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jasmine Hicks</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-08T15:27:02-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-08T15:27:02-05:00</updated>
    <title>Sony shows off a robot grabber, 4K OLED panels for VR, and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e1vTG29mrjApDs9sRdAlIUPqqEA=/0x0:2391x1594/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70246409/Screen_Shot_2021_12_08_at_11.09.19.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Sony&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="asltNV"&gt;Sony’s holding &lt;a href="https://www.sony.com/en/SonyInfo/technology/activities/Tech2021/"&gt;its Technology Day event&lt;/a&gt; to show off what it’s been working on in its R&amp;amp;D labs, and this year, we got some great visuals of tech the company’s been working on. Amidst the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ugil99qEyX8"&gt;rehashes of the PS5’s haptics and 3D audio&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZBO6ZVrFBYc"&gt;demo reel&lt;/a&gt; of Sony’s admittedly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/6/22217554/sony-selling-microled-production-display-mandalorian-production"&gt;awesome displays for making virtual movie sets&lt;/a&gt;, we got to see a robot hand that Sony said could figure out grip strength depending on what it was picking up, a slightly dystopian-sounding “global sensing system,” and more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q5hZNV"&gt;Perhaps the most interesting thing Sony showed off was a headset that featured OLED displays with “4K-per-inch” resolution. While the headset Sony used in its presentation was very clearly something intended for lab and prototype use, the specs Sony laid out for the panels were reminiscent of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/10/22429523/playstation-vr-ps5-rumors-eye-tracking-foviated-render-4k-screen-haptics"&gt;rumors swirling around the PlayStation VR 2&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hfOK3_X-yMnj4CS5glhM8SyvhBw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23071607/Screen_Shot_2021_12_07_at_16.30.05.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This probably isn’t what the next PlayStation headset will look like.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="3G4cxC"&gt;They don’t exactly line up, though; Sony said the headset it showed off was 8K, given the 4K display per eye, and the PS VR 2 will supposedly only be 4K overall with 2000 x 2040 pixels per eye. Still, it’s exciting that Sony is working on VR-focused panels, along with latency reduction tech for them. In a Q&amp;amp;A session for journalists, Sony wouldn’t answer questions about when the displays would show up in an actual product but said that various divisions were already looking into how they could integrate them into products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="SBCojs"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QkJJA0PCOxI?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gBsFFw"&gt;Sony also showed off a robotic grabber, a mechanized pincer that could be used to let a machine pick up objects. While that’s nothing new, Sony did say that its version had the ability to precisely control grip strength depending on what it was holding, letting it hold things tightly enough that they don’t slip (and adjusting if they do start to fall) without crushing delicate items like a vegetable or flower.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AK4UPgdwyCxxPYbszxegP-6FPB8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23073689/ezgif_7_4177876d6075.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Gif: Sony&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oh to have a robot hand me a rose and then be able to hold my hand without crushing it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="U9JdzF"&gt;Sony says the grabber could be used to cook or line up items in a shop window, though to get that level of functionality, it would have to be paired with a way to move and AI that let it determine what objects it needed to pick up. It’s hard to imagine we’ll see that sort of thing in public any time soon, but it does make for an impressive demo. It’s also nice that Sony made it look very robotic rather than having it look like a hand — I’ve had my fill of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/5/22819328/humanoid-robot-eerily-lifelike-facial-expressions"&gt;eerily human-looking robot parts&lt;/a&gt; for this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="fVjngG"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/T6vX7FcBQMs?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XejNNl"&gt;Sony’s presentation also had some neat visuals to go with other projects, as well as another look at some devices we’ve seen before. It showed off some machine-learning supersampling tech (similar to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/16/22784404/nvidia-icat-dlss-spatial-temporal-upscaling-graphics"&gt;Nvidia’s DLSS system&lt;/a&gt;), which it said it could use to improve resolution and performance for ray-traced rendering. A GIF of Sony’s comparison shots would ruin the quality, but you can check it out in the video below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WELE6p"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AL7Odi8wCO8?rel=0&amp;amp;start=231" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pCNStaC8deGruFUNXmjiXafAUuU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23073663/ezgif_7_a538a62c91c0.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Sony&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Sony had some neat visuals to show off its depth sensor that it says can be used for Lidar systems &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/8/21056404/sony-vision-s-electric-concept-prototype-first-look-ces-2020" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;in cars.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="gctRAG"&gt;Finally, Sony talked about its “Mimamori” system, which it said is designed to watch over the planet. When I was watching the presentation in real time, I started to get a little worried when I saw this slide:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KKTselBaQJ2GPYZsvqmTCyx6zUc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23071665/Screen_Shot_2021_12_07_at_16.56.11.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Whatcha up to here Sony?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="8dhfYz"&gt;Sony went on to explain, though, that its idea was to use satellites to gather data from sensors placed all over the earth, made to collect information about soil moisture, temperature, and more. Its pitch is that it could help scientists gather information on how the climate is changing and help farmers adapt to those changes. Mimamori seemed like it was closer to a pitch than a prototype, but it shows that Sony is at least looking into how it can leverage &lt;a href="https://www.sony-semicon.co.jp/products_en/eltres/technology.html"&gt;some of its tech&lt;/a&gt; to help deal with climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="BRGYcV"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5QborgyXIkk?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sLvFiM"&gt;While some of the ideas Sony showed off seem like moonshots, it’s interesting to get a peek into what Sony’s doing in its labs, beyond creating PlayStations and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/4/22817957/spider-man-across-the-spider-verse-part-one-sequelanimated-multiverse-miles-morales"&gt;Spider-Verse sequels&lt;/a&gt;. Even if we don’t end up getting consumer devices out of it, at least we got some pretty cool futuristic visuals.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22823188/sony-technology-day-presentation-vr-oled-screens-robot-grabber"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22823188/sony-technology-day-presentation-vr-oled-screens-robot-grabber</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-08T14:55:27-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-08T14:55:27-05:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon’s excellent Smart Thermostat is even more affordable today </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-rikk4ve-Dbaex2opcFzYLFT5Tg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70244108/jtuohy_211115_4885_0006.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can use the Alexa app to control Amazon’s Smart Thermostat, which is currently enjoying its first discount.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Jennifer Pattison Tuohy / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="85aJOu"&gt;Even without a discount attached to it, Amazon’s surprisingly great Smart Thermostat is a good deal in itself. After our reviewer spent a decade testing almost every smart thermostat since the launch of the Nest Learning Thermostat, she &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22791333/amazon-smart-thermostat-review-learning-geofencing-hunches"&gt;found&lt;/a&gt; it to be one of the best yet. That’s saying a lot, and it’s pretty impressive given this is an affordable smart thermostat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZJWOjc"&gt;The thermostat is discounted for the first time today, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08J4C8871?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;selling for $47.99 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; — a 20 percent discount on its typical $59.99. Built in collaboration with Resideo, the makers of Honeywell Home Thermostat Technology, this gadget is capable of learning and adapting to your schedule, just like more expensive thermostats out there. With the price in mind, it does lack some features. Perhaps the most egregious omission is that it doesn’t integrate with platforms or voice assistants besides Alexa. Yet, if you’re looking for a good basic thermostat with which you can control the temperature of your home (even while traveling), this is definitely worth considering. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="took9t"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10907379"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SE0OPc"&gt;Sonos is offering great deals on its refurbished products through December 31st. You can buy, for example, the latest generation of the Sonos One for &lt;a href="https://www.tkqlhce.com/click-8836598-11556673?sid=VergeDeals120821&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.sonos.com%2Fen-us%2Fshop%2Fone-b-stock.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$129&lt;/a&gt;, nearly $100 less than its full $219 retail cost when purchased new. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2017/10/18/16490866/sonos-one-speaker-review-alexa"&gt;first-generation&lt;/a&gt; is also on sale for $129, but lacks Bluetooth Low Energy support, has a slower processor, and comes with less memory than the second-gen. Meanwhile, the first-generation &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/27/17507796/sonos-beam-speaker-soundbar-alexa-review"&gt;Sonos Beam&lt;/a&gt; soundbar is selling for &lt;a href="https://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8532386-11556673?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.sonos.com%2Fen-us%2Fshop%2Fbeam-white-b-stock.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$259&lt;/a&gt; as opposed to $399, the price when purchased new. While it lacks Dolby Atmos support like the second-gen model, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22701137/sonos-beam-gen-2-atmos-soundbar-review-specs"&gt;we found&lt;/a&gt; it’s still a competent smart speaker that shares many features in common with the newer version. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HZAD3l"&gt;All of the discounted refurbished products will arrive in a box with the original accessories and cables. They’ve also been certified directly from Sonos, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21530290/refurbished-tech-products-gadgets-where-to-buy-amazon-ebay"&gt;means&lt;/a&gt; the company has tested and given each an internal and external cleaning and inspection. Each product also comes with a one-year warranty and a 45-day money-back guarantee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="N3fELm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10523576"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="TMUytT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9603369"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mDSO0B"&gt;If you prefer earbuds to bulkier headphones, you might want to grab the second-gen Apple AirPods at Amazon since they’re just &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Charging-Latest-Model/dp/B07PXGQC1Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$99.99&lt;/a&gt;. That matches its second-lowest price after we saw the earbuds drop to $89 during early Black Friday sales. It’s also a lower price than what we saw on Black Friday and Cyber Monday, when they were selling for around $110. Typically around $129, this model offers excellent wireless performance, reliable battery life, and is easy to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zVYh9F"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Y89YAm"&gt;If you’ve got a little more cash to spare, and you’re in the market for a pair of excellent over-ear headphones, &lt;a href="https://adorama.rfvk.net/c/482924/51926/1036?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.adorama.com%2Fsowh100xm4ba.html&amp;amp;subid1=VergeDeals120821"&gt;Adorama&lt;/a&gt; is bundling Sony’s WH-1000XM4 with Mophie’s Power Boost XXL 20,800mAh battery power bank for just $248. That matches the Black Friday and Cyber Monday price many retailers sold the $349.99 headphones for just by themselves. Mophie’s power bank typically sells for $39.95 itself, so this bundle is valued at around $390. Plus, the bundle also includes a small microfiber cleaning cloth to boot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B6501a"&gt;As we noted in our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21356313/sony-1000xm4-noise-canceling-headphones-review-price-specs-features"&gt;review&lt;/a&gt; (and as you’ve probably read in our deals coverage many times before), Sony’s excellent WH-1000XM4 boast the company’s best noise-canceling capabilities yet. We gave the headphones a 9/10 partly because of it, along with their stellar comfort, sound quality, and the fact they also let you connect to two Bluetooth sources simultaneously (this was missing in the XM3). Meanwhile, Mophie’s portable power bank comes with two USB-A ports so you can charge your headphones and phone simultaneously, and it charges via Micro USB. The company claims as well that its 20,800mAh battery offers up to 77 hours of extra battery life, but note we haven’t tested this product, so we can’t confirm if this is truly the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lQfWTW"&gt;Of course, if you prefer to just buy the headphones by themselves, many are still selling them for just $248, including &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf2gyfQV3mV" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-1000XM4-Canceling-Headphones-phone-call/dp/B0863TXGM3?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="90yl6V"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10907261"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ezhNoP"&gt;Govee’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22566408/govee-immersion-ambilight-tv-backlight-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Immersion TV LED backlights&lt;/a&gt; are fun, colorful lights that can make watching movies and gaming look more immersive. They sync to the colors on your screen (it supports 55- to 65-inch TVs) to make it appear as if its bezels have disappeared and the colors are expanding onto your walls. In other words, they’ll make for some pretty cool holiday gifts. Govee’s backlighting kit released in 2020 is back on sale at Amazon. For a limited time, you can pick one up for just $63.99 once you clip the $20 off coupon at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Govee-Immersion-Backlights-Ambient-Assistant/dp/B08LVPWQQP/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, which is nearly the product’s best price to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qsGMEZ"&gt;Govee is also selling this product direct &lt;a href="https://us.govee.com/products/immersion-tv-backlights" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;for $62.99&lt;/a&gt; as a part of its holiday sale, which is a little cheaper. Still, if you prefer to shop from Amazon or are a Prime member, the Amazon deal could be the better option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="plsQMm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10681491"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8zH8SZ"&gt;For those still trying to nab a PlayStation 5 — or for those lucky enough to already have one — one of our picks for the best SSDs compatible with the PS5 is currently at its best price ever. Normally $229.99, Amazon is selling the 1TB version of Samsung’s 980 Pro for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08GLX7TNT/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$169.99&lt;/a&gt; instead. That’s a $60 discount on Samsung’s blazingly fast SSD, which is one of the few kinds of drives on the market that meet Sony’s performance requirements. It’s also compatible with PC, though you’ll only get its advertised PCIe 4.0 speeds if you have a compatible motherboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zyhOxD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10678130"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="NPAcho"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The PlayStation 5 will be available for Walmart Plus members on Wednesday","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/6/22821037/ps5-playstation-5-restock-available-walmart-plus-queue-deal-sale"},{"title":"Why the PS5 paywall isn’t worthwhile at Amazon, Walmart, or Best Buy","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22771984/ps5-restock-xbox-best-buy-walmart-amazon-subscription"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="VzJPoI"&gt;Shifting away from SSDs to gaming controllers, Razer’s Kishi is a great gift for gamers on the go traveling this holiday season. You can clamp it onto your Android phone and easily transform it into a Nintendo Switch lookalike. It’s also compatible with many games available on a variety of cloud-based gaming platforms, including Google Stadia, Microsoft xCloud, and more. It’s typically a bit pricey at $79.99, but right now both &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf9PMTEDGaM" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B086X8DHN2/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; are taking nearly 50 percent off, selling it for $44.99 instead. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21285073/razer-kishi-review-game-controller-phone-price-nintendo-switch-stadia" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wf8m22"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10882522"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="CH57MS"&gt;But wait! There’s more! Here are some other notable deals happening:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="title"&gt;If you’re an iPhone 12 Mini owner, Amazon is selling Apple’s black MagSafe leather case for just &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08L5PWGZY/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$23.99&lt;/a&gt; instead of $59 — a 59 percent discount.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="CUE8yB"&gt;Right now, PayPal is selling a $100 GameStop gift card for &lt;a href="https://www.paypal.com/us/gifts/brands/gamestopdecgood"&gt;$90&lt;/a&gt; that you can also use at ThinkGeek, EB Games, Babbage’s, and Planet X stores. It’s a good chance to save a little on a holiday gift or while treating yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="OKgxx0"&gt;Amazon’s also offering a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/events/epicdeals" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;variety of deals&lt;/a&gt; on gift cards, like this &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Vudu-Gift-Cards-Email-Delivery/dp/B09J7SKH8N?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$50 Vudu card for $40&lt;/a&gt; when you use the code &lt;strong&gt;VUDU&lt;/strong&gt; at checkout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="o4qnWv"&gt;Costco members can get one of Microsoft’s latest Xbox wireless controllers in white &lt;a href="https://www.costco.com/xbox-wireless-controller-robot-white.product.100735150.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;for just $30&lt;/a&gt; (normally around $55).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="4VjdQW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="rThZTp"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction December 8th, 11:45AM PT:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;An earlier version of this story claimed that the Amazon Smart Air Thermostat was “built in collaboration with Honeywell Home.” It was not. It was instead built in collaboration with Resideo, the makers of Honeywell Home Thermostat Technology. We regret the error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qlP4ir"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gZN9Jk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yvs6YS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nkTGGe"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/12/8/22822289/amazon-thermostat-sonos-samsung-980-pro-razer-kishi-airpods-govee-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/12/8/22822289/amazon-thermostat-sonos-samsung-980-pro-razer-kishi-airpods-govee-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-08T14:46:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-08T14:46:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>Biden wants the US government to eliminate CO2 emissions by 2050</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-POLITICS-BIDEN-AUTOMOBILE-ENVIRONMENT-GM-ENERGY" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jCa0_Ue66CN9ZUrDknbamT5Jz1o=/0x1:3497x2332/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70246056/1236627157.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by MANDEL NGAN/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mnCXiB"&gt;President Joe Biden signed an &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/08/fact-sheet-president-biden-signs-executive-order-catalyzing-americas-clean-energy-economy-through-federal-sustainability/"&gt;executive order&lt;/a&gt; Wednesday outlining a sweeping plan for the federal government to achieve carbon neutrality by 2050. Under the plan, the government would spend billions of dollars to purchase electric vehicles, upgrade federal buildings, and leverage the power of the government to shift to cleaner forms of electricity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f43JPn"&gt;It won’t be a completely seamless transition, though. The government would stop purchasing gas-powered passenger cars in 2027 but would only achieve 100 percent electric vehicle purchases by 2035. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="kvblGX"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Biden’s order would direct the government to reduce its greenhouse gas emissions by 65 percent by the end of the decade&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iXOjO9"&gt;Biden’s order would direct the government to reduce its greenhouse gas emissions by 65 percent by the end of the decade before reaching full carbon neutrality by 2050. Based on the scope of the government’s electricity demands, the president expects this would help add 10 gigawatts of clean electricity to the grid by 2030. The plan also calls for federal buildings to be “net-zero” by 2045, including a 50 percent reduction in carbon emissions by 2032. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TgzklL"&gt;The 2050 deadline for carbon neutrality is in line with what scientists have found is necessary globally to prevent catastrophic climate change. And it reflects &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22394366/joe-biden-pledge-us-greenhouse-gas-emissions-2030"&gt;the president’s broader goals&lt;/a&gt; to slash greenhouse gas emissions nationwide. Under the Paris Agreement, the US agreed to cut its emissions by up to 52 percent this decade compared to 2005 levels. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GBdHdx"&gt;There’s a growing urgency to reduce planet-warming pollution at the federal level. Experts have determined that global carbon emissions need to drop by half this decade and reach close to zero by the middle of the century in order to achieve the goals of the Paris Agreement and prevent some of the most devastating effects of climate change. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KymtGj"&gt;The US is the second-largest producer of greenhouse gases after China, but a lot of momentum was lost under former President Donald Trump, who pulled the US out of the Paris Agreement and rolled back regulations governing vehicle tailpipe emissions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="BSM9Wx"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The US is the second-largest producer of greenhouse gases after China&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9gdSFz"&gt;Regarding electric vehicles, the executive order represents the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22249237/biden-electric-vehicle-government-fleet-ev"&gt;fulfillment of a promise Biden made on the campaign trail&lt;/a&gt; to swap government fleet vehicles with American-made EVs. The second piece of his plan to spur the mass adoption of electric vehicles is to offer generous tax incentives, which is being debated in the Senate as part of the president’s Build Back Better plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="muzC6U"&gt;As of 2020, there were nearly 657,506 vehicles in the federal government’s fleet, &lt;a href="https://www.gsa.gov/policy-regulations/policy/vehicle-management-policy/federal-fleet-report"&gt;according to the General Services Administration&lt;/a&gt;. This includes 250,499 civilian vehicles, 181,462 military vehicles, and 225,545 post office vehicles. In total, that fleet represents $4.2 billion in vehicle leases, acquisitions, and purchases. And despite the pandemic, those vehicles traveled 4.16 billion miles in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vevcUq"&gt;The White House provided some early examples of how the government will begin to transition to using electric vehicles, including the Interior Department and US Park Police using electric motorcycles and dirt bikes, and the Department of Homeland Security field testing the Ford Mustang Mach-E as an enforcement vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TTLVC1"&gt;Biden’s plan represents a validation for the EV investments made by automakers over the last several years. Ford has said it will spend $29 billion introducing a raft of new EVs, while GM has committed to spending $35 billion on electric and autonomous vehicles through 2025. Meanwhile, Tesla’s remarkable stock market rally over the last two years has made it the most valuable automaker in the world and its CEO, Elon Musk, the richest man on the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ANrji9"&gt;Biden’s order may not be a direct win for Tesla, though, which has mostly focused on luxury and performance vehicles. Automakers that could benefit include Ford, which is working on an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21559954/ford-e-transit-electric-delivery-cargo-van-price-specs-range"&gt;electric version of its Transit vans&lt;/a&gt;, and GM, which just &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22225394/gm-brightdrop-electric-delivery-ep1-ev600-ces-2021"&gt;spun out a new company called BrightDrop&lt;/a&gt; focused on electric delivery vehicles. Both companies are in the process of rolling out electric trucks that would be useful for a variety of governmental purposes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Cea9Rh"&gt;&lt;q&gt;the industry will need to overcome delays related to the semiconductor shortage&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gJDUg2"&gt;But to achieve the government’s electric vehicle goals, the industry will need to overcome delays related to the semiconductor shortage and install enough charging stations to make EVs more practical. Last month, Biden &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22783684/biden-infrastructure-bill-bipartisan-broadband-ev-electrical-grid-climate"&gt;signed the $1.2 trillion infrastructure bill&lt;/a&gt; into law, which includes $7.5 billion for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/16/22765438/biden-infrastructure-bill-electric-vehicle-ev-charging-level-2"&gt;electric vehicle charging stations&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RH37M8"&gt;The hope is that Biden’s order will help spur demand for clean electricity, zero-emissions vehicles, and more sustainable building materials across the country. “The government is a significant driver of demand,” Sarah Bloom Raskin, a Duke University law professor who served as treasury deputy secretary under President Barack Obama, told &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;, adding that federal procurement officers can “send a signal” even without adopting new regulations or passing legislation. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22824500/biden-executive-order-climate-change-carbon-emissions-electric-vehicles"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22824500/biden-executive-order-climate-change-carbon-emissions-electric-vehicles</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-08T14:34:18-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-08T14:34:18-05:00</updated>
    <title>Epic v. Apple ruling put on hold after appeals court grants a stay</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BhhnGIA6YVp8MxJFlWN2Y26V12M=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70245982/acastro_20200818_1777_epicApple_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1jIgGu"&gt;An appeals court has paused one of the most consequential parts of the Epic v. Apple ruling, &lt;a href="https://s3.documentcloud.org/documents/21150555/order.pdf"&gt;placing a stay&lt;/a&gt; on the enforcement of the injunction issued by the lower court. As a result of the stay, Apple can maintain its IAP system as the sole source of in-app payments on iOS, despite the district court’s earlier ruling that the exclusive arrangement is illegal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s1Em08"&gt;The stay, issued Wednesday afternoon, does not reverse the earlier ruling but puts enforcement on hold until the appeals court can fully hear the case, a process that will likely take months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oOvKZr"&gt;“Apple has demonstrated, at minimum, that its appeal raises serious questions on the merits of the district court’s determination,” the ruling reads. “Therefore, we grant Apple’s motion to stay part (i) of paragraph (1) of the permanent injunction. The stay will remain in effect until the mandate issues in this appeal.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JU4TLH"&gt;Notably, the stay does not extend to the second part of the injunction, which dealt with user communications outside iOS. Specifically, the court ordered Apple to allow “communicating with customers through points of contact obtained voluntarily from customers through account registration within the app.” That order will remain unaffected by the stay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qZrVrh"&gt;Apple will also remain bound by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22653264/apple-reader-app-exception-anti-steering-signup-page"&gt;its agreement with the Japan Fair Steering Commission&lt;/a&gt;, which placed similar anti-steering restrictions on iOS outside the context of the Epic case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SOST0D"&gt;In September, Judge Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers required Apple to allow third-party payment systems on iOS apps as part of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/12/22667694/epic-v-apple-trial-fortnite-judge-yvonne-gonzalez-rogers-final-ruling-injunction-breakdown"&gt;a broader ruling that dismissed antitrust allegations&lt;/a&gt; brought by Fortnite developer Epic Games. Specifically, the court ruled that beginning December 9th, Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22667161/app-store-epic-ruling-difference-button-external-link"&gt;could no longer prohibit “buttons or external links”&lt;/a&gt; that direct users to payment systems outside the App Store, as the company previously had in its app store guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8HJUzU"&gt;Epic Games declined to comment when reached by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. Apple did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aqRNki"&gt;Apple had previously moved for an injunction from the district court to pause its order but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22773082/epic-apple-fortnite-lawsuit-ruling-injunction-stay-app-store-anti-steering-rules"&gt;was denied&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="YubKG3"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/21150555-order/?embed=1&amp;amp;responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="Order (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="905" style="border: 1px solid #aaa; width: 100%; height: 800px; height: calc(100vh - 100px);" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22814147/epic-apple-app-store-injunction-paused"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22814147/epic-apple-app-store-injunction-paused</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-08T14:21:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-08T14:21:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple and Hyatt begin rolling out hotel keys in Apple Wallet</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aZJlWeDJdvLeptcVsB_PQp7yiNY=/0x0:5100x3400/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70245866/apple_hyatt_hotel_keys.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Using a hotel key stored in Apple Wallet | Photo by Hyatt&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="schzpU"&gt;Apple is partnering with Hyatt to give some hotel guests the ability to store their room keys in their Apple Wallets, as announced in a post on &lt;a href="https://newsroom.hyatt.com/news-releases?item=124174#assets_all"&gt;Hyatt’s newsroom&lt;/a&gt;. Instead of checking your pockets for your room key, you’ll now be able to use your iPhone or Apple Watch to unlock your room, as well as any other areas around the hotel that require a key for entry.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jkVOqsVC9lD_s-1TszF6Tr5FLyM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23073568/hyatt_apple_watch_unlock.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Hyatt&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your Apple Watch can unlock your hotel room at participating Hyatt hotels.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="zUQSog"&gt;There are currently only six Hyatt hotels in the US that support this feature, although Hyatt says it plans to eventually include it in hotels worldwide. But for now, the participating hotels include: Andaz Maui at Wailea Resort, Hyatt Centric Key West Resort and Spa, Hyatt House Chicago / West Loop-Fulton Market, Hyatt House Dallas / Richardson, Hyatt Place Fremont / Silicon Valley, and Hyatt Regency Long Beach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n5faq1"&gt;Just keep in mind that in order to use the feature, your iPhone will need iOS 15 or above, and your Apple Watch must run watchOS 8 and above. Hyatt notes that once you’ve completed your reservation, you can add your room key to your Apple Wallet through the &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/world-of-hyatt/id476639005"&gt;World of Hyatt&lt;/a&gt; app. The key will display your room number and will only activate when your room is ready for check-in. If you need to make any changes to your room, you can do so through the app, and your key will be updated automatically. Your key will deactivate once you’ve checked out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Kpfb4U"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522864/apple-wallet-iphone-airport-ids-hotel-key-card-ios-15-wwdc"&gt;Apple previewed this feature&lt;/a&gt; at WWDC 2021 alongside its digital ID feature. Once launched, this will allow users in participating states to digitally store their identification cards in their Apple Wallets. Although &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22652051/apple-iphone-drivers-license-state-id-arizona-georgia-ios-15"&gt;Arizona and Georgia&lt;/a&gt; were supposed to be the first states to let residents store their IDs on their iPhones, its rollout &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22799338/apple-digital-driver-license-delay-2022-ios-15"&gt;has been delayed until 2022&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22824367/apple-wallet-hyatt-hotel-key"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22824367/apple-wallet-hyatt-hotel-key</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-08T14:16:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-08T14:16:47-05:00</updated>
    <title>Blizzard victim says she was demoted after reporting sexual harassment</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FpA0SBx2jW9LOKR7XqqYb2QT2VI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70245839/acastro_210729_1777_blizzard_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GdfR8p"&gt;Today, in front of Blizzard Entertainment’s Irvine, California headquarters, Christine (her last name withheld to protect her privacy) &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CXOuBCopsvw/"&gt;held a press conference&lt;/a&gt; in which she spoke about her experiences of sexual harassment and retaliation while employed at the embattled game developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5XO6tX"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content warning&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;This story contains discussions of sexual harassment.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z1wqy5"&gt;Christine gave a tearful statement detailing how working at Blizzard was her “dream job” but how she was then subjected to inappropriate touching, rude comments about her body, and invitations to have sex with her supervisors. When Christine complained to HR, she said she was told the people who made those comments were “just joking” and that they “did nothing wrong by law.” She further claimed that after making those reports, she was demoted, denied her full profit sharing benefits, and received minimal raises in the four years of her employment at Blizzard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2y6dYM"&gt;Christine’s attorney, Lisa Bloom, also spoke at the press conference. Bloom, a celebrity lawyer known for representing survivors in high-profile sexual assault cases who also once made headlines for taking an advisory role in serial-predator Harvey Weinstein’s assault case, detailed the many suits brought against Activision Blizzard for its culture of sexual harassment and retaliation. She notably criticized the consent decree between &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22697341/us-eeoc-sues-activision-blizzard-sexual-harassment-discrimination"&gt;Activision Blizzard and the EEOC&lt;/a&gt;, saying that some of the parameters set forth by this decree had not yet happened within the agreed-upon timeline. She also said that the $18 million victim compensation fund established by the consent decree wasn’t enough. “Given that there are hundreds of victims, I think we can all agree that the $18 million number is woefully inadequate,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ED2tIW"&gt;Bloom then outlined three demands of the company: a streamlined process for victims to resolve their claims with an increased compensation fund in excess of $100 million, a real apology from corporate leadership, and an investigation by a neutral third party into the damage Activision Blizzard’s culture of harassment has had on employees’ careers and a plan to repair that damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9SLprB"&gt;The press conference ended with Bloom asking other victims to join them in the fight against Activision Blizzard. “We don’t want Christine to stand alone. I know she does not stand alone.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kdkJCl"&gt;This press conference is the latest example of employee activism at Activision Blizzard. Last week, when &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/3/22816827/raven-software-qa-contractor-layoff-activision-blizzard-call-of-duty"&gt;layoffs hit the QA department of Raven Studios&lt;/a&gt;, a Wisconsin-based Activision Blizzard subsidiary known for working on the &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt; franchise, hundreds of workers across the Activision Blizzard ecosystem &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/6/22820549/activision-blizzard-raven-software-layoffs-walkout-call-of-duty"&gt;walked out in solidarity&lt;/a&gt;, making this the third walkout since news of the lawsuits broke. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fZXr8w"&gt;In October, the &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/16/22785457/activision-blizzard-bobby-kotick-ceo-wall-street-journal-wsj-report-allegations"&gt;released a report&lt;/a&gt; stating that Bobby Kotick, Activision Blizzard’s CEO, knew about, enabled, and sometimes participated in the harassment himself. After calls for Kotick’s resignation from shareholders and employees, Activision Blizzard’s board of directors &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/21/22795286/activision-ceo-bobby-kotick-is-not-resigning-yet"&gt;affirmed their support for him&lt;/a&gt; even as the big three gaming companies, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787848/playstation-boss-jim-ryan-calls-out-activision-blizzard-staff-memo"&gt;PlayStation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22789881/microsoft-xbox-boss-phil-spencer-deeply-troubled-by-activision-blizzard-bobby-kotick"&gt;Xbox&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.fanbyte.com/news/nintendo-issues-internal-response-to-activision-blizzard-reports/"&gt;Nintendo&lt;/a&gt;, expressed concerns about these developments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TBfNVB"&gt;Christine represents one of the first active employees of Blizzard Entertainment to publicly call out the company. Another outspoken Blizzard employee, Jessica Gonzales, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BlizzJess/status/1465714592189849613?s=20"&gt;resigned from the company&lt;/a&gt; in November after months of detailing how her open criticisms of her employer made her subject to harassment from some of her colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="41PbrH"&gt;In a statement provided to &lt;em&gt;The Verge,&lt;/em&gt; an Activision Blizzard spokesperson said: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TGYL1h"&gt;&lt;em&gt;We appreciate the courage of our current and former employees in coming forward with reports of misconduct, and we are truly sorry for any victims of people whose conduct did not live up to our values.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8tYK7H"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22823991/activision-blizzard-sexual-harassment-victim-press-conference"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22823991/activision-blizzard-sexual-harassment-victim-press-conference</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-08T13:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-08T13:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google releases first Android 12L beta for large-screen devices</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Hl2nMx9xoOltgiai1zhOzPV5JaI=/164x0:1436x848/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70245382/Untitled_3.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;One of Android 12L’s biggest features is a two-column UI for things like the notification shade and lock screen.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="j1QSJX"&gt;Google has announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22746599/android-12l-feature-drop-big-screens"&gt;its Android 12L update&lt;/a&gt; — the one designed to give its OS a better experience on tablets and large folding phones — is getting its first beta release today. While Beta 1 still seems very much pointed toward developers, it could be a chance to see what Google’s working on in a (slightly) more polished state than the developer preview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8H6vAt"&gt;With Android 12L, Google is adding a two-column layout for devices with larger screens, which will let you get at more information at once. For example, your quick settings and notifications can display side by side. Google’s also working to improve multitasking, letting you drag an app into split-screen mode from the taskbar (which you can also use to quickly switch between apps).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="12L multitasking" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FD3D0_mO4f485sllpdRAZ3BUjzY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22959161/12L_multitasking.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google says 12L should make it easier to multitask.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="n74WU5"&gt;As with the developer preview, Google says you should be able to run the beta on an actual large-screen device if you have a Lenovo Tab P12 Pro, though it does say that the beta won’t be available until “a later date.” If you don’t have one of those lying around or don’t feel like waiting, you can also run the 12L beta &lt;a href="https://developer.android.com/about/versions/12/12L/get#resizable-emulator"&gt;in an emulator&lt;/a&gt; to get a feel for how it’ll look when it becomes more widely available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UUCadF"&gt;Google also says you’ll be able to install 12L on your “supported Pixel device,” a &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/android/beta#faq"&gt;list that currently includes&lt;/a&gt; the Pixel 3A through the Pixel 5A, though you won’t be able to test out the large screen UI. If you really just want to be on the bleeding edge, though, or are testing out apps that make use of 12L’s new APIs, you can &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/android/beta#devices"&gt;enroll your Pixel here&lt;/a&gt;. Keep in mind that as the first beta, it’s probably a little rough around the edges. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22824287/google-android-12-beta-1-release-large-screen-devices-tablet-pixel"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22824287/google-android-12-beta-1-release-large-screen-devices-tablet-pixel</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
