<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2022-01-18T16:48:15-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-18T16:48:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-18T16:48:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft addresses last week’s buggy Windows Updates that broke VPNs and rebooted servers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AxtVkD8xycgQTchuCqOYvrQtVwI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70405577/acastro_180507_1777_microsoft_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="NackkG"&gt;Microsoft &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/release-health/windows-message-center#2777"&gt;released&lt;/a&gt; an out-of-band (OOB) update yesterday to fix some Windows issues caused by last week’s monthly patching cycle on Patch Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h8w4jm"&gt;The January 2022 updates that shipped last week included security patches and a fix for Japanese text appearance issues in Windows 11 (&lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/topic/january-11-2022-kb5009566-os-build-22000-434-eee797fa-5ee3-4501-aeec-db3bc73b2c7b"&gt;KB5009566&lt;/a&gt;) and Windows 10 (&lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/topic/january-11-2022-kb5009543-os-builds-19042-1466-19043-1466-and-19044-1466-b763552f-73bd-435a-b220-fc3e0bc9765b"&gt;KB5009543&lt;/a&gt;) — along with a secret payload of issues, including unexpected restarting of Domain Controllers and VPN connections using L2TP failing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t2Wy9L"&gt;One of the major issues that came up during the week for IT admins included finding that Windows Server 2012 became stuck in a boot loop, while other versions suffered broken Windows VPN clients, and some hard drives appeared as RAW format (and unusable). Many IT Admins were forced to roll back the updates — leaving many servers vulnerable with none of last week’s security patches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QEdQbt"&gt;The process is leaving some IT Admins frustrated and sharing grievances &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/sysadmin/comments/s6ix86/update_on_windows_updates_breaking_your_domain/?sort=new"&gt;on Reddit&lt;/a&gt;. They found that the OOB update (an update separate from the usual timing that is downloaded and distributed manually by staff) would force them to first run last week’s buggy patches — risking some Domain Controllers to continuously reboot, loss of access to external drives formatted as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/microsoft/2012/1/16/2712061/microsoft-unveils-windows-8-refs"&gt;ReFS&lt;/a&gt; (Resilient File System), and broken VPN connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Co44N6"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;An out-of-band update has been released to address issues related to VPN connectivity, Windows Server Domain Controllers restarting, Virtual Machine start failures, and ReFS-formatted removeable media failing. &lt;a href="https://t.co/mx9Le4ZXcV"&gt;https://t.co/mx9Le4ZXcV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Windows Update (@WindowsUpdate) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WindowsUpdate/status/1483212333560172545?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 17, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IeAUcE"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; spoke with an IT Admin for a university, who was able to confirm they, too, had to roll back last Tuesday’s update because external ReFS drives had become incompatible — with no warning from Microsoft. Microsoft’s documents state that ReFS should only be used on fixed drives, so this department (and other IT admins &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/windows/comments/s5uans/the_sad_sad_state_of_windows_updates_almost/"&gt;on Reddit&lt;/a&gt;) had to migrate data before running the updates again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DY5opw"&gt;Should the ReFS issue have not been addressed any sooner by Microsoft, they might have believed the drives were faulty, then tried reformatting to NTFS and losing the data (that might be a good idea anyway, as other posts Reddit shared accounts of &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/exchangeserver/comments/s1y5pw/january_updates_refs_became_raw_for_database/"&gt;ReFS failing on them&lt;/a&gt; regardless of this update).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4bgXh5"&gt;This OOB update is available to IT admins with access to Microsoft’s update catalog and can be loaded into Windows Server Update Services (WSUS) — but does not, as of yet, appear in the WSUS catalog, leaving Admins forced to manually download and load it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hPCZen"&gt;An individual by the name of syshum on the sysadmin subreddit jokes: “To Microsoft the question is Why are you still using DomainControllers. You should be using Azure AD only.” There are reasons why many might believe there’s an uneven allocation of resources — subscription cloud services like Azure contribute more to the company’s constant revenue flow than a long-term supported Active Directory solution on-premises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QWcrYy"&gt;Thankfully, support for on-premise solutions isn’t gone yet. Cliff Fisher, Microsoft’s product manager for Active Directory, addressed the problems of patching the older Server 2012 R2, which erroneously reboots too fast to take the whole cumulative patch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Hn9AXA"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;A quick thread on patching with Windows Updates on downlevel platforms like 2012R2.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;There are two types of updates on OSes on the older servicing stack - a Monthly Rollup (MR) and a Security-Only (SO).&lt;/p&gt;— Cliff Fisher (@brdpoker) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/brdpoker/status/1483468179108106241?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 18, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="E26VtO"&gt;Some of these fixes are available now for Windows 11 and Windows 10 as an optional update if you go to Windows Update on your computer. As of writing, there is still no fix for Windows Server 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889670/microsoft-windows-server-update-vpn-refs-domain-patch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889670/microsoft-windows-server-update-vpn-refs-domain-patch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Umar Shakir</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-18T15:38:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-18T15:38:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>White House warns ‘small percentage’ of people can’t order its rapid COVID-19 tests</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="President Biden Delivers Remarks On Administration’s Covid-19 Response" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7WtICOOKkmPYeWfnL-21_MIS1qY=/0x0:5418x3612/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70405325/1364441499.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QRtrEH"&gt;Nearly a month after President Joe Biden first announced that Americans would be able to order rapid at-home COVID-19 tests for free from the government, the administration’s website &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889571/free-covid-19-tests-usps-website"&gt;finally went live on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;. But hours after the site’s launch, users struggled to place orders to homes or apartment buildings where other tenants may have already placed an order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hHQ35U"&gt;The extent of the problem is still unclear as of publication, but White House spokesperson Kevin Munoz said, “It’s a really small percentage and USPS will be sending our statement on this shortly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vAdOc8"&gt;Users trying to order tests to multiple-family homes and apartments seem to be experiencing this issue the most. Once a user enters their information into the form, they’re prompted with an error message that says their order could not be placed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZY66aK"&gt;“Our records show that at-home COVID-19 tests have already been ordered for this address. We are unable to process duplicate orders for the same address,” the ordering site’s error page reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hLO3CQ"&gt;Last week, the White House &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/14/fact-sheet-the-biden-administration-to-begin-distributing-at-home-rapid-covid-19-tests-to-americans-for-free/"&gt;issued a statement&lt;/a&gt; saying that users will be able to call a hotline to order tests if they are unable to access the website. “There will be free tests available for every household, and to promote broad access, the initial program will allow four free tests to be requested per residential address,” the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22890031/white-house-rapid-covid-tests-apartment-bug-usps"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22890031/white-house-rapid-covid-tests-apartment-bug-usps</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-18T15:27:52-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-18T15:27:52-05:00</updated>
    <title>The US’s free COVID test website has more visitors than all other .gov sites combined</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cXhzE3iHhTjYS5rflEvz_ZWGfPk=/50x0:406x237/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70405277/home_test_hero.2099b1df64ebd24bb68a.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The site appears to be handling the traffic.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: USPS&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9lZj3M"&gt;The US government’s site to claim free COVID tests, which has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889571/free-covid-19-tests-usps-website"&gt;started accepting orders a day before it was scheduled to&lt;/a&gt;, is drawing in a &lt;em&gt;lot &lt;/em&gt;of visitors — more than every other government page combined, according to &lt;a href="https://analytics.usa.gov"&gt;the government’s own analytics site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZQ2QRA"&gt;Web traffic numbers change by the second, but at 1:32PM ET, when I ran the report to download real-time numbers for all governmental pages, &lt;a href="http://COVIDTests.gov"&gt;COVIDTests.gov&lt;/a&gt; (along with its FAQ page and versions of the site in other languages) had 685,817 visitors. The visitor counts for the 3,853 other pages included in the report totaled 419,615. Traffic doesn’t seem to have dropped since then. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BoBQdKE3TBNrpq7MOyg3n88qRgw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23177347/Screen_Shot_2022_01_18_at_11.29.05.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;At times, the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="http://COVIDtests.gov" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;COVIDtests.gov&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; page had over 705,000 visitors.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="bC4HT5"&gt;There have been concerns that the site wouldn’t be able to handle the load since it was announced. So far, though, it seems to be handling the rush — though it’s always possible we could see an even bigger wave of visitors on the site tomorrow, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22884217/free-covid-19-test-biden-500-million-january-19-usps"&gt;the date the general public was told it would go live&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7D1jKT"&gt;That’s not to say that things have been perfectly smooth. Several people &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NickySundt/status/1483521702315405315"&gt;have reported&lt;/a&gt; that living in an apartment building can cause issues, with some residents receiving an error message that tests had already been ordered for their address. As &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/biden-government-at-home-covid-tests-e98c4a7a4ee340345a5786c4c407c5fb"&gt;the &lt;em&gt;Associated Press&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;, it’s hard to tell how widespread the issue is, and there have been conflicting reports on how to solve it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="fADXHH"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"White House warns ‘small percentage’ of people can’t order its rapid COVID-19 tests","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22890031/white-house-rapid-covid-tests-apartment-bug-usps"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="ujVbAt"&gt;The government has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/21/22848887/joe-biden-google-free-covid-test-near-me"&gt;committed to sending out 500 million tests&lt;/a&gt;, with a limit of four per household. If you’re looking to order yours, you can &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22889745/rapid-covid-tests-free-website-how-to"&gt;read our guide on how to do so here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889769/us-government-free-covid-test-website-massive-page-viewcount"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889769/us-government-free-covid-test-website-massive-page-viewcount</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-18T15:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-18T15:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Democrats unveil bill to ban online ‘surveillance advertising’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="House Hearing Held On Protecting Scientific Integrity In Coronavirus Response" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Wrhonqg8wd857w3gbTkSNvO9R3M=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70405137/1212981411.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Greg Nash-Pool/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VJ7lpW"&gt;On Tuesday, Democrats introduced a new bill that would ban nearly all use of digital advertising targeting on ad markets hosted by platforms like Facebook, Google, and other data brokers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FGm3Z2"&gt;&lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23177323/Banning_Surveillance_Advertising_Act.pdf"&gt;The Banning Surveillance Advertising Act&lt;/a&gt; – sponsored by Reps. Anna Eshoo (D-CA), Jan Schakowsky (D-IL), and Sen. Cory Booker (D-NJ) – prohibits digital advertisers from targeting any ads to users. It makes some small exceptions, like allowing for “broad” location-based targeting. Contextual advertising, like ads that are specifically matched to online content, would be allowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Aq1Mv"&gt;“The ‘surveillance advertising’ business model is premised on the unseemly collection and hoarding of personal data to enable ad targeting,” Eshoo, the bill’s lead sponsor, said in a Tuesday statement. “This pernicious practice allows online platforms to chase user engagement at great cost to our society, and it fuels disinformation, discrimination, voter suppression, privacy abuses, and so many other harms. The surveillance advertising business model is broken.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="S3rGSP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The surveillance advertising business model is broken”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="a1tmAs"&gt;If enacted, the bill would radically change Facebook and Google’s business models. For years, lawmakers have debated &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22710539/facebook-whistleblower-hearing-instagram-child-safety-congress"&gt;ways to regulate the tech industry&lt;/a&gt; on issues like privacy, disinformation, and content moderation. Eshoo and her co-sponsors argue that the tech industry’s current advertising models incentivize the spread of harmful content and encourage them to amplify damaging posts to keep users on their platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qIJSnH"&gt;The bill empowers the Federal Trade Commission and state attorneys general with the authority to enforce the new rules for ad targeting. It also allows individual users to sue platforms like Facebook and Google if they break the law, granting up to $5,000 in relief per violation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SnQmyf"&gt;“Surveillance advertising is a predatory and invasive practice,” Sen. Booker said in a statement on Tuesday. “The hoarding of people’s personal data not only abuses privacy, but also drives the spread of misinformation, domestic extremism, racial division, and violence.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dviilJ"&gt;Since Facebook whistleblower Frances Haugen testified before Congress last year, lawmakers have put out a number of new bills to regulate social media algorithms to address the spread of harmful content. Last October, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22726290/malicious-algorithms-section-230-bill-eshoo-pallone-doyle-schakowsky-facebook-whistleblower"&gt;House Democrats unveiled a measure&lt;/a&gt; that would strip away a platform’s Section 230 liability protections if their algorithms were found to have recommended harmful content to users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ca0ej6"&gt;At Haugen’s first Senate hearing, Sen. Richard Blumenthal (D-CT) said &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22710371/facebook-whistleblower-congress-hearing-instagram-kids-safety-privacy-blumenthal"&gt;the leaks confirm&lt;/a&gt; “that Facebook routinely puts profits ahead of kids’ online safety.” He continued, “we know it chooses the growth of its products over the well-being of our children.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889903/democrats-targeted-advertising-facebook-google-surveillance"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889903/democrats-targeted-advertising-facebook-google-surveillance</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-18T14:53:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-18T14:53:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>YouTube will stop making most original shows</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jMj6GYhMIMN3oP8RTpPjNJAfNj8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70405082/acastro_180321_1777_youtube_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8sHbJe"&gt;YouTube will scale back a significant portion of YouTube Originals, which produced original content including scripted series, educational videos, and music and celebrity programming. Chief business officer for YouTube Robert Kyncl announced the changes today in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rkyncl/status/1483502275804872704"&gt;a statement&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sc50hg"&gt;Going forward, the company will only fund originals in the YouTube Kids Fund and the Black Voices Fund, a program &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21288066/youtube-black-creator-amplify-fund-initiative-ceo"&gt;created in 2020&lt;/a&gt; that committed $100 million to “amplify” Black creators on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fZEM8e"&gt;“With rapid growth comes new opportunities and now our investments can make a greater impact on even more creators when applied towards other initiatives, like our Creator Shorts Fund, Black Voices Fund, and Live Shopping programming to name a few,” the statement reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="RD7Xdb"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Over six years, YouTube made few titles that looked like breakout hits&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="EKtGYt"&gt;YouTube Originals has changed approaches throughout the years. Created in 2016 and led by Susanne Daniels, it began with scripted shows and movies focused on creators, like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/2/3/10905654/youtube-red-originals-premiere-date-scare-pewdiepie"&gt;comedy-thriller series &lt;em&gt;Scare PewDiePie&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. In 2017, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/6/22/15855570/youtube-red-originals-250-million-views"&gt;YouTube said&lt;/a&gt; the subscriber-only first season of originals racked up 250 million views. The company began &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/29/18116154/youtube-premium-free-ads-subscription-red"&gt;pivoting&lt;/a&gt; toward ad-supported &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/5/4/15552204/youtube-original-tv-shows-kevin-hart-ellen-degeneres"&gt;content featuring celebrities&lt;/a&gt; like Katy Perry and Kevin Hart, free for users to access without a subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EL2Ecm"&gt;But over six years, YouTube made few titles that looked like breakout hits. And by the end, it was unclear what the original programming provided strategically to a service that’s already one of the most popular video destinations in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jyiSgW"&gt;Today’s statement also announced Daniels will depart the company in March, which also contributed to the decision to scale back the division.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IR8TK9"&gt;New original programs were being announced as recently as last year, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419244/youtube-will-smith-alicia-keys-new-originals"&gt;series featuring&lt;/a&gt; Will Smith and Alicia Keys. YouTube says it will honor existing commitments for shows in progress and will contact creators in the coming days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3z2W38"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PDReOk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889889/youtube-originals-series-ending-susanne-daniels"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889889/youtube-originals-series-ending-susanne-daniels</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mia Sato</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-18T14:50:14-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-18T14:50:14-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla owner is the first to face felony charges for deadly Autopilot crash</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/F8weZ8ndkC8rz5_VnK1zwbYU38Y=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70405072/tesla_model_y_3543.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wFp41e"&gt;California prosecutors filed two felony charges against the owner of Tesla Model S for a deadly crash in 2019 that involved the vehicle’s Autopilot system, marking the first time that a Tesla owner has been criminally charged in the US in a case involving the automaker’s advanced driver assist system. &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/technology-business-only-on-ap-california-united-states-91b4a0341e07244f3f03051b5c2462ae"&gt;The charges were first reported by the &lt;em&gt;AP.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g5VbQx"&gt;According to the LA County District Attorney, the incident took place in Gardena, a suburb of LA, on December 29, 2019. Kevin George Aziz Riad, 27, was exiting a highway in his black Model S when he ran through a red light, slamming into a Honda Civic and killing two people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aMblfk"&gt;Riad, a limousine service driver, will now face two charges of vehicular manslaughter, according to charges filed with the California Superior Court. He is currently free on bail while the case is pending, according to the AP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="6C37Yc"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Autopilot has come under increased scrutiny from federal regulators&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Xkmofu"&gt;Autopilot, which can control steering and braking functions as well as perform automatic lane changes while on certain highways, has come under increased scrutiny from federal regulators. Last year, the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration opened an investigation into over a dozen incidents involving Tesla vehicles using Autopilot that have crashed into stationary emergency vehicles. Autopilot has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/4/20849499/tesla-autopilot-crash-culver-city-2018-ntsb-report"&gt;contributed to a number of fatal crashes&lt;/a&gt; in the past, and the families of deceased drivers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/1/20750715/tesla-autopilot-crash-lawsuit-wrongful-death"&gt;have sued Tesla&lt;/a&gt; for wrongful death.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ORVgoq"&gt;Tesla warns that drivers need to keep their eyes on the road and hands on the wheel at all times, though the automaker has declined to include a more robust driver-monitoring system (like infrared eye tracking, for example) to ensure its customers are following safety protocols. Autopilot is considered a Level 2 “partially automated” system by the Society of Automotive Engineers’ standards, which requires that drivers keep their hands on the wheel and eyes on the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZcsqqC"&gt;Some Tesla drivers have been caught misusing Autopilot, and some have even publicized the results themselves. Drivers have been found sleeping in the passenger seat or backseat of their vehicles while speeding down a crowded highway. A &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/18/21445168/tesla-driver-sleeping-police-charged-canada-autopilot"&gt;Canadian man was charged with reckless driving&lt;/a&gt; after being pulled over for sleeping while traveling at speeds of 93mph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SclivX"&gt;The criminal charges document does not mention Autopilot. But NHTSA, which dispatched a team to investigate the crash in 2019, confirmed that the driver assist feature was active at the time of the incident. The agency plans on publishing its findings from the investigation soon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zb3wkt"&gt;“NHTSA reminds the public that no commercially available motor vehicle today can drive itself,” a spokesperson said. “Whether a L2 automated driving system is engaged or not, every available vehicle requires the human driver to be in control at all times, and all State laws hold the human driver responsible for the operation of their vehicles.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889768/tesla-autopilot-criminal-charges-la-fatal-crash"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889768/tesla-autopilot-criminal-charges-la-fatal-crash</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-18T14:22:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-18T14:22:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>AT&amp;T and Verizon are limiting C-band 5G expansion around airports even more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-AVIATION-TELECOMMUNICATION" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T4iAQgSV6HjP97Cu82K0kGdmOqU=/0x0:4000x2667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70404653/1237809011.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;AT&amp;amp;T says airlines “have not utilized the two years they’ve had to responsibly plan for this deployment.” | Photo by STEFANI REYNOLDS/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4xeFnP"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon have announced that they will push back plans to activate some 5G towers around airports after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889141/us-airlines-united-american-delta-5g-c-band-disruption-radar-altimeter"&gt;airline operators warned&lt;/a&gt; that the deployment could cause “catastrophic disruption” to travel and shipping. While both carriers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/8/22873765/faa-verizon-att-airport-5g-carriers-buffer-zone"&gt;have an agreement with the Federal Aviation Administration&lt;/a&gt; to create buffer zones around 50 airports, AT&amp;amp;T has confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that it’s halting the rollout of even more towers than originally planned, and that the decision applies to a “limited number of towers around certain airport runways.” Verizon responded to an email asking if it was planning on doing more than the agreement requires with &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.verizon.com/about/news/verizon-goes-ultra-wednesday" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a statement&lt;/a&gt; that says it’s “voluntarily decided to limit our 5G network around airports.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vVXv6n"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T is clearly unhappy with the situation. In a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge,&lt;/em&gt; it said that it will “continue to work with the aviation industry and the FAA to provide further information about our 5G deployment, since they have not utilized the two years they’ve had to responsibly plan for this deployment.” The statement also said that the company is “frustrated by the FAA’s inability to do what nearly 40 countries have done, which is to safely deploy 5G technology without disrupting aviation services, and we urge it do so in a timely manner.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q8wKv8"&gt;Verizon expressed similar frustration, saying: “The Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) and our nation’s airlines have not been able to fully resolve navigating 5G around airports, despite it being safe and fully operational in more than 40 other countries.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="r2GsBH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Airlines claim that C-Band 5G could disrupt sensitive equipment&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="e6kKSH"&gt;Both AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon have clashed with airline operators, who claim that their new C-Band 5G towers could disrupt sensitive equipment, making it difficult to land in low-visibility conditions. We have a great explainer that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22867221/att-verizon-5g-midband-spectrum-faa-air-safety-delay-cband"&gt;breaks down the whole situation&lt;/a&gt;, but the TL;DR is that this is just the latest in a series of delays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="kgCgnx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Why AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon are feuding with the US government over a last-minute delay to 5G","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22867221/att-verizon-5g-midband-spectrum-faa-air-safety-delay-cband"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="V5HccX"&gt;In an attempt to finally get the rollout started, AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/8/22873765/faa-verizon-att-airport-5g-carriers-buffer-zone"&gt;made an agreement with the FAA&lt;/a&gt; earlier this month, which would allow them to activate their towers on January 19th, except for in select areas around 50 airports. On Monday, however, several airlines &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889141/us-airlines-united-american-delta-5g-c-band-disruption-radar-altimeter"&gt;reportedly signed a letter sent to government officials&lt;/a&gt;, again warning about the rollout. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L7V5CS"&gt;In a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, United Airlines said on Monday that the 5G expansion would “result in not only hundreds of thousands of flight cancellations and disruptions for customers across the industry in 2022, but also the suspension of cargo flights into these locations, causing a negative ripple-effect on an already fragile supply chain.” The airline also said that it “implore[s] the Biden administration to act quickly and apply the same common sense solutions here that have clearly worked so well around the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NM6nDi"&gt;For his part, President Biden thanked the carriers “for agreeing to delay 5G deployment around key airports and to continue working with the Department of Transportation on safe 5G deployment at this limited set of locations” in &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/18/statement-by-president-biden-on-5g-agreement/"&gt;a statement on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;. He said that his team “has been engaging non-stop with the wireless carriers, airlines, and aviation equipment manufacturers to chart a path forward for 5G deployment and aviation to safely co-exist,” and that work would continue until they found “a permanent, workable solution around these key airports.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sLhcJG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 18th, 2:53PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to add statement from President Biden.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ux39cX"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 18th, 2:22PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to reflect that Verizon has also stated that it’ll be limiting rollout around airports.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889664/att-5g-limits-c-band-expansion-airports-further-carrier-airline"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889664/att-5g-limits-c-band-expansion-airports-further-carrier-airline</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-18T14:20:49-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-18T14:20:49-05:00</updated>
    <title>Moon Knight’s English accent is its first villain</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6vthh4l2yJiUdJaCjv9Ry6zgrIw=/194x0:1970x1184/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70404970/Screen_Shot_2022_01_18_at_1.51.50_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GAH7me"&gt;As you watch the first trailer for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/23/20830548/she-hulk-moon-knight-disney-plus-streaming-kevin-feige-marvel-cinematic-universe"&gt;Marvel’s &lt;em&gt;Moon Knight &lt;/em&gt;series&lt;/a&gt;, a few things quickly become clear about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/27/22457292/oscar-isaac-moon-knight-disney-plus-casting-marvel"&gt;Oscar Isaac’s take on the titular hero&lt;/a&gt;. The first: like his comics counterpart, this Moon Knight will &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/1/25/14385948/split-movie-m-night-shyamalan-james-mcavoy-horror-psycho-hitchcock"&gt;grapple with having multiple personalities&lt;/a&gt;. The second: one of those personalities is meant to be believably British, despite his having one of the most ludicrous British accents recently captured on camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UUO63V"&gt;In Marvel’s comics, Moon Knight — created by Doug Moench and Don Perlin — is both a codename and one of the alternate personalities coexisting within Marc Spector, a former Marine turned mercenary who appears to gain otherworldly abilities after dying and seemingly being resurrected by an Egyptian moon deity known as Khonshu. Though the specific details of Marc’s mental health and how it factors into his life as a costumed hero have shifted over the years, many &lt;em&gt;Moon Knight&lt;/em&gt; stories, including the new show, have revolved around the complications that arise when Marc’s other alters begin to surface and assert dominance over their shared existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FwllWw"&gt;After alluding to the issues that Isaac’s character has been having with sleeping, the &lt;em&gt;Moon Knight &lt;/em&gt;trailer makes sure to highlight how he takes one of London’s iconic, red double-decker buses to work and that he very much prefers to be called “Steven” by his colleagues at the British Museum. It all &lt;em&gt;almost &lt;/em&gt;works, even as the trailer smoothly shifts into &lt;em&gt;Moon Knight&lt;/em&gt;’s more supernatural elements, but the Marvel magic of it all never manages to come together because of how gobsmackingly &lt;em&gt;weird &lt;/em&gt;Isaac’s choice of accent is here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="MGv1f3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Steven” has somehow built a life where actual British people believe he’s one of them&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XSrH0z"&gt;What’s strange about the way that the &lt;em&gt;Moon Knight &lt;/em&gt;trailer alludes to Steven and Marc being the same person is the implication that “Steven” has somehow managed to build a life in Britain where actual British people believe he’s one of them, despite his sounding as if he’d wandered off the stage of a &lt;em&gt;Pygmalion &lt;/em&gt;revival. The offness of Steven’s English accent is likely meant to be an unsubtle hint at the fractured nature of Marc Spector’s mind, but Marvel’s history with iffy accents makes it so that those kinds of details are easy to interpret as straight-up bad decisions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JmB8cx"&gt;In the years after Wanda Maximoff first hexed her way onto the Avengers in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/4/22/8464479/avengers-age-of-ultron-review"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Age of Ultron&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;with her Sokovian accent fully intact, the vaguely Eastern European lilt in her voice faded much in the same way that she gradually became a redhead. Though those choices initially felt somewhat inexplicable and arbitrary, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22233625/wandavision-marvel-avengers-mcu-disney-plus-episode-review"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;partially retconned them to have much more emotional significance than they appeared to, and &lt;em&gt;Moon Knight &lt;/em&gt;could very well do something similar with Steven / Marc. What might also be the case, though, is that &lt;em&gt;Moon Knight &lt;/em&gt;is about to join &lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange &lt;/em&gt;in the pantheon of MCU projects that should have just stuck with their leads’ actual speaking voices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tYg81T"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moon Knight &lt;/em&gt;hits Disney Plus on March 30th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22889548/marvel-moon-knight-trailer-english-accent-villains"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22889548/marvel-moon-knight-trailer-english-accent-villains</id>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Pulliam-Moore</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-18T14:12:50-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-18T14:12:50-05:00</updated>
    <title>God of War for PC just got its first discount</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vn3IXOolOj0PI3VraU-aEOFw4RQ=/197x0:1366x779/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70404919/God_of_War.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XcY4gr"&gt;The PlayStation epic &lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt; was released to PC a mere four days ago but is &lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=20387&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=VergeGodOfWarPC011822&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.eneba.com%2Fus%2Fsteam-god-of-war-pc-steam-key-global%2Fgames-federation" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently discounted to just $37.76 at Eneba&lt;/a&gt;, an excellent break on the regular $49.99 price tag. This amazing reboot of the classic Sony franchise brings back Kratos in his role as the iconic God of War in a sweeping narrative bedded in the lore of Norse mythology. The RPG-inspired gameplay is made even stronger with the help of an amazing story that adds some much-needed depth to the otherwise one-dimensional diety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="J2fuOR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10894782"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="vIFbeW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Microsoft to acquire Activision Blizzard for $68.7 billion","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889258/microsoft-activision-blizzard-xbox-acquisition-call-of-duty-overwatch"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="F6NeOr"&gt;The Gigabyte G32QC 32-inch curved gaming monitor is currently discounted to match its lowest price ever at Newegg. Normally, this curved gaming panel costs $369.99 but &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=OHlcvPYhHQM&amp;amp;mid=44583&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fp%2FN82E16824012036%3FItem%3DN82E16824012036%26quicklink%3Dtrue" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;has been reduced to just $299.99&lt;/a&gt; when you use the promo code GNLBNA8242 at checkout. This monitor boasts some impressive specs for its price point, with a 1440p resolution and a snappy 165Hz refresh rate, the G32QC checks virtually all the boxes when it comes to gaming monitors. Beyond its excellent visual fidelity, this monitor also includes a variety of connectivity options, with HDMI and DisplayPort hookups in addition to USB outputs for data and power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dudAWh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10983686"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="Vj6rjY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to pick a new monitor for working from home","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22877788/best-monitor-work-from-home-screen-choice-4k-qhd-refresh-rate-ultrawide"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="voLXP5"&gt;Right now, you can grab the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cgrHnvXMx8N" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;HyperX Cloud Alpha Pro for $59.99 at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, matching its lowest price ever with a solid $40 discount. This versatile, wired headset is remarkably comfortable and boasts impressive sound quality for its price. The padded, over-ear design is perfect for extended gaming sessions, and the removable boom mic makes it perfect for gaming or just vibing to podcasts. The HyperX Cloud Alpha Pro headset is an excellent option as long as you don’t mind wires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="AEqn12"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10983845"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CkUhvX"&gt;This RoboVac from Eufy is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/eufy-Super-Thin-Super-Strong-Self-Charging-Medium-Pile/dp/B07R295MLS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently on sale at Amazon for $179.99&lt;/a&gt; — just click the applicable coupon before adding it to your cart. This is a generous discount from the typical $249.99 price tag of this autonomous cat taxi that also cleans your floors. Perfect for hardwood, tile, or carpets, some other notable features of the 11S Max include a run time of up to 100 minutes, a slim 2.85-inch profile for getting into hard-to-reach spaces, and quiet operation. The 11S Max also has a variety of cleaning modes to accommodate whatever space it needs to clean. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="SbE1Wq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10983947"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="4qqS5E"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Roomba j7 Plus vs. Jet Bot AI Plus: can these robot vacuums pass the poop test?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22880352/irobot-roomba-j7-plus-samsung-jet-bot-ai-plus-robot-vacuum-review-comparison-test"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="6sb7oK"&gt;The base configuration of the Google Pixel 6 is &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cgrIfDJKGPC" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently discounted to $549.99 at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; if you activate the device on a Verizon plan or $499.99 if you activate it on T-Mobile or AT&amp;amp;T. A rare price break on this new device. In &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22750387/google-pixel-6-pro-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;our review&lt;/a&gt; by Dan Seifert, he declared the Pixel 6 and 6 Pro to be the “best phones that Google has ever made.” The base model of the Pixel 6 comes equipped with 8GB of RAM, 128GB of storage, and a 50-megapixel wide-angle camera. The discount is only available for the black, blue, and pink colorways. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6ytx3v"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10815891"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mRVluj"&gt;It may not share the same specs as the vaunted G15, but the Asus Zephyrus G14 remains a solid option for anyone in the market for a gaming-focused, 14-inch ultrabook. &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cf8cMzdkvIY" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Currently, the G14 is discounted to $1,299.99 at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and while this isn’t the lowest price we’ve seen for this laptop, it is still a solid value for a laptop that normally retails for $1,549.99. In &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22702219/asus-rog-zephyrus-g14-2021-gaming-laptop-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;our review by Monica Chin&lt;/a&gt;, she was generally impressed by the battery life and performance of this Ryzen 9-equipped laptop, even though the lack of a webcam seemed like a curious omission. Besides the Ryzen CPU, the G14 also comes equipped with a 1TB SSD, 16GB of RAM, and an RTX 3060 graphics card. The 14-inch display might feel a bit crowded but features excellent fidelity with a 1440p resolution and 120Hz refresh rate.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="YIPboV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9505867"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="FAd9DC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Best gaming laptop in 2021: seven laptops to get your game on","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22295181/best-gaming-laptop"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="HdDrw7"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 18th, 4:26PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Although Best Buy is selling an unlocked configuration of the Google Pixel 6, the discount only applies when activating the phone on certain networks. We updated the copy to better reflect the exact terms of the deal. We regret the omission.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Naiifr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2022/1/18/22889395/god-of-war-pc-gigabyte-gaming-monitor-hyperx-headset-google-pixel-asus-laptop-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2022/1/18/22889395/god-of-war-pc-gigabyte-gaming-monitor-hyperx-headset-google-pixel-asus-laptop-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-18T14:10:45-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-18T14:10:45-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to order free rapid COVID tests from the US government</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LgtoQhZkOTVWBaOd8vOYa6rdkPk=/155x0:2441x1524/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70404905/Screen_Shot_2022_01_18_at_1.39.58_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;div id="Wt6wH5"&gt;
&lt;script type="application/ld+json"&gt;
{
 "@context": "https://schema.org",
 "@type": "HowTo",
 "name": "How to order free rapid COVID tests from the US government",
 "description": "The US federal government has created a website where you can order four free rapid test kits per month per household. ",
 "step": [
  {
   "@type": "HowToSection",
   "position": "1",
   "name": "It’s extremely simple to put in your order.",
   "itemListElement": [
    {
     "@type": "HowToStep",
     "position": "1",
     "itemListElement": [
      {
       "@type": "HowToDirection",
       "position": "1",
       "text": "Go to COVIDTests.gov."
      }
     ]
    },
    {
     "@type": "HowToStep",
     "position": "2",
     "itemListElement": [
      {
       "@type": "HowToDirection",
       "position": "1",
       "text": "Tap on the button reading \"Order Free At-Home Tests.\" \n"
      },
      {
       "@type": "HowToTip",
       "position": "2",
       "text": "If you don’t see the button for any reason, you can go directly to the USPS site (which is where the button would send you anyway) at special.usps.com/testkits. \n"
      }
     ]
    },
    {
     "@type": "HowToStep",
     "position": "3",
     "itemListElement": [
      {
       "@type": "HowToDirection",
       "position": "1",
       "text": "Fill in your name, email address (if you want to receive notifications), and shipping address.\n",
       "image": "https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23177189/Screen_Shot_2022_01_18_at_1.34.45_PM.png"
      }
     ]
    },
    {
     "@type": "HowToStep",
     "position": "4",
     "itemListElement": [
      {
       "@type": "HowToDirection",
       "position": "1",
       "text": "Click on the green \"Check Out Now\" button — and you’re done!\n"
      }
     ]
    }
   ]
  }
 ]
}
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PdzOjp"&gt;With the rise of the Omicron variant, we’ve been urged to use COVID-19 rapid antigen tests to make sure that we don’t spread the virus to friends and family. However, it’s been very difficult to follow that suggestion, what with long lines at COVID testing stations and high prices for home kits — when you can find them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="euZO1K"&gt;To try to alleviate this situation, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889571/free-covid-19-tests-usps-website"&gt;the US federal government has created a website&lt;/a&gt; where you can order four free rapid test kits per month per household. While the site was scheduled to officially open Wednesday, January 19th, it started taking names and addresses a day early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WRPiGo"&gt;It’s extremely simple to put in your order. You will not need to submit a credit card or any other financial information. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="HeKtVl"&gt;Go to &lt;a href="http://covidtests.gov/"&gt;COVIDTests.gov&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="KSN8FP"&gt;Tap on the button reading “Order Free At-Home Tests.” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="1XuoG7"&gt;If you don’t see the button for any reason, you can go directly to the USPS site (which is where the button would send you anyway) at &lt;a href="https://special.usps.com/testkits"&gt;special.usps.com/testkits&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DLzP1J"&gt;Fill in your name, email address (if you want to receive notifications), and shipping address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="egN7Sd"&gt;Click on the green “Check Out Now” button — and you’re done!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The USPS form for ordering free rapid tests is very simple." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vWK2i6OSwH_RhFwxKvSiPp2A0Gs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23177189/Screen_Shot_2022_01_18_at_1.34.45_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The USPS form for ordering free rapid tests is very simple.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MNKDCC"&gt;So far, we haven’t had any reports of problems with the site itself although (as can be imagined), it’s highly popular. (According to the site &lt;a href="http://analytics.usa.gov"&gt;analytics.usa.gov&lt;/a&gt;, as of 2pm on Tuesday, January 18th, over 700,000 people had already visited the website.) There will also be a call line for those who cannot access the website for any reason, but as of this writing, the number hadn’t been announced yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DQEAia"&gt;The kits are supposed to ship within 7-12 days, starting in late January. Until then, as far as rapid tests are concerned, we’re still on our own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fQTbBP"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: &lt;/strong&gt;Some apartment dwellers are reporting problems with putting in an order if somebody else in their building already did:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="BLXfsZ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Houston, we have a problem!  People at same street address but different apartment numbers are being refused free COVID test kits at &lt;a href="https://t.co/Rm7vj6zgKS"&gt;https://t.co/Rm7vj6zgKS&lt;/a&gt; if another apartment dweller ordered first.  This happened to me and I’m not the only one. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/USPS?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#USPS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/CovidTesting?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#CovidTesting&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/ZllXT7m6jq"&gt;pic.twitter.com/ZllXT7m6jq&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Nicky Sundt (@NickySundt) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NickySundt/status/1483521702315405315?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 18, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KBv29U"&gt;There have been a number of solutions suggested if this happens to you, including putting your apartment number on the same line as your street address, putting your apartment number on the second address line, or using a word (such as “suite” or “apartment”) rather than a hash sign. None of these have been verified; we’ll let you know if we hear anything further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="9ahUCa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"White House warns ‘small percentage’ of people can’t order its rapid COVID-19 tests","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22890031/white-house-rapid-covid-tests-apartment-bug-usps"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Gid8Jy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 18th, 2:45PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to add info about possible issues with ordering from an apartment.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22889745/rapid-covid-tests-free-website-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22889745/rapid-covid-tests-free-website-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
