<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-08T16:32:50-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-08T16:32:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-08T16:32:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>NASA sets new date for James Webb Space Telescope launch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8I905fOz9SxBpBKEzLuMrxZeB68=/0x500:7466x5477/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69831613/webbcomplete3.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JxScVZ"&gt;The James Webb Space Telescope, humanity’s next big space-bound eye on the cosmos, has a new launch date of December 18th, NASA announced on Wednesday. It’s the latest among dozens of other delays for a telescope that was originally planned to go to space as early as 2007. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HK0luF"&gt;The $8.8 billion observatory, named after NASA’s second administrator, is a tennis court-sized successor to NASA’s famed Hubble telescope. Its 18 hexagonal gold-plated mirrors will allow the spacecraft to view distant planets and the far reaches of the universe with a level of detail that far surpasses Hubble’s capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WeY4hp"&gt;Astronomers have been looking forward to the telescope’s launch for years, but its development has been set back by years of delays, development challenges, and cost overruns. NASA and Northrop Grumman, the telescope’s prime contractor, initially set a $1 billion budget for James Webb and a launch date for sometime in 2007. By 2011, the launch date had slipped to 2018, but that was pushed ever further, with development accidents driving up costs. Early last year, NASA’s inspector general &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/28/21112504/nasa-james-webb-space-telescope-delay-gao-audit-march-2021"&gt;foresaw delays due to a handful of technical challenges&lt;/a&gt;. And the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/16/21327601/nasa-james-webb-space-telescope-launch-delay-october-31-2021"&gt;pandemic added more delays last year&lt;/a&gt;, pushing the launch date to October 31st. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FDMJ7r"&gt;The latest delay had nothing to do with the telescope. The Ariane 5 rocket James Webb will launch on was effectively grounded for nearly a year due to problems with its payload fairings that were detected in two separate commercial missions in 2020. The rocket successfully launched a batch of satellites in July. In the same month, the European Space Agency — NASA’s partner on the telescope — signed off on James Webb’s new launch plan in a key review that showed “positive results” during technical evaluations, the agency said at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7s67ZZ"&gt;NASA &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/nasa-readies-james-webb-space-telescope-for-december-launch"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; the new date was set in consultation with Arianespace, the French company whose Ariane 5 rocket will send James Webb to space from a launch site in Kourou, French Guiana managed by the European Space Agency (ESA). The observatory, a joint project between NASA, ESA, and the Canadian space agency, &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2021/nasa-s-james-webb-space-telescope-has-completed-testing"&gt;wrapped up final tests&lt;/a&gt; late last month, and now it’s undergoing shipment operations. Engineers will enclose the spacecraft in a custom (and very expensive) shipping container before it’s sent to Kourou. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="odGG6K"&gt;While it &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; has a new launch date to space, the exact timing of when the spacecraft sets sail to South America is still being kept under wraps as a security precaution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iuTGoT"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y4eZfj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22663027/nasa-james-webb-space-telescope-launch-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22663027/nasa-james-webb-space-telescope-launch-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-08T15:49:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-08T15:49:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Whoop’s new fitness tracker is better thanks to a battery breakthrough</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9xbxLslNmTUuEVtEf83IsE90XYg=/189x0:2211x1348/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69831427/WHOOP_SILA_2.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1TIDKy"&gt;Fitness company Whoop has a &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/introducing-whoop-4-0-and-whoop-body-featuring-any-wear-technology-301371503.html"&gt;new tracker&lt;/a&gt; that squishes five LEDs, four photodiodes, a pulse oximeter, skin temperature sensor, and more into a package that is 33 percent smaller than its predecessor — all while still offering five days of battery life. But a particular change to the tracker’s battery chemistry is one of the biggest reasons Whoop was able to do all this in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jzdMa6"&gt;The change was pioneered by a Silicon Valley company called Sila Nanotechnologies, which was co-founded in 2011 by Gene Berdichevsky, one of Tesla’s earliest employees. And it’s one that, if it scales up, could help break some of the biggest limitations currently facing lithium-ion technology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jXy9i0"&gt;On paper, it’s a simple change: the battery’s anode is now made of silicon instead of graphite, which allows for greater energy density (up to 20 percent, Sila claims). Greater energy density means device makers can use a smaller battery to accomplish the same tasks — or free up more space to do things they couldn’t before. And it doesn’t require any hardware changes to the cell production process. In fact, that’s one of Sila’s biggest selling points to battery makers: its silicon anode is more or less plug-and-play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rj3zcV"&gt;In practice, though, this change was only possible after years of trial and error and millions of dollars spent. Sila toiled with a number of different so-called “precursors,” or raw materials, in order to find the right mix to be able to create its breakthrough silicon powder. And it did this with a mandate from Berdichevsky that those precursors had to be widely available — even if that made it harder to reach the theoretical performance jumps silicon anodes can provide. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="7917MH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Far greater energy density, which means more room for new features&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eK1f0p"&gt;“Those constraints, they sharpen the innovation,” Berdichevsky tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “[But] they make it harder. So you have less degrees of freedom&lt;em&gt;.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q4JJbF"&gt;As a result, Berdichevsky says it took Sila about twice as long as he originally hoped to get into a consumer product. But considering the supply chain shortages currently strangling just about every industry imaginable, it was a prescient decision to build on such a foundation. He also says it’s helped Sila attract a deep roster of smart minds from multiple highly competitive fields. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JxnRx6"&gt;“Creative people love those really, really hard problems. And so I think that’s really what distinguishes us from from so many other [startups in the space],” he says. “You have less competition when you solve the hardest problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fsKJdY"&gt;Sila also had to fight the natural tendency of silicon to expand and break down when used in a battery, because the reason it can store more lithium ions is that they actually briefly bond with the silicon — meaning the ions sort of have to be ripped out of the anode. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wHJHSy"&gt;All of this is why Berdichevsky is so visibly happy to finally get his company’s battery science into the first consumer device when we talk via videoconference. It’s both a proof of the concept &lt;em&gt;and &lt;/em&gt;of the myriad benefits that come with a more efficient battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MrlXFU"&gt;Berdichevsky says he originally envisioned the first place Sila’s tech would appear would be in smartphones, since the batteries they use occupy so much space that could otherwise be allocated for flagship features like advanced camera systems. What he didn’t expect when founding Sila, though, was the boom in wearable tech, which opened up a lot of new doors. Whoop first started talking to Sila roughly two years ago, Berdichevsky says, and the company’s tech is coming to a few other consumer devices soon (though he declined to say what those would be). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fYUzG5"&gt;“Having innovative technologies where size really matters is a really great place for a technology like ours,” Berdichevsky says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HTz1VM"&gt;The biggest potential for Sila’s silicon anode could be with much larger batteries, like the ones that power electric vehicles. It could help automakers create smaller, more affordable EVs without sacrificing range, or get even more miles out of the big battery packs found in larger cars. And as long as the company has in fact found a way to make sure the silicon powder it’s creating can withstand being constantly charged and discharged, it’s possible that Sila-powered EVs could fill up faster than modern ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="I9rAGQ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Sila’s capacity will be limited until it builds a new factory later this decade&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zMAGNs"&gt;At the consumer device level, Berdichevsky says that Sila doesn’t necessarily offer companies like Whoop a shot at cost savings, since right now the production of its silicon powder is so limited. Sila would have to make far more of its material if it were to provide enough to help power fleets of EVs, but the benefit of scaling up to that level is that the relative cost of production would go down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gu7ZTc"&gt;None of that will happen until at least mid-decade, though. Berdichevsky says his company is planning to build a much larger production facility, &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/26/sila-nanotechnologies-raises-590m-to-fund-battery-materials-factory/"&gt;using the $590 million it raised in January&lt;/a&gt;. Until then, Berdichevsky says the company will have “very limited capacity.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ho2gCS"&gt;By the time that new facility is up and running, Sila is destined to have some company. Tesla CEO (and Berdichevsky’s former boss) Elon Musk said late last year that Tesla is working to increase the level of silicon in the anode of the batteries it uses. Other companies are working to swap graphite for silicon, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZVUYdv"&gt;But Berdichevsky says he thinks there’s plenty of space for Sila to keep growing — not only because of the performance gains, but also because of how Sila’s business is currently structured. “We help [battery companies] deliver a higher performing battery that we do charge a premium for, and then we split that premium with them,” he says. “At the end of the day, if you’re making a better product, and customers just want to buy it, then there’s plenty to go around.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22662979/whoop-fitness-tracker-sila-silicon-anode-battery-electric-cars"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22662979/whoop-fitness-tracker-sila-silicon-anode-battery-electric-cars</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-08T15:22:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-08T15:22:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>Coinbase says SEC threatened lawsuit over Lend feature</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Na1dk2p7WjRbXvf-yIjf9wv01Qc=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69831310/acastro_170726_1777_0007_v5.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uFYqWA"&gt;Cryptocurrency exchange Coinbase seems to have some issues with the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) over a planned feature that lets people lend cryptocurrency through its platform. &lt;a href="https://blog.coinbase.com/the-sec-has-told-us-it-wants-to-sue-us-over-lend-we-have-no-idea-why-a3a1b6507009"&gt;In a Medium post&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday, Coinbase’s chief legal officer wrote that the regulatory agency threatened to sue the company if it launched the feature. Coinbase’s CEO &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/brian_armstrong/status/1435439291715358721?s=20"&gt;posted a Twitter thread&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday evening saying that the SEC wasn’t clear about what it wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rSmRbh"&gt;According to Coinbase’s CEO, Brian Armstrong, the company told the SEC about its new Lend feature as a courtesy but didn’t anticipate pushback, based on his impression that similar features exist on other platforms. However, according to Armstrong, the SEC informed the company that the lend feature would be considered a &lt;a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/s/security.asp"&gt;security&lt;/a&gt;, meaning it would be regulated as an investment. Coinbase disputes that classification, but they weren’t able to make their case in the same informal channels. Instead, according to Armstrong and the company, the SEC opened an investigation into Coinbase, asking for employee testimony and &lt;a href="https://blog.coinbase.com/the-sec-has-told-us-it-wants-to-sue-us-over-lend-we-have-no-idea-why-a3a1b6507009"&gt;the names and contact information&lt;/a&gt; of people who had signed up for the Lend waitlist. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;
&lt;div id="lFgz34"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;5/ They responded by telling us this lend feature is a security. Ok - seems strange, how can lending be a security? So we ask the SEC to help us understand and share their view. We always make an effort to work proactively with regulators, and keep an open mind.&lt;/p&gt;— Brian Armstrong (@brian_armstrong) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/brian_armstrong/status/1435439543692365828?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 8, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="86NDM3"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;7/ Look….we're committed to following the law. Sometimes the law is unclear. So if the SEC wants to publish guidance, we are also happy to follow that (it's nice if you actually enforce it evenly across the industry equally btw).&lt;/p&gt;— Brian Armstrong (@brian_armstrong) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/brian_armstrong/status/1435439676429537281?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 8, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xUQm2F"&gt;Armstrong says that Coinbase is looking for clearer information from the SEC and a written explanation of how it's judging Lend to be a security. According to the Medium post, the SEC told Coinbase that it had assessed Lend against two benchmark securities cases tried in the Supreme Court: &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SEC_v._W._J._Howey_Co."&gt;&lt;em&gt;SEC v. W. J. Howey Co.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lexisnexis.com/community/casebrief/p/casebrief-reves-v-ernst-young#"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reves v. Ernst &amp;amp; Young&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The former set the standard that investments would be considered securities if there’s “a reasonable expectation of profits to be derived from the efforts of others,” &lt;a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/h/howey-test.asp"&gt;according to Investopedia&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ru4eMf"&gt;Coinbase’s upcoming Lend feature, according to &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.coinbase.com%2Flend&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F8%2F22662826%2Fcoinbase-sec-lend-regulation-crypto-lawsuit-exchange" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;its website&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://blog.coinbase.com/sign-up-to-earn-4-apy-on-usd-coin-with-coinbase-cdad79e5f5eb"&gt;a Medium post&lt;/a&gt;, is meant to let people lend out their cryptocurrency and earn interest doing so. Coinbase says that the loans would go to “verified borrowers” and that the company would guarantee the initial value (so if you lent $100 through the program, Coinbase promises you’d get $100 back). It also says you can expect a return of 4 percent APY. &lt;a href="https://blog.coinbase.com/the-sec-has-told-us-it-wants-to-sue-us-over-lend-we-have-no-idea-why-a3a1b6507009"&gt;The company says&lt;/a&gt; that, in light of its SEC troubles, it won’t launch Lend “until at least October.”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OVPga4"&gt;A spokesperson for the SEC told &lt;em&gt;Reuters &lt;/em&gt;that the agency “does not comment on the existence or nonexistence of a possible investigation.” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sarthakgh/status/1435624549576499207?s=20"&gt;Many have&lt;/a&gt; seen a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SEC_Investor_Ed/status/1435606347807006728"&gt;recent tweet&lt;/a&gt; from the SEC’s Investor Education Twitter account as &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/chiaseedpuddin/status/1435633054488219651?s=20"&gt;trolling Coinbase&lt;/a&gt;, though: it contains a video explaining the concept of bonds, financial instruments that allow you to give a loan to a company or government, in return for interest payments. The tweet was posted Wednesday morning, after Armstrong’s Tuesday-night thread. However, the account regularly posts &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SEC_Investor_Ed/status/1433440325222154249?s=20"&gt;similar videos&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SEC_Investor_Ed/status/1435623989129383944"&gt;tips&lt;/a&gt;, so it’s possible the timing is coincidental. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yjrGwG"&gt;The SEC’s tiff with Coinbase may be indicative of its move toward regulating crypto more heavily. The current chairman &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22620464/tether-backing-cryptocurrency-stablecoin"&gt;has said that Stablecoins&lt;/a&gt;, or cryptocurrencies whose value is pegged to something else like the US dollar, may fall under the SEC’s jurisdiction. That could be relevant to Coinbase’s woes — the Lend feature that started all this was set to launch using USDC, a Stablecoin. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22662826/coinbase-sec-lend-regulation-crypto-lawsuit-exchange"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22662826/coinbase-sec-lend-regulation-crypto-lawsuit-exchange</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-08T15:19:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-08T15:19:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>How a GameStonk YouTuber is shaking up the California recall</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qQ8Jy52hudcA8QVHHoVhcOkRat0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69831303/acastro_210831_kevinPaffrath_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Kevin Paffrath wants to be the candidate for the /r/wallstreetbets voter&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="Th4KFr"&gt;Walking up to a podium in San Francisco this summer, Kevin Paffrath grabs the microphone. “Hodl that AMC,” he says with a smile, gazing out at the few dozen or so people, predominantly young men, attending the rally, a reference to the “meme stock” moment from earlier this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZwZckP"&gt;Paffrath, better known as MeetKevin on YouTube, is running to unseat Gov. Gavin Newsom in California’s recall election this month. It’s rare that a gubernatorial candidate would lead off a speech with such a painfully online reference, but that’s part of Paffrath’s appeal. He’s branded himself as the candidate for the r/wallstreetbets crowd — and so far, it’s working. As of publication, he’s the top polling Democrat at &lt;a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/california-recall-polls/"&gt;8 percent&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9AddDu"&gt;Since 2017, Paffrath has made YouTube videos full-time from his home in Ventura, streaming his takes on the financial and cryptocurrency markets to an audience of over 1 million subscribers. He’s also the only Democrat &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2021/08/24/trailer-bring-troops-home-why-afghanistan-crisis-isnt-reviving-gop-hawks/"&gt;spending big&lt;/a&gt; to win the election, and it’s made him the most viable candidate outside of Republicans like Larry Elder, a popular conservative talk radio host.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ld6Y8V"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s rare that a gubernatorial candidate would lead off a speech with such a painfully online reference&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gD7ysQ"&gt;Paffrath has no choice but to run as an outsider. He’s not a prominent figure in the Democratic Party or a well-seasoned politician. He’s a 29-year-old man in a suit, a real-estate guy, and a poster fluent in crypto-speak. Paffrath sees his outsider status as an advantage rather than a drawback, in the same vein as entrepreneurs like Donald Trump and Andrew Yang who turned their massive media followings into powerful political movements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mtGLyT"&gt;The chaos of California’s recall system can reward that kind of outsider bid. Newsom remains deeply unpopular (although his polling has improved in recent weeks). If he loses the up or down vote, the actual gubernatorial vote will be split among a dozen different candidates, with only a plurality needed to win. In 2003, that same chaos saw Gary Coleman and Arianna Huffington throwing their hats in the ring — and Arnold Schwarzenegger becoming governor. In 2021, California has seen a more representative crop: a conservative radio host, a reality television star, and a social media influencer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z891xs"&gt;If Paffrath wins on September 14th, he says he wants to “bring YouTube to government,” he told me over the phone last Tuesday. “YouTube could be a transparency tool as much as it could be a transparency weapon,” he said. “To make sure Californians know what’s standing in the way of the legislature getting things done.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wemmvm"&gt;Streaming in front of a colorfully backlit set, Paffrath earns more than “several million dollars a year in ad revenue alone” on YouTube, according to &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-social-media-stars-who-move-markets-11630056601"&gt;a recent &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal &lt;/em&gt;report&lt;/a&gt;. His video thumbnails often show him donning shocked faces, and his titles use emotional or humorous phrasing like “the fed JUST froze over” or “Stock Market YOLO.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JzVJNO"&gt;At the height of the meme stock movement in February, Paffrath gained over 150,000 subscribers, &lt;a href="https://socialblade.com/youtube/user/kevinpaffrath"&gt;according to SocialBlade&lt;/a&gt;. As that stock rush slowed, so did his growth. A few months later, he launched his gubernatorial campaign. But just as the Wall Street Bets posters sought to send GameStop “to the moon,” Paffrath is leveraging many of their same strategies to win his own moonshot campaign this month. Or maybe it’s just another growth hack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="5M2ic8"&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="zavcpL"&gt;At that same July rally, Paffrath lamented the loss of businesses and celebrities who had recently moved out of California due to what he said to be rising real estate prices.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GPpUP7"&gt;“Gavin says he doesn’t care if Tesla leaves. He doesn’t care if businesses leave,” Paffrath said, holding an iPad to read off his remarks. “Joe Rogan left. Elon Musk left. Coinbase left. Snowflake left. Palantir left. Hewlett Packard left.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iCO25c"&gt;When his mic stopped working, Paffrath told the crowd, “I’m shorting Sennheiser” with a laugh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="zrc08D"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Joe Rogan left. Elon Musk left. Coinbase left.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3G73TR"&gt;It’s this list of people and businesses Paffrath sees as representing his vision of California’s future. “We got to start by thinking big,” he told me over the phone last week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U0Gy1h"&gt;By big, he explains that he wants to end homelessness in 60 days by tasking the National Guard “with compassionately serving” the homeless community and moving them into vacant buildings. By big, he says he wants to incorporate “financial education” into the school system and partner with businesses in exchange for workers in “high-demand” careers like computer programming and electrical engineering. He wants to fully legalize gambling to help invest in “Las Vegas Strip style entertainment,” projecting $5–10 billion in tax revenue for the state. At his first debate earlier this summer, Paffrath touted these ideas along with others, like &lt;a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/politics/article/A-water-pipeline-to-the-Mississippi-River-16412788.php"&gt;building a giant pipeline&lt;/a&gt; to the Mississippi river to solve California’s drought problems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Id3Vi9"&gt;It may seem far-fetched for someone like this to be gaining ground, but he’s using a set of tactics that have proven to be immensely powerful for building a devoted base online. On YouTube, Paffrath calls on his subscribers to send texts for him to help get out the vote. Three months ago, he launched an app, notably listed in the “finance” category on the App Store, including a big “donate” button for his campaign. If someone uploads five screenshots of pro-Kevin posts they’ve made to the app, they score points. At one point, the highest scorers could win a meeting with Paffrath &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/newsom-challenger-offers-1-000-000-for-2-hour-governor-debate-301350382.html"&gt;on a private jet&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ks0uNI"&gt;“YouTube is very, very incredible because we can make a video and go ‘Hey, I need help for the next 48 hours,’” he says. “There’s just thousands of volunteers willing to do whatever it is we need. It’s very flattering.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="76Z1Bm"&gt;More recently, Paffrath filmed himself attending, or trying to attend, a Newsom rally. Earlier this week, Paffrath posted a video of himself being turned away from one. &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/california-recall-kevin-paffrath-newsom-warren"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fox News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;wrote up the incident. He tweeted it, along with other posts about being “BANNED,” scoring almost one thousand likes on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XcJg5w"&gt;“This is the 3rd time Fox National has cover the abuse of the Democratic process,” Paffrath &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/realMeetKevin/status/1434346877072277505?s=20"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt;. “Censorship by Instagram (deleting my initial announcement, CNN saying there’s no Democrat running vs Newsom (while a then current poll showed me beating Elder, + this.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tXEn23"&gt;These outrage posts, giveaways, and gamification have helped boost Paffrath in the polls. He’s using tactics familiar to his finance audience online, but in a way that expands his influence outside of that insular community. It’s a growing tactic over the last few election cycles as influencers spanning the gamut of right-wing reactionary &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/11/20689402/joey-salads-youtube-campaign-congress-trump-republican-political-bias"&gt;YouTube pranksters&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/21/21067086/joshua-collins-joshua4congress-tiktok-discord-campaigning-bernie-sanders-aoc"&gt;socialist TikTok stars&lt;/a&gt; have decided to throw their hats into the electoral ring, finding plenty of hype and little success. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JbF0Ih"&gt;“If a politician can speak to that constituency through skillful (and not cringey) use of insidery memes and language, it signals that they understand and are committed to all of that,” Lana Swartz, an assistant professor of media studies at the University of Virginia, told me last week. “It can be a very powerful message that transcends traditional partisan divides and eclipse other issues.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ElTHk5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It can be a very powerful message”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HuDefq"&gt;Next Tuesday is the last day for Californians to decide whether Newsom will remain as governor, and if not, who will replace him. This week, Arnold Schwarzenegger said that Newsom was in &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/arnold-schwarzenegger-newsom-is-in-a-dangerous-place-politically-2021-9"&gt;a “very dangerous” position&lt;/a&gt;, comparing the current recall climate to the one that ultimately launched the &lt;em&gt;Terminator&lt;/em&gt; star to the governor’s office back in 2003. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rEVFaB"&gt;But for Paffrath, the model is less Arnold and more Elon. He talks about Musk constantly — when I asked him why, he said simply: “He’s brilliant.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uyhHjU"&gt;“You should see what Elon Musk said this morning,” he told me, pointing me to a video he retweeted earlier in the day of Musk in Berlin complaining about the state of politics. “He recognizes and is willing to say what’s wrong,”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cpiqTq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22662970/gavin-newsom-california-kevin-paffrath-crypto-robinhood-gamestonk"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22662970/gavin-newsom-california-kevin-paffrath-crypto-robinhood-gamestonk</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-08T14:42:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-08T14:42:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>The first ‘Designed for Google Meet’ device is a $200 phone dock</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rxJRKqB2NxiDgul3f5QfdaQqzu4=/0x0:2000x1333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69831085/download__2_.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Appcessori Corporation&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EfEGdr"&gt;As cool as videoconferencing hardware can look, it’s often exorbitantly expensive — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22661653/series-one-desk-27-google-meet-laptop-monitor"&gt;the $2,000 Series One Desk 27&lt;/a&gt; for Google Meet being a perfect example. Luckily, alongside that expensive Meet machine, &lt;a href="https://workspaceupdates.googleblog.com/2021/09/coming-soon-new-google-meet-hardware.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+GoogleAppsUpdates+%28Google+Workspace+Updates+Blog%29"&gt;Google also announced&lt;/a&gt; its “Designed for Google Meet” program and a more affordable first entry, &lt;a href="https://rayzaudio.com/products/rayz-rally-pro"&gt;the Rayz Rally Pro&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a $200 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/21/20921173/google-nest-mini-echo-dot-assistant-smart-speaker-review"&gt;Nest Mini-like&lt;/a&gt; phone speaker that doubles as a microphone for Google Meet calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KDzqjH"&gt;The Rayz Rally Pro comes in a gray-tone fabric-covered body that looks a bit like Google’s smart speakers but with a phone dock carveout. The speaker dock comes in two varieties: a Lightning connector iPhone model and a Google Pixel version that should work with any USB-C phone. Both versions can work as a Bluetooth speaker, omnidirectional microphone, and 20W passthrough fast-charging dock for whatever phone you connect.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/z1iEGz5bdSTEZg5XYH1UOcTYvxE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22834705/download__1_.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Appcessori Corproation&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Rayz Rally Pro is a phone dock and microphone for Google Meet calls.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XoMjiL"&gt;The big trick of the Rally Pro and all of the third-party devices included in Google’s Designed for Google Meet program is its close integration with Google Meet. According to the Rally Pro’s manufacturer, Appcessori, “joining a Google Meet video call is as simple as plugging in a smartphone and then tapping the Google Meet invite that is automatically launched at plug in.” The device also features “active noise suppression and automatic gain control” and a dedicated mute button. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4PPqAm8ba2z-tMmgo-UOIOfgdfs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22834709/download__3_.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Appcessori Corporation&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Rally Pro can work standalone as a Bluetooth speaker and microphone, but also check out that mute button.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="D6aZU6"&gt;It’s not clear if those features will work the same way on a non-Google platform like iOS or if they’re compatible with other video chat software like Zoom or Webex. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; has contacted Appcessori for more information and will update if we learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KKsRBA"&gt;A note on Google Meet products: &lt;a href="https://meetingdevices.withgoogle.com/"&gt;The Series One line&lt;/a&gt; features Google’s design language, but are made by Avocor and Lenovo. “Designed for Google Meet” is a separate program for third party manufacturers. The program “identifies peripherals designed by partners specifically for and to work with Google Meet,” Google writes. Basically, some companies get to almost cosplay as Google, while others just get a stamp of approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T02kHg"&gt;The use cases for a microphone and speaker for video chatting on your phone seem like they might be limited. If you’re traveling and taking calls, a laptop could do the trick. But with phone selfie cameras frequently taking better video than &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"&gt;the built-in webcams in most laptops&lt;/a&gt;, maybe it starts to make more sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P6kZQH"&gt;You can preorder the Rayz Rally Pro for $199.99 now for an expected ship date of September 17th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="GnneRN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Series One Desk 27 is a $2,000 Google Meet machine that doubles as a laptop monitor ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22661653/series-one-desk-27-google-meet-laptop-monitor"},{"title":"Google announces its own Meet hardware bundle, but it’s only for conference rooms ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/15/21437114/google-meet-series-one-videoconferencing-hardware-conference-rooms-lenovo"},{"title":"Asus reveals new Google Meet videoconferencing hardware for offices ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/18/21262996/asus-google-meet-videoconferencing-hardware-offices-compute-system"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="xVDxlK"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 8th, 3:10PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added explanation of two Google Meet product lines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22662690/designed-for-google-meet-ray-z-rally-pro-phone-speaker"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22662690/designed-for-google-meet-ray-z-rally-pro-phone-speaker</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-08T14:25:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-08T14:25:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft’s new Xbox controller firmware lets you quickly switch between paired devices</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M72aIyRqFp9H6sI_RoxXSZsHQRo=/16x0:4912x3264/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69830992/xboxonescontroller.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Existing Xbox One controllers.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Tom Warren / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="neWzXy"&gt;Microsoft is starting to test a new firmware update for existing Xbox One, Xbox Elite 2, and Xbox Adaptive Controllers today that will bring some important improvements to existing hardware. The biggest addition is the ability to quickly switch between paired devices on an Xbox controller, and Microsoft is also adding Dynamic Latency Input (DLI) to improve input latency on older controllers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vkXdzY"&gt;This new firmware update includes Bluetooth Low Energy support for compatible controllers. Most of Microsoft’s existing Xbox One controllers include Bluetooth support for use on smartphones or PCs, but the controllers connect to Xbox consoles through the Xbox Wireless protocol. This new firmware will now make it easier to switch between the two, allowing the controllers to remember your Bluetooth phone and an Xbox console and quickly switch between connected devices by double-tapping the pair button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Dbtsa3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;DLI support is coming to Xbox One controllers&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CINr53"&gt;Microsoft’s other main addition is DLI, which reduces the input latency on controllers connected to Xbox Series X / S consoles to make gameplay more responsive. The addition of DLI means any older Xbox One controller will have reduced latency with an Xbox Series S or X console, just like the latest controllers that ship with these consoles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GJNQFY"&gt;Both are new features that the latest Xbox Series X / S controllers already support, but it’s good to see Microsoft extend this to older hardware. “We believe it’s important to maintain backward compatibility with Xbox accessories people already have in their collection and to ensure we deliver the best gaming experience no matter how you choose to play,” &lt;a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2021/09/08/xbox-controller-firmware-update-rolling-out-to-insiders-starting-today/"&gt;says Daniel Ruiz&lt;/a&gt;, a product marketing manager for Xbox accessories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hLnDQh"&gt;Microsoft is starting to test this new controller firmware with Alpha Skip-Ahead and Alpha Xbox Insiders today, and it should arrive for all Xbox owners in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22663039/microsoft-xbox-controller-firmware-dynamic-latency-input-dli-bluetooth-low-energy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22663039/microsoft-xbox-controller-firmware-dynamic-latency-input-dli-bluetooth-low-energy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-08T13:57:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-08T13:57:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best AirPods deals you can get right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Xuyyq2uKdLAhw_sX1Ij4bBYJxio=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67012056/cwelch_191031_3763_0003.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Apple’s AirPods Pro wireless earbuds are a go-to pick that’s often on sale | Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BJnRvD"&gt;Apple’s AirPods are among the most popular headphones on the market. Both the AirPods and AirPods Pro are compact, easy to pair with your devices, and offer reliable connectivity, which isn’t always the case with even the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds"&gt;best true wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt;. The AirPods Max, the latest pair of headphones to join the AirPods lineup, are just as dependable, albeit at a higher price and larger size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OR97R2"&gt;With Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/7/22648593/apple-fall-event-2021-date-iphone-macbook-watch"&gt;invite to its September 14th event just going out&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586507/apple-airpods-2021-refresh-rumor-iphone-se-2022-5g-15-details"&gt;rumors circling that new AirPods might be on the docket&lt;/a&gt;, we may see new versions of the standard AirPods soon. Luckily for those who seek a deal on the tried and true current crop, many of the most popular models routinely see discounts. There are often sizable sales on the second-gen base AirPods as well as the more expensive AirPods Pro and Max, which offer noise cancellation and better sound quality than the standard model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eJ0Ffb"&gt;Here, we’ll run through the best deals available on the AirPods, AirPods Pro, and AirPods Max. We’ll also include options for the AirPods with wireless charging case, if that’s something you prefer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dpo0N4"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="2RS0YX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best Apple Watch deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21289209/best-apple-watch-deals"},{"title":"The best deals on MacBooks right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22399419/apple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="VFDHZw"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;AirPods&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="R1mQdI"&gt;The AirPods are Apple’s entry-level wireless earbuds. They are a reliable pair with a one-size-fits-most design. They usually retail for $160, which is not a bad price, but this model frequently gets discounted. Right now, for instance, you can find Apple’s most affordable pair of AirPods for $119 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Charging-Latest-Model/dp/B07PXGQC1Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Charging-Case-Latest-Model%2F604342441&amp;amp;subid1=VergeAirPodsDeals03172021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, or for $130 at &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-airpods-with-charging-case%2F-%2FA-54191097%3Fclkid%3D48833994N865a11eb8ae142010a246e3b%26lnm%3D1003525%26afid%3DVox%2520Media%26ref%3Dtgt_adv_xasd0002&amp;amp;subid1=VergeAirPodsDeals03172021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1747976896193620917#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Evae3q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="PK1JRu"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AirPods (with wireless charging case)&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ImEUfP"&gt;The AirPods with a wireless charging case are identical in every way to the standard second-gen AirPods, save for one thing: their case can be charged via the included Lightning cable or a Qi wireless pad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rYNUWv"&gt;You’ll need to provide your own wireless charger to take advantage of this feature, but, thankfully, chargers like &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Anker-Wireless-PowerWave-Upgraded-Fast-Charging/dp/B07THHQMHM/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Anker’s PowerWave pad&lt;/a&gt; are now relatively cheap. If you have no use for wireless charging, however, we recommend saving more and opting for the base AirPods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="AFyzAp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9507432"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="glqkTs"&gt;Most of the time you can find this version for less than Apple’s sticker price of $199, but be on the lookout for deals that bring the price down to $150 or below. Right now, you can get them for $150 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Wireless-Charging-Latest/dp/B07PYLT6DN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Wireless-Charging-Case-Latest-Model%2F482532021&amp;amp;subid1=vergeairpodsbestdeals" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, or $160 at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1747977841356115870#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-airpods-with-wireless-charging-case%2F-%2FA-54191099%3Fclkid%3D48833994N865a11eb8ae142010a246e3b%26lnm%3D81938%26afid%3DVox%2520Media%26ref%3Dtgt_adv_xasd0002%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;subid1=VergeAirPodsDeals03172021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="eG2fnz"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="s9Ofwq"&gt;Apple’s premium true wireless earbuds, the AirPods Pro, have better sound quality than the models above and offer noise cancellation. They also come with swappable silicone tips and support &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/2/21498931/apple-spatial-audio-airpods-pro-surround-sound-quick-auto-switching" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;spatial audio&lt;/a&gt;, a feature Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525028/apple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;rolled out to Apple Music in June&lt;/a&gt;. We think they’re the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;best wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt; that iPhone owners can buy, regardless of the price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bM8uVd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ci8unb"&gt;Thankfully, the AirPods Pro are frequently available for less than their asking price of $249, and sometimes drop to as low as $170. The lowest price you can grab a pair for right now is $190 at &lt;a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-Pro%2F520468661%3Fwmlspartner%3Dwlpa%26selectedSellerId%3D0%26%26adid%3D22222222227317608597%26wl0%3D%26wl1%3Dg%26wl2%3Dc%26wl3%3D395477009936%26wl4%3Dpla-834433976587%26wl5%3D9061079%26wl6%3D%26wl7%3D%26wl8%3D%26wl9%3Dpla%26wl10%3D8175035%26wl11%3Donline%26wl12%3D520468661%26veh%3Dsem%26gclid%3DCjwKCAjwr56IBhAvEiwA1fuqGoJTvXd60Wil7w2NpRvHJQwNPXUkWno3r0nNI2Z3XwNpX4tSWE601RoCuScQAvD_BwE%26gclsrc%3Daw.ds" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MWP22AM-A-AirPods-Pro/dp/B07ZPC9QD4?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, or for $200 at &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/1122332/2092?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-airpods-pro%2F-%2FA-54191101" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="x5NHYH"&gt;The best &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22177494/apple-airpods-max-headphones-review-price-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AirPods Max&lt;/a&gt; deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ESUeUd"&gt;The AirPods Max aren’t the iconic in-ear style that has become synonymous with the AirPods name. They’re large and luxurious, wrapped in aluminum, steel, and mesh fabric that remains comfortable during extended listening sessions. They also sport excellent noise cancellation, Apple’s spatial audio feature, and wide, balanced sound, even if they lag behind some of their peers when it comes to bass response. They’re not the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21345733/best-noise-canceling-headphones" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;best noise-canceling headphones&lt;/a&gt; for most people — blame the $550 sticker price — but it’s hard to find a pair of Bluetooth headphones that sound better and feature more intuitive controls. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="KBAAwB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10361602"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="irGZgJ"&gt;Although the AirPods Max have been discounted to under $450 at retailers like Amazon, Best Buy, and Simply Mac in the past, there are currently few sales that deep to speak of. The best price right now comes from &lt;a href="https://www.tkqlhce.com/click-8836602-13527013?sid=VergeDailyDeals090221&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Felectronics.woot.com%2Foffers%2Fapple-airpods-max-headphones-1%3F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Woot&lt;/a&gt;, where you can get a new pair of AirPods Max for $470, as long as you don’t mind the silver color scheme. The Max are also currently available in all colorways at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-Apple-AirPods-Max-Space/dp/B08PZHYWJS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; for $499, which is their typical sale price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Mpx47T"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
      <name>Brandon Widder</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-08T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-08T13:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google says Android 12 is a ‘few weeks away,’ makes beta available on Pixel 5A</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JKu9hDgm-mwKRqgwrMcJFhK0CIE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69830535/ajohnson_210813_4713_0007.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Et3S04"&gt;Google is releasing what it says is the fifth and final version of the Android 12 beta, adding that the official release of the full Android 12 operating system is “just a few weeks away.” The new beta release will also be the first one that Pixel 5A owners will be able to install. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PzzUsN"&gt;People who are already running the beta aren’t likely to notice much of a difference, as its focus is on getting developers ready for the impending official Android 12 release, rather than adding new features. But, for those who’ve gotten their hands on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22628205/google-pixel-5a-review-price-screen-battery-specs"&gt;Google’s latest phone&lt;/a&gt;, there’s now the opportunity to see what that release will be like before it happens — and without a ton of risk, since the beta has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/11/22619546/android-12-beta-4-released-platform-stable-af"&gt;entered its “platform stability” phase&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GMak6I"&gt;The Pixel 5A &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/17/22627253/google-pixel-5a-specs-price-screen-battery-availability"&gt;launched in late August&lt;/a&gt;, and the beta hasn’t been officially available on it until now. While the phone’s launch has been limited — it’s only being sold in the US and Japan — anyone who’s picked one up can now play with the new version of Android before it officially releases. If you’re like me, running the beta could be a way to get some experience with a new release before it officially launches and you start getting questions about it from family members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="AvhWac"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Android 12 brings big UI changes that may prompt questions from less techy family members&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MIULNa"&gt;For this specific release, that experience may be useful. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22439777/android-12-design-features-widgets-first-look-google"&gt;Android 12 is a big UI redesign&lt;/a&gt; (at least on Pixels) with a theming system, a new widget system, and a different location for smart home controls and Google Pay. Though the OS’ official release is imminent, when you’ll be able to install it depends on your phone’s manufacturer. If you’re a Pixel 5A owner, though, or you have any of the other supported phones, you can &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22442576/android-12-public-beta-install-how-to-update"&gt;follow our guide on how to install the beta&lt;/a&gt; to get Android 12 as soon as you’d like.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22661647/android-12-final-beta-5-pixel-5a-stability-ui-changes-preview"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22661647/android-12-final-beta-5-pixel-5a-stability-ui-changes-preview</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-08T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-08T13:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter takes on Facebook Groups with invite-only Communities</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VQZe4G0c6z8svuO-u6nKfZtzcLE=/0x4:1320x884/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69830548/Twitter_Communities_hero.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Twitter&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="S85jJ4"&gt;Twitter is launching Communities, its rival to Facebook Groups and Reddit, for tweeting with others who share specific interests. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F9iHKZ"&gt;Starting Wednesday, Twitter users can be invited to an initial batch of Communities that include #AstroTwitter, #DogTwitter, #SkincareTwitter, and #SoleFood (a group for sneaker enthusiasts). Once people join a Community, they can tweet directly to other members rather than to just their followers. Only members of a Community can like or reply to tweets sent by other members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iPzVNv"&gt;Similar to how groups on Facebook and Reddit’s subreddits work, each Twitter Community will have its own moderators who are able to set rules and invite or remove people. Twitter invited a handful of users to create the first Communities and will let anyone apply to create their own &lt;a href="https://help.twitter.com/en/forms/communities-interest"&gt;on its website&lt;/a&gt;. “Communities are just invite-only for now, but we’re working on ways for people to discover and join Communities they want to be a part of,” the company said in a statement. That makes Communities harder to join than subreddits or public groups on Facebook. Twitter is also approving moderators to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AloP93"&gt;Communities is a somewhat obvious move for Twitter, given that its users have long formed niche groups around specific interests, like media and crypto. Twitter is now formalizing that dynamic into a product that it plans to eventually put front and center on the main navigation bar of its mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FFkpVV"&gt;Those who have access to Communities on iOS can access them through the tab on the navigation bar, while users on the web will see a Communities tab on the sidebar. On Android, you’ll only be able to read Community tweets for now — additional functionality is “coming soon,” Twitter says.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/t0Uwv90lKU32yRFqi8k1FUbdXDc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22833067/LEq8g8SJJehgbNSEi7FAl3Qnb8C3ciak5BAhHgVFhWi3pcjUJVQKUbZ5XKn1dL4vTufxy4ZP4_MeJOtDb1bLOYVpfc_7h0HIoVcdjQgJ6rwNoeLN_0wQ_UHura288IsIw3q319G9_s0.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="SaEUlL"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The feature could make Twitter more compelling for casual users&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5ukeAS"&gt;Twitter has long struggled with retaining people who come to it and don’t consistently find relevant tweets or accounts to follow. To help fix the problem, the company has in the past couple of years prioritized recommending topics, such as professional sports teams, to follow. If Twitter lets anyone create and easily promote their own Communities, the feature could make the app more compelling for casual users who haven’t put in the effort to heavily curate their main timeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M7hOGU"&gt;Twitter first previewed that it was working on Communities in February &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301375/twitter-super-follows-communities-paid-followers"&gt;during a presentation to investors&lt;/a&gt;, saying its goal was to make it “easier for people to form, discover, and participate in conversations that are more targeted to the relevant communities or geographies they’re interested in.” That implies Communities could also take on apps like Nextdoor by suggesting groups for people who live in a specific city or neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aZCYUt"&gt;Communities is the latest in a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22319527/twitter-kayvon-beykpour-interview-consumer-product-decoder"&gt;string of big product bets from Twitter&lt;/a&gt; over the last year, including its audio chat feature Spaces, paywalled tweets, and push into newsletter hosting.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22661649/twitter-releases-communities-facebook-groups-reddit-competitor"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22661649/twitter-releases-communities-facebook-groups-reddit-competitor</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Heath</name>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-08T12:34:13-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-08T12:34:13-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sony buys The Playroom developers to bolster its PlayStation Studios</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2OXdIFHA9SH6M-9EgLUssa0a3Dg=/100x0:1180x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69830456/Playroom2_compressed.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A screenshot from &lt;/em&gt;The Playroom&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Firesprite&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yefJSC"&gt;Sony announced that it will &lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/09/08/welcoming-firesprite-to-the-playstation-studios-family/"&gt;acquire UK-based studio Firesprite&lt;/a&gt;, the developers of &lt;em&gt;The Playroom&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Playroom VR. &lt;/em&gt;It’s unclear what Firesprite might be working on in its new first-party capacity, but executives are already hyping what’s to come. “Firesprite’s ability to weave best-in-class gameplay with new technology is exceptional and I think fans will be excited about their creative vision for the future,” Hermen Hulst, the head of PlayStation Studios, &lt;a href="https://www.firesprite.com/news/2021/09/sony-interactive-entertainment-to-acquire-firesprite-games/"&gt;said in a press release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4xlFfS"&gt;Firespite was founded by staffers from Sony Interactive Entertainment’s Liverpool studio, so there are already strong connections between the two companies. While Firesprite’s experience with &lt;em&gt;The Playroom VR&lt;/em&gt; could suggest that the company is working on a game for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609558/sony-playstation-psvr-oled-aaa-eye-tracking-controllers"&gt;Sony’s next-gen PlayStation VR headset&lt;/a&gt;, in an &lt;a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/articles/2021-09-08-why-playstation-is-buying-firesprite-one-of-the-uks-fastest-growing-games-studios"&gt;interview with &lt;em&gt;GamesIndustry.biz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Hulst didn’t commit to anything. “It’s too early to talk about what specific platforms or experiences that we’re going to collaborate on with Firesprite,” he said. “But that experience [in VR] is very valuable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="I0zAQG"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Firesprite will be the 14th studio in the PlayStation Studios lineup&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oG5ZgG"&gt;Firespite will be the 14th studio in the PlayStation Studios lineup. The acquisition is the third in what’s been something of a buying spree for Sony as of late; it acquired &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22408468/returnal-ps5-dualsense-3d-audio"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Returnal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; developer &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22555358/sony-housemarque-returnal-developer-acquisition-bluepoint"&gt;Housemarque in June&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nixxes.com/nixxes-joins-playstation-studios/"&gt;Dutch studio Nixxes in July&lt;/a&gt;. Other PlayStation Studios include big names like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22523093/ratchet-clank-rift-apart-review-ps5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ratchet &amp;amp; Clank&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; developers Insomniac Games, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641595/horizon-zero-dawn-60fps-update-ps5-1-53"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Horizon Zero Dawn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; developers Guerrilla Games, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21286964/the-last-of-us-part-2-review-ps4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Last of Us&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; developers Naughty Dog.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22662706/sony-firesprite-the-playroom-developers-playstation-studios"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22662706/sony-firesprite-the-playroom-developers-playstation-studios</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
