<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-22T07:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-22T07:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-22T07:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to watch Microsoft’s Surface event today</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8CAc52AX9dhUytzuOgLyInbrUyo=/200x0:2333x1422/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69892135/Screen_Shot_2021_09_20_at_3.48.57_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="sfr0cq"&gt;Microsoft is holding an online hardware event on Wednesday, September 22nd, at 11AM ET / 8AM PT, where it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671271/microsoft-surface-event-pro-8-surface-book-4-rumors"&gt;expected to announce&lt;/a&gt; redesigned Surface tablets and laptops (and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/26/22593992/microsoft-surface-duo-2-triple-camera-leak-photos"&gt;potentially a new phone&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;will be covering any announcements from the event and running a world-class live blog, and here’s how you can watch along with us, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mKM4HQ"&gt;It’s simple: Microsoft will have a livestream &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fevent" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on the events page of its website&lt;/a&gt;, and you’ll also be able to watch it on on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/surface/status/1435618941473148938"&gt;Microsoft’s Surface Twitter account&lt;/a&gt;. You can follow &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/verge"&gt;@verge on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; to see news from the event as it happens. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nIayK4"&gt;Looming over the event is the upcoming release of Windows 11, which will be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22649940/windows-11-release-date-features-devices-free-upgrade"&gt;coming out on October 5th&lt;/a&gt;. While it’s almost a given that anything Microsoft announces at Wednesday’s event will be running the new OS, it will be interesting if the rumors about Microsoft releasing a new version of its Arm-based Surface Pro X tablet are true. We don’t have a very clear picture of how Windows 11 will pair with Microsoft’s long-running Arm computing ambitions — and a new computer, perhaps one with a new Microsoft-designed chip, could be a great time for the company to talk about the future of Windows outside of Intel, AMD, and x86 in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dmbhw0"&gt;There are also likely to be some traditional x86 computers shown off at the event, with rumors suggesting that we’ll see a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/19/22682271/surface-pro-8-120hz-display-thunderbolt-support-leak-rumors"&gt;Surface Pro 8 tablet&lt;/a&gt;, a new &lt;a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/surface-book-4"&gt;Surface Book laptop&lt;/a&gt;, and an updated &lt;a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/surface-go-3"&gt;Surface Go&lt;/a&gt;. There’s also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22683595/microsoft-surface-duo-2-fcc-5g-nfc-wireless-charging-support-features"&gt;the real possibility&lt;/a&gt; we’ll see a follow-up to Microsoft’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21428763/microsoft-surface-duo-review"&gt;Surface Duo folding phone&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="kh4Oxo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"What to expect from Microsoft’s Surface event","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671271/microsoft-surface-event-pro-8-surface-book-4-rumors"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="VCm1Z5"&gt;But, if you're listening, Microsoft, I’d really like to see a version of the beautiful &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fsurface-ergonomic-keyboard%2F90pnc9ljwpx9%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%3Aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Surface Ergonomic Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;, this time one without a number pad to get in the way of mousing. Your other keyboard, the Sculpt Ergonomic, is just not terribly well-built, and I’d prefer Bluetooth to a USB dongle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i5e9Ep"&gt;To see the news as it happens on Wednesday morning, stay tuned to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, and head to &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fevent" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft’s website to see the stream&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22684741/microsoft-surface-event-watch-live-stream-start-time-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22684741/microsoft-surface-event-watch-live-stream-start-time-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-22T07:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-22T07:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Gitamini is a cute, compact, cargo-carrying robot that will follow you around like a dog</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AXy-B0D4yQrpZ6xzLmPPBma6J-8=/0x0:6582x4388/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69892140/459_GitaStudio_Lifestyles_167_edit.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Gitamini uses machine vision and AI to follow its owner. &lt;/em&gt; | Image: Piaggio Fast Forward&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4avhGt"&gt;Piaggio Fast Forward, a subsidiary of storied Italian automotive firm Piaggio, has launched its second robot, a compact version of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/15/20897348/piaggio-vespa-gita-cargo-robot"&gt;cargo-carrying bot Gita&lt;/a&gt; named Gitamini. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ge34FS"&gt;The form and function of Gitamini remain the same as that of full-sized Gita (the name is Italian for a small trip or outing). The robot consists of two large wheels, a central trunk, and a machine vision system that it uses to identify and follow its owner. Gitamini weighs 28 pounds and can carry up to 20 pounds in its interior for 21 miles. That makes an interesting comparison to Gita, which can carry more — 40 pounds but only for 12 miles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r5QaSJ"&gt;Gitamini uses an array of cameras and sensors, including radar (not available for the original Gita), to navigate and follow its user. To activate this follow mode, you simply stand in front of the Gitamini and tap a pairing button. The robot will then lock on to you using vision only (no GPS or Bluetooth are utilized) and will follow you at speeds of up to 6mph. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/j-uTgPX9oYxBqARsdC1emn5ymR8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22867230/459_GitaStudio_Lifestyles_31_edit.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Piaggio Fast Forward&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The original Gita (left) and new Gitamini (right). &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="0G0KYl"&gt;The robot’s trunk can be locked and its follow mode disabled, but there are no active theft mitigation features. When asked about this, Piaggio Fast Forward’s CEO Greg Lynn told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that it was “unlikely someone could get away with walking away with it unnoticed” as it’s such a noticeable object. “A stolen Gita isn’t of much use to anyone as it uses a secure connection to a phone to be unlocked, updated, and used,” says Lynn. “We have yet to learn of a Gita being stolen or broken into while being used or when parked.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7r5lAd"&gt;The Gita has always been a bit of an odd product. It certainly looks fantastic, and videos &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/2DaDnC-uhHM"&gt;suggest it works more or less as advertised&lt;/a&gt; (though it’s noisier than you might expect). But it’s not clear exactly who’s going to spend thousands of dollars on something that only carries a few bags and is stymied by steps and stairs. Gitamini doesn’t change any of these basic annoyances, though it is at least a little cheaper — it costs $1,850 (and will be available to buy from October 15th at &lt;a href="http://mygita.com/"&gt;mygita.com&lt;/a&gt;) while the launch sees the price of the original Gita drop to $2,950. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vndv3Y"&gt;When we asked CEO Greg Lynn about the robot, he declined to share any sales figures with us but said there were Gita robots operating in “half the states in the US [...] with a focus on the Southern belt where outdoor weather is more friendly year-round.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mgoVg3"&gt;“Most of the consumer Gitas are being used to replace car trips for neighborhood errands in a variety of communities, and they are used outdoors for round trips of a mile or more,” said Lynn. Though, he noted that the company had some business customers, too. There are currently Gitas in eight airports in the US (including JFK and LAX) and a number more in planned communities, like Water Street Tampa in Florida and Ontario Ranch in California. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L5BXN2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22685649/gita-gitamini-cargo-carrying-robot-piaggio"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22685649/gita-gitamini-cargo-carrying-robot-piaggio</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-22T06:37:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-22T06:37:52-04:00</updated>
    <title>Uber thinks it could actually turn a profit this quarter</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Mm0wObFy_epb8ZP6MauhmFwuXc8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69892062/acastro_180927_1777_uber_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="F0CwRU"&gt;Uber says it may be profitable this quarter for the first time in its history. The disclosure came in a &lt;a href="https://sec.report/Document/0001552781-21-000710/0001552781-21-000710.txt"&gt;new filing&lt;/a&gt; made with the US Securities and Exchange Commission. Whereas the company previously expected to make a net loss of under $100 million, it now believes it could make an adjusted profit of up to $25 million. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZkYFYc"&gt;“We believe Uber is now tracking towards Adjusted EBITDA [earnings before interest, tax, depreciation and amortisation] breakeven in Q3, well ahead of our prior guidance,” said the company’s CFO, Nelson Chai, in the filing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pnKb4N"&gt;In a worst case scenario, the company cautions that it could still make a loss of $25 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6O7GBa"&gt;However, criticism has been levelled at the way Uber calculated its adjusted profits. &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/uber-says-its-on-track-to-maybe-make-a-fake-profit-1847716786"&gt;G&lt;em&gt;izmodo &lt;/em&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt; that the company’s definition of EBITDA includes an unusually large list of exclusions, and argues it’s not an accurate measure of the company’s overall profitability. Nevertheless, Uber shareholders were pleased, with the stock closing up 11 percent on the updated forecast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NY6RNH"&gt;“They say that crisis breeds opportunity and that’s certainly been true of Uber during the last 18 months,” CEO Dara Khosrowshahi said, adding that the quarter could prove to be an “important milestone” for the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="X9DnS1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“They say that crisis breeds opportunity”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="psvvzL"&gt;It would certainly be an important milestone for Khosrowshahi, who took over as CEO in 2017, and has steered the company through a pandemic that rocked its core ride-hailing business as people drastically cut back on their travel. In May last year the company reported that its ride-hailing business &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/7/21251111/uber-q1-earnings-rides-loss-eats-delivery-coronavirus"&gt;suffered an 80 percent drop&lt;/a&gt;, contributing to a $2.9 billion quarterly loss for the company. In response, Khosrowshahi laid off &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/18/21262337/uber-layoff-3000-employees-covid-19-coronavirus"&gt;thousands&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/10/20859413/uber-job-layoffs-announcement-engineering-product-profit"&gt;employees&lt;/a&gt;. Uber also sold off its self-driving car unit &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/7/22158745/uber-selling-autonomous-vehicle-business-aurora-innovation"&gt;at the end of last year&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7gJEBt"&gt;However, with the easing of lockdown restrictions around the world, demand for Uber’s ride-hailing business has started to recover, resulting in an acute &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22371850/uber-lyft-driver-shortage-covid-bonus-stimulus"&gt;driver shortage&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year. Meanwhile, the company’s food-delivery business, while still unprofitable overall, has &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/05/uber-earnings-food-delivery-revenue"&gt;boomed over the course of the pandemic&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7EhQMV"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/uber-says-it-will-post-its-first-adjusted-profit-11632220496"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; notes&lt;/a&gt; that Uber has posted a rare net profit in the past due to one-time investments and divestitures, but this could be the first time its core operations turn a net profit since its founding over a decade ago. A &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/df377e2b-6e3a-445a-b8d7-1c29d170a2fd"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt; report from June&lt;/a&gt; said that Uber’s total losses since its founding in 2009 measured over $22 billion. Its main US rival, Lyft, posted an adjusted profit in the second quarter of this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4h7URS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22687501/uber-adjusted-profit-q3-2021-pandemic-ride-hailing-food-delivery"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22687501/uber-adjusted-profit-q3-2021-pandemic-ride-hailing-food-delivery</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-22T05:30:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-22T05:30:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>Need to trap a Roomba? You don’t need anything more sophisticated than a rug</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HGokXA-X3tb2MmVPlVoRUp9d6N4=/0x127:3000x2127/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69891976/Roomba_980_wall_follow.0.0.1442365225.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="A6rB7j"&gt;iRobot recently launched a new robot vacuum cleaner that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22660467/irobot-roomba-ai-dog-poop-avoidance-j7-specs-price"&gt;uses AI to avoid dog poop&lt;/a&gt;, but the company’s Roombas have long struggled with a more basic problem: confusing dark patterns on carpets and rugs for perilous drops. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0qteOu"&gt;A video &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DimaKrotov/status/1436150021792149506"&gt;recently shared on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; by IBM researcher Dmitry Krotov shows exactly the problem: a Roomba rolling around inside a rectangular box pattern on a rug, refusing to drive over the lines as if were physical walls. Usually, iRobot’s software flags this sort of problem as a dangerous “cliff,” and a quick search on Twitter for “&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=roomba%20rug%20cliff&amp;amp;src=typed_query"&gt;roomba rug cliff&lt;/a&gt;” shows it’s a pretty common error. As one user &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jamester74/status/1267074557778722817"&gt;complains&lt;/a&gt;: “I swear that Robby the Roomba is a right drama queen!! This is NOT a cliff Robby. It’s a rug!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1CmKY6"&gt;The actual mechanics behind this error are pretty fascinating, though. And it has nothing to do with machine learning, but rather the cost constraints on the robot vacuums’ hardware. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3qMpBq"&gt;As iRobot research scientist Ben Kenhoe &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ben11kehoe/status/1440355689830838280"&gt;explained in response&lt;/a&gt; to Krotov’s video, the basic problem is that Roombas detect sudden drops like stairs and steps using a combination of an LED and a photodiode — a sensor that detects light. As Kenhoe &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ben11kehoe/status/1440362451095068672"&gt;puts it&lt;/a&gt;: “Does the photodiode detect reflected light from the LED? Great, the floor is there! No reflected light? Uh oh, that must be a cliff. Dark black carpet-&amp;gt;no reflected light, it looks like a cliff!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="URzAK7"&gt;The problem, notes Kenhoe, is balancing the accuracy of the Roomba’s sensors while keeping unit costs low. “Our newer models don’t suffer from this, but it took YEARS to figure out how to make the sensor robust to this while remaining cost effective,” he &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ben11kehoe/status/1440355689830838280"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sc7m1n"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZKE2Po"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/9/22/22687449/roomba-rug-dark-pattern-cliff-edge-why-problem"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/9/22/22687449/roomba-rug-dark-pattern-cliff-edge-why-problem</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-22T03:28:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-22T03:28:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix makes its biggest acquisition ever — the Roald Dahl catalog</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/q0Q6WAWoZOdi0eRhr1bmOt0bZ1Q=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69890125/RD_NETFLIX_LH_V009__0_00_07_21_20181127_5885_fizs41.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FqxhXv"&gt;Nearly three years after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/27/18114572/netflix-animated-adaptations-willy-wonka-matilda-bfg-roald-dahl-books"&gt;Netflix signed a deal with The Roald Dahl Story Company&lt;/a&gt; to create a universe of animated features based on the author’s books, the company has acquired the works outright. &lt;a href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/netflix-acquires-iconic-roald-dahl-story-company"&gt;Netflix made the deal official&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday after news of the impending acquisition was first reported by &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-09-21/netflix-is-said-to-be-nearing-deal-to-buy-roald-dahl-catalog"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w8zHLF"&gt;There’s no word on exactly how much it costs to own Willy Wonka, the BFG, Matilda, and all the rest, but in 2018, &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-news/netflixs-roald-dahl-deal-could-create-tv-universe-1164419/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hollywood Reporter &lt;/em&gt;cited&lt;/a&gt; sources claiming that simply licensing 16 titles from the catalog cost Netflix more than $100 million. A deal for this catalog would likely rank as Netflix’s largest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="6Vmd8w"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Reed Hastings and the Giant Acquisition&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OB1nK0"&gt;Under the previous deal, Taika Waititi is &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2020/tv/news/taika-waititi-netflix-charlie-and-the-chocolate-factory-animated-series-willy-wonka-oompa-loompa-1203524577/"&gt;working on Roald Dahl animated series projects for Netflix&lt;/a&gt;, covering &lt;em&gt;Charlie and the Chocolate Factory &lt;/em&gt;and its sequel, &lt;em&gt;Charlie and the Great Glass Elevator&lt;/em&gt;. That’s in addition to two different versions of Matilda, including a film version of &lt;em&gt;Matilda the Musical&lt;/em&gt; and an animated series, plus plans to make a&lt;em&gt; The BFG&lt;/em&gt; cartoon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NFTybM"&gt;Netflix now plans to bring the collection to more audiences in new formats. “These projects opened our eyes to a much more ambitious venture,” said the streaming company in a press release. “The creation of a unique universe across animated and live action films and TV, publishing, games, immersive experiences, live theatre, consumer products and more.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m9mWcX"&gt;Prior to the deal’s announcement, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;noted that it would happen despite the shadow cast by Dahl’s history of antisemitic statements and sometimes &lt;a href="https://www.newstatesman.com/politics/2018/11/i-d-still-read-roald-dahl-s-books-my-children-we-can-t-forget-he-was-anti-semite"&gt;misogynistic storytelling&lt;/a&gt;. The Dahl Family and the Roald Dahl Story Company &lt;a href="https://www.roalddahl.com/global/rdsc-and-family-notice"&gt;released an apology&lt;/a&gt; for the remarks in 2020, saying, “We hope that, just as he did at his best, at his absolute worst, Roald Dahl can help remind us of the lasting impact of words.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LD482v"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclosure: The Verge is currently producing a series with Netflix.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bei4u7"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 22nd, 3:40AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Story updated with confirmation of the acquisition and relevant quotes from press release.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3sf4lP"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686472/netflix-rumor-roald-dahl-willy-wonka-bfg-matilda"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686472/netflix-rumor-roald-dahl-willy-wonka-bfg-matilda</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
      <name>Thomas Ricker</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T23:34:12-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T23:34:12-04:00</updated>
    <title>iOS 15.1’s first beta suggests we could see SharePlay soon</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5YnyT9jGz12swQUpHyi1jxKduWE=/13x0:2032x1346/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69891587/D3743FFE_9B62_4074_ADC3_50C2232BB74A.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="h4zR8p"&gt;SharePlay has returned in the iOS 15.1 beta, &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/09/21/ios-15-1-beta-1-re-enables-shareplay-feature-following-delay/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/17/22629165/apple-shareplay-ios-ipad-os-15-macos-delayed"&gt;Apple delayed the major iOS 15 feature&lt;/a&gt; to “later this fall” instead of having it launch alongside the OS upgrade as planned. It’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22684483/ios-15-announced-features-shareplay-airpods-universal-control"&gt;not the only feature&lt;/a&gt; that’s hasn’t made it to release yet, but it could be a useful one during the ongoing pandemic — it lets you watch videos, screen share, or listen to music with other people over a FaceTime call. Its existence in Tuesday’s new beta could indicate that it could be coming sooner than later, though that’s not a sure thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VIWUKs"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/09/21/ios-15-vaccine-card-wallet-app/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that the 15.1 beta also lets users add their COVID vaccine card to the Wallet app, once you’ve first added it to Health. Similar to how &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/30/22558245/google-pay-covid-vaccination-card-android-digital-pass"&gt;Google’s version of this feature works&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll have to get your vaccine info from your medical provider or your state’s healthcare system before you can add it to your phone. &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=7h3vwlh5"&gt;Apple says&lt;/a&gt; the feature uses the SMART Health Card format, which is currently &lt;a href="https://www.commontrustnetwork.org/verifier-list"&gt;supported by a handful of states and some major vaccination providers&lt;/a&gt;. The list includes states like California, Hawaii, New York, and Louisiana, as well as pharmacy providers like CVS, Rite Aid, and Walmart, but you can click the link for the full details. As always, check with your local healthcare provider for more info.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rBb0fAMdqijdEosAZ6EFa_PFPzo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22868514/2048.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can add verified vaccine records from certain health providers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="gO6R9t"&gt;These features showing up in the iOS 15.1 beta don’t necessarily mean they’ll be in the final iOS 15.1 release — after all, SharePlay was introduced during the iOS 15 beta, but was later removed. However, Apple &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fios%2Fios-15%2Ffeatures%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F21%2F22686897%2Fios-15-1-beta-shareplay-feature-announced-removed-coming-soon-vaccine-card" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;does still say&lt;/a&gt; that SharePlay will ship “later this fall,” and there’s only so much time left for that (plus, it would be a bit odd if it was removed from &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; beta). The vaccine card feature will be included in an “upcoming software update,” according to the company, so it’s possible it’s further out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tdzwDB"&gt;It also may be a bit before we see iOS 15.1, given that iOS 15 was just released yesterday (iOS 14.1 &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201222"&gt;came about a month after&lt;/a&gt; iOS 14). But if this early beta is any indication, it could be bringing some nice new features with it when it does show up. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686897/ios-15-1-beta-shareplay-feature-announced-removed-coming-soon-vaccine-card"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686897/ios-15-1-beta-shareplay-feature-announced-removed-coming-soon-vaccine-card</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T20:19:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T20:19:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>The first patient testimony about a Theranos test result: a miscarriage that wasn’t</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Elizabeth Holmes Theranos Trial Continues In California" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w4XCIP1egTfv2lejhSiPtn2oGIE=/0x0:4502x3001/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69891173/1340934529.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Theranos founder and CEO Elizabeth Holmes.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Justin Sullivan/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;‘You can’t provide accurate patient care with inaccurate results.’&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="eY0C0L"&gt;Brittany Gould, wearing a black mask with a clear window through which you could see her mouth, got choked up as she told the court about her experience with Theranos in 2014. She’d used the company’s tests because they were cheap — her language was “cost-effective” — and the results told her, wrongly, that she was miscarrying. It would have been her fourth miscarriage in a row.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dolu6h"&gt;The defense in US v. Elizabeth Holmes blocked testimony from Gould about the emotional impact of the bad test, so jurors didn’t hear how it affected her. But “the loss of all these babies and pregnancies, and going through the experience of thinking I’m losing another one, is a lot,” &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/theranos-patients-the-emerging-wild-card-in-the-trial-of-elizabeth-holmes-11627915111"&gt;Gould told &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in an interview before the trial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="WQ8mCL"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The experience was unremarkable — until the wrong result came back&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CFDfIp"&gt;Gould’s bad results are the first real-world example of how Theranos’ tests affected patients. So far we’ve heard from employees about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/15/22676789/elizabeth-holmes-theranos-wire-fraud-erika-cheung-whistleblower"&gt;bad labs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22680372/elizabeth-holmes-wire-fraud-emails-gangakhedkar"&gt;inaccurate results&lt;/a&gt; — but we haven’t seen ordinary people whose lives have been affected by them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rYO57h"&gt;Gould is among the patients that the government will call to testify against Holmes, who is facing 10 counts of wire fraud and two of conspiracy to commit wire fraud. But it’s hard to know exactly how many patients received bad results. Though there was a company database of millions of results, it was encrypted and &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/a-theranos-database-is-useless-what-happened-11614205525"&gt;the government didn’t get the password to it&lt;/a&gt;; the original version of the database has been destroyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VziAKv"&gt;Gould went to Walgreens, which hosted Theranos wellness centers, and “got my finger poked,” she testified. Besides the finger stick test, the experience was unremarkable — until the wrong result came back. Her nurse practitioner called Gould, and had to give her the bad news that it looked like she was miscarrying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nv94ry"&gt;Though Gould’s moment on the stand was brief, her nurse practitioner, Audra Zachman, testified at more length. Zachman had received Theranos’ promotional materials at her practice, Southwest Contemporary Women’s Care. Theranos was “very exciting” when she first heard about it, especially since the company offered to install a lab below one of the practice’s offices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="SN1AQK"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Such a red flag.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="c7dxeL"&gt;Gould’s previous miscarriages meant her pregnancy was considered high-risk, so Zachman ordered tests for hCG, an important hormone in pregnancy. In a normal pregnancy, its value doubles every 48 to 72 hours, Zachman said. Gould first took a test from Quest on September 30th, 2014, with a value of 1,005. Then, on October 2nd, a Theranos test showed her levels had jumped to 12,558; on October 4th, another Theranos test showed those values had plummeted to 125.58.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ok80Zd"&gt;While Zachman told Gould the test values suggested a miscarriage, she also told Gould to keep taking her prenatal vitamins and to get another test. This test, from Quest, on October 6th, showed results consistent with a normal pregnancy. So did the next value from Quest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jPpovl"&gt;Those results “stood out as such a red flag” about Theranos, Zachman said. She’d never seen anything like the results Gould received.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jq3Pc9"&gt;Zachman complained to Theranos, and apparently corresponded with Holmes’ brother, Christian. He blamed the data entry process, not the test. But the corrected values were still concerning, since they were the same as the October 2nd results. Usually, when hGC doesn’t go up, that indicates an ectopic pregnancy, where the fetus has implanted outside the womb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PxT7W3"&gt;Because Zachman didn’t receive an explanation that satisfied her from Theranos, she stopped referring patients there. Still, she kept getting results from Theranos because her patients brought them in; they didn’t need a doctor’s order to get a blood draw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="xRTKAg"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“You can’t provide accurate patient care with inaccurate results.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zdJsxG"&gt;On cross-examination, Zachman testified to a number of corrective measures Theranos offered — which made the company sound like one of those Amazon sellers that begs you to remove your bad review. See, Zachman sat on the Southwest Contemporary Women’s Care board that evaluated new products. So Theranos offered to run, and did run, a study in 30 people comparing its results to those of Quest and a third party lab. Christian Holmes offered her his private email address and phone number. She was also offered a meeting with Elizabeth Holmes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8xQTM7"&gt;When the results came back from Theranos’ study, conducted with her employer, Zachman still didn’t refer patients to Theranos and says her colleagues largely didn’t either. The experience with Gould was so jarring to her — both as a healthcare provider and as a woman, she said — that the study couldn’t convince her to use the tests. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rFOsIq"&gt;Gould didn’t use Theranos again, either. “You can’t provide accurate patient care with inaccurate results,” she said on the stand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JyVCpQ"&gt;But between October 2015 and October 2016, Theranos did another 300 hCG tests for patients at Southwest Contemporary Women’s Care, according to evidence from the defense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dr1QBn"&gt;Obviously, the goal was to blunt the impact of Zachman’s testimony; the defense did not question Gould. The question the defense wanted the jurors to ask themselves, it seemed, was: “Would Theranos go above and beyond — with the study and so on — if it were really a fraud?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="dRruj4"&gt;&lt;q&gt;These documents were also used to point the finger at the lab directors &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IXb5Tm"&gt;The morning’s testimony was in a similar vein: Surekha Gangakhedkar, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22680372/elizabeth-holmes-wire-fraud-emails-gangakhedkar"&gt;who’d formerly developed tests at Theranos&lt;/a&gt; and quit over her concerns about bringing those tests to patients, was cross-examined. First, the defense tried to establish that she’d done real, good work with drug companies Centocor and Celgene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8nghfD"&gt;The defense also showed emails from Holmes congratulating Gangakhedkar on her work, one of which came at 12:20AM on a Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f5LE5B"&gt;Then, to show that Theranos had taken its tests seriously, a number of documents were introduced that Gangakhedkar had signed off on. These reports detailed how the tests had been developed, and were voluminous. But those documents aren’t the same thing as what’s required to get approval for testing in patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AoYb8W"&gt;These documents were also used to point the finger at the lab directors as being ultimately responsible for the tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="M2RVKy"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Holmes was presented as the “good boss”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="c2Pj71"&gt;With Gangakhedkar, as with Zachman, Holmes was presented as the “good boss” who just wanted to get things right. It wasn’t just the kudos emails. Holmes approved a month-long vacation so Gangakhedkar could take her family to meet extended family in India. And when Gangakhedkar quit, Holmes tried to talk her out of it. Holmes offered a leave of absence, and asked if there was anything else she could do to make Gangakhedkar stay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IRwzuh"&gt;Balwani, by contrast, was painted as the “bad boss,” who had repeatedly downplayed Gangakhedkar’s team’s work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eH7UwO"&gt;The testimony from Zachman and Gangakhedkar felt similar — when something went wrong, Theranos or Holmes tried to fix it. But one thing stood out: Gould didn’t have a similar story. &lt;em&gt;She&lt;/em&gt; was the one most affected by the bad test results, not Zachman. And Theranos knew the bad results belonged to her. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="uwSold"&gt;While Zachman was offered Christian Holmes’ phone number and a meeting with Elizabeth Holmes, Gould didn’t testify to anything similar. Maybe she just wasn’t important enough for Theranos to want to win over. After all, she was just a patient.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22687026/theranos-patient-bad-test-miscarriage-pregnancy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22687026/theranos-patient-bad-test-miscarriage-pregnancy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Elizabeth Lopatto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T20:17:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T20:17:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>The best deals on true wireless earbuds right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EMA4Er2sFrxHrUuDpHfpSH0b1VM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68898291/bfarsace_201130_4322_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="USGxSy"&gt;When it comes to true wireless earbuds, there are a ton of brands and products to choose from. Whether you enjoy the unconventional design of Samsung’s Galaxy Buds Live or prefer Jabra’s compact Elite 75t, there’s a pair of wireless earbuds for just about everyone. Fortunately, many of the best wireless earbuds go on sale on a regular occurrence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AsWVXq"&gt;Regardless of which brand you prefer, we have compiled some of the best deals on wireless earbuds available right now. Of course, if you want to do more research before making a buying decision, we also encourage you to read our guide to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds"&gt;best wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt;, which can help you determine which pair of earbuds are best for you. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Apple’s second-generation AirPods" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/H4c7403UDVQ2p-JvX1pB9iSnj8U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15993021/akrales_190327_3315_0012.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="c27rNd"&gt;Apple AirPods deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="2vr3VH"&gt;If you own an iPhone or multiple Apple products, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt; are likely the best true wireless earbuds on the market for you. Unlike the base AirPods, the Pro variant offer better sound quality and feature active noise cancellation, not to mention seamless integration with iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ftMREv"&gt;Apple’s flagship Pro wireless earbuds tend to go on sale frequently, and we often see them drop as low as $200. Right now, for instance, you can get a new pair for &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-Pro%2F520468661&amp;amp;subid1=VergeBestAirPodsDeals02262021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$197 at Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MWP22AM-A-AirPods-Pro/dp/B07ZPC9QD4?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://goto.target.com/QObva3"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kPY6Vk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="X9766m"&gt;Alternatively, you can buy a pair of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;second-generation AirPods&lt;/a&gt;, which include either a wired or wireless charging case. Although they normally retail for $160, you can get the version with the wired charging case for &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/994132/9383?subId1=VergeBestAirPods030121&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Charging-Case-Latest-Model%2F604342441%3F&amp;amp;veh=aff" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$119 at Walmart&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Charging-Latest-Model/dp/B07PXGQC1Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="DcXNMK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eJgls2"&gt;If you prefer a little more convenience, you can also get a new pair of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;AirPods with a wireless charging case&lt;/a&gt; for a few dollars more. At their regular price of $200, they aren’t as good of a value, but you’ll rarely find yourself paying the usual price. At the moment, you can get them for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Wireless-Charging-Latest/dp/B07PYLT6DN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$153 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iGBbls"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9507432"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GvE4V_5ezL8yYRQFDA0uPj1WyN8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21700189/IMG_0628_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung Galaxy Buds Live.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="HGCqrw"&gt;Samsung Galaxy Buds Deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="v5RLzc"&gt;Samsung has a few different wireless earbuds to choose from, including its latest flagship wireless earbuds, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22231848/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-review"&gt;Galaxy Buds Pro&lt;/a&gt;. These earbuds include active noise cancellation and some of the best sound quality of any Samsung earbuds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pyxi2K"&gt;Right now Amazon is offering the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Samsung-Wireless-Cancelling-Charging-Included/dp/B08MWZHHKP?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Galaxy Buds Pro for $49 off&lt;/a&gt;, bringing the price down to $151 in select colorways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WZ42v1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10401237"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="4pY4R1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best AirPods deals you can get right now ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals"},{"title":"The best deals on 4K TVs ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22371561/best-4k-tv-deals-sale-lg-samsung-sony-tcl"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="x23GrZ"&gt;Samsung only released the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22619305/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-review-specs-price-features"&gt;Galaxy Buds 2&lt;/a&gt; — a good-sounding pair of earbuds with active noise cancellation — in late August, but we’re already starting to see some discounts at retailers like Woot and Amazon. Right now, for example, you can get a free Galaxy SmartTag tracker with the purchase of the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Wireless-Cancelling-Bluetooth-Lightweight/dp/B09FHRN4NT?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Galaxy Buds 2 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. The bundle is typically worth $180, however, Amazon is currently selling all styles for $150 instead — the same price the Galaxy Buds 2 normally retail for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Eo52gY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10707231"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aZthMF"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/24/21147654/samsung-galaxy-buds-plus-review-wireless-earbuds-sound-quality-battery-life"&gt;Galaxy Buds Plus&lt;/a&gt; were our top pick last year for the best wireless earbuds overall. A successor to the original Galaxy Buds, the Plus model extends the battery life by up to 11 hours and, unlike AirPods, comes in an assortment of colors. Right now, you can buy the Galaxy Buds Plus for $100 at places such as &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B083KVM9VW?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1748159989908648779#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/3Pk6Pr" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, which is the lowest price we’ve seen in the last several months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="c8pRgb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10368022"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mPBmzD"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21356260/samsung-galaxy-buds-live-review-wireless-earbuds-beans-design-specs-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Galaxy Buds Live&lt;/a&gt; are some of the more unconventional wireless earbuds on the market right now, but don’t let their bean-shaped design fool you. The Buds Live are a good option if you want earbuds that produce powerful sound and showcase marathon battery life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="52C6bu"&gt;Right now, you can purchase a pair of the Galaxy Buds Live in a multitude of colors for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Samsung-Wireless-Cancelling-Charging-Included/dp/B089B7LX7N/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$100 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1577733-REG%2Fsamsung_sm_r180nznaxar_galaxy_buds_live_noise_canceling.html%3Fap%3Dy%26smp%3Dy&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22307388%2Fwireless-earbuds-deals-airpods-galaxy-buds-powerbeats" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;, a $60 discount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xJfsfQ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10685823"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a2Ol0J-O6sW1PwuvoXPBBDrB7Pc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/18279734/cwelch_190702_3528_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="i2Ah0B"&gt;Sony WF-1000XM3 deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="HggHzb"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22523584/sony-wf-1000xm4-wireless-earbuds-headphones-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sony’s WF-1000XM4&lt;/a&gt; are the true wireless headphones to beat, but they haven’t been discounted yet given how recently they launched. Their predecessor, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/5/20682334/sony-wf-1000xm3-wireless-earbuds-hands-on-preview-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;WF-1000XM3&lt;/a&gt;, however, remain an excellent pair of headphones that do routinely go on sale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="haWqZJ"&gt;Like the most recent model, the WF-1000XM3 feature phenomenal sound quality and considerable battery life, a small feat for a pair of true wireless earbuds. They also manage to deliver noise cancellation in a sleek, copper-adorned package, one that’s both attractive and professional. Typically $230, Sony’s last-gen WF-1000XM3 are on sale at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WF-1000XM3-Industry-Canceling-Wireless/dp/B07T81554H/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1747336499962657708#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; for around $168, one of the best prices we’ve seen on the earbuds outside of Prime Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8F3h1H"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9563643"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="9wJvFX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Verge Deals on Twitter","description":"Join our 39,000 followers, and keep up with our best daily tech deals with @vergedeals","label":"Follow us!","url":"http://bit.ly/2JzR5Ud"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="1TXXf4"&gt;Other true wireless earbuds deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="58GOfq"&gt;Compared to the competition, Jabra’s wireless earbuds have a rare feature that has yet to become standard in the true wireless earbud market: the ability to connect to two devices concurrently. Ideally, this is great for users who switch between two devices often (like, say, a phone and a laptop). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vJ5wIC"&gt;Last year, Jabra released the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549587/jabra-elite-85t-review-features-specs-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Elite 85t wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt;, which are the highest-tier model in Jabra’s lineup. They have more advanced noise cancellation than the 75t, however, they also feature less bass and an inferior fit. If you can live with those compromises, however, you can buy the Jabra Elite 85t for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Jabra-Wireless-Bluetooth-Earbuds-Titanium/dp/B08HR78C46?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$180 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfDfB2WVItB#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, their second-best price to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LacpUE"&gt;If the price on the Elite 85t is still intimidating but you want a pair of Jabra earbuds, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/15/21066947/jabra-elite-75t-review-wireless-earbuds-airpods-alternative" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Elite 75t&lt;/a&gt; are also a good option. We consider the Jabra 75t — which are currently selling for &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfDfEmv2ecW#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$130 at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Jabra-Elite-75t-Earbuds-Comfortable/dp/B07X9VG6ZJ/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://goto.target.com/WDNvBA" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt; — the best true wireless earbuds for multitaskers, and they remain a solid alternative if you don’t want to buy AirPods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="IE8ocy"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Jabra overhauls true wireless earbuds lineup with three new models","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22649800/jabra-elite-7-pro-active-3-features-price"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="OvElfP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10386608"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mqq7gj"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22532970/beats-studio-buds-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Beats Studio Buds&lt;/a&gt; may be the latest fitness earbuds from Apple, but if you’re currently in the market for a reliable pair of wireless earbuds for your workouts, you also can’t go wrong with their predecessor, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/10/18563329/apple-powerbeats-pro-review-wireless-fitness-headphones-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Beats Powerbeats Pro&lt;/a&gt;. These earbuds have an over-ear hook that keeps them in place while exercising; they’re also IPX4 sweat- and water-resistant, so you don’t have to worry about ruining them should your workout get intense. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aryAiB"&gt;Currently, there are a few different discounts available for the Powerbeats Pro. The lowest we see right now is at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Powerbeats-Pro-Totally-Wireless-Earphones/dp/B088KTR418/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, which is selling the earphones in three colorways (red, yellow, and green) for $175.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0RcdxX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10058925"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="11vDvx"&gt;Much like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/29/20937559/amazon-echo-buds-wireless-earbuds-review-features-bose-noise-reduction-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;first-gen predecessor&lt;/a&gt;, the 2021 edition of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22432633/amazon-echo-buds-2021-review-features-specs-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Echo Buds&lt;/a&gt; represent a tremendous value. Amazon’s latest true wireless earbuds offer improved comfort and better noise cancellation, along with a terrific passthrough mode that ensures you can always hear what’s going on around you. The $120 earbuds also feature hands-free Alexa support and sound that’s remarkably satisfying, with more bass than the AirPods Pro and an appropriate amount of restraint when it comes to the high end. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cb3iGA"&gt;Although the second-gen Amazon Echo Buds were on sale for $90 during Amazon’s Labor Day sale, they’re currently not discounted anywhere. That said, we expect to see similar discounts later in the fall as we approach Black Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PgPi8b"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10600144"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="de2M6w"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22307388/wireless-earbuds-deals-airpods-galaxy-buds-powerbeats"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22307388/wireless-earbuds-deals-airpods-galaxy-buds-powerbeats</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
      <name>Brandon Widder</name>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T18:35:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T18:35:29-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to fix Deathloop ‘stuttering’ issues on PC </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZSKgq9V7V_faIif-gORFVpgmnAE=/429x0:2589x1440/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69885518/deathloop.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EojSD0"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671207/deathloop-review-ps5-pc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deathloop&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;is the big triple-A game of the moment, and it’s an amazing experience — assuming you’re not fighting your gaming PC to get it to run smoothly. Bethesda is aware, and a patch seems to be on the way. But as &lt;em&gt;Digital Foundry&lt;/em&gt;’s Alex Battaglia explains in &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lu_XHyO-6zY"&gt;this in-depth video&lt;/a&gt;, there may be a few things you can try right now to fix it, including one weird, counterintuitive trick that instantly made my seemingly stuttery performance smooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wfDENn"&gt;Also, there’s a new patch as of September 21st &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1252330/view/5568127835954403760?linkId=132678876"&gt;that Bethesda says&lt;/a&gt; might &lt;em&gt;partially&lt;/em&gt; fix the issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="flFyMD"&gt;Here’s the TL;DR. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="9x4UgO"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Obvious:&lt;/strong&gt; Reduce your quality settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Lk2mRz"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Also obvious: &lt;/strong&gt;Try the initial hotfix, &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1252330/view/5568127835954403760?linkId=132678876"&gt;now available in Steam&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="aCrtfP"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Counterintuitive: &lt;/strong&gt;Lock your framerate at 60 or 120fps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="ydt9Pq"&gt;Let’s start with that last one, because it’s what worked for me — and it may be the only thing that works if you’ve got a fancy G-Sync / FreeSync monitor with variable refresh rate. Simply go to the game’s &lt;strong&gt;Video Settings &lt;/strong&gt;page, turn off &lt;strong&gt;V-Sync&lt;/strong&gt; entirely, and set your &lt;strong&gt;FPS Limiter&lt;/strong&gt; to 60 or — if your performance is high enough — 120 fps.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0TTplP6vb5HA_GerONCujKTZhSk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22865395/deathloop_fps_limiter.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scroll down the video settings menu and you’ll find V-Sync and FPS Limiter. You’ll have to turn off V-Sync first.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MJjnuC"&gt;You might be asking: “Isn’t the whole point of V-Sync and my fancy VRR monitor to keep this sort of stutter from happening?” Yes, but as &lt;em&gt;Digital Foundry &lt;/em&gt;explains, what you’re seeing has more to do with mouse movement than syncing your GPU’s frames to your monitor’s refresh rate. This isn’t the tearing you see when frames hit in the middle of a refresh, or the microstutter you might have experienced when frames are delayed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tm0oL8"&gt;In fact, Battaglia shows that &lt;em&gt;Deathloop&lt;/em&gt; can deliver excellent frame times — there’s just a mismatch when you’re turning your digital character’s head at non-standard refresh rates, like the ones your variable refresh monitor is &lt;em&gt;designed &lt;/em&gt;to provide. With an RTX 3080, my GPU could easily send 80 fps to my G-Sync monitor in many scenes at near-4K resolution, but locking it to 60 counterintuitively made everything feel far smoother. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GTiD7I"&gt;Another thing you might want to do (though you may also want to &lt;em&gt;undo&lt;/em&gt; it&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;after the next public patch: try the hotfix &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/deathloop/status/1438540739856715788"&gt;that Bethesda’s currently asking users to help test&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pu8YA3"&gt;&lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1252330/view/5568127835954403760?linkId=132678876"&gt;As of September 21st&lt;/a&gt;, this may now be as easy as updating your game. Originally, you had to right click on &lt;em&gt;Deathloop&lt;/em&gt; in your Steam library, select &lt;strong&gt;Properties &lt;/strong&gt;and then &lt;strong&gt;Beta&lt;/strong&gt;, type &lt;strong&gt;juliannashotme&lt;/strong&gt; into the access code field, hit &lt;strong&gt;Check Code&lt;/strong&gt;, then and &lt;strong&gt;Opt into&lt;/strong&gt; the public_beta branch that appears. Let us know if you see a difference between the beta and new patch?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zOoYdaCHIyqHA1h6wwX-flwdCvY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22865439/Vqbx0fxvgO.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You’ll have to hit Check Code and also Opt into before the beta hotfix will work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="gYDNFo"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Digital Foundry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;reports the hotfix seems to smooth over one of the mouse issues, though Battaglia still points out other problems in his full video, including one where you may need to quit out of a mission or start the next level before it resolves itself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bvb9Y2"&gt;Lastly, it’s possible you’re just picking graphical settings that are unnecessarily high for what’s quite a demanding game. &lt;em&gt;Deathloop&lt;/em&gt; looks great at High levels of detail, often with little noticeable difference compared to Very High or Ultra, as you can see in the video atop this post. Don’t knock it until you’ve tried it? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Vh3sSu"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;DEATHLOOP PC players, we have released an update that addresses Steam achievements and adds descriptive error reporting for crashes on launch. We are also investigating reports of "stuttering" on PC, and are exploring fixes. More info:&lt;a href="https://t.co/uO6qu7Vrzb"&gt;https://t.co/uO6qu7Vrzb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— DEATHLOOP (@deathloop) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/deathloop/status/1438540739856715788?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NzfNrq"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 21st, 6:35PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added that a hotfix is live, and may no longer require the beta.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2dao4H"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XReVzr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22684588/deathloop-stutter-pc-game-nvidia-amd-rtx-vrr-gsync-vsync-fps-framerate"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22684588/deathloop-stutter-pc-game-nvidia-amd-rtx-vrr-gsync-vsync-fps-framerate</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-21T17:50:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T17:50:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Oversight Board wants answers about Facebook’s celebrity moderation program</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pbXdYtwFK0OkrXAH8FMn2A4hAhU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69890688/acastro_180720_1777_facebook_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bTUrov"&gt;The Oversight Board, a semi-independent body that reviews Facebook’s moderation policies, &lt;a href="https://oversightboard.com/news/3056753157930994-to-treat-users-fairly-facebook-must-commit-to-transparency/"&gt;announced on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt; that it wants more information about the “cross-check” system Facebook uses to “review content decisions relating to some high-profile users.” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671565/facebook-xcheck-moderation-system-high-profile-exemptions"&gt;Cross-check is getting called into question&lt;/a&gt; because of &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-files-xcheck-zuckerberg-elite-rules-11631541353?mod=hp_lead_pos7"&gt;a report from &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that claimed the system lets high-profile users break the rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WI9XTK"&gt;“In light of recent developments, we are looking into the degree to which Facebook has been fully forthcoming in its responses in relation to cross-check, including the practice of whitelisting,” the board writes. “We expect to receive a briefing from Facebook in the coming days and will be reporting what we hear from this as part of our first release of quarterly transparency reports, which we will publish in October.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="p2ChUI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Cross-check has the Oversight Board’s attention&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="i1v4RH"&gt;Cross-check (sometimes referred to as XCheck) is supposed to add an extra level of scrutiny to high-profile moderation calls that could cause controversy for Facebook. But the &lt;em&gt;Journal &lt;/em&gt;claims it covered a huge swathe of 5.8 million people in 2020, and only 10 percent of the posts sent to the program got reviewed by Facebook’s second layer of specialized moderators. According to the report, users included in the program include Senator Elizabeth Warren, conservative commentator Candace Owens, and former President Donald Trump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nwU8aC"&gt;Trump’s relative protection via cross-check came up &lt;a href="https://www.oversightboard.com/decision/FB-691QAMHJ"&gt;in the board’s decision&lt;/a&gt; to uphold&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22320329/facebook-oversight-board-trump-ban-decision"&gt; the former President’s Facebook ban&lt;/a&gt;. At the time, the board noted that there’s limited public information about cross-check reviews — &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2018/07/working-to-keep-facebook-safe/"&gt;a 2018 blog post&lt;/a&gt; is one of the most recent. It advised the company to “clearly explain the rationale, standards, and processes of review, including the criteria to determine which pages and accounts are selected for inclusion.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NVUxAY"&gt;As with all Oversight Board actions, Facebook allows itself some flexibility in how to respond. The company has publicly committed to following the organization’s calls on individual moderation decisions but reserves the right to not follow broader recommendations. It’s also not legally bound to follow the board’s rules. With today’s announcement and renewed pressure to clarify a program with issues Facebook’s already working to address, maybe we’ll finally learn more about the controversial program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="WE1kei"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Facebook’s Oversight Board has upheld Trump’s ban — what’s next?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22428768/facebook-oversight-board-trump-ban-kate-klonick-interview"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686364/facebook-oversight-board-xcheck-moderation-exemption"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686364/facebook-oversight-board-xcheck-moderation-exemption</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
