<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-25T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-25T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-25T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to watch Netflix’s major Tudum event today</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yRXM4NJgFQbiY85XuKdTx27ngeI=/285x0:2592x1538/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69907134/Screen_Shot_2021_09_23_at_1.40.26_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fT7BsD"&gt;Netflix is kicking off a massive fan event today. Tudum — named for the ubiquitous chime that plays before Netflix titles — is a global event that will feature a huge slate of news, trailers, celebrity appearances, and more. It’s essentially the Lollapalooza of Netflix news, and anyone hoping to stay ahead of the streamer’s biggest upcoming announcements will definitely want to tune in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="DtHsL3"&gt;What is Tudum?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="eQgFEa"&gt;Tudum is a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641142/netflix-tudum-fan-trailers-interviews-announcements-date-movies-shows"&gt;global mega-event&lt;/a&gt; — the first of its kind for Netflix. It kicks off Saturday and will feature more than 145 celebrities, 70-plus series, and 28 films over the course of several hours. Expect exclusive clips and news for forthcoming titles like &lt;em&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; The Sandman&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Tiger King&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Cobra Kai&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Witcher&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Red Notice&lt;/em&gt; starring Dwayne Johnson and Ryan Reynolds, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uCdyJF"&gt;Tudum will be available in 29 languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="UfR2kQ"&gt;What time is Tudum?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ybMpj7"&gt;The event will kick off at 9AM PT (or 12PM ET for our East Coast readers). The main event will last three hours, but Netflix will also host pre-shows for Korean and Indian films and series, as well as anime programming that will begin at 5AM PT (or 8AM ET). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="rMnFCA"&gt;Where can I watch Tudum?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="LDEK9d"&gt;Great question! Netflix will stream &lt;a href="https://www.tudum.com/?lang=en"&gt;Tudum&lt;/a&gt; on its &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lKgMA0MoY2Y"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; channels worldwide, as well as on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/netflixus/videos/899218064345155"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/netflix"&gt;Twitch&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/netflix"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Hb5vUc"&gt;Is there a Tudum schedule?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="CZ6IIs"&gt;There is! For an hour-by-hour breakdown of what shows will be included in which time slots, please see Netflix’s handy fan guide below.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BTFxcGtwY3oY4eGv-XWXV8RL4xc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22873357/EN_US_Tudum_Static_FullscheduleGraphics_FullPageFlyer20210920_4522_26pehp__1_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/25/22690499/netflix-tudum-how-to-watch-witcher-cowboy-bebop-stranger-things"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/25/22690499/netflix-tudum-how-to-watch-witcher-cowboy-bebop-stranger-things</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-25T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-25T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Save $50 on the Nanoleaf Elements wood-styled LED panels</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/77Ii9fSdM-oaV1YgwzupIyidAeM=/313x0:3688x2250/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69907183/Elements_7x_Dining_Winter_4000x2250px.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nanoleaf Elements are a unique decor whether they’re illuminated or not.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Nanoleaf&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gr4MSu"&gt;Kicking off these deals on the smart home lighting front, the Nanoleaf Elements light-up wall panels — just released in the summer — have a nice discount at Best Buy. The wood accent hexagon-shaped panels are &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1752882625164258609#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$50 off for a seven panel kit, bringing them down to $250&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to go beyond seven you can opt for a &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1752882728847809246#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;three panel expansion kit for $80&lt;/a&gt; (saving you $20). These panels are customizable and you can connect up to 22 of them in one contiguous pattern. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gX2bHn"&gt;You may be familiar with the colorful Nanoleaf panels that are popular with Twitch streamers and YouTubers, but the Elements promise a more refined look with their wood grain and white illumination that ranges from cool to warm tones. When turned off their subtle wood aesthetic still complements a room without looking like light panels that have gone out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="NwkUpd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Nanoleaf’s light-up wall panels now look like wood accent pieces","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/3/22466594/nanoleaf-elements-light-panel-smart-home-price-release"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="b9TMTQ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10771267"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IqHwmg"&gt;Also on the smart home front, Best Buy is offering several great deals on Philips Hue lighting through their Geek Squad-certified refurbished offers. Our top pick is the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1752885816627976467#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;multicolor LED Starter Kit with three bulbs, Bridge, and dimmer switch, all for $135&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to that, there are some nice options for accent lighting with the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1752888958340730338#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Hue Play Gradient Lightstrip 65” for $225&lt;/a&gt; (a savings of $25) and a &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1752888988022964482#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;two pack of Hue Play Smart LED light bars for $100&lt;/a&gt; (saving you $50). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nimiqt"&gt;Either of those can do wonders to a room or entertainment center setup for some added drama, while the starter kit can outfit an entire bedroom and give you easy control with the dimmer. If you’re in need of a Hue Bridge for some bulbs you have already invested in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/8/31/22648480/philips-hue-bulbs-labor-day-beats-studio-buds-jabra-elite-75t-apple-pencil-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;from a prior deal&lt;/a&gt;, Best Buy also has the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1752889079688132692#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2nd-generation Bridge for $40&lt;/a&gt; (saving you $20).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="sgZfO9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10771290"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="39zg2l"&gt;Bose’s line of Bluetooth-enabled audio sunglasses are pretty unique. They come in a few different styles, with some models looking more casual and sleek while others more fitting for action. Right now there are some noteworthy deals on both the Bose Frames Tempo and Bose Frames Tenor at multiple retailers. Both offer wireless audio that does not block your ears or prevent you from hearing things in your vicinity, which can be very helpful when riding a bike, commuting, or just roaming some city streets. Best Buy has both the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1752877755605596210#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Tempo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1752878896488204939#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Tenor&lt;/a&gt; for a discounted price of $224, knocking $25 off the price of each. Additionally, you can get the same pricing from &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bose-Frames-Tempo-Sunglasses-Connectivity/dp/B08CZL53F3/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon for the Tempo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1591431-REG%2Fbose_851338_0110_frames_tenor_audio_sunglasses.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F9%2F25%2F22691304%2Fnanoleaf-elements-philips-hue-refurbished-bose-frames-tempo-tenor-nintendo-switch-games-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H has the Tenor&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22351451/bose-frames-tempo-audio-sunglasses-review-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our Bose Frames Tempo review here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nyXc9l"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10771102"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="s6bWHK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10771150"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8eHwJI"&gt;The Nintendo eShop is offering some of its best deals on a whole slew of excellent titles during its &lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/sales-and-deals/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Blockbuster Sale&lt;/a&gt; running through October 3rd. There are amazing indie games to choose from at some of their best-yet prices, like &lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/overcooked-2-switch/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Overcooked! 2&lt;/em&gt; for $8.49&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/ori-and-the-will-of-the-wisps-switch/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ori and the Will of the Wisps&lt;/em&gt; for $19.49&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/the-messenger-switch/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Messenger&lt;/em&gt; for $8&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/dicey-dungeons-switch/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dicey Dungeons &lt;/em&gt;for $5.09&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/axiom-verge-switch/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Axiom Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (no relation) &lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/axiom-verge-switch/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;for $8&lt;/a&gt;, and many more. Though our top choice might have to go to &lt;em&gt;Hades&lt;/em&gt;, which has matched its &lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/hades-switch/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;historical low on the eShop at $17.49&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s truly priceless. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/1/21496904/hades-supergiant-games-review-nintendo-switch" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="pKXVwP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10267751"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="xdB5YE"&gt;A PAIR OF INEXPENSIVE DEALS FOR YOUR SMARTPHONE BATTERY&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="AQiPo2"&gt;Anker’s Powerbank Slim 10,000mAh power bank is just &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07QXV6N1B?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$15 on Amazon&lt;/a&gt; when you use promo code &lt;strong&gt;ANKRSD1229&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s not the fastest outputting charger out there, but that’s a more than modest amount of on-the-go juice for just 15 bucks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xWJUfj"&gt;Aukey’s Minima 20W PD USB-C charger is incredibly compact, and when you use promo code &lt;strong&gt;MINIMA &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Faukeyplus.com%2Fproducts%2Faukey-minima-20w-charger-black&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F9%2F25%2F22691304%2Fnanoleaf-elements-philips-hue-refurbished-bose-frames-tempo-tenor-nintendo-switch-games-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;it’s just&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;$5&lt;/a&gt;. This is one of the smallest chargers on the market that can deliver 20W to an iPhone or other quick-charging phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="vM7ACk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/9/25/22691304/nanoleaf-elements-philips-hue-refurbished-bose-frames-tempo-tenor-nintendo-switch-games-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/9/25/22691304/nanoleaf-elements-philips-hue-refurbished-bose-frames-tempo-tenor-nintendo-switch-games-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-24T21:49:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-24T21:49:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>How Elizabeth Holmes sidelined the real scientists at Theranos</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Theranos Trial" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-Zj-xw6GfDSKBGFowX-wWZnezgo=/0x0:4781x3187/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69906352/1341968229.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Jane Tyska/Digital First Media/The Mercury News via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;By leaving them off email threads&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="FiQ3pL"&gt;Former Theranos lab director Adam Rosendorff was the second employee who testified in Elizabeth Holmes’ trial who kept his work emails. Forwarding work emails to a personal account can violate a non-disclosure agreement, which Rosendorff signed when he joined the company. But, like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22680372/elizabeth-holmes-wire-fraud-emails-gangakhedkar"&gt;Surekha Gangakhedkar&lt;/a&gt; before him, he was worried he’d be blamed for the company’s problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iVZJF4"&gt;He was right to worry: he’s one of the people Elizabeth Holmes’ defense is trying to blame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="ElyIGK"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The company was more about PR and fundraising than patient care.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="erCXly"&gt;In opening arguments of US v Elizabeth Holmes, the defense agreed there were problems in Theranos’ lab. But Lance Wade, Homes’ attorney, said that problems in the clinical lab were ultimately the responsibility of the lab director. And besides, that lab director reported to Holmes’ co-defendant, Sunny Balwani, who is being tried separately. They face 10 counts of wire fraud and two counts of conspiracy to commit wire fraud. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mluaic"&gt;Today’s testimony was about bad Theranos tests. A lot of new emails were introduced, showing Holmes was aware of the company’s problems, and was even actively trying to manage the situation. Several times in those emails, Rosendorff tried to get Theranos labs to run FDA-approved tests instead of the ones Theranos developed. But maybe even more telling were the emails that Rosendorff was excluded from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V3ZPHj"&gt;Rosendorff didn’t mince words when he took the witness stand. He quit because of many things, he said. “One was the unwillingness of management to perform proficiency testing as required by law, I felt pressured to vouch for tests I did not have confidence in.” That wasn’t all. He came to believe “the company was more about PR and fundraising than patient care,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DpnXpy"&gt;When he first joined Theranos in April 2013, Rosendorff thought Theranos might be the next Apple. But the sheen wore off the company quickly — and he began looking for other jobs by that summer. In August, before Theranos’ launch in patients, the clinical lab was “anxious” about testing real people, he said; the pace around the launch “extremely rushed and hurried.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="VM23Yt"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Raising alarm bells”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="35adBP"&gt;On August 31, 2013, Elizabeth Holmes sent a 1AM email asking for an update on how many tests had completed validation. An employee wrote back that none of them had. The launch was scheduled for September 9th, 2013, and the schedule came from Holmes and Balwani, Rosendorff said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gjsvt4"&gt;Increasingly worried, he tried to stall it. He was “raising alarm bells.” In an email a little more than a week before the scheduled launch, Rosendorff wrote to Holmes and Balwani raising concerns about some of the tests. He also thought the lab needed more staff with better training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bqdzoX"&gt;He needed “a few more weeks to sort through these medical and logistical issues,” he wrote in the email. That would mean delaying bringing Theranos’ tests to patients. He even met with Holmes about his concerns, because he felt Balwani wasn’t taking him seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iWvsXR"&gt;During that meeting Rosendorff described Holmes as “very nervous.” “She was not her usual composed self. She was trembling a little bit,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8XuTTm"&gt;Despite Rosendorff’s concerns, the launch went ahead as planned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="oaKHg0"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Theranos devices “failed so frequently it raised doubts in my mind regarding the accuracy of the tests themselves.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xUWsGJ"&gt;Some of his testimony corroborated what previous Theranos employees had said. He echoed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22674657/elizabeth-holmes-theranos-trial-wire-fraud-financial-witness"&gt;Erika Cheung’s concerns about removing outliers&lt;/a&gt; from Theranos data. As both Cheung and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22680372/elizabeth-holmes-wire-fraud-emails-gangakhedkar"&gt;Gangakhedkar&lt;/a&gt; testified, the Edison machines frequently failed quality control. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gb0nJ5"&gt;While a quarter of Theranos’ devices routinely failed quality control, failures of commercially-available tech was far less frequent. Theranos devices “failed so frequently it raised doubts in my mind regarding the accuracy of the tests themselves,” Rosendorff said. He emailed Balwani about the failure rates, who wrote back, “Adam. This is not the case.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v5eN5H"&gt;Normally lab directors deal with doctors who have concerns about lab results — this was part of Rosendorff’s job at his previous employer, the University of Pittsburgh. But Theranos installed Holmes’ brother, Christian, as a liaison for complaints. Rosendorff said he was pressured to come up with explanations about bad results that didn’t call into question the tests themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r5TDRB"&gt;But the tests were bad. In the case of a key pregnancy hormone — one that we heard testimony about from&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22687026/theranos-patient-bad-test-miscarriage-pregnancy"&gt; a patient who was wrongly told she was miscarrying&lt;/a&gt; — Rosendorff sent an all-caps email to his staff in May 2014 telling them that all future tests were to be run on an FDA-approved device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="cxboS6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“A complete mess”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nQqoGc"&gt;This didn’t happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oaSCAX"&gt;In fact, there was a June 2014 email chain where Christian Holmes wrote his sister, CCing Balwani, that the test was “causing serious complaints and patient issues.” Additionally, the lab was “a complete mess.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="70Qz2H"&gt;Holmes wrote back that she’d connect with her brother, then added, “Sunny / this is already handled.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0uSxFV"&gt;There are a few notable things about the exchange. First, it demolishes the idea that Holmes could have been misled about the state of the clinical lab and its tests. Second, it shows her clearly taking charge of the situation, even telling Balwani to stand down. But third, it’s remarkable for who’s missing from the chain: Rosendorff, who may not have even been aware that his instruction to use FDA-cleared devices &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; was ignored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3kybhb"&gt;The first time he saw those emails was in court, he said. It was not the only set of emails about patient complaints we saw where Rosendorff wasn’t included, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="P3xRFA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The test has lost any diagnostic value.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FcQlOd"&gt;In February of 2014, Rosendorff also tried to convince the company to stop running its HDL  (“good”) cholesterol test on Theranos devices. He sent an email to Balwani and added Holmes, because he thought Balwani wasn’t listening to him. “I got a lot of pushback” for suggesting the lab use approved devices, Rosendorff said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fmQnzB"&gt;That pushback came from Holmes, Balwani, and VP Daniel Young, he testified. And though Young didn’t have a medical degree, he often offered suggestions about what was “really” wrong with tests, Rosendorff said. Through his testimony, Rosendorff generally talked about Young in a tone that suggested he loathed the VP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fpHtLH"&gt;The problems in the lab were widespread, Rosendorff testified, pointing to tests of bicarbonate, and an email where he pointed out that two-thirds of patients were reading below the normal range. “The test has lost any diagnostic value,” he emailed in September 2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="4Zkoq8"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I am not sure what to do with these lab results????”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dbQhUV"&gt;But Theranos wasn’t honest with physicians or providers about this. Instead, customer service representatives were instructed to say that the results “were not reported due to temporary unavailability.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vtIOHL"&gt;Another email from a healthcare provider said it didn’t realize Theranos’ methods weren’t FDA-approved, and complained about testosterone and blood sugar tests. “I am not sure what to do with these lab results????” the email read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BvlHx7"&gt;Part of the problem was that all the validation studies had been done on venous blood, Rosendorff testified. See, to get enough fingerprick blood to run all the studies, you’d need to prick every finger on the patient — so as a matter of convenience, venous blood was drawn. But if you draw blood from fingerpricks, you’re far more likely to destroy red blood cells in the process, leading to faulty readings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4InyxK"&gt;Among the bad tests was one for sodium, potassium, and chloride, called ISE. Young, who was a statistician, not a doctor, suggested the faulty results for this test was because of the red blood cells breaking apart, and urged a visual examination of the blood to confirm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="wrstfW"&gt;&lt;q&gt;This bad assay had been used on patients since September 2013. In June 2014, there were still problems with the tests.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zC31Kc"&gt;This was bad for several reasons. First of all, the FDA-approved machines detected this immediately, not after a weird reading. Second, evidence of broken red blood cells wasn’t always obvious to the eye, Rosendorff testified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EYGbQv"&gt;This bad assay had been used on patients since September 2013. In June 2014, there were still problems with the tests, and Young’s suggested fixes, including a “bias-correction” method, still weren’t working. So Theranos voided tests that fell above and below accepted values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p5dd39"&gt;That was a problem, too. We saw an email from a doctor dated October 27th, 2014, addressed to a customer service rep. The patient had low sodium levels — which was why the test had been ordered. A customer service rep emailed Rosendorff saying, “Is it possible that that was the value? If she comes in again, and the value is still critical low, will it be voided again?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jYz8re"&gt;Rosendorff forwarded this email to Balwani and Holmes, writing, “I’m not sure of a clinical value of a sodium assay in which the only time we can report it is when it is not critical and the very situations that require accurate measurement and reporting of abnormal sodium results are voided.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="FCwAg6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s pretty obvious we have issues with calcium, potassium, and sodium.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="N3NMGN"&gt;Calcium testing, too, was bad. “Are there any findings we can relay about high trends in calcium reporting?” Christian Holmes wrote to Young and Balwani. “Seems to be by far the majority of questions we get about accuracy now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AkjEFW"&gt;He then forwarded this to his sister. “It’s pretty obvious we have issues with calcium, potassium, and sodium, specifically,” he wrote. “Obviously I can’t tell them we are wrong, but they continue to send patients to Quest [another blood-testing company] after we report high, and the results continue to come back normal.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9b9zRE"&gt;Rosendorff wasn’t included on this chain, and took issue with “specifically.” There were lots of problems with other tests, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C42Wab"&gt;“I didn’t believe at this point that Theranos could solve these problems,” Rosendorff testified. He began avoiding speaking to doctors, and told one or two physicians that he didn’t trust the results. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9xrZpu"&gt;All of this is bad for Holmes  — not only is she aware of the problems, she’s calling the shots. But her defense hinted at what the cross-examination of Rosendorff may bring. One of his subsequent employers was also investigated by the federal authorities, as well as another company that was subject to a justice department probe. (We found this out before the jury was allowed in the courtroom.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="cds0js"&gt;It’s not clear that Rosendorff’s post-Theranos employment will be deemed relevant to the current case — the jury may hear nothing about this. But the defense will certainly have some work to do. Though Rosendorff’s testimony was much more technical than that of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22689083/elizabeth-holmes-trial-james-mattis-testimony-theranos-fraud"&gt;board member James Mattis yesterday,&lt;/a&gt; it was possibly even worse for Holmes. If she’s trying to convince the jury that any fraud was mostly Balwani’s fault, she’s going to have to explain the ample evidence she was giving marching orders.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22692600/elizabeth-holmes-theranos-bad-tests-complaints"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22692600/elizabeth-holmes-theranos-bad-tests-complaints</id>
    <author>
      <name>Elizabeth Lopatto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-24T21:06:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-24T21:06:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple says an issue is preventing some animations from using high refresh rates on the iPhone 13 Pros</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The iPhone 13 Pro and Pro Max keep the major redesigns introduced last year — they still feel fresh and modern." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qE7KKhm4BbsB-hqoA8GkQQwKWzo=/0x0:1995x1330/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69906241/vpavic_210916_untitled_0031.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aSCxYB"&gt;Apple’s iPhone 13 lineup launched Friday, and one of the key features of the 13 Pro and 13 Pro Max are their ProMotion displays with variable refresh rates that can top out at 120Hz. But &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/09/24/iphone-13-promotion-third-party-apps/"&gt;as spotted by &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, some app animations in third-party apps are currently only running at 60Hz. That might be frustrating if you were expecting to see buttery-smooth animations across all of your apps with the new phones, but when we asked Apple what was going on, the company shared two reasons why this might be happening. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="McbI7i"&gt;One reason is that developers will need to update their apps to declare that they use the higher refresh rate. This can be done by adding an entry to the app’s plist, Apple tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, and the company says it plans to share documentation about the entry you need to add soon. But in some cases, animations built with the company’s Core Animation technology are also affected by an issue that will be fixed in an upcoming software update, Apple says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c3q9Uz"&gt;Variable refresh rate screens offer a lot of benefits, including smoother animations and scrolling when you’re using the device and battery savings the screen runs at lower refresh rates. We were impressed with the screens on the 13 Pro and 13 Pro Max &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22684033/apple-iphone-13-pro-max-review"&gt;in our review&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s good to hear that third party apps will be able to take full advantage of what they have to offer — though some may have to wait until after that software update.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22692557/apple-iphone-13-pro-max-high-refresh-rate-screen-promotion-animations-issue"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22692557/apple-iphone-13-pro-max-high-refresh-rate-screen-promotion-animations-issue</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-24T18:19:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-24T18:19:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix queues up a roguelike PC game to go with its action movie Kate</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Kate: Collateral Damage" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vYqNg8SfnbM5EaMSdMOJa4jhzwg=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69905778/FAESDXVVEAgLmmT.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Kate: Collateral Damage | Image: Ludic Studios&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Uz6WjG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kate: Collateral Damage&lt;/em&gt; isn’t the first gaming tie-in we’ve seen for a Netflix original, but now that it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585802/netflix-gaming-mobile-subscription-earnings"&gt;seriously entering the space&lt;/a&gt;, each title feels a little different. Developed by Ludic Studios, the new game is a “time-attack action roguelike” that relates to the movie &lt;em&gt;Kate&lt;/em&gt;, a Netflix movie starring Mary Elizabeth Winstead about an assassin who has 24 hours to find the antidote to a poison that is killing her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n1jvIN"&gt;The plot of the movie makes the game’s time attack approach easy to understand as players take over the central character on her quest. As its &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1623000/Kate_Collateral_Damage/"&gt;Steam description&lt;/a&gt; reveals, players extend the length of each run by killing enemies to slow down the constantly depleting timer, and earning stimulant syringes that reset it entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PP6DJN"&gt;The movie’s plot also comes into play through your hostage-turned-companion Ani and its grimy neon-lit atmosphere. Unlike an earlier Ludic Studios game, &lt;em&gt;Akane&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Kate: Collateral Damage&lt;/em&gt; leans into a &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;⁄&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; view, but comparing their trailers shows why the Brazilian developer was a good match for the content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZsD8xB"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5a_AvatAd7s?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oxZClF"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kate: Collateral Damage&lt;/em&gt; is scheduled for release via Steam on October 22nd. There’s no pricing listed, but it doesn’t look like this game is tied to your subscription &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585802/netflix-gaming-mobile-subscription-earnings"&gt;like the ones Netflix is testing on Android&lt;/a&gt;. Instead, like the Eden Unearthed App Lab that &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=43993&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oculus.com%2Fexperiences%2Fquest%2F3632378823549307%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;recently popped up on Oculus VR&lt;/a&gt;, this has the feel of a marketing tie-in that could help &lt;em&gt;Kate &lt;/em&gt;stand out among a slew of &lt;em&gt;John Wick&lt;/em&gt;-like action movies with female leads that have popped up lately. Maybe we’ll find out more during the streamer’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641142/netflix-tudum-fan-trailers-interviews-announcements-date-movies-shows"&gt;Tudum fan event this weekend&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22692313/kate-collateral-damage-steam-netflix-roguelike-action"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22692313/kate-collateral-damage-steam-netflix-roguelike-action</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-24T18:14:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-24T18:14:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter says new videos will be less pixelated</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Twitter’s blue bird silhouette logo on a black background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/33wiyGe-HoR2R0mu_kerGv5-pi0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69905758/acastro_180827_1777_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4R41TM"&gt;Twitter’s poor video quality has been a long-running frustration for users on the platform, but on Friday, the company shared some potentially promising news: videos uploaded to the service will now “appear less pixelated for a better watching experience,” Twitter said &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1441475693863391232"&gt;in a tweet&lt;/a&gt; from its support account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gs4VkS"&gt;Twitter removed a pre-processing step in its video pipeline when you upload, the company tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge.&lt;/em&gt; After we published this article, the company clarified that this removed step split videos into smaller chunks for ingestion, which could reduce quality because of the additional processing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U1JW3I"&gt;App researcher Jane Manchun Wong &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/wongmjane/status/1441488893778415616"&gt;uploaded a video&lt;/a&gt; intended to put the supposed improvements to the test. (The sound on this video is a little loud, so you might want to turn down your volume before you watch it.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ddrzRL"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;less pixelated videos huh. let’s see...&lt;a href="https://t.co/b6SBDnLnsc"&gt;https://t.co/b6SBDnLnsc&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/TrlZQJHSH0"&gt;pic.twitter.com/TrlZQJHSH0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Jane Manchun Wong (@wongmjane) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/wongmjane/status/1441488893778415616?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 24, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iwZrAA"&gt;While it might appear better — and it did, in my eyes — Twitter told us after we first published this that the changes announced Friday aren’t yet supported in Twitter Media Studio, which is what Wong used to upload the video. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Nr16Y"&gt;If you want to see a video that Twitter says &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; use the improved video quality, check out the video &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/erinbeess/status/1441489334901878787"&gt;in this reply to Wong&lt;/a&gt; (which, I should warn you, is also loud).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="V2NgY8"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;u wanna go &lt;a href="https://t.co/UVuZJZkHvX"&gt;pic.twitter.com/UVuZJZkHvX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— erin | sigh.eth (@erinbeess) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/erinbeess/status/1441489334901878787?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 24, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jeyxb2"&gt;This second video does seem somewhat improved, but it’s hard to tell exactly by how much with the mostly-black background. Both videos are clearly not as crisp as a high-quality video that you might watch on YouTube or Twitch, though. And this upgrade only applies to newly-uploaded videos, so older videos won’t see the improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TFw6Oy"&gt;That said, it’s promising to see that Twitter is putting some effort into improving its video experience. And the upgrades may extend past video quality, as earlier this week, Wong’s research suggested that Twitter is also working on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/wongmjane/status/1440094616980578306"&gt;video playback speed options&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XRLFEG"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Twitter is working on video playback speed options &lt;a href="https://t.co/5PH9lQPSfj"&gt;pic.twitter.com/5PH9lQPSfj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Jane Manchun Wong (@wongmjane) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/wongmjane/status/1440094616980578306?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 20, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GpAYcF"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 24th, 8:33PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Added additional detail from Twitter and a second video that the company says takes advantage of the video improvements.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22692348/twitter-video-quality-less-pixelated"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22692348/twitter-video-quality-less-pixelated</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-24T17:45:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-24T17:45:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter seeking input as it explores Filter and Limit controls on tweets</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gY8xfAXW-F8VHr-Z0tmwGqMiGrU=/0x0:1654x1103/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69905624/FAETvl9VcAo62_J.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Twitter&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YLEnGk"&gt;Twitter is looking for input on two new potential features that could give users more control over the tone and quality of replies to their tweets. Filter and Limit, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/paulabarcante/status/1441457192712818692?s=20"&gt;as shared by Twitter designer Paula Barcante&lt;/a&gt;, would intelligently hide offensive or harmful replies or prevent repeat offenders from replying at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0dyR1G"&gt;Based on the concept images Barcante shared, Twitter would detect whether or not you’ve received harmful replies and then prompt you to turn on Filter or Limit. “If you have Filter on, potentially harmful replies to your Tweet wouldn’t be shown to you or anyone else,” Barcante writes. With Limit enabled, accounts with a history of offensive or “repetitive, uninvited tweets” would be prevented from replying at all.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VGR7vqapHT29IW9E4RXur8vPYhc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22876139/FAEUnKCVgAEN_y4.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Twitter&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;In Twitter’s concept, filtered replies are still visible to the person who tweets them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="f6d7Ar"&gt;Twitter’s concept is fairly upfront about whether or not you have Filter or Limit enabled. In the case of filtered tweets, they still appear for the person replying, with added text that says: “This reply is only visible to you.” For accounts with Limit enabled, Twitter would show a warning explaining that “Reply limit is on” with a link to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TDeu1ZW-4uLDDAwMgI7U1YdOSh4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22876140/FAEUdlcUcAIHuvY.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Twitter&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter tries to make it clear when reply limits are on.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="no03rh"&gt;Now since this — entirely hypothetical — process is automated, it’s bound to not be accurate all of the time. Barcante notes that Twitter is also considering letting users review the tweets that get caught in either feature’s net in case the user disagrees with Twitter’s automated decision and wants to correct it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K4HoZX"&gt;In terms of features Twitter has experimented with as of late, Filter and Limit definitely sound &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22577166/twitter-fleets-shuts-down-stories-clone"&gt;more useful than, say, Fleets&lt;/a&gt; (RIP). It’s easy to imagine enabling those settings could largely prevent &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/12/22574082/black-players-england-italy-football-soccer-racist-instagram-twitter-telegram"&gt;the racist abuse highly visible users can experience&lt;/a&gt; on the platform. Twitter’s also looked at other ways to protect users’ experience, like adding &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22654061/twitter-features-archive-old-tweets-hide-likes-remove-followers-plans"&gt;the ability to hide old tweets&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22558731/twitter-trusted-friends-facets-features-pre-announce"&gt;select who will see a tweet before you send it&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UhDh2d"&gt;Like many of Twitter’s experiments, these all sound like great ideas; now, they actually need to be implemented. Barcante didn’t give a timeline for when that might happen. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22692264/twitter-filter-limit-tweet-replies-automatic"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22692264/twitter-filter-limit-tweet-replies-automatic</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-24T16:51:13-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-24T16:51:13-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to customize your Windows 11 taskbar </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oIyYtF3JZA7beM4sATh_CNxbbqU=/100x0:1180x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69905381/windows11darkmode.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BNEkZJ"&gt;If you’ve updated your computer from Windows 10 to Windows 11, you may find that your taskbar isn’t quite as configurable — and perhaps not quite as useful — as it was before. For example, the old, familiar Start menu with its configurable Live Tiles is now gone. The search box is no longer within the taskbar but is accessed by first clicking on the Start menu — an extra step. (Although the fact that Cortana is no longer automatically part of that search box can be considered, by many at least, as a plus.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yFG6MC"&gt;Another thing: the taskbar is now permanently affixed to the bottom of the screen — so if you were more comfortable having it on top of the screen, or on either side, you’re out of luck. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L9vb32"&gt;As you might imagine, Windows users are already posting fixes for at least some of these issues — as long as you’re comfortable tweaking your Windows Registry. For example, there’s one that purportedly lets you &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0lbh92l2OPM"&gt;move the taskbar to the top of the screen&lt;/a&gt;, and another that lets you &lt;a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/how-to/change-taskbar-icon-size-windows-11"&gt;change the size of the taskbar&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SpL8Ka"&gt;It’s possible that Microsoft will bring back some of these abilities in future updates of the new OS. For now, let’s concentrate on how you can adjust the current Windows 11 taskbar. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="5oxSxP"&gt;Pin an app to the taskbar&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="xm0W0C"&gt;Pinning an app to the taskbar at the bottom can be a little — well, weird. There are several ways to handle it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="DuFnpG"&gt;If an app is running, its icon will appear in the taskbar with a line underneath to indicate that it is active. If you want its icon to remain in the taskbar even after you’ve closed it, then right-click on the icon and select “Pin to taskbar.”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Right click on an active icon and select “Pin to taskbar”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rkWVFm4q0PWeQdKmmf3P_u9eiZI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22875740/Screenshot__34_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Right-click on an active icon and select “Pin to taskbar”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="09hcS0"&gt;If an app isn’t running, but its icon is on your desktop, you can pin it to the Taskbar as well. Right-click on the desktop icon and click on “Show more options.” A longer menu will open up; about two-thirds down, you’ll see “Pin to taskbar.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hQjzy1"&gt;You can also click on the Start icon, select the “All apps” button, and then right-click on the app you want. If you don’t see “Pin to taskbar” in the menu that pops up, then select “More” and you’ll see “Pin to taskbar.” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can also pin an app to your tasks from the “All apps” menu." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6np8xh9IUC6f59MjCRtRConOfHQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22875750/Screenshot__36_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can also pin an app to your taskbar from the “All apps” menu.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="r03xsL"&gt;Remove an app from the taskbar&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="E2JcFt"&gt;Most apps are simple to remove: just right-click on the icon and select “Unpin from taskbar.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9uxtIx"&gt;A few of the icons take a little more effort to remove. The Start menu icon is, as might be expected, unremovable. But there are four other icons that can’t be removed but can be hidden. The easiest way to do that is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="9xBEcg"&gt;Right click on the taskbar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ux21Pe"&gt;Select “Taskbar settings.” (You can also get there by going to “Settings” &amp;gt; “Personalization” &amp;gt; “Taskbar.”)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="KF2cGN"&gt;Toggle off any of the four icons — “Search,” “Task view,” “Widgets,” or “Chat” — that you want to hide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can hide four of the standard taskbar icons." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QiYYZmbY59G4ZdXo0G9DWK5dBv8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22875769/Screenshot__3_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can hide four of the standard taskbar icons.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1kOnJJ"&gt;Move your icons to the left&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="gdcBIZ"&gt;Those of us who having been using Windows 10 (or 7 or earlier iterations) are used to accessing the Start menu from the lower left-hand corner of the screen. If your muscle memory keeps your hand drifting to that corner, you can move the center app icons so they are to your left instead:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="kSbuWv"&gt;Right-click on the taskbar and click on “Taskbar settings.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NEijmh"&gt;Select “Taskbar behaviors.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="gsR825"&gt;Look for “Taskbar alignment” and click on the button on the right where it says “Center.” Select “Left” instead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="1yMLuh"&gt;Close the settings window, and you’ll see that the app icons in the taskbar have moved to the left, with the Start menu icon in the corner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can move the icons from the center to the left of the taskbar." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/H-FgiO1ySPF2dpoOxTmo2SVJxg8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22875775/Screenshot__22_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can move the icons from the center to the left of the taskbar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5N9RJr"&gt;Incidentally, the “Taskbar behaviors” section of the settings lets you do more than move your icons to the left. It also lets you automatically hide the taskbar (something that’s been a taskbar behavior for a very long time); show a badge on taskbar apps to let you know if, say, you have any unread messages; handle how the taskbar works on multiple displays; and show a clean desktop by clicking on the far right corner of the taskbar.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Taskbar behaviors include hiding the taskbar and showing unread messages." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Yd_Js0N3g_rBNpWrUNRAirK35N0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22875863/Screenshot__39_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Taskbar behaviors include hiding the taskbar and showing unread messages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="YdaFXX"&gt;Taskbar corner icons and overflow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ZXqHQ2"&gt;While the taskbar corner icons and the overflow window aren’t new, I never actually knew what they were called before. To tell you the truth, when I first saw the phrase “Taskbar corner overflow,” I pictured a bunch of app icons flowing out of the display like Niagara Falls. Turns out the corner icons are the icons in the right corner of the taskbar — the ones that show the time and date, your battery status, your volume level, and your Wi-Fi status, among other things. The overflow is the little pop-up menu that appears when you select the arrow to the left of those corner icons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tRrZ8r"&gt;For the most part, the icons in the overflow window are meant to notify you when there is something that needs to be done — messages that have arrived or an update that is needed. This is also handy for apps, like Discord, that tend to run in the background; you can shut them down easily from the overflow by right-clicking on the icon and looking for the “quit” selection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KTnUzo"&gt;While most of the corner icons that come with Windows are permanent, some — specifically, the Pen menu, the Touch keyboard, and the Virtual touchpad — can be hidden. They can be found on the same taskbar settings menu that let us move the icons to the left; just click on “Taskbar corner icons” and toggle off the ones you don’t want to see.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The overflow menu lets you handle apps that run in the background." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9I4VHcwITYBFbABqI0QfPPnH_fM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22875820/Screenshot__37_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The overflow menu lets you handle apps that run in the background.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="uwrcVG"&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Qzwzv1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22688307/windows-11-microsoft-taskbar-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22688307/windows-11-microsoft-taskbar-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-24T16:17:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-24T16:17:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>It’s Friday, here’s the Galaxy S22 Ultra render that has the Android blogosphere abuzz</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tPAqt1bFg8PNssyPiGSlNCBun-M=/400x0:4720x2880/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69905230/GALAXY_S22_ULTRA_5K4.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Digit, OnLeaks&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pA0XYz"&gt;It’s Friday, it’s fall, there’s a breeze in the air (hopefully), and there’s fresh, I’d argue ridiculous, renders of Samsung’s expected Galaxy S22 Ultra to show you. The renders come &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OnLeaks/status/1441426057316368389?s=20"&gt;courtesy of @OnLeaks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.digit.in/news/mobile-phones/samsung-galaxy-s22-ultra-exclusive-leaked-renders-specs-61203.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Digit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and they feature a new Samsung flagship with what looks like a Galaxy Note 20-inspired body and back that... well you should see for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GBQsVb"&gt;Since deciding &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22335502/galaxy-note-2021-delay-canceled-samsung"&gt;to skip the Galaxy Note in 2021&lt;/a&gt; — apparently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/15/22676054/t-mobile-cfo-peter-osvaldik-samsung-supply-no-note"&gt;much to the chagrin of T-Mobile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; — &lt;/em&gt;Samsung’s been seeding Note features across its popular phones. Both the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22227772/samsung-galaxy-s21-plus-ultra-price-specs-release-date-unpacked"&gt;Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22617206/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3-features-specs-price-hands-on"&gt;Galaxy Z Fold 3&lt;/a&gt; offer stylus support. If these new renders are to be believed, the Galaxy S22 Ultra will go even further. According to OnLeaks and &lt;em&gt;Digit&lt;/em&gt;, the new phone will come with the hole-punch selfie camera and candy bar shape of last year’s Note, along with stylus support and what looks like an actual stylus slot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="fLZ8ro"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Sooo... Here comes your very first and early look at the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Samsung?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Samsung&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GalaxyS22Ultra?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#GalaxyS22Ultra&lt;/a&gt; and its quite "unique" rear camera housing design! (360° video + stunning 5K renders + dimensions)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;On behalf of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/digitindia?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@digitindia&lt;/a&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/vBGM3WJfru"&gt;https://t.co/vBGM3WJfru&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/YDqfFrVGLW"&gt;pic.twitter.com/YDqfFrVGLW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Steve H.McFly (@OnLeaks) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OnLeaks/status/1441426057316368389?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 24, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NW5kU6"&gt;The render of the back of the device is where things get interesting, weird, or bad, depending on your taste. The Galaxy S22 Ultra appears to morph &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22241506/samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-review-camera-price"&gt;the camera “plateau” of the S21 Ultra&lt;/a&gt; into an unmistakable letter P shape. Is the P for... photos? Pictures? Maybe periscope? There certainly seems to be plenty of room. For reference, the previous Ultra included a main 108-megapixel wide-angle sensor, two 10-megapixel telephoto sensors, and a 12-megapixel ultrawide sensor on the back of the device. Who knows what the new S22 Ultra will fit?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ATuyJXVgnfueUq6vLwNSV-oIdbY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22875857/GALAXY_S22_ULTRA_07.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Digit, OnLeaks&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s hard to miss the P-shaped cameras, a little bit easier to miss the stylus slot at the bottom of the rumored device.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="sDJGdj"&gt;There’s some reason to believe this could be Samsung’s design, beyond it fitting with a general trend of camera bumps becoming big and increasingly... visible on devices like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22684033/apple-iphone-13-pro-max-review"&gt;the iPhone 13 Pro&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605094/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-specs-ai-ml"&gt;yet-to-be-released Pixel 6&lt;/a&gt;. OnLeaks has a fairly good track record of leaking phones, pretty closely matching the looks of both &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/21/21395173/leaked-google-pixel-5-renders-specs-october-launch"&gt;the Pixel 5&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447011/google-pixel-6-leaks-renders-pics-specs"&gt;the Pixel 6&lt;/a&gt;. This kind of refinement to a camera housing also doesn’t seem out of the picture, in many ways it’s a reduction of the S21 Ultra’s cameras: a corner has been removed. That doesn’t mean it doesn’t look strange, though.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Galaxy S21 Ultra, in Phantom Black" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b1pRvJgZl0Ynhub4j7_nMUn0Zt0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22248961/vpavic_210119_4377_0170.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;I can imagine seeing a “P” on the Galaxy S21 Ultra if I really look at it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22691985/samsung-galaxy-s22-ultra-render-p-camera-stylus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22691985/samsung-galaxy-s22-ultra-render-p-camera-stylus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-24T16:15:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-24T16:15:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>US agrees not to pursue fraud charges against Huawei CFO</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Huawei Chief Financial Officer Meng Wanzhou returns to British Columbia Supreme Court on August 18, 2021, in Vancouver, Canada, during her last extradition hearing." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uQFgAPJZkOf73pWuG3orRdK7yi4=/0x0:6658x4439/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69903844/1234750724.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by DON MACKINNON/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7TxP6A"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/huawei-cfo-meng-appear-brooklyn-federal-court-2021-09-24/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/meng-wanzhou-us-court-1.6188093"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CBC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; first reported that Huawei CFO Meng Wanzhou would appear in a Brooklyn federal courtroom today via streaming video and enter a plea regarding US charges against her. Canadian authorities &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/5/18128057/huawei-cfo-canada-arrest-iran-sanctions-violation"&gt;arrested the Chinese executive in December 2018&lt;/a&gt; on suspicion of violating US sanctions, and she has remained there &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/11/18134938/huawei-cfo-meng-wanzhou-bail-house-arrest-us-china"&gt;on house arrest&lt;/a&gt; ever since, fighting US attempts at extradition. Hearings in her extradition case ended in August, with the ruling scheduled for October 21st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8lrgI9"&gt;Meng was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/28/18201023/us-charges-huawei-fraud-stealing-t-mobile-justice-department"&gt;indicted on fraud charges claiming the Chinese technology and telecommunications company misrepresented its relationship with an Iranian affiliate&lt;/a&gt;, along with accusations it stole intellectual property from T-Mobile. The &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-edny/pr/chinese-telecommunications-conglomerate-huawei-and-huawei-cfo-wanzhou-meng-charged"&gt;13-count indictment&lt;/a&gt; named Meng, Huawei, and two of its subsidiaries — Huawei USA and Skycom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WKwrEt"&gt;On Friday afternoon, Meng pleaded not guilty. Prosecutors submitted a statement of facts (&lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/press-release/file/1436211/download"&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt;) asserting that in 2013 she told financial institutions the Iranian company Skycom was a partner of Huawei while knowing that Skycom was owned and controlled by a Huawei subsidiary to act as its agent in the region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fDDhgV"&gt;As part of the deal in making this admission, the prosecution says “Meng has agreed to the accuracy of a four-page statement of facts that details the knowingly false statements she made to Financial Institution 1.” They are withdrawing their request for extradition from Canada, and as long as she doesn’t commit any other crimes the charges will be dropped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3KMWho"&gt;According to the &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/justice-department-reaches-deal-with-huawei-executive-11632494001?st=n81fv8iy9e669cs&amp;amp;reflink=desktopwebshare_twitter"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Justice Department officials under the Biden administration revisited negotiations that had broken down under President Trump. Its sources report that Huawei itself is not a part of the deal and will continue to fight &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/16/18185771/huawei-trade-secrets-charges-federal-investigation"&gt;its charges of fraud and trade secret theft&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="46hhwq"&gt;Spokespeople for the US Attorney’s Office and Huawei have not commented publicly on the matter. A former Canadian diplomat told the &lt;em&gt;CBC &lt;/em&gt;he expects her release would lead to China deporting two Canadians it arrested and charged with espionage following Meng’s arrest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mFIHHw"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 24th, 3:24PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to add Meng’s court appearance, not guilty plea, and prosecution agreement details.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dm5s3l"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 24th, 4:14PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to add details from the plea and deferred prosecution agreement.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22691518/huawei-meng-wanzhou-cfo-fraud-plea-china-canada"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22691518/huawei-meng-wanzhou-cfo-fraud-plea-china-canada</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
