<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-07-01T14:08:16-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T14:08:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T14:08:16-04:00</updated>
    <title>Robinhood’s IPO filing reveals Dogecoin helped its revenue skyrocket in 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oGtv-QQ3hAyqeWQ2TGueZWtx3R8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69530339/acastro_210129_1777_robinhood_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustrations by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OtBmN3"&gt;The moment &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22373990/robinhood-ipo-form-regulators-finance"&gt;that some of you have been waiting for&lt;/a&gt; is here — Robinhood’s &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1783879/000162828021013318/robinhoods-1.htm"&gt;S-1 filing to go public has been revealed&lt;/a&gt;, laying bare the kind of secrets you only learn when a company is legally obligated to reveal them. Only one day ago the company agreed to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/30/22557419/robinhood-finra-fine-70-million"&gt;pay a record-breaking $70 million fine&lt;/a&gt; “for systemic supervisory failures and significant harm suffered by millions of customers,” and now its paperwork touts a commitment to “maintaining strong relationships with our loyal customer base and earning our customers’ trust when they choose our platform on their financial journeys.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XuwHNi"&gt;So what does the much-anticipated document include? There’s a note that the United States Attorney’s Office for the Northern District of California has executed a search warrant for co-founder and CEO Vladimir Tenev’s phone, as well as information about a recent SEC Enforcement Division inquiry into Robinhood’s “For You” feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nCtSpo"&gt;According to Robinhood, some 1,600 jointly represented customers “may pursue arbitration of individual claims against us arising out of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/9/21171584/robinhood-outage-week-us-stocks-third-market"&gt;the March 2020 Outages&lt;/a&gt;, in addition to other alleged system outages.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZEeLDj"&gt;GameStop is mentioned five times in the document (usually along with AMC and other popular Reddit stonks), mostly in describing Robinhood’s decision to limit trading of them this spring. There have been about 50 class action lawsuits filed over the incident, as well as investigations or inquiries from the USAO, DOJ, SEC, FINRA and any other combination of letters you can imagine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ioLHIV"&gt;Memes are inextricably a part of Robinhood’s business, as it notes that in the first three months of 2021, “34 percent of our cryptocurrency transaction-based revenue was attributable to transactions in Dogecoin.” At the same time, revenue from cryptocurrency transactions from for four percent for the last three months of 2020, to 12 percent of its total revenue in the first three months of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TrJ1pB"&gt;Robinhood (HOOD) says it as about 17.7 million monthly active users, and despite the spike in activity, lost nearly $1.5 billion in the first three months of 2021. Its S-1 filing also addressed the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/31/22360639/robinhood-confetti-ipo-removed-app-stock-market"&gt;recent removal of a confetti celebration effect in the app&lt;/a&gt;, saying “this practice drew scrutiny from certain regulators and the media and, in 2021, we introduced new unique visual experiences to mark milestones in our customers’ financial journeys.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559438/robinhood-ipo-dogecoin-hood-revenue-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559438/robinhood-ipo-dogecoin-hood-revenue-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T14:00:27-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T14:00:27-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sony’s camera-centric Xperia 1 III to ship on August 19th for $1,299</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/51YwlW54zMbn6cAuknjyqSuLwAk=/547x0:6454x3938/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69530326/Xperia_1_IIIcameraZeiss_frostedBlack.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Xperia 1 III puts an emphasis on advanced camera features and high-end display specs.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Sony&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8Go4M5"&gt;Sony’s next flagship phone, the Xperia 1 III, will ship on August 19th in the US — for a whopping $1,299.99. It’s available to preorder today, the company announced. The new photography-focused phone is designed as a complement to Sony’s Alpha camera range, and it introduces a variable periscope-style telephoto lens. It’s also equipped with just about everything you’d expect from a flagship Android phone in 2021, including a Snapdragon 888 processor, 5G, and a 6.5-inch display with 120Hz refresh rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PQSJmb"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/24/21268097/sonys-xperia-1-ii-ships-july-24th-1199-us-united-states"&gt;Xperia 1 II launched at $1,200&lt;/a&gt; — pricey even for a top-of-the-line device — and Sony isn’t backing off by pricing this one at an extra $100. In this case at least, users in the US will be able to utilize its 5G connectivity; last year’s model had the right hardware but couldn’t use US 5G networks. The 6.5-inch 4K display has also been upgraded to a faster 120Hz refresh rate compared to last year’s model (which had a standard 60Hz rate), and you’ll get a bigger 4,500mAh battery, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="j6bena"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Sony Xperia 1 II review: it’s a stretch","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21322518/sony-xperia-1-ii-review-smartphone-new-camera-photo-pro"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="fDWEEb"&gt;If the Xperia 1 III sounds appealing but paying $1,300 does not, the Xperia 5 III is a smaller-screen variant that will likely cost a bit less, though US price and shipping are still unannounced. In the meantime, if you are willing to shell out top dollar for the 1 III, Sony’s offering a healthy preorder incentive by throwing in a pair of WF-1000XM3 noise-canceling earbuds for free on orders placed by September 26th. The Xperia 1 III will be sold &lt;a href="https://electronics.sony.com/"&gt;directly from Sony&lt;/a&gt; and other third-party retailers.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559213/sony-xperia-1-iii-camera-price-availability-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559213/sony-xperia-1-iii-camera-price-availability-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T13:57:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T13:57:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Want to be an Amazon supplier? It could cost a piece of your company</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Media tour at Miami International Airport" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b0YaQ3s4wQHvLudD0vgaDtQE398=/0x0:5680x3787/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69530300/1233493336.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Marco Bello / Anadolu Agency via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YPxT1O"&gt;Amazon demands that suppliers let it buy up to 30 percent of their company at a fixed rate often below market valuation, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/amazon-demands-one-more-thing-from-some-vendors-a-piece-of-their-company-11624968099"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal &lt;/em&gt;report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qp4SeY"&gt;Amazon has added these kinds of stipulations to contracts with companies that supply it with aircraft, Amazon Fresh groceries, and call center services more than 75 times over the last 10 years, according to the &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt;. Its potential equity in other firms is valued at nearly $3 billion, according to Amazon’s latest quarterly financial filings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fYZrTD"&gt;These kinds of deals are called warrants, and they function similarly to stock options granted to employees of a company. Amazon gets the option to buy its supplier’s stock at a certain price, set before the deal is announced. When that stock shoots through the roof, Amazon can hold the warrants over the long-term or sell it off to make a tidy profit. Many of these deals are contingent on Amazon giving its suppliers a certain amount of business in a set time limit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pBhrUR"&gt;Here’s an example: as Amazon was trying to build out its logistics fleet with cargo planes, it was negotiating with Atlas Air Worldwide Holdings Inc for a 10-year lease. Part of the agreement Amazon proposed was the ability to buy 20 percent of the company over five years, with a potential 10 percent more equity later, according to the &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt; report. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pzweVj"&gt;Atlas agreed, with Amazon’s fixed price for the stock set at $37.50. When the deal was announced, the stock rose 27 percent. Amazon later sold 9 percent of its stake in the company, able to pocket the difference between its initial $37.50 price and the inflated price after the announcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hwVoXw"&gt;The deals could be considered a good thing for both sides of the agreement, as &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2021-06-30/amazon-got-some-warrants"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg’s&lt;/em&gt; Matt Levine has argued&lt;/a&gt;. Levine refers to one of the deals discussed in the &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt; article, where Amazon secured warrants for a potential 15 percent of grocery supplier SpartanNash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3lOEpW"&gt;He notes that SpartanNash’s stock jumped 26.3 percent the day the Amazon deal was announced, while Amazon only would be able to buy 15 percent of that equity market value. “26 is more than 15,” Levine shrewdly &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2021-06-30/amazon-got-some-warrants"&gt;noted&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S2pkiB"&gt;But Amazon reportedly strong-arms these companies into agreeing to otherwise unheard-of terms, relying on its enormous buying capacity and clout among investors. Former Amazon executives told the &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt; that companies offered deals including warrants couldn’t refuse that part of the contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sdHujw"&gt;“There was definitely a sense that if it wasn’t agreed to there wouldn’t be a deal,” one source involved in the Atlas deal told the &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559147/amazon-equity-warrants-suppliers-discount"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559147/amazon-equity-warrants-suppliers-discount</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dave Gershgorn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T13:22:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T13:22:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple launches public beta of macOS Monterey, bringing updates to FaceTime and Safari</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A MacBook Pro running macOS Monterey sits on a table in front of a window. The screen displays the Quick note app on top of a pink and purple background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CNYGStZnZP-kSXROO5wLnd6PJpY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69530097/mchin_210701_4658_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Need a quick note? There’s an app for that.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="juxc3a"&gt;The public beta of macOS 12 Monterey, Apple’s next big macOS release, is now available for download. The operating system has the same general look and feel as its predecessor, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/16/21564490/macos-big-sur-review-apple-macbook-pro-air-mac-ipad-m1"&gt;macOS 11 Big Sur&lt;/a&gt;, but it brings some new features and a number of tweaks to Apple’s most popular services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nxcR1j"&gt;Before we get into this, friendly reminder that Monterey is, for now, a beta. It may not be the best idea to install on a primary device, as you might encounter bugs, unfinished features, and incompatibility with third-party apps. If you will be installing the program on your daily driver, make sure you’ve backed up anything you can’t afford to mess with first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z2tJJv"&gt;For those who take the leap and install the public beta, the component Apple seems most excited about is its updates to FaceTime. My favorite of these is Portrait Mode, which blurs the background behind you while you’re speaking on a call (similarly to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/30/22556236/ios-15-ipados-iphone-ipad-software-update-public-beta-preview-apple"&gt;the iPhone’s feature with the same name&lt;/a&gt;). Portrait Mode didn’t always get everything — sometimes when there were multiple different surfaces behind me, it seemed to get a bit confused and leave some parts un-blurred. But it wasn’t difficult to find areas where the feature worked just fine. Apple says Portrait Mode will be available for adoption in third-party apps as well, but we’ll have to wait for them to issue updates to support it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="xI6srY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"iOS 15 and iPadOS 15 preview: a first look at Apple’s latest software","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/30/22556236/ios-15-ipados-iphone-ipad-software-update-public-beta-preview-apple"},{"title":"How to install the macOS Monterey public beta","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22558991/macos-monterey-how-to-install-public-beta"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A screenshot of a MacBook screen where a user is on a FaceTime call with a blurred bright bedroom background. A FaceTime drop-down menu is open in the top right with Portrait selected." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2NsKif8IbPqAUClq3MVExUI7Bcg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22692197/IMG_9643.JPG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;macOS Monterey’s new FaceTime Portrait Mode did a decent job of blurring out my background.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="RPSdWc"&gt;Even though it’s had the ability to make group calls for a few years, I’ve always viewed FaceTime as a tool for calling one person at a time. But Monterey introduces a few other features that are clearly meant to make the tool a stronger Zoom competitor, conducive to meetings and larger calls. It now supports a grid view and Spatial Audio (which makes other people’s voices sound like they’re coming from the area on the screen where their face is positioned). You can generate a link to a FaceTime call ahead of time (the same way you generate a Zoom link), and users of Android and Windows can join from their browsers. And a new Voice Isolation feature uses machine learning to mitigate background noise while you’re speaking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5DK3OV"&gt;There’s a new feature called SharePlay, which is like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/24/21191503/netflix-party-stream-movies-tv-chat-watch-friends-social-distance"&gt;Netflix Party&lt;/a&gt; or Scener but for FaceTime. Like Netflix Party, it allows you and other people on your FaceTime call to watch content from certain streaming services together by syncing everyone’s video playback and controls. (So we’re both watching the video on our own devices, with our own accounts. But when I pause or start, you pause or start as well.) SharePlay isn’t a new idea, but it’ll certainly be convenient to have on FaceTime. While the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522904/apple-shareplay-facetime-music-hulu-videos-tiktok-wwdc"&gt;list of supported services&lt;/a&gt; includes some big players (such as Disney Plus, Hulu, HBO Max, Paramount Plus, Twitch, Pluto TV, and — hilariously — TikTok), it doesn’t appear to include Netflix, which is the one streaming service I and all of my friends and family reliably have in common. Until that’s added to the roster, I don’t see myself using this that often. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bvui2D"&gt;A new feature that I do think I’ll be using a lot is Quick Note. Quick Note gives you an easy way to take notes on an article you’re reading (or items you’re viewing in Maps, Photos, or other apps). You can right-click highlighted text to add it to a Quick Note, and it’ll appear there along with a link to the source. (You can press Fn+Q to pull up a blank one as well.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="On9s5f"&gt;Quick Notes sync across devices and are available in a specific “Quick Notes” folder in the Notes app. The handiest thing, I think, is that if you’ve got an app open where you’ve previously created a Quick Note, you can hover your cursor in the bottom-right corner of the screen and a thumbnail of the note will pop up. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A screenshot of a MacBook Pro screen. The Verge’s review of the Razer Blade 14 is open in Safari. A paragraph is higlighted with “Add to Quick Note” in an adjacent drop-down menu selected. A Quick Note is open on the left side of the screen with more text and a link to the article." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/09b_x2tfr-du0C0QCPK7kHPH8mI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22692276/Screen_Shot_2021_06_30_at_4.25.44_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;I took some notes on my recent review of the Razer Blade 14. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dIYFeJ"&gt;Apple has introduced a few “continuity” features that are meant to make it easier to use Macs alongside other Apple devices. Arguably the most exciting one, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22523613/macos-monterey-wwdc-apple-ipad"&gt;Universal Control&lt;/a&gt;, won’t be ready until a future beta. What you can try now is AirPlay, which has made its way to macOS for the first time. AirPlay makes it easier to cast content to a Mac computer: it can mirror or extend your iPhone’s screen, for example, or can function as an AirPlay 2 speaker. I was able to set this up easily (you just need to wait until the devices detect each other and then enter a code on your phone), and it worked well. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A screenshot of a macOS notification that reads “Airplay: Look What You Made Me Do would like to AirPlay to this Mac.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f31vkR0ekMZegf2SG1Ow2M2dQw0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22692357/Screen_Shot_2021_06_30_at_4.48.05_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes, that is the name of my iPhone. Long story.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="o4V6EO"&gt;Safari has some tweaks, mainly concerning tabs. The URL bar now lives next to your tabs, which gives you more browsing space. Tabs have a rounder appearance now, and you can click one to reveal its page’s full address. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TdaBeU"&gt;The new feature that I think is quite useful is tab groups. The way this works is that if you have, say, five tabs open, you can click a little icon in the top-left corner to make them into a “tab group”. Later on, if you open the sidebar on the left, you’ll see the group listed in the “Tab Groups” section; click on it, and Safari will reopen those five tabs. Also in that sidebar lives a bookmarks list, a reading list, and a list of links that have been shared with you in Messages. You can test-drive the new Safari browser in older versions of macOS without having to update to the Monterey beta by installing the &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/safari/technology-preview/"&gt;Safari Technology Preview&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A screenshot of Safari open on a MacBook Pro. A Verge Windows 11 video is open on YouTube. The sidebar is open showing two tab groups: Verge Videos and Verge Articles." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NwyeAMV8Q-G7S-8Q1e7rjn0-B7Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22692376/Screen_Shot_2021_06_30_at_5.00.18_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tab groups are almost instant to click in and out of.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7Key8M"&gt;There are a number of other odds and ends built into macOS Monterey. Shortcuts is available on macOS, Focus allows you to filter notifications based on the task you’re doing, it’s gotten easier to save photos that you receive in Messages, etc. I look forward to digging more into these features for our full review, but the things I’ve highlighted here are the ones I see being the most immediately impactful to daily use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PtT8tL"&gt;The phrase “odds and ends” really sums up my impressions after using macOS Monterey for a few days. macOS Big Sur completely overhauled the Mac experience. That’s not the case here (which is fine — not every update needs to be a revolution). Apple seems to have made some tweaks here and some tweaks there. My reactions have largely been: “Alright, that could be handy.” Which is fair. I’ll take handy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LjiYcv"&gt;Here’s the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523116/apple-ios-ipados-15-watchos-8-macos-monterey-wwdc-2021"&gt;list of devices&lt;/a&gt; that will support macOS Monterey: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="i7zV7I"&gt;iMac (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201634"&gt;late 2015 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DT8GDM"&gt;iMac Pro (2017 and later)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="TDG4DT"&gt;Mac Pro (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/HT202888"&gt;late 2013 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cZc8bq"&gt;Mac Mini (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/HT201894"&gt;late 2014 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="SkWfhc"&gt;MacBook Pro (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/HT201300"&gt;early 2015 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="FavKjr"&gt;MacBook Air (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/HT201862"&gt;early 2015 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="SncFxN"&gt;MacBook (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/HT201608"&gt;early 2016 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="0hkh24"&gt;Notably, this doesn’t include a few models that did get Big Sur last year, including the 2013 MacBook Air, the late-2013 MacBook Pro, and the 2014 iMac. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="3QPTht"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Some of macOS Monterey’s best features aren’t coming to Intel Macs","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526224/macos-monterey-best-features-macs-intel-m1-exclusive"},{"title":"macOS Monterey lets you run Shortcuts and share files between Macs and iPads","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22458628/apple-macos-12-monterey-features-updates-wwdc-2021"},{"title":"How Universal Control on macOS Monterey works","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22523613/macos-monterey-wwdc-apple-ipad"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22557880/apple-macos-public-beta-facetime-safari-updates"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22557880/apple-macos-public-beta-facetime-safari-updates</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T13:16:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T13:16:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>Federal Trade Commission expands antitrust powers in Chair Lina Khan’s first open proceeding</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/N8tKEklo9uNmXFyeiIGqLHhi-_g=/127x0:1507x920/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69530049/image__11_.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Chair Khan, appearing at the hearing via Zoom&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aFe8yj"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/press-releases/2021/07/ftc-holds-open-commission-meeting-today"&gt;In an open meeting on Thursday&lt;/a&gt;, the Federal Trade Commission passed a pair of pivotal measures expanding its power to regulate anti-competitive business practices, setting the stage for a more aggressive enforcement approach from the embattled agency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J7cACE"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/press-releases/2021/06/ftc-announces-agenda-july-1-open-commission-meeting"&gt;Announced last week&lt;/a&gt;, Thursday’s proceeding is the first open business meeting of the commission in more than 20 years, as commission proceedings have traditionally been closed to the public. Chair Lina Khan plans to hold public meetings on a monthly basis going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tgVpbH"&gt;The meeting paved the way for an aggressive antitrust approach from the agency, with three separate measures expanding the commission’s power to prosecute anti-competitive business practices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="9sLpf7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We want to send a signal that today’s FTC is ready to take on the challenge of the modern economy”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6dVHHq"&gt;In the most aggressive effort, the commission voted to rescind a 2015 “Statement of Enforcement Principles” that restricted the FTC Act’s prescriptions on “unfair methods of competition” to explicit violations of existing antitrust law (specifically the Sherman and Clayton Acts). The vote proceeded along party lines, passing 3-2 with Democrats in the majority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BlbQZV"&gt;“In practice, the 2015 statement has doubled down on the agency’s longstanding failure to investigate and pursue unfair methods of competition,” said Khan, introducing the motion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YL6prU"&gt;Without that restriction, the FTC will be free to pursue lawsuits against misconduct that might not violate classical antitrust law. The commission is still considering whether to replace the statement with blanket guidelines or an array of more specific rulemaking against particular practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xJNumY"&gt;Rescinding the 2015 order remains controversial among pro-business groups and is likely to face a legal challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o9xYDb"&gt;“A clear majority of the Supreme Court has expressed their intention to revive the non-delegation doctrine, which holds that only Congress may make laws,” said the pro-business think tank TechFreedom &lt;a href="https://techfreedom.org/ftc-to-rescind-competition-policy-statement-streamline-consumer-protection-rulemakings-competition-investigations/"&gt;in a statement&lt;/a&gt; in advance of the vote. “The FTC might well wind up as the first test case for that long-dormant doctrine if it departs from the clear principles developed by the courts under antitrust law.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V3W8Dk"&gt;In another 3-2 vote, the FTC moved to simplify the rulemaking process for “prohibiting unfair or deceptive acts or practices.” Introduced by Commissioner Rebecca Kelly Slaughter, the changes are broadly procedural, lifting a number of self-imposed bureaucratic restrictions on the commission, allowing it to respond more efficiently to perceived misconduct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rs72V2"&gt;“We want to send a signal that today’s FTC is ready to take on the challenge of the modern economy,” said Slaughter at the hearing. “I hope that with these streamlined procedures, we can tackle cutting-edge issues.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UfRokn"&gt;A third 3-2 vote passed a series of resolutions to streamline FTC investigations, including enabling individual commissioners to launch staff investigations into specific industries and conduct. Introducing the measure, Khan said she believed there were a number of industries where such an investigation would be appropriate, “including technology platforms, healthcare, and pharmaceuticals.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X5THoN"&gt;Expanding FTC powers has long been a goal of antitrust activists and has been the subject of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22338763/facebook-google-antitrust-cicilline-ftc-slaughter-monopoly"&gt;several proposals from Congressional Democrats&lt;/a&gt;. But it’s been met with intense pushback, including from tech companies themselves. An FTC complaint against Facebook was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/28/22554476/ftc-facebook-instagram-antitrust-case-whatsapp-federal-court"&gt;dismissed in court earlier this week&lt;/a&gt;, and it remains unclear how well Khan’s agenda will fare against judicial challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559131/ftc-open-meeting-antitrust-chair-lina-khan-sherman-act-powers"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559131/ftc-open-meeting-antitrust-chair-lina-khan-sherman-act-powers</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T13:14:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T13:14:52-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to install the macOS Monterey public beta</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oICKh8FKrnULXwm4qBHN2qU3CHg=/0x0:2400x1600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69530037/Apple_macos_monterey_shortcuts_gallery_06072021.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="V6zJVU"&gt;Apple has launched &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22321921"&gt;the public beta for macOS Monterey&lt;/a&gt;. This is the next big update coming to Mac computers (the final version is expected later in 2021) and it brings several big changes. In this article, we’re going to walk you through how to get the beta onto your computer, should you want it. Once you install the beta, it will likely receive several updates between now and the final release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G0YsSM"&gt;(Looking for steps to install the iOS 15 and iPadOS 15 public betas? &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22557308/ios-ipados-15-public-beta-apple-install"&gt;We’ve got you covered here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="VxGaqm"&gt;What’s new about macOS Monterey?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="qrSMDX"&gt;One of the most impressive demos that Apple showed during WWDC 2021 was the new drag-and-drop feature called Universal Control that’ll let you seamlessly move your cursor and files between an iPad and Mac computer, as if they were all hard-wired together. Check out Dieter Bohn’s video below to find out more about that feature. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="BzFd4h"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="The best demo at WWDC 2021|102457" data-volume-uuid="8630beec6" data-volume-id="102457" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-284" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yZtXH3"&gt;Macs will also get &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/guide/shortcuts/welcome/ios"&gt;Shortcuts&lt;/a&gt; and will be able to act as AirPlay targets, so your computer will be able to play content from your iPhone or iPad. There are more changes in the update, and my colleague Mitchell Clark &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22458628/apple-macos-12-monterey-features-updates-wwdc-2021"&gt;covers all of the highlights here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MpJ1SU"&gt;Here’s some more coverage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="hSuGwu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Some of macOS Monterey’s best features aren’t coming to Intel-based Macs","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22526224/macos-monterey-best-features-macs-intel-m1-exclusive"},{"title":"iOS 15 and macOS 12 take a small but significant step towards a password-less future","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22529266/passkeys-icloud-keychain-ios-15-passwordless-future-security-login"},{"title":"macOS and tvOS are getting spatial audio support with the AirPods Pro and Max","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22523914/macos-tvos-spatial-audio-support-airpods-pro-max"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="aoruii"&gt;What devices are supported for macOS Monterey?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="KRiLOM"&gt;Here’s the list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="i7zV7I"&gt;iMac (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201634"&gt;late 2015 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DT8GDM"&gt;iMac Pro (2017 and later)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="TDG4DT"&gt;Mac Pro (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/HT202888"&gt;late 2013 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cZc8bq"&gt;Mac Mini (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/HT201894"&gt;late 2014 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="SkWfhc"&gt;MacBook Pro (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/HT201300"&gt;early 2015 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="FavKjr"&gt;MacBook Air (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/HT201862"&gt;early 2015 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="SncFxN"&gt;MacBook (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/HT201608"&gt;early 2016 and later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IYh6eGH4UP7Q5H8ddZjpFtunO8I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22693426/macos_monterey_features.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="agPCNn"&gt;How to install the macOS Monterey beta on your main partition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="21T5f4"&gt;First off, &lt;strong&gt;back up your data&lt;/strong&gt; via Time Machine. This will allow you to revert to Big Sur should things not go well with the Monterey beta. If you’re planning to install this beta on your main machine, keep in mind that you may encounter problems (bugs, incompatibility issues, worse-than-usual battery life) that might get in your way — not what you want if you’re on any kind of deadline. Also, make sure that you have around 20GB of free space available on your hard drive before trying to install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0EmTzc"&gt;There’s a way to avoid some of this possible drama. If you’re using a machine with macOS High Sierra or later, you can &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT208891"&gt;use built-in tools to partition your hard drive&lt;/a&gt; so the beta can live in isolation. This way, you can test out the new features, then boot into your stable macOS partition with the rest of your data when you’re done. We’ll walk through that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cnjek8"&gt;Let’s get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="tusDFy"&gt;Head to &lt;a href="https://beta.apple.com/sp/betaprogram/"&gt;Apple’s beta software portal&lt;/a&gt; via Safari.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="k1OEft"&gt;If you haven’t previously installed a public beta, you’ll need to sign up for access with your Apple ID. Otherwise, click “Enroll Your Devices” at the top-right corner of the webpage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xOFsNr"&gt;Click “macOS,” the middle option at the center of the next page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NcQIKX"&gt;Scroll down until you find a button that says “Download the macOS Public Beta Access Utility.” Click on it to download a .DMG file, which will enroll your computer. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AQuRZs"&gt;Upon booting the installer, you’ll be prompted if it doesn’t detect a Time Machine backup. (You did make a backup, right? Like I suggested above?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jIcbwa"&gt;Lastly, head to “Software Update” from the System Preferences app (if it doesn’t open automatically) to install the beta. If you’ve enrolled in the beta program, you should see the message “This Mac is enrolled in the Apple Beta Software Program” located underneath the big “Software Update” icon. Note: the download might not be available to you immediately. You’ll receive a notification once it is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="5L1JEw"&gt;The update file will take a while to download. Once it’s done, hit install and run through the steps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ksY059"&gt;How to create a separate partition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="k9dw4y"&gt;Open Disk Utility (a built-in app you can find by typing its name into the Spotlight search bar). Your hard drive’s partitions will be listed under “Internal” along the left side of the window. You might only see one.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="If your machine is using APFS, click the plus sign at top to create a new partition." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Lj2ov76oEhHDPo6067qC8ptp7Cg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22693724/Screen_Shot_2021_07_01_at_12.22.36_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If your machine is using APFS, click the plus sign at top to create a new partition.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="qoWZtE"&gt;If you’re using a machine with macOS High Sierra or newer, clicking your main partition should reveal that it’s a “&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT208891"&gt;APFS Volume&lt;/a&gt;.” If so, you can then simply click the plus button above the word “Volume” at the top-left corner of the Disk Utility window to make a new volume.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="751ZpM"&gt;You can name the volume anything you want, then hit “Add.” Since storage formatted to APFS is shared across volumes, there’s no need to worry about how much space to set aside in the new volume when you create it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="aljRC4"&gt;(Note: If your machine’s drive is formatted to Mac OS Extended instead of APFS, you can select the “Partition” button near the top of the Disk Utility window instead. You’ll need to name the partition, then decide how much storage you’d like to have on that slice of hard drive. Given that previous public betas have been over 10GB in size, I’d suggest at least 30GB to be safe.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6sYvFc"&gt;Now that you have another volume (or partition), you can choose to install the beta to that instead of your main drive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="IDctbM"&gt;To switch between volumes or partitions, you’ll need to restart the machine and hold down the Option key during startup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="LozlSM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="WbKXb1"&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22558991/macos-monterey-how-to-install-public-beta"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22558991/macos-monterey-how-to-install-public-beta</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T12:58:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T12:58:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Ghost of Tsushima is getting an enhanced director’s cut on the PS4 and PS5</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_l-NArfs588lxVoks9T5B40PiR8=/0x0:1350x900/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69529908/51282495139_763df069a8_h.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Sony&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8hDhb4"&gt;Sony and Sucker Punch’s hit game &lt;em&gt;Ghost of Tsushima&lt;/em&gt; is getting an enhanced director’s cut edition for both the PS4 and PS5 that will include a new island to explore and all of the content that has been released so far for the original game. The upgraded game will be available on August 20th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M89Zgl"&gt;The new content takes place on the island of Iki, and Sucker Punch says there will be new story content, characters, environments, armor, enemies, and more. “There are even new animals to pet!” &lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/07/01/ghost-of-tsushima-directors-cut-arrives-on-ps5-and-ps4-consoles-on-august-20/"&gt;Sucker Punch’s Andrew Goldfarb said in a blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NJyfK3NNBaHiEKqrMDCFoRidnh8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22693702/51281763051_48114bdd53_h.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Sony&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;An image of Iki Island in &lt;/em&gt;Ghost of Tsushima’s&lt;em&gt; expansion.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="NsxI21"&gt;Alongside the additional content, &lt;em&gt;Ghost of Tsushima Director’s Cut&lt;/em&gt; will also have some PS5-exclusive features, such as using the haptic feedback and adaptive triggers on the DualSense controller. In addition, the PS5 version of the game will feature lip-synced voices for the Japanese voiceover option, addressing a major criticism from the original release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HXM4EZ"&gt;“There will also be enhancements to 3D audio on PS5, as well as drastically improved load times, 4K resolution options and framerates targeting 60 FPS” for the PS5 version of the game, Goldfarb said. It’s unclear how these updates may improve upon the PS5 optimization patch Sucker Punch &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SuckerPunchProd/status/1314641549406265346"&gt;released last year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VH9Wzx"&gt;If you already own &lt;em&gt;Ghost of Tsushima,&lt;/em&gt; a patch will be available with “some” of the new updates when the director’s cut is available, according to Goldfarb. Current owners will also be able to bring their save over to the PS5 version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pJdeNA"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ghost of Tsushima Director’s Cut&lt;/em&gt; will launch on its own for $69.99 on the PS5 and $59.99 on the PS4. But if you have the PS4 version of the original game, the path to upgrading to the director’s cut is a little complex. Here’s how Sony lays it out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="hTjFjX"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you already own Ghost of Tsushima on PS4:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NvyExW"&gt;You can pre-order an upgrade to &lt;em&gt;Director’s Cut&lt;/em&gt; on PS4 for $19.99 USD. This upgrade will become available starting on August 20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0a3639"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starting on August 20:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8EPN0i"&gt;If you bought &lt;em&gt;Director’s Cut&lt;/em&gt; PS4, you’ll be able to upgrade to &lt;em&gt;Director’s Cut&lt;/em&gt; PS5 at any time for $9.99 USD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xk7Yhl"&gt;You can also upgrade directly (from original &lt;em&gt;Ghost of Tsushima&lt;/em&gt; PS4) to &lt;em&gt;Director’s Cut&lt;/em&gt; on PS5 for $29.99 USD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="UtLRu9"&gt;This all means that for people who want to upgrade to the PS5 version, it’s going to cost $30 whether you take the option to pay $20 now and $10 on August 20th or you choose to just pay $30 at launch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="p1MQjF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Ghost of Tsushima is a beautiful samurai tale buried under a familiar open-world game","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21323144/ghost-of-tsushima-review-ps4-game-developer-samurai"},{"title":"An ode to Ghost of Tsushima’s katana ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21327396/ghost-of-tsushima-katana-weapon-gameplay-impressions-ps4"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559264/ghost-of-tsushima-directors-cut-sony-ps4-ps5-sucker-punch-iki-island"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559264/ghost-of-tsushima-directors-cut-sony-ps4-ps5-sucker-punch-iki-island</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T12:50:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T12:50:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter, TikTok, Google, and Facebook promise to boost protections for women online</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Tik Tok Application: Illustration" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xXUHYCjOFyMEHm36EC_CdU00yzs=/0x0:4895x3263/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69529871/1058608390.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chesnot/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3h5nvg"&gt;At the UN Generation Equality Forum in Paris on Thursday Twitter, TikTok, Google, and Facebook committed to tackling online abuse and improving safety for women on their platforms. The pledge came following &lt;a href="https://ogbv.webfoundation.org/"&gt;consultations with the World Wide Web Foundation&lt;/a&gt; (WWWF) over the past year, aimed at examining online gender-based violence and abuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BTuNyK"&gt;The WWWF said the consultations showed women want more control over who could reply or comment on their social media posts and more choice around what they see online, where, and when. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bM0y76"&gt;According to the WWWF, the companies have pledged to “build better ways for women to curate their safety online” by offering more granular settings, such as who can see, share, or comment on posts; more simple and accessible language; easier navigation and access to safety tools, and by “reducing the burden on women by proactively reducing the amount of abuse they see.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BOuKIt"&gt;The way that last part is worded is a bit frustrating; it addresses the aftermath or the location of abuse, but not the person / people &lt;em&gt;committing&lt;/em&gt; the abuse. And just because the women aren’t &lt;em&gt;seeing&lt;/em&gt; the abuse on social media, doesn’t mean the abuse has gone away. The platforms certainly bear some responsibility to make their online spaces safer, but until they get more proactive and less reactive, and go after the abusers, the onus will continue to fall on women and marginalized groups to report abuse and convince a social media platform that it’s worthwhile for them to address. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="24r1YY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The pledge includes the platforms improving their systems to report abuse&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ctmDnI"&gt;In addition to the “better curation” checklist, as part of the pledge, the companies will put in place improvements to their reporting systems by offering users the ability to track and manage their reports, and establish additional ways for women to get help and support when they report abuse. They’ll also enable “greater capacity to address context and/or language,” which may allow for more subtle forms of verbal abuse or threats to be incorporated into enforcement measures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z9zly1"&gt;These all sound like excellent goals, but the release from the WWWF didn’t include any specifics about how each platform plans to achieve them. Nor did the companies themselves offer any comment as part of the news release, so we’ve reached out to all four for comment. Vijaya Gadde, head of legal, public policy, and trust &amp;amp; safety at Twitter said in an emailed statement that keeping everyone who uses Twitter safe and free from abuse is its top priority. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P2aoPT"&gt;“While we have made recent strides in giving people greater control to manage their safety, we know there is still much work to be done,” Gadde wrote, noting that women and underrepresented communities are disproportionately affected by abuse (which is pretty well known at this point). Gadde said abusive behavior “has no place on our service. It hurts those who are targeted and is detrimental to the health of the conversation and the role Twitter plays in the expression and exchange of ideas where people — no matter their views or perspectives — can be heard.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SWSeWR"&gt;Facebook’s global head of safety Antigone Davis said in an email that the company was looking forward to working with other tech companies to make the internet safer for women. “To keep women safe from abuse, exploitation, and harassment online and offline, we regularly update our policies, tools, and technology in consultation with experts around the world—including with over 200 women’s safety organizations,” Davis said in the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JcmTsl"&gt;Tara Wadhwa, director of policy for TikTok US, &lt;a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-us/promoting-online-safety-for-women"&gt;wrote a blog post &lt;/a&gt;outlining the company’s plans. “Over the coming months, we’ll begin to develop and test a number of potential product changes to our platform that address these priorities and help make TikTok an ever safer place for women,” Wadhwa wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FRMY1B"&gt;Google didn’t immediately reply to a request for comment Thursday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AIWmgG"&gt;At this point, there doesn’t appear to be anything binding the companies to these “commitments” other than the prospect of public shaming if they fail to deliver. And unfortunately, that tends to be the best way to get social media platforms to respond to users’ problems.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I9o9ks"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559115/twitter-tiktok-google-facebook-protect-women-abuse"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559115/twitter-tiktok-google-facebook-protect-women-abuse</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T12:23:12-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T12:23:12-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google investigates why a carrier linked VPN ads to an SMS two-factor code</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An illustration of a letter envelope with a target over it with pixels floating around both." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qHXTx8FoTTBZ4IwZTQGqHQ7X_z8=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69529651/VRG_4614_3_EmailTracking.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Maria Chimishkyan&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6LHgvf"&gt;Earlier this week, Australian developer Chris Lacy tweeted about a curious experience while logging into a rarely used Google account. When Google texted his two-factor authentication code, the message popped up along with an ad including a link for VPN services. Considering the downsides of phishing or malware distribution attached to a code that’s specifically intended to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22465512/cybersecurity-online-security-privacy-breaches"&gt;keep your account secure&lt;/a&gt;, this didn’t go over well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="yLns0c"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to set up two-factor authentication on your online accounts","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22215571/factor-authentication-2fa-apple-microsoft-google-how-to"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="UrZprx"&gt;While Lacy did not name the carrier who delivered the text, Google Identity and Security senior director Mark Risher &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mrisher/status/1410017611018952704?s=21"&gt;clarified&lt;/a&gt; that the ad didn’t come from his company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OfEioX"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“These are not our ads and we are currently working with the wireless carrier to understand why this happened.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5iXZAJ"&gt;Google’s official statement on the matter is that “These are not our ads and we are currently working with the wireless carrier to understand why this happened.” The Messages app on Android didn’t display a preview, flagging it as possible spam, but it’s a less than ideal implementation of two-factor authentication. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RwTA9j"&gt;&lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/06/29/google-verification-code-sms-ad/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; points out that at least in some countries, Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/12/21012601/google-messages-spam-detection-verified-sms-features"&gt;uses Verified SMS&lt;/a&gt; to authenticate and secure messages, but it’s not clear if that would be possible here. I’ve never seen any spam attached to verification on texts, but until RCS and end-to-end encryption are widespread, it’s just one more reason to opt for code generators, hardware keys, or push notifications for login security instead of a text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="pj2BXT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to use a two-factor security key","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22458935/two-factor-security-key-how-to-yubico"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/2021/7/1/22558989/google-2fa-text-sms-spam-vpn-security-phishing"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tech/2021/7/1/22558989/google-2fa-text-sms-spam-vpn-security-phishing</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-01T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google TV rolls out new Watch With Me series for celeb-curated streaming</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nYZOJbT0gFUKB0idwykUSRprMxA=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69529501/Laverne_Cox_Google_TV_UI.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google TV&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="g1QBAY"&gt;Evidently acknowledging our collective content fatigue, Google TV has announced a new celebrity-curated Watch With Me series that should make finding something to binge a little less painful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z6gOXg"&gt;Google &lt;a href="https://www.blog.google/products/google-tv/watchwithme-lavernecox"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that the &lt;a href="https://goo.gle/3gRFjFe"&gt;Watch With Me&lt;/a&gt; series will spotlight series and movies loved by entertainers and artists. In addition to Watch With Me showcasing celebrities’ favorite flicks, the series will feature interviews with those curators about why they hand-selected a specific title to be featured. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="KA3PlW"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Celebrities and artists will handpick their favorite titles to help you find something to watch&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="p3Vutr"&gt;Google TV’s algorithm is fairly good at surfacing relevant titles, but the idea is to allow these hosts to guide users specifically through a collection of movies that inspired them. The hub is yet another place to find something good to watch, and the added contextualization of each film may help introduce users to a title they may have missed on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vp3EkH"&gt;Google TV isn’t the first to spotlight titles with celebrity-curated hubs. HBO Max uses the format to spotlight favorites from featured personalities like Gal Gadot and Zack Snyder, and YouTube has &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jimmyfallon/status/995059982893797376"&gt;similarly experimented&lt;/a&gt; with the format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3mDaKM"&gt;Google TV’s new series will kick off with a collection selected by actress Laverne Cox, who chose titles like &lt;em&gt;Moonlight&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Color Purple&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Pretty in Pink&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Matrix&lt;/em&gt;, among other groundbreaking films. Google says users will be seeing the watchlist “over the next few days,” and when you have it, it can be found in the For You section of the platform. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22558282/google-tv-watch-with-me-series"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22558282/google-tv-watch-with-me-series</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
