<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-05-13T14:04:34-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-13T14:04:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-13T14:04:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>Friends reunion will premiere on HBO Max May 27th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P-tsi_DZNQoYH6QKPw_vOIwMayA=/289x0:2592x1535/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69282093/Screen_Shot_2021_05_13_at_10.35.19_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: HBO&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KoUMMt"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Friends&lt;/em&gt; reunion special finally has a release date: Thursday, May 27th. The episode was was meant to launch with HBO Max in May 2020 but was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/18/21186045/friends-reunion-special-delayed-hbo-max-streaming-coronavirus-pandemic"&gt;delayed due to the pandemic&lt;/a&gt;. It will feature all six original cast members, as well as guest stars like Malala Yousafzai, Lady Gaga, and BTS, &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-news/friends-reunion-trailer-hbo-1234952671/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;The Hollywood Reporter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UVG68z"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Friends&lt;/em&gt; was previously available on Netflix, but HBO bought the streaming rights for &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/live-feed/friends-officially-leaving-netflix-warnermedias-streaming-service-1223151"&gt;an eye-watering $425 million&lt;/a&gt;. HBO Max seems to be trying to set itself up as the streaming service for ’90s nostalgia. It’s also hosted a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/15/21566042/trailers-fresh-prince-breach-black-beauty-happiest-season-pixar-netflix-hulu-hbo-disney"&gt;reunion for &lt;em&gt;The Fresh Prince of Bel-Air&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and is the streaming home of both that show, &lt;em&gt;Friends&lt;/em&gt;, and movies like &lt;em&gt;The Matrix &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Pulp Fiction&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dLvCPs"&gt;HBO has even released a teaser for the &lt;em&gt;Friends&lt;/em&gt; reunion, which certainly teases by showing almost nothing (though it gets at least some cleverness points for its inclusion of “The one where they get back together”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6gk21s"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MedRN92V6lE?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NP8cC2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22434515/friends-reunion-episode-streaming-date-hbo-max"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22434515/friends-reunion-episode-streaming-date-hbo-max</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-13T13:40:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-13T13:40:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>Xbox is testing accessible chat options like transcription and speech synthesis</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/v-Zsx2XnnirSRXerDoLY-BZofG4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69281910/acastro_190530_1777_xbox_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Desl66"&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2021/05/12/introducing-party-chat-speech-transcription-and-synthesis/"&gt;Microsoft has announced&lt;/a&gt; new text-to-speech and speech-to-text features for Xbox Party Chat, which aim to help make communication on the platform more accessible. The features are currently being tested through the Xbox Insider program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dIW5x7"&gt;The speech-to-text feature puts a window on the screen with automatic transcriptions of what people in the voice chat are saying, along with an indicator of whether the message was typed or spoken aloud. This could help people who are hard of hearing to participate in the chat, even if the other participants are speaking instead of typing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6fdinfxdUGWBBKR5dWYqTwWeXJk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22512069/image_1_1.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The window in the top right shows transcribed text from voice chat.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5JLNYa"&gt;The text-to-speech feature goes the other way, reading out a user’s typed messages for the rest of the party chat members to hear. The user is also able to choose from a list of voices to better customize what their messages sound like to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oP02ed"&gt;Microsoft has recently been pushing accessibility with Xbox: it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22286216/microsoft-xbox-games-tested-accessibility-guidelines"&gt;started a program earlier this year&lt;/a&gt; to help developers make their games more accessible, and it has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/31/21117342/xbox-adaptive-controller-freedom-wing-adaptor-wheelchair-joystick"&gt;made the Xbox Adaptive Controller&lt;/a&gt; to help gamers with a wide range of motor abilities. It’s good to see them continuing that work, especially around voice chat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d3TT7G"&gt;If you’re an Xbox Insider, you can enable the features by going to Settings &amp;gt; Ease of Access &amp;gt; Game and chat transcription, or by going to Options &amp;gt; Ease of Access settings while in a chat.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22434389/xbox-accessible-party-chat-test-speech-synthesis-transcription"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22434389/xbox-accessible-party-chat-test-speech-synthesis-transcription</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-13T13:33:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-13T13:33:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>Preorders for the modular Framework Laptop are now open, starting at $999</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A Framework Laptop angled slightly to the right, seen from above. The screen displays mountains and a valley. On either side are a number of modules." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fNtB0J1yE83m0E-XNMAyEI6T-Zo=/0x0:6000x4000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69281854/studio_image_01.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Framework&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jY13pv"&gt;The modular Framework Laptop is now available for preorders, with prices starting at $999 for a fully assembled computer or $749 for the DIY Edition, which adds the option of paying less upfront if you’re willing bring your own RAM, SSD, charge, and Wi-Fi card. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OaJv9E"&gt;For prebuilt systems, Framework is offering three starting configurations. There’s the entry level, $999 Base, which offers a Core i5-1135G7 processor, 8GB of RAM, a 256GB NVMe SSD, and Wi-Fi 6. The Performance model, starting at $1,399, ups the processor to a Core i7-1165G7 and doubles the RAM and SSD storage. And the Professional configuration, starting at $1,999, has a Core i7-1185G7, 32GB of RAM, 1TB of storage, and Windows 10 Pro. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h1Sh97"&gt;Whether fully prebuilt or DIY, the Framework features a 13.5-inch 2256 x 1504 screen, a 1080p 60fps webcam, a 55Wh battery, and a 2.87-pound aluminum chassis. Ports are handled through a customizable expansion card system, which allows users to select up to four from a selection of USB-C, USB-A, HDMI, DisplayPort, and microSD slots. There’s also the option to add extra storage through removable USB-C SSDs, too, and Framework promises more port options in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ot9ovvJ26VTz3z89BbaizbFfLao=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22512128/766f6b5c_5af2_4e2c_a60b_72849c79afe3_Blog21011___Pre_Orders_Open___img02.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="RVi01U"&gt;To preorder, Framework is only asking that users put down a $100 deposit, with the first laptops set to ship at the end of July. Preorders are only available in the US for now; Canada is promised in “the next few weeks,” and European and Asian availability is set for later this year. Additionally, Framework warns that due to the ongoing global supply shortages, it’ll have limited supply at launch but plans to do its preorders in batches that should ship throughout the year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RP64DU"&gt;Framework is obviously a new company with an untested platform here. It is offering a 30-day return guarantee and a one-year limited warranty, though, which might help anyone deciding whether to plunk down the cash for a new computer.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22434359/framework-laptop-modular-preorders-available-price-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22434359/framework-laptop-modular-preorders-available-price-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-13T13:09:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-13T13:09:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>Colonial Pipeline reportedly paid the hackers nearly $5 million, despite suggestions to contrary</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-IT-OIL-CRIME-HACKING-PIPELINE-EPA" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8Os-FKeD7_0TWUtTJfUq9k0PQWk=/12x0:6048x4024/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69281586/1232843570.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by JIM WATSON/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QWrpNV"&gt;After &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/10/22429433/colonial-pipeline-cyber-security-ransomware-attack"&gt;a devastating and deeply embarrassing cyberattack&lt;/a&gt; on one of the United States’ largest oil pipelines, one that forced many gas stations to shut down and reportedly caused average national gas prices to &lt;a href="https://wlos.com/news/local/78-of-gas-stations-without-fuel-in-region-gas-prices-rise-above-3-nationally"&gt;rise above $3 for the first time since 2014&lt;/a&gt;, the oil is flowing again. But &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-13/colonial-pipeline-paid-hackers-nearly-5-million-in-ransom?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;is reporting&lt;/a&gt; that Colonial Pipeline had to pay a nearly $5 million ransom to get there, and it paid that ransom within mere hours. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5qIOkB"&gt;That’s striking, because it’s the opposite of what &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/colonial-pipeline-has-no-plan-pay-ransom-hackers-sources-2021-05-12/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/05/12/politics/colonial-pipeline-ransomware-payment/index.html"&gt;CNN&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and others reported in the wake of the attack. “Sources familiar with the company’s response,” a phrase often used when a company doesn’t want to be named, suggested the company had no plans to pay hackers. CNN’s sources insisted Colonial Pipeline had not yet paid the ransom, and would probably not &lt;em&gt;need &lt;/em&gt;to pay, suggesting it had already “managed to retrieve the most important data that was stolen” with help from the US government. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="44pPXX"&gt;It’s also a little worrying because of how a successful ransom might encourage hackers in future. Over the years, we’ve heard reports of smaller companies and local government entities paying ransoms to regain access to their computers, but this is perhaps one of the most high-profile examples of ransomware yet, and the news might inspire copycats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IfyjIM"&gt;On the plus side, a digital forensics expert who spoke to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; suggested that $5 million isn’t a particularly large sum of money for something like this: “Ransom is usually around $25 million to $35 million for such a company. I think the threat actor realized they stepped on the wrong company and triggered a massive government response,” LIFARS CEO Ondrej Krehel told the publication. On Monday, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/10/22428996/colonial-pipeline-ransomware-attack-apology-investigation"&gt;the Colonial Pipeline hackers apologized for the “social consequences”&lt;/a&gt; and promised to ransom less controversial targets in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TandVF"&gt;It’s not clear which parts of the Colonial Pipeline were at risk: a spokesperson suggested there was no evidence the company’s operational systems were compromised; CNN&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;had three sources yesterday say that the pipeline shut down because its billing system was affected, and the company wasn’t sure it’d be able to charge properly for fuel. &lt;a href="https://zetter.substack.com/p/ransomware-infection-on-colonial"&gt;Reporting by cybersecurity journalist Kim Zetter&lt;/a&gt; suggests the decision was likely more complicated than that, as other entities in the oil distribution system were also worried the ransomware could spread to their computers as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4HOLaz"&gt;Yesterday, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/12/22433266/biden-executive-order-cybersecurity-government-infrastructure-colonial-pipeline-solarwinds-hafnium"&gt;President Biden signed an executive order aimed at improving national cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt;, with the White House specifically naming the Colonial Pipeline, the SolarWinds hack, and the Microsoft Exchange server vulnerabilities as the kinds of infrastructure failures the government hopes to address.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nW8iLmOH2HqYJ6T5xWQTPBEdWrQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22512044/colonial_pipeline_restart.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="eb28XF"&gt;The Colonial Pipeline &lt;a href="https://www.colpipe.com/news/press-releases/media-statement-colonial-pipeline-system-disruption"&gt;began resuming operations on Wednesday evening&lt;/a&gt;, with President Biden saying it should be “reaching full operational capacity as we speak” in a briefing early Thursday afternoon. Oil supplies should be “seeing a region-by-region return to normalcy beginning this weekend,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mw2ZMw"&gt;Still, he warns, “this is not like flicking on a light switch — this pipeline is 500,000 miles long, it had never been shut down in its history... it’s going to take some time, and there may be some hiccups along the way here.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GIbIDo"&gt;Biden says the US isn’t blaming Russia directly: “We do not believe the Russian government was involved in this attack, but we do have strong reason to believe that the criminals who did the attack are living in Russia,” he says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HOEDHL"&gt;He also announced a specific measure against ransomware: “Our Justice Department has launched a new task force dedicated to prosecuting ransomware hackers to the full extent of the law.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8PS2O8"&gt;President Biden declined to comment on whether Colonial Pipeline paid the ransom. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LPY3QS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TWyZJ9"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22434381/colonial-pipeline-darkside-hacker-ransomware-ransom-oil"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22434381/colonial-pipeline-darkside-hacker-ransomware-ransom-oil</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-13T13:02:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-13T13:02:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>A podcast app is exposing subscribers-only shows</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HeubL6mLdU4_TFdLspnUu8PqSwY=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69281526/VRG_ILLO_4584_Castbox.0.gif" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Grayson Blackmon / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The beauty and misery of private RSS feeds&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="XSQEuV"&gt;There’s only supposed to be one way to hear exclusive podcast content from sports host Scott Wetzel: by paying $5 a month to subscribe to his Patreon. But the show’s also been available on a smaller podcasting app for free. In fact, leaked podcast feeds from dozens of subscription-only shows, including Wetzel’s and &lt;em&gt;The Last Podcast On The Left&lt;/em&gt;, are available to stream through Castbox, a smaller app for both iOS and Android, just by searching for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KqXOUl"&gt;Two people in the podcast space tell me they’ve reached out to Castbox multiple times, only for the company to remove a show and then have it pop up again, an infuriating cycle for someone trying to charge for their content. “It’s a little bit like playing whack-a-mole with them,” says one source, who asked to remain anonymous because of their ongoing work in the space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KpN9ym"&gt;Podcast subscriptions have existed for years, but they’ve gained wider attention this past month. Apple, which makes the dominant podcasting app, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22381980/apple-podcasts-app-subscriptions-new-design"&gt;introduced&lt;/a&gt; in-app subscriptions with a button that lets people directly subscribe to a show from the app. Spotify &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22404273/spotify-podcast-subscriptions-monetize-subscriber-shows"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; its own subscription product, too, but with caveats — the main one being there’s no actual in-app button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="mRk9QZ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Multiple private RSS feeds are publicly available through Castbox&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BohG0I"&gt;Prior to both of these proprietary solutions, the podcasting world’s subscription products mostly centered on private RSS feeds, or links typically assigned to individual listeners that allow them to access shows. The links can be pasted into any supporting podcast app, like Apple Podcasts, Overcast, and Pocket Casts, and for the most part, the system’s worked. Podcasting remains a mostly open ecosystem, and although this content is paywalled, shows still benefit from seamless RSS distribution. Notably, podcasters don’t have to manage multiple backends across services and can publish all their subscribers’ content at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fsXSc4"&gt;But private feeds still have a glaring downside: these links can be easily shared, and anyone with the link can access private content. Piracy might become a growing concern, too, as the industry looks toward subscription and exclusive models. Already we’ve seen &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/14/21436713/anchor-copycat-podcasts-mike-mignano-spotify-upload"&gt;pirated shows on Anchor&lt;/a&gt;, and re-uploads of the Spotify-exclusive &lt;em&gt;The Joe Rogan Experience&lt;/em&gt; on Castbox, as well. Although Castbox is small enough that the leaks likely aren’t on most podcasters’ radars, they still illustrate the problems one weak link in the distribution chain can create.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LBFbTT"&gt;“This is the beauty and the mess of the open system — the web is amazing and allows us to publish content everywhere, but restricting access to content is always going to be tricky,” says Justin Jackson, co-founder of podcast hosting service Transistor.fm. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uwSDmO"&gt;He adds that, inevitably, people will find ways to subvert the system, whether that’s recording audio and distributing it on their own or sharing their private feed links among friends. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="lSFvOS"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Much of the podcast subscription industry is built around private RSS feeds, but a link can be shared&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aOstzF"&gt;To prevent situations like this, software has been touted as a possible solution. Slate’s Supporting Cast — which powers multiple membership-oriented shows, including Slate’s own Slate Plus network — monitors private RSS feeds for suspicious activity, like thousands of downloads on what’s supposed to be someone’s single-person feed. The software also monitors the IP addresses where someone is listening and the podcast app they’re using to see if anything seems out of the ordinary. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8mVfmW"&gt;So far, the issue hasn’t become a huge problem. Supporting Cast CEO David Stern says the team has only had to take action fewer than 100 times in the year and a half that the automated monitoring has been active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nirVRY"&gt;“You could always share a username and password to Hulu or Netflix, and that’s sort of okay. The companies let you get away with that,” Stern says. “You’ve got to strike a balance. We’re not talking about national security secrets here.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hyvHdv"&gt;The software-side workarounds can be effective — especially considering RSS, the backbone upon which the podcast industry was built, doesn’t allow for many technical improvements. However, it’s an investment that not every company might want to make. So the broader solution for locking down private feeds is simpler: tags, or literal snippets of text, that are part of a podcast feed’s metadata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="RXxMKo"&gt;&lt;q&gt;When software solutions fail, tags should help&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DgTRq7"&gt;Multiple distribution companies and hosting platforms now &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/podcast-publishers/answer/9747492?hl=en"&gt;verify the owners of RSS feeds&lt;/a&gt; through tags. These tags list an owner’s email address, which the platforms then use to verify the person uploading the feed, thereby preventing people from trying to pass an already established show off as their own. Feeds can also be “locked,” a separate tag that, if respected, stops platforms from importing a show. A third and final tag, which is particularly relevant to private RSS feeds, instructs podcast apps not to index a particular show. Google Podcasts, as an example, scours the web to index shows and include them in the app, similarly to how its search engine populates results. If this tag is placed in an RSS feed, as it likely would be for a private feed, the app won’t index it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rMPCKe"&gt;“What most platforms are doing is making it as difficult as they can for people to pirate podcast feeds – for people to submit podcast feeds to the directories — but still, at the same time, trying to make it easy for folks [who listen],” Jackson says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xTQxiE"&gt;The catch with tags, though, is they’re only as good as the platforms allow them to be. You might tell a platform not to index a program, but it doesn’t have to obey that request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7BZDJo"&gt;Jackson posits that this appears to be happening in Castbox’s case. These RSS feeds likely aren’t being verified when they’re submitted and, if a feed’s metadata requests that it not be indexed, Castbox isn’t heeding that ask. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qjl2Xl"&gt;None of these feeds appear to have been uploaded maliciously to Castbox and most have a small number of plays — the damage is minimal. I reached out to the owner of the private RSS for Wetzel’s podcast, and he confirmed that he only meant to listen to this podcast on his own, not to make it public. He “didn’t give it any thought” that the show would become public when he added the RSS feed to listen on Castbox. (&lt;em&gt;The Joe Rogan Experience&lt;/em&gt; copycat, however, has more than 400,000 plays and over 14,000 subscribers.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pL1950"&gt;It’s unclear what’s happening on Castbox’s end. The company says it supports private RSS feeds, but presumably doing so wouldn’t mean making them public. Verifying a feed should also prevent it from going public, as should some of these tags. We’ve reached out to Castbox to confirm the details, but seemingly, the industry’s safeguards failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="7FztU0"&gt;Podcasters and app developers clearly see paid memberships as part of the industry’s future, but the risks of private RSS feeds could compromise the industry’s headway. It might even give Spotify and Apple a leg up on competitors that have built entire businesses around locking down the open technology. But even a proprietary solution can’t prevent piracy entirely, and for podcasters, they’ll likely have to accept some risk and rely on the good faith of the podcasting players themselves to keep their shows from going wide.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22433143/castbox-private-rss-feeds-tags-patreon"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22433143/castbox-private-rss-feeds-tags-patreon</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-13T12:57:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-13T12:57:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>Xbox is partnering with the studio behind the world’s biggest mobile games</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pQ4t5F8Px6hufNCA7SW4dzjy_kM=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69281464/gamescom_2014_halo_2_anniversary_sanctuary_faceoff_962e37887e26434c93ee8f859f2b8641_8f8f59dd34bb4cb184ec3f3d03fb0960.5.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: 343 Industries&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="L6SdX4"&gt;Microsoft’s Xbox Game Studios is teaming up with Tencent’s TiMi Studios, developer of the wildly successful mobile hits &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Mobile &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Honor of Kings&lt;/em&gt;. According to a Google Translated version of &lt;a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s?__biz=MzA4ODA2MjM5Nw==&amp;amp;mid=2656159665&amp;amp;idx=1&amp;amp;sn=7b156d011bbf8ac94212a7383a974175&amp;amp;chksm=8b8a8763bcfd0e757b4b3a0b8eb259f3643ace2de77cf350cbc19aeb204ba78a821311d338be&amp;amp;scene=132#wechat_redirect"&gt;the announcement from TiMi&lt;/a&gt;, the two companies have formed a “strategic partnership” to create “game content,” but it’s unclear exactly what that might mean or when we might be able to play anything resulting from the cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N631Dr"&gt;TiMi Studios is no stranger to adapting hit franchises to mobile: &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Mobile&lt;/em&gt; just crossed &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/timistudios/status/1389760380566601728"&gt;500 million downloads worldwide&lt;/a&gt; and the studio is also the developer of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/24/21301541/pokemon-unite-team-game-strategy-tencent-nintendo-switch"&gt;upcoming mobile strategy game &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Unite&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps Microsoft wants to bring some of its biggest titles to mobile platforms in some way. (Not counting &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22391561/microsoft-xcloud-ios-pc-xbox-game-streaming-beta-features"&gt;streaming games over xCloud&lt;/a&gt;, of course.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o29n2h"&gt;TiMi Studios may very well be the world’s largest developer, having reportedly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/4/22367089/tencent-timi-studios-call-of-duty-mobile-10-billion-2020"&gt;earned $10 billion in revenue in 2020&lt;/a&gt;. Its biggest title, the China-only &lt;em&gt;Honor of Kings&lt;/em&gt;, had an eye-popping 100 million &lt;em&gt;daily&lt;/em&gt; active users as of November, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-tencent-videogames-honorofkings/tencents-honor-of-kings-reports-100-million-daily-users-expands-into-new-genres-idUSKBN27H1HX"&gt;according to Tencent&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Dt4REO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Tencent-owned studio behind Call of Duty: Mobile reportedly earned $10 billion in 2020","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/4/22367089/tencent-timi-studios-call-of-duty-mobile-10-billion-2020"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22434272/xbox-tencent-timi-studios-strategic-partnership-mobile"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22434272/xbox-tencent-timi-studios-strategic-partnership-mobile</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-13T12:28:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-13T12:28:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>Enola Holmes is getting a sequel on Netflix</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Enola Holmes" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7HnPUFPZchWSxwj_-N4XSXTKyL0=/0x0:8256x5504/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69281291/EH_02421_R.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Alex Bailey/Legendary&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JfX7Ns"&gt;Sherlock’s kid sister is making a return. Today, Netflix announced &lt;em&gt;Enola Holmes 2&lt;/em&gt;, a sequel to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/25/21455049/enola-holmes-review-millie-bobby-brown-henry-cavill-netflix"&gt;last year’s crime caper&lt;/a&gt; that took the Sherlock story in a slightly younger direction, focusing on the famous detective’s teenage sister.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="00a2RU"&gt;We don’t have many details about the new movie just yet — such as what it’ll be about or when it’s hitting the streaming service — but at the very least, many of the key figures are returning. That means Millie Bobby Brown and Henry Cavill will reprise their roles as Enola and Sherlock, respectively, and that director Harry Bradbeer and writer Jack Thorne are also on board again. The new movie will be produced by Legendary “in partnership with Netflix.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="cW3Vxl"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;The sequel is afoot!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The adventure continues as Millie Bobby Brown &amp;amp; Henry Cavill return to the world of ENOLA HOLMES, reteaming with director Harry Bradbeer &amp;amp; writer Jack Thorne on a second film based on Nancy Springer’s book series about Sherlock Holmes’ brilliant sister.   &lt;a href="https://t.co/7tsr1fbej2"&gt;pic.twitter.com/7tsr1fbej2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— NetflixFilm (@NetflixFilm) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NetflixFilm/status/1392872309497737222?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 13, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="A78FtQ"&gt;The movies are based on a series of young adult novels by Nancy Springer. And the first film also holds the distinction of forcing a lawsuit, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/25/21302942/netflix-enola-holmes-sherlock-arthur-conan-doyle-estate-lawsuit-copyright-infringement"&gt;after the estate of Sir Arthur Conan Doyle sued Netflix for giving Sherlock too many feelings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22434366/enola-holmes-2-sequel-netflix-millie-bobby-brown-henry-cavill"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22434366/enola-holmes-2-sequel-netflix-millie-bobby-brown-henry-cavill</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-13T11:38:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-13T11:38:44-04:00</updated>
    <title>The best deals on 4K TVs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rmtJvuBPnkpZu39fUo0GC39vOAg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69151213/jbareham_170613_1754_0016_main_04.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;TCL 6-series Roku TV | Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vtXpJr"&gt;There are a lot of 4K TVs available to choose from, complete with a wide variety of prices and performance. But even if your budget is less than $500, you can get a good 4K TV in a bigger size than you might expect. Whether you want a secondary TV for a bedroom or a high-end OLED for next-gen gaming, we’ve picked out the best TV deals across four common categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="zUfn7z"&gt;Best 4K TV deals for most people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="sFCZyo"&gt;Best budget 4K TVs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3C0Il4"&gt;Best OLED TVs &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jVQclk"&gt;Best 4K TVs for the PS5 and Xbox Series X&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="d2lRkA"&gt;We will provide regular updates to this post so be sure to check back periodically for the most up-to-date info on the deals available. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="f9MF2Z"&gt;The best 4K TV deals for most people&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="mszLRr"&gt;A 55-inch TV is the most popular size available now. It is not too big, nor is it too small, making it a safe size if you’re looking to upgrade the TV in a living room or bedroom. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6NyQnT"&gt;Vizio’s M-series 4K TVs have QLED panels, making the lineup one of the better options for color contrast and accuracy. They include four HDMI 2.0 ports, which makes it easy to hook up a variety of set-top boxes or gaming consoles at the same time. This TV is available in four sizes (50, 55, 65, and 70 inches). Sam’s Club is currently offering the 55-inch model at a discount, but only with a valid membership. The 55-inch model is &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=38733&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.samsclub.com%2Fp%2F55-4k-hdr-smart-tv-m-series%2Fprod24922142%3Fpid%3Dps_acq_Google_PLA_12454823946%26wl0%3D%26wl1%3Dg%26wl2%3Dc%26wl3%3D501964891149%26wl4%3Dpla-1039532178666%26wl5%3D9061079%26wl6%3D%26wl7%3D%26wl9%3Dpla%26wl10%3D1247713%26wl11%3Donline%26wl12%3D%257Bproductid%257D%26wl13%3D%26wl15%3D122079216841%26wl16%3D%26wl17%3D%26wl18%3D%26wl19%3D%26wl20%3DCjwKCAjw-e2EBhAhEiwAJI5jg_04sS80MuYwe-hwlKiK4e18tcM-tbpozYnXmb-tNyWmP1xRGkJd6BoCuTgQAvD_BwE%26wl23%3D1039532178666%26gclid%3DCjwKCAjw-e2EBhAhEiwAJI5jg_04sS80MuYwe-hwlKiK4e18tcM-tbpozYnXmb-tNyWmP1xRGkJd6BoCuTgQAvD_BwE" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available for $439 ($40 off)&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="X3LwO3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10255489"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JbaBai"&gt;The TCL 6-Series R635 model is a good option if you are looking to balance price and performance. The R635 also includes &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/11/21363318/tcl-2020-5-6-series-4k-tvs-qled-mini-led-backlighting-gaming-ps5-xbox-series-x"&gt;Mini-LED backlighting&lt;/a&gt;, which brings better brightness and contrast while in use. The 55-inch model is available for $798 at &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FTCL-55-6-Series-4K-UHD-Dolby-Vision-HDR-QLED-Roku-Smart-TV-55R635%2F796005169&amp;amp;subid1=BestTVDealsDeals04122021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; and $799 at &lt;a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Ftcl-55-class-6-series-4k-uhd-mini-led-qled-dolby-vision-hdr-roku-smart-tv-55r635%2F6424672.p%3FskuId%3D6424672&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; right now. You can also get it in 65- or 75-inch sizes if you want something bigger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="y8BpYm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10327662"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MPfLVC"&gt;Samsung’s Crystal TU-8000 series line of TVs offers many features, such as multiple screen mirroring. Currently, the TU-8000 is available in a wide variety of sizes, ranging from 43 all the way to 85 inches. Right now, the 55-inch model is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-55-Inch-Crystal-TU-8000-Built/dp/B084JH43DJ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$548 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9SocSo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10444776"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="EYhbja"&gt;The best TV deals on a budget&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="zWYgij"&gt;You don’t have to spend a lot for a 4K TV: $500 or less can still get good image quality. This includes Toshiba’s 50-inch Smart Fire TV Edition 4K LED, which normally retails for $380. As the name implies, it offers the option to stream content on services like Disney Plus or Netflix and includes the option to watch live TV. You can get a &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1737687233984981481#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;50-inch model for $350 at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/All-New-Toshiba-50LF621U21-50-inch-Vision/dp/B086VR2KY8?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, or step up to the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1737687411898346509#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;55-inch model&lt;/a&gt; for just $50 more at Best Buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="cW4VPC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10444802"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="74eOSC"&gt;TCL also has competitively priced televisions, and its 4-series line is one of the more affordable options on the market. The S435 model features a built-in Roku interface, dual-band Wi-Fi, HDR10, and support for Alexa, Google Assistant, and Siri voice assistants. You can get the 43-inch model for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/TCL-4K-Smart-LED-43S435/dp/B08DHDS4T3?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$288 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Ftcl-43-34-class-4-series-4k-uhd-hdr-smart-roku-tv-8211-43s435%2F-%2FA-52177069&amp;amp;subid1=Best4KTVDeals4192021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$289 at Target&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="HtnMEi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9740197"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="I7fy7f"&gt;Hisense’s H6510 model is a good option if you want to buy a 4K LED TV at a competitive price. A Best Buy exclusive, the H6510 includes Android TV software built in and has three HDMI ports. It comes in three additional sizes (65, 75, and 85 inches). Right now, you can get the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1737592810150199993#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;55-inch model for $380 ($20 off its regular price)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ffRx8b"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10265690"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="qm44jO"&gt;The best deals on OLED TVs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="vbJRlM"&gt;OLED televisions offer the best image quality in a mainstream TV. LG’s BX line supports HDMI 2.1, meaning this TV is perfect for people looking to take advantage of the PS5 or Xbox Series X. You can get it in either the 55- or 65-inch sizes and save up to $200 on it, depending on the size. The popular &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/LG-OLED55BXPUA-Alexa-Built-Ultra/dp/B0829RXYSN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;55-inch model is currently $1,297 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OMVgrF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9733758"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JvNG4d"&gt;Sony’s A8H OLED TV has sterling picture quality and contrast, and it runs Google’s Android TV software. It comes in two sizes, 55 and 65 inches, and the starting price is $1,900. But you can get the 55-inch model for as low as &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-A8H-55-Inch-Compatibility/dp/B084KQFNBX?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$1,498 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1545415-REG%2Fsony_xbr55a8h_a8h_55_class_hdr.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;. The 65-inch is also on sale for &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1545413-REG%2Fsony_xbr65a8h_a8h_65_class_hdr.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22371561%2Fbest-4k-tv-deals-sale-lg-samsung-sony-tcl" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$2,298 at B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;, about $200 off its usual $2,500 price tag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OvRhzP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9733790"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MB8PX4"&gt;Despite the high price tag, LG’s Gallery Series GX OLED is a good TV for those looking for a more cinematic experience. It includes support for Google Assistant and Alexa, and for those who want to use their TV for gaming, it features Nvidia G-Sync and HDMI 2.1 support, meaning it can take full advantage of the RTX 30-series cards or Sony’s and Microsoft’s next-gen gaming consoles. Right now, you can get the 55-inch for as low as &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B086TSW95T?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$1,797 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FLG-GX-55-inch-Class-with-Gallery-Design-4K-Smart-OLED-TV-w-AI-ThinQ-54-6-Diag-OLED55GXPUA%2F152371849%3Firgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_33DRwsUfoxyLULpwUx0Mo387UkESb%253AWnWQ-N3A0%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_1943169%26clickid%3D33DRwsUfoxyLULpwUx0Mo387UkESb%253AWnWQ-N3A0%26sharedid%3D%26affiliates_ad_id%3D565706%26campaign_id%3D9383&amp;amp;subid1=BestTVDeals04142021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;. There are also 65- and 70-inch models available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lpiA85"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10445785"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="O5Vjam"&gt;4K TVs for the Sony PS5 and Microsoft Xbox Series X &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="OxIzpR"&gt;Sony’s PS5 and Microsoft’s Xbox Series X can play 4K games with HDR at up to 120 frames per second. So naturally, if you don’t have a TV that takes full advantage of the consoles, it might be time to upgrade to one of our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22399437/best-gaming-tv-playstation5-ps5-xbox-series-x-s" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;recommendations&lt;/a&gt;. For the best experience, you’ll want a TV that supports HDMI 2.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JEEOlw"&gt;Vizio recently released its first OLED TV, and it remains a good option for people looking to buy a TV that takes full advantage of the PS5 and Xbox Series X hardware. It supports HDR and HDMI 2.1, so you can game at up to 120Hz in 4K. &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1738235849043083583#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; currently has a deal on this TV where you can buy the 65-inch for $1,799 ($100 off).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xr7I2E"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9733767"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3Nkhmv"&gt;Alternatively, LG’s CX series of TVs include support for Nvidia’s G-Sync and AMD’s FreeSync adaptive sync technologies, as well as a low 1ms response time. The big difference between the CX and BX is the CX line can have slightly better brightness, which is better for HDR content. It comes in three sizes: 55, 65, and 77 inches. Right now, you can grab a 65-inch for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0817H41YN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;as low as $1,950 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.costco.com/lg-65%22-class---cx-series---4k-uhd-oled-tv---%24100-allstate-protection-plan-bundle-included.product.100657326.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Costco&lt;/a&gt;. The latter deal requires a &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://costcomembershipoffer.com/Purchase/Purchase/cj?qid=e6583bbeb3f911eb830f05100a1c0e10" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Costco membership&lt;/a&gt;, but it also nets you an Allstate Protection Plan — a three-year warranty for your TV — and a $100 credit toward Hulu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="F5GsVe"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9534696"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5fwgNK"&gt;Samsung’s Q80T is one of the best LCD TVs on the market, and it’s a good option for early adopters of next-gen consoles. The Q80T produces vibrant and accurate colors, supports 120Hz gaming, and includes a variable refresh rate. Right now, you can get a 65-inch model for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-65-inch-Class-QLED-Built/dp/B0845ZSMWS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$1,698 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; or for $1 more at &lt;a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fsamsung-65-class-q80t-series-qled-4k-uhd-smart-tizen-tv%2F6402408.p%3FacampID%3D0%26cmp%3DRMX%26irclickid%3DwC60TbWZHxyLWTm0RHQK3XRkUkB2RKykExnTVM0%26irgwc%3D1%26loc%3DNarrativ%26mpid%3D376373%26ref%3D198%26skuId%3D6402408&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.samsung.com/us/televisions-home-theater/tvs/qled-4k-tvs/65-class-q80t-qled-4k-uhd-hdr-smart-tv-2020-qn65q80tafxza/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung’s online storefront&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OGJPin"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9733779"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22371561/best-4k-tv-deals-sale-lg-samsung-sony-tcl"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22371561/best-4k-tv-deals-sale-lg-samsung-sony-tcl</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-13T11:30:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-13T11:30:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>Qualcomm is the latest major company to skip MWC’s in-person show this year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4IywQI3xUz-250OpuDNYG9PZtnA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69280917/acastro_180529_1777_qualcomm_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zwVjAq"&gt;Qualcomm has announced that it will skip Mobile World Congress’ in-person show in Barcelona this year, making it the latest major company to announce that it will miss the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287802/mwc-event-barcelona-testing-masks-vaccines"&gt;potential COVID-19 superspreader event&lt;/a&gt; in June in favor of an online presence at the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ac822a"&gt;“While we appreciate the health and safety measures being put into place by the GSMA for MWC Barcelona, we have decided that it is in the best interest of our employees and customers for Qualcomm’s participation to be virtual this year,” the company said in a statement &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/05/12/qualcomm-wont-be-exhibiting-in-person-at-mwc/?guccounter=1&amp;amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly9uZXdzLmdvb2dsZS5jb20v&amp;amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAAVkG2fo1pR2bTqIZSfKZd5kxZ9e2u3fNw5XNOikLFfzwDpFDDSR5ulJ9J4Dw_6DQwlpcS1II1EBJ-bdsmKcC-S6dgBjCDb6g3nQtVFinKW_ZUziSHkrdXCMbDpqsVpvX0D9bgpJkZHBWFqEvLCwXS_0NaOjmzdQxv_Tnxpe0wIP"&gt;obtained by &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6K9zHH"&gt;Qualcomm is by no means the only major company opting for a digital appearance at MWC this year: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/31/22360692/google-mwc-mobile-world-congress-phone-2021-nokia-ericsson"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, Nokia, Ericsson, Sony, and Oracle have all pulled out of this year’s show entirely, while &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/11/22430649/samsung-mobile-world-congress-mwc-barcelona-remote-covid"&gt;Samsung and Lenovo&lt;/a&gt; have announced that they will also attend digitally instead of their traditional in-person appearances. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ECaHxk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"MWC insists on holding potential COVID-19 superspreader event in Barcelona","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287802/mwc-event-barcelona-testing-masks-vaccines"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="aChfGB"&gt;MWC 2020 was one of the first major conferences to shut down due to the COVID-19 pandemic, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/5/21123846/mobile-world-congress-gsma-coronavirus-lg"&gt;despite the GSMA’s attempts&lt;/a&gt; to try to put on the show, even with rapidly increasing case numbers around the world and new travel restrictions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L2JevQ"&gt;The GSMA is still insisting on holding this year’s event with only minimal COVID-19 mitigation policies, including asking attendees to have had a negative COVID-19 test within 72 hours of their arrival and plans for “controlling crowd density” — neither of which is expected to be enough to prevent the spread of the coronavirus at an event this large. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WlRm5e"&gt;In 2020, MWC was only canceled after numerous major companies (like LG, ZTE, Sony, and Amazon) pulled out of the event. And while the GSMA has given no indication that it’ll be looking to adjust its plans for this year’s show yet, it’s possible the increasing number of  exhibitors that won’t be attending could change that. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22434223/qualcomm-mwc-2021-skipping-covid-19-digital"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22434223/qualcomm-mwc-2021-skipping-covid-19-digital</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-13T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-13T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Discord is making it easier to find interesting social audio rooms</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RevZ9Rn5n57c_7sAEwc1NVymOZA=/188x0:1313x750/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69280669/Discord_IAP_KeyVisuals_Header_02.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uMAq3s"&gt;Thursday is Discord’s sixth birthday, and to celebrate, the company is announcing some new features — including one coming in June to help people discover its new Clubhouse-like social audio rooms &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/31/22356682/discord-stage-channels-clubhouse-like-feature-voice"&gt;called Stage Channels&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N3fUSG"&gt;The new “Stage Discovery” feature will let you see a feed of public Stage Channels you might be interested in that’s curated using machine learning. You can listen to a Stage Channel’s audio right from the feed, and if you want, you can then hop into the room so that you can be part of the audience. While in a public room, you might also see a link to join the Discord server where the Stage Channel is being hosted if you want to join the community that’s hosting the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GrfZwl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10495334"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="G3VME7"&gt;Once Stage Discovery has rolled out, which Discord tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; will happen on June 1st, you’ll be able to access the feed via a new Stage Channels icon found on the main toolbar in the mobile app and in the Home menu on desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AOtkgs"&gt;Discord says that Stage Channels can’t use profane language in their titles or descriptions, and explicit, graphic, or sexual content is prohibited. Users can report Stage Channels that violate the rules. And to help prevent bad stuff from bubbling up the feed, the company will also enforce its policies through technology, Discord’s own trust and safety team, and community moderation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nAkEXD"&gt;The new discovery feed isn’t the only new Stage Channels feature on the way. Discord is also working on ticketed Stage Channels, meaning hosts will be able to charge for access to a Stage Channel. They’ll be rolling out this month, first in a pilot with fewer than 50 US-based creators. A Discord spokesperson wouldn’t say if it will take a cut of ticket sales, though they noted that the company is evaluating options during the experiment. Discord &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22413033/twitter-spaces-android-ios-ticket-schedule-clubhouse-captions"&gt;follows Twitter&lt;/a&gt; in announcing ticketed social audio rooms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4CBjeC"&gt;And for those of you who sometimes find following Discord conversations to be overwhelming (like me), you’ll be pleased to hear that the company plans to add the ability to make threads, which should make it easier to corral conversations. Discord says threads will start rolling out this summer and will be available to all servers before the end of this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dxxFp2"&gt;Alongside the new features announced today, Discord is unveiling a new brand identity with a slightly tweaked logo (which, if you didn’t know, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/discord/status/843764258810814465"&gt;is named Clyde&lt;/a&gt;). You can see the new logo at the top of this post or in this GIF.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AYyRafCiER5IuTA8EsBpcMU_5Y0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22508348/Discord_IAP_KeyVisuals_Header_01.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="uL2ScF"&gt;Discord, which was originally built as a place for gamers to hang out and talk, has grown significantly during the pandemic, particularly as many non-gaming communities have started to use the service. The company revealed that it now has more than 150 million monthly active users, up from 140 million &lt;a href="https://venturebeat.com/2020/12/17/discord-raises-100-million-as-its-social-hub-hits-140-million-users/"&gt;in December&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22431438/discord-stage-channel-discovery-social-audio-threads-logo-clyde"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22431438/discord-stage-channel-discovery-social-audio-threads-logo-clyde</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
