<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-07-07T14:59:53-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-07T14:59:53-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-07T14:59:53-04:00</updated>
    <title>Melinda French Gates will leave foundation if she and Bill Gates can’t ‘work constructively’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="INDONESIA-IMF-WORLD BANK-DIPLOMACY" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UfopBOBcHCfxDmt8Uhgb8SS6bdc=/0x42:4000x2709/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69552418/1051872980.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo credit should read SONNY TUMBELAKA/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3TxH9o"&gt;Melinda French Gates and Bill Gates &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22418019/bill-melinda-gates-marriage-separation-charity-foundation"&gt;recently announced their divorce plans&lt;/a&gt; but largely left the question of how the co-chairs would continue to work together at the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation unanswered. Now, &lt;a href="https://www.gatesfoundation.org/ideas/media-center/press-releases/2021/07/bill-melinda-gates-foundation-mark-suzman-plans-evolve-governance"&gt;a new statement from the foundation&lt;/a&gt; has offered some clarity: they might not (via &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/07/07/business/gates-foundation-divorce.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The foundation says Melinda French Gates will resign from her position as co-chair and trustee if either she or Bill Gates decides they are unable to work together after two years. It’s not clear how the organization settled on that timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qoBvoh"&gt;Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation CEO Mark Suzman announced the two-year post-divorce trial period along with the commitment of an additional $15 billion from Melinda and Bill toward the foundation’s efforts to fight poverty, disease, and inequity. Suzman also writes that the co-chairs have decided to expand the charitable foundation’s number of trustees:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="y3YUos"&gt;The additional trustees will bring new perspectives, help guide resource allocation and strategic direction, and ensure the stability and sustainability of the foundation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="38On7J"&gt;Per the statement, Melinda and Bill are “are fully committed to continuing to work constructively together at the foundation,” but if Melinda does resign after two years, Suzman suggests she’ll keep giving under her own brand:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="t679yR"&gt;Melinda would receive personal resources from Bill for her philanthropic work. These resources would be completely separate from the foundation’s endowment, which would not be affected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="2N8rTv"&gt;The amount of those resources are unknown, but given Melinda’s &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/rachelsandler/2021/05/05/melinda-gates-now-a-billionaire-after-she-gets-stock-transfer-from-bill-gates/?sh=2da61953e5a5"&gt;reportedly significant personal wealth&lt;/a&gt;, her philanthropic work might not be hindered much either way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UjqUCD"&gt;Melinda and Bill &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/13/21179214/bill-gates-steps-down-microsoft-board-philanthropy"&gt;long ago resigned from their positions at Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; but have continued to have an outsized impact on the world through the work of their foundation (being billionaires helps, too). The Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation has recently focused its efforts on combating the COVID-19 pandemic, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/26/21237482/coronavirus-pandemic-gates-foundation-microsoft"&gt;donating $250 million&lt;/a&gt; toward the development of vaccines and other treatments in 2020. Last month, the foundation committed &lt;a href="https://www.gatesfoundation.org/ideas/media-center/press-releases/2021/06/gates-foundation-commits-2-1-billion-to-advance-gender-equality-globally"&gt;$2.1 billion over the next five years&lt;/a&gt; toward women’s economic empowerment, health, and leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rEGvxU"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xiCPdc"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pgFCYI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22566889/bill-and-melinda-gates-foundation-divorce-governance-plan-two-years"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22566889/bill-and-melinda-gates-foundation-divorce-governance-plan-two-years</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-07T13:43:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-07T13:43:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Verizon has its own version of spatial audio and it’s already pushing it on phones</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XdA7Nx_txiaOx-y7u2tg4yvul0g=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69552002/acastro_200109_1777_verizon_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="h7fivc"&gt;You know spatial audio is having quite a moment when wireless carriers decide to create their own implementations of it. Verizon has announced a new sound feature it’s calling “Verizon Adaptive Sound,” and the company claims it “produces a brilliant spatial surround experience regardless of what headphone, soundbar, or earbud brand you use or what application you’re watching or listening to.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QNuXwO"&gt;The audio trick, which Verizon says has been in the works since 2019, is coming to Motorola phones first, including the new Motorola One 5G UW Ace that goes on sale July 8th. The Motorola Edge Plus also just received a firmware update that seems to add this feature, &lt;a href="https://www.droid-life.com/2021/07/05/motorola-edge-update-adds-something-called-verizon-adaptive-sound/"&gt;as noted by &lt;em&gt;Droid Life&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R6jFwE"&gt;Verizon Adaptive Sound is integrated right into the settings menu on Android devices in the sound section. From there, you can adjust sliders for treble, bass, voice enhancement, and spatial surround sound. For those who’d prefer to ignore VAS completely and hear everything as normal, it can toggled on or off in settings. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lrjWt6xY5uE9XG2fHYt6KgndHCA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22703786/Screen_Shot_2021_07_07_at_12.57.02_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Verizon&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="YhXV3I"&gt;“While some technology solutions have attempted to provide premium sound experiences to some specific (usually expensive) devices and to a limited subset of content, most devices and content experiences have been relegated to a disjointed, sub-optimal, and lowest-common-denominator-like experience,” a Verizon spokesperson said by email, in an obvious reference to Apple, Sony, and Amazon. “We wanted to change that.” Some devices that offer 360-degree audio do indeed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22360437/sony-srs-ra5000-speaker-review-360-audio-features"&gt;come at a premium&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gHGt2H"&gt;Verizon Adaptive Sound is based around “an innovative software and cloud-based solution,” a spokesperson said. That’s on the vague side, so I’ve asked the carrier for more specifics on exactly how it works and what it does. Is this just some kind of gimmicky, fake virtual surround effect? Or does it mix down Dolby Atmos channels (when available) to make the sound profile, similar to Apple’s spatial audio? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vLxleo"&gt;Apple spatial audio works with AirPods earbuds and the AirPods Max headphones to create immersive surround sound — with head tracking — when watching TV shows and movies in supported apps. The company has more recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525028/apple-music-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-hands-on"&gt;added spatial audio to its Apple Music service&lt;/a&gt;, though the results are very inconsistent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iWaUx8"&gt;Verizon’s big talking point seems to be universal support across hardware and streaming services. But until we can give Verizon Adaptive Sound a try ourselves on one of these Moto devices, we can’t say how it compares to existing approaches. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h9kqCY"&gt;The feature “will be made available on a broader portfolio of new devices in the future, as well as some existing devices via an over-the-air software update,” according to Verizon. My initial hunch was that we’ll mostly see this on entry-level and midrange 5G phones, but the carrier told me it won’t be specific to budget devices. Does that mean Verizon will force this into the sound settings of something like Samsung’s Galaxy S21? For now, Motorola is the only partner being named. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22567035/verizon-spatial-audio-adaptive-sound-motorola"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22567035/verizon-spatial-audio-adaptive-sound-motorola</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-07T12:56:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-07T12:56:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>Donald Trump files sweeping, nonsensical lawsuits against Facebook, Twitter, and Google</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Celebrity Sightings In New York City - July 06, 2021" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P8cVR--ep2OLrhzgoCisq0YyJcA=/111x0:3329x2145/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69551618/1327350293.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by James Devaney/ GC Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eEPVci"&gt;Former President Donald Trump has filed proposed class action lawsuits against &lt;a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.flsd.595800/gov.uscourts.flsd.595800.1.0_1.pdf"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.flsd.595801/gov.uscourts.flsd.595801.1.0.pdf"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.flsd.595803/gov.uscourts.flsd.595803.1.0.pdf"&gt;Google subsidiary YouTube&lt;/a&gt; as well as CEOs Mark Zuckerberg, Jack Dorsey, and Sundar Pichai. The lawsuits come six months after Trump was permanently or temporarily suspended from all three platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8Qtbx5"&gt;Trump announced the lawsuits at a press conference today, following &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/trump-lawsuit-facebook-twitter-82323cf3-b8ce-48ed-8cab-cafe31f0bae7.html?utm_campaign=organic&amp;amp;utm_medium=socialshare&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter"&gt;an early report by &lt;em&gt;Axios&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. He referred to the cases as “a very important game-changer for our country.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZmU2sX"&gt;However, the claims are based on an amalgamation of mostly untested or disregarded legal arguments, and they come after numerous other failed attempts to sue social media companies over suspensions or other forms of moderation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FsowUa"&gt;The complaints allege that social media companies violated the First Amendment by suspending Trump and other users from their networks, an argument that courts have typically disregarded — ruling overwhelmingly that the First Amendment is intended to limit censorship by the government, not private companies. His effort is backed by the America First Policy Institute, an advocacy group founded by former Trump officials, including Linda McMahon and Brooke Rollins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xJIE1O"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The suits are backed by the pro-Trump America First Policy Institute&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JpKbaW"&gt;Trump’s lawsuits seek damages on behalf of any users who have had an account “wrongly restricted or curtailed” on Facebook, Twitter, or a Google service. It asks courts to declare Section 230 of the Communications Decency Act unconstitutional. Trump paradoxically cited Section 230 as a legal justification for suing the companies in his press conference, however, saying incorrectly that “once they got Section 230 they’re not private companies.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ckCtHz"&gt;The claim also seemingly challenges the premise of social media terms of service agreements — complaining that Facebook, for instance, “expressly conditioned” usage on agreeing to “speech restrictions imposed by Facebook.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kX6PIB"&gt;Twitter and Facebook declined to comment on the lawsuit. Google did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="XY3y1Q"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Judges have repeatedly rejected claims that social media companies are public venues&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QuxC7m"&gt;Trump described the class action as an attempt to stop companies from violating US speech laws. “We’re not looking for a settlement. We don’t expect a settlement,” Trump said in response to a question during the press conference, suggesting that companies could be liable for “potentially trillions of dollars” in damages, “a number the likes of which nobody’s ever seen before.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AR4cKO"&gt;This appears unlikely. On Twitter, attorney and legal writer Eric Goldman &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ericgoldman/status/1412798837647831040"&gt;cited an upcoming paper&lt;/a&gt; that found courts almost invariably side with web platforms when users sue for being banned. Judges have thrown out not only suits &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/27/21272066/social-media-bias-laura-loomer-larry-klayman-twitter-google-facebook-loss"&gt;from conservative users&lt;/a&gt;, but also ones that allege discrimination based on protected classes — as in a &lt;a href="https://news.bloomberglaw.com/us-law-week/google-beats-youtube-users-suit-alleging-racial-discrimination"&gt;recently dismissed lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; against Google, which some Black creators accused of suppressing or demonetizing videos about race. Users have prevailed in rare cases where censorship is done not by platforms, but by government agencies and politicians using them, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/11/20688860/trump-loss-knight-institute-second-circuit-court-twitter-block-lawsuit-analysis"&gt;including Trump himself&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="8QbLid"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Trump apparently cited emails between Facebook and his own administration as evidence of collusion&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5jGHdV"&gt;Trump’s new lawsuits are far more elaborate — and often confusing — than many of these claims. The suits suggest Facebook, Twitter, and Google became state actors not only because they own powerful platforms for hosting speech, but also because members of Congress called them into hearings and urged them to remove specific categories of content, including false information and incitement to violence. (Trump was banned from Facebook, Twitter, and YouTube for violating rules against incitement during the January 6th riot that sought to nullify President Joe Biden’s election.) There is no legal precedent for using this common practice — which the suits refer to as “legislative coercion” — as a justification for punishing companies themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EDvlaw"&gt;Trump also accuses the platforms of “closely coordinated interaction ... to constrain free speech” with National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases director Anthony Fauci and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. In the press conference, Trump appeared to cite &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/factcheck-fauci-zuckerberg/fact-check-mark-zuckerberg-email-to-fauci-mentioned-pandemic-response-not-elections-or-ballots-idUSL2N2NM23G"&gt;an email thread&lt;/a&gt; between Zuckerberg and Fauci from March 2020, which was during Trump’s own presidency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xTN7Uy"&gt;Judges have almost universally rejected claims that social media platforms are public spaces that must host any content protected by the First Amendment. While Supreme Court Justice Clarence Thomas has pushed for more direct regulation of how companies can moderate, he did so in a case that was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/5/22368045/clarence-thomas-social-media-regulation-knight-v-trump"&gt;effectively unrelated to the issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SY2KZ3"&gt;Trump clashed with social media companies well before he was banned from them this year. As president, he &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/28/21273822/trump-signs-executive-order-facebook-twitter-section-230-social-media-companies"&gt;signed an executive order&lt;/a&gt; asking federal agencies to reduce Section 230’s protections, but the order had little effect and was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/15/22437627/biden-revokes-trump-executive-order-section-230-twitter-facebook-google"&gt;revoked by President Joe Biden&lt;/a&gt; a year later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="USlM5d"&gt;In the press conference, Trump equivocated on whether he would actually return to Facebook, Twitter, and Google should they rescind their bans. “I don’t know. I might not,” he said. “If I put out a press release, I’m getting extremely good pickup.” Trump launched a blog to distribute announcements in May but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22464930/donald-trump-blog-facebook-twitter-social-media-platform"&gt;shut it down within a month&lt;/a&gt; after attracting a reportedly low readership.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22566729/trump-lawsuit-facebook-twitter-google-social-media-censorship"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22566729/trump-lawsuit-facebook-twitter-google-social-media-censorship</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-07T12:39:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-07T12:39:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook’s new AR feature for Portal lets you dress up as Harry Potter characters</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ME2T-vRW4LjZKxU8zOF7bkTZijE=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69551537/CD21_427_Harry_Potter_Portal_Tech_Blog_Header.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook’s &lt;/em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;em&gt;-themed AR masks for Portal.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Facebook&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3hwA3y"&gt;Facebook’s Portal video calling device is getting a &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Cursed Child&lt;/em&gt; crossover that lets you and up to three friends dress up as characters from the play using augmented reality technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N3GHvH"&gt;Here’s how you can use it, &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/07/harry-potter-and-the-cursed-child-takes-center-stage-on-portal-with-curtain-call-ar-experience-plus-new-story-time-content/"&gt;according to a Facebook blog&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="Lv7bye"&gt;Anyone can initiate the experience by tapping “Curtain Call” in the effects tray on Portal. You can then select one of three locations from the menu to visit: Hogwarts Great Hall, the Ministry of Magic or the Edge of the Forbidden Forest. When the lights come up, each person on the call will embody a character from the show with a unique spell, which is assigned randomly. Simply nod your head or tap the screen to cast it and watch as your friends marvel at the magic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Knr6Iy"&gt;The AR masks that transform you into a character, which are powered by Facebook’s Spark AR technology, will also match your skin tone. “Callers can fully embody the characters thanks to real-time skin sampling that matches the 3D character to your unique skin tone before converting it into an AR mask for seamless integration,” Facebook says in its blog. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="6tSoha"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The feature works in the US and the UK&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sz4JQM"&gt;The feature works with Portal-to-Portal video calls for users in the US and UK. And if you don’t have a Portal device, “fans on Instagram and Facebook can still interact with the AR masks via each app’s camera and share video and photos via Stories,” according to the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wYyCSE"&gt;Facebook has been ramping up its augmented reality efforts; it announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/16/21438403/facebook-spark-creator-ar-effects-messenger-portal"&gt;last September&lt;/a&gt; that creators would be able to make AR effects for Messenger and Portal in 2021. The company is also investing heavily in AR and VR devices, with nearly 10,000 employees &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22326875/facebook-reality-labs-ar-vr-headcount-report"&gt;reportedly working in its Reality Labs division&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22566878/facebook-ar-harry-potter-cursed-child-characters"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22566878/facebook-ar-harry-potter-cursed-child-characters</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-07T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-07T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Ladies and gentlemen, a leather case for your MagSafe puck</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4ILxqlDEUnwChx43BVOb6jJg7F0=/0x0:5472x3648/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69551329/856500010205_Lifestyle_04.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;What if MagSafe, but covered in leather?&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Nomad&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ldz8wB"&gt;I’m not going to pretend to understand how product development meetings work, but there must have been something pretty special in the water when Nomad’s crack team of accessory specialists put together its latest pitch. From the company that was brave enough to encase your &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/28/21111850/nomad-leather-airpods-pro-case-rugged-design-apple-accessory"&gt;AirPods Pro case in leather&lt;/a&gt;, comes an &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://nomadgoods.com/products/leather-cover-for-magsafe-rustic-brown" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;all-new leather MagSafe case&lt;/a&gt;. That’s right, it’s a leather case for the iPhone 12’s magnetic charging puck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cbQHjj"&gt;Nomad’s argument is that the case, which is available in either black or brown, gives a MagSafe charger “a classic, yet bold new look,” and that it makes the charger slightly bigger and easier to grip to remove from a phone. But it also costs $25. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R5zK_6fLsV4DWMd50ob2xCvu4eM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22699659/856500010199_Lifestyle_13.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Nomad&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nomad’s expanded leather universe.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="FVhHnC"&gt;As a tech blogger, I consider it my duty to maintain a base level of open-mindedness about new technology. But I also reserve the right in exceptional circumstances to point out when something seems just plain silly, and encasing a charging puck in leather is one of those moments. I can get behind the idea of a leather case for anything you’re going to be carrying around in your pockets to protect it from the stresses of everyday life, but a charger? A charger that you’re almost certainly going to leave plugged in next to your bed for 99 percent of its life? &lt;em&gt;Please.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XbVkJJ"&gt;If you’re already a fully paid-up member of Nomad’s expanded leather universe, and you’ve already got a leather case for your &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22176171/nomad-new-leather-macbook-pro-sleeves-luxury-expensive-price-release-date-hands-on"&gt;MacBook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287731/nomad-rugged-leather-iphone-12-magsafe-wireless-charging"&gt;your iPhone&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/28/21111850/nomad-leather-airpods-pro-case-rugged-design-apple-accessory"&gt;your AirPods&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394331/apple-airtag-release-launch-accessory-roundup-nomad-belkin"&gt;your AirTags&lt;/a&gt;, then sure, why not also cocoon your MagSafe charger in leather for the hell of it. Maybe try following our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/16/17357436/how-to-patina-iphone-x-leather-case-saddle-brown-processor"&gt;exhaustive guide to getting a nice patina&lt;/a&gt; on your leather accessories while you’re at it. You’ve earned it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZaRvih"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KkiOzZ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/7/7/22563631/nomad-magsafe-leather-cover-charger-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/7/7/22563631/nomad-magsafe-leather-cover-charger-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-07T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-07T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Final Fantasy VII Remake’s directors wanted to show ‘a new side’ of Midgar with Yuffie chapter</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jOMu8IhVthIfmwJ1rPZoAGNxCR4=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69550977/FF7RIntergrade_AprilScreenshot_01_bmp_jpgcopy.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="F76Jpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/6/21207441/final-fantasy-7-remake-ff7-review-ps4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; isn’t a complete story. Instead, the game explores the beginning of the classic RPG, with later chapters planned to finish the narrative at some point in the future. This means you’ll meet most of the main cast, but certain characters haven’t yet made an appearance — which turned out to be helpful when co-director Motomu Toriyama&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;started thinking of the game’s first add-on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LsKhyr"&gt;“We were going to depict a side of Midgar that took place during the same timeline as the &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/em&gt; base game, and so I thought Yuffie, who was an optional character [in the original game], was the logical choice,” he tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Even in the source material, she makes an appearance in the middle of the journey, but the events of her journey were never depicted, so I took the liberty to create this new story.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C0GRnx"&gt;The result is a short add-on called &lt;em&gt;Episode Intermission&lt;/em&gt;, which recently launched alongside an enhanced PS5 version of the game. It stars Yuffie Kisaragi — a fan-favorite ninja obsessed  with materia, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/7/21203140/final-fantasy-vii-remake-materia-size-aerith-hair-director-hamaguchi"&gt;&lt;em&gt;FFVII’&lt;/em&gt;s strange magical orbs&lt;/a&gt; — as she heads to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/9/21213574/final-fantasy-7-remake-midgar-city-design-ps4-interview"&gt;the sprawling metropolis of Midgar&lt;/a&gt; to meet up with the Avalanche and seek out a particularly powerful magical item. The story takes place concurrently with the main game; you’ll even see characters like Barrett and Jessie in brief snippets and hear about the impact of events that they were involved in. &lt;em&gt;Episode Intermission&lt;/em&gt; only lasts a few hours, but it’s designed to show the story and world from a different perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="uSew5t"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10640850"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Ofxtnz"&gt;“Players can see a new side of Yuffie, the Avalanche members living in the slums, and the dark side of Shinra, allowing them to immerse themselves even deeper into the world of Midgar,” Toriyama explains. “By getting an understanding of &lt;em&gt;FFVIIR Intermission&lt;/em&gt;, I think players can further enjoy the relationships between the main characters and more of the world of &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remak&lt;/em&gt;e opening up.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="78cjsc"&gt;Yuffie wasn’t the only optional character in the original &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII&lt;/em&gt; that launched in 1997. Players were also able to recruit Vincent Valentine, a gunslinger with a dark, mysterious past. And while his dual-pistols would probably be a lot of fun with &lt;em&gt;FFVIIR&lt;/em&gt;’s more action-oriented combat, his backstory made it a more challenging fit. Yuffie, on the other hand, had a less-defined history, making her an almost ideal candidate.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AvD2SFfGumpAg2P5FsUHIzfhAhQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22703331/re_08_Battle_Yuffie_LimitBreak_Bloodbath_activation_stance__EN_bmp_jpgcopy.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Aaz9l6"&gt;“If, for example, this were Vincent, he would have been sleeping in a coffin in the Shinra mansion, so we couldn’t move him around; but Yuffie was traveling the world as a materia hunter,” Toriyama says. “By having the events from Midgar depicted in &lt;em&gt;FFVIIR Episode Intermission&lt;/em&gt; be a part of her travels as a materia hunter, we are able to see the emotions beneath her fun character, which will then connect to the story.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5yfBAG"&gt;Aside from the new story elements, the new episode also has some gameplay tweaks as well. One of the highlights of &lt;em&gt;FFVIIR &lt;/em&gt;is how each character has a very different feel; combat is completely different if you’re wielding Cloud’s comically large sword or Tifa’s kickboxing skills. For Yuffie, her ninja background means she moves incredibly fast and can attack both from up close and afar, giving her a distinct style among the cast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S0GLeo"&gt;She even moves through the world quickly outside of combat. &lt;em&gt;Intermission&lt;/em&gt; has a number of environmental puzzles that involve clambering up pipes and running along walls. “The controls focus on leveraging the lore of her being a ninja, so we were very particular about making Yuffie’s movements fit that unique characteristic about her, with having her deftly move across latticed walls and poles,” says co-director Naoki Hamaguchi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dk10PM"&gt;The new episode is relatively brief — you can probably experience all of it in around five hours — but it manages to cram a lot into that small package, from gigantic boss battles to brand-new characters. And while we still know very little about when the next main part of &lt;em&gt;FFVVIIR&lt;/em&gt; is coming or what it will actually entail, it sounds like this isn’t the last players will see of Yuffie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W6nZSe"&gt;“With this episode, we were able to delve further into Yuffie’s back story, have her go through an experience similar to Cloud and his team, and leave Midgar at around the same time,” says Toriyama. “This will then lead to her encounter them — as an ally — in the story down the line.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22565517/final-fantasy-7-remake-intermission-intergrade-yuffie-interview-ps5"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22565517/final-fantasy-7-remake-intermission-intergrade-yuffie-interview-ps5</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-07T10:55:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-07T10:55:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>BMW’s actually making the futuristic CE 04 electric scooter</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kNQE_sd5ZLqY0rrdTAu6LjbW37c=/0x0:2250x1500/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69550920/P90428705_lowRes.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: BMW&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nxUvz8"&gt;BMW has been warning us for years that it wants to make and sell a radical electric city scooter, and now it’s following through. On Wednesday, the German automaker announced that its Motorrad division will put &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/11/21560306/bmw-electric-scooter-concept-motorrad-definition-ce-04"&gt;the striking BMW CE 04 into production&lt;/a&gt;, with decent range and speed on offer as well as plenty of futuristic vibes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ryl6b6"&gt;The CE 04 broke cover as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/11/21560306/bmw-electric-scooter-concept-motorrad-definition-ce-04"&gt;a concept scooter in November 2020&lt;/a&gt;, though that itself was basically just a reimagining of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/5/26/15698882/bmw-motorrad-motorcycle-concept-link-photos"&gt;another concept that BMW debuted in 2017&lt;/a&gt;. What’s really striking about the images BMW released Wednesday is how similar the production version looks. Instead of watering down the bold design in an attempt to please a wider range of buyers, the CE 04’s bright orange accents and sharp, angular lines make it look just as much like it belongs in an anime as its concept predecessors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="YddRJ7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s striking how little BMW changed the design from the concepts&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pO7GtU"&gt;BMW is really angling the CE 04 as a city vehicle — so much so that the press release quite seriously opens with an &lt;a href="https://www.press.bmwgroup.com/global/article/detail/T0337029EN/the-new-bmw-ce-04"&gt;extended first-person narrative written from the perspective of a fictional owner and parka-obsessed city-dweller&lt;/a&gt; that I cannot recommend enough. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="49tow7"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10640976"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ypwkiy"&gt;This framing helps contextualize the limited 81-mile range, which is made possible by a lithe 8.9kWh battery (built on the same cells &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22462746/bmw-ix-suv-ev-price-specs"&gt;that power the new iX SUV&lt;/a&gt;). But while that pales in comparison to the three-digit range figures of most every modern four-wheel electric vehicle, it’s enough to cover the kinds of daily short trips one typically makes with a scooter like the CE 04. Driving in a city means there will also be a lot of braking, which presents ample opportunity to use regenerative braking to feed energy back into the battery. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SNOM40"&gt;For however long the battery lasts, it sounds like the CE 04 will be a fun ride. BMW says it has a maximum output of 31kW (42 horsepower) and a top speed of 120 kilometers per hour (roughly 75mph). Automatic stability control, dynamic traction control, and an anti-lock braking system — technologies that BMW has been iterating on for a while now, with the company going so far as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/12/17847508/bmw-motorrad-self-driving-motorcycle"&gt;developing a prototype self-driving motorcycle&lt;/a&gt; — are all available to help riders keep that quickness in check. A 10.25-inch TFT screen between the handlebars will offer onboard navigation and smartphone connectivity. (And the bike will have an “[a]ctively ventilated mobile phone charging compartment with USB-C charging port” to boot, according to BMW.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="URT1Uu"&gt;BMW &lt;em&gt;has &lt;/em&gt;sold a futuristic electric scooter before, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/9/29/13103000/bmw-c-evolution-scooter-usa-paris-auto-show-2016"&gt;the C Evolution&lt;/a&gt;, which was quite well-received despite never really catching on — likely thanks to the $13,000 price tag. Eager buyers hoping for a break here aren’t going to catch one, though, as the CE 04 starts at around $12,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8Tgn2Y"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update July 7th, 12:45PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added pricing information from BMW’s website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22566683/bmw-ce-04-electric-city-scooter-futuristic-design-motorrad"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22566683/bmw-ce-04-electric-city-scooter-futuristic-design-motorrad</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-07T10:36:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-07T10:36:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>Grubhub will use Russian-made robots to deliver food on college campuses</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9TO-_5-2J1gun8PXu1PKtINdH5g=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69550815/YanexRoverDeliveryMI_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="p4Nktj"&gt;Grubhub and Russian self-driving startup Yandex are teaming up to use robots to deliver food on US college campuses. It represents the latest deal that envisions hundreds of six-wheeled self-driving robots that essentially act as roving lunchboxes in cities across the country. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BWLiXV"&gt;The robot-powered delivery service won’t kick off until this fall when college students return to campus. Yandex, which is often described as Russia’s Google, will operate the robots, as well as handle the entire food delivery process. Grubhub, which has partnerships with over 250 college campuses in the US, will serve as the platform for the delivery transactions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="AAV6pn"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Grubhub cited the cost savings it will get by eliminating delivery workers&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="y87zhx"&gt;Grubhub cited the cost savings it will get by eliminating the delivery worker from the equation as a potential benefit from the deal with Yandex — though neither company disclosed the financial terms of the partnership. “We’re excited to offer these cost-effective, scalable and quick food ordering and delivery capabilities to colleges and universities across the country that are looking to adapt to students’ unique dining needs,” said Brian Madigan, vice president of corporate and campus partners at Grubhub, in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="76a5yH"&gt;Yandex says that its delivery robots can navigate pavement, pedestrian areas and crosswalks, and reach campus areas not accessible by car. “Such functionality enables the robots to handle delivery tasks traditionally performed by people and provides efficient last-mile logistics automation,” the company says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xQ7Iso"&gt;Food delivery via robot is nothing new in the US. There are many startups operating delivery robots of varying sizes — everything from fully sized minivans &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/8/18173776/udelv-self-driving-delivery-walmart-baidu-ces-2019"&gt;like Udelv&lt;/a&gt; to robots that look almost identical to Yandex’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/23/18194566/amazon-scout-autonomous-six-wheeled-delivery-robot"&gt;like Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/20/20812184/starship-delivery-robot-expansion-college-campus"&gt;Starship&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/13/18139394/postmates-serve-autonomous-delivery-robot-los-angeles"&gt;Postmates has a delivery robot called Serve&lt;/a&gt; that can carry 50 pounds of cargo. There are even some &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/14/18265397/nuro-robot-delivery-houston-texas-kroger"&gt;like Nuro&lt;/a&gt;, which has made what can be best described as a mini-robotic car, that fall somewhere in between. All claim to be autonomous, but some require human monitors to track their movements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pGYR6F"&gt;Demand for delivery robots has skyrocketed since the pandemic, though it remains to be seen whether that holds up as the economy reopens and fewer people rely on takeout from restaurants. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rXbA2l"&gt;Delivery services view the use of robots as one of the many ways they can cut down on labor costs and achieve profitability. Earlier this year, DoorDash acquired salad-making robot startup Chowbotics. But most seem to be stuck in the experimental phase, with companies unclear on how exactly to scale up the use of these automated helpers. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22566652/grubhub-delivery-robot-yandex-college-campus-autonomous"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22566652/grubhub-delivery-robot-yandex-college-campus-autonomous</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-07T10:11:12-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-07T10:11:12-04:00</updated>
    <title>Ubisoft is reportedly shaking up Assassin’s Creed with new live-service game</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b8Jk6JTNN5dRm39_Ecxig8h03a0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69550726/acastro_190528_1777_ubisoft_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8wPUuh"&gt;Ubisoft has officially confirmed the existence of &lt;a href="https://news.ubisoft.com/en-us/article/GZi5hT4dBeM8YITOsJeCn/an-update-on-assassins-creed-infinity-and-the-future-of-the-assassins-creed-franchise"&gt;a new &lt;em&gt;Assassin’s Creed&lt;/em&gt; game codenamed &lt;/a&gt;“&lt;a href="https://news.ubisoft.com/en-us/article/GZi5hT4dBeM8YITOsJeCn/an-update-on-assassins-creed-infinity-and-the-future-of-the-assassins-creed-franchise"&gt;Infinity&lt;/a&gt;,” after a &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-07-07/assassin-s-creed-infinity-to-offer-live-online-game-service?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;report from &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; detailed the new online service-based game. While Ubisoft’s announcement doesn’t shed much light on what form the new game will take, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reports that it will be an evolving online game similar to the likes of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;GTA Online&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rs1XUu"&gt;Infinity&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;marks what is likely to be the biggest change in the franchise’s history since its debut in 2007. Until now, Ubisoft has tended to release a new standalone &lt;em&gt;Assassin’s Creed&lt;/em&gt; game once every one or two years, each focused on a single location and time period. But according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;, Infinity&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;will feature multiple connected settings that may look and play differently, and this number may expand over time. The new game is reportedly years away from release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="MuOfxS"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A huge change for the franchise&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OKdcgG"&gt;The title also marks a shift in how Ubisoft develops &lt;em&gt;Assassin’s Creed&lt;/em&gt; games, the company says. While previous titles have generally been led alternatively by its teams in Montreal and Quebec City, the new game is being developed under a “collaborative, cross-studio structure” between the two studios. “Rather than continuing to pass the baton from game to game, we profoundly believe this is an opportunity for one of Ubisoft’s most beloved franchises to evolve in a more integrated and collaborative manner that’s less centered on studios and more focused on talent and leadership, no matter where they are within Ubisoft,” the company says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nLG1C0"&gt;Development of the title has reportedly been impacted by a recent wave of sexual misconduct allegations that emerged against senior Ubisoft employees &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/21/21332534/ubisoft-serge-hascoet-harassment-sexism-racism-metoo"&gt;last&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/26/21305018/ubisoft-multiple-employees-administrative-leave-sexual-misconduct"&gt;year&lt;/a&gt;. Employees are reportedly angry that managers accused of misconduct are still in senior positions within the company. A spokesperson for Ubisoft told &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg,&lt;/em&gt; “Any employee that had allegations and remain at Ubisoft has had their case rigorously reviewed by a third party and were either exonerated or underwent appropriate disciplinary actions.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OzfV4F"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S0u4Eu"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22566676/assassins-creed-infinity-ubisoft-confirmed-online-service-based-game"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22566676/assassins-creed-infinity-ubisoft-confirmed-online-service-based-game</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-07T09:59:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-07T09:59:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>Moderna starts human trials of an mRNA-based flu shot</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Grubb’s Pharmacy..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xGQTzAzBbrIl9uuhVjWbdCy5h4Q=/0x0:5568x3712/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69550599/1232272941.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo By Tom Williams/CQ-Roll Call, Inc via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Uf8Ys7"&gt;Moderna gave its mRNA-based seasonal flu vaccine to the first set of volunteers in a clinical trial, the pharmaceutical company &lt;a href="https://investors.modernatx.com/news-releases/news-release-details/moderna-announces-first-participant-dosed-phase-12-study-its"&gt;announced today&lt;/a&gt;. The start of the trial marks the next stage of the company’s work on this type of vaccine technology after the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/16/21569345/moderna-covid-19-vaccine-coronavirus-efficacy-announcement"&gt;overwhelming success&lt;/a&gt; of its COVID-19 vaccine, which was built using the same &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/22/21266897/coronavirus-vaccine-development-strategies-pros-cons"&gt;strategy&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="274cru"&gt;Before the COVID-19 pandemic, mRNA vaccines were still largely experimental, even as they were heralded as &lt;a href="https://cen.acs.org/pharmaceuticals/vaccines/coronavirus-help-mRNA-DNA-vaccines/98/i14"&gt;the future&lt;/a&gt; of vaccine development. People who get an mRNA vaccine are injected with tiny snippets of genetic material from the target virus. Their cells use that genetic information to build bits of the virus, which the body’s immune system learns to fight against. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W3ktch"&gt;The high efficacy of the mRNA COVID-19 vaccines made by Moderna and Pfizer / BioNTech was a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21562309/pfizer-coronavirus-vaccine-gene-based"&gt;major endorsement&lt;/a&gt; for this type of vaccine. Now, pharmaceutical companies plan to use this technology to fight other types of infectious diseases, including flu. The flu shots available each year in the United States are usually between &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/flu/vaccines-work/vaccineeffect.htm"&gt;40 and 60 percent&lt;/a&gt; effective. The most common shots are made by growing the influenza virus in cells or chicken eggs, and then killing the virus so it’s no longer dangerous. It takes a long time to grow the virus, so companies have to start making the shots around six months ahead of time, based on predictions around which strain of the flu will be circulating that year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lt33qK"&gt;Pharmaceutical companies hope that mRNA-based flu vaccines can be more effective than the traditional shots. Because they’d be faster to make, production wouldn’t have to start so far in advance, and they could theoretically be more closely matched with the type of flu spreading each season. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qbzijl"&gt;Moderna is the second group&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;to start testing its mRNA flu shot in human trials — &lt;a href="https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/sanofi-translate-bio-start-seasonal-mrna-flu-vaccine-trial-gaining-early-lead-over-moderna"&gt;Sanofi and Translate Bio&lt;/a&gt; kicked off a trial this summer. Pfizer and BioNTech have been interested in mRNA flu shots for &lt;a href="https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/pfizer-pays-biontech-120m-to-form-mrna-flu-vaccine-pact"&gt;a few years&lt;/a&gt;, and they’re pushing forward with those plans &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/05/11/covid-vaccines-pfizer-scientist-says-mrna-technology-could-create-more-potent-seasonal-flu-shots.html"&gt;as well&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0dxkqG"&gt;Moderna says it hopes to eventually create combination vaccines that could protect people against flu, COVID-19, and other respiratory infections with one shot. “Our vision is to develop an mRNA combination vaccine so that people can get one shot each fall for high efficacy protection against the most problematic respiratory viruses,” Stéphane Bancel, chief executive officer of Moderna, said &lt;a href="https://investors.modernatx.com/news-releases/news-release-details/moderna-announces-first-participant-dosed-phase-12-study-its"&gt;in a press release&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qWGrAR"&gt;If flu shots using this technology prove to be safe and effective, it could also make us more prepared for a potential pandemic flu in the future. It’s a fairly simple process to design a shot that could target&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;a new influenza virus. “[mRNA] gives us a very strong platform for a rapid response,” Rosemary Rochford, an immunologist at the University of Colorado, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21562309/pfizer-coronavirus-vaccine-gene-based"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; last fall&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="52c53K"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22566634/moderna-mrna-flu-vaccine-trial"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22566634/moderna-mrna-flu-vaccine-trial</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
