<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-10T00:45:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-10T00:45:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-10T00:45:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple Music is adding more DJ mixes with new features powered by Shazam</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T2ZQnxXtXtKmSK-HQGqIANMbcsE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69838305/acastro_210831_1777_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="quFQc3"&gt;Last year Apple showed how it could &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/17/21444506/apple-ios-14-2-beta-shazam-identify-music-phone-apps-headphones"&gt;embed Shazam’s music identification features even more deeply within iOS 14&lt;/a&gt;, and now it’s taking things another step forward within Apple Music. Apple Music initially &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/3/15/11235428/apple-music-stream-remixes-dj-mixes-dubset"&gt;introduced DJ mixes and mash-ups in 2016 through a partnership with Dubset Media Holdings&lt;/a&gt; to identify and pay for licensed music within mixes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uj1TvW"&gt;Now Apple says that by building upon the Shazam tech &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/24/17896350/apple-shazam-app-acquisition-complete-free"&gt;acquired in 2018&lt;/a&gt; and partnering with various labels, Apple Music has the tools to identify and compensate individual creators, event promoters, labels, etc. It also allows subscribers to see the names of individual tracks, skip songs within the mix, listen with lossless audio on “most mixes,” and save them to their library for viewing offline. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cNlCJzWhvaL4iJTap0cLoW47L58=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22839129/applemusic_6001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Apple Music DJ Mix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="mQg5zT"&gt;So yes, the same fingerprint ID tech that tells you the name of a song playing in the mall can apparently figure out which festival it’s from, which DJ’s mix it is, and pick out different sounds as they blend together. This is apparently detailed enough, relying on matching across Apple Music’s database of 75 million songs or so, to enable recurring revenue streams for the clubs that host sets and the DJs that make them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BTumey"&gt;There’s a dedicated genre page for DJ mixes within the Apple Music app, and the company says engagement has tripled in the last twelve months, with over 300 million streams of DJ mixes so far.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Un-C3A-NrrZPin1pIWYhKSifwl0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22839132/applemusic_600t.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Apple Music DJ Mix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="bHBPrU"&gt;Apple has already been on a tear adding mixes over the last year or so, including some from Charlotte de Witte, Tiësto, Carl Cox, and others. Studio K7! founder Horst Weidenmueller said in a statement that “Through the partnership with Apple we finally have a place to celebrate DJ-Kicks with additional 14 editions which haven‘t been in the market for over 15 years.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PERn2v"&gt;Apple Music says it’s commissioning more mixes (following series released earlier this year to mark Black Music Month and Pride) and working closely with DJs to get additional content on the service. This is a new path for getting DJ mixes onto Apple Music alongside older ones like Dubset’s platform. If you already enjoy existing mixes on Apple Music, we’re told they aren’t going anywhere, even if they don’t have all the new features included. Still, it isn’t yet accessible for bedroom DJs or lesser-known names posting their mixtapes to SoundCloud, so there’s some room between this and the wild days of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Muxtape"&gt;Muxtape&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22662684/apple-music-dj-mix-shazam-streaming-ugc"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22662684/apple-music-dj-mix-shazam-streaming-ugc</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-10T00:24:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-10T00:24:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple won’t let Epic bring Fortnite back to South Korea’s App Store</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EXYdbBwcc_0-tFM38okb09faDjw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69838257/vpavic_180607_2652_0089.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eLYuio"&gt;Apple says it won’t let Epic Games back in the App Store until they agree to “play by the same rules as everyone else.” Earlier today &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665826/epic-games-apple-reinstate-fortnite-ios-korea-app-store-payment"&gt;Epic asked Apple&lt;/a&gt; to reinstate its developer account so that it could re-release the iOS version of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; in South Korea, which recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22643800/apple-google-south-korea-app-store-payment-legislation-passes"&gt;passed a bill&lt;/a&gt; forcing Apple and Google to allow alternate in-app payment systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4BVTLT"&gt;Apple, however, maintains it’s under no obligation to let Epic in the App Store at all. “As we’ve said all along, we would welcome Epic’s return to the App Store if they agree to play by the same rules as everyone else,” an Apple spokesperson says in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Epic has admitted to breach of contract and as of now, there’s no legitimate basis for the reinstatement of their developer account.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="N0dBfY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"All the best emails from the Apple vs. Epic trial","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22611236/epic-v-apple-emails-project-liberty-app-store-schiller-sweeney-cook-jobs"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Yl5sa3"&gt;The South Korean legislation has not yet gone into effect, but if and when it does, according to Apple, that wouldn’t have any bearing on the company’s process for approving developer accounts. Until Epic agrees to comply with the App Store’s app review guidelines, Apple isn’t going to consider its request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LlEPyh"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;, one of the most popular video games in the world, has been unavailable on the App Store &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21366438/apple-fortnite-ios-app-store-violations-epic-payments"&gt;since August of last year&lt;/a&gt;. Apple ultimately terminated Epic’s developer account in response to a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21366259/epic-fortnite-vbucks-mega-drop-discount-iphone-android"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; update&lt;/a&gt; that dodged the App Store’s in-app payment requirement in order to get around paying Apple the 30-percent cut. Epic then sued Apple and went to trial in May, with a verdict yet to come.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22666146/apple-epic-korea-fortnite-developer-account-rules-response"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22666146/apple-epic-korea-fortnite-developer-account-rules-response</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T23:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T23:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Vivo finally adopts wireless charging with new X70 Pro Plus flagship</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VvNw_B1RXfeUxBh1ueLvdoreV1E=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69838079/vivo_X70_Series_Photo_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1f8OIT"&gt;Vivo has announced the X70 series, its latest line of flagship phones. It sees the company further extend its camera partnership with renowned lens company Zeiss while refining the blueprint laid down by the X50 and X60 phones from the past year-plus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VfwdW3"&gt;The X70 Pro Plus is the top-of-the-line device, featuring a Snapdragon 888 Plus processor, a 6.783-inch (yes that’s the stated spec) 1440p OLED screen, and a 4,500mAh battery that uses Vivo’s 55W FlashCharge technology. More importantly, it has 50W wireless fast charging that also works with Qi. This is Vivo’s first ever phone to support wireless charging, which should make it a more viable switching option for anyone who’s already put Qi chargers all over their house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m9QWaP"&gt;The X70 Pro Plus’ Zeiss-branded camera array includes a 50-megapixel main sensor, a 48-megapixel gimbal-stabilized ultrawide, a 12-megapixel telephoto, and an 8-megapixel periscope telephoto. Vivo has added three new simulated bokeh modes based on the optical characteristics of classic Zeiss glass, including Distagon, Planar, and Sonnar. The Pro Plus also has a new Vivo-designed image processor called the Imaging Chip V1 that’s designed to improve performance in noise reduction and motion compensation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NHxEAVX3jccigTqloEf670PS-eM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22836445/vivo_X70_Pro_Photo_1.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XVn4nW"&gt;The X70 Pro and X70 have smaller 6.56-inch 120Hz displays, Mediatek Dimensity 1200 processors, and 44W FlashCharge — but still no wireless charging. The X70 Pro’s camera system bumps the ultrawide down to 12 megapixels, while the X70’s triple array includes a 40-megapixel primary and two 12-megapixel sensors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WL6CLI"&gt;Vivo hasn’t given full pricing or release information for the X70 series except to say that it’s “gradually rolling out in markets such as India, Thailand, Indonesia, Malaysia, Taiwan, the United Arab Emirates, and more” from today. We’ll bring you more as we have it — the X70 Pro Plus in particular is looking like a compelling device.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22664290/vivo-x70-pro-plus-series-announced-zeiss-wireless-charging"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22664290/vivo-x70-pro-plus-series-announced-zeiss-wireless-charging</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T22:33:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T22:33:29-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple fires senior engineering program manager Ashley Gjøvik for allegedly leaking information</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MpOe7Q2Tn1pUSlE7lq2TwQwZi2A=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69838038/acstro_190902_apple_event_0004.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xfqpAL"&gt;Apple has fired senior engineering program manager Ashley Gjøvik for allegedly violating the company’s rules against leaking confidential information. For months, Gjøvik has been tweeting openly about allegations of harassment, surveillance, and workplace safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7fO2x3"&gt;“When I began raising workplace safety concerns in March, and nearly immediately faced retaliation and intimidation, I started preparing myself for something exactly like this to happen,” she says. “I’m disappointed that a company I have loved since I was a little girl would treat their employees this way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O0K58X"&gt;Gjøvik has raised concerns that her office is in an Apple building located on a superfund site, meaning it requires special oversight due to historical waste contamination. She also says that she faced harassment and bullying from her manager and members of her team. More recently, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22648265/apple-employee-privacy-icloud-id"&gt;she’s begun raising privacy concerns&lt;/a&gt; related to Apple’s policies on how it can search and surveil employees’ work phones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0nYUnz"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Sooo, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Apple?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Apple&lt;/a&gt; has pics of my boobs. During a discovery thing 3yr ago, legal forced me to hand-over all my texts. They refused to let me delete anything, even "fully personal," even when I said "by fully personal I mean nudes." They said they're in their "permanent evidence locker"&lt;/p&gt;— Ashley M. Gjøvik (@ashleygjovik) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashleygjovik/status/1428495420917837826?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 19, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4dviGK"&gt;She was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22610112/apple-female-engineering-manager-leave-sexism-work-environment"&gt;placed on administrative leave in early August&lt;/a&gt; while Apple investigated some of these concerns — a placement she says she requested as a last resort. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8ayee9"&gt;A member of Apple’s employee relations team reached out to Gjøvik earlier today saying the company was looking into a sensitive intellectual property matter and wanted to speak to her within the hour. Gjøvik said she wanted to keep all communications in writing, and noted she was forwarding the correspondence along to the NLRB, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-national-labor-relations-board-investigating-two-complaints-apple-workers-2021-09-02/"&gt;where she recently filed a charge&lt;/a&gt;. The employee relations representative responded to say that because she had chosen not to participate in the discussion, they would move forward with the information they had and — “given the seriousness of these allegations” — suspend her access to Apple systems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TWdgdI"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Any bets if I get a literal knock on my physical door from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Apple?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Apple&lt;/a&gt; today? &lt;a href="https://t.co/oFqw4VFaGi"&gt;pic.twitter.com/oFqw4VFaGi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ashley M. Gjøvik (@ashleygjovik) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashleygjovik/status/1436078307859066890?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PXSOMR"&gt;Hours later, Gjøvik received an email that her employment at Apple was being terminated, effective tomorrow. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mDhGAH"&gt;In response to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, Apple spokesperson Josh Rosenstock said: “We are and have always been deeply committed to creating and maintaining a positive and inclusive workplace. We take all concerns seriously and we thoroughly investigate whenever a concern is raised and, out of respect for the privacy of any individuals involved, we do not discuss specific employee matters.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22666049/apple-fires-senior-engineering-program-manager-ashley-gjovik-for-allegedly-leaking-information"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22666049/apple-fires-senior-engineering-program-manager-ashley-gjovik-for-allegedly-leaking-information</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T20:58:09-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T20:58:09-04:00</updated>
    <title>Vape receipts help DOJ nab man who allegedly botnetted thousands of passwords</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/q-qMR2bo13723-o2ojmc44Q_GMQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69837773/acastro_170621_1777_0001_fin.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YEfHY3"&gt;28-year-old Ukrainian national Glib Oleksandr Ivanov-Tolpintsev has been &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-mdfl/pr/ukrainian-cyber-criminal-extradited-decrypting-credentials-thousands-computers-across"&gt;indicted by the Department of Justice&lt;/a&gt; for allegedly using a botnet to brute force people’s passwords, and then selling the credentials on a dark web store ominously called The Marketplace. According to the DOJ, Ivanov-Tolpintsev bragged that he was able to get at least 2,000 logins a week, and he allegedly told one of The Marketplace’s admins that he had cracked over 20,000 passwords. The DOJ’s description of the alleged methods and victims serve as a reminder of how much stolen information is out there, and the importance of implementing basic security principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2Uk6zG"&gt;The indictment, which can be read in full below, alleges that Ivanov-Tolpintsev talked about controlling a botnet, which is essentially a group of computers whose users don’t know they are infected with malware. He’s accused of using those computers’ power to guess people’s passwords over and over, far faster than he could with his own hardware. Then, according to the DOJ, he would sell those passwords to cybercriminals who used them to carry out fraudulent activity, such as ransomware attacks, or even accessing someone’s home security cameras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="koEZMo"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Botnets can let you guess passwords faster than you could with a single machine&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0FmXpe"&gt;Some of the alleged victims are perhaps a bit surprising. The &lt;a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/21059498-tolpinstev-complaint"&gt;criminal complaint&lt;/a&gt; lists two victims who were interviewed; one ran an IT business, the other was a security systems consultant who did work for the Department of Corrections. While the two victim’s systems are only a small portion of the over 6,000 compromised logins Ivanov-Tolpintsev is accused of putting up for sale, his alleged contributions are in turn just a drop in the bucket for The Marketplace. According to the complaint, vendors on the site are selling access to over 700,000 machines, and past buyers have used info purchased on The Marketplace to carry out over $100 million of fraud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="vjB4u6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Investigators were able to track Ivanov-Tolpintsev using an email address&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Ecplj0"&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://www.cyberscoop.com/irs-ukraine-scammer-vape-store-receipts/"&gt;a report by &lt;em&gt;CyberScoop&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, simple mistakes made it easier for investigators to accuse Ivanov-Tolpintsev. The IRS was granted access to email addresses with a warrant, and was able to link the alleged hacker to them using receipts from local vape and smoke shops, scans of his passport, and pictures on Google Photos. The emails also allegedly linked him to other accounts and identities that were related to The Marketplace, where the passwords were sold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vy2Qx0"&gt;The DOJ says that if Ivanov-Tolpintsev is found guilty he could face up to 17 years in prison, and would have to hand over more than $80,000 that he allegedly made from selling information. He was originally caught by Polish authorities in late 2020, and was extradited to the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PbxXeG"&gt;The story serves as a reminder of why good security practices are important. Things like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22311182/best-free-password-manager-bitwarden-zoho-vault-roboform-sticky-password"&gt;using strong passwords&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22215571/factor-authentication-2fa-apple-microsoft-google-how-to"&gt;two-factor authentication&lt;/a&gt; can help better protect you against brute-force attacks, and occasionally scanning your computer for malware can keep your computer from inadvertently working to crack other people’s passwords. While authorities may be able to catch some cybercriminals, the vastness of The Marketplace (itself just a single site), shows that there’s plenty of people out there trying to get their hands on unprotected data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Ttzu6W"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/21060290-doj-ivanov-tolpintsev-indictment/?embed=1&amp;amp;responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="DOJ Ivanov-Tolpintsev Indictment (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="908" style="border: 1px solid #aaa; width: 100%; height: 800px; height: calc(100vh - 100px);" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665545/doj-cybercrime-indictment-botnet-cracking-passwords-online-safety"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665545/doj-cybercrime-indictment-botnet-cracking-passwords-online-safety</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T20:49:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T20:49:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google Stadia’s director of games has left for Google Cloud</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZhbZyRUZHUV7dQFjBlnrTs5yptI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69837752/akrales_191113_3779_0317.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oFeu31"&gt;Google’s Stadia cloud gaming service appears to have lost &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334101/jade-raymond-haven-game-studio-playstation"&gt;another&lt;/a&gt; top video game industry veteran — kind of. Jack Buser, Stadia’s Director for Games and a former PlayStation exec, is moving to the company’s Google Cloud division to head up “Gaming Solutions,” according to &lt;a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/google-cloud-zeroes-in-on-gaming-taps-stadia-exec-jack-buser-to-lead-the-way/"&gt;a &lt;em&gt;ZDNet&lt;/em&gt; report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w79TN2"&gt;Google confirms Buser is leaving the Stadia group for Google Cloud, providing this statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="rqS3dp"&gt;Gaming is an incredibly important vertical at Google and we’re seeing huge momentum across all products and services. Jack’s new role will allow us to better bring customers the best of Google across our Cloud services, Stadia, YouTube, and more. Stadia continues to be led by its GM Phil Harrison, and Stadia’s business development and partner management teams will continue to be led by Michael Abbattista, who took over the role in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="5qKSzp"&gt;While it’s easy to think Google’s just trying to spin a loss for Stadia as synergy for Google’s bigger gaming goals, it might make a lot of sense for Stadia’s future. As I wrote in February when the company axed its own game studios, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22260994/google-stadia-platform-white-label-option"&gt;the writing’s on the wall&lt;/a&gt; — Stadia boss Phil Harrison sent a clear message that the future of Stadia is to run it as “a technology platform for industry partners,” not a Netflix-of-games or a place to build groundbreaking games of its own. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EHkvIm"&gt;And now, it sure sounds like Buser’s going to work on that overall technology platform for Google’s partners, which it already sells as Google Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="SIp3dH"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The writing’s on the wall for Google Stadia","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22260994/google-stadia-platform-white-label-option"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="TxZ2N1"&gt;If Google does eventually decide to add Stadia to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/26/20977968/google-graveyard-products-shut-down-dead-not-supported-discontinues-spring-cleaning"&gt;its Google graveyard&lt;/a&gt;, it might be easier to swallow if the company manages to turn it into a different kind of business first. But it could also be that Google has decided to invest more, not less in gaming, by taking it a different route. &lt;em&gt;ZDNet&lt;/em&gt; quotes a Google Cloud spokesperson that gaming “is one of the key verticals we are investing in,” and writes that the idea behind Buser’s move “is to connect with players through a holistic suite of products and services.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="apUOBi"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“end-to-end collaboration solutions”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="05Obt4"&gt;“The tech giant could offer, for instance, end-to-end collaboration solutions that include YouTube as a streaming partner for live broadcasts or e-sporting events,” &lt;em&gt;ZDNet &lt;/em&gt;adds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="743PRg"&gt;Some of that brings to mind &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22631907/google-gaming-vision-android-windows-mac-cross-screen-controller"&gt;the 70-page confidential Google document&lt;/a&gt; we unearthed from the &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;/em&gt; trial last month, which describes a plan to make Google “the world’s largest game platform” by 2025, starting by bringing roughly 100 Android games to Windows PC, and later expanding to Mac, smart displays, and TVs, all bolstered by Google’s cloud services. The document suggested cloud gaming might be part of that vision too, and that the platform would “super-premium” games as well, with &lt;em&gt;Shadow of the Tomb Raider&lt;/em&gt; as a representative example. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ybb0Ub"&gt;Buser has plenty of experience trying to attract premium games at both Google and at Sony, where he headed up Sony’s own cloud gaming service PlayStation Now, and soon he might have a more attractive pitch to bring those games in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VN2IVc"&gt;While Stadia &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/26/22303496/google-stadia-struggle-wired-bloomberg-reports-studios"&gt;has had some serious struggles&lt;/a&gt;, it’s also been steadily trying to make the service more attractive, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575619/google-stadia-revenue-share-developers-games-summit"&gt;recently slashing its revenue share to hook more developers&lt;/a&gt;, adding &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/13/22624023/stadia-direct-touch-control-scheme-humankind-stadia"&gt;a direct touchscreen control option&lt;/a&gt;, and finally &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/31/22603498/google-stadia-controller-chromecast-play-watch-bundle"&gt;bringing Stadia to the Chromecast with Google TV.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665805/google-stadia-jack-buser-games-cloud"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665805/google-stadia-jack-buser-games-cloud</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T19:39:37-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T19:39:37-04:00</updated>
    <title>Epic tests Apple with new request: let us relaunch Fortnite in Korea</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7TZ6sK9iqu192z0_337ftVRFx2I=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69837530/acastro_20200818_1777_epicApple_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zAkiU5"&gt;Epic Games has asked Apple to reinstate its &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; developer account so it can release the game in South Korea, following the passage of a bill that will force Apple and Google to let apps &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22643800/apple-google-south-korea-app-store-payment-legislation-passes"&gt;use alternative payment systems&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IR6usc"&gt;“Epic has asked Apple to restore our &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; developer account,” Epic said &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FortniteGame/status/1436105346184056832?s=20"&gt;in a tweet on the official &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; account&lt;/a&gt;. “Epic intends to re-release &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; on iOS in Korea offering both Epic payment and Apple payment side-by-side in compliance with the new Korean law.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4mLcOx"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Epic has asked Apple to restore our Fortnite developer account. Epic intends to re-release Fortnite on iOS in Korea offering both Epic payment and Apple payment side-by-side in compliance with the new Korean law.&lt;/p&gt;— Fortnite (@FortniteGame) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FortniteGame/status/1436105346184056832?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rGDyc8"&gt;It’s unclear if Apple will agree to the request, or if Epic’s intentions are genuine: after all, Epic used Apple’s responses to its prior demands &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/14/21368651/apple-fortnite-ios-app-store-ban-lawsuit-epic-games-payments"&gt;to help spring its original #FreeFortnite legal trap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4ZdOAo"&gt;In August 2020, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21366438/apple-fortnite-ios-app-store-violations-epic-payments"&gt;Apple kicked &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; off the App Store&lt;/a&gt; hours after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21366259/epic-fortnite-vbucks-mega-drop-discount-iphone-android"&gt;Epic introduced a direct payment system&lt;/a&gt; to the game that bypassed Apple’s own. Epic &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21367963/epic-fortnite-legal-complaint-apple-ios-app-store-removal-injunctive-relief"&gt;then sued Apple&lt;/a&gt;, starting off a contentious legal battle between the two companies. The case went to trial &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/27/22454959/epic-apple-trial-recap-video-tim-cook-xbox-playstation-business"&gt;in May&lt;/a&gt;, and we are still awaiting a verdict. The entire time, &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; hasn’t been on the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yfsEsi"&gt;Apple didn’t immediately reply to our request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665826/epic-games-apple-reinstate-fortnite-ios-korea-app-store-payment"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665826/epic-games-apple-reinstate-fortnite-ios-korea-app-store-payment</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T19:00:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T19:00:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter is beginning to test labels for bot accounts</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zdrA0ZldqBQjcj9HcUNseUl_r88=/0x342:2048x1707/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69837371/pasted_image_0.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An example of what an automated account label looks like on Twitter.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Twitter&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Cb2VMR"&gt;Twitter is beginning to roll out labels for automated accounts (or bot accounts), the company announced Thursday. “Examples of automated accounts you might see on Twitter include bots that help you find vaccine appointments and disaster early warning systems,” &lt;a href="https://help.twitter.com/en/using-twitter/automated-account-labels"&gt;Twitter said in an FAQ&lt;/a&gt;. “When these accounts let you know they’re automated, you get a better understanding of their purpose when you’re interacting with them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uLqckn"&gt;Initially, in what Twitter is calling a test, a small number of developers will be invited to be able to apply the labels to their accounts. For accounts in the test that have activated the labels, an “Automated” label will appear on profile pages and on tweets themselves for accounts. Twitter says all developers will be able to use the labels by the end of the year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qW6OlE"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;What's a bot and what's not? We're making it easier to identify &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GoodBots?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#GoodBots&lt;/a&gt; and their automated Tweets with new labels.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Starting today, we’re testing these labels to give you more context about who you're interacting with on Twitter. &lt;a href="https://t.co/gnN5jVU3pp"&gt;pic.twitter.com/gnN5jVU3pp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Twitter Support (@TwitterSupport) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSupport/status/1436073604173770754?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WIucV5"&gt;The rollout is kicking off a bit later than the July timeframe that was previously promised. Twitter is also working on a label to memorialize people who have died. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22435770/twitter-public-verification-program-launch-2021-pronouns-profile"&gt;Last we heard&lt;/a&gt;, that label was scheduled to be available this year.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665748/twitter-automated-account-bot-labels-tweets-test"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665748/twitter-automated-account-bot-labels-tweets-test</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T18:06:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T18:06:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>Refusing to wear a mask on an airplane could now cost you up to $3,000 in fines</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="United Airlines Cabin" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4CqNt8v08nhvefExpltypo1x04U=/0x209:5000x3542/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69837108/1335940043.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Gado/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pRMsvv"&gt;Refusing to wear a mask on an airplane is about to get really expensive. The Transportation Security Administration (TSA) announced that it was doubling civil penalties for those who refuse to comply with federal mask mandates on commercial airlines, at airports, or on certain forms of public transportation like passenger rail or intercity buses. Repeat offenders could now face fines of up to $3,000. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8c1Mn8"&gt;First time offenders will be fined $500-$1,000, up from the previous amount of $250. Second offenders will be fined $1,000-$3,000. The new TSA penalties, which are separate from the fines issued by the Federal Aviation Administration for unsafe behavior, will take effect September 10th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="G9oPOE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Wearing a mask protects the traveling public”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lUNMU9"&gt;“Wearing a mask protects the traveling public and all of the personnel who make the travel experience safe, secure, and comfortable,” said Secretary of Homeland Security Alejandro Mayorkas in a statement. “We will continue to enforce the mask mandate as long as necessary to protect public health and safety.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DI0Vd5"&gt;The day after he took office, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/21/22242249/biden-mask-required-public-transportation-airplane-covid"&gt;President Joe Biden issued an executive order&lt;/a&gt; requiring masks to be worn while traveling by airplanes, buses, or trains. It was an abrupt change from his predecessor Donald Trump, who actively blocked the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention from issuing a similar order in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2QIZ5F"&gt;That mandate had been set to expire in September 2021, but the TSA today extended it through January 18, 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="et1NOj"&gt;Enforcement of the mask mandate generally falls on airline crews, who have had to deal with a sharp increase in unruly passengers since flights resumed after lockdown. So far this year, the FAA logged 4,184 unruly passenger reports, the vast majority of which — 3,057 — involved mask wearing. Flight attendant union leader Sara Nelson recently said that the situation with poorly behaved passengers on planes was “completely nuts.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665625/tsa-mask-mandate-airplane-fines-covid-train-bus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665625/tsa-mask-mandate-airplane-fines-covid-train-bus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-09T17:37:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T17:37:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>FDA has rejected nearly one million flavored e-cigarettes </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/O1_ikkqlbqf2l3I19ZYt2FXuQMo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69836982/acastro_190916_1777_juul_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OLiRTC"&gt;After a year-long review of millions of e-cigarette&lt;strong&gt;-&lt;/strong&gt;related products, the Food and Drug Administration says it has rejected 946,000 flavored products, prohibiting them from being marketed or sold. It also said that the applications for 4.5 million products were missing materials that the agency required to make a decision. All of those products must also be removed from the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8bX9ui"&gt;The FDA &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/fda-makes-significant-progress-science-based-public-health-application-review-taking-action-over-90?utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=govdelivery"&gt;said in a statement&lt;/a&gt; Thursday that it has reviewed 93 percent of the applications submitted, which included 6.5 million products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iWkVjs"&gt;It will continue to review the remaining 7 percent of products. Notably, that group includes e-cigarettes made by Juul, a market leader and the company that drew &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/2/17928616/juul-ecig-vaping-fda-raid-inspection-smoking-nicotine"&gt;federal attention&lt;/a&gt; for its product’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/12/17850376/juul-ecigs-vaping-fda-smoking-nicotine-health-science"&gt;popularity&lt;/a&gt; among kids and teenagers, the &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/fda-to-seek-more-time-to-decide-fate-of-juul-11631196029?mod=pls_whats_news_us_business_f"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;. Juul only submitted applications for its tobacco- and menthol-flavored products — it stopped selling its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/17/20919415/juul-suspends-sale-fruity-flavor-pods-ecigarette"&gt;fruit&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/7/20953865/juul-mint-flavor-discontinue-ban-fda-vaping-illness"&gt;mint&lt;/a&gt; flavors in 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oBMKAu"&gt;The announcement marks the end of a year-long period where companies were allowed to sell vaping and e-cigarette products while the FDA reviewed applications from manufacturers. It’s also a turning point for the industry, which spent years operating outside the typical regulations around tobacco products. The FDA’s rules state that any new tobacco products have to submit an application and get authorization before they’re marketed and sold. As of 2016, vaping products and e-cigarettes were subject to those rules. But for years, the FDA deferred any enforcement, allowing those products to continue to be sold.  In 2019 a federal judge said companies had until September 2020 to submit their applications to stay on the market and ordered the FDA to review those applications within a year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wtVwOd"&gt;Now, any vaping and e-cigarette products that stay on the market without authorization are “marketed unlawfully,” the FDA warned in its statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dox2sc"&gt;The FDA’s review focused on whether a vaping or e-cigarette product had enough benefit to adult smokers — like helping adults smokers quit cigarettes — to outweigh the risk of attracting kids and teenagers. The rejected flavored products didn’t meet that bar because flavors are popular with kids and teenagers, the agency said. Teen vaping spiked in 2018 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/9/21429132/vaping-ecig-teens-decrease-school-juul-cdc"&gt;before dropping off&lt;/a&gt; in 2020, and the products were blamed for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/15/18096316/electronic-cigarette-flavor-ban-vaping-fda-pods-juul-myblu"&gt;hooking kids&lt;/a&gt; on nicotine who may have never started smoking otherwise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dVvJAx"&gt;“Continuing to take appropriate regulatory actions to protect the public, especially youth, from the harms of tobacco products remains one of the agency’s highest priorities,” Janet Woodcock, acting FDA commissioner, and Mitch Zeller, director of the FDA’s Center for Tobacco Products, said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665333/fda-vaping-flavors-authorization-juul"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22665333/fda-vaping-flavors-authorization-juul</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
