<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-11T19:20:57-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T19:20:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T19:20:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>Alexa can now greet people from your Ring Doorbell Pro</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sQfSsxf_Dx27xw_WPm7Ttly-2ho=/186x0:2028x1228/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68806917/Screen_Shot_2021_02_11_at_2.44.44_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Ring Video Doorbell Pro can now talk to your visitors with Alexa.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Amazon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hSQzzs"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.ring.com/2021/02/10/now-your-ring-video-doorbell-answers-the-door-for-you-with-smart-responses/"&gt;Amazon is announcing&lt;/a&gt; that it’s adding Alexa to its Ring Video Doorbell Pro, giving it the ability to talk to people when they come to your house. The feature is called Alexa Greetings, and requires that you have a Ring Protect subscription, which starts at $3 a month. If you do, Alexa can ask your visitors what they want, and they can choose to leave a video recording as a message. If they’re a delivery person, Alexa will be able to tell them where to leave the packages — assuming the delivery person is willing to talk to your robotic doorbell. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xy8hFM"&gt;Beyond automating the process of taking video messages and directing deliveries, it’s unclear if Alexa will bring any additional functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="H6PB2H"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EyzJ4wVr8JI?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Ar9kl1"&gt;The company is also announcing a Quick Replies feature, which should work on most of its doorbells without needing that subscription (though the company’s cheapest doorbell, the $60 Ring Video Doorbell Wired, isn’t getting that feature either). The feature lets you choose a canned response such as “we can’t answer the door right now, but if you’d like to leave a message, you can do it now” or “please leave the package outside. If you’d like to leave a message, you can do it now.” Of course, there are also replies that let the person standing at your door know that you’ll be there in just a minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jyguRv"&gt;Lastly, Amazon is also bringing a motion warning to some of its doorbells and cameras, which will audibly tell anyone around that Ring is recording if it detects motion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2qvK1O"&gt;All the new features can be turned on or off in the Ring app, so if you don’t want Alexa answering the door for you, you can simply not enable the feature. Also, if we’re adding new features to the Ring doorbells, it would be great to see &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227528/arlo-touchless-video-doorbell"&gt;a touchless doorbell function added&lt;/a&gt; (especially since most of these these new features require actually pressing the button).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iz6PFi"&gt;The announcements come at a time when the company is both receiving criticism for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/31/22258856/amazon-ring-partners-police-fire-security-privacy-cameras"&gt;working with police to provide footage&lt;/a&gt; captured by Ring cameras, and attempting to increase the cameras’ appeal to privacy-centric users by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22225716/ring-end-to-end-encryption-video-launch"&gt;testing end-to-end encryption support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22279020/alexa-ring-doorbell-greeting-quick-replies"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22279020/alexa-ring-doorbell-greeting-quick-replies</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T19:08:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T19:08:38-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tron invades Fortnite with Light Cycles and new skins</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gbp3hRkbcCqiSBruOIi25NQlt-w=/257x0:1877x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68806851/Et_fq5wXMAEgyf1.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xReTHl"&gt;Today Epic revealed the latest crossover for its battle royale hit, which brings the &lt;a href="https://www.epicgames.com/fortnite/en-US/news/tron-outfits-arrive-in-fortnite"&gt;retrofuturistic world of &lt;em&gt;Tron&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; into the game. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HogqRG"&gt;There are ten different &lt;em&gt;Tron&lt;/em&gt;-themed skins available in the in-game store right now, and each has a removable helmet. You can also get a Light Cycle glider and an Identity Disc pickaxe. It’s not yet clear whether you’ll be able to throw it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CeMrLa"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Welcome to the Grid.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Gear up as Grid Warriors and fight for the users! Tron Outfits are in the Shop now.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;More info: &lt;a href="https://t.co/brB6ItQaeH"&gt;https://t.co/brB6ItQaeH&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/XwXFIbh0Il"&gt;pic.twitter.com/XwXFIbh0Il&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Fortnite (@FortniteGame) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FortniteGame/status/1360015763684397064?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 12, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YQ3k5G"&gt;This season of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; has been particularly busy when it comes to licensed crossovers. The season debuted with the inclusion of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/22028767/the-mandalorian-fortnite-perfect-character-season-5"&gt;The Mandalorian and Baby Yoda&lt;/a&gt;, who have since been joined by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/3/22151470/fortnite-god-of-war-kratos-skin-now-available"&gt;Kratos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22166187/fortnite-master-chief-halo-the-walking-dead-the-game-awards"&gt;Master Chief&lt;/a&gt;, the Predator, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/30/22256564/fortnite-gi-joe-snake-eyes"&gt;G.I. Joe’s Snake Eyes&lt;/a&gt;. There’s also been a new skin based on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225416/thegrefg-record-fortnite-viewers-icon-skin-reveal-eu-heretics"&gt;Spanish streamer TheGrefg&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22231705/fortnite-soccer-skins-manchester-city-juventus-ac-milan-faze-clan"&gt;a line of soccer skins based on real-world teams&lt;/a&gt;. This followed a season that was entirely Marvel-themed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rCi2hbl17eDLABGfL5cFrq0gbjg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22298870/tron_gear_arrives_in_fortnite_1920x1080_494f59d9da92.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="OKAPqB"&gt;Truly, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22242696/fortnite-predator-marketing-brands-cross-promotion"&gt;no brand is safe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22276283/fortnite-tron-crossover-skins-light-cycles"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22276283/fortnite-tron-crossover-skins-light-cycles</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T18:27:42-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T18:27:42-05:00</updated>
    <title>Please GameStop it, Hollywood</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/D7x8u4sxOk_dUI2bqTZxUjzFO_s=/0x0:4015x2677/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68777408/gamestop_stock_sean_hollister.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mrbs5G"&gt;Okay, screenwriters, directors, authors, and production companies — we get it. You have some experience telling stories about Wall Street, the video game industry, or social networks, and you see some &lt;em&gt;mighty&lt;/em&gt; big dollar signs in the true tale of how Reddit managed to drive an ailing video game retailer’s stocks to completely ridiculous highs through sheer power of will plus a David versus Goliath narrative that probably &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/this-hedge-fund-made-700-million-on-gamestop-11612390687"&gt;doesn’t hold up under close examination&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JgitZr"&gt;So you’re making movies — five of them&lt;em&gt; — &lt;/em&gt;and two shows. Why not? It’s not like any one person has the rights to a news event like this! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9B0px3"&gt;As of Thursday, February 11th:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="NPyjwt"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/tv/news/gamestop-series-hbo-1234901914/"&gt;HBO now has a movie&lt;/a&gt; from the guy who wrote &lt;em&gt;Too Big to Fail &lt;/em&gt;and co-created Showtime’s &lt;em&gt;Billions&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="L4CGtC"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22261036/wallstreet-bets-movie-adaptation-deals-netflix-mgm"&gt;MGM optioned a movie&lt;/a&gt; based on a book that hasn’t even been written yet&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;whose author you’ll probably know from the book that became David Fincher’s &lt;em&gt;The Social Network&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7YcB5W"&gt;WallStreetBets’s founder &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/reddits-wallstreetbets-founder-sells-life-story-to-movie-producer-ratpac-entertainment-11612440001"&gt;has sold his life story to RatPac&lt;/a&gt;, a production company that worked on movies like &lt;em&gt;X-Men: First Class&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Revenant&lt;/em&gt;, before &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2018/film/news/brett-ratner-warners-cofinancing-deal-ends-1202750809/"&gt;its founder was accused of sexual misconduct in 2018&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="bmw51S"&gt;Netflix is negotiating with the screenwriter of &lt;em&gt;The Hurt Locker &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Zero Dark Thirty&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2021/02/netflix-gamestop-stock-movie-screenwriter-mark-boal-noah-centineo-scott-galloway-makeready-1234684568/"&gt;to write yet another movie&lt;/a&gt;, with one of those cute guys &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/12/21134580/netflix-to-all-the-boys-ive-loved-before-release-stream-subscriber"&gt;from &lt;em&gt;To All The Boys I’ve Loved Before&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; playing a role&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wz146r"&gt;Netflix is &lt;em&gt;also &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/tv/news/gamestop-docuseries-production-netflix-story-syndicate-1234906437/"&gt;working on a docu-series with Story Syndicate&lt;/a&gt;, the production company behind HBO’s &lt;em&gt;I’ll Be Gone In The Dark&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cxRrXy"&gt;The writer and director of &lt;em&gt;Console Wars &lt;/em&gt;(a book, also a movie) &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2021/02/jonah-tulis-gamestop-documentary-submarine-1234687991/"&gt;now have a feature-length documentary&lt;/a&gt; that’s “fully financed and already in production”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="IWCNng"&gt;And yes, there’s &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2021/02/pinky-promise-limited-series-to-the-moon-1234684845/"&gt;a whole TV show&lt;/a&gt;. How can this possibly turn into a TV show?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="DcVG6v"&gt;No. But just in case &lt;em&gt;yes&lt;/em&gt;, we imagine this set of completely disparate productions will need some excellent titles going forward. May we humbly suggest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="x4vgLr"&gt;GameStop: Never Stop Stopping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9Dbqnx"&gt;Uncut GMEs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EJW0P4"&gt;Meme Streets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="loazlg"&gt;Short Stop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="X0Y6yi"&gt;From Pre-Order to Stock Order&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7RC4H0"&gt;I Have No Shares, and I Must Sell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hQfsZM"&gt;Hate the Player, Not the GME&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="eEfdMO"&gt;The Weeb of Wall Street&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="X6plIl"&gt;The Game is Up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Z1PcBM"&gt;GameStop Won’t Stop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="g416y3"&gt;Diamond Hands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="l6gkQd"&gt;Robinhood and the Men in Gamer Chairs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LBHO7m"&gt;To The Moon, or How I Learned to Stop Worrying and HODL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RJjNcV"&gt;This Theater Still Exists Because of This Movie’s Events (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22251964/amc-stock-price-reddit-wallstreetbets-trading-gamestop"&gt;remember AMC&lt;/a&gt;?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qyXOgV"&gt;The Bankrupting of the Hedge Fund Melvin Capital by the Internet Message Board WallStreetBets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="ZsGbDh"&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.S. The dictionary definition of the word “stonk” is “a concentrated artillery bombardment,” so if I told you there is now a stonk of GameStop movies in development, that would largely be correct.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XCJBk1"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 11th, 6:24PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added two more projects to the list, because Hollywood doesn’t know when to hodl.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22268952/gamestop-stock-stonks-reddit-wallstreetbets-movies-tv-shows-hbo-netflix"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22268952/gamestop-stock-stonks-reddit-wallstreetbets-movies-tv-shows-hbo-netflix</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T18:20:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T18:20:38-05:00</updated>
    <title>Elon Musk tells Joe Rogan he wants the new Tesla Roadster to hover</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CEBcdt-l2GJvvikUQblQP9qJj_g=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68806667/Roadster_Front_58.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Tesla&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FXDNfq"&gt;Elon Musk has said for years that he wants to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/16/17459224/tesla-roadster-elon-musk-spacex-falcon-copv"&gt;offer a rocket thruster package to increase the already ludicrous speed of the second-generation Tesla Roadster&lt;/a&gt;. But now he says he’s considering using the thrusters to make the Roadster hover, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qcXMzW"&gt;“I want it to hover, and I was trying to figure out how to make this thing hover without, you know, killing people,” Musk told Joe Rogan in &lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/2aB2swgyXqbFA06AxPlFmr?si=_8doDtUvSn-kkUNFE9Kp7w&amp;amp;nd=1"&gt;a new episode of of the Joe Rogan Experience released Thursday&lt;/a&gt;. “Maybe it can hover like a meter above the ground, or something like that. If you plummet it’ll blow out the suspension but you’re not gonna die.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3CcwtM"&gt;It’s an extraordinary idea, and one that is sure to create a headache for safety regulators if Musk actually goes through with it when the new Roadster hits the market in 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tOwbLP"&gt;Musk has a history of pushing boundaries with Tesla’s cars, though he seems more willing lately to make choices that could force regulators to act. The redesigned Model S sedan and Model X SUV announced last month, for instance, each feature a U-shaped yoke steering wheel that &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/roadshow/news/tesla-model-s-yoke-steering-wheel-regulations-nhtsa/"&gt;was reportedly a surprise to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration&lt;/a&gt;. Those new vehicles will also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/29/22256504/teslas-model-s-x-redesign-automatic-shifting-prnd-gears"&gt;automatically shift between park, reverse, neutral, and drive&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sdyACj"&gt;Rogan asked Musk whether the steering wheel was legal in the new interview. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HlZAlZ"&gt;“Yeah, I mean they use a yoke in Formula One,” Musk said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ApqppD"&gt;“Yeah, but you’re not on the highway in a Formula One car,” Rogan responded. “I like driving like this, resting my hand on the top of the wheel.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xy6XQe"&gt;“Well, Autopilot is getting good enough that you won’t need to drive most of the time,” Musk said. “I find you can rest your hand on your knee... it works great.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c6ZsFx"&gt;In 2013, Musk bought James Bond’s submarine car from &lt;em&gt;The Spy Who Loved Me&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/10/18/4853098/elon-musk-will-make-bond-submarine-car-actually-transformbale"&gt;and pledged to make it transform&lt;/a&gt;. He &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CyberpunkGame/status/1354966674525597698"&gt;still owns the car&lt;/a&gt;, but has not responded to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/StarFire2258/status/1354967678058827779"&gt;repeated&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/StarFire2258/status/1197647960898600961"&gt;requests&lt;/a&gt; for comment about whether he’s achieved that goal.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278792/elon-musk-joe-rogan-tesla-roadster-spacex-hover-thrusters"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278792/elon-musk-joe-rogan-tesla-roadster-spacex-hover-thrusters</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T18:02:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T18:02:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>GameStop surge reportedly under federal investigation for possible manipulation</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b8kvcR2ycHxpOWSujM1x3bs7nXo=/0x0:2603x1735/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68806542/gamestop_sean_hollister_stock_photo.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zKkU5Z"&gt;Several US government agencies are investigating the GameStop stock brouhaha to determine whether there was market manipulation involved, &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/gamestop-mania-is-focus-of-federal-probes-into-possible-manipulation-11613066950"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt;. An enthusiastic group of day traders on Reddit’s r/WallStreetBets board encouraged each other to buy the stock and created what’s known as a short squeeze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gGJnDJ"&gt;The Department of Justice and the San Francisco US attorney are seeking information about activity surrounding GameStop’s stock by brokers and users on Reddit and other social media sites. Prosecutors have subpoenaed information from brokers, including Robinhood, where much of the trading activity occurred, the &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt; reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="v0dnUA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Reddit vs. Wall Street: the latest in the GameStop saga","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22253363/wall-street-bets-verge-stories-gamestock-reddit-discord"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="wNYTgx"&gt;During a two-week period that started in January, GME rose by some 500 percent, hitting a high of $483 on January 28th before coming back down. The stock closed Thursday at $51.50. Regulators are likely looking into whether the Reddit activity constituted an illegal pump-and-dump scheme, where traders spread inaccurate information to artificially boost a stock’s price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rfaP2M"&gt;The Securities and Exchange Commission &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/02/01/962946809/sec-acting-chair-unpacks-the-gamestop-reddit-robinhood-wall-street-debacle"&gt;is also looking into&lt;/a&gt; whether there was manipulation and probing whether Robinhood and other brokerages that temporarily froze or otherwise restricted trading of GME were in compliance with federal regulations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OTN78B"&gt;Robinhood is also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22254656/robinhood-gamestop-stonks-trade-freeze-class-action-lawsuits"&gt;facing dozens of lawsuits&lt;/a&gt; after it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/28/22254102/robinhood-gamestop-bloc-stock-purchase-amc-reddit-wsb"&gt;restricted several stocks&lt;/a&gt; popular on the r/WallStreetBets subreddit, with people alleging the company sought to “manipulate the market” to help other financial institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2eLCUe"&gt;The House Financial Services Committee is holding a hearing into the GameStop drama on February 18th, where Reddit CEO Steve Huffman and Robinhood founder Vlad Tenev are &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2021/02/01/robinhood-ceo-testify-maxine-waters-464491"&gt;expected to appear&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3NWqzW"&gt;Robinhood did not immediately respond to a request for comment Thursday. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278799/gamestop-surge-federal-investigation-manipulation-robinhood-reddit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278799/gamestop-surge-federal-investigation-manipulation-robinhood-reddit</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T17:31:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T17:31:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>LG’s new Gram laptops are available for purchase</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Three LG Gram laptops open, facing the camera in a convex semicircle. Each screen displays a space image." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h2aFXC_utXKY5Eas7P7LtOs28KU=/160x0:865x470/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68806349/2021_LG_gram_Lineup.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: LG&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Iru5I6"&gt;Several of LG’s 2021 Gram laptops are now available for purchase. LG announced the new lineup &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/6/22217915/lg-gram-17-2021-laptops-announced-specs-ces"&gt;earlier this year&lt;/a&gt; but had not yet announced pricing or availability. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vAsSxb"&gt;The models you can buy now are the Gram 14, the Gram 16, and the Gram 17. The company also has two convertible laptops — the Gram 14 2-in-1 and the Gram 16 2-in-1 — coming in mid-March. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The 14-inch LG Gram 2-in-1 standing in tent mode, angled to the left. The start menu is open; a stylus appears to press one of its icons." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ETV6PqtFNSCIWHOSCrY20n2KTA0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22298501/14T90P_G_9.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: LG&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 14-inch convertible is coming in mid-March.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6WHbKS"&gt;The models are targeting the high-end ultraportable space, with Gram 14 configurations starting at $999. Gram 16 models start at $1,299, while the singular Gram 17 model is $1,799. This last model only comes in black, while the 16-inch and 14-inch counterparts come in white and silver as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3BFRWb"&gt;Gram laptops are known for being unusually light: the Gram 17 is just 2.98 pounds, which is virtually unheard of for a 17-inch laptop. Gram models we’ve reviewed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21310392/lg-gram-17-review-display-weight-specs-price-features"&gt;in the past&lt;/a&gt; have also featured excellent battery life and good, roomy displays. (All Gram models have 16:10 aspect ratios.) The new laptops all include Intel’s new 11th Gen processors and are certified through Intel’s Evo program (which means Intel thinks they’re top performers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="AhIGOQ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"LG Gram 17 review: lighter than it looks","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21310392/lg-gram-17-review-display-weight-specs-price-features"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="2WMVl7"&gt;You can purchase available models now on LG’s website. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="HpsSMN"&gt;
&lt;aside id="6rGpbN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"LG Gram 14","description":"$999.99","label":"Buy from LG","url":"https://www.lg.com/us/laptops/lg-14z90p-k.aaw3u1-ultra-slim-laptop"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id="J8vlr0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"LG Gram 16","description":"$1,399.99","label":"Buy from LG","url":"https://www.lg.com/us/laptops/lg-16z90p-k.aab6u1-ultra-slim-laptop"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id="j4k53c"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"LG Gram 17","description":"$1,749.99","label":"Buy from LG","url":"https://www.lg.com/us/laptops/lg-17z95n-g.aas9u1-ultra-slim-laptop"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278923/lg-gram-laptops-2021-launch-price-release-date-purchase"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278923/lg-gram-laptops-2021-launch-price-release-date-purchase</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T17:28:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T17:28:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>NASA is bargaining with a US space startup for a Soyuz seat</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Expedition 46 Soyuz Launch" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0x5ZdrBIGgnFNWSPb6rF7ZotnKM=/247x0:5662x3610/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68806316/501438224.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by NASA/ Joel Kowsky via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uhx1Hs"&gt;NASA is planning to buy an astronaut seat on a Russian Soyuz spacecraft through Texas-based aerospace firm Axiom Space, according to two people familiar with the plans. The seat is a backup for NASA in case its upcoming ride with SpaceX runs into technical problems, and it suggests the agency is proceeding cautiously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eKrzWF"&gt;The agency announced Tuesday it was weighing options to procure a Soyuz seat as a safety net to keep the International Space Station staffed with US astronauts. It’s the second time NASA has procured a Russian seat through a US-based company, following a deal with Boeing in 2017 for five Soyuz seats. This time, the deal is with Axiom – a startup that arranges private astronaut rides to space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RW8Ytd"&gt;The terms of the agreement for the astronaut seat are still being negotiated, according to the two people who spoke &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;under the condition of anonymity because the talks are private.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="XNYrJA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Buying Soyuz seats from a US company has only happened once before&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lR1eZV"&gt;The space agency relied on Russia to provide rides to the space station when the US shuttle program retired in 2011. NASA started its Commercial Crew Program after Russia hiked the prices of its Soyuz seats as high as $90 million — without it, Russia would have been the only option. Last year, SpaceX launched its first crew of US astronauts to space under the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vv8nVb"&gt;An Axiom spokesman declined to comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fT1hNk"&gt;“A U.S. company reached out to NASA with a proposal that could meet NASA’s needs,”&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;agency spokesman Josh Finch said in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge.&lt;/em&gt; “However, we are unable to share the name of the company as NASA has not entered into any agreement regarding the seat and that information is procurement sensitive.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6C4Bsg"&gt;NASA has been in talks with Russia’s space agency, Roscosmos, for months to trade Crew Dragon or Boeing Starliner seats for additional seats on Soyuz spacecraft, rather than buying those seats with cash. NASA expects to fly Russian cosmonauts alongside American astronauts starting in fall 2021, Finch said. The astronaut in the Axiom-brokered Soyuz seat would fly sometime between spring and fall of this year, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ns2FnG"&gt;In 2020, NASA bought a Soyuz seat from Russia for Kate Rubins for $90 million — and agreed to launch Russian cargo to the station for a period of two years, an “in-kind” deal potentially worth millions more. Now, NASA wants a seat on the April 10th MS-18 mission, which already has three Russian astronauts booked to fly. The deal with Axiom would likely involve booting one of the Russians from MS-18 to make room for a US astronaut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="my7l54"&gt;It was unclear how much NASA is considering paying Axiom for the single Soyuz seat or what cut Axiom would get from the deal. Buying Soyuz seats from a US company has only happened once before, in 2017. Then, NASA bought from Boeing, which had obtained the rights to five seats in an unrelated settlement with Russia’s Energia. Boeing sold the seats to NASA for a total of $374 million, the agency said at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278958/nasa-axiom-soyuz-russian-commercial-crew-spacex"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278958/nasa-axiom-soyuz-russian-commercial-crew-spacex</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T17:15:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T17:15:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>I Miss My Bar is like audio therapy for barflies</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Art from I Miss My Bar" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yLMP8xtzXGQPnLGXjwFvgiu-5TQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68806270/imissmybar.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Maverick&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2qxcBD"&gt;Sure, you can drink at home with some music on, but that doesn’t replicate the feeling of being out at a bar among friends and total strangers. As it turns out, nothing can, other than... well, being at a bar. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HhOWy7"&gt;But a project called I Miss My Bar, via &lt;a href="https://belong.io/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;belong.io&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, comes the closest to making me feel like I’m at my local watering hole — loud voices, street sounds, and all. The only element missing is the trademark bar scent of booze mixed with cleaning products. &lt;em&gt;You know the smell&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UQYrHh"&gt;Anyway, &lt;a href="http://www.imissmybar.com/"&gt;head to I Miss My Bar&lt;/a&gt;, where, unlike real life, you can choose just how loud everyone is talking. You can also tweak the volume of a number of different sound effects that might make you even more nostalgic for better times, like the clinks of a bartender working, corks being popped, liquid being poured into a glass, the rain pattering on a window, horns honking outside, you get the idea — the normal commotion of pre-pandemic gatherings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="z66O9C"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;the only thing this is missing is presets, like "corner booth at Lucky Strike" or "music too loud in backroom at Von" &lt;a href="https://t.co/rrdB9tpAcn"&gt;https://t.co/rrdB9tpAcn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Rex Sorgatz (@fimoculous) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fimoculous/status/1359898059707146240?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="EacAJD"&gt;This project was kicked off by &lt;a href="https://maverickmty.com/"&gt;Maverick&lt;/a&gt;, a bar out of San Pedro Garza García, Mexíco. It was developed and designed by two companies, Lagom and Tandem, that operate out of the same city, so it’s less of a fan project and more of an ad campaign of sorts. Nevertheless, folks who work at that bar are updating the playlist on the site each week, and I already like what I’m seeing here. This particular week is hosting nothing but David Bowie, and if you want to subscribe to its playlist on Spotify, &lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/playlist/63Qxq57TekCoexHgBivTwu?si=Cb7h8zxATpqLBkgjgMGJlA"&gt;you can do that right here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fQnNO0"&gt;Once you’re all settled, hop on Zoom or your preferred video chat app, and try to relive some of the good times with friends and family. Cheers.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278889/i-miss-my-bar-maverick-site-sounds-playlist-people-talking"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278889/i-miss-my-bar-maverick-site-sounds-playlist-people-talking</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T17:06:28-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T17:06:28-05:00</updated>
    <title>Disney Plus hits 94.9 million subscribers, beating its four-year goal in 14 months</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Mandalorian" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1M0rMXAaY5Jf6uadtKdQCQ_AmEc=/713x0:3128x1610/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68806212/HUC2_FF_003556.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Lucasfilm Ltd.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FJi26x"&gt;Disney Plus reached a new high of 94.9 million subscribers around the world, the company announced in its Q1 2021 earnings report. Hulu now has 39.4 million subscribers, while ESPN Plus has 12.1 million subscribers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dMaeoj"&gt;The strong numbers for Disney Plus show a noticeable jump from the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22165579/disney-plus-86-million-subscribers-netflix-hbo-max-streaming"&gt;86 million subscribers&lt;/a&gt; Disney announced it had reached at its investor day in December 2020. The surge in subscribers likely came from holiday streaming releases of major titles like Pixar’s &lt;em&gt;Soul&lt;/em&gt; and the final episodes of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22188706/the-mandalorian-season-2-episode-8-rescue-star-wars-grogu-skywalker-saga"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt;’s second season&lt;/a&gt; in December. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="zlYQYZ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Disney Plus is doing better than Disney ever imagined&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rQpgZe"&gt;It also means that Disney has already crossed its original 90 million subscriber goal for the service — a number the company originally expected to take four years to reach. The company has &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2020/digital/news/disney-plus-hits-86-8-million-subscribers-1234850846/"&gt;since revised that four-year plan&lt;/a&gt; with a new goal of reaching between 230 million and 260 million subscribers by 2024. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MnpnrS"&gt;Notably, that 94.9 million benchmark was as of January 2nd, 2021, which means it doesn’t factor in possible boosts in subscribers that Disney may have received from the debut of its first Marvel Studios TV series, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22229076/wandavision-marvel-studios-disney-plus-streaming-loki-falcon-winter-solider-black-widow-theatrical"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which was released on January 15th. Assuming the highly anticipated show has caused a similar bump in subscribers, it’s possible that Disney has already managed to cross the 100 million subscriber mark by now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="4rTzYR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The 52 things Disney just announced","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167976/disney-investor-day-2020-biggest-announcements-plus-marvel-star-wars-pixar-animation"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="fS8tHq"&gt;Overall, Disney’s direct-to-consumer streaming business is up 73 percent year over year, with revenue of $3.5 billion. Disney is still working on increasing the amount of money it actually makes from its nearly 100 million Disney Plus subscribers, though: average monthly revenue per paid subscriber dropped to $4.03 per subscriber, in part because it’s now factoring in Disney Plus Hotstar (available in India and Indonesia), which charges considerably less than the service in other markets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r2Axkx"&gt;Disney is planning to help boost those numbers in the coming months, though, with its first price increase for the service in the US set to arrive next month: starting on March 26th, Disney Plus will cost $7.99 per month or $79.99 per year (up from $6.99 a month or $69.99 per year). The Disney bundle — of Disney Plus, Hulu, and ESPN Plus will also see a $1 increase to $13.99 a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="71waDk"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Streaming was one of the brighter spots for Disney in its quarterly earnings&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PVr3cb"&gt;Streaming was one of the brighter spots for Disney in its quarterly earnings. While the company beat expectations, with total revenue of $16.25 billion, revenue was still down more than 20 percent year over year. That’s largely driven by the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic, which has shuttered the company’s cruise ship business and heavily limited the number of customers it can host at its parks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7ZIJFV"&gt;Similarly, limited movie theaters have forced the company to delay many of its major blockbusters, although a similar reduction in marketing and distributing those films means that film delays have had less of an impact on Disney’s business overall. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0z0L1g"&gt;Disney is continuing to focus on its direct-to-consumer offerings in the coming months: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22165950/disney-star-streaming-service-hotstar-international-movies-tv"&gt;Star&lt;/a&gt;, its replacement for Hulu for international customers, will release in Europe, Canada, and New Zealand on February 23rd. &lt;em&gt;Raya and the Last Dragon&lt;/em&gt; is set to debut on Disney Plus as a paid Premier Access title on March 5th, along with Marvel shows &lt;em&gt;The Falcon and the Winter Soldier&lt;/em&gt; in March and &lt;em&gt;Loki&lt;/em&gt; in May. The company also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167976/disney-investor-day-2020-biggest-announcements-plus-marvel-star-wars-pixar-animation"&gt;recently announced dozens of new Marvel, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;, and Disney shows and films&lt;/a&gt; planned for the streaming platform for the next several years. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278874/disney-plus-94-9-million-subscribers-q1-2021-earnings"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278874/disney-plus-94-9-million-subscribers-q1-2021-earnings</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T16:40:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T16:40:38-05:00</updated>
    <title>Uber and Lyft are getting less unprofitable, but COVID-19 is still a drag on their business</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-TRANSPORT-RIDESHARE-DEMONSTRATION" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JeElLBGx7Xxif5eP3mhq9LsG3Vo=/0x0:5568x3712/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68806094/1227939563.jpg.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by ROBYN BECK/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Hougm8"&gt;Uber and Lyft reported their quarterly earnings this week, and while both companies are showing signs of improvement, the COVID-19 pandemic continues to cast a long shadow over the overall ride-hailing business. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FvPCaM"&gt;It raises the question of how both companies, neither of which have ever turned a profit, can hope to claw their way out of the deeper financial pit in which they’ve been cast by COVID. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="9auZ7q"&gt;&lt;q&gt;2020 was a brutal year for Uber and Lyft&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cLZogC"&gt;Uber lost $968 million over the last three months, with its adjusted net revenues down 16 percent compared to the fourth quarter of 2019. Over the entire year, the company reported a net loss of $6.7 billion, down slightly from the $8.5 billion it lost in 2019. It brought in less revenue compared to 2019 — $11.1 billion versus $13 billion — likely due to facilitating fewer trips, 5 billion in 2020 versus 7 billion in 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oTkA0M"&gt;On the flip side, Lyft lost $458.2 million over this past quarter, with its adjusted net revenues down a staggering 44 percent year over year. It lost $1.8 billion over the entire year, compared to $2.6 billion lost in 2019. (Both Uber and Lyft factor in stock-based compensation and payroll tax expenses into its net losses.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qzvrno"&gt;As coronavirus cases spiked in much of the country over the winter, Uber and Lyft started to lose a significant portion of their customer base. People stayed at home, or when they did go out, they opted not to use ride-hailing apps. Uber said it had 93 million “monthly active platform consumers,” its term for users who take at least one ride on Uber or buy at least one meal on Uber Eats — a 16 percent decrease year over year. Meanwhile, Lyft reported a drop in monthly active users of 45 percent, from 22 million in the fourth quarter of 2019 to 12.5 million in 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rSQ69N"&gt;They may offer nearly identical services, but Uber and Lyft have very different strategies for stabilizing their businesses. Uber’s plans involve growing the parts of its business that it perceives as doing well, such as food and grocery delivery, while shedding those line items that aren’t generating any revenue and likely would continue to be a financial drain for years to come. It acquired two delivery startups, Cornershop and Postmates, and sold off its micromobility, autonomous vehicle, and aerial taxi divisions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="yxJckY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Uber is predicting that its delivery business will be profitable in 2021&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nwIbHJ"&gt;Uber is predicting that its delivery business will be profitable in 2021. It’s certainly looking better than the company’s other line items: delivery gross bookings was $10.05 billion this year, up 130 percent from 2019. “While the external environment remains uncertain, I am more optimistic than ever about Uber’s future,” CEO Dara Khosrowshahi said in an earnings call this week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9r5zFq"&gt;Delivery is no slam dunk for Uber; if anything, it could end up proving as risky as ride-hailing. Third-party delivery apps have &lt;a href="https://www.eater.com/22224695/uber-eats-postmates-grubhub-delivery-wars-2021"&gt;come under fire in recent months&lt;/a&gt; for imposing exorbitant fees on already-struggling restaurants. Consumer pushback against UberEats and its competitors DoorDash and GrubHub is growing, while the companies are spending billions of dollars to grow their customer bases. But state legislatures are wary of the potential for food delivery to metastasize into something as problematic as ride-hailing and are already eyeing legislation to rein in onerous fees. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xtNh98"&gt;Lyft, on the other hand, has no delivery service of its own, so instead, it’s focusing on reducing costs, and in some cases, reducing supply to help mitigate those costs — that means preventing new drivers from joining the app while reducing its spending on marketing and other incentives. “Given the effect on demand, we were able to reduce driver acquisition and incentive spend, which had a positive impact on our financial results,” Lyft CEO Logan Green said in an earnings call. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S6f9QW"&gt;Uber has the resources to grow (and shrink) its way out of the pandemic, while Lyft does not. It needs to focus on staying small, but not too small that it can’t compete with its much larger rival. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kWHe28"&gt;Despite a brutal year, the market has been kind to both Uber and Lyft. Lyft’s shares moved 14 percent higher in 2020, and the stock enters this trading week 23 percent higher than where it was at the start of last year. Uber’s shares shrank slightly after its earnings report, but the company still trades at a much higher revenue multiple than Lyft. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xHuyQB"&gt;Meanwhile, Uber and Lyft drivers are pushing ahead with their &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227042/uber-lyft-prop-22-lawsuit-overturn-drivers-california"&gt;legal challenges against Prop 22&lt;/a&gt;, the ballot measure that allows the companies to continue treating their workers like independent contractors. President Joe Biden, who opposed Prop 22, &lt;a href="https://news.bloomberglaw.com/daily-labor-report/biden-moves-to-oust-top-labor-board-attorney-robb"&gt;fired a Trump-appointed member of the National Labor Relations Board&lt;/a&gt; who authored several opinions affirming Uber and Lyft’s refusal to classify drivers as employees. And Democrats in Congress are hoping to push a bill that would echo California’s failed effort to make it harder for companies to treat workers as independent contractors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cSkd9p"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/5/21551136/uber-prop-22-victory-national-q3-2020-earnings"&gt;The victory lap&lt;/a&gt; could be short-lived. Regulatory hurdles dot the road ahead for these ride-hailing companies. Profitability may be the least of their concerns. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22277043/uber-lyft-earnings-q4-2020-profit-loss-covid"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22277043/uber-lyft-earnings-q4-2020-profit-loss-covid</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
