<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2022-01-12T13:08:41-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-12T13:08:41-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-12T13:08:41-05:00</updated>
    <title>Magic Leap’s new AR headset is rolling out to healthcare companies</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Magic Leap 2 headset" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sh8re6TBmhn0PkKEtBz7HXPhiLw=/504x0:2376x1248/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70379646/ML_Teaser_Desktop.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.magicleap.com/en-us/news/op-ed/my-first-year-at-magic-leap-and-the-opportunity-ahead" target="_blank"&gt;Magic Leap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="E0ocSw"&gt;Augmented reality headset maker Magic Leap has announced early partners for its Magic Leap 2 headset — a signal that the once consumer-focused company is still moving ahead with its enterprise-focused business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yQmIyM"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/magic-leap-announces-health-technology-early-access-program-participants-for-magic-leap-2-301459403.html?tc=eml_cleartime"&gt;In a press release today&lt;/a&gt;, Magic Leap named four healthcare partners that are getting access to the device: clinical data visualization company SentiAR, neurotechnology company SyncThink, diagnostics company Heru, and surgical software tool Brainlab. The Magic Leap 2 is slated for more general release in mid-2022. It’s a smaller, lighter follow-up to the Magic Leap headset that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/10/17960722/magic-leap-one-creator-edition-shipping-continuous-us"&gt;debuted in 2018&lt;/a&gt;; in an interview with &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;, Magic Leap CEO Peggy Johnson said it would be “slightly” pricier than its predecessor, which starts at $2,295.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="02Qe3D"&gt;Johnson tells &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; that Magic Leap sees potential for buyers in “industries that are used to wearing something on their eyes,” a category including surgeons and manufacturing workers. Magic Leap is also interested in military customers who could use the headsets for training; the company previously pursued a US Army contract &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/28/18116939/microsoft-army-hololens-480-million-contract-magic-leap"&gt;that eventually went&lt;/a&gt; to Microsoft’s competing HoloLens headset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="scqTdj"&gt;Magic Leap raised billions of dollars as a consumer headset company, but the company downscaled its plans rapidly — and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/7/21315864/magic-leap-new-ceo-microsoft-business-vp-rony-abovitz-step-down"&gt;replaced its previous CEO Rony Abovitz with Johnson&lt;/a&gt; — in 2020 amid significant layoffs. It’s reportedly considered acquisition offers from other companies, &lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/2020-03-12-magic-leap-up-for-sale.html"&gt;allegedly including&lt;/a&gt; the major healthcare player Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson, but ultimately &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/11/22721345/magic-leap-500-million-funding-ar-headset"&gt;raised $500 million&lt;/a&gt; in funding for enterprise applications last year. If Magic Leap pivoted back to the consumer market, it could find itself competing with more established brands, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22819963/snap-ar-spectacles-glasses-hands-on-pictures-design-features"&gt;including Snap&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22749008/facebook-oculus-project-cambria-pro-vr-ar-headset"&gt;Meta, formerly known as Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="idv6D2"&gt;However, the company is apparently “absolutely” open to returning — although Johnson says that AR technology would have to become smaller and its potential applications more compelling to be worth the shift.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22880090/magic-leap-2-ar-headset-rollout-healthcare-companies"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22880090/magic-leap-2-ar-headset-rollout-healthcare-companies</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-12T12:54:52-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-12T12:54:52-05:00</updated>
    <title>The PS5 and Xbox Series X will restock on Thursday for Walmart Plus subscribers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hlNr08zeaUX12iagwr-22yVLtwI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70379557/acastro_210511_1777_psRestock_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4C9oZp"&gt;In case you hadn’t noticed, it’s becoming ever-so-slightly less of a maddening exercise to get your hands on a PS5 or Xbox Series X. Granted, it’s still harder than it should be, but recent retailer restocks have taken longer to sell out than they used to. So, here’s hoping that you’re able to purchase whichever console you want &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fshop%2Fearlyaccess&amp;amp;sharedid=vergerestock01132022" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;during tomorrow’s restock at Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, which is specifically for paid Walmart Plus subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BJbH1G"&gt;Starting at 3PM ET / 12PM PT on Thursday, January 13th, Walmart will offer the &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-PlayStation-5-Video-Game-Console%2F165545420&amp;amp;sharedid=vergerestock01132022" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$499.99 PS5 with a disc drive&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-PlayStation-5-Digital-Edition-Video-Game-Consoles%2F987823383%3Fathbdg%3DL1100&amp;amp;sharedid=vergerestock01132022" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$399.99 PS5 console that can only play digital titles&lt;/a&gt;, as well as the &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FXbox-Series-X-Video-Game-Console-Black%2F443574645%3Fathbdg%3DL1100&amp;amp;sharedid=vergerestock01132022" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$499.99 Xbox Series X&lt;/a&gt;. These consoles will be available to non-trial Walmart Plus members, meaning you actually have to opt-in to pay Walmart for the service to get access (&lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Faccount%2Fplus%2Foverview&amp;amp;sharedid=vergerestock01132022" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;here’s where you can sign up for Walmart Plus&lt;/a&gt;). Though, Walmart is calling these “early access” deals, perhaps suggesting that they’ll open up to non-Plus customers after a window of time. In the past, the window of exclusivity has been three hours. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PEO0nO"&gt;To ease the checkout process, make sure you have your shipping and payment info ready to go ahead of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="mdeeQD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10971562"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="MTdDxK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10971567"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="I0pbDz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10297750"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="GyhutA"&gt;Some essentials for PS5 owners&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="gahs20"&gt;In case you plan to get lucky with buying a console today, there are several excellent games and accessories that we recommend. Starting with games, head over to this list to see the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22825859/ps5-best-games-playstation-5-sony-2021"&gt;PS5’s best games of 2021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OfzOFX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10911764"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="MapxSt"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10687661"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="4jPPkA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10499033"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="potP0F"&gt;Getting an Xbox Series X? Check out these add-ons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="3yJrjt"&gt;If you’re on team Xbox, you may already know about Game Pass Ultimate, which gives you discounts, access to the ever-expanding catalog of Game Pass games, along with online multiplayer. You may never need to pay full price for a game for your new console. Though, whether you do want to pay full price or you just need some ideas on what to play, check out the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22825913/xbox-series-x-s-best-games-microsoft-2021"&gt;Xbox’s best games of 2021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="QLDoEs"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10420028"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="MhgToB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9562459"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="AqRy4o"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22879881/ps5-xbox-series-x-digital-disc-console-restock-walmart-plus-early-access-subscriber"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22879881/ps5-xbox-series-x-digital-disc-console-restock-walmart-plus-early-access-subscriber</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-12T12:49:27-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-12T12:49:27-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Nvidia Shield is getting Android 11 and other upgrades</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VuVW_PvcnT5BtEWkMIzJ_U1yHXs=/130x0:1150x680/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70379533/SHIELD_TV_Experience_9.0_1280x680.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MErG59"&gt;The seemingly indefatigable Nvidia Shield is getting another major Android update, with the new &lt;a href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/2022/01/12/shield-experience-9/"&gt;Shield Software Experience Upgrade 9.0&lt;/a&gt; that adds Android 11 and a host of other upgrades. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JJtuji"&gt;The new update is rolling out to all Shield set-top boxes, including the original model from 2015 — which originally ran Android 5.0 Lollipop when it first launched. The latest upgrade to Android 11 gives the popular set-top box the honor of being one of the most upgraded Android devices ever released. To put that in perspective, a comparable Android phone from 2015 would be the Galaxy S6, which never got past Android Nougat (Android 7.0). &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rShSYTLzaMiFOev2WsrauwRWtn8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23163718/blog_preview_image_1280x680_no_copy_1.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="IaVdii"&gt;In addition to updating the OS to Android 11, the latest Shield software is also bringing some other benefits. Nvidia is switching to use Google’s Gboard keyboard by default for text entry (meaning it’ll be easier to use Google Assistant in text fields), and Bluetooth support has been updated to add support for Bluetooth aptX and to automatically disconnect Bluetooth devices when the Shield enters sleep mode. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JZOklq"&gt;Subscribers to GeForce Now will also see some new perks. The Shield now supports 4K HDR streaming for customers who pay for GeForce Now’s RTX 3080 tier (the service’s priciest level of service at $99.99 for six months). And all GeForce Now customers are getting better Twitch integration, with simultaneous gaming and streaming now available in high quality and support for more Bluetooth mice and keyboards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a7gKTO"&gt;The update marks the latest for Nvidia’s set-top box hardware, which also received major software releases last year, adding things &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/17/22538142/nvidia-shield-android-tv-update-redesign-discover-tab-apps"&gt;like a modern Google TV-style UI&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/26/21402819/nvidia-shield-tv-update-4k-upscaling-remote-customize"&gt;improved 4K upscaling on newer Shield hardware&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8V8TJg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22880057/nvidia-shield-android-11-update-set-top-box-streaming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22880057/nvidia-shield-android-11-update-set-top-box-streaming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-12T12:47:08-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-12T12:47:08-05:00</updated>
    <title>Sony says it’s still making new PS4s, but most stores aren’t selling them</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="ps4 playstation 4 stock" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MV4zctYkXiDZSs-8CtxVU5JpKFY=/0x0:1100x733/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70379517/DSCF4074.1419980353.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;ps4 playstation 4 stock&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UJEKiD"&gt;While many of us fall somewhere between trying to find a new-generation gaming console like the Xbox Series X / S and PlayStation 5 or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22791886/ps5-xbox-series-x-next-gen-consoles-games-delays-supply-shorage"&gt;trying to find worthwhile gaming experiences once we have them&lt;/a&gt;, Sony tells &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-01-12/sony-tackles-playstation-5-shortage-by-making-more-ps4-consoles"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; it’s still manufacturing new PlayStation 4s. According to the report, an internal plan had projected an end to the production of the system in 2021, but the ongoing shortages will cause the company to build about a million PS4s in 2022, according to sources. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="cNEMix"&gt;&lt;q&gt;If you really need one, Sony will still sell you a PS4 Slim for $300&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tL2OZW"&gt;Sony confirmed that PS4 production is still ongoing, providing a quote to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; saying the system “is one of the best-selling consoles ever, and there is always crossover between generations.” That fits, since it certainly feels like the PS4 should still be around — there are still new cross-generation games coming out like &lt;em&gt;Horizon Forbidden West&lt;/em&gt;, and it’s not like you can reliably find a PS5 just sitting on store shelves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WR9Dkw"&gt;The curious thing is that, at least online, we couldn’t find many new PlayStation 4 consoles either. A check of Best Buy, Amazon, Walmart, and Target showed all the stores either lacking a listing for PlayStation 4 consoles entirely or saying they’re out of stock on new systems. Only GameStop had even a hint of a new system but only in-store, and stores within 500 miles of my location all claimed not to have any. If you absolutely must have a PS4 Slim right now, &lt;a href="https://direct.playstation.com/en-us/consoles/console/playstation4-1tb-console.3003348"&gt;Sony will sell you one directly&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2017/4/18/15344360/sony-ps4-slim-1tb-hard-drive-announced"&gt;the same $299.99 price it’s charged since 2017&lt;/a&gt;. But you can only get one — as its site notes, “[due] to high demand, consoles are limited to 1 per household.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D2tZiC"&gt;Microsoft’s Xbox One lineup is in similar shape, if not worse. Prior to the launch of the Xbox Series consoles, Microsoft &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/16/21327330/microsoft-xbox-one-x-s-digital-edition-discontinued"&gt;told us it would discontinue the Xbox One X and Xbox One S Digital Edition while continuing production of the standard, disc-equipped Xbox One S&lt;/a&gt;. We haven’t seen an official update since, but it appears that many months have passed since anyone in the US has reported seeing a new Xbox One console on sale anywhere. &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fd%2Fxbox-one-s-1tb-console-starter-bundle%2F93pzdx8q3t97%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%3Adealstab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;A Microsoft Store page is still offering bundles&lt;/a&gt;, but we couldn’t quite click the button to put one in our digital shopping cart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zNGGQD"&gt;Microsoft didn’t immediately respond to a question about the manufacturing status of older systems, but for now, the Xbox Series S might be the only easily obtainable gaming system that you can get brand new. Various iterations of the Nintendo Switch seem to come and go on retail websites, so it mostly depends on which model you’re looking for. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wpDO3B"&gt;For the PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X, there are signs the situation is improving. Retail drops have lasted longer and come on a more regular basis than usual. At the same time, reseller prices on sites like &lt;a href="https://stockx.pvxt.net/c/482924/530344/9060?u=https%3A%2F%2Fstockx.com%2Fmicrosoft-xbox-series-x-console-black&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;StockX&lt;/a&gt; have continued to slip. For the PlayStation 5, the recent peak for sale prices came in early November at $811, while systems are currently moving for $638. StockX sale prices for the Xbox Series X similarly have dropped over the same period, from $797 on November 4th to the $570–$580 range recently.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22880062/ps4-manufacturing-sony-ps5-shortage-xbox-one"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22880062/ps4-manufacturing-sony-ps5-shortage-xbox-one</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-12T10:45:20-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-12T10:45:20-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s largest iPad Pro with the M1 processor is $100 off</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The iPad Pro with the Liquid Retina XDR display" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3c1n-CLOaIRAs0MA4nf51TOTOH8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70378854/vpavic_210512_4592_0192.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The larger 12.9-inch iPad sports a Mini LED screen and more real estate for use with Apple’s Pencil.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mpzFb6"&gt;There is no better screen in the world of tablets (yet) than the Mini LED panel on the 12.9-inch iPad Pro of 2021. While Mini LED is not super common yet — though we did see &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22871890/computer-monitors-ces-2022-lg-samsung-asus-alienware-oled-qd-mini-led-ark"&gt;more of it announced at CES 2022&lt;/a&gt; — it’s appealing as it achieves deeper black levels, a high contrast ratio, and high brightness. It’s also more expensive than a traditional LCD panel, so any dollar saved can be a worthwhile one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Kcfaiz"&gt;If you want that Mini LED-equipped iPad Pro, we have a solid discount to share. Apple’s Wi-Fi-equipped base 128GB storage configuration is $100 off. This model usually runs for $1,099, but &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0932BKSLP/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; is selling it in the silver colorway for $999. The 2021 iPad Pro also packs Apple’s stellar M1 processor, ensuring its performance can not only push all those pixels but do so with speed and with the promise of enough performance headroom to likely stay that way for years to come. If you prefer more storage, you can get the 256GB configuration for $1,099 at &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-12-9-inch-iPad-Pro-2021-Wi-Fi-256GB-Space-Gray%2F385211636&amp;amp;subid1=vergedailydeals011222" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; (also $100 off). &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22442084/ipad-pro-2021-review-features-screen-mini-led-m1-processor"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="VjMeBq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10474637"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aYPmhE"&gt;The PowerA Fusion Pro wireless controller for Switch is an intriguing alternative to Nintendo’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2017/2/24/14699044/nintendo-switch-pro-controller-hands-on-preview"&gt;Switch Pro controller&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08XXTW41G?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; has the Fusion Pro in its slick white-and-black colorway for $65.99, a savings of $34 off its usual price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6zjE22"&gt;The PowerA Fusion Pro may be worth considering if you want to try something that’s as close as you can get to a Switch-equivalent to the Xbox Elite controller. It has customizable analog sticks and optional rear paddle buttons. When it’s wired to your Switch dock, its 3.5mm headphone jack can pipe game audio to your headphones. It also lacks some things found in the Switch Pro controller, like rumble and Amiibo support. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22608203/powera-fusion-pro-customizable-analog-sticks-paddles-nintendo-switch-controller-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lt5ZZK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10973226"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Qrvxhl"&gt;From a cute white controller to a cute white camera, the Wyze Cam v3 is an inexpensive home camera that supports 1080p recording with weather resistance for outdoor use. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B095NWYQBC?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; has it with kitted out with a spotlight LED for just $36.60, saving about $16 and making it an excellent option for monitoring a front door, like a mini flood light for a much cheaper price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cq87FF"&gt;The Wyze Cam v3 also supports both color and black-and-white night vision, so its ability to see in the dark is quite good even when the spotlight is not in use. These little cameras are some of the most affordable ones around, offering solid video quality with motion detection, two-way audio, and support for both Alexa and Google Assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="mnpk7X"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Wyze’s security camera pay-what-you-want subscription accepts $0","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22879759/wyze-cam-plus-lite-pay-what-you-want-subscription-person-detection-cloud-recordings-12-seconds"},{"title":"Wyze’s cameras can now be a monitored home security system","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22750594/wyze-cams-monitored-security-smart-switches-price-release-date-specs"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="hVbINL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10973234"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tAKO0S"&gt;While the recent &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22870203/ces-2022-best-of-gadgets-concepts-tech"&gt;CES 2022&lt;/a&gt; announcements featured new innovations &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22865220/sony-a95k-qd-oled-qdoled-4k-tv-announced-features-explainer"&gt;coming to OLED TVs&lt;/a&gt;, the promise of even better tech will ultimately bring us even more expensive OLEDs. As for the here and now, the 48-inch LG A1 OLED is just $796.99 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/LG-Built-Refresh-AI-Powered-OLED48A1PUA/dp/B092LZNZB7?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, saving $403 off MSRP. The A1 may not be the top tier in LG’s lineup, but if you don’t need a giant TV you can’t go wrong saving money on this affordable panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XiTCRr"&gt;OLEDs are a great choice in general for deeper black levels and excellent contrast, but you don’t have to break the bank. We have featured the popular LG C1 OLED TVs numerous times, though today’s deal on its entry-level A1 counterpart gets us below $1,000 — not something you see every day for OLED. Unlike the C1, which features a 120Hz refresh rate and HDMI 2.1 ports, the A1 tops out at 60Hz and doesn’t support 4K at 120Hz. Still, it seems like a solid TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="LyFvW0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10959416"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tj92BW"&gt;More deals to deal with:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="L6SAZv"&gt;The Razer Nari Essential gaming headset is a bit long in the tooth, but if you don’t mind Micro-USB charging it seems like a fine wireless headset for just $41.99 ($58 off MSRP) at &lt;a href="https://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8836602-13527013?sid=vergedailydeals011222&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fcomputers.woot.com%2Foffers%2Frazer-nari-essential-gaming-headset-27" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Woot&lt;/a&gt;. That’s a new all-time low, though it’s also available at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-Nari-Essential-Wireless-Auto-Adjusting/dp/B07HZ5N8QT?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; for $49.99.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="msGnnF"&gt;GoPro’s latest Hero10 Black action camera is still $429.99 ($70 off) at &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1658382-REG%2Fgopro_chdhx_101_hero10_black.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2022%2F1%2F12%2F22878428%2Fapple-ipad-pro-nintendo-switch-controller-lg-a1-oled-wyza-cam-v3-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/GoPro-HERO10-Black-Waterproof-Stabilization/dp/B09CS9X5F5?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, the lowest price available on this cam launched in the late summer of 2021. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22675560/gopro-hero10-action-camera-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="oxbzCp"&gt;If you’re looking to use video games to get in shape for a New Year’s resolution, not only is &lt;em&gt;Ring Fit Adventure&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Ring-Fit-Adventure-Nintendo-Switch/dp/B07XV4NHHN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;still on sale for $54.99&lt;/a&gt; ($25 off) but now &lt;em&gt;Fitness Boxing 2: Rhythm &amp;amp; Exercise&lt;/em&gt; is also on sale for $34.99 ($15 off) from &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Fitness-Boxing-Exercise-Standard-Digital/dp/B08JZN6T9M?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; as a Nintendo Switch digital download.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6ahcA9"&gt;Lenovo’s Smart Clock 2 with wireless charging dock is just $69.99 ($20 off) at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cgo6mfTa46d" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and makes for a handy companion to sit beside your bedside table. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22714538/lenovo-smart-clock-2-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="Wepfnf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2022/1/12/22878428/apple-ipad-pro-nintendo-switch-controller-lg-a1-oled-wyza-cam-v3-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2022/1/12/22878428/apple-ipad-pro-nintendo-switch-controller-lg-a1-oled-wyza-cam-v3-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-12T10:35:07-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-12T10:35:07-05:00</updated>
    <title>Kirby’s post-apocalyptic Switch adventure is coming in March</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V2nEwwzbe0lUpGHwU7z8wAijWno=/0x0:5400x3600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70378832/KirbyandtheForgottenLand_KeyArt_16x9.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UrgsKR"&gt;Horizon Zero Kirby, better known by its official title, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689905/kirby-and-the-forgotten-land-nintendo-switch-trailer"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kirby and the Forgotten Lands&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, launches on March 25th and has a new trailer showing off the game’s co-op features and all the cool powers you’ll be able to suck out of the local fauna. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wtcSPA"&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Kirby and the Forgotten Lands&lt;/em&gt;, the eponymous Pepto-Bismol-colored creature travels to a mysterious land dotted with overgrown buildings and rusted-out cars to investigate the mass kidnappings of Waddle Dees. Kirby, eater of worlds, is joined on his journey by a cute blue sidekick called Elfilin, who will help him defeat the evil Beast Pack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TVjjrF"&gt;The trailer showcases two new abilities Kirby can learn using his power of vore: Drill and Ranger. With Drill, Kirby can dive underground dodging attacks and surprise enemies from below. The Ranger ability gives Kirby a blunderbuss that he can use to snipe enemies from afar. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dH3sO7"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kirby and the Forgotten Lands&lt;/em&gt; features a town populated by the Waddle Dees Kirby saves. The more Waddles he rescues, the more amenities and mini-games are unlocked in the town. Kirby can moonlight at the Waddle Dee Café, serving up delicious treats quickly and to the right patrons to beat the high score. There’s also fishing and gacha games Kirby can play. The journey through the Forgotten Lands can be solo or local co-op, with a second player taking command of Bandana Waddle Dee. Though there is no online co-op, players can connect online to see interesting stats like the most-used copy ability or how many Waddle Dees players have saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7eaXtR"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kirby and the Forgotten Lands&lt;/em&gt; releases on the Nintendo Switch March 25th, 2022. This year also marks Kirby’s 30th anniversary, long may he &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/XBvRzwXxzSQ"&gt;poyo&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22879956/post-apocalyptic-kirby-game-release-date-trailer-nintendo-switch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22879956/post-apocalyptic-kirby-game-release-date-trailer-nintendo-switch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-12T10:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-12T10:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix’s The House is an unsettling anthology wrapped in cozy stop-motion</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The House" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wVFHVLI_thRY-DS65Z30eWAzOE4=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70378802/The_House_Chapter3_01_01_26_08.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YFwmIs"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The House&lt;/em&gt;, one of Netflix’s first new releases of the year, is a straightforward concept. It’s a film split into three chapters, each helmed by a different director, all of which explore a different story related to the same sprawling home. What connects each short, aside from the physical house and stop-motion animation, is a creeping sense of dread. &lt;em&gt;The House&lt;/em&gt; looks cute, with talking animals and dollhouse-like visuals, but in each story there’s something lurking just beneath the surface; something wrong, unsettling. It could be a recession or a scary creature — but when you put it together the result is an anthology with a trio of distinct, yet clearly connected stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xEnSEO"&gt;The first chapter, directed by Marc James Roels and Emma de Swaef, is an origin story of sorts, which opens with the ominous phrase, “and heard within, a lie is spun.” It’s a story about envy: when visiting relatives mock a young family’s home, the father makes a drunken arrangement with an eccentric architect offering to build them the house of their dreams free of charge. Initially, it’s an almost idyllic scenario; not only is the house huge and beautiful, but food appears as if from nowhere and the lights turn themselves on. But slowly things unravel. One day stairs go missing as the architect decides to rearrange his masterpiece, while zombie-like workers lurk around in silence. Later the architect gifts the parents bizarre clothing to match the decor. It’s hard to tell whether something supernatural is going on or if it’s just a cruel psychological experiment, and it’s all rendered in soft felt that only adds to the surreality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rm8K7R"&gt;Later stories move the timeline forward. Chapter two, directed by Niki Lindroth von Bahr, is set in modern times, when a struggling contractor — who is also a mouse — is renovating the house in an attempt to make some big money. Unfortunately, everything seems to go wrong; not only is he investing everything in the project in the midst of a recession, but he has to deal with persistent problems like a mysterious bug infestation. When the house is complete, only one couple bites: and there is something clearly wrong with them. I won’t spoil anything, but this one is worth watching for the final twist alone. The last chapter, helmed by Paloma Baeza, pushes things further into the future when the house is surrounded by a flooded city. However, a young cat, who has converted the home into apartments, refuses to cave to reality and literally tries to wallpaper over her problems while her remaining tenants do what they can to help her move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GAOyA3"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wqbZlAEUb5w?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="B2odPM"&gt;Despite the various circumstances and timelines, in each story the house represents a kind of lifeline for the characters. It’s a chance for a family to inspire jealousy, for a mouse to pull himself out of the crushing weight of debt, and for a cat to slowly build the home of her dreams. The house seems to attract the desperate. What’s most interesting about &lt;em&gt;The House&lt;/em&gt; is how each story offers a different riff on this theme. The first two chapters lean into being creepy, particularly their unsettling endings, but while the first is more of a slow-building dread, the second is much more tangible. Meanwhile, the final chapter, despite starting out quite bleak, ends on a surprisingly hopeful note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x9dsSf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The House&lt;/em&gt; also features some of the best-looking stop-motion animation you’ll see &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/8/18/12500814/laika-studios-behind-the-scenes-kubo-and-the-two-strings-video"&gt;outside of a Laika film&lt;/a&gt;. Each story has a different vibe. The felt characters of chapter one lend it an almost cozy vibe, that makes the darker elements even more stark, while the second chapter is incredibly lifelike and detailed, right down to the little piece of tape covering the webcam on the contractor’s laptop. The final story, meanwhile, is more ethereal, with foggy backdrops that signal something approaching the end of the world. The only constant is the house, which is always recognizable despite superficial changes over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mkkL4b"&gt;It’s an almost ideal anthology: connected and yet standalone. And, at around 30 minutes each, the chapters are short enough that they don’t overstay their welcome, while also being strange enough to stick with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qB3xcD"&gt;&lt;small&gt;The House &lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;streams on Netflix starting January 14th.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bKu5iI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7WyvER"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22878767/the-house-review-netflix"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22878767/the-house-review-netflix</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-12T10:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-12T10:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Biden administration announces major new initiatives to clean up the electric grid </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Installation of offshore wind farm at Block Island, Rhode Island" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P0lW-Lrg780O07AhzoN96Gnf2sw=/0x0:6000x4000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70378804/1328686375.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Block Island, R.I: Deepwater Wind installing the first offshore wind farm at Block Island, Rhode Island, August 14, 2016. | Photo by Mark Harrington/Newsday RM via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mz7RDt"&gt;On Wednesday, the Biden administration &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/12/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-races-to-deploy-clean-energy-that-creates-jobs-and-lowers-costs/"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; a slew of new moves to transition the US to renewable energy, with a focus on upgrading the power grid and using public lands and waters to harness solar, wind, and geothermal energy. It’s the administration’s latest effort to clean up the nation’s electricity grid, as Democrats struggle to make headway on key legislation needed to tackle the climate crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iYjYpG"&gt;The Department of Energy is rolling out a “Building a Better Grid” initiative, which will put federal dollars to work after the recently passed bipartisan infrastructure law allocated &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/11/06/fact-sheet-the-bipartisan-infrastructure-deal/"&gt;$65 billion&lt;/a&gt; for grid improvements. Notably, there’s $2.5 billion earmarked for new and improved transmission lines that will be crucial for zipping renewable energy from far-flung solar and wind farms to communities. Another $3 billion will go towards &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22419206/smart-grid-renewable-energy-power-sector"&gt;smart grid technologies&lt;/a&gt; that aim to make homes more energy efficient and reduce pressure on the grid while balancing the flow of intermittent sources of renewable energy like wind and solar. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6xUp5a"&gt;There’s also more than $10 billion in grants to states, tribes, and utilities for efforts to harden the grid and help prevent power outages. As the grid ages and extreme weather events are worsened by climate change, blackouts have grown longer in the US, with the average American going &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774266/power-outages-worse-united-states-electricity-grid-climate-change"&gt;more than eight hours without power in 2020&lt;/a&gt; — twice as long as was typical when the federal government started keeping track in 2013. Things could get worse without efforts to rein in greenhouse gas emissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="4X0zHA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Plans to auction off vast swaths of federal waters for offshore wind farms&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gVqbJ7"&gt;The administration is also commissioning new national studies to inform its deployment of thousands of miles of additional transmission lines. And it pledged to convene with tribes, states, and local governments that might have a stake in the build-out of these lines, which &lt;a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09644016.2021.1952799"&gt;often meet fierce opposition&lt;/a&gt; from local communities in their path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rTNqGv"&gt;Plans to auction off vast swaths of federal waters for offshore wind farms also moved forward today. The Bureau of Ocean Energy Management (BOEM) posted the &lt;a href="https://www.boem.gov/renewable-energy/state-activities/new-york-bight"&gt;final sale notice&lt;/a&gt; for six commercial lease areas in the New York Bight off the coasts of New York and New Jersey. Those lease areas stretch across 488,201 acres. Once developed, wind farms there could generate up to 7GW of clean energy — enough to power 2 million homes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l6J6dD"&gt;Still, members of the fishing industry have voiced &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jul/24/offshore-wind-development-new-jersey-us-fishermen-ocean-life"&gt;concerns&lt;/a&gt; over how the wind farms could harm marine ecosystems and coastal economies. Interior Secretary Deb Haaland, New York Governor Kathy Hochul, and New Jersey Governor Phil Murphy announced a new partnership to work together on “job creation and environmental justice.” The National Oceanic Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) and BOEM also said they are entering a new interagency agreement focused on “protecting biodiversity and promoting cooperative ocean use.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="bEdMAA"&gt;&lt;q&gt; A “really, really big deal”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8wk5HT"&gt;Senior administration officials described the lease sale, scheduled to take place next month, as a “really, really big deal” in a call with reporters. It is considered a key pillar in the administration’s plan to install &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/03/29/fact-sheet-biden-administration-jumpstarts-offshore-wind-energy-projects-to-create-jobs/"&gt;30GW of offshore wind capacity&lt;/a&gt; across the United States by 2030. Throughout the year, BOEM plans to keep momentum going on proposals to bring wind farms to areas off the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22735645/new-orleans-east-hurricane-ida-entergy-power-shift"&gt;Gulf Coast&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453282/joe-biden-california-west-coast-offshore-wind"&gt;California&lt;/a&gt;, Oregon, and central Atlantic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hcNDlP"&gt;The Biden administration also wants to “fast-track” the permitting process for wind, solar, and geothermal projects onshore. To speed up reviews, five agencies — the Departments of the Interior, Agriculture, Defense, Energy, and the Environmental Protection Agency — issued a memorandum of understanding to prioritize renewable energy proposals on public lands. The aim is to permit 25GW renewable energy projects on public lands by 2025. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I2SQoY"&gt;Biden is trying to make good on commitments he’s made to move the power sector entirely to clean energy by 2035 and virtually eliminate planet-heating pollution from fossil fuels by 2050. But those efforts are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/21/22848603/democrats-build-back-better-bill-clean-energy-power-grid-manchin"&gt;in jeopardy&lt;/a&gt; as West Virginia senator Joe Manchin drags out Democrats’ negotiations on their roughly $1.75 trillion environmental and social spending bill. With clean energy provisions already whittled down in the bill, Biden will likely have to rely more heavily on the executive branch to meet his goals on climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZOGHFx"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22879269/biden-climate-public-lands-water-renewable-energy-offshore-wind-solar-grid"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/12/22879269/biden-climate-public-lands-water-renewable-energy-offshore-wind-solar-grid</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-12T10:05:35-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-12T10:05:35-05:00</updated>
    <title>Becca’s ‘buds’ beat out other words</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T6OpJQeym4rvePZ9rpnBKF6HkEw=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70378711/VRG_ILLO_BeccaData.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Grayson Blackmon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Buds, buds, buds, buds!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div id="CNRiWq"&gt;&lt;script src="https://d3js.org/d3.v7.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KwCqo9"&gt;After working on a data piece &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22744897/verge-coverage-stories-data-charts"&gt;analyzing everything &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;has ever written&lt;/a&gt;, I thought it might be fun to look at some other &lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;data to see what I could find. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eaWNsm"&gt;Becca Farsace is one of the best sports we have on our team here, and she also has some of the most distinctive speech patterns — and catchphrases — so I asked her if she would let me dive into the data of her words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FwMT6G"&gt;Her Slack response: “Wowee... I’m terrified, but go for it!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ungVqp"&gt;We all have a tendency to use the same vocabulary and phrases from day to day — it’s a part of what makes us who we are, of course. So I pulled the transcripts of every video Becca has hosted on our YouTube channel (over 30!) to get an impression of her speech patterns. A few videos didn’t have transcripts, and I didn’t include videos where she was only a guest for ease of analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gWRrWZ"&gt;After collecting the raw transcripts and analyzing them, I took out some common words, such as “a,” “the,” “and,” “I,” and so on, and came away with some interesting findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9UvKjz"&gt;
&lt;div id="Becca_Data_BarChart"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;script src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23131058/Becca_Data_alt_BarChart.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dLMqBE"&gt;You can view the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/20725204"&gt;original version here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jbq0eEjocU7wyaeQhS6ncjWrxtE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161603/VRG_ILLO_4967_Becca_Bar_Chart.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MIFZDV"&gt;In the chart above, you can see Becca’s top words across all videos she’s ever hosted. No surprise: “buds” is the top word with nearly 300 uses, followed by “really” and “camera.” “Buds” is a common term of endearment from Becca, referring to us the viewer, but it also reinforces what we already know: that Becca covers a ton of earbuds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8FZ6jU"&gt;
&lt;div id="Becca_Data"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;script src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161554/Becca_Data_alt.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="x4Ho64"&gt;You can view the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/20725204"&gt;original version here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-V2_8RJHW4oYqYxwRZ9I-t-PfD4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161611/VRG_ILLO_4967_Becca_Scatter_Chart.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="waPESh"&gt;By looking at Becca’s top words per video, we can see how her language shifts from video to video — generally to highlight the topic being discussed. Again, “buds” (highlighted in pink) takes the top spot here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XcNkGw"&gt;The use of “buds” is increasing over time, too. Is this due to an ever-growing number of “buds” named products she reviews or a deeper personal connection with her audience?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7TSfaG"&gt;Mostly, it seems to align with what she’s covering. They can be broken down into five buckets: action cameras, cameras, earbuds, phones, and an assorted bucket of everything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="OaZ2N3"&gt;Action Cameras, with six videos, didn’t have any particular word or phrase stand out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="SJGFfq"&gt;Cameras had “camera” as the top word three videos out of a total of five.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JhVodu"&gt;Earbuds had “buds” as the top word in nine out of 10 videos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Sqp1p2"&gt;Phones, with three videos, had “Pixel” or “Pixel / iPhone” in two videos as the top word.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qckkAq"&gt;In the Other category, the top word seemed to match the topic of the video, with an even spread over five videos of “AI,” “fiber,” “video,” “board,” and “bike.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="Ii3eYg"&gt;The data suggests that Becca’s speech most closely mirrors the topic she’s covering in each video, rather than being skewed by a favored catchphrase. Though it still goes without saying: Becca says buds &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VqYIwR"&gt;“In my defense, ‘buds’ is a product category I cover, but it is also a part of my everyday language,” Becca told me. “Is it time that changes? Maybe I’ll let the buds decide.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/20961163/becca-farsace-buds-youtube-data-language-video-host"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/20961163/becca-farsace-buds-youtube-data-language-video-host</id>
    <author>
      <name>Grayson Blackmon</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-12T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-12T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Buy Nothing exploded on Facebook — now it wants a platform of its own</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An illustration of groups of people holding computers, connected to other groups by narrow lines" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/90fX_57QysM80_XtPwId-cbD-Xk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70378635/acastro_220111_4960_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;A new app hopes to be an independent platform for the wildly popular Buy Nothing groups&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="uFJU5X"&gt;In the same week, Katylin has seen a banana and a boat given away between neighbors, no strings attached. In her local Buy Nothing group in Seattle, neighbors share what they have to give — vacations, gift wrap, symphony tickets, Airbnb accommodations — up for grabs to whoever wants or needs it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4uB7Kp"&gt;This is the essence of a Buy Nothing group: instead of tossing what you don’t need or buying something you do, try offering it up or asking your neighbors first. Bartering and trading are prohibited, and users are required to give and receive freely. Everything given is worth the same, no matter the perceived value. Bikes and boats are listed next to dryer lint and chicken feces. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hcyYk0"&gt;“The banana and the boat are both just gifts — they’re a way to connect with your neighbors,” Katylin says. “They’re actually equal.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="bvJXjD"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There are 7,000 individual Buy Nothing communities across 44 countries, from a group for New York’s Chinatown to a suburb of Reykjavík in Iceland. &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YnwArQ"&gt;The Buy Nothing Project is a rare success story of digital community-building on Facebook that blossoms offline. Founded in 2013, the project grew organically, primarily through closed Facebook groups, and then exploded in popularity during the pandemic, now counting more than 5 million members. There are 7,000 individual Buy Nothing communities across 44 countries, from a group for New York’s Chinatown to a suburb of Reykjavík in Iceland. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aj1a06"&gt;After so much success, Buy Nothing is now facing a dilemma: whether to leave Facebook behind. The platform allowed Buy Nothing groups to spread across the globe and easily connect neighbors with surplus goods. But it’s also posed an increasing number of problems, from moderating sprawling, disconnected communities to reaching people beyond the walls of the highly contentious social network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DuCgYb"&gt;To solve those problems, the Buy Nothing Project launched a mobile app of their own in November, which they’re hoping will be a more sustainable option long term as it continues to grow. Project co-founders Liesl Clark, Rebecca Rockefeller, and new business partners Tunji Williams and Lucas Rix formed a public benefit corporation, ShareThing, in 2021 and raised money from friends and family to fund the app’s development. After years of being approached by potential investors, Clark and Rockefeller finally felt ready to begin building their own platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A series of comments of someone asking for and being offered a sprinkler." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yh64ypF_QuxcO_LUXrDx3rpiMAY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23162084/Comments_copy.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Buy Nothing Project&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Users are encouraged to ask neighbors for things they need.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tgQt4U"&gt;The app attempts to solve headaches and hiccups that moderators and leaders have dealt with while using Facebook. Because most of the groups exist on Facebook, even knowing how many Buy Nothing community members there are is a herculean task. Volunteers like Katylin must hand count membership numbers using a spreadsheet, logging member count for each of the thousands of groups. Admins of groups must go through the steps of creating groups, manually adding new members, and coming up with geographic boundaries before people can start gifting and receiving items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UudApk"&gt;But asking 7,000 groups to try a new platform presents its own issues. Though the thousands of Buy Nothing groups follow the same manual and guiding principles, in practice each is responsible for itself. Different administrators have different rules of engagement. For example, Facebook groups will lay out the exact boundaries of where you must live to join the community, but some moderators allow people who work or go to school in the area to join, or who are slightly outside of the neighborhood limits. Some admins have developed regular community events in the neighborhood that might not exist in a nearby area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Grz0MY"&gt;The app dissolves those clearly defined communities, creating a somewhat borderless experience with the individual user at the center. Instead of being in a network for your town or neighborhood, the app uses a person’s location and distance preferences to create a radius with other users nearby. The role of admins, too, is redefined — on Facebook, they are responsible for even the most tedious of tasks, like troubleshooting tech issues. On the app, anyone who takes a training course can become a “community builder,” whose job it is to model best practices and facilitate activity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The app presents three distance settings for users from “hyperlocal” to “surrounding areas.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4hPr-GeZvP6gst_HhbgAb_DMO2A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23162040/IMG_7239.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Buy Nothing Project&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The BuyNothing app creates a borderless experience instead of clearly defined boundaries that Facebook groups have.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="M33ABG"&gt;This in-between period, Clark admits, is a little bittersweet and awkward. Thriving communities might feel threatened by yet another space with the same mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uyN9m5"&gt;“At times, people will feel that there’s only room for one group,” Clark says. “But I think that if we do this over and over and over again, and practice it, then we won’t even need an app, we won’t even need Facebook groups. We’ll just be doing it in real life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e0zV2I"&gt;So far, most Buy Nothing users seem to be staying where they are: the app only has 166,000 downloads as of late December, though Clark says it is growing by 5 percent week to week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lpGnLs"&gt;Eddie Chang, a moderator of a Buy Nothing group on the Upper East Side in New York, says some administrators feel the addition of the app might unnecessarily complicate a system that was already working well. Expanding the project requires the money to cover increasing costs, potentially putting it in a tough spot if funding dries up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vJDmIk"&gt;“You already have a very rich product that you created, and you have people who have skin in the game as owners of their own individual communities within this umbrella organization,” he says. “If [donations] dry up, and you get paid through another outlet, how does that change the philosophy?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8vWCM4"&gt;Even though buying and selling aren’t allowed in the Buy Nothing universe, money is a key question in this new chapter. Though it’s free to participate, Clark says any costs associated with the project — from creating resources for the public, to hiring developers — have been covered since day one by herself and co-founder Rebecca Rockefeller. (In December, the &lt;a href="https://buynothingproject.org/"&gt;Buy Nothing website&lt;/a&gt; for the first time featured a banner asking for supporters to consider chipping in.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZuAmvu"&gt;The fine print currently allows for admins to have a “&lt;a href="https://bnponfb.org/2020/12/22/a-brief-history-of-the-buy-nothing-project-complete-with-controversies/"&gt;gratitude jar&lt;/a&gt;,” and Clark says she would like to see volunteers compensated for the time and skills they’ve already devoted to keeping groups afloat. But the topic of compensation has at times been contentious, with many administrators deeply against it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="qlayIw"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Do I need to spend 40 hours a week on this thing? No, I don’t. But it’s a labor of love.” &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ltNebv"&gt;“I think there are the purists who believe that an endeavor like this should all be free,” Clark says. “Managing this is full time and then some … We can’t earn a living and just give away all our time. We do need to feed our families.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PAaTG1"&gt;Chang, the administrator of the Upper East Side group, doesn’t believe he should be paid for the work he does. As opposed to similar community groups that allow sponsored content, Chang believes that without money changing hands, Buy Nothing can remain a safe, influence-free space. The reward, he says, is meeting and building relationships with the people around you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sm5vR1"&gt;“Do I need to spend 40 hours a week on this thing? No, I don’t,” he says. “But it’s a labor of love.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9Tw2Ex"&gt;The middle ground for communities has been to attempt to keep both the Facebook group and the app active, an option that Clark and other project co-founders encourage if it makes sense for the group. Admins like Chang suggest members try out the app or crosspost items and asks. From what he’s seen, most admins either say nothing about the app, or facilitate activity on both platforms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dmYnAv"&gt;“We’re trying to embrace it,” Chang says. “We’re not getting out of it yet what we’re getting out of the group, so it’s not fully adopted. It’s still in early days.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="pYhtDH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“On the app, I will have to teach people the water is fine. You don’t know all your neighbors yet.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xbeVc7"&gt;Other admins like Katylin are thrilled to begin the transition away from Facebook toward something custom built for the Buy Nothing mission. The move has helped her prepare to leave Facebook, a platform she’s spent countless hours on while building a community she believes in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nKqap5"&gt;“On the app, I will have to teach people the water is fine,” Katylin says. “You don’t know all your neighbors yet. But within time, you probably are going to be comfortable enough to show all the sides of yourself you showed in your Facebook group.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SJZaoU"&gt;A fresh platform owned and operated by people dedicated to Buy Nothing feels like a blank slate to build on, Clark says. For instance, she says the borderlessness is an attempt at correcting a phenomenon of Facebook group boundaries that recreated historic redlined maps. Leadership is considering what it might look like to have participants have equity in the project or how Buy Nothing could partner with municipalities and states on educational programs around reuse and recycling efforts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D1dWYt"&gt;Even though Clark has high hopes for how the app can evolve in the future, she says the less social media platforms are needed to do this work, the better. And though she hears the trepidation from people who worry having another platform could dilute the existing communities, Clark believes both can thrive — the point is that people are exposed to the ethos of a gift economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="baQmyl"&gt;“What we want to do is bring about behavioral change,” Clark says. “That is our number one agenda.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UNajyh"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DvHuOp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NorUqz"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QnLeqM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g3Upbs"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q2AeCS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/2022/1/12/22878353/buy-nothing-groups-facebook-app"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tech/2022/1/12/22878353/buy-nothing-groups-facebook-app</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mia Sato</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
