<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-05-07T17:36:50-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-07T17:36:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-07T17:36:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>Instagram’s head apologizes for bug that deleted activists’ stories</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xl6UwwaCyRqIXfZfQwPNa0cU-i0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69254588/acastro_190919_1777_instagram_0002.0.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YQFHcq"&gt;Head of Instagram Adam Mosseri &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mosseri/status/1390764512521768960?s=20"&gt;has tweeted an apology&lt;/a&gt; about a bug that deleted users’ story posts on Thursday. The timing was unfortunate for activists trying to raise awareness about missing Indigenous women, with organizations Red Dress and National Day of Awareness of Missing and Murdered Indigenous Women and Girls (MMIWG, abbreviated by some as MMIWG2S to include two-spirit people) &lt;a href="https://indiancountrytoday.com/news/mmiwg-movement-erased-online"&gt;questioning whether their posts&lt;/a&gt; had somehow been erased deliberately. According to Instagram, however, the bug affected stories, archives, and highlights of Instagram users across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lD8DCx"&gt;Mosseri and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/InstagramComms/status/1390376354332487681"&gt;Instagram’s statement&lt;/a&gt; about the deletions say this isn’t the case and that the stories were not removed because of anything content-related. He specifically addressed the Indigenous people’s concerns. “This day is incredibly important to raise awareness of this critical issue and support our Indigenous community on Instagram,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mosseri/status/1390764511808737283?s=20"&gt;Mosseri tweeted&lt;/a&gt;. “We apologize to all those who felt like they could not bring attention to these incredibly important causes, and many others around the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="QClRa0"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Many people thought we were removing their content because of what they posted or what hashtag they used, but this bug wasn’t related to the content itself, but rather a widespread issue that has now been fixed.&lt;/p&gt;— Adam Mosseri   (@mosseri) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mosseri/status/1390764510378532864?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="y1naSV"&gt;The issue of &lt;a href="https://indiancountrytoday.com/news/known-and-not-forgotten"&gt;the high rates of violence against Indigenous people&lt;/a&gt; — especially women, girls, and two-spirit people — isn’t one that often gets a spotlight outside of reservations, so spreading awareness is especially important, activists say. &lt;a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/indigenous/instagram-stories-vanish-mmiwg-red-dress-day-1.6017113?cmp=rss"&gt;Speaking to CBC News&lt;/a&gt; about the importance of days like May 5th, community organizer Kakeka Thundersky said that “[e]veryone’s just stuck at home on their phone, unable to gather and able to go to the rallies, unable to talk to face to face with people,” making online platforms like Instagram a key tool for activists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ikA81A"&gt;Emily Henderson, an Inuk arts and culture writer, said that “[t]he digital space in general is really, really important right now just for maintaining community connections or connections.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425415/instagram-delete-activist-stories-bug-apology-mmiwg2s"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425415/instagram-delete-activist-stories-bug-apology-mmiwg2s</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-07T17:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-07T17:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>What would a billionaire do on SNL?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="elon-musk-asa-mathat-02" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yaTXxXu4Zhdg2miU5t_Cbl8f-xc=/0x0:2592x1728/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69254543/REC_ASA_CODE2016-20160601-211928-4028.0.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Asa Mathat/Recode&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CzdmWR"&gt;Tesla CEO Elon Musk — the first or second richest man in the world, depending on the phase of the Moon — will host &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/24/22401253/elon-musk-hosting-saturday-night-live-miley-cyrus-tesla-spacex"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Saturday Night Live&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; this weekend (the first or second funniest show that airs on Saturday evenings, depending on if anything else is on TV). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ZMe6U"&gt;The event is a strange confluence of things that &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;covers: a powerful tech leader with ambitions that are as huge as his blind spots, and someone destined to barrage you with so many dad jokes that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388609/wolf-collar-camera-fish-voyageurs-minnesota"&gt;one is bound to land at some point&lt;/a&gt;. Plus maybe &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22387486/dogecoin-run-valuation-cryptocurrency-spike-elon-musk"&gt;Dogecoin&lt;/a&gt;? (A meme gone so awry that it’s shaping the actual landscape of the physical world is definitely some &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; shit.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fzSP6h"&gt;So what can we expect when Musk takes the stage late on Saturday evening? Using a bit of algorithmic trickery and some advanced machine learning (aka &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; staff typing eagerly into a shared Google Doc), we’ve made our best predictions of what this episode of &lt;em&gt;SNL&lt;/em&gt; is likely to bring. And because we’re a little deranged from spending the week &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22373826/epic-games-v-apple-fortnite-app-store-antitrust-lawsuit"&gt;covering &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we also decided to turn it into a game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r6xILB"&gt;Behold: Elon &lt;em&gt;SNL&lt;/em&gt; Bingo!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/N6XPnoRXERrLY2wamK2H_GA6h2w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22499097/VRG_ILLO_ELONMUSK_BINGO_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Illustration by Grayson Blackmon / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22424877/elon-must-snl-bingo-game-saturday-night-live"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22424877/elon-must-snl-bingo-game-saturday-night-live</id>
    <author>
      <name>Verge Staff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-07T17:18:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-07T17:18:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google childcare workers ask for commute stipend in new petition</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LnCBo7IkVZd4ycMtfFKPVKgTX5A=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69254490/acastro_180508_1777_google_IO_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eUqK53"&gt;More than 200 Alphabet employees have &lt;a href="https://justiceforgcc.org/"&gt;signed a petition&lt;/a&gt; from Google childcare workers asking for a commute stipend. The petition calls for workers to be given an extra $1,500 per month to help pay for ride-shares, car rentals, or other transportation costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wZGIFd"&gt;Google is asking childcare workers and educators to return to in-person work on Monday, May 10th, while the company’s shuttle service remains suspended. Some make as little as $25 an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dAIPSR"&gt;“Transportation isn’t just a nice-to-have for us, it’s fundamental if we want to do our job,” said Denise Belardes, a childcare worker, in a press release. “We’re not the ones making hundreds of thousands of dollars every year. We do not have the option to work from home as other Googlers. We need this stipend.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="To5FFX"&gt;Google maintains four childcare centers in the Bay Area, where workers help educate and care for the children of Google and Alphabet employees. Many of the workers employed there don’t live close to the office due to the prohibitively high cost of housing, so transportation is a particularly vital issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TYT33l"&gt;During the pandemic, the workers began meeting with children over Google Meet, which made the transportation stipend unnecessary. But now, as &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/03/31/google-speeds-partial-office-reopening-and-puts-limits-on-remote-work.html#:~:text=Google%20employees%20will%20begin%20returning,will%20need%20to%20formally%20apply."&gt;Google starts to slowly bring employees back to the office&lt;/a&gt;, they’re being asked to return to in-person work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jpy5MV"&gt;In the petition, workers say Google did not respond well to the initial request. “When workers raised this issue, the corporate response was ‘transportation is just a perk, not a benefit,’” they wrote. “Shifting this cost to essential workers, who earn far less than the Googlers whose children they care for, is unacceptable. Google must do better.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rBFzGs"&gt;The petition, which is addressed to CEO Sundar Pichai as well as other executives, is backed by the Alphabet Workers Union. Google did not immediately respond to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ppWJNl"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VlnJeJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425388/google-childcare-workers-commute-stipend"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425388/google-childcare-workers-commute-stipend</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-07T17:15:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-07T17:15:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s Nest Mini is only $19 at Adorama</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-xpoTfF92Qtq4xTE5D_ODlNDAzY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69254470/cwelch_191016_3737_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google’s Nest Mini hits an all-time low — at least price-wise.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tWtukP"&gt;Whether you’ve fully committed to the smart home ecosystem or are just dabbling in the space for the first time, picking up a smart speaker is a no-brainer for most people. If you haven’t yet grabbed an Amazon or Google smart speaker, however, &lt;a href="https://adorama.rfvk.net/c/482924/1062332/1036?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.adorama.com%2Fga00638us.html"&gt;Adorama is taking $31&lt;/a&gt; off the Google Nest Mini as part of its latest flash sale through Sunday, May 9th. Simply use the promo code &lt;strong&gt;EXTRAOFF11 &lt;/strong&gt;at checkout to knock an additional $11 off the listed sale price and receive free shipping. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PTeMeC"&gt;Like its predecessor, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/21/20921173/google-nest-mini-echo-dot-assistant-smart-speaker-review"&gt;Google Nest Mini&lt;/a&gt; offers a range of voice-activated features, only with bolder sound, capacitive touch zones, and an improved design that allows you to hang the device on your wall. At the core of the fabric-lined puck is Google Assistant, which allows you quickly set reminders, stream music, control your smart lights, and carry out a range of other tasks with nothing more than a quick “Hey, Google.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ye17xF"&gt;The sound isn’t as robust as, say, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21501300/google-nest-audio-assistant-smart-speaker-review-price-specs-features"&gt;Google Nest Audio&lt;/a&gt;, but this marks the lowest price we’ve seen on the Nest Mini this year. It’s even available in two colors, chalk or charcoal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="j7wJhr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9736399"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zmZoJf"&gt;If you’re looking for additional Mother’s Day gift ideas — and don’t mind opting for in-store pickup — we’ve also rounded up a set of electric ideas, from bath balms and AirPods to a classic pair of sandals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CgVKOA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10443858"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425265/google-nest-mini-smart-speaker-deal-sale-adorama"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425265/google-nest-mini-smart-speaker-deal-sale-adorama</id>
    <author>
      <name>Brandon Widder</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-07T14:58:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-07T14:58:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Impossible Foods eyes schools for new customers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="2nd China International Import Expo (CIIE) - Day 5" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VRIV5LrRvrcoS5w6deNAM8vlbbw=/0x0:4896x3264/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69253559/1186664879.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Impossible Burgers sit on a tray at the Impossible Foods Inc. booth on day five of the 2nd China International Import Expo (CIIE) at the National Exhibition and Convention Center on November 9, 2019 in Shanghai, China. | Photo by Gao Yuwen/VCG via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HhKWO4"&gt;Impossible Burgers will be making their way onto school menus across the US. The meatless burger just received the Child Nutrition Label from the USDA, which could make it easier for public schools to serve the product because the Impossible Burgers will be eligible for national school lunch funding. Impossible Foods hopes to offer up protein-packed lunches that don’t generate as much greenhouse gases as red meat. But slapping branding on foods served up to kids can still be harmful, even if the meals might be better for the environment.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Kv8XkD"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Companies should really keep their branding out”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7Gxjz7"&gt;“Just on principle, we believe that schools should be commercial free,” says Marlene Schwartz, director of the Rudd Center for Food Policy and Obesity at the University of Connecticut. “Companies should really keep their branding out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OwEwuu"&gt;Adults can carry loyalties to brands that they’re exposed to as kids, &lt;a href="https://arizona.pure.elsevier.com/en/publications/how-childhood-advertising-exposure-can-create-biased-product-eval"&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; has shown. That’s not great for their health if they’re developing a taste for junk food, so advocates have pushed for more nutritious options, including plant-based foods, in schools. Impossible Burgers are plant-based and have gotten the green light from the Food and Drug Administration to be sold in grocery stores (despite some activists’ &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22418036/impossible-foods-legal-battle-key-ingredient-heme-fda"&gt;concerns over its key genetically engineered ingredient&lt;/a&gt;, heme, that the company says makes its burgers “taste like meat”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rEspOV"&gt;The problem that Schwartz sees with Impossible Foods’ move into schools has more to do with its branding than with its product. (She’s unable to comment on whether Impossible Burgers are any better or worse than other foods.) If schools want to serve meals with less meat and a smaller carbon footprint, then they should serve the meatless patties without the Impossible trademark, she says.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ANtFA"&gt;“When you allow a giant corporation to use that setting to get their brand in front of kids … It’s completely in conflict with the purpose of schools in the first place and I just think it’s completely unfair,” Schwartz says. “There’s something sacred about the school environment, that it should be a place where students aren’t being pressured to buy particular products.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="ueMGVv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Impossible™ Frito Pie”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="s1DFCu"&gt;Schools in Palo Alto, California; Aberdeen, Washington; Edmond, Oklahoma; and Union City, Oklahoma, will start pilot programs serving Impossible Burgers this month. The product won’t just appear in a bun, either. There will be “Impossible™ Street Tacos,” “Impossible™ Frito Pie,” and “Spaghetti with Impossible™ Meat Sauce.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ilOsfR"&gt;Impossible Foods seems to want to take more schools by storm soon. “Making Impossible™ products available everywhere people consume meat, which for kids often includes schools, is key to the mission of the company,” Pat Brown, CEO and Founder of Impossible Foods, said in a &lt;a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210506005414/en/Impossible-Foods-Secures-Child-Nutrition-Label-for-Impossible%E2%84%A2-Burger-Launches%C2%A0-Insights-Report-on-Kids-Climate-Change"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wgbgk6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xTMQRr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425006/impossible-foods-burgers-school-lunch-marketing-kids"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425006/impossible-foods-burgers-school-lunch-marketing-kids</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-07T14:12:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-07T14:12:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Verizon and T-Mobile want your business more than ever right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tTzrv5sYQQxZijH2KvfJrbK-GNg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69253302/acastro_180430_1777_5G_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;US telecom companies are braced for expensive changes in the coming years — and by extension, so are the rest of us.&lt;/em&gt; | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Expect generous promotions and shiny new plans as the expensive 5G buildout continues&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="PCj6nX"&gt;It’s a good year for old, crappy phones. The dusty old phone in your desk drawer running Android frozen-dessert-something-or-other — the one that might have a cracked screen — saw its stock go up recently with two generous trade-in promotions. T-Mobile and Verizon are both offering to take your old, damaged phone off your hands and replace it with a shiny new 5G model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HUwvCI"&gt;There are a couple of reasons for this generosity. Verizon, in particular, has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299903/fcc-cband-auction-results-verizon-att-tmobile"&gt;written some big checks&lt;/a&gt; to pay for new C-band frequencies — highly desirable spectrum for 5G that offers good range and speed. The company has reassured its shareholders that the hefty expenditure will help grow its customer base and increase the amount of money it makes on existing accounts. It told investors at its March analyst event that “with C-band included, we think step-ups to premium [plans] will only accelerate.” So it’s unsurprising that the cracked phone deal requires a commitment to a “select unlimited plan.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="U0WiyG"&gt;&lt;q&gt;That free 5G phone is just the start of what the carrier hopes will be a long, lucrative relationship&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2ByLkC"&gt;Meanwhile, T-Mobile wants to make the most of a relatively strong hand right now. It has taken every opportunity possible to declare itself the “leader in 5G” and is likewise focused on reaching new customers, getting a 5G device in their hands, and getting them hooked on its 5G network. T-Mobile CEO Mike Sievert talked up the success of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295466/t-mobile-magenta-max-unlimited-data-5g-4k-video-announced"&gt;new Magenta Max plan&lt;/a&gt; — an unlimited plan that doesn’t impose slowdowns after you reach a certain monthly data threshold — on the company’s first quarter earnings call as a kind of “if you build it, they will come” moment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MhtIFy"&gt;Customers on the plan use 70 percent more data than a typical LTE customer, and Sievert says they’re using their 5G data connection in situations when they might otherwise have looked for a public Wi-Fi network to join. “When you give somebody a true unlimited plan on a 5G phone that’s screaming fast on the biggest and best 5G network in this country, they use it.” That free 5G phone is just the start of what the carrier hopes will be a long and, ultimately, lucrative relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WzcTYa"&gt;Outside of those two companies, US wireless carriers across the board are braced for big changes this year — the impact of which will be felt by the rest of us in one way or another. The beginning of the year saw telecom companies on the upswing compared to last year’s tumultuous first quarter, with most adding more customers than they did in this quarter last year. T-Mobile gained a net of 773,000 postpaid phone customers, and AT&amp;amp;T added 595,000, its highest number in 10 years. Across the industry, companies felt the positive impacts of retail stores reopening to welcome customers with stimulus checks ready to spend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="OPuCJp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Companies felt the positive impacts of retail stores reopening to customers with stimulus checks to spend&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VHnP2f"&gt;While they’re in a better spot than they were when the country started shutting down this time a year ago, there are major hurdles to overcome in the near future. Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T, in particular, have a major project ahead of them in getting ready to deploy that newly won C-band — a costly venture on top of what they owe the federal government for the licenses. C-band is particularly important to those two companies, which are gambling on it to breathe life into their &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22292074/5g-nationwide-verizon-att-tmobile-c-band"&gt;struggling nationwide 5G networks&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hYBUA3"&gt;Verizon is wasting no time; having pledged to spend $10 billion over the next three years on C-band deployment, it’s on track to spend between $2 and 3 billion by the end of the year and says it’s already ordered half of the equipment it will need. AT&amp;amp;T, meanwhile, is proceeding with a more cautious outlook, citing uncertainties around stressed global supply chains, and that other auctions this year could help fill out the company’s spectrum portfolio. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="PTDKZZ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Verizon has pledged to spend $10 billion over the next three years on C-band deployment&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kuENHA"&gt;Meanwhile, this is all the more motivation for T-Mobile to push aggressively for more subscribers now while the other players catch up to its relatively strong position in spectrum holdings. The company &lt;a href="https://investor.t-mobile.com/news-and-events/t-mobile-us-press-releases/press-release-details/2021/T-Mobile-Raises-2021-Guidance-as-Network-Leadership-Fuels-Industry-Leading-Growth-with-Strong-First-Quarter-2021-Results/default.aspx"&gt;raised its investor guidance&lt;/a&gt; and now expects to add a net of between 4.4 and 4.9 million postpaid customers this year, up from 4.0 to 4.7 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oVc1pi"&gt;There’s another storm on the horizon, too, one that could potentially affect hundreds of thousands of wireless customers: T-Mobile’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/2/22364126/boost-mobile-3g-cdma-t-mobile-shutdown-customers-costs"&gt;impending shutdown of its old CDMA network&lt;/a&gt;, which a large number of Boost Mobile (owned now by Dish) customers rely on. Dish says that T-Mobile is moving ahead with the shutdown much earlier than it said it would as an anti-competitive tactic, and Dish Chairman Charlie Ergen’s cries of foul play have gotten more dire in recent weeks, more or less &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22409800/dish-charlie-ergen-t-mobile-cdma-shutdown-grinch"&gt;calling Sievert a “Magenta Grinch.”&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="J6oc8R"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Dish Chairman Charlie Ergen’s cries of foul play have gotten more dire in recent weeks&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="x1rBXS"&gt;The company has also asked the California Public Utilities Commission to &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/dish-california-regulators-t-mobile-inquiry-reopen-9d87c61c-8349-440c-97eb-8cde807ba9bf.html"&gt;reopen the Sprint / T-Mobile merger case&lt;/a&gt;, and it has appealed to Capitol Hill lawmakers to review the situation. If the shutdown goes ahead as currently planned, lots of Boost Mobile customers will be shopping for a new phone soon — and potentially even a new wireless provider, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V0ectx"&gt;So what’s next? For one, we can expect the aggressive play for new customers to continue, along with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22409675/verizon-att-tmobile-5g-mmwave-c-band"&gt;dull roar of the 5G Hype Machine&lt;/a&gt; we’re all tired of hearing by now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="6ScUNY"&gt;In addition to the device offers, your carrier might try to upsell you to one of those premium unlimited plans if you do upgrade to a 5G device. Verizon is committed to those customer “step-ups,” and Sievert hinted that more Magenta Max-type offerings may be on the way, saying the plan is “only the beginning.” So if you do decide to dust off that old phone and turn it in for a new device this year, more power to you — might as well put an old piece of tech to work for you. Just be sure to take a good look at the fine print on the deal.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425022/verizon-t-mobile-att-phone-promotion-magenta-max-5g-c-band"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425022/verizon-t-mobile-att-phone-promotion-magenta-max-5g-c-band</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-07T13:51:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-07T13:51:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google Assistant will sing you a song about getting vaccinated</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Google Assistant" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/q1XT27l8npf8ZyfN8F364VSvaRo=/0x0:1820x1213/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69253157/acastro_180510_1777_google_assistant_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="G0uqwM"&gt;Many of us are excited that COVID-19 vaccines are now widely available in the US, and it seems like Google Assistant is joining in. In fact, it’s got a song to share about it (&lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/05/07/google-assistant-hopes-the-medium-of-song-will-persuade-you-to-get-a-covid-vaccine/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9svoPD"&gt;You can listen to the song yourself by asking Google Assistant to “sing the vaccine song,” but I’ve also recorded it. Take a listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PadBRX"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Happy Friday, here’s a song &lt;a href="https://t.co/hetzPYP8QD"&gt;pic.twitter.com/hetzPYP8QD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Mitchell (@strawberrywell) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/strawberrywell/status/1390714375447584770?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tngQgk"&gt;Okay, hmm... where to start? I’ll give the music some props. It’s got a fun beat with a kind of crispy-sounding snare. I’d also call the synths “tastefully restrained.” Assistant will also, I discovered, sing the song in either a male- or female-sounding voice, depending on your settings. The range!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rttDN5"&gt;Unfortunately, the lyrics aren’t great. If you’re not able to listen, here’s a sample:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Let’s celebrate that we have the vaccine To help us bring a change to this old routine It can help us build our immunities While taking care of our communities" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vvqNVEUSGOsRQIJJM9_epaA4OfA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22498904/Screenshot_20210507_101654.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;To be fair, the subject matter doesn’t lend itself well to song.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="xwphiB"&gt;Yeah, the presentation isn’t really helped by the emoji that punctuate each line. I can fully support the message: my hat’s off to the people who worked hard on developing the vaccines, and we should all get it so we can return back to normal. But I don’t think the best messenger is a digital assistant. I also doubt it’ll be that convincing to people who are distrustful of the vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yKUxYH"&gt;(Also, who’s pining for handshakes to come back?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rz7gBi"&gt;I’m feeling a strong four to a light five on this one. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22424917/google-assistant-vaccine-song-covid"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22424917/google-assistant-vaccine-song-covid</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-07T13:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-07T13:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google goes nuclear against Roku by adding YouTube TV to the main YouTube app</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8pb5quvxP-CvBjZR-tuSKdVLlwI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69253022/acastro_180321_1777_youtube_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Ty3nbu"&gt;A week after their broken-down negotiations &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22412430/roku-youtube-tv-google-feud-explainer-timeline"&gt;spilled into the public&lt;/a&gt;, Google and Roku still haven’t been able to reach a deal to renew YouTube TV’s presence on the huge streaming platform. But Google has come up with something of a workaround in the meantime: it’s going to let people access YouTube TV directly from the main YouTube app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gdp0O4"&gt;YouTube users will start seeing a “Go to YouTube TV” option in the main YouTube app over the next few days. When they select that, they’ll then be switched over to the standard YouTube TV user experience. This option is coming to Roku devices first — where it’s currently most needed — but will also come to YouTube on other platforms as well.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/60xc5D8nnFQBEoj2MbMl-dfkvQU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22498898/Untitled_presentation__5_.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: YouTube&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="PoV6Aw"&gt;In essence, Google has basically stuffed the YouTube TV app into YouTube itself, a solution that seems unlikely to make Roku very happy. Google says it’s “still working to come to an agreement with Roku to ensure continued access to YouTube TV for our mutual customers,” and it notes the YouTube TV app remains usable for those who already have it installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5repmz"&gt;But in the event that things totally fall apart, Google says it’s “in discussions with other partners to secure free streaming devices in case YouTube TV members face any access issues on Roku.” A Google spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that this workaround is only for consumption of YouTube TV; customers cannot sign up for new subscriptions through the YouTube app at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ykhp1d"&gt;On Friday afternoon, Roku responded to Google’s latest move by calling the company “an unchecked monopolist.” Roku also criticized Google’s decision to bundle the services together as an example of its “predatory business practices.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="csdrIx"&gt;Here’s Roku’s full statement, which suggests the company won’t be goaded into removing the main YouTube app:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="tZb47w"&gt;Google’s actions are the clear conduct of an unchecked monopolist bent on crushing fair competition and harming consumer choice. The bundling announcement by YouTube highlights the kind of predatory business practices used by Google that Congress, Attorney Generals and regulatory bodies around the world are investigating. Roku has not asked for one additional dollar in financial value from YouTubeTV. We have simply asked Google to stop their anticompetitive behavior of manipulating user search results to their unique financial benefit and to stop demanding access to sensitive data that no other partner on our platform receives today. In response, Google has continued its practice of blatantly leveraging its YouTube monopoly to force an independent company into an agreement that is both bad for consumers and bad for fair competition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="sIHVNm"&gt;Google said in its Friday blog post that it’s “in ongoing, long-term conversations with Roku to certify that new devices meet our technical requirements,” another confirmation that the company is insisting hardware makers implement support for AV1 decoding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="YFfmZc"&gt;This certification process exists to ensure a consistent and high-quality YouTube experience across different devices, including Google’s own — so you know how to navigate the app and what to expect. We’ll continue our conversations with Roku on certification, in good faith, with the goal of advocating for our mutual customers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="4fqUlP"&gt;Roku has argued that Google’s requirements are unreasonable and will lead to higher prices for its products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C0gUJY"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update May 7th, 3:20PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; The article has been updated to include comment from Roku.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425035/google-youtube-tv-roku-app-feud"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425035/google-youtube-tv-roku-app-feud</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-07T12:50:27-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-07T12:50:27-04:00</updated>
    <title>Watch — and hear — NASA’s Ingenuity copter zip around on Mars</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Yz-Cndas9RFA_wo85ITfLHyeDmI=/49x0:1486x958/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69252765/Mars_Perseverance_ZL0_0050_0671377559_653ECM_N0031950ZCAM05020_110085J.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nAB1Z3"&gt;NASA just released video and audio of its mini Mars helicopter, Ingenuity, flying around the Martian surface during its fourth flight test, as captured by the craft’s robotic partner Perseverance from nearly a football field’s distance away. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eTqdr0"&gt;The footage, combining audio and video of an Ingenuity flight test for the first time, starts off with the soft, rumbling hum of the Martian wind. Ingenuity can be seen stationary on the surface in the right-hand corner of the frame before taking off for flight. When the copter ascends, the ambient hum intensifies; the faint, muffled sound of Ingenuity’s twin rotor blades spinning at 2,537 RPM picks up and it eventually zips across the frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qKpY41"&gt;Perseverance’s Mastcam-Z device captured the video, a sequence of hundreds of images compiled at six frames per second. That camera has returned stunning &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392259/nasa-ingenuity-footage-helicopter-mars-perseverance"&gt;images and video&lt;/a&gt; of Ingenuity in the past, but those views were never synced with audio until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="BM2bzY"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Listen closely  &lt;br&gt;The microphone on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NASAPersevere?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@NASAPersevere&lt;/a&gt;'s SuperCam caught sound during &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MarsHelicopter?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#MarsHelicopter&lt;/a&gt;’s 4th flight. The rumbling is Martian wind, but those rhythmic hums come from Ingenuity. Scientists made it easier to hear by isolating the 84 Hz blade sound. &lt;a href="https://t.co/uua5h40BPL"&gt;https://t.co/uua5h40BPL&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/fGWlMRpVji"&gt;pic.twitter.com/fGWlMRpVji&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— NASA JPL (@NASAJPL) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NASAJPL/status/1390684766345650182?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XGXsHZ"&gt;The audio was recorded using Perseverance’s SuperCam laser instrument, a device that zaps Mars rocks with a laser beam and records the zapping sounds with an onboard microphone. While a spectrometer visually analyzes the makeup of the dust kicked up by the laser, the microphone captures audio to help scientists get an aural idea of how hard the rock is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="mwfvkH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“This recording will be a gold mine for our understanding of the Martian atmosphere.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="q7Kkgp"&gt;That microphone worked overtime last Friday to bring us the first AV experience of Ingenuity’s fourth flight in its legendary test campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LQsnNF"&gt;David Mimoun, science lead for SuperCam’s microphone, said in a statement that prior tests on Earth indicated the device would barely be able to hear Ingenuity’s flight. But hearing the gentle hum of the helicopter’s blades on Mars was “a very good surprise,” he said. “This recording will be a gold mine for our understanding of the Martian atmosphere.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fJyy7x"&gt;The four-pound helicopter &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289668/nasa-mars-perseverance-rover-success"&gt;arrived on Mars&lt;/a&gt; nestled inside NASA’s Perseverance rover on February 18th and was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/4/22366887/nasa-mars-rover-perseverance-ingenuity-helicopter-drops-off"&gt;deployed&lt;/a&gt; on the surface on April 4th. Its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22391496/nasa-ingenuity-helicopter-mars-flight-success"&gt;first flight&lt;/a&gt; on April 19th made history as the first to take place on another world. Initially, engineers planned to conduct just five flight demonstration tests with Ingenuity inside a 31-day window so Perseverance — working as both a photographer and communications hub for Ingenuity — can carry on with its primary mission of hunting for signs of ancient life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oO00S6"&gt;But engineers, impressed with the helicopter’s performance, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22412154/nasa-ingenuity-aces-fourth-flight-mars-advance-new-testing"&gt;gave Ingenuity&lt;/a&gt; another 31-day mission to carry out a few more flights while Perseverance begins its hunt nearby. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fYBsrJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22424821/nasa-ingenuity-mars-perseverance-video-audio-helicopter"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22424821/nasa-ingenuity-mars-perseverance-video-audio-helicopter</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-07T12:41:56-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-07T12:41:56-04:00</updated>
    <title>Tile’s trackers will work with Amazon’s Sidewalk network starting June 14th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yyXWdv2bRCNHn9qoFDx5jXr8Ho0=/62x0:2429x1578/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69252703/Screen_Shot_2021_05_07_at_11.56.17_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gFu5HJ"&gt;Tile has announced that it’ll be &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/tile-to-join-amazon-sidewalk-later-this-year-301134312.html"&gt;launching support for Amazon Sidewalk&lt;/a&gt; — the &lt;a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/devices/amazon-sidewalk-a-new-way-to-stay-connected"&gt;company’s local, Bluetooth network&lt;/a&gt; — on June 14th, allowing Amazon’s Echo devices to strengthen Tile’s network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PmlL7w"&gt;The two companies had already announced plans for Tile to join Sidewalk last fall, but today’s announcement gives an &lt;a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/devices/echo-tile-and-level-devices-join-amazon-sidewalk"&gt;actual date and details for the integration&lt;/a&gt;. The addition of Tile support comes just a few days after Amazon is turning on Sidewalk support for compatible Echo devices in the US on June 8th, too. Also getting access to Sidewalk are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21304792/level-lock-smart-homekit-review-test-price-specs-features"&gt;Level’s smart locks&lt;/a&gt;, which will be able to leverage Sidewalk to directly connect to Ring doorbells, allowing the locks to be used even when outside of Bluetooth range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Bwvbhe"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Amazon will launch a new location-tracking mesh network system later this year","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/21/21448926/amazon-sidewalk-ring-echo-tile-wifi-mesh-ble-location-tracking"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="u9KBn8"&gt;According to Amazon, Sidewalk uses a combination of “Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE), the 900 MHz spectrum, and other frequencies” to allow devices to communicate without Wi-Fi. Devices that support Sidewalk — &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-Sidewalk/b?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;node=21328123011"&gt;including a variety of Echo and Ring&lt;/a&gt; gadgets — can serve as “Sidewalk Bridges” that work together as access points to the Sidewalk network (think of them almost like individual points on a neighborhood-wide mesh router system).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1F63Sn"&gt;When Tile joins Sidewalk, its trackers will be able to be found using Amazon’s network in conjunction with Tile’s existing Bluetooth network, making it even easier to find your missing devices. Additionally, Tile is expanding support for &lt;a href="https://tileteam.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/115005861707-Amazon-Alexa-with-Tile"&gt;Amazon’s Echo smart speakers&lt;/a&gt; by allowing users to see the Echo device to which the missing tag is closest. It’s not quite on the level of the hyper-localized tracking of an ultra-wideband network, though. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PVMmsK"&gt;The news also comes as Apple launches its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22396693/apple-airtag-location-tracker-hands-on-find-my-privacy-safety"&gt;own AirTag trackers&lt;/a&gt;, a direct competitor to Tile’s. Apple’s trackers rely on a mixture of the company’s Find My network — which leverages the Bluetooth capabilities of iPhone, iPad, and Mac devices — and its ultra-wideband radio technology to help locate missing tracking tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KdPnut"&gt;&lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/20/tile-bashes-apples-new-airtag-as-unfair-competition/#:~:text=In%20a%20statement%20released%20today,a%20market%20Tile%20created%2C%20saying%3A&amp;amp;text=The%20reason%20so%20many%20people,value%20we%20offer%20our%20consumers."&gt;Tile has recently criticized Apple’s trackers&lt;/a&gt;, claiming that Apple is using its control over its hardware and software stack for unfair advantages that third-party companies (like Tile) are unable to access. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22424837/tile-amazon-sidewalk-support-release-date-2021-bluetooth-tracking-airtags"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22424837/tile-amazon-sidewalk-support-release-date-2021-bluetooth-tracking-airtags</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
