<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2022-01-20T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-20T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-20T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Boost Celero 5G review: budget phone with budget battery life</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Boost’s first 5G phone is cheap but unremarkable&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="ukL1pq"&gt;Boost Mobile, the MVNO owned by the Dish Network as a result of the Sprint / T-Mobile merger, is in a tricky spot. Not only does it need to expand its user base for nationwide 5G service, but it also needs to migrate over a million Boost customers from Sprint’s CDMA 3G network to its 4G / 5G service (operated by T-Mobile and AT&amp;amp;T) soon since &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/23/22741762/tmobile-delays-shutdown-sprint-3g-network-dish-boost"&gt;T-Mobile will be shutting down Sprint’s CDMA network by March 31, 2022&lt;/a&gt;. This means the carrier will need to convince its many customers to upgrade to newer 4G or, more preferably, 5G phones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hJv8Us"&gt;That’s where Dish’s first self-branded phone, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22697318/dish-5g-game-279-boost-mobile-exclusive-5g-phone-prepaid"&gt;$279.99 Celero 5G&lt;/a&gt; (though often discounted to less), comes into play. This Android phone with iPhone-like looks works better than you’d expect and takes decent photos in good lighting conditions. Unfortunately, it has the exact same price as the popular and well-reviewed Samsung Galaxy A32 5G that’s also available at Boost, making the Celero a direct competitor. So how does the Celero 5G stack up?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wloz9j"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10954511"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Celero 5G’s silver back cover" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QDWJHBxlyr5CXKDjc9NhGN0OSh8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23098805/gsin_190404_4933_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Celero 5G’s plastic body actually makes the phone more lightweight and comfortable to hold.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Q51CwH"&gt;Celero 5G Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="MjNajL"&gt;Like T-Mobile’s REVVL V Plus 5G and AT&amp;amp;T’s Radiant, the Celero 5G is made by Wingtech Technology and custom-designed for Boost (when you plug the phone into a computer, the phone is named “WT Celero 5G”). At first glance, it looks like an iPhone clone: it has an all-round silver trim, square camera array, and the unmistakable rims around the camera lenses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7tp0or"&gt;While its matte silver back cover is surprisingly smudge-resistant, its smooth surface makes the phone way too easy to slide off tables and hands — you’ll want to get a case to protect it. For a big phone (it measures 6.56 x 3 x 0.33-inch (166.60 x 76.20 x 8.40mm)), the Celero’s all-plastic body and beveled edges make it comfortable to hold, and it’s not too heavy either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Closeup of the Celero 5G’s power button" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZyCvq8Ct59l-U9QZM33Du8cr8ow=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23098806/gsin_190404_4933_0003_cropped.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The placement of the Celero 5G’s power and fingerprint sensor is too low and recessed for easy access.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A closeup of the bottom of the Celero 5G" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2XTbUN1GuPYJSnR21TiXjH36KR4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23098807/gsin_190404_4933_0004_cropped.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Celero 5G’s 3.5mm audio jack is located at the bottom of the phone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KYi1dO"&gt;The power button and integrated fingerprint sensor on the Celero are too low and too recessed to use easily, however. As a result, it takes an extra second to unlock the phone with the fingerprint sensor — because I’m usually fumbling for the power button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="oqrFrR"&gt;Celero 5G Performance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="4zJeD8"&gt;The Celero 5G’s screen is big but dim: you need to set the screen brightness to around 100 percent to use it comfortably indoors (you’ll be squinting at this screen outdoors). It has a large 6.5-inch LCD display that is only 720p in resolution, which means high-resolution photos and videos won’t look the sharpest here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RGKj1j"&gt;For a sub-$300 phone using the &lt;a href="https://www.notebookcheck.net/Dimensity-700-vs-Dimensity-720_13199_12994.247596.0.html"&gt;“fast mid-range SoC” MediaTek Dimensity 700 processor&lt;/a&gt; and 4GB RAM for support, the Celero 5G can handle basic tasks without any significant lag. I was able to cycle between my many opened tabs and apps quickly and could even play a YouTube video while I read an article. Like the Samsung A32, the Celero comes with just 64GB of internal storage, but the Celero has a microSD card slot that can support up to a 2TB card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="g2qLIG"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Celero 5G’s display is dim and low-resolution&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0QbKaI"&gt;I played a round of &lt;em&gt;Pokemon Unite,&lt;/em&gt; and the Celero 5G handled the game like a champ. The responsive touchscreen made it easy to move my Charmander around the battlefield, even as the attack moves became more complicated. When I plugged in my wired headphones into its bottom-facing audio jack, I could hear a vocal track on the game’s theme music that I’d previously missed. Its bottom-firing mono-speaker is passable: it managed to play the demanding “Dance at the Gym: Mambo” from the 2021 &lt;em&gt;West Side Story&lt;/em&gt; soundtrack with clarity, if not a bit too loudly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cY4NzL"&gt;Although I appreciate that this phone is running a mostly unmodified version of Android 11, the Celero is unfortunately full of bloatware. In addition to the usual suspects like a folder worth of Amazon apps, there are two folders called “Lifestyle” and “Games’’ that contain a bunch of app shortcuts that the phone will download if you click on the “Add” button. There is even an App Spotlight app that shows you 24 app shortcuts the carrier is encouraging you to download (including &lt;em&gt;The Epoch Times&lt;/em&gt;). To make matters worse, every time you wake or turn on your phone, you will see three apps doing some sort of configuration in the background, but it’s not clear how to disable those processes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IWoJmE"&gt;As Dish’s first self-branded phone, it’s hard to know if and when the Celero will receive any OS or security updates to extend its lifespan. This is a far cry from more established brands like Samsung, which have a four-year software commitment on the A32.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R3xpRV"&gt;The battery life on the Celero 5G is not as long as its 4,000mAh battery would imply. Although I managed to get about 8 hours and 15 minutes of screen time before I had to recharge it, that was with very moderate use. I was only on Wi-Fi to listen to a couple of podcasts, post on Twitter, check email, and chat with family on Google Hangouts. If you use mostly 4G or 5G on this phone, you’ll probably need to keep the charger or a portable battery close by because the Celero might not last a full day of heavy use. The included 15W charger is not exactly a fast charger either: it took over two hours to fully recharge the battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="A4UaIl"&gt;Celero 5G Camera&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Closeup of the Celero 5G’s rear cameras" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nSiJcKjP46v0jttLhpuJYDH5__o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23098808/gsin_190404_4933_0005_cropped.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Celero 5G’s cameras are pretty basic and not suitable for night or sports photography.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="h3Zgcp"&gt;The Celero 5G’s cameras are the standard fare for its class: it has a 16-megapixel rear camera, a 5-megapixel ultrawide, a 2-megapixel depth sensor, and an 8-megapixel front-facing camera for selfies. With good lighting and the right framing, you should be able to get some good photos with good details to share online. However, I wouldn’t use this phone to take action or night photography because these cameras just aren’t capable enough for more challenging situations. The front camera, on the other hand, can capture relatively bright selfies even in dim lighting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zn42Wa"&gt;Like other budget phones, the Celero’s ultrawide photos tend to skew yellow, especially when you compare a photo taken with the main camera of the same scene. Whether I take outdoor holiday decoration photos or indoors inside a diner, the ultrawide camera has a knack for inexplicably boosting the yellow channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="77JkcT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10954550"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bITS9Q"&gt;Worst of all, the Celero’s camera app is annoying to use. It can take an extra second to switch between the main and the ultrawide cameras or different modes, which might be the difference between you getting or missing the shot. It also takes about two seconds to process a live focus shot, so you’ll need a steady hand and patience when using this mode. When I tried to take a photo that happened to have a QR code, the app kept asking me if I wanted to visit that website, even after I repeatedly tapped “No.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="EPlgm0"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Celero 5G’s silver back cover" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4M0ExMH_y5UcI_d8jbdBZvWTxeY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23098811/gsin_190404_4933_0011.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Celero 5G has tough competition from budget 5G phones from Samsung, Motorola and OnePlus.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cdKDPA"&gt;As much as I enjoyed the $279.99 Celero 5G for its iPhone-like looks and capable performance, I have a hard time recommending it over the same-priced Samsung Galaxy A32 5G. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jzivR5"&gt;For the same money, the Samsung Galaxy A32 5G offers a bigger battery at 5,000mAh, a better 48-megapixel main camera, C-band 5G compatibility, and four years of software support from Samsung. With the Celero, it’s hard to know if it’ll get software support like security updates, from whom and for how long, not to mention its smaller battery and less powerful cameras. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zYk2yt"&gt;Boost also offers the $249.99 Motorola Moto G Stylus 5G, which is $30 cheaper than the Celero, comes with double the internal storage at 128GB, and also features a 48-megapixel camera. The best-in-class OnePlus Nord N200 5G is even cheaper at $239, and it includes a 1080p display with a 90Hz refresh rate, though it’s not clear if this unlocked phone will be compatible on Boost’s network. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="cq9KHM"&gt;I wish Boost would give the Celero 5G a permanent price cut, like its current promotional price of $139.99 or lower. This would make it a whole lot easier to recommend the Celero despite its shortcomings — shorter battery life, more bloatware, untested brand. But without that significant discount, the Celero 5G is not your best bet at Boost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xY6oTC"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by: Gloria Sin / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="62NXyZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10987297"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22837805/celero-5g-review-phone"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22837805/celero-5g-review-phone</id>
    <author>
      <name>Gloria Sin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-20T09:44:35-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-20T09:44:35-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to get your money back for at-home COVID test kits</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GULD0K745HlgEtR2XE-g9bohGOI=/50x0:406x237/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70411785/home_test_hero.2099b1df64ebd24bb68a.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: USPS&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;div id="2nCrDr"&gt;
&lt;script type="application/ld+json"&gt;
{
 "@context": "https://schema.org",
 "@type": "HowTo",
 "name": "How to get your money back for at-home COVID test kits",
 "description": "However, if you’ve got private insurance through an employer or a group, you do have an alternative: you can get a reimbursement for — or pick up free at approved retailers — up to eight FDA-authorized at-home COVID tests per person per month.",
 "step": [
  {
   "@type": "HowToSection",
   "position": "1",
   "name": "How do you take advantage of this? ",
   "itemListElement": [
    {
     "@type": "HowToStep",
     "position": "1",
     "itemListElement": [
      {
       "@type": "HowToDirection",
       "position": "1",
       "text": "Currently, the best way to find out how to get reimbursed for tests you have purchased is to log on to your health insurance site."
      },
      {
       "@type": "HowToTip",
       "position": "2",
       "text": "I checked about six insurance sites, and currently, most are offering claim forms that you can fill out and submit with proof of purchase."
      }
     ]
    }
   ]
  },
  {
   "@type": "HowToSection",
   "position": "2",
   "name": "Some other things to be aware of:",
   "itemListElement": [
    {
     "@type": "HowToStep",
     "position": "1",
     "itemListElement": [
      {
       "@type": "HowToDirection",
       "position": "1",
       "text": "You will have to provide proof of purchase along with your claim form, so if you make the purchase at a local store, don’t lose that receipt.\n"
      }
     ]
    },
    {
     "@type": "HowToStep",
     "position": "2",
     "itemListElement": [
      {
       "@type": "HowToDirection",
       "position": "1",
       "text": "Your insurance company may have a list of approved kits and / or approved retailers that it will accept claims for. "
      },
      {
       "@type": "HowToTip",
       "position": "2",
       "text": "As a result, it’s a good idea to check your insurer’s site before buying."
      }
     ]
    },
    {
     "@type": "HowToStep",
     "position": "3",
     "itemListElement": [
      {
       "@type": "HowToDirection",
       "position": "1",
       "text": "You can buy an FDA-approved kit outside of your insurer’s approved retailer network; your insurance company is required to reimburse those purchases at a rate of $12 per test."
      }
     ]
    },
    {
     "@type": "HowToStep",
     "position": "4",
     "itemListElement": [
      {
       "@type": "HowToDirection",
       "position": "1",
       "text": "If you ordered a COVID test kit online before January 15th but didn’t receive it until after, you may still be covered. Either check with your insurer, or submit the form with proof of purchase and delivery, and hope for the best."
      }
     ]
    },
    {
     "@type": "HowToStep",
     "position": "5",
     "itemListElement": [
      {
       "@type": "HowToDirection",
       "position": "1",
       "text": "The requirement covers eight tests per person — not eight kits. So if your kit contains two or more tests (and many do), then keep that in mind when submitting your claim.\n"
      }
     ]
    }
   ]
  }
 ]
}
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ydgALv"&gt;While it’s nice that the government will be sending us &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889571/free-covid-19-tests-usps-website"&gt;four free at-home rapid COVID test kits a month&lt;/a&gt;, that’s not going to be enough for many households. However, if you’ve got private insurance through an employer or a group, you do have an alternative: you can get a reimbursement for — or pick up free at approved retailers — &lt;a href="https://www.cms.gov/how-to-get-your-at-home-OTC-COVID-19-test-for-free"&gt;up to eight FDA-authorized at-home COVID tests per person per month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ct2JeT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to order free rapid COVID tests from the US government","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22889745/rapid-covid-tests-free-website-how-to"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="XhHXmX"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2022/01/10/biden-harris-administration-requires-insurance-companies-group-health-plans-to-cover-cost-at-home-covid-19-tests-increasing-access-free-tests.html"&gt;Announced back in January&lt;/a&gt;, the new rules state that private health insurers are required to cover these tests without needing approval from a doctor or other medical provider. (If you need more kits, you can also get them covered if it is ordered by a medical provider.) This requirement went into effect on January 15th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xNVdGk"&gt;How do you take advantage of this? That depends on your specific health insurer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t3ozFB"&gt;Currently, the best way to find out how to get reimbursed for tests you have purchased is to log on to your health insurance site. I checked about six insurance sites, and currently, most are offering claim forms that you can fill out and submit with proof of purchase. Eventually, according to the announcement, we should be able to pick up kits at approved pharmacies and stores; however, it’s early days yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DvVEp9"&gt;Some other things to be aware of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="vQtkWn"&gt;You will have to provide proof of purchase along with your claim form, so if you make the purchase at a local store, don’t lose that receipt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BqFMmH"&gt;Your insurance company may have a list of approved kits and / or approved retailers that it will accept claims for. As a result, it’s a good idea to check your insurer’s site before buying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="s8Fhd5"&gt;You &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; buy an FDA-approved kit outside of your insurer’s approved retailer network; your insurance company is required to reimburse those purchases at a rate of $12 per test.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WiPybb"&gt;If you ordered a COVID test kit online before January 15th but didn’t receive it until after, you may still be covered. Either check with your insurer, or submit the form with proof of purchase and delivery, and hope for the best.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="L9pjb7"&gt;The requirement covers eight tests per person — not eight kits. So if your kit contains two or more tests (and many do), then keep that in mind when submitting your claim.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="P862Xd"&gt;Unfortunately, this leaves Medicare and Medicaid health insurance recipients — and those who don’t have insurance — pretty much out in the cold. The government is now providing four free test kits per month per household if you sign up for them, but that isn’t going to go very far if you have more than a couple of people in your household and a need to test frequently. According to &lt;a href="https://www.hrsa.gov/coronavirus/testing-supplies"&gt;the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA&lt;/a&gt;), HRSA- and Medicare-supported health clinics are being supplied with at-home test kits to distribute; you will need to check with your local clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="edOJ6t"&gt;You can find more information for reimbursements from the &lt;a href="https://www.cms.gov/how-to-get-your-at-home-OTC-COVID-19-test-for-free"&gt;Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="07Niyz"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22891974/covid-test-kits-purchase-reimbursement-insurance"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22891974/covid-test-kits-purchase-reimbursement-insurance</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-20T09:08:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-20T09:08:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>Craig of the Creek’s getting a spinoff, a new movie, and a fifth season</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4xUjQsNR2JVV8YK3gIm9qIcw4Us=/229x0:1545x877/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70411687/Craig_of_the_Creek_Key_Art.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Cartoon Network&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IRsAMT"&gt;Though the newest season of Cartoon Network’s &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/craig-of-the-creeks-world-of-summertime-wonder-is-getti-1834568544"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Craig of the Creek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;only just picked back up earlier this week, the network’s already decided that it wants to see much, much more of Craig, the rest of the Johnson family, and the other Creek Kids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SeKSKL"&gt;In a move that’s sure to calm fans who can never be certain if and when these shows are coming back, Cartoon Network has just announced that &lt;em&gt;Craig of the Creek &lt;/em&gt;has been renewed for a fifth season that will continue to follow the adventures of Craig (Philip Solomon), Kelsey (Noël Wells), and J.P. (H. Michael Croner) as they discover new depths of the creek they call a second home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fO0iVo"&gt;With a whole new half of the Creek suddenly becoming accessible to Craig and the gang in the show’s last season, &lt;em&gt;Craig of the Creek&lt;/em&gt;’s been hinting at the introduction of even more characters with fresh ideas about how best to imagine the shared space as something more than the woods around their neighborhood. Though &lt;em&gt;Craig of the Creek&lt;/em&gt;’s core cast of characters is going to have a hand in how everyone’s understanding of the creek &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/craig-of-the-creek-turned-pokemon-into-an-important-lif-1837669116"&gt;continues to evolve&lt;/a&gt;, the larger &lt;em&gt;Craig of the Creek &lt;/em&gt;franchise is also about to go through a growth spurt thanks to a new spinoff series and origin film.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4S6vDr6uafqFODd-eMV3R7imbxY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23180673/Jessica_s_Big_Little_World_Key_Art.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Cartoon Network&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Key art for Jessica’s Little Big World.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="EUVEoE"&gt;With Craig’s younger sister Jessica (Lucia Cunningham) finally being old enough to go to preschool, she’s also ready to become the star of &lt;em&gt;Jessica’s Little Big World&lt;/em&gt;, her own series co-created and executive produced by Matt Burnett, Ben Levin, and Tiffany Ford that explores the world from Jessica’s unique perspective. Promotional art for &lt;em&gt;Jessica’s Little Big World &lt;/em&gt;appears to depict Jessica alongside a talking version of her beloved stuffed animal, Small Uncle, as well as a curiously different (read: older, and more together) version of the Creek Kid Wren, alluding to how many things about the series are depicted as Jessica sees them rather than as they actually are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AIu6HD"&gt;In addition to &lt;em&gt;Jessica’s Little Big World&lt;/em&gt;, Cartoon Network also announced that &lt;em&gt;Craig of The Creek: The Movie&lt;/em&gt;, an animated feature detailing Craig’s earliest days as the new kid in the neighborhood, has been greenlit for production and is slated to premiere on both Cartoon Network proper and HBO Max. While there’s currently no word on when &lt;em&gt;Jessica’s Little Big World &lt;/em&gt;will debut, both &lt;em&gt;Craig of the Creek: The Movie &lt;/em&gt;and the show’s fifth season are slated to premiere sometime in 2023. &lt;em&gt;Craig of the Creek&lt;/em&gt;’s current season is now airing on Cartoon Network ahead of the whole season coming on HBO Max on February 17th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22892102/craig-of-the-creek-season-5-the-movie"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22892102/craig-of-the-creek-season-5-the-movie</id>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Pulliam-Moore</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-20T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-20T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Mercedes-Benz acquires stake in lidar maker Luminar, will use its sensors for future autonomous vehicles</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="EMBARGO: June 15, 2021, 10:30am ET" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W4d0e8VTfWkLOkvXWNOvDrG_tic=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70411654/VRG05AH_210614_4634_006.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;EMBARGO: June 15, 2021, 10:30am ET | Photo by Andrew J. Hawkins / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wYNLpV"&gt;Mercedes-Benz announced it will integrate Luminar’s lidar sensors into future production vehicles to enable autonomous driving capabilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GBpjRh"&gt;The German automaker is also taking an equity stake in the Orlando, Florida-based company, acquiring a total of 1.5 million shares. Based on Luminar’s share price of $13.45 at market close January 19th, Mercedes-Benz is purchasing approximately $20.2 million worth of shares, or less than 1 percent of the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9TixBq"&gt;Lidar, a key ingredient in autonomous driving, is a laser sensor that uses near-infrared light to detect the shapes of objects. This helps autonomous vehicles “see” other objects on the road, like cars, pedestrians, and cyclists, all without the help of GPS or a network connection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="mOXjOT"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Mercedes-Benz says it plans to integrate Luminar’s lidar sensors into its production vehicles&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ykhdt2"&gt;Mercedes-Benz says it plans to integrate Luminar’s lidar sensors into its production vehicles, but there’s a lot that we still don’t know. The automaker declined to share a timeline for integrating Luminar’s lidar into its vehicles, which models would be getting the laser sensor, or what kind of autonomous capabilities it would enable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IUujp5"&gt;Mercedes-Benz has said that its model year 2023 S-Class and EQS sedans will come with the automaker’s Drive Pilot advanced driver assistance system, which it describes as capable of Level 3 automation. Mercedes claims to be the first to “secure internationally valid system approval for conditionally automated driving (SAE Level 3) – marking a milestone in automotive development.” The feature will &lt;a href="https://www.caranddriver.com/news/a38475565/mercedes-drive-pilot-autonomous-germany/"&gt;only be available in Germany&lt;/a&gt;, though, and not the US.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UYYRoj"&gt;Level 3, as defined by the Society of Automotive Engineers, means the driver’s supervision is not required in a highly controlled setting, like on certain mapped highways. The driver still needs to be ready to take control at a moment’s notice, leaving it somewhere in a nebulous zone between Level 2 advanced driver assist systems, like Tesla’s Autopilot, and Level 4 fully driverless vehicles, like Waymo’s autonomous taxi service in Phoenix, Arizona.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pNvvpY"&gt;A lot of companies are claiming to release Level 3 capable vehicles in the coming years. Volvo, which is also using Luminar’s lidar in its upcoming electric vehicles, said its Ride Pilot will enable its vehicles to drive themselves on certain highways without any human supervision — though the company is only &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/5/22866190/volvo-ride-pilot-level-3-autonomous-subscription-california"&gt;planning on enabling the feature in California once it receives authorization&lt;/a&gt; from the state’s Department of Motor Vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="eCPAJN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A lot of companies are claiming to release Level 3 capable vehicles in the coming years&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bgyxFH"&gt;Most AV companies, including Waymo, Argo, and Cruise, have said they are skipping Level 3 and working exclusively on Level 4 technology. The reason is that Level 3 is seen as being potentially dangerous, given the likelihood that drivers will be confused about when they need to takeover control of the vehicle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GHLCXL"&gt;There is also a data sharing angle to Mercedes’ new partnership with Luminar. The company’s CEO, Austin Russell, said the ability to collect data from Mercedes’ vehicles will ultimately help improve his company’s autonomous vehicle software. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rDEboV"&gt;Russell noted that Waymo, the AV company under Alphabet, has one of the the largest AV fleet in the world, with hundreds of vehicles operating in suburban Phoenix, Arizona. He said the ultimate goal was to have “hundreds of thousands of vehicles” on the road around the world gathering data on road conditions and traffic, enabling companies like Luminar to launch autonomous vehicle features in a broader range of markets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="SPjzKV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It takes not just hundreds, but hundreds of thousands of vehicles to actually be able to get to the global level of data that’s needed”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9ojzIs"&gt;“It takes not just hundreds, but hundreds of thousands of vehicles to actually be able to get to the global level of data that’s needed, and not just in one specific suburban area,” he said. “Also you don’t have to pay drivers. It’s people that are driving the cars already that allow it to continue to improve and get better and better and better.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OYHnhL"&gt;This isn’t the first time that a Daimler-owned company has bought shares in Luminar. Daimler Trucks, a division of Mercedes-Benz’s parent company, also &lt;a href="https://daimler-trucksnorthamerica.com/PressDetail/daimler-trucks-and-torc-partner-with-2020-10-30"&gt;bought a minority stake&lt;/a&gt; in the company in 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XszUIi"&gt;Luminar has secured commitments from a number of companies to purchase its lidars. In addition to Mercedes-Benz, the company has deals with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/6/21248415/volvo-luminar-lidar-self-driving-highway-pilot-spa2"&gt;Volvo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/18/18144506/audi-self-driving-car-volkswagen-luminar-lidar"&gt;Audi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/4/16849422/toyota-self-driving-car-platform-3-lexus-lidar"&gt;Toyota Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/intel-mobileye-int/mobileye-looks-to-build-its-own-lidar-to-drive-down-self-driving-costs-idUSKBN28P2GW"&gt;Intel’s Mobileye&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/26/22399389/luminar-airbus-lidar-aviation-evtol-partnership"&gt;Airbus&lt;/a&gt;, and two Chinese companies: &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/03/18/saic-motor-to-use-luminar-sensors-in-high-tech-line-of-vehicles.html"&gt;automaker SAIC&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/10/22424726/pony-ai-luminar-lidar-robotaxi-california-china"&gt;AV operator Pony.ai&lt;/a&gt;. Luminar may even have a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/24/22451404/tesla-luminar-lidar-elon-musk-autonomous-vehicles"&gt;partnership with Tesla&lt;/a&gt;, despite Elon Musk’s vocal derision of lidar as a “crutch” and a “fool’s errand.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22891314/mercedes-benz-luminar-equity-stake-lidar-autonomous-vehicles"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22891314/mercedes-benz-luminar-equity-stake-lidar-autonomous-vehicles</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-20T08:28:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-20T08:28:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>Streaming music report sheds light on battle between Spotify, Amazon, Apple, and Google  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wlyKvNdo2QIPi4WU8-WJs6N6TqM=/1x0:1600x1066/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70411565/music_streaming_market_share.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Market share for the world’s largest music streaming services.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Midia Research&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Y8KfeM"&gt;Spotify was the largest music streaming service in the world as of the second quarter of 2021 with a market share of 31 percent, with Apple Music in second place at 15 percent, and Amazon Music and Tencent Music each tied at third with 13 percent apiece. That’s according to a &lt;a href="https://www.midiaresearch.com/blog/music-subscriber-market-shares-q2-2021"&gt;report from Midia Research&lt;/a&gt;, a media and entertainment-focused research and analysis agency. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vazr2E"&gt;Although exact subscriber numbers and market shares may have changed in the months since Q2 2021 (the use of older data is because of how long the market analysis process takes, Midia tells me), the report sheds light on how the world’s biggest music streaming services are stacking up against one another. While Spotify releases official subscriber numbers at the end of each quarter (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22746682/spotify-q3-2021-earnings-podcast-music-streaming-financials"&gt;most recently in October last year&lt;/a&gt;), competitors like Apple and Amazon are less forthcoming with exact figures, and the most recent &lt;a href="https://musically.com/2020/07/28/spotify-apple-how-many-users-big-music-streaming-services/"&gt;official figures compiled by &lt;em&gt;Music Ally&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are from 2019 and 2020 respectively. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="VCP899"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple and Amazon Music have reported market shares of 15 and 13 percent&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tGROGm"&gt;Based on Midia’s claim that there were 523.9 million total music streaming subscribers in Q2 2021, this suggests Spotify had just over 162.4 million subscribers paying for its music streaming service (although the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22596155/spotify-earnings-q2-2021-podcasting-investments-acquisitions-subscribers"&gt;official figure for Q2 was 165 million&lt;/a&gt;). Midia’s estimates would then put Apple Music at almost 78.6 million subscribers for the quarter, and Amazon Music and China-exclusive Tencent Music at a little over 68.1 million each. YouTube Music follows up in fifth place with an 8 percent market share corresponding to 41.9 million subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tsukxG"&gt;According to Midia, the music streaming market is continuing to grow, and increased by 26.4 percent to the second quarter of last year. Although Spotify’s commanding lead means it’s unlikely to be overtaken anytime soon, Midia notes that its market share dropped from 33 percent in Q2 2020 to 31 percent in Q2 2021, and its growth was outperformed by Amazon and YouTube Music, with the latter growing by over 50 percent compared to a year earlier. Growth in emerging markets was reportedly also strong, with Yandex, Tencent, and NetEast growing by a combined 37 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iIOwEh"&gt;Given these figures date back to the second quarter of last year, they’re unlikely to show the full impact of the lossless audio streaming changes that were made last year. Apple Music, for example, added &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523228/apple-music-lossless-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-features"&gt;lossless-quality and spatial audio streaming features in June&lt;/a&gt;, while &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22440058/amazon-music-hd-price-cut-apple-lossless-audio"&gt;Amazon stopped charging extra for lossless streaming in May&lt;/a&gt;. However despite making a big splash with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295273/spotify-hifi-announced-lossless-streaming-hd-quality"&gt;lossless audio announcement of its own&lt;/a&gt;, Spotify’s new Hi-Fi tier missed its planned 2021 release window.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22892939/music-streaming-services-market-share-q2-2021-spotify-apple-amazon-tencent-youtube"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22892939/music-streaming-services-market-share-q2-2021-spotify-apple-amazon-tencent-youtube</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-20T08:23:31-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-20T08:23:31-05:00</updated>
    <title>Crypto.com admits over $30 million stolen by hackers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An illustration of bitcoin" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r-X86g3esA40PBuwSKzgPvw0R5A=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70411559/acastro_bitcoin_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1QmLWm"&gt;In a &lt;a href="https://blog.crypto.com/crypto-com-security-report-next-steps/"&gt;blog post &lt;/a&gt;published in the early hours of Thursday morning, cryptocurrency exchange Crypto.com acknowledged that the company had lost well over $30 million in Bitcoin and Ethereum after a hack that took place on January 17th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CtVQDs"&gt;The company has been criticized for vague communication around the hack, which was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891949/crypto-ceo-confirms-hundreds-accounts-hacked-bloomberg-ethereum"&gt;only officially confirmed yesterday&lt;/a&gt; by CEO Kris Marszalek.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ljdoau"&gt;The new blog post said that the total value of the unauthorized withdrawals was 4,836.26 ETH and 443.93 BTC — equivalent to roughly $15.2 million and $18.6 million respectively, at current exchange rates — as well as $66,200 worth of other currencies. According to the post, 483 Crypto.com users had their accounts compromised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vi8rXY"&gt;Crypto.com has said that all affected customers have been fully reimbursed for the losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ev8V6n"&gt;The latest communication from the company provides the most insight yet into the security breach, although details of the exact method of compromise remain unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cH4sby"&gt;“On Monday, 17 January 2022 at approximately 12:46 AM UTC Crypto.com’s risk monitoring systems detected unauthorized activity on a small number of user accounts where transactions were being approved without the 2FA authentication control being inputted by the user,” the post reads. “This triggered an immediate response from multiple teams to assess the impact. All withdrawals on the platform were suspended for the duration of the investigation. Any accounts found to be impacted were fully restored.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="udhlC1"&gt;As a result of the hack, the exchange has migrated its two-factor authentication system to a new architecture, and revoked all existing 2FA tokens, meaning that all customers will need to switch over to the new system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0K2L70"&gt;The Crypto.com hack is the latest in a string of attacks targeting cryptocurrency exchanges, which are some of the most high-value targets in the steadily growing cryptocurrency ecosystem. In 2021 there were more than 20 exchange hacks &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/security/bitcoin-crypto-exchange-hacks-little-anyone-can-do-rcna7870"&gt;where the hacker escaped with more than $10 million&lt;/a&gt; in profit according to an analysis by NBC News, and six cases where the value of funds stolen exceeded $100 million.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22892958/crypto-com-exchange-hack-bitcoin-ethereum-security"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22892958/crypto-com-exchange-hack-bitcoin-ethereum-security</id>
    <author>
      <name>Corin Faife</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-20T07:57:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-20T07:57:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook and Instagram are reportedly exploring plans to make, showcase, and sell NFTs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/etvX5rtiaCTyUCg4JIHykXMqiMI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70411423/acastro_211101_1777_meta_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7ygsQG"&gt;Social media conglomerate Meta is exploring plans to let users create, showcase, and sell NFTs on Facebook and Instagram, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/2745d50b-36e4-4c0a-abe0-e93f035b0628"&gt;report from &lt;em&gt;The Financial Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cwVpv9"&gt;If the company launches such tools, it would be the biggest show of mainstream support for NFTs to date, and help solidify the controversial assets’ place in the digital world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FSNC2G"&gt;As per the &lt;em&gt;FT&lt;/em&gt;, the plans are “at an early stage and could yet change.” The publication says teams at Facebook and Instagram are “readying” a feature that will let users display NFTs as their profile pictures, as well as working on a prototype to let users mint new NFTs. Others at Meta are reportedly discussing “launching a marketplace for users to buy and sell NFTs.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pu7AG9"&gt;Exactly how far along these plans are is impossible to say, but it’s not the first show of interest in NFTs we’ve seen from Meta’s leaders. Instagram chief Adam Mosseri &lt;a href="https://uk.finance.yahoo.com/news/instagram-currently-exploring-nfts-ceo-183537502.html?guce_referrer=ahr0chm6ly93d3cuz29vz2xllmnvbs8&amp;amp;guce_referrer_sig=aqaaaekjfquyoqo6ejm4nkpo6ql9wubt42gt1x9bhwu6dkukkijdfpioi9ipkou3-hg2txjqjzpm0ig0xfs03d3mlcbjq8sv4zrrl2ktawdmqhg7hsn23k6-vqwykp8ev50g_jxenb5zlut9ldbmwzmhlfvecvhrjy9loianefjvxcij"&gt;said last December&lt;/a&gt; that the company is “actively exploring NFTs and how we can make them more accessible to a wider audience,” while last October Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/4/videos/572525803829402/"&gt;spoke about&lt;/a&gt; how the metaverse will need to support “ownership of digital goods or NFTs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="V5rAxj"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Web stalwarts like Reddit and Twitter have also shown interest in NFTs&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Jt83R3"&gt;NFTs, or non-fungible tokens, have been gaining support with other established web platforms in recent months. Twitter is working on ways to showcase such &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744540/twitter-blockchain-linked-collectibles-tab"&gt;blockchain-supported items&lt;/a&gt;, while Reddit launched its own &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/CryptoCurrency/comments/o6ms0b/introducing_cryptosnoosa_very_reddit_take_on_nfts/"&gt;collection of NFT avatars for users&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S0sUfk"&gt;Although NFTs are much derided for their speculative value (prices rise and fall with shocking speed) and lack of security (they’re frequently stolen despite claims by some that they guarantee ownership), these assets will become more significant if existing tech giants choose to support them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HM2JYl"&gt;An NFT is, at heart, a way to claim ownership of a digital item like a JPG or a GIF via a unique address on the blockchain. And despite claims that these assets embody a decentralized forms of ownership, their legitimacy rests upon recognition from existing online platforms. If Twitter or Instagram lets anyone copy and paste your JPG of a smoking chimp, who’s to say who really owns it? But if companies start enforcing ownership rights as signified by NFTs, they could become legitimate digital assets (at least on those platforms). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6J05E9"&gt;For Meta, embracing NFTs could also help it wield greater influence in what the company has labelled the metaverse — a nebulous concept of interconnected virtual worlds, similar to promises of VR universes floated in the 1990s and before. That could potentially boost the value and importance of NFTs while simultaneously centralizing control over the assets.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22892917/meta-facebook-instagram-plans-make-show-case-sell-nfts"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22892917/meta-facebook-instagram-plans-make-show-case-sell-nfts</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-20T07:19:50-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-20T07:19:50-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter Communities now work on Android</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Twitter’s blue bird silhouette logo on a black background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/etAeUP-_caPc9foT6JqNCspNXsk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70411369/acastro_180827_1777_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FYLPuE"&gt;Twitter is rolling out its Communities feature, a rival to Facebook Groups and Reddit, to Android users worldwide. Since its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22661649/twitter-releases-communities-facebook-groups-reddit-competitor"&gt;launch in September&lt;/a&gt;, Twitter Communities has been limited to iOS or the web, meaning Android users could only join and participate in communities through a browser and not the native Twitter app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aFQbo5"&gt;Android users can now easily join, request to join, or participate in Twitter Communities, opening up the feature to a lot more of Twitter’s userbase. Twitter Communities work like a private group, or like a subreddit. Twitter users can choose to tweet directly to a Twitter community, and that tweet won’t show up on their own feed or to their followers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="aHzh8T"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Twitters Communities is still in beta&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iMMGDF"&gt;Twitter Communities is still an invite-only feature for those wanting to create their own private community. Group owners can choose whether people need an invite to join a community or whether they’re open. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SVGrQ0"&gt;If you’re interested in trying out the Twitter Communities feature, Twitter is highlighting the &lt;a href="https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=https-3A__twitter.com_i_communities_1456210950697201667&amp;amp;d=DwMFaQ&amp;amp;c=7MSjEE-cVgLCRHxk1P5PWg&amp;amp;r=Su-ijVCWM-EpsR7XUMEZwdX5A6GYA0UuAkKC7MrcZ3s&amp;amp;m=Uv9qWPlVC6bLoWR3OGaRwo3ukTdrKzk8B9dOoqZh0hz6zJ26DLBV3m1ROlVaqoGC&amp;amp;s=Rqoogv5hj3GkJ0cEq4S-U7uav8wkd2DfRMfphOhuCWM&amp;amp;e="&gt;Roblox&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=https-3A__twitter.com_i_communities_1455305732912418820&amp;amp;d=DwMFaQ&amp;amp;c=7MSjEE-cVgLCRHxk1P5PWg&amp;amp;r=Su-ijVCWM-EpsR7XUMEZwdX5A6GYA0UuAkKC7MrcZ3s&amp;amp;m=Uv9qWPlVC6bLoWR3OGaRwo3ukTdrKzk8B9dOoqZh0hz6zJ26DLBV3m1ROlVaqoGC&amp;amp;s=M83vv79CLhSEGG9_7g2pqkisivtxcOA8SL5qJ7Eu-4w&amp;amp;e="&gt;Xbox Community&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=https-3A__twitter.com_i_communities_1472105760389668865&amp;amp;d=DwMFaQ&amp;amp;c=7MSjEE-cVgLCRHxk1P5PWg&amp;amp;r=Su-ijVCWM-EpsR7XUMEZwdX5A6GYA0UuAkKC7MrcZ3s&amp;amp;m=Uv9qWPlVC6bLoWR3OGaRwo3ukTdrKzk8B9dOoqZh0hz6zJ26DLBV3m1ROlVaqoGC&amp;amp;s=jmUmmI7YfVP9GDEWDLpyEBJaDu9_nnKcTufoC1rpqu0&amp;amp;e="&gt;Tech Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=https-3A__twitter.com_i_communities_1455315897657270281&amp;amp;d=DwMFaQ&amp;amp;c=7MSjEE-cVgLCRHxk1P5PWg&amp;amp;r=Su-ijVCWM-EpsR7XUMEZwdX5A6GYA0UuAkKC7MrcZ3s&amp;amp;m=Uv9qWPlVC6bLoWR3OGaRwo3ukTdrKzk8B9dOoqZh0hz6zJ26DLBV3m1ROlVaqoGC&amp;amp;s=v1wORJFKp8-gYXri4ARRZvCCwBA8A3THdu_mWBM3wEU&amp;amp;e="&gt;Fashion&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=https-3A__twitter.com_i_communities_1473375845628710916&amp;amp;d=DwMFaQ&amp;amp;c=7MSjEE-cVgLCRHxk1P5PWg&amp;amp;r=Su-ijVCWM-EpsR7XUMEZwdX5A6GYA0UuAkKC7MrcZ3s&amp;amp;m=Uv9qWPlVC6bLoWR3OGaRwo3ukTdrKzk8B9dOoqZh0hz6zJ26DLBV3m1ROlVaqoGC&amp;amp;s=H3u0iKCcwnEfiZMlk3AEJP6xVXAf2mpIQxfBBKWSjaQ&amp;amp;e="&gt;R&amp;amp;B Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=https-3A__twitter.com_i_communities_1442988929070731268&amp;amp;d=DwMFaQ&amp;amp;c=7MSjEE-cVgLCRHxk1P5PWg&amp;amp;r=Su-ijVCWM-EpsR7XUMEZwdX5A6GYA0UuAkKC7MrcZ3s&amp;amp;m=Uv9qWPlVC6bLoWR3OGaRwo3ukTdrKzk8B9dOoqZh0hz6zJ26DLBV3m1ROlVaqoGC&amp;amp;s=0j4xDJNevlBE8Iq9ZEUAvintdRD7523SQWEq0G8hcps&amp;amp;e="&gt;Formula 1&lt;/a&gt; communities that are all public for anyone to join.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A6TKnx"&gt;Twitter is also exploring a “request to join” option for communities, so groups can more closely monitor who joins a community. Alongside this new option, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HiCommunities/status/1478795193050701825"&gt;Twitter is also planning&lt;/a&gt; to test a ranked timeline that will show top tweets from a community, ways for mods to highlight content in community, and methods for Q&amp;amp;As to be held with mods or members.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22892904/twitter-communities-android-release"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22892904/twitter-communities-android-release</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-20T06:41:44-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-20T06:41:44-05:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon’s first clothing store lets you summon clothes to the fitting room  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A touchscreen in Amazon Style’s fitting room." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TEWbc6GviwcZTzgk8Kr84T1Ozz0=/51x0:609x372/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70411286/image.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Amazon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JBpEmM"&gt;Amazon Style is a new kind of physical store from the online shopping giant that will focus on clothing, footwear, and other fashion accessories, the &lt;a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/retail/amazon-reimagines-in-store-shopping-with-amazon-style"&gt;company announced today&lt;/a&gt;. It’s due to open at The Americana at Brand shopping mall in Los Angeles later this year, where it will be Amazon’s “first-ever physical apparel store.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9YT49E"&gt;In line with Amazon’s existing retail locations, the new Amazon Style store is packed to the gills with shopping tech. Amazon says clothes racks will feature QR codes, which customers can scan to see available sizes, colors, customer ratings, and product details. Then, with a tap of a button, selected items will be sent to a fitting room to try on without having to first rummage through racks. Amazon will also send additional items its algorithms think you might like. A promotional video shows how Amazon’s app will alert customers when a fitting room is ready.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Yv_gzjgKsOSwtEwIZ9AzXpvE_cg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23181750/Screen_Shot_2022_01_20_at_11.25.18_AM.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Amazon&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A video shows Amazon’s app alerting a customer when their fitting room is ready.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="1lId4P"&gt;The fitting rooms will also feature touchscreens of their own, so customers can request more items be brought to them. Items can either be purchased in store or saved to the Amazon Shopping app to buy at a later date. Alternatively, customers at home can use the app to find clothing they want, before having them delivered to the Amazon Style store to try on in person. The store will support &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/1/21496673/amazon-one-palm-reading-vein-recognition-payments-identity-verification"&gt;Amazon One&lt;/a&gt;, a technology that lets you pay for items by using the palm of your hand for identity verification. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A touchscreen in Amazon Style’s fitting room." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/c760_Cb5E8zQA5r_2NjZ4uKIbgM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23181734/image.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Amazon&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fitting rooms are equipped with touchscreens that can be used to request more clothes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="rvl2Wc"&gt;Conspicuously absent is any mention of Amazon’s “Just Walk Out” technology, which it’s previously used in its own &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/17/17869294/amazon-go-store-chicago-cashier-less"&gt;Amazon Go&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/15/22534570/amazon-fresh-full-size-grocery-store-just-walk-out-cashierless-technology-bellevue-washington"&gt;Amazon Fresh&lt;/a&gt; stores, as well as an increasing number of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/16/22784994/amazon-cashierless-technology-uk-customers-sainsburys"&gt;external stores&lt;/a&gt;, to allow customers to pick up items and walk out without needing to pay for them at a register.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sXseSW"&gt;Amazon says its new store is far more space-efficient, with Amazon Style able to offer “more than double the number of styles” as a traditional store of a similar size. But if it works, it also sounds like it could remove some of the pain points of in-store shopping, like having to awkwardly walk about a store half-clothed in search of a different size. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9FtD5k"&gt;Although it appears to rely heavily on automation, Amazon says its new Style store will still have traditional employees, who will be focused on customer service, delivering items to fitting rooms, helping customers at checkout, managing back-of-house, and processing payments.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I2wlmC"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22892880/amazon-style-fashion-apperal-retail-los-angeles-fitting-room"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22892880/amazon-style-fashion-apperal-retail-los-angeles-fitting-room</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-20T06:24:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-20T06:24:37-05:00</updated>
    <title>Windows 11 is getting a new Task Manager design</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h-60_7eMujDpoL-DdFysOtrhvvY=/75x0:1455x920/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70411262/unknown.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MaK7zh"&gt;Microsoft is getting ready to overhaul the Task Manager in Windows 11. Like the rest of the operating system, the Task Manager is getting a new design that matches Microsoft’s new Fluent Design language. It seems Microsoft hid the new design in the bowels of recent Windows 11 builds, but engineering student &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gus33000"&gt;Gustave Monce&lt;/a&gt;, who previously got &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22558999/microsoft-windows-11-windows-phone-port-developer-engineer"&gt;Windows 11 running on a phone&lt;/a&gt;, uncovered the work-in-progress and shared it on Discord this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s01iqn"&gt;It’s possible to enable the new Task Manager inside the latest preview builds of Windows 11, but Microsoft hasn’t officially announced the redesign. “This is a hidden feature in the new build,” says Monce. “Everything is broken though.” It’s clearly early days for this new design, but it already includes a dark mode and interface that closely matches the big design changes in Windows 11 — rounded corners, pastel shades, and a focus on simplification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0yU42B"&gt;The tabs in the existing Task Manager have been replaced with a sidebar that allows you to switch between the various sections of the app. Task Manager is a big legacy part of Windows that originally debuted with Windows NT 4.0. It hasn’t had any significant changes for nearly 10 years after it was last overhauled in Windows 8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mKHBhi"&gt;Microsoft is gradually redesigning most of the legacy parts of Windows. A new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/16/22785617/microsoft-windows-11-media-player-app-audio-video-features"&gt;Media Player app is currently in testing&lt;/a&gt;, and Windows 11 is also getting a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822651/microsoft-windows-11-notepad-redesign-find-replace-insider"&gt;redesigned Notepad app with dark mode support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22892879/microsoft-windows-11-new-task-manager-design"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22892879/microsoft-windows-11-new-task-manager-design</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
