<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-01-08T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-08T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Roku says Roku TV was best-selling smart TV OS in North America for 2020</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VaQVMYdnpaEgYItJccbhqzVEbxM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68637554/cwelch_181128_3103_0677_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GAmeFF"&gt;Roku says its Roku TV line was the top-selling smart TV OS in the US and Canada throughout all of 2020, using NPD data to illustrate the company’s powerful standing. “Roku TV held 38 percent of market share in the US and 31 percent in Canada, based on available data from January 5th through December 26th, 2020, maintaining the lead spot in both regions,” the company said in a press release today. That would signify that Samsung’s Tizen has fallen to second place. (Samsung is still the most popular individual TV maker, however, since Roku TV is divided among brands like TCL, Hisense, and others.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lk3CLx"&gt;Roku attributes the success of Roku TV to its simple user interface, vast app catalog, and a wide range of TV sizes at appealing prices. TCL has really carved out a reputation as the best choice for picture quality among all the companies making Roku TVs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VYgA8Z"&gt;In line with the strong momentum, Roku is also using CES 2021 to announce that partners for its “Roku TV Ready” initiative will soon be able to release wireless soundbars for Roku TV sets. Roku has a new reference design for the wireless soundbar, which connects to Roku TVs over Wi-Fi. Customers won’t have to worry about any lip sync problems, as latency is communicated between hardware devices to ensure proper A/V synchronization. Roku essentially picks the brains and processing for the reference design but leaves other choices — like enclosure design and the drivers / speakers used — to manufacturers. You’ll be able to quickly set up and adjust settings on these wireless soundbars right from the Roku TV’s settings menu. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Uoehv6"&gt;Separate from this, Element is joining the Roku TV Ready program and plans to release a 2.0 soundbar and 2.1 soundbar / subwoofer combo later in 2021. Roku says it plans to expand the program to other countries throughout the year and will announce partners as that effort progresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rEFPCj"&gt;Roku’s continued success and influence have led to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21324139/peacock-roku-amazon-fire-tv-hbo-max-streaming-warnermedia-nbcuniversal-disney-apple"&gt;standoffs with streaming service providers&lt;/a&gt; in recent months; it took right up until the release of &lt;em&gt;Wonder Woman 1984&lt;/em&gt; for the company to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/21272058/hbo-max-roku-watch-wonder-woman-1984-movies-amazon-fire-stream-comcast-warnermedia"&gt;work out a deal with WarnerMedia&lt;/a&gt; to get HBO Max on its platform. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22220330/roku-tv-number-one-smart-os-us-canada-2020"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22220330/roku-tv-number-one-smart-os-us-canada-2020</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-08T08:12:03-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T08:12:03-05:00</updated>
    <title>The JLab JBuds Frames are open-ear headphones you clip to your glasses</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GqzF79mcQiHk7RXfUs8Jy52vA4g=/0x500:3000x2500/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68637359/JLab_JBuds_Frames_glasses_greyed_out.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KpPQna"&gt;JLab is introducing a new Bluetooth audio gadget designed to be clipped onto your existing glasses or sunglasses. The JBuds Frames are two modules with downward-firing speakers you position right outside your ears. They are part of a resurgent trend of open-ear audio that has usually been the domain of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/10/21429753/bose-frames-tenor-soprano-tempo-audio-sunglasses-announced-price"&gt;Bluetooth-enabled sunglasses&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/23/20706156/aftershokz-aeropex-bone-conduction-headphones-wireless-review"&gt;bone-conducting bands&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="90kFsW"&gt;They’re retailing for just $50, which fits in with another trend: JLab’s history of offering &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/2/25/17046000/jlab-epic-sport-earbuds-workout-headphones-review"&gt;surprisingly inexpensive headphones&lt;/a&gt;. Sometimes, those headphones &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/8/9/12404118/bluetooth-wireless-headphones-earbuds-running-jbl-beats-jaybird"&gt;outperform their price point&lt;/a&gt; and so the company is hoping it can pull that trick off again by undercutting Bose, Amazon, Aftershokz, and others. However, so far, there’s a fairly low ceiling on audio quality for open-ear headphones — so don’t expect audiophile quality regardless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y9Uy0d"&gt;The JBuds Frames are two largish modules which clip to the temples of the glasses you already own. Unlike integrated solutions, there’s no attempt whatsoever to hide the fact that you’ve got headphones in your eyeglasses. They ship with multiple sizes of clips so they can fit to more sizes of glasses.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SdZXKfECZrh-okO8_n8vU_4DSMw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22220878/JLab_JBuds_Frames_on_sunglasses_with_blue_lenses.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="s8YrPE"&gt;For audio, each unit has a 16mm driver that JLab says won’t be “heard by those close by.” That’s the basic premise of open-ear audio: although the audio is playing just outside your ears, it is directed in such a way that only you will hear it. You might not get the greatest fidelity, but your ears won’t be covered so you can pay attention to the world around you if you are out exercising. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9UWrU8"&gt;The JBuds Frames have an IPX4 water resistance rating, so they should be good for the rain or sweat. They have buttons to control volume, accept or reject calls, and switch EQ settings. JLab says they can be used as a pair or independently, if you just want to attach and use one. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OtxXtn2muWH83uX3W4AzuD6sf6s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22220877/JLab_Frames_included_accessories___USB_to_magnetic_pin_connection_cable.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="thPw6Q"&gt;Battery life is rated at over eight hours of audio playback — and it ought to be good, given the size of these modules. Rather than coming with a charging case, they ship with a special cable that splits into two magnetic charging points. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="amXCb2"&gt;I recently reviewed the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22197463/amazon-echo-frames-review-alexa"&gt;Amazon Echo Frames&lt;/a&gt; and found having open-ear access to audio throughout the day to be really convenient. In theory, the JLab Frames would offer that same convenience without asking me to change my eyeglasses. There’s competition, however, in the form of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22215281/base-sport-open-earbuds-ambient-noise-workout"&gt;recently announced (and much more expensive) Bose Sport Open Earbuds&lt;/a&gt;, which rest on your ears instead of your glasses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rV2CXU"&gt;Both are going to be available in the early spring of 2021, so we’ll have a chance to test both of them out soon.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22219425/jlab-audio-jbuds-frames-open-ear-headphones-price-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22219425/jlab-audio-jbuds-frames-open-ear-headphones-price-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-08T08:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>I hope to someday sit in Kohler’s new voice-activated smart bath</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MYXC2L776lbS_A15s-S024WqUNA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68637258/Kohler_aad32136_rgb_SM.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Kohler&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XbqLyy"&gt;Kohler has revealed a new smart bath that lets you use an app, or your voice, to fill up the water. That by itself seems pretty handy to me, but depending on which model you buy, you can elevate your bathing experience by changing the color of lights around the tub or even &lt;em&gt;adding some fog&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Noatfb"&gt;You’ll also be able to establish preset routines to turn on features in a certain order so you can set your bath exactly the way you want it. For example, you can have the tub fill itself up to a specified level and a certain temperature, and once that’s done, add some fog or turn on some aromatherapy, all with a voice command to Amazon’s Alexa or Google Assistant. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UrvHF6"&gt;Take look at the Stillness Bath for yourself in this footage provided by Kohler. I gotta say, it seems like a really relaxing tub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vqbiGz"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Kohler Broll|100112" data-volume-uuid="664865c9f" data-volume-id="100112" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-73" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ilmNEb"&gt;If you want this luxurious bath experience in your own home, though, it won’t come cheap. Just to control the temperature and depth of the water, you’re looking at a model with an estimated price of $8,698. If you want the “Experience Tower” that lets you activate fog and aromatherapy, that’ll cost around $10,998. Both of those models will be available in July. The version that also has floor grates for overflow and the lights has an estimated price of $15,998, and it will be available in October. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9v0kR4"&gt;While the Stillness Bath seems neat, I have to say that it isn’t quite as awe-inspiring as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/6/18170575/kohler-konnect-bathroom-smart-gadgets-numi-intelligent-toilet-ces-2019"&gt;Kohler’s Numi 2.0 Intelligent Toilet&lt;/a&gt;, which has surround sound speakers, ambient lighting, and Alexa voice controls. It earned &lt;em&gt;The Verge’s&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/11/18177016/verge-ces-2019-awards-best-tv-laptop-gaming-device"&gt;“Most CES” award&lt;/a&gt; for CES 2019. However, it appears you still can’t buy the toilet just yet — though you can sign up to be notified when it’s available on &lt;a href="https://www.smarthome.kohler.com/smart-intelligent-toilets-numi2"&gt;Kohler’s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22218786/kohler-smart-stillness-bath-amazon-alexa-google-assistant"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22218786/kohler-smart-stillness-bath-amazon-alexa-google-assistant</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-08T07:14:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T07:14:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla’s Model Y now available in cheaper Standard Range option</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jETDuW0U4O6O9hdmrYdKWZdYM4w=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68637201/msedge_LxyYS8lexd.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new Standard Range model sits alongside the existing Long Range and Performance versions.&lt;/em&gt; | Screenshot:  Tesla.com&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CATuRF"&gt;Tesla is now taking orders for a cheaper &lt;a href="https://www.tesla.com/modely/design#battery"&gt;Standard Range version of the Model Y&lt;/a&gt;. The new variant, whose availability was reported &lt;a href="https://electrek.co/2021/01/07/tesla-model-y-standard-range-rwd-third-row-option/"&gt;by &lt;em&gt;Electrek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, has a cheaper starting price of $41,990 compared to $49,990 for the Long Range model. The discount comes with a lower EPA estimated range of 244 miles rather than 326 miles, and rear-wheel rather than all-wheel drive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uu8DPv"&gt;Alongside the new cheaper Model Y version, Tesla is also selling a new 7-seat option for a $3,000 premium. The version has a third seating row, which can be folded flat along with the second row for cargo storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="yfbPWP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Standard Range option was originally announced with a 230-mile range&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aq2aok"&gt;Tesla originally announced the Standard Range version of the Model Y back at the car’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/14/18264446/tesla-model-y-suv-compact-announcement-price-release-date-features-elon-musk#g0UiFs:~:text=The%20cheaper%2C%20standard%20range%20version%20with,said.%20It%20will%20sell%20for%20%2439%2C000."&gt;announcement in March 2019&lt;/a&gt;. At the time, Tesla CEO Elon Musk &lt;a href="https://electrek.co/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2021/01/tesla-march-event-28-1.jpg?resize=1536,857"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; the company was targeting a release date of Spring 2021 for the entry-level Model Y with a 230-mile range and $39,000 price tag. However, in July last year, Musk said Tesla shelved its plans for the Standard Range model because its “&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1282496094908243968"&gt;range would be unacceptably low&lt;/a&gt;” at under 250 miles. This new $41,990 Standard Range Model Y appears to be a compromise on the original plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sfn25S"&gt;If you want to order the new variant, Tesla notes that estimated delivery times currently range from two to five weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22220265/tesla-model-y-standard-range-cheapest-version-reduced-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22220265/tesla-model-y-standard-range-cheapest-version-reduced-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-08T05:32:45-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T05:32:45-05:00</updated>
    <title>No headline can possibly do this photo justice</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Z4k1iNz2xeYKMM5W0MIZjA16oGQ=/101x76:845x572/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68636964/20210108_pokemon_genger_05.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Overwhelmed by life? Shove your head in a Gengar.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://p-bandai.jp/item/item-1000153723/" target="_blank"&gt;P-Bandai.jp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ukacdp"&gt;Pokémon has an illustrious history of beautifully bizarre merch including a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/9/21556433/pokemon-pod-metapod-costume-pokeshopper"&gt;human-sized Metapod sleeping bag&lt;/a&gt; or a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22152607/ditto-pokemon-chair-price"&gt;Ditto chair&lt;/a&gt;, but this &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fp-bandai.jp%2Fitem%2Fitem-1000153723%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Ftldr%2F2021%2F1%2F8%2F22220219%2Fgengar-tongue-cushion-plushie-sleeping-bag-cocoon#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;giant Gengar plushie&lt;/a&gt; might be the best yet. It’s cute, sure, but it’s also incredibly practical. Just roll out its roughly 170cm-long tongue and you’ve got yourself a compact futon for sleeping on. There’s even a cozy little space in its open mouth for your head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DoXrYH"&gt;But this Gengar isn’t just a novelty mattress replacement. No, it’s capable of &lt;em&gt;so much more&lt;/em&gt;. Tired of reality? Shove your head in the Gengar’s mouth. Need an impromptu blanket? Use the Gengar’s tongue. When you’ve got a giant Gengar with a long-ass tongue, the sky’s the limit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RPo0uGrUAmfc-270gPGn-4bWNMQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22221714/20210108_pokemon_genger_09.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fp-bandai.jp%2Fitem%2Fitem-1000153723%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Ftldr%2F2021%2F1%2F8%2F22220219%2Fgengar-tongue-cushion-plushie-sleeping-bag-cocoon#donotlink" target="_blank" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener"&gt;P-Bandai.jp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be not afraid.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TqRmjMSS22v4xYs6S0YcS06nUDc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22221718/20210108_pokemon_genger_05__1_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fp-bandai.jp%2Fitem%2Fitem-1000153723%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Ftldr%2F2021%2F1%2F8%2F22220219%2Fgengar-tongue-cushion-plushie-sleeping-bag-cocoon#donotlink" target="_blank" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener"&gt;P-Bandai.jp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gengar is here to help with nap time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d4JEMIYVsx1ad-w8DNFo8aJ-gTc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22221719/20210108_pokemon_genger_06__1_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fp-bandai.jp%2Fitem%2Fitem-1000153723%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Ftldr%2F2021%2F1%2F8%2F22220219%2Fgengar-tongue-cushion-plushie-sleeping-bag-cocoon#donotlink" target="_blank" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener"&gt;P-Bandai.jp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The title of the product listing literally translates to “Gengar who absolutely wants to be licked.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Xfbnnc"&gt;Unfortunately, despite its high price of 25,950 yen (around $250) and a ship date that’s still months away in June 2021, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Pokeshopper/status/1347382246643298305"&gt;Pokéshopper.com reports&lt;/a&gt; that pre-orders for the Gengar cushion sold out in less than two hours. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p8D8uM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PyO3If"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/1/8/22220219/gengar-tongue-cushion-plushie-sleeping-bag-cocoon"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/1/8/22220219/gengar-tongue-cushion-plushie-sleeping-bag-cocoon</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-08T05:25:08-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T05:25:08-05:00</updated>
    <title>Sony’s 360-degree audio is coming to streaming video</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ydRI0JLtuR_9qotUmzWvAZHlS1I=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68636934/dseifert_191031_3770_0006.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Amazon’s Echo Studio speaker, which supports Sony’s 360 Reality Audio format. | Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xzjvZx"&gt;Sony has &lt;a href="https://www.sony.net/SonyInfo/News/Press/202101/21-001E/"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; an expansion of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/15/20915250/sony-360-reality-audio-release-date-amazon-partners"&gt;its 360 Reality Audio platform&lt;/a&gt;, bringing the 360-degree music format to more devices and media as well as offering new creation tools. 360 Reality Audio uses object-based spatial audio technology to place instruments or vocals around the listener’s head in a virtual sound field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qf4Dqh"&gt;Now, Sony is expanding the audio tech into video. The company says it’s working with record labels and service providers to start streaming video content with 360 Reality Audio later this year, and the first example will be a &lt;a href="https://square.sony.com/ces2021/360RA"&gt;live performance&lt;/a&gt; from Sony-signed artist Zara Larsson next week. You’ll be able to watch through Sony’s Artist Connection mobile app at 5pm ET on January 11th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="25lUNV"&gt;Sony is releasing two new 360 Reality Audio-compatible speakers this spring, the SRS-RA5000 and SRS-RA3000, although there isn’t much detail on either beyond support for Amazon’s Alexa and the Google Assistant. Sony has also developed a new 3D audio plugin called the 360 Reality Audio Creative Suite, which is compatible with DAWs like Pro Tools and will be released at the end of this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r8HTUG"&gt;There are currently around 4,000 songs available in 360 Reality Audio across services like Tidal and Deezer, Sony says. The format works with most regular headphones or compatible speakers like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/6/20950100/amazon-echo-studio-smart-speaker-alexa-3d-audio-test-review-price-specs-features"&gt;Amazon’s Echo Studio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22220223/sony-360-degree-audio-video-speakers-software"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22220223/sony-360-degree-audio-video-speakers-software</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-07T20:50:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T20:50:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s next Nest Hub could use radar to track your sleep, and I have questions  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BFcEgN7UupmwA5VvET7OnRIT0jY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68635781/dseifert_181018_3039_1267.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="C3dtmd"&gt;Earlier this week, we reported that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/4/22213539/google-nest-hub-update-fcc-filing-soli-motion-sense-gestures"&gt;Google could be working on an updated Nest Hub&lt;/a&gt; that had Soli technology, and &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/01/07/nest-hub-soli-sleep/"&gt;a report from &lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; now suggests that it could be for something unexpected: sleep tracking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R8AUsp"&gt;If you aren’t familiar, Soli is Google’s radar technology used to detect gestures and human presence. It was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/15/20908083/google-pixel-4-project-soli-radar-motion-sense-explainer"&gt;first introduced in the Pixel 4&lt;/a&gt; (which was discontinued &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/6/21356745/google-pixel-4-xl-discontinued-out-of-stock"&gt;in August&lt;/a&gt;), and while it isn’t in any of Google’s current Pixel devices, it’s now showing up in smart home devices, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21725036/google-nest-thermostat-2020-review"&gt;like the Nest Thermostat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1jyILr"&gt;So there is precedent for Google including the tech in its smart home devices. And the Nest Hub already looks a bit like an alarm clock, and because it doesn’t have a camera built-in, it may be more accepted into the bedroom for sleep tracking. But I still have a couple of questions about how it might work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="BzpDML"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There are a lot of ways having motion controls in an alarm clock makes sense.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CFhuUt"&gt;As almost every sleep aid commercial points out, we all sleep differently. So far, Soli has been pretty short range, so what happens if you roll over to the other side of the bed? Is it going to lose track of you? What if you have a pet who likes to come and lay by (or on) your head? Will it start tracking their movement instead?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HrisBH"&gt;There’s also the problem of nightstands. Those who do own nightstands may have them in totally different places in relation to where they sleep, and some may not have them at all. So far, Soli has only been used directionally, so it’s unclear how Google would handle having to deal with detecting movement and presence at a variety of angles and distances. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PWiQh3"&gt;Perhaps Google will surprise us and have this all figured out when they announce the product, or maybe sleep tracking will only work under certain circumstances. Despite my questions, though, I think there are a lot of other ways in which having motion controls in an alarm clock makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WYAkfa"&gt;I’m not necessarily able to coherently speak when I first wake up, so being able to, as my coworker suggested, wildly wave my hand at the Nest Hub to turn off an alarm would be a neat trick. People who wake up to music could also wave to skip a song if the one that comes on isn’t how they want to start their day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HqPxjk"&gt;If all this sounds intriguing to you, the &lt;em&gt;9to5Google &lt;/em&gt;report says that the Soli-enabled Nest Hub should come at some point this year. The FCC filings that hit this week could also indicate that the product may be coming soon. While they don’t always guarantee that a product will be released, we do sometimes see them before official product announcements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="4bLsVS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Google may be updating the Nest Hub by adding Soli gestures","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/4/22213539/google-nest-hub-update-fcc-filing-soli-motion-sense-gestures"},{"title":"Google’s Project Soli: the tech behind Pixel 4’s Motion Sense radar","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/15/20908083/google-pixel-4-project-soli-radar-motion-sense-explainer"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22219686/google-nest-hub-radar-track-sleep-soli"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22219686/google-nest-hub-radar-track-sleep-soli</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-07T20:42:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T20:42:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>FCC chairman Ajit Pai gave up on his legally dicey attempt to ‘clarify’ internet law</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="FCC Chair Ajit Pai Testifies Before Senate On Agency’s Oversight" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/htTsnxvwBaOv77TyT1bDL8aANlI=/0x0:6720x4480/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68635745/1251845368.jpg.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Alex Wong/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rkAMIQ"&gt;On October 15th, FCC chairman Ajit Pai &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/15/21518097/fcc-social-media-censorship-moderation-ajit-pai-section-230-nypost-biden"&gt;promised that the FCC would “move forward with a rulemaking”&lt;/a&gt; to clarify the “meaning” of Section 230, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21273768/section-230-explained-internet-speech-law-definition-guide-free-moderation"&gt;the all-important internet law&lt;/a&gt; that protects free speech online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FUkYGV"&gt;Apparently, Pai never got around to that — and less than three months later, he no longer plans to, either, explaining he’s short on time. “[T]here’s simply not sufficient time to complete the administrative steps necessary in order to resolve the rule-making. Given that reality, I do not believe it’s appropriate to move forward,” &lt;a href="https://www.protocol.com/ajit-pai-distancing-trump"&gt;he tells &lt;em&gt;Protocol&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QYZPQz"&gt;The reason he’s short on time is pretty simple: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/30/21726572/ajit-pai-fcc-step-down-date-trump-telecom-net-neutrality"&gt;he’s stepping down on January 20th&lt;/a&gt;, when Joe Biden becomes President of the United States. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="79gM2W"&gt;But he might also be giving up because the idea that the FCC had the power to do such a thing was laughable. &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/21519337/section-230-trump-fcc-twitter-facebook-social-media-ajit-pai"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;Recode&lt;/em&gt; explains in depth&lt;/a&gt;, the FCC’s justification was effectively that it has the power to make whatever rules it needs to make — which flies in the face of the logic Pai’s own FCC used to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/14/16776154/fcc-net-neutrality-vote-results-rules-repealed"&gt;kill net neutrality&lt;/a&gt;. But that didn’t stop Pai from claiming the FCC did have the authority to do it, a political tactic that’s become so common in the Trump administration that my colleague Russell Brandom &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/russellbrandom/status/1346858060929785856"&gt;coined a phrase for it&lt;/a&gt;: “stunt legalism.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ez2Btg"&gt;Never mind that Section 230 isn’t actually that difficult to understand — though that admittedly &lt;a href="https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20210104/01172345990/60-minutes-episode-is-pure-misleading-moral-panic-about-section-230-blames-unrelated-issues-it.shtml"&gt;didn’t keep &lt;em&gt;60 Minutes&lt;/em&gt; from falling on its face&lt;/a&gt; earlier this week. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21273768/section-230-explained-internet-speech-law-definition-guide-free-moderation"&gt;Here’s our explainer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="HcgbIW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Everything you need to know about Section 230","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21273768/section-230-explained-internet-speech-law-definition-guide-free-moderation"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="ixRVol"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22219677/fcc-ajit-pai-section-230-its-over"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22219677/fcc-ajit-pai-section-230-its-over</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-07T19:50:42-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T19:50:42-05:00</updated>
    <title>TikTok will remove videos of Trump inciting supporters to storm the Capitol</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eR0u1wlxMI_S0sfFMKd1ZLf3dgk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68635555/acastro_190723_1777_tiktok_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qRk7zR"&gt;TikTok will remove videos of President Trump’s speech inciting supporters &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/6/22217411/capitol-building-lockdown-protesters-trump-supporters"&gt;to mob the US Capitol&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday, saying they violate the company’s misinformation policy. TikTok will still let people post “counter speech” videos that dispute incorrect claims, however, and will let videos remain on the platform if they condemn violence or if they’re posted by news organizations. &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt; was &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/07/tiktok-bans-videos-of-trump-inciting-mob-blocks-stormthecapital-and-other-hashtags/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29"&gt;the first to report the news&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SgW8gL"&gt;“Hateful behavior and violence have no place on TikTok,” the company said in a statement. “Content or accounts that seek to incite, glorify, or promote violence violate our Community Guidelines and will be removed.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IfnPDT"&gt;TikTok is also blocking certain hashtags related to the riots, such as #stormthecapitol and #patriotparty, like it did with other hashtags that represented election-related conspiracy theories &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/5/21551717/facebook-tiktok-block-election-conspiracy-theory-hashtags-twitter-monitoring"&gt;in November&lt;/a&gt;. If you try to search for one of these blocked hashtags, you’ll see a page that says the hashtag “may be associated with behavior or content that violates our guidelines.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9Eh4wBvXBkcQF5qrluizrIZx16c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22221052/IMG_0144.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="709u3a"&gt;TikTok joins other social media platforms in restricting some content about Wednesday’s riots. Facebook committed to removing content supporting the storming of the Capitol or encouraged Wednesday’s events, among other measures in a &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/01/responding-to-the-violence-in-washington-dc/"&gt;blog that it posted Wednesday evening&lt;/a&gt;. The company went a step further by banning Trump’s account “indefinitely” on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22218725/facebook-trump-ban-extended-capitol-riot-insurrection-block"&gt;Thursday morning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6noS7X"&gt;Twitter said it was &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSafety/status/1346926979505737729"&gt;taking action&lt;/a&gt; against tweets that violated its rules and that it was “significantly restricting engagement with Tweets labeled under our Civic Integrity Policy due to the risk of violence.” The company placed a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/6/22217686/trump-twitter-account-locked-capitol-hill-riot-tweets-policy-violations"&gt;temporary lock&lt;/a&gt; on Trump’s account on Wednesday evening and has threatened a permanent suspension if he violates its rules again. Trump returned to Twitter &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22218794/trump-twitter-ban-lifted-unbanned-realdonaldtrump"&gt;Thursday evening&lt;/a&gt;, promising a smooth transition of power to the Biden administration. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22219644/tiktok-videos-trump-inciting-supporters-us-capitol"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22219644/tiktok-videos-trump-inciting-supporters-us-capitol</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-07T19:27:19-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T19:27:19-05:00</updated>
    <title>Trump returns to Twitter and promises a smooth transition of power</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="President Trump Holds Campaign Rally For GOP Senate Candidates Ahead Of Runoff Election" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bn1-0MmJnhaEsmo-vqdcVGpaOew=/0x0:8192x5461/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68635509/1294537766.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Alex Wong/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YRutCc"&gt;Twitter has lifted its ban on President Donald Trump, and his latest tweet is very different than the ones we’ve seen for many months. Though he does not say he lost, his latest video feels like a concession speech. “Now that Congress has certified the results, a new administration will be inaugurated on January 20th,” he says. “My focus now turns to ensuring a smooth, orderly and seamless transition of power.” Trump had issued a similar statement about “an orderly transition” this morning &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DanScavino/status/1347103015493361664?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1347103015493361664%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cnbc.com%2F2021%2F01%2F07%2Ftrump-says-there-will-be-an-orderly-transition-of-power.html"&gt;through a surrogate account&lt;/a&gt; — that of White House social media director Dan Scavino.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MZ5NaA"&gt;The president’s own account was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/6/22217686/trump-twitter-account-locked-capitol-hill-riot-tweets-policy-violations"&gt;locked on Wednesday&lt;/a&gt; after a mob of his supporters broke into the US Capitol, and Twitter said it would stay that way until he deleted several tweets and then waited 12 hours. A Twitter spokesperson confirmed Thursday morning that the tweets in question had been removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="pgnNgK"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="und" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://t.co/csX07ZVWGe"&gt;pic.twitter.com/csX07ZVWGe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1347334804052844550?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 8, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xI8MDi"&gt;Trump returns to Twitter in a more tenuous position than ever before. The company said he’s now at risk of a permanent ban if he continues to violate Twitter rules around misinformation and incitement of violence. Once Trump leaves the White House on January 20th, he’ll also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/7/21552606/trump-twitter-world-leader-public-interest-exception-ends-january-loss"&gt;lose special “public interest” protections&lt;/a&gt; that applied to his account while he was in office, which could make it easier for the company to enforce its rules over Trump tweets that cross the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KMVCua"&gt;Twitter banned Trump on Wednesday over a series of tweets spreading lies about the election outcome and a video the company said posed a “risk of violence.” In that video, Trump reiterated his false claims that the election was stolen, praised the mob that broke into the US Capitol, and told them it was time to “go home.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cG88Ns"&gt;Facebook and YouTube removed the same video from Trump. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22218725/facebook-trump-ban-extended-capitol-riot-insurrection-block"&gt;Facebook later “indefinitely” banned Trump&lt;/a&gt; due to his use of the platform to “incite violent insurrection against a democratically elected government,” saying the risks are “are simply too great” of allowing him to remain. Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg said the ban would remain in place at least through Inauguration Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IbUNaU"&gt;Trump’s new video still includes misinformation, specifically a lie that he “immediately” deployed the National Guard to the Capitol. However, Twitter says that it won’t be placing a label on the tweet due to that, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RMac18/status/1347339743940419584"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/em&gt;’ Ryan Mac&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4XeTwZ"&gt;Five people died during the Capitol riot, according to reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="4cf3n6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Online researchers scramble to identify Capitol raid participants","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22219416/capitol-raid-identify-faces-online-footage-charges-law-enforcement-doxxing"},{"title":"In photos: the pro-Trump mob’s invasion of Congress","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/6/22217601/congress-capitol-building-takeover-coup-photos-pro-trump-mob"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="bjvGl8"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22218794/trump-twitter-ban-lifted-unbanned-realdonaldtrump"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22218794/trump-twitter-ban-lifted-unbanned-realdonaldtrump</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
