<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-08-26T17:43:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-26T17:43:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-26T17:43:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Hacker claims responsibility for T-Mobile attack, bashes the carrier’s security</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pXBsKWjydj1cjknGWtEqYLTyrtc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69780942/acastro_191108_1777_t-mobile_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RiK1Qi"&gt;A person claiming to be behind the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/15/22626270/t-mobile-investigating-report-customer-data-breach"&gt;T-Mobile data breach&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630446/t-mobile-47-million-data-breach-ssn-pin-pii"&gt;exposed almost 50 million people’s info&lt;/a&gt; has come forward to reveal his identity and to criticize T-Mobile’s security, &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/t-mobile-hacker-who-stole-data-on-50-million-customers-their-security-is-awful-11629985105"&gt;according to a report by &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. John Binns told the &lt;em&gt;WSJ &lt;/em&gt;that he was behind the attack and provided evidence that he could access accounts associated with it, and he went into detail about how he was able to pull it off and why he did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qiPTSg"&gt;According to Binns, he was able to get customer (and former customer) data from T-Mobile by scanning for unprotected routers. He found one, he told the&lt;em&gt; Journal&lt;/em&gt;, which allowed him to access a Washington state data center that stored credentials for over 100 servers. He called the carrier’s security “awful” and said that realizing how much data he had access to made him panic. According to the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt;, it’s unclear whether Binns was working alone, though he implied that he collaborated with others for at least part of the hack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="unWKVf"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Binns called T-Mobile’s security “awful”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LFRnna"&gt;The information the hacker gained access to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630446/t-mobile-47-million-data-breach-ssn-pin-pii"&gt;includes sensitive personal data&lt;/a&gt;, like names, birthdates, and Social Security numbers, as well as important cellular data like identification numbers for cellphones and SIM cards. T-Mobile has &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fnews%2Fnetwork%2Fadditional-information-regarding-2021-cyberattack-investigation&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F8%2F26%2F22643277%2Ft-mobile-hacker-data-leak-claims-responsibility-criticizes-security" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;said in a statement&lt;/a&gt; that it’s “confident” that it’s “closed off the access and egress points the bad actor used in the attack.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gXOl4y"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/t-mobile-hacker-who-stole-data-on-50-million-customers-their-security-is-awful-11629985105?page=1"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt;’s report&lt;/a&gt; goes in depth into Binns’ history as a hacker. He claims that he got his start making cheats for popular video games and that he discovered the flaw that ended up being used in a &lt;a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2019/09/satori-iot-botnet-operator-pleads-guilty/"&gt;botnet that attacked IoT devices&lt;/a&gt; (though he denies actually working on the code).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="vX0k93"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Binns describes a troubled relationship with US intelligence services&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gEbWj5"&gt;According to Binns, his relationship with US intelligence services is troubled, to say the least. A lawsuit that appears to have been filed by Binns in 2020 demands that the CIA, FBI, DOJ, and other agencies tell him what information they have on him. The lawsuit also accuses the government of, among other things, having an informant try to convince Binns to buy Stinger missiles on an FBI-owned website, attacking Binns with psychic and energy weapons, and even with being involved in his alleged kidnapping and torture. An FBI response to his lawsuit denied he was being investigated by the bureau for the botnet or having information related to the alleged surveillance, and abduction, and torture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c4ArHL"&gt;Binns told the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt; that one of his goals behind the attack was to “generate noise,” saying that he hopes someone in the FBI will leak information related to his alleged kidnapping. It’s not likely that Binns’ situation will be improved now that he’s shone a spotlight on himself as the person who hacked one of the US’s major carriers. However, if his reports about how he gained access to a vast trove of T-Mobile data are true, it paints a concerning picture of the carrier’s security practices.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22643277/t-mobile-hacker-data-leak-claims-responsibility-criticizes-security"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22643277/t-mobile-hacker-data-leak-claims-responsibility-criticizes-security</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-26T16:26:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-26T16:26:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>Palantir invested $25 million in Faraday Future</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0MNnGRzGYvKD6Jp-Ygh_h6DWNEU=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69780537/19060IOVS_001_Header_final.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wOlpxH"&gt;Data-mining firm Palantir invested $25 million in Faraday Future shortly before the electric vehicle startup &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22587530/faraday-future-nasdaq-ffie-spac-ipo-investors-funding"&gt;became a publicly traded company in July&lt;/a&gt;, according to a previously unreported Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001805521/000121390021044112/ea146046-s1_faraday.htm"&gt;document&lt;/a&gt; filed late last week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vo9Zfd"&gt;In addition, Faraday Future signed a commercial contract to use Palantir’s software, according to one of Palantir’s &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001321655/000095012321010430/d175251d10q.htm"&gt;most recent SEC filings&lt;/a&gt;. Neither company disclosed how much Faraday Future is paying, though Palantir’s filing notes the contract will last between four and six years. Representatives for both companies did not immediately respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iuFGZg"&gt;Palantir says its software is meant to serve as a “central operating system” for companies that need to sift through lots of data. Its customers have included &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/12/21/14012534/palantir-peter-thiel-trump-immigrant-extreme-vetting"&gt;the US Customs and Border Protection agency&lt;/a&gt;, which used Palantir software to track immigrants during the Trump administration, as well as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/2/27/17054740/palantir-predictive-policing-tool-new-orleans-nopd"&gt;police departments&lt;/a&gt; around the country, which have used Palantir’s controversial predictive policing software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="XqTrzI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Palantir has recently invested in a number of startups — and sold them software, too&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tDVzkY"&gt;Palantir’s investment was part of the so-called Private Investment in Public Equity (PIPE) portion of the merger with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21502700/spac-explained-meaning-special-purpose-acquisition-company"&gt;special purpose acquisition company&lt;/a&gt; (SPAC) that made Faraday Future public. PIPEs are essentially a fundraising round that happens concurrently with many SPAC mergers. Faraday Future raised a total of around $795 million in its PIPE, which included other investors like Geely, China’s largest private automaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="diE1Xj"&gt;Palantir’s participation in the PIPE is just the latest in a rash of investments the company has made in startups that are (or were) in the process of merging with SPACs. In some of those instances, Palantir has followed up its investment with a deal to sell its software services to the company in question, as &lt;a href="https://www.newcomer.co/p/is-palantir-buying-revenue"&gt;was first reported in July by journalist Eric Newcomer&lt;/a&gt;. (One robotics startup, Newcomer reports, is paying Palantir $42 million to use its software, following a $21 million investment from the data-mining company.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P7V2tg"&gt;Faraday Future’s electric vehicles are going to create an incredible amount of data — at least, once they’re built. The company’s first vehicle, the FF 91 SUV, isn’t supposed to go into production until at least July 2022, and has been delayed for years as the company struggled. But when it exists, the electric SUV will be dotted with sensors and cameras meant to power an advanced driver assistance system in the near term and one day (perhaps) something closer to full autonomy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J4lZpL"&gt;The inside of the FF 91 will be even more of a data-generation machine. There are cameras &lt;a href="https://www.ff.com/us/futuresight/building-FF91-user-experience-II/"&gt;in every seat capable of performing facial recognition&lt;/a&gt;, which will be used to quickly pull up all sorts of preferences for drivers and passengers, like their personalized app and media libraries, favored seating positions and climate settings, and more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WLHrJ0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22643233/palantir-faraday-future-investment-data-mining-contract"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22643233/palantir-faraday-future-investment-data-mining-contract</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-26T16:16:59-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-26T16:16:59-04:00</updated>
    <title>Pokémon TV app now available on Switch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Z-58mhMysu_3Mw13uh70rJqOFw8=/0x0:1602x1068/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69780491/Screen_Shot_2021_08_26_at_3.55.03_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VH6MeB"&gt;The Switch still doesn’t have apps like Netflix or Twitch, but Nintendo decided to do us one better by &lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/pokemon-tv-switch/"&gt;announcing that Pokémon TV&lt;/a&gt; — the media app devoted to all things &lt;em&gt;Pokémon&lt;/em&gt; — is now available on the console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e0N7Zb"&gt;Pokémon TV is an app that &lt;em&gt;Pokémon&lt;/em&gt; enthusiasts can use to watch episodes of the long-running cartoon series, videos offering tips and tricks to players, and competitive &lt;em&gt;Pokémon&lt;/em&gt; broadcasts. The app launched in 2019 on mobile and smart TVs and is now available for free on Switch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6qlnh4"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eefmgiP7Kfo?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="s0eha7"&gt;In addition to being able to watch episodes from all seven series of &lt;em&gt;Pokémon&lt;/em&gt; shows free of charge, the Pokémon TV app is also launching a Junior category with programming geared toward younger players and fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dSBjAv"&gt;Twenty-five years after its debut in Japan, &lt;em&gt;Pokémon&lt;/em&gt; still enjoys an incredible amount of success. Last week, The Pokémon Company shared more information on its open-world, &lt;em&gt;Pokémon &lt;/em&gt;meets &lt;em&gt;Breath Of The Wild&lt;/em&gt; title,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630388/pokemon-legends-arceus-nintendo-switch-battle-system-trailer"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pokémon Legends: Arceus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as well as updates on the forthcoming remakes &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Brilliant Diamond &lt;/em&gt;and&lt;em&gt; Shining Pearl&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Pokémon&lt;/em&gt; got into the MOBA scene this year with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/23/22590249/pokemon-unite-nintendo-switch-hands-on-esports"&gt;wildly popular and surprisingly accessible &lt;em&gt;Pokémon&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Unite&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Pokemon&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Go&lt;/em&gt; is still &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/10/21060877/pokemon-go-record-revenue-2019-niantic-labs-ar-growth"&gt;crushing the mobile market&lt;/a&gt; five years after its launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F1jhwe"&gt;Trainers who want to be the very best, like no one ever was, can download the Pokémon TV app from the Nintendo eShop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lbrzfj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22643450/pokemon-tv-now-available-on-nintendo-switch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22643450/pokemon-tv-now-available-on-nintendo-switch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-26T16:09:07-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-26T16:09:07-04:00</updated>
    <title>Streamlabs launches monthly tipping service as an alternative to Twitch subscriptions</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hLCAsDnKd8z_BP57HuVrxVNko4c=/479x0:1079x400/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69780449/monthly_tipping_ui_a_1090x400.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Streamlabs&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HgPj2B"&gt;Streamlabs, the popular livestreaming software company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/26/20886060/logitech-streamlabs-obs-acquisition-twitch"&gt;owned by Logitech&lt;/a&gt;, is rolling out &lt;a href="https://streamlabs.com/content-hub/post/streamlabs-unveils-new-way-for-viewers-to-subscribe-to-live-streamers"&gt;a “monthly tipping service”&lt;/a&gt; as an alternative way for streamers to earn money from their fans. Streamlabs Creator Subscriptions will offer streamers flexibility on what kinds of subscriptions they offer, and they will integrate directly into Streamlabs’ OBS software suite for streaming to Twitch, YouTube, or Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s4oail"&gt;&lt;a href="https://streamlabs.com/content-hub/post/streamlabs-monthly-tipping-tutorial"&gt;Using Streamlabs Creator Subscription&lt;/a&gt; seems about as simple as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/17/21026148/streamlabs-charity-twitch-mixer-red-cross"&gt;the company’s earlier donation tools&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://streamlabs.com/content-hub/post/how-to-create-a-custom-tip-page-with-streamlabs"&gt;the tipping feature&lt;/a&gt; that already existed on the platform. Creators can enable or disable monthly tips in settings, along with setting specific subscription prices. There’s also the option to let a viewer tip whatever amount they want and send redeemable monthly tip notifications during a stream. Money from tips are deposited directly in creators’ PayPal accounts and Streamlabs says it doesn’t take a cut, though payments are subject to payment processing fees.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tTxPtmtMvnAOfDUa4Bs8VVfLWDA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22807535/0_6KK2z4_28jbsi19F.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Streamlabs&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Streamers can enable and disable monthly tips and pause payments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="PyNA9M"&gt;As yet another method for streamers to earn money off their work, Streamlabs’ feature could be a meaningful one, especially in comparison to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21445923/platform-fees-apps-games-business-marketplace-apple-google"&gt;the 50 percent cut of subscription revenue Twitch offers&lt;/a&gt; through its platform directly — a feature that’s limited to Twitch Partners. In comparison, “Streamlabs Creator Subscription is open for anyone with a Streamlabs tip page, regardless of size or how often they stream,” according to Ashray Urs, Streamlabs’ head of product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FOj95M"&gt;The relative openness of Streamlabs has come with its own problems, however. The company &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/streamlabs-streamelements-far-right-white-supremacy-monetize/"&gt;has struggled with moderating less savory uses of its payment features&lt;/a&gt;, particularly by white supremacist and far-right figures. As more of a payment manager than a payment processor, Streamlabs does have some built-in distance between it and the things its products are used for, leaving moderation to payment processors like PayPal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Memynt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AoIJ6n"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hEppf2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22643160/streamlabs-monthly-tipping-subscription-twitch-zero-fees"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22643160/streamlabs-monthly-tipping-subscription-twitch-zero-fees</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-26T15:34:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-26T15:34:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>You can stream Cruella for free on Disney Plus starting on August 27th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Emma Stone as Cruella de Vil. She has black and white hair and is dressed in a structured leather ballgown. " src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/C-hTb-MKAEWdTBpI0xpjH-JXREA=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69780257/cru_24747_r2_79c1746d.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Disney&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DcjG5L"&gt;&lt;a href="https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/c/482924/1135784/9358?subId1=VergeCruella082621&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.disneyplus.com%2Fmovies%2Fcruella%2F2GJTZuO8I01c" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Disney Plus&lt;/a&gt; subscribers will finally be able to watch the Queen of Mean on the service at no additional cost beginning Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nswpll"&gt;The live-action origin story of Disney’s notorious Cruella de Vil will hit the service tomorrow after debuting simultaneously in theaters and on Disney’s Premier Access platform on May 28th. Premier Access releases typically run viewers an additional $30 on top of their monthly or yearly subscription costs to be able to access the film early. But &lt;a href="https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/c/482924/1135784/9358?subId1=VergeCruella082621&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.disneyplus.com%2Fmovies%2Fcruella%2F2GJTZuO8I01c" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cruella&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; will officially join the Disney Plus library beginning this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9L7Gkl"&gt;Emma Stone stars alongside a pack of &lt;a href="https://www.thewrap.com/cruella-director-craig-gillespie-real-cgi-dogs/"&gt;sometimes real, sometimes CGI dogs&lt;/a&gt; in a spin on Disney’s animated &lt;em&gt;One Hundred and One Dalmatians&lt;/em&gt;. This one, though, is set in 1970s London and sees Stone take on fashion icon Baroness von Hellman. The plot deviates pretty significantly from the 1961 original, so don’t walk into Stone’s spin on de Vil expecting a mere live-action remake. Instead, Stone serves up an almost &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22400212/cruella-review-disney-plus-emma-stone-101-dalmatians"&gt;Joker-like spin&lt;/a&gt; on Disney’s infamous dog murderer that leans &lt;em&gt;heavily&lt;/em&gt; into OG Cruella’s taste for the extravagant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="cExXJO"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DbnTIRNKipg?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Zj8JlO"&gt;The film centers on a young girl named Estella — who later becomes known as Cruella — with a flare for punk fashion in 1970s London. Along the way, she teams up with a pair of thieves, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22400212/cruella-review-disney-plus-emma-stone-101-dalmatians"&gt;inexplicably develops&lt;/a&gt; a wicked personality, and ultimately becomes a revenge-hungry maniac with delectable taste in clothing. (Stone looks fabulous pretty much the entire movie.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5xjj9V"&gt;Despite the film’s campy absurdity, it seems Disney is already working on a Cruella franchise. Earlier this month, &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/business-news/emma-stone-cruella-sequel-deal-with-disney-1234998854/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hollywood Reporter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; cited sources as saying that Stone had locked in an eight-figure payout for a Cruella sequel. Details about who’s attached to the project and when it’s projected to release, however, are still under wraps.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22643373/stream-cruella-disney-plus-august-27"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22643373/stream-cruella-disney-plus-august-27</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-26T15:30:07-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-26T15:30:07-04:00</updated>
    <title>ULA stops selling its centerpiece Atlas V, setting path for the rocket’s retirement</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An Atlas V rocket with NASA’s Perseverance Mars rover..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nhGbIg2Bwmwvz4lxwL20alxIKJA=/0x0:4071x2714/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69780215/1227844386.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Paul Hennessy / SOPA Images / LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jOEqmz"&gt;United Launch Alliance won’t be selling any more of its workhorse Atlas V rockets, and it has stopped buying the launch vehicle’s Russian-made rocket engines for good, the company’s chief executive told &lt;em&gt;The Verge. &lt;/em&gt;ULA’s decision sets up the retirement of one of the US government’s most trusted launch vehicles and is expected to mark the end for Russia’s iconic — but controversial — RD-180 engine, an engineering marvel and a core source of revenue for Russia’s space program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yzMOw9"&gt;“We’re done. They’re all sold,” CEO Tory Bruno said of ULA’s Atlas V rockets in an interview. ULA, a joint venture between Boeing and Lockheed Martin, has 29 Atlas V missions left before it retires sometime in the mid-2020s and transitions to its upcoming Vulcan rocket, Bruno said. The remaining Atlas V missions include a mix of undisclosed commercial customers and some for the Space Force, NASA, and Amazon’s budding broadband satellite constellation, Project Kuiper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mZraOW"&gt;First launched in 2002, the expendable Atlas V launcher was the centerpiece vehicle that helped cement ULA’s near-monopoly on national security satellite missions and some of NASA’s biggest space exploration initiatives, including all of the agency’s robotic missions to Mars. But when the US sanctioned Russia over its annexation of Crimea in 2014, Congress directed the Air Force to end its reliance on Atlas V because of its Russian-made RD-180 engines. Current law requires the Space Force (which manages much of the launch-related duties that used to be under the Air Force) to stop using Atlas V for Pentagon launches by 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="NASA Introduces Atlas V Booster" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UdhCwcdN6CWYeV4RRaL7WJjyY6A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22807140/123986661.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Bill Ingalls / NASA via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Former NASA Administrator Charlie Bolden takes questions in front of an Atlas V rocket booster in 2011 before it launched NASA’s Curiosity rover to Mars.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="WNNag1"&gt;Bruno said three or four RD-180s are installed on Atlas V rockets for upcoming missions, and the rest are sitting in a warehouse. “We took early delivery, if you will, with the RD-180, so I can end that relationship and not be dependent upon [Russia] because that’s what Congress asked us to do,” he said. In all, the US has taken delivery of 122 RD-180 engines, generating billions in revenue for Russia’s space program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OulBVo"&gt;The last six RD-180 engines were delivered to the US in April, Russia’s space agency, Roscosmos, has previously said. That month, Bruno’s Russian counterparts told the CEO that if ULA ever decides to buy more RD-180 engines in the future, they’d be willing to build more and sell. But with no plans for ULA to buy more, the RD-180 program will likely come to an end, Bruno said. He took Russia’s offer with a grain of salt, skeptical that Energomash, the state-owned manufacturer of the RD-180, would be able to restart its engine production line and testing regime after it closes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fP59EZ"&gt;A spokesperson for Roscosmos, which speaks on Energomash’s behalf, declined to comment on whether RD-180 production is ending. The space agency’s former director, Igor Komarov, said in 2017 that Roscosmos has had “requests from some countries that are developing launchers and their expertise in space” to use the RD-180 engine, but those prospective engine customers remain to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="R7SHdv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Atlas V saw tough competition from SpaceX&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PfyBSA"&gt;The geopolitics of the RD-180 engine wasn’t the only reality setting Atlas V back. The rocket struggled to compete with SpaceX’s Falcon 9, a cheaper reusable rocket that chipped away at ULA’s monopoly on government launch contracts. Though a recent win for the rocket came in April when &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22391508/amazon-ula-rocket-launches-internet-satellites-kuiper"&gt;Amazon revealed it picked Atlas V&lt;/a&gt; to launch its internet-beaming Kuiper satellites into space. The value of the deal wasn’t disclosed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rdraeF"&gt;ULA has slashed the price for Atlas V missions from roughly $187 million to around $100 million as competition from SpaceX mounted, but it never closed in on Falcon 9’s launch price of roughly $62 million. Once a dominant force for national security launches, ULA now competes head to head with SpaceX for lucrative Pentagon launch contracts. Last year, Space Force awarded billions to ULA and SpaceX to launch 30 to 35 missions for the Pentagon between 2022 and 2027, with ULA getting 60 percent of the workload and SpaceX getting the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="08hSyA"&gt;For those Pentagon missions, ULA will mainly use its next-generation lower-cost Vulcan rocket, the replacement for Atlas V. Vulcan will use BE-4 engines under development by Jeff Bezos’ Blue Origin — but those engines have been delayed, further pushing Vulcan’s launch debut from late 2021 into early 2022. Development issues with the engine’s turbo pump and excessive vibrations that would occur while the engine was test-firing were the main factors for the delays, Bruno said, but they’ve since been resolved. “What is pacing us now is just building hardware,” he said, expecting delivery of the first flight-ready engines by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="T0hrNq"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Obviously we’re concerned, but we’re engaged with ULA”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ngnX26"&gt;The Space Force is weighing whether it’ll need to come up with “backup options,” should BE-4 delays continue into next year, Gen. Jason Cothern, the deputy commander of Space Force’s rocket acquisition unit, said Wednesday. Those options could include shifting some of Vulcan’s workload under its share of Pentagon launches to SpaceX, but officials are waiting to make a move on any contingencies until next year to see how the final chapter of BE-4 development plays out. “Obviously we’re concerned, but we’re engaged with ULA and they’re heavily engaged with Blue Origin to bring it along,” Cothern said, adding “we’re cautiously optimistic” that the flight-ready BE-4 engines will be delivered to ULA by year’s end.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22641048/ula-boeing-lockheed-end-sales-atlas-v-rocket-russia-rd180"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22641048/ula-boeing-lockheed-end-sales-atlas-v-rocket-russia-rd180</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-26T14:57:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-26T14:57:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>Blizzard to change name of Overwatch’s McCree following sexual harassment lawsuit</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YwfGwUtTaryZA_Bk3ecqAi3YlZQ=/60x0:2273x1475/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69779998/Screen_Shot_2021_08_23_at_8.46.38_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The gunslinger character in &lt;/em&gt;Overwatch&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Activision Blizzard&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="apoeHv"&gt;Blizzard says it plans to change &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PlayOverwatch/status/1430964453865046025"&gt;the name of &lt;em&gt;Overwatch’s&lt;/em&gt; gunslinger character&lt;/a&gt; following the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22588215/activision-blizzard-lawsuit-sexual-harassment-discrimination-pay"&gt;explosive sexual harassment lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; brought against Activision Blizzard by the state of California. The character was originally named “McCree” after Jesse McCree, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/11/22620800/activision-blizzard-departures-lawsuit-diablo-4-director"&gt;a former longtime Blizzard staffer&lt;/a&gt; who appears to be pictured in the so-called “Cosby Suite” &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/inside-blizzard-developers-infamous-bill-cosby-suite-1847378762"&gt;reported on by &lt;em&gt;Kotaku&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NqNJAX"&gt;Blizzard hasn’t shared a new name for the character yet, and the studio will delay an in-game narrative arc where he played a “key part” due to the change. The company also committed to no longer naming in-game characters after real employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="EdC9qj"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;A message from the Overwatch team. &lt;a href="https://t.co/2W3AV7Pv6X"&gt;pic.twitter.com/2W3AV7Pv6X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Overwatch (@PlayOverwatch) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PlayOverwatch/status/1430964453865046025?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 26, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9LDdAd"&gt;Recently, some &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League casters had &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-league-casters-stop-saying-mccree-s-name-1847474058"&gt;chosen to not say&lt;/a&gt; the gunslinger character’s former name, instead calling him “the cowboy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pT2PkK"&gt;The planned change follows promised updates to &lt;em&gt;World of Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; to remove &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22597006/blizzard-world-of-warcraft-activision-remove-references-harassment-lawsuit"&gt;“references that are not appropriate for our world,”&lt;/a&gt; which may have referred to &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/blizzard-harasser-from-lawsuit-is-still-all-over-world-1847345457"&gt;references of former &lt;em&gt;World of Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; senior creative director Alex Afrasiabi in the game&lt;/a&gt;. Afrasiabi was singled out in the lawsuit for his problematic actions while at Blizzard. He &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/inside-blizzard-developers-infamous-bill-cosby-suite-1847378762"&gt;was fired from Blizzard&lt;/a&gt; and appears to have worked for the company &lt;a href="https://us.forums.blizzard.com/en/wow/t/alex-afrasiabi-whered-he-go-o/749539"&gt;until June 2020&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PHPEIx"&gt;The change also follows a recent decision by Blizzard &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/blizzard-isnt-making-any-more-skins-for-overwatch-leagu-1846540244"&gt;not to create skins for &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League MVPs&lt;/a&gt; after sexual assault allegations surfaced against &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323695/jay-sinatraa-won-valorant-suspended-sexual-assault-allegations"&gt;former &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; pro and MVP Jay “Sinatraa” Won&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ERMu1s"&gt;When Blizzard confirmed that Jesse McCree was no longer at the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/11/22620800/activision-blizzard-departures-lawsuit-diablo-4-director"&gt;this month&lt;/a&gt;, it said that longtime employees Luis Barriga and Jonathan LeCraft were gone, too. Blizzard’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608320/blizard-jesse-meschuk-leave-company-hr-svp"&gt;former head of HR Jesse Meschuk&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22607356/blizzard-president-leaving-harassment-protest-brack"&gt;former president J. Allen Brack&lt;/a&gt; also left earlier in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gNT4uL"&gt;This week, California’s Department of Fair Employment and Housing (DFEH) accused Activision Blizzard of “withholding and suppressing evidence” needed for its investigation &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/24/22640302/california-activision-blizzard-lawsuit-update-withholding-info-expanded-victims"&gt;in an amended complaint&lt;/a&gt;. Employees &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22598410/activision-blizzard-employee-walk-out-protest-sexism-discrimination-lawsuit"&gt;walked out in protest&lt;/a&gt; of the company’s initial public response to the lawsuit in July. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22638947/blizzard-overwatch-mccree-name-change-lawsuit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22638947/blizzard-overwatch-mccree-name-change-lawsuit</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-26T14:50:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-26T14:50:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>Overwatch League cancels its in-person playoff events</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Overwatch League" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q2CfIQRqpKfsNROLy2jW5y2NsrE=/0x0:9000x6000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69779959/121639_S3W5D1_TorontoDefiantVsAtlantaReign_Stewart_VollandB.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo courtesy Stewart Volland for Blizzard Entertainment.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DTUhZn"&gt;The 2021 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22631026/overwatch-league-fourth-season-overview-blizzard"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League&lt;/a&gt; playoffs have hit a slight snag. Yesterday, the League announced it will no longer host live playoff matches in Dallas and Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CVo47P"&gt;“Due to significant changes in the environment affecting travel for some teams, we’ve decided to pivot away from originally scheduled live events in Dallas and Los Angeles,” the League wrote in a statement on Twitter. “Instead, postseason competition will return to Hawai’i for playoffs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vk1mW0"&gt;The move is likely in response to the COVID-19 delta variant surge that’s spreading across the globe and the diminishing ability for travelers to obtain visas to and from the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LtOKVj"&gt;Last season, the League split into two regions: North America and Asia Pacific, or APAC. Regular season play and the playoffs &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/22/21229380/overwatch-league-remote-cloud-production-studio-esports-blizzard"&gt;were sequestered within the regions&lt;/a&gt;, with each sending their top team to Korea to play in an online broadcast LAN grand final. This year, the League decided to introduce cross-regional play by sending qualifying NA teams to Hawaii. Dubbed “&lt;a href="https://overwatchleague.com/en-us/videos/yyy_2l6aOirhdQI"&gt;Project Aloha&lt;/a&gt;,” the &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League partnered with the University of Hawaii Manoa to provide facilities and support for visiting &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League teams to play against teams in Asia on servers designed to reduce game latency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="607NUr"&gt;While Project Aloha was a great way to introduce cross-regional play — something the &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League community greatly desired during the 2020 season — it wasn’t a perfect solution. Teams still had to travel to Hawaii, a problematic solution since COVID numbers are surging there and the governor is currently urging visitors to stay away. And though teams were playing on servers at as low a latency as possible, latency cannot be totally eliminated, affecting the quality of play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ruhtBG"&gt;After the announcement, &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League players voiced their concerns on social media with some remarking that it was unfortunate because they believed the setup disadvantaged North American teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OKtzKd"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;sucks that NA teams will be playing on a massive disadvantage again but not much u can do about this   &lt;a href="https://t.co/4q1nxGY6lt"&gt;https://t.co/4q1nxGY6lt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— nero (@ow_nero) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ow_nero/status/1430687870579183619?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 26, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="C0GYFo"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; asked the &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League why it decided to resume sending teams to Hawaii for games. A source with knowledge of the situation confirmed that visa difficulties and the constantly evolving situation with the delta variant necessitated a solution that reduced international travel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H5IP1F"&gt;Esports organizers are finding it increasingly difficult to plan live events as the world opens and shuts back down again due to the delta variant. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/24/22638914/league-of-legends-world-championships-2021-moved-china-europe"&gt;&lt;em&gt;League of Legend&lt;/em&gt;s’ Worlds tournament &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22567520/dota-2-the-international-bucharest-romania-sweden-october-location-date"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dota 2&lt;/em&gt;’s The International&lt;/a&gt; both made changes to their venues as countries restrict international travel and live event gatherings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xsuDG9"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Overwatch &lt;/em&gt;League’s decision to abandon live events comes amid Blizzard’s continuing legal battles against the state of California for enabling harassment and discrimination. Earlier this week, the Department of Fair Employment and Housing (DFEH) accused Blizzard of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/24/22640302/california-activision-blizzard-lawsuit-update-withholding-info-expanded-victims"&gt;“withholding and suppressing evidence.”&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n1Nzqd"&gt;The League is currently taking a short break as it prepares for the playoffs that begin on September 4th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tUQ3sp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VrDmOj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22643253/overwatch-league-owl-2021-playoffs-hawaii"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22643253/overwatch-league-owl-2021-playoffs-hawaii</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-26T14:17:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-26T14:17:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>Go read the harrowing story of the world’s first CO2 pipeline explosion</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Inside Saudi Aramco’s Hawiyah Natural Gas Liquids Recovery Plant" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/o3KbFt08UOXrPlqsVgbxzXq9pus=/0x0:5760x3840/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69779800/1233713474.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Location sign for the ‘CO2 to pipeline’ apparatus at the Hawiyah Natural Gas Liquids Recovery Plant, operated by Saudi Aramco, in Hawiyah, Saudi Arabia, on Monday, June 28, 2021. The Hawiyah Natural Gas Liquids Recovery Plant is designed to process 4.0 billion standard cubic feet per day of sweet gas as pilot project for Carbon Capture Technology (CCUS) to prove the possibility of capturing C02 and lowering emissions from such facilities. | Maya Siddiqui/Bloomberg via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zFL6Oj"&gt;Last year, a pipeline carrying compressed carbon dioxide mixed with hydrogen sulfide ruptured, engulfing the small town of Satartia, Mississippi, in a green haze, leaving many residents convulsing, confused, or unconscious. That explosion serves as a vivid&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;warning about the risks posed by what could be the next generation of pipelines to crisscross the US, in a new investigation by &lt;a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/gassing-satartia-mississippi-co2-pipeline_n_60ddea9fe4b0ddef8b0ddc8f"&gt;&lt;em&gt;HuffPost&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://climateinvestigations.org/"&gt;Climate Investigations Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="wHc5s6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It was almost like something you’d see in a zombie movie.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="N4gVIv"&gt;“It was almost like something you’d see in a zombie movie,” Sheriff’s Officer Terry Gann tells journalist Dan Zegart about what happened that night. Zegart pieces together the events of February 2020&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;through harrowing 911 calls and the voices of family members racing to reach others before the toxic haze could overcome them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LLaDLL"&gt;The story is a scathing investigation of the company, Denbury, that operates the pipeline, which did little to nothing to warn local officials and residents about the danger they faced, according to Zegart’s reporting. It’s also probably the closest thing to a PSA on the risks other&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;communities could face if proposals to build out tens of thousands of miles of CO2 pipelines come to fruition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cbbtjc"&gt;CO2 is the most high-profile greenhouse gas driving the global climate crisis. To keep CO2 from doing its damage in the atmosphere, some lawmakers and big green groups are pushing for new technology to capture carbon dioxide from the air or from smokestack emissions. That captured carbon dioxide would ultimately need to be transported to places where it can be stored underground. It’s an idea that’s gained so much steam recently that the bipartisan infrastructure package making its way through Congress &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22606395/pipeline-battle-co2-removal-carbon-capture-bipartisan-infrastructure"&gt;includes billions of dollars to develop the technology and the network of pipelines&lt;/a&gt; that would come with it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="59jUy4"&gt;Fossil fuel companies are also big backers of carbon capture technologies, selling it as a way for them to clean up their emissions while still selling oil and gas products responsible for climate change. They already move and use concentrated CO2 in a process called enhanced oil recovery: they shoot CO2 into the ground to help them extract more from their wells. The Denbury pipeline that exploded was transporting CO2 for that purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="aPVz3h"&gt;&lt;q&gt;CO2 might sound harmless — but at high concentrations, it’s an asphyxiant&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="r0Lpf5"&gt;Despite the growing support for carbon capture, there’s not a lot of information out there for the public about what this proposed new infrastructure could mean for communities like Satartia. None of the residents Zegart spoke to had heard about plans to build more CO2 pipelines across the country — even as &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WDRhM7tBWWI"&gt;officials eye&lt;/a&gt; the Gulf region as a potential hub for carbon capture in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7HVPuQ"&gt;CO2 might sound harmless — it’s in the air we breathe, after all — but at high concentrations, it’s an asphyxiant. Did you know that CO2 accidents kill around 100 workers globally each year? I did not, and I report on this kind of stuff for a living. What happened in Satartia is the world’s first known example of mass outdoor exposure to piped CO2, according to the World Health Organization’s Climate Change and Environmental Determinants of Health Unit. It might not be its last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WHMk3L"&gt;To learn more, read Zegart’s reporting in &lt;a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/gassing-satartia-mississippi-co2-pipeline_n_60ddea9fe4b0ddef8b0ddc8f"&gt;&lt;em&gt;HuffPost&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and hold on, this story is a nail-biter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="J8Jxjl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The infrastructure deal could create pipelines for captured CO2 ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22606395/pipeline-battle-co2-removal-carbon-capture-bipartisan-infrastructure"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id="TYvTSs"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The tech some countries are betting on to reach new climate goals ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/26/22404056/climate-tech-joe-biden-summit-carbon-capture-green-hydrogen"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="abZmrm"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NZqARj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xGFoZN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5kKMeM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22642806/co2-pipeline-explosion-satartia-mississippi-carbon-capture"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22642806/co2-pipeline-explosion-satartia-mississippi-carbon-capture</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-26T14:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-26T14:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nuro is building a factory and test track in Nevada for its autonomous delivery robots</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y_WwpIcWTzDfc4eXkAhkMkt2Ljs=/0x0:6720x4480/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69779727/nuro_r2_05_original.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Nuro&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xn2YHw"&gt;Nuro, the autonomous delivery startup founded by two ex-Google engineers, announced a dramatic expansion of its physical footprint. The company said it will spend $40 million on the construction of a manufacturing facility and test track for its fleet of self-driving robot vehicles. Both facilities will be located in Southern Nevada, which in recent years has become a hotbed for manufacturing and testing for the future of transportation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F1oZbM"&gt;Nuro, which is valued at $5 billion, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/30/16936548/nuro-self-driving-delivery-last-mile-google"&gt;was founded in 2016 by Dave Ferguson and Jiajun Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, two veterans of the Google self-driving car project that would go on to become Waymo. It is one of the few companies to be operating fully driverless vehicles — that is, vehicles without safety drivers behind the wheel — on public roads today. Its R2 vehicle is about half as wide as a compact sedan, shorter than most cars, and there’s no room inside for human passengers or drivers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="phOA5U"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The company plans on producing its third-generation vehicle at its Nevada facility&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Bg0IiV"&gt;The R2 is an updated version of Nuro’s original R1 prototype, with around 50 percent more capacity (which translates into about 18 more grocery bags). The company plans on producing its third-generation vehicle at its Nevada facility once it is fully operational in 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SDZoWCbI-JV9aGXP7QoogOYIQM0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22807074/Nuro_Manufacturing_Site.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Nuro&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nuro’s new manufacturing facility will include 125,000 square feet of space and 80 acres of property development.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="U5Suvh"&gt;The new 125,000-square-foot factory will have the capacity to build “tens of thousands of delivery vehicles,” Nuro says. The vehicle’s powertrain, which includes the electric motor and battery, will be made in the US by BYD, a Chinese company that is one of the largest manufacturers of electric vehicles in the world. Nuro says it will develop all the autonomous software and digital infrastructure “from United States-based servers to ensure safety and privacy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="D6kFQr"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Nuro says its $40 million investment will translate into $2.2 billion of “economic impact”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gPuZEC"&gt;Nuro says its $40 million investment will translate into $2.2 billion of “economic impact” for Nevada within 10 years and will result in the creation of 250 jobs. In April, the &lt;a href="http://rgj.com/story/news/money/business/2021/04/02/nevada-office-economic-development-approves-tax-incentives-9-companies/4839753001/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reno Gazette Journal&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; that Nuro will receive $170,519 in tax abatements over 10 years from Clark County. In exchange for the tax break, the company will create about 60 jobs within five years at an average wage of $28.80 per hour, the paper reported. The company also applied last September to receive an estimated $500,000 in tax abatements over a 10-year period from the Nevada Governor’s Economic Development Board, a spokesperson said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TtKCdK"&gt;Once the company’s manufacturing facility is up and running, Nuro will need a closed course to test and validate its vehicles safely. (As an example, Waymo uses &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/31/16579180/waymo-self-driving-test-facility-castle-google"&gt;a former Air Force base in central California&lt;/a&gt; which it originally leased in 2012.) Nuro said it is “taking over” 74 acres of the Las Vegas Motor Speedway to build a “world-class, closed-course testing facility that will allow sophisticated development and validation of its autonomous on-road vehicles.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LQoJIc"&gt;According to a spokesperson, Nuro will takeover the entire speedway for its testing facility. The race track was closed in November 2020 for COVID restrictions but has since been &lt;a href="https://www.fox5vegas.com/coronavirus/las-vegas-motor-speedway-plans-100-capacity-as-clark-county-lifts-capacity-restrictions/article_e277c48a-b847-11eb-9ad4-7b3ec4e7427b.html"&gt;reopened for events&lt;/a&gt;. The South Point 400 race is currently scheduled for September 24th-26th.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dUkPaJRZuAQEFLbd1iuoGxRRh9w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22807077/Nuro_Testing_Site.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Nuro&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nuro is taking over 74 acres of the Las Vegas Motor Speedway for its test track.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="3uFnWd"&gt;The test track is also expected to be operational by 2022, at which point Nuro plans on putting its driverless robots through a battery of tests, including “avoiding pedestrians and pets to giving bicycles space on shared roadways, as well as environmental tests and vehicle systems validation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="BLZcKu"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“This is a significant moment for Nuro”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qxwLpi"&gt;“This is a significant moment for Nuro,” said Zhu, Nuro’s co-founder and CEO, in a statement. “Building on our tremendous momentum—including strategic partnerships with industry leaders such as Domino’s, Kroger, and FedEx and operations in three states—we are now able to invest in the infrastructure to build tens of thousands of robots.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pwtnNp"&gt;The company is relatively unknown compared to its rivals in the autonomous vehicle space, mostly because of its focus on delivery and not ferrying human passengers in robotaxis. Still, Nuro has made incredible progress on the regulatory front, becoming &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/6/21125358/nuro-self-driving-delivery-robot-r2-fmvss-exemption"&gt;the first company to receive a special exemption from certain federal safety requirements&lt;/a&gt; and recently getting the green light to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22197980/nuro-licensed-autonomous-deliveries-california"&gt;charge money for its deliveries in California&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22642846/nuro-autonomous-delivery-factory-test-track-nevada"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/26/22642846/nuro-autonomous-delivery-factory-test-track-nevada</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
