<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-01T09:00:05-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-01T09:00:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-01T09:00:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>Dems push for federal probe of alleged ad collusion between Google and Facebook</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7LKeQsqKCsRGt0kUids_2hmUCKU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69802612/acastro_180406_1777_facebook_Congress_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="taXJrJ"&gt;Four Democratic members of Congress are calling for an investigation into whether an alleged secret 2018 agreement between Google and Facebook concerning digital advertising violated federal antitrust law. Sens. Elizabeth Warren (D-MA) and Richard Blumenthal (D-CT) and Reps. Pramila Jayapal (D-WA) and Mondaire Jones (D-NY) wrote a letter to Attorney General Merrick Garland and Acting US Attorney General Nicholas Ganjei of Texas asking them to determine whether federal charges might be warranted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ND3HXX"&gt;“If the reports are accurate, the behavior appears to be a clear violation of Section 1 of the Sherman Antitrust Act (Sherman Act), which criminalizes “mak[ing] any contract” “in restraint of trade or commerce,” the letter states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Pw746z"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The behavior appears to be a clear violation of... the Sherman Antitrust Act”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LvGx5P"&gt;Attorneys General in ten states &lt;a href="https://www.texasattorneygeneral.gov/sites/default/files/images/admin/2020/Press/20201216%20COMPLAINT_REDACTED.pdf"&gt;filed suit against Google&lt;/a&gt; in December over a program reportedly nicknamed “Jedi Blue,” according to an &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/inside-the-google-facebook-ad-deal-at-the-heart-of-a-price-fixing-lawsuit-11609254758"&gt;unredacted draft version&lt;/a&gt; viewed by the &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal.&lt;/em&gt; The Texas attorney general’s office led the suit, alleging that Facebook and Google worked to sabotage “header bidding,” which allows advertisers, including competitors, to bypass Google’s ad auctions. Google “repeatedly used its monopolistic power to control pricing,” according to the complaint. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mU5pPH"&gt;The Jedi Blue agreement &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/inside-the-google-facebook-ad-deal-at-the-heart-of-a-price-fixing-lawsuit-11609254758"&gt;allegedly guaranteed that Facebook&lt;/a&gt; would receive a fixed percentage of advertising bids on Google. In return, Facebook agreed to curtail its involvement with header bidding in ad auctions, the complaint states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gBROFu"&gt;In February, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/8/22272230/west-virginia-newspaper-google-facebook-lawsuit-digital-ad-revenue"&gt;parent company of a West Virginia newspaper chain&lt;/a&gt; filed an antitrust suit against the two companies, alleging that they were siphoning digital ad revenue away from news organizations. HD Media alleged in its complaint that the Jedi Blue agreement was an illegal quid pro quo. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tmpIV6"&gt;Now the members of Congress want the Justice Department to investigate whether Google and Facebook should be subject to sanctions, including possible criminal penalties. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3M4h50"&gt;Both companies strenuously deny any wrongdoing, and have issued detailed rebuttals to the charges. In response to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, a Google spokesperson referred to a &lt;a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/public-policy/ag-paxtons-misleading-attack-on-our-ad-tech-business/"&gt;January blog post written by Adam Cohen&lt;/a&gt;, the company’s director of economic policy. Titled “AG Paxton’s misleading attack on our ad tech business,” the post states that Facebook is one of more than 25 partners in its Open Bidding program, and that having the Facebook Audience Network’s participation actually helps publishers, by increasing the demand for publishers’ ad space, which allows the publishers to earn more revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6518jf"&gt;“AG Paxton inaccurately claims that we manipulate the Open Bidding auction in FAN’s favor. We absolutely don’t,” Cohen writes in the post. “FAN must make the highest bid to win a given impression. If another eligible network or exchange bids higher, they win the auction. FAN’s participation in Open Bidding doesn’t prevent Facebook from participating in header bidding or any other similar system. In fact, FAN participates in several similar auctions on rival platforms.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GdzTaO"&gt;A Facebook spokesperson declined to comment on the letter, but pointed to the company’s December statement on the matter, in which the company said that such partnerships are common in digital ad markets. “Any suggestion that these types of agreements harm competition is baseless,” the previous statement reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IfbCv4"&gt;Still, the specific allegations in the Texas case have been enough to spark further action. In the letter, members of Congress are particularly interested in the claim that the Jedi Blue deal was &lt;a href="https://mlexmarketinsight.com/news-hub/editors-picks/area-of-expertise/antitrust/googles-description-of-jedi-blue-clarifies-states-us-antitrust-complaint"&gt;signed by Google senior vice president Philipp Schindler and Facebook COO Sheryl Sandberg&lt;/a&gt;. The two may have been aware they were violating antitrust laws, as suggested by “a provision governing the parties’ options  to terminate the agreement in the event of certain government investigations of the agreement,” which could be evidence of criminal intent, according to the letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lRsbpi"&gt;The Jedi Blue deal amounts to bid rigging, the letter suggests, in violation of the Sherman Act which states that a “contract … or conspiracy, in restraint of trade  or commerce … is declared to be illegal.” Criminal penalties could range up to $100 million for a company found in violation and up to $1 million in fines and ten years in prison if an individual is found guilty.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22650550/facebook-google-antitrust-congress-democrats-ad-collusion-jedi-blue"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22650550/facebook-google-antitrust-congress-democrats-ad-collusion-jedi-blue</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-01T09:00:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-01T09:00:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>No Man’s Sky free update adds alien settlements for you to discover and rule</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/o9O3GCSjO31bf-431W2bCUg9lmI=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69802602/No_Man_s_Sky_Frontiers_Screen_1.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OsmPZ8"&gt;&lt;em&gt;No Man’s Sky&lt;/em&gt;’s latest update is adding alien settlements for you to discover as you explore its procedurally-generated universe. The appropriately titled “Frontiers” expansion was &lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/08/09/as-no-mans-sky-celebrates-its-fifth-anniversary-hello-games-reflects-on-the-journey-so-far/"&gt;first teased last month&lt;/a&gt;, and represents the game’s seventeenth major update since its launch five years ago. It’s available to download today, free of charge, like the rest of &lt;em&gt;No Man’s Sky&lt;/em&gt;’s updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BtzmbE"&gt;A brief trailer released by developer Hello Games gives an idea of what players can expect from these settlements, which come complete with aliens wandering their streets. Players will be able to become the Overseer of a settlement, and build it up from a small collection of buildings into a larger town. Once you’re in control, citizens will ask for help with their problems, and the town itself will need to be defended against attack. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5svzF1V22di-SZK5AQgFjDPWY5M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22819496/No_Man_s_Sky_Frontiers_Screen_4.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Hello Games&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A wretched hive of scum and villainy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="c3xtAe"&gt;Alongside settlements, the Frontiers update includes more base-building parts and a redesigned construction interface. There’s also a new expedition which will task players with mapping and exploring planets, as well as more minor quality of life improvements like redesigned visual effects, and the addition of deep space nebulae to pretty up the night sky. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SlJqk7"&gt;Frontiers looks like another impressive free update for a game whose launch was rocky, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2018/jul/20/no-mans-sky-next-hello-games-sean-murray-harassment-interview"&gt;to say the very least&lt;/a&gt;. But over the past five years Hello Games has turned &lt;em&gt;No Man’s Sky&lt;/em&gt; into an experience that arguably exceeds anything its developers promised prior to its release. No wonder it now has such a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/18/18683405/no-mans-sky-billboard-hello-games-sean-murray-gofundme-thank-you-beyond"&gt;dedicated following&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GKQ5W3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qdpeV9"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22651804/no-mans-sky-frontiers-free-update-alien-settlements-overseer-release-date-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22651804/no-mans-sky-frontiers-free-update-alien-settlements-overseer-release-date-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-01T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-01T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>How Android 12 lets you control your phone with facial gestures</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Android 12" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b2-h7Z7MoiSJKcKXVegDNs-e49M=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69802559/VRG_1777_Android_12_002.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="koRjta"&gt;A new accessibility feature that is being introduced with Android 12 allows you to control your screen using facial gestures: raise eyebrows, smile, open mouth, look up, look left, look right. This feature, called “Camera switches,” uses the phone’s camera to watch for these gestures and allows them to signal simple screen operations. These operations include: go to the next actionable screen object, select an object, go to the previous object, touch and hold, scroll forward, and scroll backward; you can also pause the camera switch itself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VmzBWL"&gt;It’s not a long list: it only includes six facial gestures and not all that many actions. However, it’s a beginning, and it could be useful if you can’t use your hands to work your phone’s screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="av01cN"&gt;If you do have a Pixel loaded with Android 12 beta — or if you’re reading this after Android 12 becomes available — here’s how you start using the “Camera switches” feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="r5dZwU"&gt;On your phone, go to “Settings”  &amp;gt; “Accessibility” &amp;gt; “Switch Access”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PKYNED"&gt;Toggle on “Use Switch Access.” It will probably ask you to allow it to view and control your screen and interact with apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dBADsf"&gt;You’ll then be asked to choose a switch type. You can use a physical switch via USB or Bluetooth, but we’re going to go with Camera Switch instead. You’ll be asked for permission to take pictures and record video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="be3ni4"&gt;Next, the app asks you to choose between using one switch or two. This is a little confusing: what it really means is that you can either just use a single gesture to start auto-scanning what’s on the screen (one switch), or you can use up to six different gestures to perform a variety of functions (two switches). I selected the second; either way, once you’ve made your choice, tap “Next.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ODnKOR"&gt;You now need to select one of three ways that you will be able to move through your actionable items using facial gestures. Linear scanning means that each gesture will move forward item by item; row-column scanning will let you select a row of items and then drill down; group selection will assign all items a color and you use facial gestures to choose which color you want, and drill down from there. I chose linear scanning, but you may want to try out all three to see which works for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="nNtKDF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10727839"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="9HjKkA"&gt;The three subsequent screens let you choose switches for three actions:  next, select, and pause (in other words, temporarily pause or unpause the use of facial gestures). You can use one or more facial gestures for each — for example, you can assign both eyebrows up and eyes right to “next.” But you can only use each gesture for one action; so if you choose to raise your eyebrows to indicate “next,” then “raise eyebrows” will be grayed out for any other actions.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="irjMw3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10727861"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="63nwas"&gt;The next screen is called “Switch Access settings.” Toggle it on to enable it. It has a “Try it” button that you can use to see if your camera can properly catch your smile, upraised eyebrows, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="HlMiM1"&gt;On this page, you can also tweak your face gesture settings to better suit your needs. For example, if you tap on “Open Mouth,” you can set how big the gesture needs to be (in other words, how open your mouth has to be), how long you need to hold it, etc. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="yOCLXg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10727943"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="j6x7WF"&gt;Try it out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="0QAiRe"&gt;At this point, it’s a good idea to leave setup and try it out. I did, and while I found it slow going (and realized very early on that I had neglected to assign the “previous” switch), it worked pretty well. I even had little trouble using raised eyebrows to indicate “next,” despite my rather heavily framed glasses. (Of course, they’re reading glasses that I often wear low on my nose, so it’s possible glasses might be a problem for others.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lz5kOk"&gt;Some things you may want to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="wAM8l5"&gt;If you want to go back and tweak your settings, you can go back to “Settings” &amp;gt; “Accessibility” &amp;gt; “Switch Access” &amp;gt; “Settings.” There you can reassign facial gestures either by going through the guided setup again (look for “Open setup guide” at the top of the page) or running through the various menu options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2R8c8F"&gt;A blue smiley face at the top of your screen will appear when the camera switches are active. When the switches are paused, you’ll see a blue “pause” symbol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vpY91h"&gt;When you go through your home screen using camera switches, a “Menu” button will appear next to the smiley face. This will bring up a quick menu of six action items, such as home, back, notifications, power options, etc. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EgIalo"&gt;One handy feature is the “Switch Access shortcut” which you can find on the main “Switch Access” page. The shortcut — a little green icon — will stay on your screen at all times, letting you turn switch access on and off at will. If it’s getting in your way, swipe it toward the edge of the screen to minimize it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="hsoiGX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10727953"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dqzXLf"&gt;Granted, Android 12’s new Camera Switch Access feature takes a while to set up and can be a little complex to tweak. In addition, I only used it for a few hours, and so I’m not a fair judge on how ultimately useful it would be to someone who may find it difficult to interact with their phone using touch. But if it is something that you might find useful, take a look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l0dsFs"&gt;One additional note if you’re using Android 10 or 11: since this feature is built into the Android Accessibility Suite, which is already part of Android 10 and 11, there is a good possibility that it will eventually become available to those versions of Android as well. According to sites such as &lt;a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/android-camera-switches-control-phone-with-face/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;XDA-Developers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, if you’re comfortable sideloading APKs on your phone, you can access it now via sites such as &lt;a href="https://www.apkmirror.com/apk/google-inc/android-accessibility-suite/android-accessibility-suite-12-0-0-381995842-release/android-accessibility-suite-12-0-0-381995842-android-apk-download/"&gt;APKMirror&lt;/a&gt;. Otherwise, stay tuned and watch for updates.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22649045/android-12-facial-gestures-accessibility-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22649045/android-12-facial-gestures-accessibility-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-01T08:30:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-01T08:30:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>1Password subscriptions are 50 percent off for Verge readers today</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/52UQahxcn0uMeTuTL6gMzvbz41s=/63x0:1938x1250/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69802439/item_details_view.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Yk8VZ1"&gt;Many of us would agree that online protection is more vital than ever before, but trying to remember a random string of letters and symbols for every site you frequent — or don’t — isn’t always easy. Password managers like 1Password are a great way to store your login credentials and beef up your security, however, one that can also save you plenty of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MDv1yP"&gt;Thankfully, &lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;readers can save 50 percent on their first year of 1Password for a limited time, whether they opt for an &lt;a href="https://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8836598-15026552?sid=VergeDeals" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;individual plan&lt;/a&gt; or a &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-8836598-15026551?sid=VergeDeals" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;family subscription&lt;/a&gt;. The individual plan normally runs $2.99 a month and comes out to be around $36 per year, yet our exclusive discount brings the annual price down to $18. The family plan, meanwhile, will run you $2.50 a month instead of $5, culminating in $30 a year. Keep in mind, however, that the family plan is limited to five people and that each plan is only available to new 1Password users, not returning customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X7rckI"&gt;In terms of features, 1Password offers quite a few. Not only does the service store your login details, but it will send you alerts for compromised sites and vulnerable passwords, while security features like authenticated encryption keep your data safe. You can also use the service on unlimited devices and enjoy 24/7 customer support if you hit a snag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0nXk1j"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10426335"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="XTiUco"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10437502"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Us84ji"&gt;If you have yet to pick up a smart speaker, the second-generation Echo Show 8 is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/All-new-Echo-Show-8-2nd-Gen-2021-release/dp/B084DC4LW6?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on sale at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1750688708099700197#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; for $100, matching its best price ever. Unlike the previous generation, the 2021 Echo Show 8 boasts faster performance and a superior 13-megapixel camera. It also features the same display, design, and speaker system as its predecessor, which is also &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Echo-Show-8/dp/B07PF1Y28C/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently on sale for $80&lt;/a&gt;. We consider the second-gen model the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22535003/best-smart-displays-alexa-google-echo-nest" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;best smart speaker you can buy&lt;/a&gt;, especially if you intend to use the smart display for video calls. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22521948/amazon-echo-show-8-2nd-gen-2021-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read the review.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qwPCKk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10611942"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mdfWru"&gt;Right now, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-75-Inch-Class-QLED-Built/dp/B08WFTZ9LY?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon is selling&lt;/a&gt; the 75-inch QLED Q80A Series TV at an all-time low, taking around $500 off the typical list price. Normally $2,700, you can pick up the TV — which was released earlier this year — for just $2,198. Better yet, a few &lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;staffers saw in the fine print that if you purchase it before September 30th and use the offer code &lt;strong&gt;B6PXLX23DQL9&lt;/strong&gt; at checkout, Amazon will give you $400 in credit to use on future purchases. Not a bad deal at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kSEQma"&gt;The 4K TV delivers wide viewing angles thanks to its IPS panel while producing bright and colorful images. It’s a good buy for gamers, too, who will enjoy the low input lag and support for variable refresh rate (VRR) and AMD FreeSync technology. While we haven’t tested this specific model, &lt;a href="https://www.reviewed.com/televisions/content/samsung-q80a-qled-tv-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reviewed&lt;/em&gt; notes&lt;/a&gt; that movie fans may not appreciate the low contrast levels or relatively lackluster local dimming feature, which can make it hard to watch HDR content or films in a dark room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Op1XkD"&gt;Amazon’s current deal comes just a week after the retailer also &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-75-Inch-Class-QLED-Built/dp/B08WFLBLWP?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;cut the price of the 55-inch model by $200&lt;/a&gt;, bringing it to a record low of $1,098. Other sizes are similarly discounted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="UuF4hd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best gaming TV to buy for the PS5 and Xbox Series X","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22399437/best-gaming-tv-playstation5-ps5-xbox-series-x-s"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="is1aOE"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10728699"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="g1p9br"&gt;If you’re looking for a pair of true wireless earbuds, you can pick up a refurbished pair of Jabra Elite 85t for &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ebay.com%2Fitm%2F164914311936%3Fmkcid%3D1%26mkrid%3D711-53200-19255-0%26siteid%3D0%26campid%3D5338794975%26customid%3DVergeGetaoneyear1Passwordsubscriptionfor50percentoffAUG312021%26toolid%3D10001%26mkevt%3D1&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F9%2F1%2F22651065%2F1password-amazon-echo-show-8-samsung-qled-tv-jabra-elite-85t-apple-deals-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$117 at eBay through Jabra’s digital storefront&lt;/a&gt; with promo code &lt;strong&gt;SAVE15LABORDAY&lt;/strong&gt;. They’re also &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Jabra-Wireless-Bluetooth-Earbuds-Titanium/dp/B08HR78C46?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently on sale at Amazon for $180 new&lt;/a&gt;, meaning eBay’s refurbished discount equates to an additional $63 in savings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qk6SHI"&gt;Released in November, the 85t are the first pair of earbuds from Jabra to ship with active noise cancellation. In contrast to the AirPods Pro and Bose’s QuietComfort Earbuds, they’re also capable of simultaneously pairing with two devices. You can also buy the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1750688339690161172#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jabra Elite 75t at best Buy right now for $100&lt;/a&gt;, however, if you want solid noise cancellation and excellent on-earbud controls, it may be worth forking over the extra $17 for the refurbished Elite 85t. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549587/jabra-elite-85t-review-features-specs-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="RAS9SD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Jabra overhauls true wireless earbuds lineup with three new models","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22649800/jabra-elite-7-pro-active-3-features-price"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="2eZPyI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10369683"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2zWZiX"&gt;For a limited time, Apple’s iPhone 11 Pro Smart Battery Case is more than half off its usual price. Once again, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B081SHMJ77/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1750684926448631384#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; are both selling the $130 case for a record low of $52. Best Buy is also throwing in a free, six-month subscription to Apple Music and Apple News Plus for new users. The case offers a decent amount of charge — Apple says you can expect “up to 50 percent” extra battery life — while boasting features such as a physical camera button and the ability to charge your iPhone and battery case simultaneously. At the same time, its soft microfiber lining gives your phone some additional protection.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="fy2ETY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10607518"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="jFyuPG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="dxa1tG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QTp5KX"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/9/1/22651065/1password-amazon-echo-show-8-samsung-qled-tv-jabra-elite-85t-apple-deals-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/9/1/22651065/1password-amazon-echo-show-8-samsung-qled-tv-jabra-elite-85t-apple-deals-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-01T08:00:37-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-01T08:00:37-04:00</updated>
    <title>DJI’s next smartphone gimbal might include a telescoping selfie stick</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0ZfpmDxIWRHnYXuIONr6WuQxIYs=/0x0:1068x712/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69802338/DJI_OM_5_1630481788_0_4.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gimbal, meet selfie stick.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://winfuture.de/news,124942.html" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WinFuture&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7Ab4x2"&gt;DJI appears to have another smartphone gimbal on the way with a telescoping selfie stick built into its handle, &lt;a href="https://winfuture.de/news,124942.html"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;WinFuture&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The Osmo Mobile 5, which is an apparent successor to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/26/21401564/dji-osmo-mobile-4-phone-gimbal-magnetic-announce-price-release-date"&gt;last year’s Osmo Mobile 4&lt;/a&gt;, is likely to make its first appearance at DJI’s &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DJIGlobal/status/1432690094750588932"&gt;September 8th launch event&lt;/a&gt; where it will reportedly earn a European price of €159, which roughly translates to a tax-inclusive price of $188. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mEY3D2"&gt;The Osmo Mobile 5 reportedly folds down to around 17cm (6.7 inches), but can be extended when you need to get closer to your subject, or further away from yourself. From the pictures, it doesn’t seem to extend quite as much as a traditional selfie stick, but it should be enough to give you a little extra flexibility with your shots. When extended, the gimbal’s controls sensibly remain down by your hand. Sure, selfie sticks have a pretty terrible reputation as the chosen accessory of inconsiderate tourists, but they’re &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2014/12/31/7470713/selfie-stick-haters-hate"&gt;pretty damn handy in the right circumstances&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oO61bB_XKLObrYmMDIs5f5cm0Z8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22819574/msedge_RuyuCYhmHG.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://winfuture.de/news,124942.html" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WinFuture&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It appears to fold down as compactly as DJI’s existing gimbals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="WER3hx"&gt;Unfortunately, it sounds like the telescoping mechanism built into the Osmo Mobile 5 has had an impact on battery life, which reportedly stands at around 6 hours and 20 minutes compared to 15 hours for the Osmo Mobile 4. Thankfully the magnetic mounting system from the Osmo Mobile 4 has stuck around, which should mean it’s as easy as ever to quickly attach and detach your phone from the gimbal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yXNl8b"&gt;Alongside the Osmo Mobile 5, &lt;em&gt;WinFuture’s&lt;/em&gt; Roland Quandt also reports that there’s a more affordable $99 version of the Osmo Mobile 4 on the way, which won’t include the original $149 gimbal’s magnetic mounting system. A shame for sure, but it’s hard to argue with the discount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="QGNn0e"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;btw... DJI OM 4 SE is also incoming: 99$ and basically the same as the original OM4, but w/o the magnetic smartpone holder. &lt;a href="https://t.co/dQO5LhKMMQ"&gt;https://t.co/dQO5LhKMMQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Roland Quandt (@rquandt) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rquandt/status/1433023533001629699?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 1, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Ei8IOX"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22651919/dji-osmo-mobile-5-smartphone-gimbal-selfie-stick"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22651919/dji-osmo-mobile-5-smartphone-gimbal-selfie-stick</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-01T07:02:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-01T07:02:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Telegram uncaps live stream viewers as part of big version 8.0 update</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/30qryDtAhkxKIX5Gssm4rnMluGQ=/61x0:1195x756/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69802138/aed1cb7af8c96e961b.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Telegram&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="sOEgks"&gt;Telegram, the messaging app that’s becoming more and more like a fully-fledged social media network, is expanding support for video live streams with its latest update. &lt;a href="https://telegram.org/blog/live-streams-forwarding-next-channel"&gt;Version 8.0 of the app&lt;/a&gt;, which is available now on both iOS and Android, allows live streams to be watched by an unlimited number of viewers, up from the &lt;a href="https://telegram.org/blog/video-1000"&gt;previous limit of 1,000&lt;/a&gt;. Other new features include more options when forwarding messages, and a shortcut to switch between channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0NbmZv"&gt;Increasing the maximum number of viewers like this opens the door to Telegram becoming a full-on mobile live streaming platform, complete with the ability for as many as 30 users to broadcast at once. “The power to run your own TV station is here, right in your pocket,” is how Telegram puts it. The service also supports &lt;a href="https://telegram.org/blog/voice-chats-on-steroids"&gt;Clubhouse-style voice channels&lt;/a&gt; with support for “millions” of live listeners. It’s rapid progress considering Telegram’s group calling feature only launched in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/26/22551652/telegram-adds-group-video-calling-chat"&gt;June this year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="0C5u4A"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The power to run your own TV station is here, right in your pocket”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8Iohab"&gt;Also included with version 8.0 of the app is an option to remove captions and hide sender names when forwarding messages and media. Scrolling to the bottom of a text channel now includes a new option to quickly swipe up to jump to the next unread channel. Other interface tweaks include a new “choosing a sticker” status in chats, and an unread messages counter in comment threads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yISqmy"&gt;As of January this year, Telegram boasted &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/telegram/status/1349014065931284480?s=20"&gt;500 million active users&lt;/a&gt;, compared to around 2 billion for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/12/21134652/whatsapp-2-billion-monthly-active-users-encryption-facebook"&gt;Facebook’s rival WhatsApp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22651880/telegram-version-8-live-streams-video-unlimited-participants-flexible-forwarding"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22651880/telegram-version-8-live-streams-video-unlimited-participants-flexible-forwarding</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-01T06:20:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-01T06:20:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>VanMoof raises $128M to become ‘most funded e-bike company in the world’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OrCFF_k0K8JRncAnn-eIzdv78kY=/7x0:2034x1351/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69802019/verge_DSC_7394_2040pxl.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;VanMoof S3 e-bike in Amsterdam | Photo by Thomas Ricker / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ebsx0K"&gt;VanMoof just raised another $128 million in funding, after announcing a $40 million investment round in September 2020. That brings Amsterdam-based VanMoof’s total haul to $182 million raised in the last two years, excluding crowdfunding rounds in 2018 and 2019, making it “the most funded e-bike company in the world,” &lt;a href="https://www.vanmoof.com/news/en-GB/202064-vanmoof-raises-128m-to-make-its-high-tech-e-bikes-the-new-standard-in-cities-worldwide"&gt;according to VanMoof&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z2hBGy"&gt;The company claims to have almost 200,000 bikes on the road currently, with the goal of getting 10 million people on VanMoof e-bikes in the next five years. Such aggressive expansion goals require significant capital. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="vuED3R"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Improve the quality and reliability of the bike&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="940gwS"&gt;VanMoof’s new funding round has been earmarked to expand production and to “reinvent the way in which hardware and software components are made,” according to a &lt;a href="https://www.vanmoof.com/news/en-GB/202064-vanmoof-raises-128m-to-make-its-high-tech-e-bikes-the-new-standard-in-cities-worldwide"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; announcing the new investment round. More specifically, VanMoof co-founder Taco Carlier tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;in a phone interview that most of the funds will go towards R&amp;amp;D, “having more people on the hardware and software development in order to improve the quality and reliability of the bike.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TbRi0G"&gt;Last September, the company said it was using about a third of its $40 million investment round to improve after-sales support that had faltered under the strain of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/16/21437704/vanmoof-interview-s3-electric-bike-issues-delays-mobile-service-network"&gt;troubled launch of its S3 and X3 e-bikes&lt;/a&gt; during a pandemic. That money is already being used to expand the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.vanmoof.com/news/en-GB/197430-vanmoof-announces-global-service-expansion-across-50-cities"&gt;dedicated service hubs from 8 to 50 worldwide cities&lt;/a&gt; by the end of 2021, and develop a “Bike Doctor Network” that sends support technicians directly to customer locations when service is needed. Today’s investment round will allow for more service hubs and branded stores in (a few) more cities, according to Carlier, while paying for the rollout of the Bike Doctor Network to those cities starting in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CBErDa"&gt;For comparison, RadPower, the largest e-bike maker in the US, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266143/rad-power-bikes-investment-electric-ebike"&gt;raised $150 million earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;, adding to the $25 million it garnered the year prior. Investors are pouring money into electric bike makers in the hope of capitalizing on the global e-bike market which is expected to be worth almost &lt;a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2021/04/06/2204781/0/en/Global-e-bike-market-size-to-reach-USD-48-46-billion-by-2028.html"&gt;$50 billion by 2028&lt;/a&gt;. In March 2021, e-bikes already represented 17 percent of all bicycle sales in Europe, and accounted for more than 50 percent of all new bike sales in countries like Germany and the Netherlands. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SBV3qq"&gt;E-bike sales in the US are also on the rise. As of April, sales were up 139 percent to $681 million for the year-to-date, compared to the same period in 2020, according to market research firm NPD Group. VanMoof says that the US is its fastest growth market, “with the post-pandemic e-bike wave showing no sign of slowing down.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22651860/vanmoof-128-million-funding-most-funded-ebike-company"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22651860/vanmoof-128-million-funding-most-funded-ebike-company</id>
    <author>
      <name>Thomas Ricker</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-01T05:57:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-01T05:57:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft is kicking unsupported PCs out of Windows 11 testing</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zODPjlEqGOmHbnnA1pGBcwDgiy8=/50x0:1550x1000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69801954/windows11stock.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Windows 11 is launching on October 5th. | Image: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="y3UAaC"&gt;Microsoft is starting to drop PCs from its Windows Insider testing program that are ineligible to upgrade to Windows 11. If you’ve been helping Microsoft test Windows 11 on a machine that doesn’t meet the minimum hardware requirements, you’ll likely see a message in Windows Update warning that you’ll need to reinstall Windows 10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9uAx7H"&gt;“Your PC does not meet the minimum hardware requirements for Windows 11,” says Microsoft’s warning. “Your device is not eligible to join the Windows Insider Program on Windows 11. Please install Windows 10 to participate in the Windows Insider Program in the Release Preview Channel.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M1oThq"&gt;Windows 11 testers in both the Dev and Beta channels have started receiving the message on incompatible PCs this week, just as Microsoft has announced its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22649940/windows-11-release-date-features-devices-free-upgrade"&gt;October 5th release date&lt;/a&gt; for the upcoming OS. It’s something that Microsoft warned testers would happen at the beginning of the beta period of Windows 11, but it still highlights the often confusing minimum hardware requirements that Microsoft has set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9uUMSX"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Microsoft has now dropped ineligible systems from the Insider program and tells them to install Windows 10. &lt;a href="https://t.co/zfALanmcuq"&gt;pic.twitter.com/zfALanmcuq&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— BetaWiki (@BetaWiki) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BetaWiki/status/1432806974022995971?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 31, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="o5Li6C"&gt;Windows 11 testers that have been running the OS on unsupported hardware will &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22644194/microsoft-windows-11-minimum-system-requirements-processors-changes"&gt;be able to use a workaround&lt;/a&gt; to install an ISO version of the final release. But Microsoft warns that devices in this unsupported state won’t be eligible for Windows Updates, and that could include security patches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ErthgY"&gt;Microsoft recommends that Windows 11 testers that don’t meet the hardware minimums should install Windows 10, as this OS will be supported until 2025. Many Windows 11 testers, who are often loyal Microsoft enthusiasts, will still be left confused why their PC isn’t officially supported even though it has likely been running the OS just fine for months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8jc3qJ"&gt;Microsoft has attempted to justify its Windows 11 minimum hardware requirements around a push for security and reliability, but it still leaves some PCs sold just a few years ago from being able to upgrade. Windows 11 raises the baseline of security to the CPU level, and Microsoft has been clear it wants to enforce or support &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22550376/microsoft-windows-11-tpm-chips-requirement-security"&gt;Trusted Platform Module (TPM)&lt;/a&gt;, UEFI Secure Boot, and virtualization-based security methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Nlkn8"&gt;Windows 11 will &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22649940/windows-11-release-date-features-devices-free-upgrade"&gt;now arrive on October 5th&lt;/a&gt;, and Microsoft will continue to release new Dev builds of the OS to testers. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22650000/microsoft-windows-11-android-apps-support"&gt;Android app integration isn’t arriving at launch&lt;/a&gt; but Windows Insider testers will get access in the coming months to the feature which relies heavily on modern hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22651851/microsoft-windows-11-testing-pcs-requirements-changes"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22651851/microsoft-windows-11-testing-pcs-requirements-changes</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-01T05:44:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-01T05:44:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>Midrange Samsung Galaxy S21 FE appears again in leaked manual</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pZZyie-EG6IUu6-eJO8tlaTIF0E=/1x0:1147x764/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69801948/msedge_cwyTkgz4Rn.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A render of the unannounced phone from the leaked manual.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Samsung (&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/galaxy-s21-fe-5g-user-manual-makes-no-mention-of-microsd-slot/?__cf_chl_jschl_tk__=pmd_CNo4aG0QZ2u7M8IsX0IwJps0YlMeItRJH4K0Ll1_CzQ-1630443096-0-gqNtZGzNArujcnBszQ0l" target="_blank"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;SamMobile&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qYtVdr"&gt;A user manual for Samsung’s Galaxy S21 FE (aka “Fan Edition”) has been &lt;a href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/galaxy-s21-fe-5g-user-manual-makes-no-mention-of-microsd-slot/?__cf_chl_jschl_tk__=pmd_CNo4aG0QZ2u7M8IsX0IwJps0YlMeItRJH4K0Ll1_CzQ-1630443096-0-gqNtZGzNArujcnBszQ0l"&gt;published online by &lt;em&gt;SamMobile&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, giving us another look at the unannounced midrange counterpart to the company’s Galaxy S21 flagship. As you’d expect from a manual, the document spends more time outlining how to use the phone than it does describing its specs, but it’s a guide for what’s to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OHbW9V"&gt;For starters, images included in the manual appear to confirm that &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1400945475558199298"&gt;previously leaked renders&lt;/a&gt; are accurate. That means we’re looking at a similar design to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22252460/samsung-galaxy-s21-review-price-camera-processor"&gt;Galaxy S21&lt;/a&gt;, albeit seemingly with a less premium finish. Three cameras are shown on the S21 FE’s rear while on the front there’s an in-display fingerprint scanner and a hole-punch notch for a selfie camera.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a-XbCbJJT3RrrhDqLSUVxy0rvuw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22819522/msedge_K8x7I5KuYH.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;One section of the manual describe’s the phone’s reverse wireless charging feature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="9wSAPz"&gt;Other details mentioned in the manual include an IP68 rating for dust and water resistance, an ultra-wide camera, and support for Samsung’s Wireless DeX software to allow the phone to mirror its display to supported TVs and use its screen as a touchpad. There’s no sign of a headphone jack, microSD card slot (which appeared on last year’s S20 FE), or an included charging brick in the box. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ncznlI"&gt;In terms of specs, &lt;em&gt;SamMobile&lt;/em&gt; notes that previous rumors claim the phone will be powered by a Snapdragon 888 or Exynos 2100 processor depending on the market, which would put it roughly in line with the Galaxy S21 flagship from earlier this year. Its battery is expected to have a capacity of 4,500mAh, with support for 25W fast charging and reverse wireless charging also mentioned. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K2SlIL"&gt;The question now is when, if ever, we might see the phone officially announced. Earlier this year &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22532816/samsung-galaxy-s21-fe-production-reportedly-halted"&gt;Samsung was forced to deny reports&lt;/a&gt; that it had cancelled production of the unannounced phone due to production difficulties caused by the global chip shortage. The emergence of a user manual suggests the phone will see an official release, though it doesn’t outright confirm it. For reference, last year’s Galaxy S20 FE was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/23/21451701/samsung-galaxy-s20-fe-price-release-date-specs-features"&gt;announced on September 23rd&lt;/a&gt;, ahead of its release on October 2nd, suggesting we might not have long to wait to find out.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22651847/samsung-galaxy-s21-fe-fan-edition-leaked-manual-specs-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22651847/samsung-galaxy-s21-fe-fan-edition-leaked-manual-specs-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-01T05:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-01T05:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Internet shutdowns by governments have ‘proliferated at a truly alarming pace’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FWbqJUz8ajVnwFEKZBcj_8REK4k=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69801939/jbareham_170410_1605_0035.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="H9atqg"&gt;The number of government-led internet shutdowns has exploded over the last decade as states seek to stifle dissent and protest by limiting citizens’ access to the web. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GVRjKN"&gt;Nearly 850 intentional shutdowns have been recorded over the past 10 years by nonprofit Access Now’s &lt;a href="https://www.accessnow.org/keepiton/"&gt;Shutdown Tracker Optimization Project&lt;/a&gt; (STOP), and although the group acknowledges that data on incidents before 2016 is “patchy,” some 768 of these shutdowns took place in the last five years. There were 213 shutdowns in 2019 alone, with this figure ticking down to 155 in 2020 as the world adapted to the COVID-19 pandemic (which delayed elections and led to lockdowns that kept populations at home more often). And already in the first five months of 2021 there have been 50 shutdowns across 21 countries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="BbxImH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It has moved from the fringes to become a common method”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OVstsN"&gt;“Since we began tracking government-initiated internet shutdowns, their use has proliferated at a truly alarming pace,” Access Now’s Felicia Anthonio, campaigner and &lt;a href="https://www.accessnow.org/keepiton/"&gt;#KeepItOn&lt;/a&gt; lead, said in a &lt;a href="https://jigsaw.google.com/the-current/shutdown/"&gt;new report on the issue&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;The Current&lt;/em&gt;, a publication of Google’s internet thinktank Jigsaw. “As governments across the globe learn this authoritarian tactic from each other, it has moved from the fringes to become a common method many authorities use to stifle opposition, quash free speech and muzzle expression.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fYybKa"&gt;The first significant internet shutdown took place in Egypt in 2011, as a response to protests against then-president Hosni Mubarak. As a result, an &lt;a href="https://blogs.oracle.com/internetintelligence/egypt-leaves-the-internet-v3"&gt;estimated&lt;/a&gt; 93 percent of Egyptian networks were blocked for five days. Earlier internet shutdowns and slowdowns were carried out in Guinea in 2007 and in Iran in 2009, but Egypt’s was the first to affect internet connections across an entire country where more than a quarter of citizens had access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C99kyL"&gt;Since then, shutdowns have spread across the world, most prominently in Asia and Africa. They’re most frequently deployed during elections or times of protest, with governments claiming shutdowns are needed to stem the spread of misinformation. In reality, though, as the report in &lt;em&gt;The Current&lt;/em&gt; notes, the intention is to “prevent opposition candidates from connecting with voters to build support, restrict the ability of citizens to organize, and undermine the efforts of election observers to ensure the integrity of the vote.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="99sWsr"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Many governments see the internet “as a threat that needs to be ‘controlled’”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pHDkyj"&gt;Speaking to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, Marianne Díaz Hernández, a Venezuelan lawyer and #KeepItOn Fellow, says the rise in shutdowns is a response to the internet’s increasing utility for organizing protest. “As more and more people use the internet, and particularly social media, to document and denounce human rights violations, civil unrest and other events, some governments start seeing the internet as a threat that needs to be ‘controlled,’” she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UPiT7u"&gt;In addition to the stifling of free speech and assembly, internet shutdowns have significant economic harms. In Myanmar, which has seen the longest-ever government-led internet shutdown in history as part of the &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-55902070"&gt;recent coup&lt;/a&gt;, it’s estimated the &lt;a href="https://www.top10vpn.com/cost-of-internet-shutdowns/"&gt;economic loss&lt;/a&gt; has been equal to 2.5 percent of the country’s GDP — around $2.1 billion. The report in &lt;em&gt;The Current&lt;/em&gt; notes that this “inflicted on the country approximately half the damage wrought by the Great Recession on the US economy in less than a third of the time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RJbwQ0"&gt;Combatting the issue seems difficult at a high level. Internet shutdowns have been condemned by various international organizations, including the G7 and the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights and Special Rapporteurs, but as Access Now’s data shows, this doesn’t seem to have dinted their use. There have also been some legislative wins, as when the Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS) Community Court, ruled that &lt;a href="https://www.accessnow.org/ecowas-togo-court-decision/"&gt;a 2017 internet shutdown in Togo was illegal&lt;/a&gt;, but it also seems unlikely such actions will actually dissuade governments who feel shutdowns are necessary to hold power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XOzS8e"&gt;The best method to combat internet shutdowns seem technological. VPNs and proxy servers allow users to rout internet traffic through another country to avoid certain blocks, while mesh networking apps can connect directly from one device to another, providing basic messaging functionality (though no access to the wider internet). But access to such tools is not guaranteed: it depends on people knowing they can be used in the first place and downloading them in advance of a shutdown. At least the internet can be used to help get the word out.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22649909/internet-sthudowns-government-freedom-speech-data-access-now-jigsaw"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22649909/internet-sthudowns-government-freedom-speech-data-access-now-jigsaw</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
