<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2022-01-14T03:30:19-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T03:30:19-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T03:30:19-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla now lets you buy some merch in Dogecoin</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OghnujLUgb5CDXHcVhzjNj5iXUo=/49x0:1834x1190/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70386815/giga_doge.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Giga Texas Belt Buckle now costs 835 DOGE.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5WSNT0"&gt;Tesla now lets customers buy select items of merchandise using Dogecoin, the company’s &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1481873421390680065"&gt;CEO Elon Musk has announced&lt;/a&gt;. Products buyable with the meme-based cryptocurrency include the Cyberquad for Kids (12,020 doge / around $2,320), the &lt;a href="https://shop.tesla.com/product/giga-texas-belt-buckle?sku=1758879-00-A"&gt;Giga Texas Belt Buckle&lt;/a&gt; (835 doge / around $161) and the Cyberwhistle (300 doge / around $58). &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/tesla-starts-accepting-dogecoin-for-merchandise-meme-coin-spike-2022-1?r=US&amp;amp;IR=T"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Business Insider &lt;/em&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt; that Dogecoin was up 16 percent to around $0.20 following the news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jUBfDC"&gt;The initiative was initially announced by Musk on Twitter &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1470703708677840896"&gt;on December 14th&lt;/a&gt; when he said that the company would “see how it goes” with the cryptocurrency payment option. It’s unclear if or when Tesla might eventually accept payment for its vehicles in Dogecoin, which Musk has previously said may be &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1113009339743100929"&gt;his favorite cryptocurrency&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kSMNPi"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Tesla merch buyable with Dogecoin&lt;/p&gt;— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1481873421390680065?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 14, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="a2e42m"&gt;The initiative appears to be supported outside the US, with the &lt;a href="https://shop.tesla.com/en_gb/product/s3xy-mug?sku=8764620-00-A"&gt;S3XY Mug&lt;/a&gt; buyable with Dogecoin from the UK Tesla store for 150 doge (around $29). As of this writing, Dogecoin now appears to be the only way to buy certain items, as their regular payment icons have disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L6UYrx"&gt;Support for Dogecoin purchases comes just months after Tesla &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/24/22347905/tesla-bitcoin-payment-us-cryptocurrency-elon-musk"&gt;started accepting Bitcoin for car purchases&lt;/a&gt;, only to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/12/22433153/tesla-suspend-bitcoin-vehicle-purchase-cryptocurrency-elon-musk"&gt;cease the practice 49 days later&lt;/a&gt;, citing concerns about the use of fossil fuels for Bitcoin mining. “Cryptocurrency is a good idea on many levels and we believe it has a promising future, but this cannot come at great cost to the environment,” Elon Musk said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/A7Jb3rYXZ9_reK4xbRfq0Q44UMU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23168399/image.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot: Tesla.com&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The S3XY Mug, available for 150 doge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="tSrIjf"&gt;Dogecoin currently doesn’t consume anywhere near the same amount of energy per transaction as Bitcoin, according to &lt;a href="https://www.trgdatacenters.com/most-environment-friendly-cryptocurrencies/"&gt;research from TRG Datacenters&lt;/a&gt;. But Dogecoin is still an energy-intensive proof-of-work cryptocurrency, as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22434617/renewable-energy-bitcoin-pollution-tesla-elon-musk"&gt;digital currency economist Alex de Vries explained in May&lt;/a&gt;. Its smaller energy use per transaction is largely because it’s currently a less valuable asset than Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VqbrdT"&gt;For his part, Musk &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1392974251011895300"&gt;said in May&lt;/a&gt; that he was working with Dogecoin developers to “improve system transaction efficiency.” He’s not been shy about his support of the cryptocurrency, which started life as a joke &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Doge_(meme)"&gt;based on the Doge meme&lt;/a&gt;. “Lots of people I talked to on the production lines at Tesla or building rockets at SpaceX own Doge,” Musk &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/10/25/elon-musk-on-his-crypto-portfolio-and-why-he-supports-dogecoin.html"&gt;told CNBC in October&lt;/a&gt;. “They aren’t financial experts or Silicon Valley technologists. That’s why I decided to support Doge, it felt like the people’s crypto.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7dto04"&gt;Another of Elon Musk’s ventures, SpaceX, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22427588/spacex-dogecoin-satellite-doge-1-to-the-moon"&gt;started accepting payment in Dogecoin in May&lt;/a&gt; and next year plans to send a satellite named DOGE-1 to the Moon. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22849725/tesla-dogecoin-cryptocurrency-merchandise-sales"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22849725/tesla-dogecoin-cryptocurrency-merchandise-sales</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T03:21:27-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T03:21:27-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla delays Cybertruck to early 2023, says report</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-AUTOMOBILE-TESLA-CYBERTRUCK" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EHnCt22c8lkRBRGEyw5o56tjyqs=/99x0:5469x3580/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70382686/1183828053.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by FREDERIC J. BROWN/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="z9xAyc"&gt;Tesla has never been fantastic at meeting deadlines, so it’s not too surprising that the company’s ambitious electric pickup — the Cybertruck — is running a little late. Recently, reference to a 2022 production schedule was scrubbed from its website. Now &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/exclusive-tesla-delays-initial-production-cybertruck-early-2023-source-2022-01-13/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; is reporting&lt;/a&gt; that production won’t begin until the first quarter of 2023, citing a person familiar with the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xOP5XX"&gt;The Cybertruck was originally announced in 2019, with Tesla promising that the vehicle would be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/21/20975475/tesla-cybertruck-announcement-musk-electric-truck-pickup-features-range-price-release-date"&gt;rolling off production lines&lt;/a&gt; in late 2021. Then, in August that year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/8/22615539/tesla-cybertruck-production-delayed-2022-elon-musk"&gt;full production was delayed&lt;/a&gt; to some time in 2022. Now, that deadline seems to have been waived, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bxWy3O"&gt;As first &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.edmunds.com%2Fcar-news%2Ftesla-cybertruck-delayed-2022.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2022%2F1%2F13%2F22881646%2Ftesla-cybertruck-production-date-2022-removed-website" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;spotted by &lt;em&gt;Edmunds&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the order page on Tesla’s Cybertruck site previously told buyers: “You will be able to complete your configuration as production nears in 2022.” Now, it just says: “You will be able to complete your configuration as production nears,” with archives of the site showing reference to the year was removed &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20211219200808/https://www.tesla.com/cybertruck/design#payment"&gt;towards the end of December&lt;/a&gt; 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0cGlqM"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;, the delay is a result of “changing features and functions” that Tesla is making to make its electric pickup more competitive. Ford recently committed to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22865664/ford-f150-lightning-double-production-150000-annual"&gt;doubling production of its F-150 Lightning&lt;/a&gt;, which it says will start shipping in the first half of 2022; buzzy newcomer Rivian finally &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/transportation/2021/9/28/22697309/rivian-r1t-electric-truck-test-drive-off-roading-camp-tested"&gt;started shipping its first R1Ts to customers&lt;/a&gt;; while brands like Hummer and Chevy have their own electric trucks scheduled for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/20/21525290/hummer-ev-electric-truck-gmc-price-specs-range"&gt;late 2022&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/5/22863648/chevy-silverado-electric-truck-specs-price"&gt;late 2023&lt;/a&gt; releases respectively. The pickup truck segment is very popular (and profitable) n America. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="sfuXMn"&gt;&lt;q&gt;the chip shortage, pandemic, and design challenges could all have contributed to delays&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jRMyUS"&gt;Lots of factors could contribute to a delay. These include external challenges, like the ongoing pandemic and global chip shortage (which has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22423479/semiconductor-shortage-new-car-truck-prices-sales"&gt;affected all automakers&lt;/a&gt;), as well as Cybertruck-specific problems. The vehicle’s angular look is controversial, attracting awe and scorn in equal measure, but it certainly comes with unique design challenges, like the problem of creating a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/10/22828220/tesla-cybertruck-prototype-drone-shot-windshield-wiper-elon-musk"&gt;huge windshield wiper&lt;/a&gt; to cover the mammoth front window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UhuzHT"&gt;Ramping up production on the Cybertruck might also be a relatively low priority for Tesla considering its other vehicles have had fantastic years. The Model 3 became the first EV to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744481/tesla-model-3-tops-sales-charts-europe-electric-vehicles"&gt;top monthly sales charts in Europe&lt;/a&gt;, for example, while the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/2/22863751/tesla-delivered-one-million-vehicles-2021"&gt;delivered close to 1 million cars&lt;/a&gt; in 2021 — an impressive 87 percent increase on shipments in 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="einkVk"&gt;Tesla’s Cybertruck can afford to delay a little, but the company risks losing potential customers as it does. We should know more about the vehicle’s future soon, though. Tesla CEO Elon Musk &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1466800941269667841"&gt;promised to share&lt;/a&gt; a “Product roadmap update” for the Cybertruck on the next Tesla earnings call. That’s scheduled for January 26th. Not long to wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BGUJx0"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 14th, 3:18AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated with Reuters report of a delay to Q1 2023.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22881646/tesla-cybertruck-production-date-2022-removed-website"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22881646/tesla-cybertruck-production-date-2022-removed-website</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-13T21:14:54-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-13T21:14:54-05:00</updated>
    <title>PUBG’s developer is suing Apple, Google, and the developer of lucrative PUBG lookalike Free Fire</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pdM5PZpvs6i6DANsf5YzSeAubPM=/91x0:1077x657/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70386271/PUBG_CPP_2_1168x657.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;PUBG-maker Krafton filed a big lawsuit Monday.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Krafton&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="N5FcXI"&gt;&lt;em&gt;PUBG&lt;/em&gt;-maker Krafton filed a &lt;a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/21179291-krafton-lawsuit-against-sea-apple-and-google"&gt;big lawsuit Monday&lt;/a&gt;: it’s suing the developer of two mobile games that it accuses of copying &lt;em&gt;PUBG: Battlegrounds&lt;/em&gt;, the hit PC battle royale shooter, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; it’s suing Apple and Google for distributing those games on their app stores. Krafton even accuses Google of hosting &lt;em&gt;YouTube&lt;/em&gt; videos with gameplay of the two games in question, as well as “numerous posts containing a feature-length Chinese film that is nothing more than a blatantly infringing live-action dramatization of &lt;em&gt;Battlegrounds&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZEIHWr"&gt;The games Krafton takes issue with are called &lt;em&gt;Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Free Fire Max&lt;/em&gt;, offered by developer Garena. On both the App Store and Google Play, they show up as &lt;em&gt;Garena Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Garena Free Fire Max&lt;/em&gt;. Both are available for free with in-app purchases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UvEfrw"&gt;According to Krafton:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="YztuSd"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Free Fire Max&lt;/em&gt; extensively copy numerous aspects of &lt;em&gt;Battlegrounds&lt;/em&gt;, both individually and in combination, including &lt;em&gt;Battlegrounds’&lt;/em&gt; copyrighted unique game opening “air drop” feature, the game structure and play, the combination and selection of weapons, armor, and unique objects, locations, and the overall choice of color schemes, materials, and textures. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="83nhLy"&gt;Krafton alleges Garena has earned “hundreds of millions of dollars” from sales from the apps and that Apple and Google have “similarly earned a substantial amount of revenue from their distribution of &lt;em&gt;Free Fire.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YsV-icHwtJtHnpDjWYzaIzWiN54=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23167824/Screen_Shot_2022_01_13_at_5.37.39_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Krafton&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the lawsuit, Krafton compiled comparisons like this to make its case against Garena.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="GBI9HR"&gt;Krafton claims that on December 21st, it took a few actions: it asked Garena to “immediately stop its exploitation of &lt;em&gt;Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Free Fire Max,&lt;/em&gt;” which Garena apparently refused; it asked Apple and Google to stop distributing the games, which are both still available on both app stores; and it asked YouTube to remove videos featuring &lt;em&gt;Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Free Fire Max&lt;/em&gt; gameplay “that include elements that blatantly infringe &lt;em&gt;Battlegrounds&lt;/em&gt; and, separately, the infringing feature-length film,” which Krafton says YouTube hasn’t done. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FMRuVD"&gt;In case you’re wondering about that film:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JJlybn"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Update on the below:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;1. The directors said it's not a PUBG movie, despite basically being a PUBG movie.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;2. Krafton said they are considering suing given the similarities to the PUBG IP. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;3. You can watch it with English subs here: &lt;a href="https://t.co/lS1SfdTRhj"&gt;https://t.co/lS1SfdTRhj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/pBdcsqZttn"&gt;https://t.co/pBdcsqZttn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Daniel Ahmad (@ZhugeEX) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ZhugeEX/status/1427026510913880073?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="smoHXo"&gt;Krafton also notes that Garena sold a game in Singapore in 2017 that “copied” &lt;em&gt;PUBG: Battlegrounds&lt;/em&gt;. While claims regarding that were settled, there was no license agreement established, according to the lawsuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oP8pg9"&gt;I’ll admit that I hadn’t heard of &lt;em&gt;Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; before this lawsuit, but I’ve since learned that it’s quite lucrative. &lt;em&gt;Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; earned $1.1 billion in player spending in 2021, according to data that analytics firm Sensor Tower shared with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, an amount that was up 48 percent from 2020. While the total dollar amount is quite a bit less than the astonishing $2.9 billion that &lt;em&gt;PUBG Mobile&lt;/em&gt; earned in player spending last year, &lt;em&gt;PUBG Mobile’s&lt;/em&gt; figures were up only seven percent year-over-year, reports Sensor Tower. That could suggest &lt;em&gt;PUBG Mobile’s&lt;/em&gt; growth is slowing down just as &lt;em&gt;Free Fire’s&lt;/em&gt; is skyrocketing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U9ebCU"&gt;We also checked with another analytics firm, Appfigures, and while the data was different, it still suggested that &lt;em&gt;Free Fire &lt;/em&gt;is catching up. &lt;em&gt;PUBG&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Mobile&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;PUBG Mobile Lite&lt;/em&gt;, and the China- and India-specific versions of &lt;em&gt;PUBG Mobile&lt;/em&gt; earned a combined $639 million in revenue last year, according to Appfigures, while &lt;em&gt;Free Fire&lt;/em&gt; earned $414 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VFvCMO"&gt;Apple and Google didn’t immediately reply to a request for comment. Jason Golz, a spokesperson for &lt;a href="https://www.sea.com/home"&gt;Garena parent company Sea&lt;/a&gt;, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;that “Krafton’s claims are groundless.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CooJaG"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/21179291-krafton-lawsuit-against-sea-apple-and-google/?embed=1&amp;amp;responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="Krafton lawsuit against Sea, Apple, and Google (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="905" style="border: 1px solid #aaa; width: 100%; height: 800px; height: calc(100vh - 100px);" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1IFBVN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OzFu8X"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22882796/pubg-developer-krafton-suing-apple-google-garena-free-fire-max"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22882796/pubg-developer-krafton-suing-apple-google-garena-free-fire-max</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-13T19:19:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-13T19:19:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>Go read this story about Amazon workers fighting the company’s robotic HR response to COVID</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PlmcXOrziRbvvKX2Xa-PHmzPbcM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70385979/acastro_190920_1777_amazon_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MHLsd1"&gt;NBC News has published &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/ailing-amazon-workers-struggle-find-covid-tests-rcna11942"&gt;a great report&lt;/a&gt; on the struggles Amazon employees face trying to get tested for COVID after the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22584386/amazon-end-onsite-covid-19-testing-us-warehouses"&gt;stopped onsite testing last summer&lt;/a&gt;, and the HR quagmire they could end up in when reporting their results or dealing with illness-related PTO. The story is well worth a read, as it delves into Amazon’s policies and systems, and gives a voice to the employees they affect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ChnNLI"&gt;The author of the report spoke to workers who faced breakthrough cases and unexpected costs as they tried to get tested for COVID, struggling with an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632378/pandemic-ransomware-health-risks"&gt;overburdened&lt;/a&gt; and difficult-to-navigate healthcare system. “I really wish they would bring free COVID testing back to us,” says one employee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="8sy6rk"&gt;&lt;q&gt;One employee says Amazon’s systems “take the human out of human resources”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aTbwDm"&gt;The story also shows the problems they could face if they test positive, or start developing symptoms. Amazon’s workers are supposed to get 40 hours of paid leave after a positive test or exposure, according to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/7/22872866/amazon-coronavirus-changed-pto-policy-cdc-guidance-update"&gt;an updated Amazon policy&lt;/a&gt;. But many of those that spoke to NBC reported that they ran into difficulties or errors trying to get time off. One worker said that the company’s “self-service kind of H.R. system” seemed designed to “to kind of take the human out of human resources.” That system has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22745029/amazon-warehouse-hr-new-york-times"&gt;faced criticism in the past&lt;/a&gt; for everything from underpaying employees to mistakenly firing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PTdYMh"&gt;But if the system is robotic, it seems to have broken down — workers told NBC News that they found it nearly impossible to get help if they test positive, and talked about systems improperly marking them as having use paid time off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ECsC67"&gt;Trying to contact an actual human isn’t much better. One employee quoted in the report talked about how the company’s phone lines were swamped: “I could not reach a live person no matter how hard I tried.” She ended up speaking to someone in person about how she needed to get tested after finding out one of her close co-workers had COVID. A contractor that works at Amazon’s COVID-19 hotline told NBC News there were 1,700 calls on hold at one point. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vzuxZJ"&gt;The company told NBC that it was looking into reports of the time-off issues, and that it offers incentives and events to help employees get vaccinated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="imMaWp"&gt;If you’re interested in the saga of how Amazon &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465357/amazon-industrial-athlete-warehouse-worker-wellness-pamphlet"&gt;manages the health of its massive workforce&lt;/a&gt;, the report is &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/ailing-amazon-workers-struggle-find-covid-tests-rcna11942"&gt;absolutely worth a read&lt;/a&gt;. It provides some great insight into the results of Amazon’s workplace protection policies, which have sparked employee protests and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22810754/amazon-new-york-ag-reinstate-fired-worker-health-safety-covid"&gt;legal pressure&lt;/a&gt; in some cases. Even if you’re not interested in Amazon specifically, you’ll probably get something out of reading the words of the employees having to deal with these systems while also making sure Amazon’s packages keep moving.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22882707/go-read-this-amazon-workers-covid-hr-system-testing-helpline"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22882707/go-read-this-amazon-workers-covid-hr-system-testing-helpline</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-13T19:11:20-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-13T19:11:20-05:00</updated>
    <title>School employee stole 3,000 Apple iPods earmarked for Native American kids</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="iPod stock" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Cx0wmx8o8BXuRQ0XGC74E1FXdeE=/0x0:1020x680/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70385965/IMG_6762.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BaYfWr"&gt;She ran a program that used iPods to teach reading and math to underprivileged Native American schoolkids living on tribal land. Now, 46-year-old Kristy Stock of New Mexico is getting 18 months in prison for stealing 3,000 of them, which she resold for a personal gain of over $800,000 between 2013 and 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Td7egN"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-md/pr/former-new-mexico-school-district-employee-sentenced-18-months-federal-prison-stealing"&gt;That’s according&lt;/a&gt; to the US Attorney’s Office for the District of Maryland (via &lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/woman-sentenced-to-prison-for-stealing-over-3000-ipods-intended-for-native-american-students-194009681.html?src=rss"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Engadget&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), and Stock isn’t the first who’s been sentenced as part of this scheme — it all seems to center around around 36-year-old Colorado resident Saurabh Chawla, who bought up stolen electronics and other goods and resold them on eBay and Amazon. Law enforcement raided him in 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-md/pr/former-eastern-shore-resident-sentenced-more-five-years-federal-prison-conspiring-sell"&gt;according to an earlier press release&lt;/a&gt;, and he bought stolen iPads from another New Mexico school district as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FIMM60"&gt;Perhaps even more significantly, Chawla worked with a FedEx distribution center manager from Delaware named Joseph Kukta to steal packages before they made it to customers like Walmart, with Chawla paying him $1.5 million according to court documents. Those thefts included shipments of Nike sneakers and devices from Apple, Epson, Kenwood, and Magellan, among other merchandise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FZ7s0N"&gt;“Kukta selected specific packages which he believed, based on the shippers of the packages, contained high-end electronics or other merchandise of value that could be easily resold,” reads a portion of &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-md/pr/delaware-facility-supervisor-sentenced-more-three-years-federal-prison-tax-evasion-and"&gt;yet another press release&lt;/a&gt;, which continues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="5iVz8w"&gt;In 2018, Kukta began to also steal packages from FedEx trailers that were loaded for delivery to a retail Store in Rehoboth Beach, Delaware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5eT1cM"&gt;Kukta went to the FedEx facility on Sundays, holidays, or other times when employees were not at the facility, and removed the packages he previously identified from the FedEx trailers. Kukta attempted to avoid detection by turning off the lights at the facility and blocking certain surveillance cameras with cardboard boxes and other objects. Kukta loaded the stolen packages into his truck or into vehicles operated by FedEx contractors and parked at the facility, then drove the vehicles to his rented storage unit in Seaford, where he unloaded and stored the items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="V9HP0w"&gt;It’s not clear if Stock, the school district employee, took iPods away from Native American schoolkids who needed them, or simply ones that went unused. One court document states that the iPods were purchased in bulk with federal grant money, and the school district stored unused ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g1955x"&gt;In November 2018, Stock allegedly told Chawla that she would check “the school’s iPod inventory and let you know what I can get headed your way” for “Black Friday,” but was apparently only able to steal 30 that time, saying that she had “to keep some on hand through year end for the students.” I suppose that’s nice of her?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/A1dQx9iTk78mMyE-867eG_geZ14=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23167554/Clipboard01.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="RGHx5f"&gt;Chawla was sentenced to 66 months in prison; Kukta got 42 months; James Bender of Maryland, who let Chawla use his eBay and PayPal accounts to sell the stolen goods, was sentenced to a year and a day. Chawla also agreed to forfeit at least $3.5 million worth of assets, with the court seizing seven bank accounts, a 2013 Tesla Model S, and forcing him to sell &lt;a href="https://www.zillow.com/homedetails/25835-E-Dry-Creek-Pl-Aurora-CO-80016/87622999_zpid/"&gt;a two-story, five-bedroom home in Aurora, Colorado&lt;/a&gt; that he purchased with fraud money. Kukta will pay $1.1 million and forfeit an additional $1.88 million in assets, &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-md/pr/delaware-facility-supervisor-sentenced-more-three-years-federal-prison-tax-evasion-and"&gt;according to the DA’s office&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oktVmL"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="96QZy5"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HLlTMe"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22882758/ipod-theft-kristy-stock-native-american-students-new-mexico-school-district"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22882758/ipod-theft-kristy-stock-native-american-students-new-mexico-school-district</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-13T19:05:14-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-13T19:05:14-05:00</updated>
    <title>Virgin Orbit launches first satellite mission after SPAC merger</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rp1PM_CUIxFOiXuj8IasSTUJHAI=/179x0:2030x1234/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70385949/Virgin_Orbit_88.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Virgin Orbit’s Cosmic Girl and LauncherOne just after rocket separation on a previous flight&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Virgin Orbit&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vsuzvK"&gt;This afternoon, small satellite launcher Virgin Orbit successfully lofted seven tiny satellites into orbit around Earth, marking the third successful mission for the Virgin Galactic spinoff company. The payloads consisted of &lt;a href="https://virginorbit.com/above-the-clouds/"&gt;various research satellites&lt;/a&gt; for the Department of Defense, along with three small satellites from companies SatRevolution and Spire Global.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hQU1fJ"&gt;The launch comes less than a week after Virgin Orbit’s stock began publicly trading for the first time on the New York Stock Exchange. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22637711/richard-branson-virgin-orbit-public-spac-satellite-launch"&gt;Virgin Orbit announced in August its plan to go public&lt;/a&gt; through a merger with a special purpose acquisition company, or SPAC, making it one of three small rocket launch companies to follow the trend in 2021. On Friday, January 7th, Virgin Orbit CEO Dan Hart rang the Nasdaq opening bell, while the company put a model of its primary rocket, LauncherOne, on display in New York City’s Times Square.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="J3fmbE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;less than a week after Virgin Orbit’s stock began publicly trading for the first time&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ON7DJ2"&gt;Virgin Orbit is one of many rocket companies that have cropped up in the last few decades, aimed at specifically launching small- to medium-sized satellites into orbit. However, the company’s approach to getting these satellites into space is a bit unique compared to its competitors. Instead of launching vertically from the ground, Virgin Orbit’s LauncherOne rocket is designed to take off from underneath the wing of a carrier aircraft, a refurbished Boeing 747 called Cosmic Girl. The plane is meant to take LauncherOne up to an altitude of approximately 35,000 feet, where the rocket is then released. In mid-air, LauncherOne ignites its main engine and propels its payloads the rest of the way into Earth’s orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SfHGCZ"&gt;Today’s flight, called “Above the Clouds,” began at 4:39PM ET, when Cosmic Girl took off from a runway at the Mojave Air and Space Port in California, where Virgin Orbit has a testing facility. The plane flew out west over the Pacific Ocean, where LauncherOne was released at 5:52PM ET. Flying the plane for this mission was Virgin Orbit’s pilot, Eric Bippert. He was accompanied in the cockpit by Matthew Stannard, or Stanny, a test pilot for the Royal Air Force in the United Kingdom who has been seconded to Virgin Orbit. Stanny was &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-59972909"&gt;the one to initiate LauncherOne’s release&lt;/a&gt; from underneath Cosmic Girl’s wing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z4phaI"&gt;Virgin Orbit’s launch occurred on the same day as &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SpaceX/status/1481699225675067395?s=20"&gt;SpaceX’s second launch of the year&lt;/a&gt;, which also sent a crop of small satellites into orbit on the company’s Falcon 9 rocket out of Cape Canaveral, Florida. SpaceX’s launch, called Transporter-3, hoisted a whopping 105 small satellites into orbit, deploying them one by one into space. Such a flight is often referred to as a rocket rideshare, and it’s another option for small satellite manufacturers to get their payloads into space. Since SpaceX’s Falcon 9 has a bigger capacity than a smaller rocket like LauncherOne, it can carry a bunch of small satellites at once into space, a bit like a cosmic carpool. SpaceX aims to launch at least three dedicated rocket rideshares a year through its Smallsat Rideshare Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="JBOPgj"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Today’s flight was called “Above the Clouds”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="h1yZWy"&gt;Rocket rideshares have their downsides, though. For one thing, small satellite manufacturers often need to wait until enough satellites are packed onto one rocket in order to launch. There are also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/2/18277344/space-situational-awareness-air-force-tracking-sso-a-spaceflight-cubesats"&gt;some logistical issues that can come with launching so many satellites at once&lt;/a&gt;. Dedicated small launch providers like Virgin Orbit can tailor their missions to just a few customers and can, in theory, provide a quicker route to the launchpad. In fact, Virgin Orbit claims that Spire’s satellite was added relatively last minute to today’s flight. “In just under two weeks, we got them on board,” Tony Gingiss, Virgin Orbit’s COO, said during a press conference ahead of the launch. “Within 24 hours of signing the contract, we already had them integrated into the fairing” — the nosecone on top of the rocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DykOGc"&gt;Of course, Virgin Orbit will need to up its launch cadence in order to offer a rapid path to space for customers. So far, the company is averaging about six months between launches. But Virgin Orbit CEO Dan Hart says the company is targeting six launches this year, which would double the launch cadence. Two of those launches are supposed to take place out of Spaceport Cornwall in the UK, established at the Cornwall Airport Newquay. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22880143/virgin-orbit-launcherone-747-cosmic-girl-air-launch-small-satellites"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22880143/virgin-orbit-launcherone-747-cosmic-girl-air-launch-small-satellites</id>
    <author>
      <name>Loren Grush</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-13T19:04:19-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-13T19:04:19-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here are some must-have accessories for your new Xbox Series X or Series S</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oDk3TIA9WbSACQAInKHXHTTfWXg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67755488/vpavic_4275_20201030_0050.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WOeZmy"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21548987/xbox-series-x-review"&gt;Xbox Series X&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549021/xbox-series-s-review"&gt;Series S&lt;/a&gt; are excellent next-gen machines, yet, no matter how good they are, there will always be room for improvement. Accessories like the Elite Series 2 Controller and the Xbox Stereo Headset can help you get the most of your new console, while others, like Seagate’s Storage Expansion Cards, will help ensure you have ample storage space for years to come. Below, we’ve listed some of the best accessories available for the Series X / S, some of which are even on sale at most major retailers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="2TZCpi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best wired or wireless gaming headsets to buy","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21549510/best-gaming-headset-wired-wireless-features-specs-price-sound-microphone-test-buy"},{"title":"8 great games for your new Xbox","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22825913/xbox-series-x-s-best-games-microsoft-2021"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="ejIGTg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9562380" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="Lgg36p"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"20 years of Xbox: a visual history","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22783104/20-years-of-xbox-visual-history-360-one-x-s-series-the-duke"},{"title":"Xbox’s 20th Anniversary museum is a metaverse full of achievements and mistakes","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22798429/xbox-museum-20th-anniversary-stats-achievements"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="ryrlag"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10784780" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="PEwWwc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10420028" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="PtU3h7"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10803294" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="Hdkf4f"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10805421" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="72J8Ar"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9546609" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="izETtY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9562459" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="Oiksir"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9532770" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="PAAIYR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10973167"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="FKvnpc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10805430" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ZJwyEe"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10839547" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="eUo4Mk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Yh7lyN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BOMZFs"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Inc6d"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lsARB1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21550830/xbox-series-x-s-wireless-controller-ssd-hard-drive-accessories"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21550830/xbox-series-x-s-wireless-controller-ssd-hard-drive-accessories</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-13T18:35:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-13T18:35:24-05:00</updated>
    <title>Paramount Plus cancels 60 Minutes Plus streaming series after one season</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="In this photo illustration, Paramount+ (Paramount Plus) logo..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KAi9IRG7GILwAT-ySI78F1IYaDo=/0x0:3888x2592/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70385782/1233727583.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Pavlo Gonchar/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rgNPY2"&gt;ViacomCBS has canceled &lt;em&gt;60 Minutes Plus&lt;/em&gt; at its tentpole streaming service Paramount Plus, axing a title that was touted as one of the service’s premium exclusives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jdzOfS"&gt;The company confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that it will no longer produce &lt;em&gt;60 Minutes Plus&lt;/em&gt;, a spinoff of its award-winning broadcast news magazine &lt;em&gt;60 Minutes&lt;/em&gt;. The series had only streamed one, 30-episode season as of the cancellation announcement, which was shared with staffers Thursday morning, &lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2022/tv/news/60-minutes-streaming-spinoff-canceled-paramount-plus-1235153381/"&gt;earlier reported&lt;/a&gt;, citing sources familiar with the situation. In a statement, the company said that the content the series produced will remain on Paramount Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="P68h8q"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The excellent work that has been done by the 60+ team will continue to be on Paramount+.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ymxMWq"&gt;“We are proud of the team at 60 Minutes+ and of the stories they produced, which informed the audience about some of the most important issues of our time,” the company said in a statement shared with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Their journalism was recognized with several awards, including a Gracie, National Headliner and NABJ Salute to Excellence Award. The excellent work that has been done by the 60+ team will continue to be on Paramount+.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k6cwgq"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt; reported that news — a key component of the Paramount Plus content pitch — will remain core to the service’s programming lineup. The company is reportedly planning to help &lt;em&gt;60 Minutes Plus&lt;/em&gt; employees find other roles within the organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Oh4G0r"&gt;The series kicked off in March of last year with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22300993/paramount-plus-streaming-wars-netflix-disney-launch-date-price"&gt;rebrand of Paramount Plus&lt;/a&gt; from its CBS All Access streaming predecessor. The series tackled topics as wide-ranging as the Capitol riot and the metaverse, and episodes ran anywhere from 15 minutes to over 20 minutes. The series was hosted by correspondents Seth Doane, Wesley Lowery, Enrique Acevedo, and Laurie Segall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="djtZDN"&gt;Currently, &lt;em&gt;60 Minutes&lt;/em&gt; is available pretty much everywhere — including through podcasts, YouTube, Facebook, and its website — and its webcast 60MinutesOvertime.com gives viewers access to behind-the-scenes video and archival programming. The company did not share comments on its decision to kill the program’s standalone streaming sibling, &lt;em&gt;60 Minutes Plus&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22882810/paramount-plus-streaming-60-minutes-plus-one-season"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22882810/paramount-plus-streaming-60-minutes-plus-one-season</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-13T17:49:53-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-13T17:49:53-05:00</updated>
    <title>Valve says the Steam Deck is on track to ship by the end of February</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ETpTiJuB49MY5PTDMHd-z1S9s2w=/0x0:1620x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70385660/steam_deck_hades.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EKtGPY"&gt;In November, Valve gave everyone some bad news, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774888/steam-deck-delayed-two-months-february-2022-launch-shipping"&gt;revealing a two-month delay for the Steam Deck&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s starting off 2022 on a better note. &lt;a href="https://steamcommunity.com/games/1675180/announcements/detail/3122683923029138793"&gt;In its latest update&lt;/a&gt;, the company says it “looks like” Steam Deck shipments will start by the end of February. Of course, we’re in a pandemic, and things can always change, but the preorder windows for &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; staffers are holding steady with their original projections — you can check your status &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/steamdeck"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;div id="K30FOB"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Happy January! We have a small update for you today -  tl;dr - we're still on track to ship in February.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Check it out here: &lt;a href="https://t.co/pQXC101JCV"&gt;https://t.co/pQXC101JCV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Steam Deck (@OnDeck) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OnDeck/status/1481754241182044160?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 13, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JlAaW4"&gt;Just as important as the hardware, however, is the games that you’ll try to play on the thing. Valve apparently shipped out “hundreds” of Steam Deck units to developers last month so that they can make sure their PC games are fully compatible with its software environment and AMD-powered hardware. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Ed9Gy"&gt;Testing is required to get a green&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733408/steam-deck-compatibility-verified-pc-gaming-valve"&gt; “verified” checkmark in Steam&lt;/a&gt;, and we’ve already seen posts on social media showing the makers of the most popular titles trying their games out on the Steam Deck. The only thing we still don’t have, oddly, is a price for or picture of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22779252/steam-deck-things-we-learned-from-valve-developer-summit"&gt;Steam Deck dock&lt;/a&gt; that’s supposed to help you put those games on the big screen. Hopefully, we’ll get a look at that, and some time with Valve’s latest hardware project, in the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="THvShO"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Steam Deck: a Switch-like portable gaming PC|103274" data-volume-uuid="2d2697872" data-volume-id="103274" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-637" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22882686/steam-deck-delays-valve-pc-gaming-handheld"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22882686/steam-deck-delays-valve-pc-gaming-handheld</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-13T17:41:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-13T17:41:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>Congress subpoenas Meta, Alphabet, Twitter, and Reddit over January 6th Capitol attack</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Trump Supporters Hold “Stop The Steal” Rally In DC Amid Ratification Of Presidential Election" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4U3Bc0r4dqgPNJTVDOVrwIY0RnE=/0x2:8192x5463/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70385640/1230728339.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Brent Stirton/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4SEYE3"&gt;&lt;a href="https://january6th.house.gov/news/press-releases/select-committee-subpoenas-social-media-companies-records-related-january-6th"&gt;Congress has sent subpoenas&lt;/a&gt; demanding information from Meta (formerly Facebook), Twitter, Reddit, and Alphabet concerning the January 6th, 2021 attack on the US Capitol. The House of Representatives Select Committee that’s investigating the attack wants each company to disclose moderation policy details and other information that could illuminate how participants organized their efforts or spread conspiracy theories about the 2020 presidential election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nKePt2"&gt;The committee &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22652392/google-facebook-microsoft-january-6-data-request"&gt;requested records&lt;/a&gt; from dozens of companies on a voluntary basis last year, but it says the response from the aforementioned four has been “inadequate” so far. “Two key questions for the Select Committee are how the spread of misinformation and violent extremism contributed to the violent attack on our democracy, and what steps — if any — social media companies took to prevent their platforms from being breeding grounds for radicalizing people to violence. It’s disappointing that after months of engagement, we still do not have the documents and information necessary to answer those basic questions,” said committee chairman Bennie Thompson (D-MS) in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="vZ5mM5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“After months of engagement, we still do not have the documents and information necessary”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SfpRUJ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://january6th.house.gov/sites/democrats.january6th.house.gov/files/2022-1-13.BGT%20Letter%20to%20Alphabet%20-%20Cover%20Letter%20and%20Schedule_Redacted.pdf"&gt;Alphabet’s subpoena letter&lt;/a&gt; asks for information about YouTube, which hosted livestreams of the attack but also suspended former President Donald Trump for inciting violence during it. It claims Alphabet has “significant undisclosed information” concerning how it developed and reviewed its moderation and demonetization rules, as well as details about how it developed policies around false election claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CUlHvr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://january6th.house.gov/sites/democrats.january6th.house.gov/files/2022-1-13.BGT%20Letter%20to%20Twitter%20-%20Cover%20Letter%20and%20Schedule_Redacted.pdf"&gt;Twitter’s letter&lt;/a&gt; says the company hasn’t released details of warnings it received about extremists organizing on its platform or “internal company analyses of misinformation, disinformation, and malinformation” relating to the election. It’s also supposed to deliver more information about its decision to suspend Trump’s account on January 8th. Twitter declined to comment on the subpoena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QURmYX"&gt;&lt;a href="https://january6th.house.gov/sites/democrats.january6th.house.gov/files/2022-1-13.BGT%20Letter%20to%20Zuckerberg%20re%20Meta%20Document%20Production%20-%20Cover%20Letter%20and%20Schedule_Redacted.pdf"&gt;Meta is supposed to&lt;/a&gt; produce documents about its decision to disband a team that dealt with election misinformation as well as “critical internal and external analyses conducted by the company regarding misinformation, disinformation, and malinformation relating to the 2020 election, efforts to challenge or overturn the election, and the use of Meta by domestic violent extremists to affect the 2020 election.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CmX6Oi"&gt;Reddit, which has by far the smallest of the platforms involved, &lt;a href="https://january6th.house.gov/sites/democrats.january6th.house.gov/files/2022-1-13.BGT%20Letter%20to%20Reddit%20-%20Cover%20Letter%20and%20Schedule_Redacted.pdf"&gt;has been asked&lt;/a&gt; to commit to a “thorough review of its records” that could reveal details about whether it played a role in the attack. “We received the subpoena and will continue to work with the committee on their requests,” Reddit said in a statement sent to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; by Sandra Chu.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22882665/congress-subpoena-meta-alphabet-twitter-reddit-january-6-capitol-attack-committee"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22882665/congress-subpoena-meta-alphabet-twitter-reddit-january-6-capitol-attack-committee</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
