<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-11T18:44:15-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-11T18:44:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-11T18:44:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook’s ‘culture fit’ is the focus of a discrimination complaint, report says</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZO9S4xs2UARQy9XgLuVb-1ibRyw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68952281/acastro_180828_1777_facebook_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="X5Kywb"&gt;A Black woman who interviewed at Facebook last year says she was told the company was “looking for a culture fit” before being rejected, &lt;a href="https://theintercept.com/2021/03/11/facebook-hiring-racism-eeoc/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/a&gt; She’s now one of four people who’ve recently complained to the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) about allegedly racist hiring and promotion practices at the tech giant. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="002qf0"&gt;The woman says she was well-suited to the managerial position on Facebook’s Global Impact Partnerships team due to her work experience and relevant doctoral degree, &lt;em&gt;The Intercept &lt;/em&gt;reports. Yet she alleged that during in-person meetings, she “sensed that the interviewers were not prioritizing her interviews because all of the interviews seemed rushed after making her wait for several hours.” &lt;em&gt;The Intercept &lt;/em&gt;agreed not to use the woman’s real name as a condition of receiving the complaint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jWIcI7"&gt;All the interviewers were white,&lt;em&gt; The Intercept&lt;/em&gt; reports. Only 3.9 percent of Facebook’s US workforce is Black, &lt;a href="https://diversity.fb.com/read-report/"&gt;according to a recent diversity report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HzlsJy"&gt;The news comes on the heels of an EEOC investigation into allegations of racial bias in Facebook’s hiring and promotion processes. The probe has been categorized as “systemic,” meaning the agency “suspects” these policies “may be contributing to widespread discrimination,” &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-facebook-workers-exclusive/exclusive-u-s-agency-probes-facebook-for-systemic-racial-bias-in-hiring-promotions-idUSKBN2AY006"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rNzk6d"&gt;The woman also alleged that one Facebook staffer told her “There’s no doubt you can do the job, but we’re really looking for a culture fit.” The term is widely used in the tech industry to refer to job applicants who staffers would want to have a beer with. But experts say it’s a “misguided hiring strategy” that can contribute to a lack of diversity, “since very often the people we enjoy hanging out with have backgrounds much like our own,” &lt;a href="https://hbr.org/2018/01/how-to-hire"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Harvard Business Review&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BcrBmB"&gt;The complaint alleges that the company’s discrimination against Black applicants is partly predicated on its “strong consideration of ‘culture fit’ in hiring, without providing sufficient objective guidance to managers and other employees on how to determine which applicants and employees will be a good ‘culture fit’ at Facebook,” &lt;em&gt;The Intercept &lt;/em&gt;reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EfCb7B"&gt;Facebook did not immediately respond to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B4SObh"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22326097/facebook-hiring-discrimination-black-applicants-culture-fit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22326097/facebook-hiring-discrimination-black-applicants-culture-fit</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-11T18:26:03-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-11T18:26:03-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft says the latest Xbox Series X update fixes controller disconnect issues</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MfJ7O76VTZRgrZIjR96rgiRN8VI=/9x0:2631x1748/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68952172/twarren_xboxseriesxcontroller_VLS_3616_2_4.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Tom Warren / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="x4lfJQ"&gt;Microsoft released a &lt;a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2021/03/09/march-xbox-update-details/"&gt;new Xbox update&lt;/a&gt; earlier this week that brings toggles for Auto HDR and FPS Boost and improvements to better support the new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22285247/microsoft-xbox-wireless-headset-release-date-price-features"&gt;Xbox Wireless Headset&lt;/a&gt;. But there was another big feature that wasn’t mentioned in the official release notes: the update also fixes “many” of the Xbox Series X controller disconnect issues that have cropped up, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jronald/status/1369696666278711298"&gt;according to the Xbox team’s Jason Ronald&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="eKXYNw"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Lots of Xbox news this week, but in case you missed it we released our March Xbox System Update yesterday. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In addition to the new features, this release also fixes many of the controller disconnects players have reported.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Keep the feedback coming.&lt;a href="https://t.co/bltTsL6Lty"&gt;https://t.co/bltTsL6Lty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Jason Ronald (@jronald) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jronald/status/1369696666278711298?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Iwj24H"&gt;Players began reporting disconnect issues with the controllers just days after the console’s launch, and you can see some of those reports in this &lt;a href="https://answers.microsoft.com/en-us/xbox/forum/xba_console/xbox-series-x-controller-keeps-disconnecting/16d9f462-57c0-4b6c-93fd-b03711e632ee?page=1"&gt;89-page thread on Microsoft’s support forums&lt;/a&gt;. In January, however, Microsoft acknowledged that it was aware of the issues and said that fixes were coming “in a future update” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22215289/microsoft-xbox-series-x-controller-disconnect-update"&gt;in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CE9M9E"&gt;We haven’t tested the new update ourselves to see if it fixes issues that people have seen. But if you have been experiencing controller disconnects, it sounds like the new update could address them for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="nuWA7u"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Microsoft commits to fix Xbox Series X controller disconnects in a future update","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22215289/microsoft-xbox-series-x-controller-disconnect-update"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22326224/microsoft-xbox-series-x-controller-disconnect-issues-march-update"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22326224/microsoft-xbox-series-x-controller-disconnect-issues-march-update</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-11T18:10:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-11T18:10:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>The latest Windows 10 update could cause your printer to crash your PC</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Asus Zenbook Flip in tent mode." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dk7W1R8uGR4Ac9sRble8LgL2MQ0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68952061/mchin_181225_4219_0006.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Mh23p0"&gt;The latest Windows update has been causing problems for some printer owners, according to a report from &lt;a href="https://www.windowslatest.com/2021/03/10/windows-10-kb5000802-march-update-is-crashing-pcs-with-bsod/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Windows Latest&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;(via &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/latest-windows-10-update-is-causing-some-printers-to-cr-1846456254"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;Users are reporting that they’re getting a blue screen when they try to open the print dialogue from Notepad, Office, or other programs. (You know that annoyingly ambiguous error message that’s like “Your PC ran into a problem and needs to restart”? It’s that one.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QZVBOV"&gt;Microsoft is aware that attempting to print in certain circumstances can blue screen your PC, and has listed the bug on the Windows 10 &lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/topic/march-9-2021-kb5000802-os-builds-19041-867-and-19042-867-63552d64-fe44-4132-8813-ef56d3626e14"&gt;Support page&lt;/a&gt;. The company doesn’t appear to have issued a fix at this time. “We are presently investigating and will provide an update when more information is available,” that website currently reads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UThk2e"&gt;It’s not clear how widespread the issue is, but &lt;em&gt;Windows Latest&lt;/em&gt; says it has “seen numerous reports of error popping up here and there.” The bug appears to impact multiple printer brands including Kyocera, Ricoh, and Zebra. “Have had at least 20 confirmed cases from 4 different clients already and it’s only been an hour into the day,” one reader told the publication. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="pN63MF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We’ve seen numerous reports of error popping up here and there”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kp6OBC"&gt;Windows users are complaining across Reddit as well. “This issue was confirmed across four computers,” said &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/sysadmin/comments/m1jkuz/kyocera_drivers_patch_tuesday_bsod/"&gt;one Reddit user&lt;/a&gt;. “We just got 3 calls from clients all experiencing this same issue,” another commenter &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/sysadmin/comments/m1jkuz/kyocera_drivers_patch_tuesday_bsod/gqgi31f?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Kyocera Corp. Founder Kazuo Inamori Interview" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/g9XgY_cO-S2kVrbw5rppfGf8nDQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363896/495767146.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LqvQNT"&gt;If you’re encountering this problem, the easiest fix is to roll back the latest Windows update. To do this, open Settings &amp;gt; Update &amp;amp; Security &amp;gt; Windows Update &amp;gt; View Update History &amp;gt; Uninstall Updates &amp;gt; Uninstall, or remove the patch manually in Command Prompt. Some Reddit users confirmed that this fixed their problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PQEGOd"&gt;A user claiming to be a Microsoft employee has also &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/sysadmin/comments/m1jkuz/kyocera_drivers_patch_tuesday_bsod/gqj91b3/"&gt;posted two temporary workarounds&lt;/a&gt; on Reddit, which commenters have confirmed to work. You can enable direct printing in the Command Prompt, or you can use the Compatibility Administrator tool to apply a fix, depending on the application you’re running. Both processes are complicated, so your best bet is to go read that Reddit comment closely if you want to try them. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22326083/windows-10-security-update-bug-printer-crash-kyocera-ricoh-zebra-microsoft"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22326083/windows-10-security-update-bug-printer-crash-kyocera-ricoh-zebra-microsoft</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-11T17:51:18-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-11T17:51:18-05:00</updated>
    <title>T-Mobile’s long-promised 5G home broadband will launch later this month</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xSH8vXRo5Bmuw4wCC_DHyAtOB6U=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68951865/acastro_191108_1777_t-mobile_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;T-Mobile hopes to expand the service to 7 to 8 million customers in the next five years | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="d8ZTO1"&gt;At an analyst event on Thursday, T-Mobile revealed that its long-awaited 5G home broadband service will launch later this month, which it confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge.&lt;/em&gt; A 4G version of the service is currently in pilot testing with 100,000 households. By the end of the year, T-Mobile says it hopes to extend the service to 7–8 million customers within five years. There’s no confirmed launch date for the service yet, but we’ll know more later this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KCrFgl"&gt;The company has been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/7/18254853/tmobile-sprint-merger-5g-home-internet-service-promises"&gt;promising 5G-based wireless broadband&lt;/a&gt; since before its acquisition of Sprint, saying that the merger would make it possible to offer service that would challenge the dominant cable companies. Before the deal was approved, T-Mobile went ahead and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/21/18275640/tmobile-lte-wireless-home-internet-service-pilot-launch"&gt;started testing out the service&lt;/a&gt; with a limited group of customers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0z9D8s"&gt;The self-styled Uncarrier isn’t the only one testing the waters of fixed wireless internet. Verizon &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.verizon.com%2Fabout%2Fnews%2Fc-band-verizon-expands-5g-home-internet&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F11%2F22325833%2Ft-mobile-5g-home-broadband-internet-launch" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;just expanded&lt;/a&gt; its 5G home internet service to ten more cities, though in testing last year &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/news/for-now-verizons-5g-home-internet-service-offers-very-little-coverage"&gt;&lt;em&gt;PCMag&lt;/em&gt; found&lt;/a&gt; that actual availability in the cities Verizon serves is scarce. If nothing else, both companies seem plenty motivated to get 5G home internet up and running. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22325833/t-mobile-5g-home-broadband-internet-launch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22325833/t-mobile-5g-home-broadband-internet-launch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-11T17:50:08-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-11T17:50:08-05:00</updated>
    <title>Go listen to Spotify’s podcast about itself that ignores the existence of iTunes</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GIvgSm29-LauAgtAIsyOvUcNsoQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68951861/mdoying_180308_1437_0082still.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Michele Doying / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="L1vT9P"&gt;Spotify is &lt;a href="https://newsroom.spotify.com/2021-03-11/introducing-the-new-miniseries-spotify-a-product-story/"&gt;making a podcast about its own history&lt;/a&gt;, and the first two episodes are well worth a listen for the details on the jump from piracy to streaming, how the company decided to build its business, and the technical details of how it did so. There are also some fun interviews included, with the podcast featuring stories from Sean Parker, inventor of Napster, and Lars Ulrich of Metallica.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RjakdV"&gt;In the podcast, the Spotify founders discuss the history of piracy in Spotify’s home country, Sweden, to give context about its development environment. It goes into the existence of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pirate_Party_(Sweden)"&gt;Sweden’s Pirate Party&lt;/a&gt;, an actual political party that once held several seats in the country’s parliament. The founders also discuss how they wanted to take the ease of pirating music but make it legitimate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hto6JX"&gt;If talk about being easier than piracy sounds familiar, it’s probably because that was part of the pitch for the &lt;a href="https://www.theledger.com/news/20130424/happy-anniversary-itunes-celebrates-a-decade-faces-new-challenges"&gt;iTunes Music Store, too&lt;/a&gt;. It seems, for the most part, that iTunes and the iPod are pretty much completely ignored. The podcast presents music distribution as going from CD stores to Napster to Spotify. Apple and Spotify &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/17/18268861/spotify-apple-antitrust-fight-latest-updates-news"&gt;aren’t the best of friends&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s honestly somewhat hilarious to hear how the story completely ignores the fact that people could, in fact, buy digital music (an option that was around even before Spotify launched).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CHyG4f"&gt;Despite the lack of objectivity about the history of digital music, the technical depth alone makes it well worth a listen. The second episode (labeled 01) gets into how Spotify used the same peer-to-peer tech used by the pirates to build its legitimate music streaming service and how its approach blew people's minds at the time. Even though the story leaves some pretty important parts out, &lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/3L9tzrt0CthF6hNkxYIeSB"&gt;it’s still worth a listen&lt;/a&gt; to hear the origins of the popular music (and, obviously, podcasting) service. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22325780/spotify-podcast-a-product-story-streaming-music-history-itunes"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22325780/spotify-podcast-a-product-story-streaming-music-history-itunes</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-11T17:35:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-11T17:35:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Pakistan is again banning TikTok, this time for ‘peddling vulgarity’ </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ufLIkvf3ZyakkULTvro5-1pWqgU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68951763/acastro_200803_1777_tikTok_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hGrOzk"&gt;Pakistan has banned TikTok yet again, citing objectionable content on the shortform video app. This is the second time the ByteDance platform has been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/9/21509817/tiktok-pakistan-ban-immoral-indecent-content"&gt;banned in Pakistan&lt;/a&gt;, following a brief 10-day shutdown in October of last year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6ONMcK"&gt;Last fall, TikTok was banned for hosting “immoral” and “indecent” videos, but the company was able to assure the Pakistani government that videos would be moderated “in accordance with societal norms and the laws of Pakistan,” and the app &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/19/21523094/pakistan-tiktok-ban-lifted-after-10-days"&gt;resumed operations&lt;/a&gt; a week and a half later. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kgMTQd"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;In respectful compliance to the orders of the Peshawar High Court, PTA has issued directions to the service providers to immediately block access to the TikTok App. During the hearing of a case today, the PHC has ordered for the blocking of App.&lt;/p&gt;— PTA (@PTAofficialpk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PTAofficialpk/status/1370044117678444544?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="s4pyxu"&gt;The company has tens of millions of users in Pakistan, and yet a high court in the city of Peshawar ordered the government’s telecom regulatory body, the Pakistan Telecommunications Authority, to ban the app in order to comply. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qOV0rz"&gt;“In respectful compliance to the orders of the Peshawar High Court, PTA has issued directions to the service providers to immediately block access to the TikTok App,” reads the announcement. “During the hearing of a case today, the PHC has ordered for the blocking of App.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rnTr1J"&gt;It’s not entirely clear why TikTok’s legality in Pakistan is again in question and whether any one video or trend on the app is the culprit. Yet, &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2021/3/11/pakistani-court-orders-tik-tok-banned-over-obscene"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Al Jazeera&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that complaints were made from Peshawar High Court Chief Justice Qaiser Rashid Khan, who accused TikTok of hosting content “unacceptable for Pakistani society.” &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/90df50e4-7fd9-4def-86e3-db256882140d"&gt;According to the &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Khan said the platform engaged in “peddling vulgarity” and ordered the ban take effect immediately during a hearing on Thursday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="n1gtY3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;This is the second ban for TikTok in Pakistani in the last year&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9vyZs6"&gt;“TikTok is built upon the foundation of creative expression, with strong safeguards in place to keep inappropriate content off the platform,” TikTok said in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “In Pakistan we have grown our local-language moderation team, and have mechanisms to report and remove content in violation of our community guidelines. We look forward to continuing to serve the millions of TikTok users and creators in Pakistan who have found a home for creativity and fun.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3wCZ8I"&gt;TikTok has endured a number of contentious government bans and other restrictions around the world — most notably, with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22262940/tiktok-leaves-india-ban-app-china-government-security-privacy"&gt;countrywide ban in India since last summer&lt;/a&gt; and the Trump administration’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/7/22160239/tiktok-ban-judge-trump-administration-us-commerce-department"&gt;hamfisted attempt&lt;/a&gt; to force the company to partner with a US tech firm to assuage fears of Chinese government influence over the platform. (That deal, with cloud giant Oracle, is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276090/tiktok-oracle-deal-biden-trump-ban-china-bytedance-white-house"&gt;apparently on life support&lt;/a&gt; under President Joe Biden.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3OJcgI"&gt;The app has faced its most serious opposition in and around Southeast Asia, where governments have extended existing control over the media to the video-centric social network using laws and regulations around what constitutes obscene or immoral content. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22326055/pakistan-bans-tiktok-again-immoral-indecent-videos"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22326055/pakistan-bans-tiktok-again-immoral-indecent-videos</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-11T17:10:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-11T17:10:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>Gogo’s 5G network launch has stalled due to the chip shortage</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Gogo in-flight internet STOCK" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lHETWhF_mED3GtwchqDhx2yO6nE=/0x1:1020x681/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68951586/gogo-internet-logo-stock1_1020.1419980305.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Gogo in-flight internet STOCK&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="t5p29N"&gt;Gogo will be delaying &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/29/18644707/gogo-5g-network-planes-developing-in-flight"&gt;the rollout of its 5G network&lt;/a&gt;, pushing it back from 2021 to 2022. &lt;a href="https://www.lightreading.com/5g/gogo-delays-5g-launch-due-to-chipset-shortages/d/d-id/768025"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;LightReading&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the global chip shortage is to blame for the delay, though Gogo didn’t provide any direct details about how the shortage was setting it back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TZONve"&gt;Gogo isn’t the only one feeling the sting of the global chip shortage: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227040/nvidia-amd-gpu-shortage-rtx-3080-3070-3060-ti-3090-rx-6800-xt"&gt;graphics cards&lt;/a&gt;, CPUs, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/6/22155611/price-ps5-xbox-series-x-nvidia-rtx-3080-3070-3090-3060-amd-rx-6800-xt-scalpers-ebay"&gt;game consoles&lt;/a&gt; have become infamous for being in short supply, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266483/ford-f150-production-slowdown-semiconductor-chip-shortage"&gt;car manufacturers are having to slow down production lines&lt;/a&gt; because of the supply constraint. The situation has gotten to the point where President Joe Biden &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22298376/biden-sign-semiconductor-shortage-executive-order-apple-amd-playstation"&gt;has signed an executive order&lt;/a&gt; calling for a review of the chip supply chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kBl0iq"&gt;The company, known for providing in-flight Wi-Fi, had a difficult 2020: it did &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/31/21350251/gogo-layoffs-furloughs-airlines-covid-19-pandemic"&gt;several rounds of layoffs&lt;/a&gt;, pay cuts, and furloughs, as people stopped taking flights. The company also ended up selling its commercial in-flight Wi-Fi business &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/1/21410368/gogo-sells-inflight-internet-business-intelsat-bankrupt"&gt;to a bankrupt satellite provider&lt;/a&gt;, which makes it slightly unclear as to what the company plans to do with its 5G network when it eventually gets it rolled out. The company &lt;a href="https://business.gogoair.com/solutions/midsize-heavy-jet/"&gt;still provides internet and in-flight entertainment&lt;/a&gt; for smaller, more business-oriented planes, so it’s possible it’ll use the network to improve that service. Gogo wasn’t immediately available to comment on its future plans for the network. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CZ3w42"&gt;The 5G network, when Gogo gets it rolled out, will be &lt;a href="https://www.lightreading.com/mobile/5g/gogo-goes-all-american-for-5g-network/d/d-id/755064"&gt;an upgrade to the company’s existing 3G cellular towers&lt;/a&gt;. Gogo gave up on its plans of upgrading the network to 4G with equipment from ZTE after the US government basically &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/18/17477170/zte-ban-senate-vote-reinstate"&gt;shut down the network equipment provider with a ban&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22325999/gogo-5g-network-delay-chip-shortage"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22325999/gogo-5g-network-delay-chip-shortage</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-11T16:55:31-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-11T16:55:31-05:00</updated>
    <title>A Game Boy Advance might be the best way to watch Tenet, actually</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/16DYdN1siI2AgwHGsj1F-hmm-N8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68951371/tenetgba.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/BobWulff/status/1370042833608994817/photo/2" target="_blank"&gt;Bob Wulff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uen3aT"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tenet&lt;/em&gt;, the latest film by director Christopher Nolan, arrived on Blu-ray in December 2020, but now it has been released in another physical format: Game Boy Advance cartridges. Via &lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/tenet-game-boy-advance-bob-wulff-christopher-nolan-202848161.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Engadget&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S4od1AdB8e4"&gt;YouTuber Bob Wulff&lt;/a&gt; managed to fit the two-hour, 30-minute time-bending film with a nearly incomprehensible plot on five cartridges, compressed down to a 192 x 128 resolution that looks blurry even on the GBA’s 240 x 160 display. The worst (best) part of the experience might be that it runs at six frames per second. They even made bespoke labels for each cartridge that are, actually, very well done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MRRdlu"&gt;Now, before you ask aloud “why?” just say “thank you, Bob Wulff!” instead. This obviously doesn’t need to exist, but the promise of these little displays of technical prowess applied in strange, delightful ways is what gets me out of bed each morning. Plus, it’s fun to imagine Christopher Nolan realizing that there’s a fate far worse than streaming services for his IMAX films to end up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AqWEFh"&gt;You can watch the video above to see how they did this. But, you know what? Why watch YouTube videos on &lt;em&gt;YouTube&lt;/em&gt;? That’s passé. Wulff turned the video above &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BobWulff/status/1370047156938227722"&gt;into a ROM download&lt;/a&gt; that you can load into a GBA emulator, like mGBA, to name one of many examples you can get on a Windows PC. Come on, you know you want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xAIvML"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22321473/tenet-game-boy-advance-christopher-nolan-bob-wulff-youtube-mod-cartridge"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22321473/tenet-game-boy-advance-christopher-nolan-bob-wulff-youtube-mod-cartridge</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-11T16:49:18-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-11T16:49:18-05:00</updated>
    <title>T-Mobile plans to turn up 5G speed this year, cover 90 percent of Americans with fast 5G by 2024</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d1ALIQN-zGC7S5F5hxvsqxiV0yk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68951303/acastro_191108_1777_t-mobile_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;T-Mobile is keen to stay ahead of the 5G competition | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5066wz"&gt;During its &lt;a href="https://investor.t-mobile.com/news-and-events/events-and-presentations/event-details/2021/T-Mobile-Virtual-Analyst-Day/default.aspx"&gt;virtual analyst event&lt;/a&gt; today, T-Mobile outlined &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/eliblumenthal/status/1370098384816779265?s=20"&gt;some bold plans&lt;/a&gt; for expanding its 5G coverage and speeding up its current offerings. The company says that by the end of 2023, it will cover 90 percent of Americans (about 300 million) with what it calls Ultra Capacity 5G (its faster mid-band and mmWave service). It also plans to cover 97 percent of Americans (approximately 320 million) by the end of 2022 with its slower low-band 5G, which it calls Extended Range. Currently, 125 million are covered by Ultra Capacity, with Extended Range covering 287 million. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oHYsUO"&gt;Additionally, those currently covered by Ultra Capacity 5G will see an increase in average speeds from 300Mbps up to 400Mbps, thanks to additional megahertz devoted to 5G, and T-Mobile says that more speed increases are on the way. This portion of T-Mobile’s 5G service is largely based on spectrum &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/1/21202726/tmobile-sprint-acquisition-ceo-finished-john-legere-steps-down"&gt;acquired from its Sprint merger&lt;/a&gt;, with mid-band frequencies well-suited to faster speeds and broad coverage. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sfFCloG7qNYmJkL-vz7n6C2PeQc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363649/slack_imgs.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;T-Mobile’s C-band acquisition figures into expansion plans starting in 2023.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="S1S5xW"&gt;Already having access to those mid-band frequencies allowed T-Mobile to take a less aggressive approach to the recent FCC C-band auction, a fact it celebrated throughout its investor call today. &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fnews%2Fnetwork%2Ft-mobile-further-solidifies-5g-leadership-position-with-successful-c-band-auction&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F11%2F22325857%2Ft-mobile-5g-coverage-ultra-capacity-extended-range" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;T-Mobile says its comparatively low bid&lt;/a&gt; of $9.3 billion (Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T bid $45.4 and $23.4 billion, respectively) went toward spectrum that would strategically supplement its current 2.5GHz holdings. Those frequencies will become available in 2023 and likely figure into the latter part of the company’s aggressive expansion plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MoyhdH"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction March 11th, 4:32PM PT: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T bid $45.4 and $23.4 billion respectively in the recent FCC auction. A previous version of this article said that the companies bid $45.4 and $23.4 million, which would have been quite a steal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QG4sGs"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22325857/t-mobile-5g-coverage-ultra-capacity-extended-range"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22325857/t-mobile-5g-coverage-ultra-capacity-extended-range</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-11T16:36:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-11T16:36:01-05:00</updated>
    <title>Go read this: the fight over YouTube creator Tim Pool’s news site — and a cat</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iUQYcKGO6KPnBCX2eosNnoMiyPM=/0x9:3918x2621/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68951186/Screen_Shot_2021_03_11_at_12.38.59_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: SCNR&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5SqUIW"&gt;YouTube drama remains some of the most interesting drama, and &lt;a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/youtube-star-tim-pools-news-site-collapses-amid-allegations-he-took-a-cat-hostage?ref=scroll"&gt;a new report from &lt;em&gt;The Daily Beast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on infighting at political YouTube creator Tim Pool’s news company — and the fate of a cat named Betsy — is no exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uccKyG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Daily Beast&lt;/em&gt;’s Will Sommer sets the scene with Pool’s background as a former &lt;em&gt;Vice &lt;/em&gt;reporter who went independent as an alt-right-adjacent YouTube creator. But the meat of the report is the fight over Subverse, a news media &lt;a href="https://scnr.com/"&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; with a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/SCNRtv/featured"&gt;YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt; (renamed SCNR for a hilarious reason you should read the report to learn) for which Pool and his former business partner, Emily Molli, raised over $1 million to start. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wBaUre"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7URS4gFQFGw?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="y0vV4A"&gt;Molli was joined by another &lt;em&gt;Vice &lt;/em&gt;alum, Rocco Castoro, to get the YouTube operation off the ground, and the resulting videos feel a lot like &lt;em&gt;Vice’s &lt;/em&gt;own documentary work. But then problems arose. “Tensions between Pool and his other partners flared...over who had access to various internal systems connected to Subverse,” writes Sommer. Those tensions would lead to Castoro and Molli investigating Pool for “unsavory internet schemes” and leave Betsy, Molli’s cat, allegedly held hostage at Pool’s mansion in Maryland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ObTlei"&gt;You should read &lt;a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/youtube-star-tim-pools-news-site-collapses-amid-allegations-he-took-a-cat-hostage?ref=scroll"&gt;Sommer’s report on &lt;em&gt;The Daily Beast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for the complicated journey Betsy took to get back to Molli. But for now, remember: never let your cat go to a second location with a YouTube creator / podcaster.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22325701/tim-pool-youtube-news-media-company-hostage-cat-daily-beast-report"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22325701/tim-pool-youtube-news-media-company-hostage-cat-daily-beast-report</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
