<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-11T14:59:55-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-11T14:59:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-11T14:59:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>French lawmakers vote to ban some domestic flights to reduce carbon emissions</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="FRANCE-TRANSPORT-AIR" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/m8eJejhACdf-h84_guXYL9yvw2w=/270x0:7923x5102/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69109693/1229782254.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Air France planes parked at Roissy Airport in Paris | Photo by THOMAS COEX/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PA5C54"&gt;French lawmakers have voted to ban domestic flights on routes that could be taken in a train ride in less than two-and-a-half hours, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-climate-change-france-flights-idUSKBN2BY0AO"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt;. The vote late Saturday comes as part of France’s larger climate bill, which seeks to reduce its 1990-level carbon emissions by 40 percent over the next decade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DGgZgs"&gt;Last week, France’s government said it would contribute 4 billion euros ($4.7 billion) to recapitalize airline Air France-KLM. The airline warned it is expecting an operating loss of 1.3 billion euros when it reports its first-quarter earnings next month. The airline industry is reeling with the impact of the coronavirus pandemic, which has led to a sharp reduction in global travel over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A7icPK"&gt;“We know that aviation is a contributor of carbon dioxide and that because of climate change we must reduce emissions,” France’s Industry Minister Agnes Pannier-Runachershe told Europe 1 radio. “Equally, we must support our companies and not let them fall by the wayside.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XbVx9N"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/travel-logistics-and-infrastructure/our-insights/back-to-the-future-airline-sector-poised-for-change-post-covid-19"&gt;McKinsey &amp;amp; Co. analysts estimate&lt;/a&gt; the airline industry will continue to feel the effects of the coronavirus pandemic for several years, predicting that air traffic won’t get back to 2019 levels until 2024. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fNBO8G"&gt;The bill to cut back domestic flights goes next to France’s Senate for a vote.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/11/22378623/french-lawmakers-vote-ban-domestic-flights"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/11/22378623/french-lawmakers-vote-ban-domestic-flights</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-11T13:08:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-11T13:08:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>Clubhouse CEO says user data was not leaked, contrary to reports</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Clubhouse App Photo Illustrations" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/l1LE1u1OdUfNNDeO2YjEE2T9XWI=/0x0:3543x2362/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69108912/1232148642.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Jakub Porzycki/NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4eTW0P"&gt;Clubhouse CEO Paul Davison said Sunday that a report claiming personal user data had been leaked was “false.”  &lt;a href="https://cybernews.com/security/clubhouse-data-leak-1-3-million-user-records-leaked-for-free-online/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyber News&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; a SQL database with users’ IDs, names, usernames, Twitter and Instagram handles and follower counts were posted to an online hacker forum. According to &lt;em&gt;Cyber News, &lt;/em&gt;it did not appear that sensitive user information such as credit card numbers were among the leaked info. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kzRTqg"&gt;Clubhouse did not immediately reply to a request for more information from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; on Sunday. But Davison said in response to a question during a town hall that the platform had not suffered a data breach. “No, This is misleading and false, it is a clickbait article, we were not hacked. The data referred to was all public profile information from our app. So the answer to that is a definitive ‘no.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6HNpFD"&gt;Last week, &lt;em&gt;Cyber News&lt;/em&gt; reported that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22374464/linkedin-data-leak-500-million-accounts-scraped-microsoft"&gt;personal data for 500 million LinkedIn users&lt;/a&gt; had been scraped and posted online. The Microsoft-owned company said that no private member account data from LinkedIn was included in the leak. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nqEDzU"&gt;That news came just a couple of days after it was discovered that personal data for some &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/4/22366822/facebook-personal-data-533-million-leaks-online-email-phone-numbers"&gt;533 million Facebook users&lt;/a&gt; was leaked online for free. The Facebook leak reportedly included users’ phone numbers, birthdates, locations, email addresses, and full names. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Z3HPp"&gt;Clubhouse had a monster first year—despite being invite-only and available only on iOS devices— seeing more than 10 million downloads. Twitter, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22359332/linkedin-clubhouse-clone-social-audio-networking-room"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/31/22356682/discord-stage-channels-clubhouse-like-feature-voice"&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22356993/spotify-locker-room-clubhouse-launch-acquisition"&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/slack-wants-to-be-more-than-a-text-based-messaging-platform/"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; have all launched or are working on competing social audio platforms, and  &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276645/facebook-clubhouse-social-audio-app-develop"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; reportedly has one in the works as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KSXhPP"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="uY4usW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to check if you’re part of the Facebook data breach","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22367727/facebook-data-breach-haveibeenpwned"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="rcY0sN"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update April 11th 1:07PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Adds comment from Clubhouse CEO Paul Davison who said the platform was not hacked. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/11/22378302/personal-information-1-million-clubhouse-users-leaked-privacy-security"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/11/22378302/personal-information-1-million-clubhouse-users-leaked-privacy-security</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-11T12:27:40-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-11T12:27:40-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google is shutting down its mobile Shopping app</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JkIEdBIgzWa_DEbdPRNDiZy3N68=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69109239/acastro_180508_1777_google_IO_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0kWpia"&gt;Google is shutting down its mobile Shopping apps for both iOS and Android and directing users to its web Shopping site instead, &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/04/09/google-shopping-app/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5 Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;reported. On Friday, &lt;a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/google-shopping-app-being-killed-off/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Xda Developers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; discovered that the term “sunset” had been added to several strings of code in the Shopping app, suggesting the apps were being discontinued. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HxSVpZ"&gt;A Google spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;9to5 Google&lt;/em&gt; that the apps will continue to function through June. &lt;em&gt;“&lt;/em&gt;Within the next few weeks, we’ll no longer be supporting the Shopping app. All of the functionality the app offered users is available on the Shopping tab,” the spokesperson said. We’ll continue building features within the Shopping tab and other Google surfaces, including the Google app.” The &lt;a href="http://shopping.google.com"&gt;shopping.google.com&lt;/a&gt; site will remain active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2C0bS3"&gt;The app allowed users to choose from among thousands of online stores and make purchases using their Google accounts. to quickly shop across thousands of stores and purchase stuff using your Google Account. This user found the Android app to be working normally on Sunday, but some users were already seeing a “something went wrong” message when they tried to use the Shopping app. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3lA23j"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;RIP Google Shopping's mobile app. Google is preparing to sunset it. New fragment in v59 of the Android app.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;CC &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/killedbygoogle?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@killedbygoogle&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/Q3RpujZr3K"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Q3RpujZr3K&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Mishaal Rahman (@MishaalRahman) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MishaalRahman/status/1380188566924431365?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 8, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dqTfkq"&gt;The mobile Shopping app is just the latest Google product to get the axe— Reader (still bitter about that one), Hangouts, Plus— the &lt;a href="https://killedbygoogle.com/"&gt;list goes on&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X2msVj"&gt;We’ve reached out to Google for more information and will update when we learn more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZT43E9"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/11/22378483/google-shut-down-mobile-shopping-apps-ios-android"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/11/22378483/google-shut-down-mobile-shopping-apps-ios-android</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-11T09:34:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-11T09:34:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>South Korea EV battery makers reach settlement in US trade dispute</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="SK Innovation Co logo seen" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PNVSVxaa-7fxRKIiooXAgtOYbqE=/0x384:4608x3456/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69108820/1070303268.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Igor Golovniov/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BqngrE"&gt;South Korean electric-vehicle battery makers SK Innovation and LG Energy Solution have reached a settlment in a US trade dispute, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-04-10/ford-vw-battery-supplier-said-to-reach-deal-to-avoid-import-ban?utm_source=url_link&amp;amp;sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;. Under the terms of the agreement, SK will pay $1.8 billion (2 trillion won) in cash and royalties to LG. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YOtNIP"&gt;In a joint statement the companies said they would “work to help the development of EV battery industry in South Korea and the US. through healthy competition and friendly cooperation,” adding that they would “work together to strengthen the battery network and environmentally-friendly policy that the Biden administration is pursuing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8suLsg"&gt;In February, the US International Trade Commission &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/9481d70b-827b-476d-9e0b-21245321e289"&gt;imposed a 10-year import ban&lt;/a&gt; on SK Innovation— due to take effect Sunday— following allegations it illegally obtained technology from rival LG. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9EOjAq"&gt;The settlement will prevent an import ban on SK Innovation batteries into the US, which would have been problematic for the Biden administration. Ford and Volkswagen both are slated to start production on electric vehicles next year, using batteries made at SK’s plant in Georgia. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z0gJBi"&gt;“This settlement agreement is a win for American workers and the American auto industry,” President Biden &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/04/11/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-electric-battery-dispute-settlement/"&gt;said in a statement Sunday&lt;/a&gt;. “A key part of my plan to Build Back Better is to have the electric vehicles and batteries of the future built here in America, all across America, by American workers. We need a strong, diversified and resilient US-based electric vehicle battery supply chain, so we can supply the growing global demand for these vehicles and components.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cp0N8A"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/11/22378323/south-korea-ev-battery-settlement-trade-dispute"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/11/22378323/south-korea-ev-battery-settlement-trade-dispute</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-11T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-11T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>LG leaves behind more than a flip phone-shaped hole in our hearts</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2nix_zd-RTVqievZhpUQKgS4w_Y=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69108712/ajohnson_210222_4437__005.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The LG Stylo 6 is one of the company’s bestselling phones in recent history.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The company leaves a void that brands like Motorola and TCL are well-positioned to fill&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="zHTSjt"&gt;LG’s exit from the smartphone business felt inevitable in the weeks leading up to it as rumors mounted. When it was finally confirmed, Avi Greengart, a longtime consumer tech analyst and president of Techsponential, noticed a trend toward nostalgia in the reactions to the news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zosnHP"&gt;“I’m not getting a lot of people saying ‘What will I do to replace my LG G8X ThinQ?’ I’m getting ‘Aw, my first phone was an LG flip phone, and it was durable and reliable and I loved it.’” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GuJe7t"&gt;As someone who spent many years covering the digital camera market, it’s a very familiar moment to me. We mourn the loss of the brand that gave us our first flip phone or our first camera with a tweet and a broken heart emoji. But truthfully, we moved on long ago, as did most of the rest of the phone- or camera-buying population. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="t7t3Mw"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Through last year, LG still held close to 10 percent market share in the US&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ChXH3e"&gt;Things &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/4/28/11525306/lg-g5-earnings-q1-2016"&gt;weren’t looking good&lt;/a&gt; for LG’s phone business in 2016 when it introduced the modular G5, and the ecosystem’s failure to take off perpetuated what would become years of losses for the mobile division. In 2020, the smartphone business &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lg.com%2Fglobal%2Fpdf%2Fir_report%2F20%25204Q%2520Earning%2520Release%2520of%2520LGE.pdf&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F11%2F22375938%2Flg-smartphone-business-exit-tcl-motorola" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;recorded an operational loss of around $750 million for the year&lt;/a&gt;; the company promised to “closely review the direction of the business,” and we know now how that turned out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IHTQMi"&gt;While most shoppers have moved on, there are still gaps left in the market when a Kodak or an LG packs it in. “This is a void. When they do leave, this will be a void,” says Ryan Reith, program vice president for IDC’s Mobile Device Tracker division. He says that through last year, LG still held close to 10 percent market share in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="84KiyC"&gt;In particular, the company still had a solid foothold in the prepaid device business. Greengart doesn’t think there will be any lack of appetite to snap up that share of the market. “The competition there is brutal. The real question is will US carriers invite a new brand in — someone like Xiaomi would be my longshot.” The company’s Redmi and Poco lineups might be good candidates, with a focus on bringing high-end features and solid performance to affordable handsets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="8l9WYc"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The real question is will US carriers invite a new brand in — someone like Xiaomi would be my longshot.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LfyPlb"&gt;Greengart also notes that OnePlus already has a foot in the door at Metro by T-Mobile, the carrier’s prepaid sub-brand. Samsung has already announced that it will sell two of its least expensive A-series phones, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22370189/samsung-galaxy-a52-a42-a32-5g-a12-a02s-price-specs-price"&gt;the A02s and A12&lt;/a&gt;, through prepaid brands like Cricket and Metro this spring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pWl2U6"&gt;As for the sub-$300 space in general, there’s no shortage of brands ready to pounce. “I would say the two brands that are probably going to take that share going to be Motorola and TCL,” Reith says. He notes that Motorola is already well-positioned to pick up LG’s Latin American customers, which was recently about 30 percent of its mobile phone business. Even on an individual device level, there are obvious heirs: one of LG’s last bestselling devices is the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22301223/lg-stylo-6-review"&gt;Stylo 6&lt;/a&gt;, and its sole competitor, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22311690/motorola-moto-g-stylus-2021-review-price-specs"&gt;Moto G Stylus&lt;/a&gt;, is quite frankly a better phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b19Eaj"&gt;TCL has also made it clear in the past couple of years that it’s eager to get its own brand devices into more consumers’ hands, in addition to the phones the company already makes for other brands. Reith says he’s “bullish” on the company’s prospects, as more US shoppers have become familiar with the brand name by way of its TV business. If one thing’s certain, it’s that more than a few companies are in a good position to fill that void LG leaves behind. As Greengart puts it, “Undoubtedly there will be plenty of substitutes; in fact there already are.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="o55aMP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Undoubtedly there will be plenty of substitutes; in fact there already are.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DH5Gs2"&gt;Although LG only had a small presence in the premium market, there’s a gap left there too — even if it’s mostly symbolic. The few devices the company still sold were an alternative to the two dominant brands in the US: Apple and Samsung. Especially considering the lower cost of entry to the S21 series this year, those remaining customers will likely be easily scooped up by the duopoly. “The market is mostly Apple and Samsung in the United States,” says Greengart. “If it was concentrated before, it’s even more concentrated today.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c6wpis"&gt;Realistically though, the market had already spoken. LG’s efforts at bold, unusual designs in the premium space never caught on and spelled serious trouble for the business. Reith points to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21536659/lg-wing-review-dual-screen-price-specs-features"&gt;the LG Wing&lt;/a&gt; as an example. “To come up with a design like that… it takes so much money for R&amp;amp;D, that when you put that out and it only sells thousands of units — not hundreds of thousands, but &lt;em&gt;thousands&lt;/em&gt; of units — it’s a big, big loss,” he says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="rfzHOP"&gt;LG’s premium devices may have been interesting and unique, but the market spoke, and the company’s mobile phone exit became seemingly inevitable. That’s how these things work, and a multitude of companies are ready to swoop in and pick up where LG left off. But whether you follow mobile tech closely or just have a special place in your heart for your old flip phone, many of us will still take the opportunity to pause and shed a digital emoji tear.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/11/22375938/lg-smartphone-business-exit-tcl-motorola"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/11/22375938/lg-smartphone-business-exit-tcl-motorola</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-11T08:57:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-11T08:57:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google reportedly ran secret ‘Project Bernanke’ that boosted its own ad-buying system over competitors</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uSEhvxYAFq6hozN3kqmpgE3Mr3M=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69108688/acastro_180427_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="l1nPWG"&gt;Google reportedly ran a secret project called “Project Bernanke” that relied on bidding data collected from advertisers using its ad exchange to benefit the company’s own ad system, &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/googles-secret-project-bernanke-revealed-in-texas-antitrust-case-11618097760?mod=djemalertNEWS"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt;. First discovered by newswire &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/KhushitaVasant/status/1379955848118726659?s=20"&gt;service MLex&lt;/a&gt;, the name of the project was visible in an inadvertently unredacted document Google had filed as part of an antitrust lawsuit in Texas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3EKR7S"&gt;A federal judge has since let Google refile the document under seal. But according to the &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt;, “Bernanke” was not disclosed to outside advertisers, and proved lucrative for Google, generating hundreds of millions of dollars for the company. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22178988/google-antitrust-ad-tech-lawsuit-texas-attorney-general-paxton"&gt;Texas filed an antitrust lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; against Google in December, alleging that the search giant was using anticompetitive tactics in which “Bernanke” was a major part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="skiRF5"&gt;Google wrote in the unredacted filing that data from Project Bernanke was “comparable to data maintained by other buying tools,” according to the &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt;. The company was able to access historical data about bids made through Google Ads, to change bids by its clients and boost the clients’ chances of winning auctions for ad impressions, putting rival ad tools at a disadvantage. Texas cited in court documents an internal presentation from 2013 in which Google said Project Bernanke would bring in $230 million in revenue for that year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NaRVoq"&gt;Why Google chose to name the secret project “Bernanke” is not clear. Ben Bernanke, who was chair of the Federal Reserve from 2006 to 2014, is probably the best-known Bernanke in the public sphere. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="21R7Dw"&gt;In an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, a Google spokesperson said the complaint by Texas Attorney General Ken Paxton “misrepresents many aspects of our ad tech business. We look forward to making our case in court.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QmGMH2"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update April 11th 10:54AM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Adds comment from Google spokesperson&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/11/22378296/google-secret-project-bernanke-ad-buying-competitors-texas"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/11/22378296/google-secret-project-bernanke-ad-buying-competitors-texas</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-10T17:10:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-10T17:10:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>China fines Alibaba $2.8 billion after antitrust investigation</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Alibaba Nanjing Headquarters" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/l3wlEvRxpLN5hTnZ03DiEKI6zOc=/0x0:3500x2333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69107211/1311787370.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Fang Dongxu/VCG via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Yux4pg"&gt;China has hit Alibaba, one of the country’s biggest online retailers, with a record $2.8 billion (18.2 billion yuan) fine, after an investigation found the ecommerce giant violated China’s anti-monopoly law, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/09/technology/china-alibaba-monopoly-fine.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reported. The fine, which represents 4 percent of Alibaba’s 2019 domestic sales, is three times higher than the $975 million fine &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/2/9/8009589/qualcomm-fined-975-million-by-chinese-anti-monopoly-regulators"&gt;China imposed on US chip company Qualcomm&lt;/a&gt; back in 2015. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PkY5lr"&gt;The Chinese government launched an investigation into Alibaba in December to determine whether the company was preventing merchants from selling their products on other platforms. China’s market regulator found that Alibaba’s practices had a negative effect on online retail competition and innovation. Alibaba used data and algorithms to strengthen its own position in the marketplace, resulting in an “improper competitive advantage,” China’s State Administration for Market Regulation &lt;a href="http://www.samr.gov.cn/xw/zj/202104/t20210410_327702.html"&gt;said in a statement&lt;/a&gt;. The company will have to reduce its anticompetitive tactics and provide compliance reports to the government for the next three years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s4oONk"&gt;Alibaba &lt;a href="https://www.alizila.com/a-letter-to-our-customers-and-to-the-community/"&gt;said in a statement&lt;/a&gt; it accepted the fine and pledged to make improvements to better serve its “responsibility to society.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ywXy4W"&gt;“We will further strengthen our focus on customer value creation and customer experience, as well as continuing to introduce measures to lower entry barriers and business costs of operating on our platforms,” the company’s statement reads. “We are committed to ensuring an operating environment for our merchants and partners that is more open, more equitable, more efficient and more inclusive in sharing the fruits of growth.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sb2yOI"&gt;The hefty fine is not likely to hurt Alibaba’s bottom line too severely, however; in February, the company reported a third quarter profit — for the &lt;a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/en/news/press_pdf/p210202.pdf"&gt;final three months of calendar year 2020&lt;/a&gt; alone— of $12 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aXkfjq"&gt;Correction: An earlier version of this story had an incorrect figure for the fine China imposed on Qualcomm. It was $975 million. We regret the error. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/10/22377500/china-fines-alibaba-2-8-billion-anitrust"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/10/22377500/china-fines-alibaba-2-8-billion-anitrust</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-10T14:55:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-10T14:55:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Lawsuit against Amazon alleging it failed to protect workers from COVID-19 moved back to NY state court</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-ROBOTICS-SCIENCE-LABOR-amazon" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/X5THg-n7uPUMuFq5Bi6QPopzs4c=/0x12:5650x3779/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69106852/1124819745.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;JOHANNES EISELE/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TI5ZPn"&gt;A federal judge has granted the New York attorney general’s request to move a lawsuit against Amazon back to New York state court, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-amazon-com-new-york-lawsuits/judge-hands-amazon-a-setback-in-new-york-lawsuit-over-covid-19-shortfalls-idUSKBN2BW2TW"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters &lt;/em&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;. AG &lt;a href="https://iapps.courts.state.ny.us/nyscef/ViewDocument?docIndex=muvelgaOEvSt6Yc1gGqzAg=="&gt;Letitia James’ lawsuit alleges&lt;/a&gt; that the ecommerce giant failed to protect workers at its Brooklyn and Staten Island warehouses from COVID-19 during the early months of the pandemic, and retaliated against employees who complained about the lack of safety measures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A54XYG"&gt;Amazon had sought to have the case moved to federal court, arguing that workplace safety issues were not under James’ purview. The company pre-emptively &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22279819/amazon-new-york-ag-state-lawsuit-covid-19-warehouse-conditions-pandemic"&gt;sued James on February 12th&lt;/a&gt;, and James sued &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287204/new-york-amazon-lawsuit-worker-safety-failures"&gt;Amazon four days later&lt;/a&gt;. Amazon then moved the lawsuit to federal court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="enrq32"&gt;“Amazon has forced its employees to work in unsafe conditions throughout this pandemic,” James said in a statement following US District Judge Jed Rakoff’s order. “We are pleased with today’s decision to allow this case to be heard in state court, where it belongs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8XXZS0"&gt;The ruling did not address the merits of the lawsuit, which seeks improved conditions for workers and damages for two Amazon workers who say the company retaliated against them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FpGYSa"&gt;Workers at Amazon’s JKF8 warehouse in Staten Island said last March that they didn’t have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/30/21199942/amazon-warehouse-coronavirus-covid-new-york-protest-walkout"&gt;necessary protective equipment&lt;/a&gt;. Amazon &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/24/21233891/amazon-coronavirus-protest-sick-out-tech-workers-climate-justice"&gt;fired several workers who protested&lt;/a&gt; the conditions, including Chris Smalls, who had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/30/21199942/amazon-warehouse-coronavirus-covid-new-york-protest-walkout"&gt;organized a walkout&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nGfROt"&gt;At the time, &lt;a href="https://ag.ny.gov/press-release/2020/ag-james-statement-firing-amazon-worker-who-organized-walkout"&gt;James called Smalls’ firing “disgraceful”&lt;/a&gt; and pushed for an investigation by the National Labor Relations Board. &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/05/07/technology/amazon-coronavirus-whistleblowers.html"&gt;Amazon said at the time&lt;/a&gt; that the workers “were not terminated for talking publicly about working conditions” but for violating safety policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fzldyv"&gt;Amazon did not immediately reply to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gf0RNF"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/10/22377308/lawsuit-amazon-protect-workers-covid-19-new-york-warehouse-smalls-jfk8"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/10/22377308/lawsuit-amazon-protect-workers-covid-19-new-york-warehouse-smalls-jfk8</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-10T13:34:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-10T13:34:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>First flight test for NASA’s Ingenuity helicopter pushed to Wednesday</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Stbpub_rH8IYvuSpE182JbrU3eA=/0x62:1578x1114/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69106684/PIA24581.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GhxL8g"&gt;NASA engineers have decided to delay the Ingenuity helicopter’s debut flight on Mars to at least Wednesday, April 14th, after running into a minor computer glitch during a rotor spin test late Friday night, the agency said on Saturday. The tiny craft is healthy, but engineers need some more time to review telemetry data from the unexpected hiccup before proceeding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="On4tsu"&gt;Ingenuity, a mini four-pound helicopter that arrived on Mars February 18th attached to NASA’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289668/nasa-mars-perseverance-rover-success"&gt;Perseverance rover&lt;/a&gt;, was initially slated to carry out its first flight test late Sunday night (or, mid-day Mars time). The first bits of data on whether the flight attempt was successful was expected to come early Monday morning, around 4AM ET. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1wHfcD"&gt;But data from a high-speed rotor test carried out on Friday showed the test sequence “ended early due to a ‘watchdog’ timer expiration,” &lt;a href="https://mars.nasa.gov/resources/25795/ingenuitys-blades-are-released/"&gt;NASA said&lt;/a&gt;. It happened as Ingenuity’s computer was trying to switch from pre-flight mode to flight mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y0qGUr"&gt;Ingenuity’s “watchdog timer” is just that — a software-based watchdog that oversees the helicopter’s test sequences and alerts engineers if anything looks abnormal. “It helps the system stay safe by not proceeding if an issue is observed and worked as planned,” NASA said in a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PD4ocC"&gt;NASA emphasized the craft is healthy, and Ingenuity is still in good contact with engineers at the agency’s Jet Propulsion Laboratory in California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="790zTJ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/4/22366887/nasa-mars-rover-perseverance-ingenuity-helicopter-drops-off"&gt;Ingenuity was deployed&lt;/a&gt; by Perseverance on the Martian surface on April 4th, kicking off a 31-day clock in which five flight tests are planned. For its first flight demonstration, the helicopter will ascend 10 feet above the surface and hover for about 30 seconds, aiming to achieve the first-ever powered flight on another world. Depending how the first test goes, subsequent tests will involve Ingenuity soaring to higher altitudes and buzzing around within its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/23/22346773/nasa-mars-ingenuity-helicopter-perseverance-rover-flight-zone"&gt;running track-shaped flight zone&lt;/a&gt; at Mars’ Jezero Crater.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/10/22377299/nasa-ingenuity-mars-helicopter-flight-delayed-wednesday"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/10/22377299/nasa-ingenuity-mars-helicopter-flight-delayed-wednesday</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-10T13:13:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-10T13:13:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook spent $23 million for CEO Mark Zuckerberg’s security in 2020</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vVU0OnzOEuKz-iOe3mZsbY453DU=/0x0:5157x3438/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69106640/1201476988.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by KENZO TRIBOUILLARD/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="d0kgVF"&gt;A new filing with the Securities and Exchange Commission shows that Facebook spent more than $23 million last year on security for CEO Mark Zuckerberg. Facebook’s annual reviews of company security “identified specific threats to Mr. Zuckerberg,” according to a  &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1326801/000132680121000022/facebook2021definitiveprox.htm"&gt;proxy statement filed Friday&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n5fk6H"&gt;“He is synonymous with Facebook, and as a result, negative sentiment regarding our company is directly associated with, and often transferred to, Mr. Zuckerberg,” the proxy says of the Facebook CEO’s role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ppohbs"&gt;The company’s annual review of security programs showed the costs of protecting Zuckerberg and his family rose in 2020 mainly due to COVID-19 travel protocols, increased security coverage during the 2020 US election season “and other periods with increased security risk,” as well as rising costs for security personnel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z5AIES"&gt;The “all other compensation” section of the proxy statement shows Facebook spent $23 million for personal security at Zuckerberg’s residences and for travel for him and his family. The CEO also got an additional $10 million to put toward security personnel and other security costs. The cost of base security was up to $13.4 million last year, compared to $10.4 million the year prior. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PhByCd"&gt;“The compensation, nominating &amp;amp; governance committee believes that these costs are appropriate and necessary in light of the threat landscape and the fact that Mr. Zuckerberg has requested to receive only $1 in annual salary and does not receive any bonus payments, equity awards, or other incentive compensation,” according to the proxy statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SqRM3L"&gt;Also in the proxy filed Friday, Facebook said it will put forward a proposal at its May 26th shareholder meeting to offer personal security to non-employee directors from time to time, which it says is necessary due to “ongoing scrutiny faced by our directors as a result of their service on our board of directors.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ern7kK"&gt;Facebook approved personal security services for some of the non-employee directors in January and February “in light of the high level of scrutiny faced by our company and our executive officers and directors, as well as the dynamic and charged atmosphere following the 2020 U.S. elections and the attack on the U.S. Capitol Building on January 6, 2021,” according to the proxy statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PYeSlE"&gt;A January report by the Tech Transparency Project found that some extremists rioters at the Capitol attack had used &lt;a href="https://www.techtransparencyproject.org/articles/capitol-attack-was-months-making-facebook"&gt;private groups on Facebook for months&lt;/a&gt; to plan and coordinate the January 6th insurgency, despite &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i4kbd5KqbIM"&gt;remarks by Facebook COO Sheryl Sandberg&lt;/a&gt; that the “events were largely organized on platforms that don’t have our ability to stop hate, don’t have our standards and don’t have our transparency.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N1Ij1A"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HUAvsM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NDFNKI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2Zu1J0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ujMqXR"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SAoLFa"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/10/22377209/facebook-spent-23-million-mark-zuckerberg-security"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/10/22377209/facebook-spent-23-million-mark-zuckerberg-security</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
