<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-23T12:00:27-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-23T12:00:27-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-23T12:00:27-04:00</updated>
    <title>Android adds facial gesture controls and handwriting recognition accessibility features</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YhSAR5NLr-vSqy9nVE9ClpNFHzM=/0x0:834x556/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69898307/ezgif.com_gif_maker__1_.0.gif" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gNVQfw"&gt;Google’s raft of &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/android/new-features-fall-2021/"&gt;new features coming to Android this fall&lt;/a&gt; includes some interesting new accessibility features. There are new facial gesture controls designed for people with motor impairments, as well as a new handwriting recognition feature for Lookout, a Google app that uses a phone’s camera to help people with low vision or blindness. There are also improvements coming for Google Assistant, Digital Wellbeing, Nearby Share, and Google’s Android keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kKsO1o"&gt;There are two parts to Android’s facial gesture controls. Camera Switches (which has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22626754/android-accessibility-face-gesture-controls"&gt;previously been spotted&lt;/a&gt; in Android 12’s beta) sits within Android’s existing Accessibility Suite and lets you use gestures like opening your mouth or raising your eyebrows to activate various commands. The second part is Project Activate, a standalone app that’s designed to help people communicate. Here, facial gestures can be set to trigger actions like playing audio or sending a text message.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/209OPL1Vbo4o5aBuQJQ181vUoaQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22871770/ezgif.com_gif_maker__1_.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Using facial gestures to control a weather app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="yje8II"&gt;Meanwhile, Google says Lookout’s handwriting recognition will be able to read out Latin-based languages and is accessible from its Documents mode. Euro and Indian Rupees are also being added to the app’s Currency mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="30D3kL"&gt;Beyond accessibility, Gboard is also seeing improvements. Most interesting is that on all devices running Android 11 and up, Google’s Android keyboard will be able to use Smart Compose to finish sentences, similar to what’s already possible in specific services like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/20/20973917/google-docs-smart-compose-feature-g-suite-update"&gt;Google Docs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/10/17340224/google-gmail-how-to-use-smart-compose-io-2018"&gt;Gmail&lt;/a&gt;. This feature has previously been exclusive to Pixel phones. Copying and pasting is also being updated to automatically separate out separate contact information and details like phone numbers and email addresses when they’re copied in a single chunk of text. Finally, Gboard will also proactively suggest sharing a screenshot if you immediately switch to a messaging app after taking one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xAJhp7"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/12/22379419/android-digital-wellbeing-heads-up-walking-google-pixel-4a"&gt;“Heads Up” Digital Wellbeing feature&lt;/a&gt;, which reminds people to stop looking down at their phones while they’re walking, is expanding from just Pixels to all Android phones, while asking Google Assistant to “open my reminders” now offers a one-stop-shop for managing all reminders added to the voice assistant. Nearby Share is also being updated to offer new visibility settings, letting you control who can see your device and send files. It’s a real grab bag of features that should offer something for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xsr0Pz"&gt;Google isn’t offering exact release dates for any of these features, and there’s no mention of whether any of them will be exclusive to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22661647/android-12-final-beta-5-pixel-5a-stability-ui-changes-preview"&gt;upcoming Android 12&lt;/a&gt;. So expect most of them to gradually roll out over the course of this fall, which is generally considered to run until the start of December.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689349/android-facial-gesture-controls-handwriting-recognition-accessibility-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689349/android-facial-gesture-controls-handwriting-recognition-accessibility-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-23T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-23T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Honda will use Google’s embedded Android Automotive in its cars starting in 2022</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Honda e Prototype" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bsHiATzJEHPEFIqd0QIKtSxgDv8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69898246/geneva_honda_eprototype_vladsavov29.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vlad Savov / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Mn0CN3"&gt;Google nabbed another big automaker in its quest to become the default operating system for cars. Honda will soon begin rolling out vehicles with Google’s embedded Android Automotive OS, which includes Google’s voice-activated Assistant, Google Maps, and other automotive-approved Android apps as the default infotainment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2fw9P7"&gt;The first Honda vehicles with embedded Android will start rolling out in 2022. The Japanese automaker wouldn’t say which models it expects to get the new infotainment systems first. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nJko9m"&gt;“We will collaborate with Google to better integrate Google in-vehicle services in our vehicles including the ability to more-easily use features like Google Assistant, Google Maps functionality and other in-vehicle apps offered through Google Play,” a Honda spokesperson said in an email. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Gqrald"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Honda wouldn’t say which models it expects to get the new infotainment systems first&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Uut7ru"&gt;To be clear, Android Automotive is distinct from Android Auto. The former is the car’s default infotainment system, controlling everything from music to navigation to heating and air conditioning, while the latter is projected from a smartphone onto the car’s dashboard display and serves as a competitor to Apple’s CarPlay. Google also had a number of announcements regarding Android Auto (that you can read about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22453578"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xdBDsA"&gt;There are only two cars available today with embedded Android Automotive: the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21365032/polestar-2-hands-on-first-drive-electric-android-automotive-photos-range"&gt;Polestar 2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22195499/volvo-xc40-recharge-ev-suv-first-drive-specs-price"&gt;Volvo XC40 Recharge&lt;/a&gt;. But Google has made deals with a number of other automakers, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260176/ford-google-android-infotainment-os-2023"&gt;Ford&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/5/20851021/general-motors-android-auto-google-infotainment"&gt;General Motors&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/18/17873502/google-android-os-cars-renault-nissan-mitsubishi-alliance"&gt;Renault-Nissan-Mitsubishi Alliance&lt;/a&gt;, that will result in millions of future vehicles released with default Android operating systems. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9GchADo27AuvRadCIJQEPOscnN4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22872025/Cars_with_Google_built_in.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7aky4h"&gt;The news that Honda is joining the Android Automotive party won’t come as a complete surprise, given that the automaker’s current operating system has been Android-based for years. Honda was also part of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/1/6/5279116/google-open-automotive-alliance-android-car-announcement"&gt;Google-led Open Automotive Alliance&lt;/a&gt;, along with Audi, Hyundai, and chipmaker Nvidia, which focused on the integration of Android into in-car infotainment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ndb0MI"&gt;But it can also be a slippery slope. Initially, car companies seemed to want &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/1/13/14268252/apple-carplay-google-android-auto-vs-carmakers"&gt;to keep big tech companies at arm’s length&lt;/a&gt; to prevent them from tapping into the lucrative customer data streams flowing in and out of their vehicles. But Honda figures that by letting Google under the hood, it can probably sell more cars to customers who would prefer a more smartphone-like in-car experience than the OS software currently provided by the automaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xIUljj"&gt;&lt;q&gt;a new dashboard for Google Assistant driving mode&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22688309/honda-google-android-auto-assistant-driving-mode-gas"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22688309/honda-google-android-auto-assistant-driving-mode-gas</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-23T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-23T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google TV mercifully launches mobile remote for Android users </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EEQZGjpH3Jm6UdWZBpkoSGF0mG8=/0x180:1080x900/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69898245/AFS_01A_VirtualRemote_IJ_Realistic_1x1_Frame_11.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OYv7u7"&gt;A new Google TV feature will allow users to use their Android mobile devices as remotes for those moments when your streaming box’s wand disappears without a trace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2oPlbW"&gt;Android mobile remote support for Google TV arrives today after the company initially &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22439777/android-12-design-features-widgets-first-look-google"&gt;announced the feature&lt;/a&gt; during Google I/O back in May. (A spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;the tool will only be available for Android at this time and did not have anything further to share about future iOS support.) &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yhGxyRTYteCRB7TF49dt9vRv7GQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22871153/1._Android_TV_Remote.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="xOkujC"&gt;Support for a mobile remote should be a tremendous help to those of us constantly losing our wands beneath mountains of blankets and pillows, but it should also streamline processes for things like entering long or complicated passwords, search terms, and titles to films and series. Google said that beyond just Google TV, support would extend to other Android TV OS devices as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8VdmwZ"&gt;The remote tool can be accessed two ways: either by adding the r&lt;a href="https://support.google.com/android/answer/9083864?hl=en"&gt;emote tile to quick settings&lt;/a&gt; from an Android device or through the Google TV app (which Google said will be launching in 14 new countries in the coming weeks). &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22688867/google-tv-mobile-remote-android"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22688867/google-tv-mobile-remote-android</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-23T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-23T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google Photos’ nude-friendly folders coming to all Android phones soon</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QdyiNMpg6RzB3GugrUVBiTqaqhk=/75x0:1176x734/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69898244/Screen_Shot_2021_05_18_at_10.46.16_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The feature lets you hide photos and videos behind a passcode or biometric security.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LsKomr"&gt;Google Photos’ Locked Folder feature, which lets you hide sensitive photos and videos from your main library and secure them in a passcode- or biometric-protected folder, is coming to all devices running Android 6 and above. The feature was released exclusively on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22524661/google-photos-locked-folder-private-videos-available-pixel"&gt;newer Pixel phones in June&lt;/a&gt;. Google hasn’t provided an exact date for when the feature is releasing more widely, noting only that it’s “rolling out soon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fcKveF"&gt;When it announced the feature onstage &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22442416/google-photos-locked-folder-private-hidden-pictures"&gt;at Google I/O in May&lt;/a&gt;, Google gave the wholesome example of the feature being used by parents hiding photos of a newly purchased puppy from their children. But I think it’s fair to say that most people are going to have very different photos stored in their Locked Folder. I don’t know about you, but in all the times I’ve had to wrench my phone out of someone’s hand to stop them scrolling through my photos, it’s never been because of a puppy picture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="85pinM"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;With Locked Folder in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/googlephotos?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@googlephotos&lt;/a&gt;, you can add photos to a passcode protected space and they won’t show up as you scroll through Photos or other apps on your phone. Locked Folder is launching first on Google Pixel, and more Android devices throughout the year. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GoogleIO?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#GoogleIO&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/yGNoQ8vLdq"&gt;pic.twitter.com/yGNoQ8vLdq&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Google (@Google) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Google/status/1394710047213633536?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 18, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Iu3G3B"&gt;You set up a Locked Folder by going to Library &amp;gt; Utilities &amp;gt; Locked Folder in the Google Photos app. Then, existing photos can be manually moved to the folder. The Pixel camera app is able to save new shots directly into the folder when taken, but it’s unclear whether this feature will also be available for other Android camera apps. Note that any images saved in a Locked Folder won’t be backed up to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VHT9xn"&gt;The wide launch of Locked Folders was announced as part of a host of new features &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/android/new-features-fall-2021/"&gt;coming to Android this fall&lt;/a&gt;. Other new features include the ability to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22452908"&gt;use Android phones as remotes&lt;/a&gt; for Google TV and Android TV OS devices, as well as new Android Auto and accessibility features.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689322/google-photos-locked-folder-passcode-protected-sensitive-images"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689322/google-photos-locked-folder-passcode-protected-sensitive-images</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-23T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-23T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Here’s how to watch the latest Nintendo Direct</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LfhYbPAIK72pJ9Yp7w6XNyjW_3o=/0x0:2160x1440/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69898251/switch_oled.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new Switch with an OLED screen.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FdZr6Z"&gt;Nintendo is hosting one of its Direct streams later today, September 23rd, where it will showcase Switch games launching this winter. Though, that doesn’t mean there won’t be some news on games coming out later in 2022. There’s also a possibility that Nintendo might show off &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/16/22677624/nintendo-new-controller-fcc-wireless"&gt;the mysterious device that recently popped up in FCC filings&lt;/a&gt;. We think it’s a controller, but given that the company makes so many strange devices, ranging from the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/17/20917908/nintendo-switch-ring-fit-adventure-review"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ring Fit Adventure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; exercise ring to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/18/17253574/nintendo-labo-review-switch-learning-diy"&gt;Labo&lt;/a&gt; and modern &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/15/22535212/nintendo-the-legend-of-zelda-ii-links-awakening-game-watch-handheld-release-date"&gt;Game &amp;amp; Watch&lt;/a&gt; handhelds, who’s to say what’s in store?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w4HYu2"&gt;Parts of the presentation will likely be focused on what’s coming in the immediate future, which for Nintendo includes its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22569208/nintendo-switch-oled-model-hands-on-screen"&gt;new Switch console that has an OLED screen&lt;/a&gt;, along with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/17/22536783/metroid-dread-yoshio-sakamoto-nintendo-switch-e3-2021"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Metroid Dread&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Both launch on October 8th, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yx9AOW"&gt;As usual, we’re going to give you the details to help you tune into the latest Nintendo Direct when it’s live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="yDafRT"&gt;When is the next Nintendo Direct?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="VHDo3O"&gt;It’s happening later today, September 23rd, starting at 6PM ET / 3PM PT. Nintendo says that the presentation will last for “roughly 40 minutes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="xgrZS2"&gt;Where can I watch the Nintendo Direct?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="mpsw2j"&gt;You can check out the Direct on &lt;a href="http://youtube.com/nintendo"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://twitch.tv/nintendo"&gt;Twitch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TkYDAM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689427/nintendo-direct-date-time-watch-how-to-switch-games"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689427/nintendo-direct-date-time-watch-how-to-switch-games</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-23T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-23T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Android Auto is getting a new look to make futzing with your car less distracting</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cfYuxHTya5QHq2n3yJuIEJUwIn8=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69898253/Sequence_02.00_01_09_21.Still007.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Ndb0MI"&gt;Google announced a few updates to Android Auto, including a new dashboard for Google Assistant driving mode. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZHDZnR"&gt;Earlier this year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22633755/google-android-auto-for-phone-screens-shutting-down-android-12-google-assistant-driving-mode"&gt;Google shut down the standalone “Android Auto for Phone Screens”&lt;/a&gt; app with Android 12. Instead, Android phone owners are now recommended to use the Google Assistant driving mode available within Google Maps or the native Android Auto interface available in select cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QNIxGq"&gt;For Android customers with older cars who use their phones for navigation and other functions, Google Assistant driving mode now includes “glanceable, tappable cards” with music, text messages, and other frequently used apps collected all in one place. Customers will be able to use voice commands like “Hey Google, let’s drive” to open the new driving mode dashboard, reducing the need to futz with your phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9WtGRo"&gt;Google says this is designed to ensure drivers keep their eyes on the road and not on their phones. Drivers can also have their incoming text messages read out loud to them using voice control.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/odU8xoJo7wek9bD5knPWRpn9qX8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22871992/Assistant_driving_mode_800px.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ffqojA"&gt;There are also new updates to Android Auto, which mirrors your smartphone’s display on your car’s infotainment screen. Drivers can select which apps they want to see when they first plug their phone into their car (or when it connects via Bluetooth). This also is designed to cut down on driver distraction. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9ZF1uP"&gt;Distraction is a major problem for drivers, especially as infotainment systems become flashier and more complicated. A recent &lt;a href="https://trid.trb.org/view/1694794#:~:text=Self%2Dreported%20data%20suggested%20that,Android%20Auto%20and%20Apple%20CarPlay."&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; found that drivers selecting music with Apple CarPlay or Android Auto had slower reaction times than those who were high from smoking pot. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/29/18117046/android-auto-new-features-updates-music-playback-messaging-safer-less-distraction"&gt;Google has been trying to work its way through this problem&lt;/a&gt; for several years now, but they have yet to arrive at a definitive solution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="cbPVZm"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Distraction is a major problem for drivers&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JrYHkM"&gt;When their car is safely parked, Android Auto customers can play games from GameSnacks right on their car’s display. For those who don’t recognize the name, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/14/21137737/gamesnacks-google-html5-games-area-120-bad-internet-connection-budget-phones"&gt;GameSnacks is Google’s series of HTML5-based browser games&lt;/a&gt; that are meant to be easy to load and play on nearly any device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e7G6B3"&gt;Lastly, Google announced that Android Auto users will soon be able to use Google Pay to pay for gas. After pulling into a gas station, drivers need only select their pump number on the screen and Google Pay will do the rest. (Of course, they’ll still need to get out of the car and pump their gas; Google hasn’t figured out how to automate that yet.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v75aFz"&gt;Automakers have been building payment options into their cars for years now. For example, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/18/17248282/chevrolet-shell-in-car-payment-gas"&gt;Chevrolet has a deal with Shell&lt;/a&gt; that lets drivers pay for gas from their vehicle’s infotainment screen. But this feature has yet to go mainstream. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kHiztD"&gt;The new Google Pay feature will be available at 32,500 gas stations in the US starting with Exxon and Mobil stations, with Shell, Conoco, Phillips 66, and 76 stations coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yk1npz"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fERA7G"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689537/android-auto-google-assistant-driving-mode-dashboard-distraction"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689537/android-auto-google-assistant-driving-mode-dashboard-distraction</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-23T11:59:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-23T11:59:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Halo-themed Xbox Series X and PS5 are now available through Walmart</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/t6etFJjv5JSjBEKdsBpJGRqCC-Q=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69898014/acastro_210511_1777_psRestock_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vBOobq"&gt;Walmart is hosting a big console restock event today, September 23rd, at 12PM ET / 9AM PT.  It’s going to have the PS5 consoles, along with the standard Xbox Series X and the limited edition &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;-themed Series X. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wbMpfd"&gt;In case you’re after that &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt;-themed console, &lt;a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FXbox-Series-X-Halo-Infinite-Limited-Edition-Bundle%2F288604110" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;try your luck at getting one through this link&lt;/a&gt;. Spec-wise, it’s no different than the standard model, but it has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641632/microsoft-xbox-series-x-halo-console-elite-2-controller"&gt;a more alluring design&lt;/a&gt;, both on the console and the included wireless controller. Two things to note: it’s $549.99, costing $50 more than the regular Series X. Another thing is that you won’t receive this until the game launches on November 15th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6F44Hm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10718933"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Mfv5Ml"&gt;Or, you can try to &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FXbox-Series-X%2F141335186&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;get the $499.99 Xbox Series X console&lt;/a&gt;, which has a Blu-ray disc drive, around 800GB of useable (but expandable) storage, and includes a wireless controller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="1LmOSa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9444130"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="9RkL9X"&gt;Getting an Xbox? Consider these add-ons:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="feA9TT"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FMicrosoft-Xbox-Wireless-Headset-for-Xbox-Series-X-S-Xbox-One-and-Windows-10-Devices%2F466809446&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xbox Wireless Headset for $98&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="QsDNIA"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-US%2Fxbox-game-pass%23join&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F23%2F22648984%2Fps5-xbox-series-x-halo-walmart-restock-time" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xbox Game Pass Ultimate is $1 for the first month for new subscribers&lt;/a&gt; ($15 per month otherwise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7DdcY6"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fsearch%3Fq%3Dxbox%2Bcontroller&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xbox Wireless controller for $60&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="HhIaF6"&gt;For people who are eager to get a PlayStation 5, Walmart has both editions of the console available today. &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-PlayStation-5-Video-Game-Console%2F994712501&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;You’ll be able to get the $499.99 version&lt;/a&gt; that has a built-in Blu-ray disc drive and a DualSense controller. &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-PlayStation-5-Digital-Edition-Video-Game-Consoles%2F979738052&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;It’s also going to sell the digital version&lt;/a&gt; that lacks a disc drive for $399.99. Both consoles have around 660GB of useable storage, but they’re expandable via their NVMe M.2 slot. If you just plan on playing PS4 games, you can use a cheaper external USB hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="VwRWZA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10384391"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="twDYRJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9563999"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="ak8TVg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The PS5 SSD buying guide","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22602046/best-ps5-playstation-5-m2-ssd-compatible-drives"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="mO7e2e"&gt;Getting a PS5? Check out these games and accessories:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="pe0i85"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FDeathloop-Arkane-Lyon-Bethesda-Softworks-PlayStation-5%2F495171229&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deathloop &lt;/em&gt;for PS5 costs $60&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hTDuHB"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FDemon-Souls-PlayStation-5%2F741555735%3Fathbdg%3DL1300&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Demon’s Souls&lt;/em&gt; costs $50&lt;/a&gt; (normally $70)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2QCYqD"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fsearch%3Fq%3Ddualsense&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Pick up an extra DualSense controller for $69&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LesDLb"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPS5-PULSE-3D-Wireless-Headset%2F667802535%3Fathbdg%3DL1200&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sony’s Pulse 3D Audio wireless headset costs $99&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="VzMYhI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hVX4te"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KUqIxG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22648984/ps5-xbox-series-x-halo-walmart-restock-time"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22648984/ps5-xbox-series-x-halo-walmart-restock-time</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-23T11:28:58-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-23T11:28:58-04:00</updated>
    <title>Judge orders Facebook to hand over Myanmar officials’ hate posts for genocide case</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="NETHERLANDS-MYANMAR-GAMBIA-ICJ-GENOCIDE-ROHINGYA" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lTqkBxzBEB8P-G7dR0oEIMZs5V4=/9x0:4491x2988/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69898087/1195405178.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by ROBIN VAN LONKHUIJSEN/ANP/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hdlhGq"&gt;A District of Columbia judge &lt;a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.dcd.218820/gov.uscourts.dcd.218820.22.0_1.pdf"&gt;ordered Facebook&lt;/a&gt; to let the Gambia government access deleted posts where Myanmar officials promoted hate against the Rohingya people. The order comes &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-myanmar-facebook/facebook-rejects-request-to-release-myanmar-officials-data-for-genocide-case-idUSKCN2521PI"&gt;more than a year&lt;/a&gt; after Facebook rejected a request for the data — which Gambia seeks to use in a genocide case before the International Court of Justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UMWAYx"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/6/18068104/facebook-business-social-responsibility-myanmar-report"&gt;Facebook has acknowledged&lt;/a&gt; that Myanmar’s military used its app — the country’s &lt;em&gt;de facto&lt;/em&gt; portal to the internet — to portray the Rohingya Muslim minority as a terrorist group. Their now-deleted posts encouraged mass murder, displacement, and other human rights abuses. Facebook has provided information separately to the United Nations Independent Investigative Mechanism for Myanmar, but it called Gambian prosecutors’ requests “extraordinarily broad” and invasive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xcj5hA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The Myanmar officials intended their reach to be public”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lLOj3R"&gt;Magistrate Judge Zia Faruqui found that the relevant Facebook posts weren’t meant as private communications that might get extra legal protection. “Although some of the pages were nominally private, the Myanmar officials intended their reach to be public, and in fact they reached an audience of nearly 12 million followers,” the order says. “Making their accounts and pages private would have defeated their goal of inflaming hate in the widest possible audience.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yktvyq"&gt;The order doesn’t criticize Facebook for deleting the content from public view, but it says Facebook hasn’t shown that handing over private backups of it now would be burdensome or violate the users’ privacy. “Facebook taking up the mantle of privacy rights is rich with irony. News sites have entire sections dedicated to Facebook’s sordid history of privacy scandals,” Faruqui wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UA5fyz"&gt;Facebook must also produce any non-legally privileged records from its investigation into the role Facebook played in the genocide. The records could help prosecutors understand how Facebook connected “seemingly unrelated” accounts to Myanmar government officials, including which accounts were operated out of the same locations. The judge rejected Gambia’s request for a deposition where Facebook would explain the documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="maO1jp"&gt;Judge Faruqui said in the order that he “came to praise Facebook, not to bury it.” But he criticized the company for failing to cooperate with the Gambian government. “Facebook can act now. It took the first step by deleting the content that fueled a genocide. Yet it has stumbled at the next step, sharing that content,” he wrote. “Failing to do so here would compound the tragedy that has befallen the Rohingya.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689559/facebook-rohingya-myanmar-official-data-order-gambia-genocide-trial"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22689559/facebook-rohingya-myanmar-official-data-order-gambia-genocide-trial</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-23T11:22:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-23T11:22:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>Consumer Reports isn’t impressed by Tesla’s reinvention of the (steering) wheel</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HqkNmn44Uzxwfj9piIW7cdbQ_yA=/0x0:1201x801/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69898054/tesla_model_s_witcher_3_3.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Tesla&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="s84wY3"&gt;For &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/5/24/15681470/teslas-consumer-reports-autopilot"&gt;years&lt;/a&gt;, the recommendations and ratings &lt;em&gt;Consumer Reports&lt;/em&gt; assigns to Tesla vehicles have yo-yoed between &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/21/18234740/consumer-reports-tesla-model-3-recommend-remove"&gt;unacceptable&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22555745/consumer-reports-tesla-vision-model-3-top-pick-iihs"&gt;incredible&lt;/a&gt;, usually due to the electric car maker’s unorthodox design and packaging decisions. When Tesla revealed its redesign of the Model S and Model X interiors this spring, future unpleasantness loomed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LGij1l"&gt;While &lt;em&gt;Consumer Reports&lt;/em&gt; lauds consistency and stability, especially for safety and usability, Tesla’s designers ditched the steering wheel and gear selector that drivers are familiar with. Now, drivers steer with a yoke that resembles what you’d find in a race car, while &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/29/22256504/teslas-model-s-x-redesign-automatic-shifting-prnd-gears"&gt;the car itself can make decisions about going forward or backward&lt;/a&gt; when you press the gas pedal unless the driver specifically selects a gear on its touchscreen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="KE8AXS"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Elon: “Yet another round wheel is boring &amp;amp; blocks the screen. FSD in panoramic mode looks way better with a yoke.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LecgY9"&gt;Ahead of more in-depth reviews based on multiple months of testing, &lt;a href="https://www.consumerreports.org/cars-driving/tesla-steering-yoke-little-benefit-potential-safety-pitfalls-a1034204120/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Consumer Reports&lt;/em&gt; dedicated an article to just the yoke&lt;/a&gt; and found that it’s not all bad. Its design does give a better view of the sedan’s gauge cluster, as &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1435917094751768582?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1435917094751768582%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.consumerreports.org%2Fcars-driving%2Ftesla-steering-yoke-little-benefit-potential-safety-pitfalls-a1034204120%2F"&gt;Elon Musk promised&lt;/a&gt;. However, that might not be worth giving up the existence of something to grab if the driver loses their grip while taking a turn at high speeds and a decided lack of padding to ease pressure during long drives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1l0fcz"&gt;The sharper criticism is reserved for the other element Tesla removed from its cars — the turn signal stalk. One driver said it “actually bothers me even more than the steering wheel,” with all the functionality — lights, window washers, etc. — shifted to touch-sensitive buttons mounted on the yoke itself. That means they change position as it turns and can be hard to interpret without the physical feedback of a button. The yoke can vibrate once or twice to indicate which mode you’re in, but on bumpy roads, like the ones we have here in Michigan, that might be hard to distinguish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r0tBNr"&gt;What Tesla buyers are willing to live with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/repkord/status/1440908464625106946"&gt;to experience life on the bleeding edge&lt;/a&gt; should more than cover any awkward grips while steering, but reading these first impressions can help you understand whether different is better in this case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="zMnZxU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Tesla reveals redesigned Model S with new interior and 520-mile range option ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22252832/tesla-model-s-redesign-plaid-mile-range-interior-refresh"},{"title":"Tesla’s new touchscreen drive selector doesn’t violate the rules, NHTSA says","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/25/22351044/tesla-nhtsa-touchscreen-gear-selector-fmvss"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22688377/tesla-steering-wheel-yoke-model-s-x-redesign"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22688377/tesla-steering-wheel-yoke-model-s-x-redesign</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-23T11:02:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-23T11:02:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>How the Microsoft Surface Pro 8 stacks up to the Surface Laptop Studio, Go 3, and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BhR6nf3Uxt3jsIG5S2vARwFZi5g=/625x0:7375x4500/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69897980/Surface_Pro_X___Modes_under_embargo_until_September_22.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="i0aKwb"&gt;At its recent hardware event, Microsoft refreshed almost its entire lineup of Surface products (sorry, Surface Book, but you’re sitting this one out). The company showed off the new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22686705/microsoft-surface-pro-8-keyboard-screen-photos-video-hands-on"&gt;Surface Pro 8&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22684608/microsoft-surface-go-3-processor-specs-price-features"&gt;Go 3&lt;/a&gt;, and it capped off the proceedings with details about its interesting and transforming &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22686706/microsoft-surface-studio-laptop-design-specs-photos-hands-on"&gt;Surface Laptop Studio&lt;/a&gt;. There was more at the event, like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22679573/microsoft-surface-pro-x-display-specs-price-release-date"&gt;Wi-Fi version of the Pro X&lt;/a&gt;, as well as the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22686707/microsoft-surface-duo-2-phone-design-specs-features-photos-hands-on"&gt;Surface Duo 2&lt;/a&gt; folding phone. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22684950/microsoft-surface-event-biggest-announcements-pro-8-duo-studio-laptop"&gt;Here are all of the biggest announcements&lt;/a&gt; if you wanted to see them in one place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="belu8g"&gt;If you’re trying to figure out which of these new Windows 11-equipped machines you should buy, knowing their specs might help you make a decision. But given that they’re different sizes and marketed to different kinds of people, professions, and hobbies, this isn’t exactly a level playing field. And we won’t know exactly how they perform until we review, which will likely happen sometime in October. To give you a little more context, we’ve added the Surface Laptop 4 into the table below since it’s a relatively new model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1IICn8"&gt;Until then, here are all of the specs that matter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="6UV4Dx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to preorder all of the new Surface hardware","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22683783/microsoft-surface-pro-x-8-3-go-laptop-studio-preorder-price-date"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="kNXo4A"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10767940"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="Je9jOC"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="UvHc0a"&gt;Related:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="zuf7MA"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Surface Pro 8 Go 3|103983" data-volume-uuid="915b4ef30" data-volume-id="103983" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-287" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22688116/surface-pro-8-go-3-laptop-studio-4-spec-gpu-power-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22688116/surface-pro-8-go-3-laptop-studio-4-spec-gpu-power-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
