<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-07-20T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-20T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-20T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung announces Unpacked event for August 11th with Galaxy Z Fold and Z Flip teaser</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JJRsXNwsE4SF8Tb9Nn-5nGY2Ngw=/0x0:1200x800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69609266/unpacked.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ymloVB"&gt;Samsung has officially announced when it will hold its next Unpacked product event: August 11th at 10AM ET / 7AM PT. It is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/11/22572858/samsung-galaxy-unpacked-2021-leak-evan-blass-galaxy-z-fold-flip-3-s21-fe-watch-4-buds-2-date"&gt;widely expected&lt;/a&gt; to announce the next version of the Galaxy Z Fold 3 and Galaxy Z Flip 3 — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/24/22549038/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3-flip-leak-image-foldable"&gt;both of which have already leaked quite a bit&lt;/a&gt;. Samsung’s not being shy about those expectations, as a quick look at its invite reveals the outline for both of those devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DMCaRV"&gt;Samsung is also expected to announce new Galaxy watches, which would be the first to use the new combined Wear platform that was announced at Google I/O earlier this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="63RkvA"&gt;Samsung is holding the event virtually again on its website, and it promises to post more &lt;a href="https://smsng.news/2TqTjNm"&gt;details on the livestream here&lt;/a&gt;. It’s also keeping up another Samsung trend: &lt;a href="https://shopsamsung.page.link/A1gWkiA6yiC9Xvvt7"&gt;letting customers “reserve” “its next flagship”&lt;/a&gt; before it’s even been officially announced. Samsung says it will offer “increased trade-in credit and 12 months of Samsung Care+ at a discounted rate” for early reservations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pIeRnR"&gt;According to the images leaked by Evan Blass, the Galaxy Z Fold 3 looks very similar to the current iteration of the folding phone. The largest upgrade will apparently be compatibility with Samsung’s S Pen stylus. Samsung itself has been telegraphing that it would add stylus support to the Fold line for a very long time now.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qZULQKv1zeeuJKAzVV0v4dZAQrE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22679450/E4qkWBHXwAgIQ_W.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1408107239903223808?s=21" target="_blank"&gt;Evan Blass / Twitter&lt;/a&gt; (tweet now deleted)&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="4zpnFF"&gt;As for the Galaxy Z Flip 3, the biggest update may be on the outside, where Samsung will replace a very tiny screen with a slightly larger but still fairly small screen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ooz3x6"&gt;Samsung has done a better job with durability on its folding devices since it switched over to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/19/21142728/samsung-foldable-glass-galaxy-z-flip-explained-schott-corning"&gt;using “Ultra thin glass”&lt;/a&gt; under a plastic sheet for these displays. However, the screens are still much more fragile than regular smartphone screens. If Samsung is intending to encourage users to poke at the Z Fold 3’s screen with a plastic stick, that folding screen will need to become more durable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="KgHEKq"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="und" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://t.co/cLlE0ot4fO"&gt;pic.twitter.com/cLlE0ot4fO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Evan Blass (@evleaks) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1413734400420896768?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4Afejm"&gt;Though it’s not likely to get top billing, the new Galaxy smartwatches are likely to be a bigger shift than the iterative updates to the folding phones. That’s because it’ll be the first Samsung smartwatch to run Google’s Wear operating system in over half a decade. Samsung had been using its own Tizen-based OS on smartwatches, which had benefits over Google’s Wear OS but did not have an app library worth using. Now that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22440483/samsung-smartwatch-google-wearos-tizen-watch"&gt;the two operating systems are combined&lt;/a&gt;, this upcoming Samsung watch will be our first real look at what the new Wear operating system really works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6G3NZn"&gt;We are expecting both a Samsung Galaxy Watch 4 with a rotating bezel and a Samsung Galaxy Watch Active 4 without to be announced, both in multiple colors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ITtldf"&gt;It’s always possible there will be more on tap — Samsung’s Galaxy Buds lineup could also be due for a new model. We’ll find out for sure when Samsung kicks off its livestream on August 11th. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585256/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-flip-watch-unpacked-event-august"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585256/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-flip-watch-unpacked-event-august</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-20T19:14:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-20T19:14:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>A fix is coming for those locked out of their Chromebooks by Google’s update</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IGDNtT94BgE2U_2DM88YHB9UrV0=/0x186:1360x1093/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69609149/mchin_181029_4126_0002sq.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Zvs0vw"&gt;A bad update to Chrome OS, version 91.0.4472.165, has left some users unable to log in to their accounts, or reportedly with boot-looping computers (&lt;a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/second-major-chrome-os-update-bug-leaving-users-locked-out-chromebooks"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Android Central&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). If you’ve found yourself locked out of your Chromebook, help is on the way: Google posted &lt;a href="https://support.cloud.google.com/portal/system-status"&gt;on its system status page&lt;/a&gt; that it’s working on a fix, which it expects to release on Wednesday. It’s also pulled the update, which should prevent more users from experiencing the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WRKjwL"&gt;According to Google, the only options to immediately regain access to your Chrome OS device (if it unfortunately downloaded and installed the update) will lead to the local data on the device being wiped. If you can wait until the new fix the issue is released, though, your device should automatically download that update as well. Or, you can manually trigger the update using the guest account. If your computer has downloaded the bad update but not installed it, you might want to avoid shutting it down or rebooting it until the fix is out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Tyv3MS"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The second bad Chrome OS update we’ve seen this month&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eQ5rVb"&gt;If you can’t wait for the fixed update, Google recommends either &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/chromebook/answer/183084?hl=en"&gt;“Powerwashing” (factory resetting) your Chrome OS device&lt;/a&gt;, rolling back the update &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/chromebook/answer/1080595?hl=en"&gt;with a recovery USB key&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/chromebook/answer/1059260?hl=en#zippy="&gt;removing your account and re-adding it&lt;/a&gt;. Again, all these solutions will delete local data on the device, so be careful. Google’s status page also doesn’t address the boot looping issues — &lt;a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/second-major-chrome-os-update-bug-leaving-users-locked-out-chromebooks?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+androidcentral+%28Android+Central%29"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Central&lt;/em&gt; says&lt;/a&gt; that if you’re experiencing those issues you’ll have to use the recovery USB key method to reinstall Chrome OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KT04LY"&gt;The broken 91.0.4472.165 update is actually the second bad Chrome OS update we’ve seen this month: &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/07/16/chrome-os-91-performance-issues-chromebooks/"&gt;Google had to pull another update&lt;/a&gt; around July 7th after users discovered that some Chromebooks were having their performance seriously throttled. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585979/chrome-os-91-chromebook-lock-screen-issue-fix-coming-soon"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585979/chrome-os-91-chromebook-lock-screen-issue-fix-coming-soon</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-20T19:06:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-20T19:06:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>An on-the-ground look at Blue Origin’s motley crew </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ohq-T7szdIwKZnts-fcaGLC8ogc=/0x0:4182x2788/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69609133/_MG_4801_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Jeff Bezos, his brother Mark and Oliver Daemen walk off New Shepard’s landing pad as Wally Funk, 82-year-old aviation icon and the mission’s fourth passenger, remains in awe at the size of New Shepard, the suborbital rocket they all launched to space on. | Joey Roulette/The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;A record-setting flight&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="vAdeNf"&gt;Today, Wally Funk, 81, and Oliver Daemen, 18, made history as the oldest and youngest people ever to go to space. They &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22582735/blue-origin-jeff-bezos-space-launch-landing"&gt;hitched a ride with Jeff Bezos&lt;/a&gt; and his brother, Mark, aboard the New Shepard, a rocket made by Bezos’ company, Blue Origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vZ2NPS"&gt;Blue Origin will eventually sell seats, though Bezos declined to say how much they’d sell for. “We’ll be announcing that later,” Bezos said, when &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; asked how much his company plans to charge. When’s “later?” “We’re not quite sure yet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jksRet"&gt;Daemen was the first paying customer — though he didn’t win the June auction for the seat. That winner, who remains anonymous, bid $28 million to fly, but had to reschedule for vague “scheduling conflicts.” (Blue Origin would not identify the bidder or explain what the issue was.) Daemen’s dad, a Dutch private equity firm’s CEO, was bumped up from the next mission, and gave the seat to his son.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zGNKTc"&gt;“We know the vehicle is safe. If the vehicle is not safe for me, it’s not safe for anyone,” Bezos said in an interview with CNN. If nothing else, it’s good advertising for space tourism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0hqGOJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10661263"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585956/blue-origin-crew-photo-launch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585956/blue-origin-crew-photo-launch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-20T18:20:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-20T18:20:29-04:00</updated>
    <title>Where to preorder the Nintendo Switch OLED model</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/evcDNXAUvZ90QSh1sO3zM2YmJ8A=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69587172/oled_model_photo_01.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="guw0Bh"&gt;After months of speculation and a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/23/22346041/oled-nintendo-switch-dlss-nvidia-chip-report"&gt;sea of rumors&lt;/a&gt;, Nintendo &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/6/22456337/nintendo-switch-oled-model-specs-date-price"&gt;officially announced&lt;/a&gt; the next iteration of its popular gaming console: the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22569208/nintendo-switch-oled-model-hands-on-screen"&gt;Nintendo Switch OLED model&lt;/a&gt;. The upcoming device serves more as a midlife update than anything else, a refinement of the 2019 model as opposed to the more powerful “Switch Pro” that was rumored (and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/6/22565469/nintendo-switch-pro-oled-timing-chip-shortages-cpu-nvidia-tegra"&gt;may still launch&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HKuikp"&gt;On sale for $350 starting October 8th, the aptly-titled &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/6/22565307/nintendo-oled-switch-screen-news-updates"&gt;Nintendo Switch OLED model&lt;/a&gt; is the next iteration of what has become one of the best-selling consoles &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21562530/nintendo-switch-lite-sales-october-2020"&gt;over the last two years&lt;/a&gt;. It’s outfitted with a 7-inch 720p OLED display, a new dock with a wired Ethernet port, and an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/6/22564942/nintendo-switch-oled-screen-new-kickstand"&gt;improved kickstand&lt;/a&gt; that seems to take a cue directly from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/23/21526702/microsoft-surface-pro-x-2020-review-arm-windows-10-apps-features-specs-price"&gt;Microsoft’s Surface Pro tablets&lt;/a&gt;. It also offers 64GB of built-in storage, up to nine hours of battery life — the same as the current Switch — and features “enhanced audio” for handheld or tabletop play. Sadly, despite persistent &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22312559/new-nintendo-switch-oled-screen-holiday-release-report"&gt;rumors of 4K support&lt;/a&gt;, the OLED model only supports 1080p resolution when docked. Apparently, Bluetooth support and an improved CPU will also have to wait. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="6ASo1a"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Nintendo denies report that OLED Switch will have higher profit margin","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583141/nintendo-switch-oled-profit-margin-report-denial"},{"title":"Nintendo Switch OLED hands-on: a small upgrade that makes a big difference","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22569208/nintendo-switch-oled-model-hands-on-screen"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="UyweAO"&gt;Still, the OLED model has plenty to get people excited, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/6/22564966/nintendo-switch-oled-display-ps5-xbox"&gt;including our own Alex Cranz&lt;/a&gt;. It plays all the same games, supports the original Joy-Cons, and ships with a sleek black-and-white finish reminiscent of next-gen consoles like the PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series S. It will also be available with the red and blue Joy-Cons, if you prefer the original model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="HnhAvm"&gt;Where to buy the Nintendo Switch OLED model&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="5An2L3"&gt;The Nintendo Switch OLED model initially went up for preorder on Thursday, and we’ve seen a few retailers allow for additional preorders in the time since. However, if you’re still looking to get your hands on the OLED-equipped Switch at launch and get ahead of what already appears to be another console shortage, you’re in luck. Right now, you can preorder the red and blue iteration of the forthcoming console for $350 at &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fconsoles%2Fproducts%2Fnintendo-switch-oled-with-blue-and-red-joy-con%2F11149259.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GameStop&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zikzMn"&gt;The white model is currently unavailable for preorder, though neither configuration is expected to ship until the console officially goes on sale on October 8th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ndcSNr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10653518"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WWUUxL"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DKRskI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22565905/nintendo-switch-oled-model-preorder-price-availability-where-to-buy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22565905/nintendo-switch-oled-model-preorder-price-availability-where-to-buy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Brandon Widder</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-20T17:01:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-20T17:01:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>Chrome for iOS will let you lock down incognito tabs with Face ID</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DhHxQL4W5zfgv8dotss3F2Kwiec=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69608611/acastro_180416_1777_chrome_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zVFCrm"&gt;Chrome’s latest update for iOS will let you secure your incognito tabs with Touch ID, Face ID, or a passcode (&lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/07/20/chrome-biometric-authentication-incognito-tabs/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). When the new feature is rolled out to you, you can turn it on by navigating to the settings menu, then tapping “Privacy,” then “Lock Incognito tabs.” I just updated the app and the option wasn’t there for me, so you might have to wait just a bit until you can flip it on. Google first revealed it was testing this new privacy feature &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22279719/google-chrome-face-id-incognito-mode-ios-support-feature"&gt;in February&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JHl2DH"&gt;The update brings a few other handy features to Google’s mobile browser, including the ability to take a full-page screenshot of a website. You can use it by snapping a screenshot with the button combination specific to your device, tapping the screenshot preview, and then tapping over to the “Full Page” tab that will appear, &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/07/20/chrome-92-ios/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. (I don’t have this feature yet, either.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aCbS8Y"&gt;You can download Chrome 92 &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/google-chrome/id535886823"&gt;from the App Store now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585624/chrome-ios-92-incognito-tabs-with-face-touch-id-passcode-full-page-screenshots"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585624/chrome-ios-92-incognito-tabs-with-face-touch-id-passcode-full-page-screenshots</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-20T16:44:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-20T16:44:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>Instagram introduces a setting to control sensitive content in your Explore tab</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R5W-igcNyErp031220QpoAoSJos=/0x0:890x593/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69608523/CD21_455_NRP_IG_Sensitivity_Content_Control_Inline.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RW1A3k"&gt;&lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/07/introducing-sensitive-content-control/"&gt;Facebook is announcing&lt;/a&gt; a new setting that allows you to limit how much potentially sensitive content shows up in your Instagram Explore tab. According to Facebook, the new Sensitive Content Control setting will let you “see more or less of some types of sensitive content,” which may be “upsetting or offensive.” How much content the three levels, “Allow,” “Limit (Default),” and “Limit Even More” will or will not show is pretty vague, and we’ve reached out to Facebook for clarification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4DfRl7"&gt;On &lt;a href="https://help.instagram.com/251027992727268"&gt;the support page for Sensitive Content Control&lt;/a&gt;, Instagram says that sensitive content could include sexually suggestive or violent posts, as well as posts that promote things like tobacco or pharmaceutical use. Facebook is clear that this setting is based on its &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/help/instagram/313829416281232"&gt;Recommendation Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;, which govern what can show up on the Explore page, and not &lt;a href="https://help.instagram.com/477434105621119"&gt;its Community Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="8XW7FB"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Graphic” violence or nudity will still be taken off the site&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="p6kT1b"&gt;Posts that flat-out violate Facebook’s rules will still be removed, Sensitive Content Control just gives users more options about how much they want to be exposed to content that could be upsetting in the Explore tab. For example, &lt;a href="https://help.instagram.com/251027992727268"&gt;Facebook says&lt;/a&gt; content showing a fight or people in see-through clothing may be considered “sensitive,” and therefore shouldn’t show up on the Explore page for people who have sensitive content limits. “Graphic” violence or nudity, however, would be taken off the site and wouldn’t show up even for those who have Sensitive Content Control set to “Allow.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kKYAVV"&gt;Facebook didn’t respond to a request for comment on how much of a difference the setting makes to the amount of potentially sensitive content that’s shown to a user. The descriptions shown in Facebook’s screenshot of the feature, seen at the top of this article, are a bit vague, though — the Limit Even More setting doesn’t say that you won’t see sensitive content, just that you “may” see fewer posts that “could” be upsetting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Pabmy2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The descriptions of how much content will be shown are a bit vague&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="I6Kgqh"&gt;According to Facebook, the setting will be accessible by going to your profile, then tapping Settings &amp;gt; Account &amp;gt; Sensitive Content Control. The feature doesn’t seem to have rolled out to all users yet: the option didn’t appear for me or a few of my colleagues. Facebook says that the setting to allow sensitive content may not be available to people under 18 years old. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VRoeXB"&gt;This announcement comes at a time when many social networks, especially &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/30/22557942/instagram-no-longer-photo-app-video-entertainment-focus"&gt;photo and video sharing platforms&lt;/a&gt;, are trying to figure out how to deal with content that may be upsetting to some users but engaging for others. Last year, TikTok &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22175889/tiktok-updated-community-guidelines-violent-disturbing-content-warning-labels-opt-in-vaccine-info"&gt;introduced warning screens&lt;/a&gt; for potentially graphic videos, and Pinterest recently announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22558960/pinterest-weight-loss-ads-ban-social-media"&gt;a ban on weight loss ads&lt;/a&gt;. Instagram itself tries to blur out images that could be potentially triggering for people struggling with eating disorders, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295693/instagram-eating-disorder-resources-help-lines"&gt;and provides resources&lt;/a&gt; to users searching for content related to disordered eating. Today’s announcement doesn’t seem to signal a drastic change for the Explore page, but it should give people a bit more control over what they see on it.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585623/instagram-sensitive-content-control-setting-explore-tab-limit-offensive-posts"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585623/instagram-sensitive-content-control-setting-explore-tab-limit-offensive-posts</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-20T16:36:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-20T16:36:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>HBO Max launches a group watch tool to stream full episodes on Snapchat </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ro3z3-ZVgfwVfP6uFGADmUpT3Uc=/0x8:2414x1617/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69608483/Triptych.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;HBO Max Minis shown on a mobile device.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: HBO Max&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jxfYD5"&gt;HBO Max has partnered with Snapchat to bring full-length episodes of its series to the social media platform. With HBO Max Minis, users will be able to stream the pilots of select series with up to 63 other Snapchatters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LYf8Mk"&gt;The feature was &lt;a href="https://pressroom.warnermedia.com/us/media-release/hbo-max-brings-free-episodes-snapchat-new-app-co-viewing-experience"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; today and is offered through Minis, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/11/21286537/snap-minis-snapchat-partner-summit-2020-announcements"&gt;launched late last year&lt;/a&gt; and hosts third-party app experiences within Snapchat. Minis allow users to do anything from meditate with Headspace to buy movie tickets with friends through Atom. And now, HBO Max Minis will allow anyone on Snapchat to view entire episodes of more than a dozen series from the streaming service for free, including pilots from &lt;em&gt;Lovecraft Country&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt;. With synchronized playback, everyone watching the title will be able to stream the same title together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QYIfX0"&gt;Snapchat users will be able to access the HBO Max episodes through search or by clicking the rocket icon from chat. Once HBO Max Mini is launched, users will be required to verify their date of birth, which will filter which episodes are streamable. The &lt;a href="https://pressroom.warnermedia.com/us/media-release/hbo-max-brings-free-episodes-snapchat-new-app-co-viewing-experience"&gt;full list of episodes&lt;/a&gt; available to stream on an age-restricted basis are as follows: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="OGHEah"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Betty&lt;/em&gt; (season 2, episode 1)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WaH0vI"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Craftopia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="1nXfAp"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Euphoria&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EG7Ru9"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Flight Attendant&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LqqCQp"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cRIeoW"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Genera+ion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0AqE1P"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Gossip Girl&lt;/em&gt; (2021)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lCEPUT"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Looney Tunes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fBQE9E"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Love Life&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fSpDFE"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lovecraft Country&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PABfbq"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Selena + Chef&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="taQVym"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Titans&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="VepaBg"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warrior&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="tesUZN"&gt;&lt;em&gt;World of Calm&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="RbU42y"&gt;Up to 64 users can join an HBO Max Mini session through a shared in-chat link or by clicking a shared sticker, and users will be able to chat and send reactions while streaming a title. The pilot episodes from the aforementioned series are free to stream even to users who aren’t subscribed to HBO Max. But users who are 18 years old and above will be prompted to subscribe to HBO Max to continue streaming a series once the pilot episode has ended. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2WCklbMEPfH1e6fc8Frn6ivBAQI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22729138/unnamed__2_.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: HBO Max&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;In-app streaming with HBO Max Minis.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="nYj9Hn"&gt;Watch parties are an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/22092452/hulu-watch-party-now-available-all-subscribers"&gt;increasingly&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/11/21432411/disney-plus-watch-party-feature-test-canada-scener-netflix-amazon-prime-video"&gt;popular&lt;/a&gt; feature launched by major streamers. Apple, for example, is releasing a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22526742/apple-facetime-shareplay-ios-15-watch-party"&gt;FaceTime integration&lt;/a&gt; later this year to support group streaming with SharePlay, but many streamers like Prime Video, Hulu, and Disney Plus have their own in-app group watch tools. HBO Max’s arrival on Minis marks the first major streamer to support streaming entire episodes without ever leaving Snapchat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KFL76x"&gt;“People love to come together to watch their favorite HBO Max shows and talk about what’s unfolding,” Sarah Lyons, EVP of DTC global product management at HBO Max, said in a statement. “Our partnership with Snapchat is another step towards fulfilling that desire for human connection and providing our fans with co-viewing opportunities, while deepening their emotional relationship with the brand.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585753/hbo-max-mini-group-watch-snapchat"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585753/hbo-max-mini-group-watch-snapchat</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-20T16:22:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-20T16:22:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix’s gaming expansion starts with mobile</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wT03y_BYKhH9s7Od7inytuRN6MQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69608381/acastro_181101_1777_netflix_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SWOM4W"&gt;Netflix revealed that its initial efforts in gaming will be focused on mobile games and that the games will be included with users’ Netflix subscriptions, the company announced as part of its second-quarter earnings report on Tuesday. The news comes just days after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22577868/netflix-video-games-confirmed-mike-verdu-ea-oculus-facebook"&gt;the company said it hired&lt;/a&gt; former EA and Oculus exec Mike Verdu to head up its gaming work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IyHJ5A"&gt;Here is exactly what Netflix said about gaming, &lt;a href="https://s22.q4cdn.com/959853165/files/doc_financials/2021/q2/FINAL-Q2-21-Shareholder-Letter.pdf"&gt;from its letter to investors&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="sm3E6C"&gt;We’re also in the early stages of further expanding into games, building on our earlier efforts around interactivity (eg, &lt;em&gt;Black Mirror Bandersnatch&lt;/em&gt;) and our &lt;em&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/em&gt; games. We view gaming as another new content category for us, similar to our expansion into original films, animation and unscripted TV. Games will be included in members’ Netflix subscription at no additional cost similar to films and series. Initially, we’ll be primarily focused on games for mobile devices. We’re excited as ever about our movies and TV series offering and we expect a long runway of increasing investment and growth across all of our existing content categories, but since we are nearly a decade into our push into original programming, we think the time is right to learn more about how our members value games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="OPRa37"&gt;There are still no details on what types of games will actually be available, though Netflix recently extended its TV deal with Shonda Rhimes &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/tv/news/netflix-shonda-rhimes-extend-deal-to-include-feature-films-gaming-and-virtual-reality-content-1235014998/"&gt;to include feature films and gaming content&lt;/a&gt;. There’s also no word on how games will be delivered to Netflix subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oXDMdT"&gt;The company has acknowledged in the past that it competes with games for time and attention, with co-CEO Reed Hastings writing that “we compete with (and lose to) &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; more than HBO” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/17/18187357/netflix-views-numbers-disney-amazon-fortnite-youtube-earnings-bird-box"&gt;in 2019&lt;/a&gt;. COO Greg Peters discussed the company’s interest in games in April (&lt;a href="https://s22.q4cdn.com/959853165/files/doc_financials/2021/q1/Netflix-Inc.-Q1-2021-Earnings-Call-Apr-20-2021.pdf"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;) as part of its first quarter earnings. And the company has already dipped its toes into gaming with experiences like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/2/18165182/black-mirror-bandersnatch-netflix-interactive-strategy-marketing"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Black Mirror: Bandersnatch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/25/21152973/netflix-carmen-sandiego-interactive-special-black-mirror-gaming"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Carmen Sandiego&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FV1aJe"&gt;But with the recent hiring of Verdu and the new information shared Tuesday about its initial plans, now it seems like Netflix is more focused on games than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="9bQ5Ri"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Netflix snags former EA, Oculus exec to lead its video game efforts","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22577868/netflix-video-games-confirmed-mike-verdu-ea-oculus-facebook"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585802/netflix-gaming-mobile-subscription-earnings"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585802/netflix-gaming-mobile-subscription-earnings</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-20T16:20:40-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-20T16:20:40-04:00</updated>
    <title>Square launches checking and savings accounts for small businesses</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eTajYh-zTRqtFianwDXWUqTVGhs=/38x0:2438x1600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69608373/square_register_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Square&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="px4Oqe"&gt;Square is &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fsquareup.com%2Fus%2Fen%2Fpress%2Fintroducing-square-banking&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F7%2F20%2F22585365%2Fsquare-banking-checking-savings-business-accounts" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;launching a new free banking service&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday that connects to the payment and point-of-sale products the company already offers to small businesses. &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fsquareup.com%2Fus%2Fen%2Fbanking&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F7%2F20%2F22585365%2Fsquare-banking-checking-savings-business-accounts" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Square Banking&lt;/a&gt; combines checking accounts, savings accounts, and Square’s existing small business loans (now called Square Loans) into a package that the company claims is both fair and accessible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hpxnK4"&gt;In terms of features, Square’s new savings account can automatically set aside money from every sale made on Square’s platform. Square Savings will also let users create custom folders for saving toward specific goals. Funds in a Square Checking account will be instantly available to use for payroll and other payments using a Square debit card, and Square says its accounts have no account minimums, overdraft fees, or recurring fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xAU9Qa"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A Square closed loop&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eJ7Xih"&gt;Square says Square Loans are offered based on a small business owner’s previous sales history through its platform &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fsquareup.com%2Fhelp%2Fus%2Fen%2Farticle%2F6454-square-capital-eligibility-faqs&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F7%2F20%2F22585365%2Fsquare-banking-checking-savings-business-accounts" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;rather than their credit score&lt;/a&gt;. The company hasn’t made any dramatic changes to its loan service (formerly Square Capital), but users will be able to pay off their loan with a percentage of each sale on Square, and Square says in the future loans will be available immediately in a Square Checking account once approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NlnJ5S"&gt;Given &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2017/5/4/15552912/square-cash-debit-card-black-rollout-launch-jack-dorsey"&gt;the banking features&lt;/a&gt; already baked into Square’s consumer-facing Cash app, it makes sense it would go all-out for its original customer base. The quasi-closed loop of taking payments through Square, keeping money in a Square account, and then spending money with a Square debit card also keep things simple for business owners, provided they’re comfortable putting all their eggs in one basket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2hhMcn"&gt;You can sign up your small business for &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fsquareup.com%2Fus%2Fen%2Fbanking&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F7%2F20%2F22585365%2Fsquare-banking-checking-savings-business-accounts" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a free Square Banking account&lt;/a&gt; today.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585365/square-banking-checking-savings-business-accounts"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585365/square-banking-checking-savings-business-accounts</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-20T15:43:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-20T15:43:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Fortnite’s Short Nite film festival is coming back on July 23rd</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yHYI4aOXL-QLV6z3_9mKesRxi84=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69608171/fortnite_gildedguy_items_1920x1080_0923ded75d70.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bqo6rX"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; is hosting a second round of its animated short film festival, dubbed “Short Nite 2,” — a successor to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22278892/fortnite-film-festival-short-nite-party-royale"&gt;game’s original Short Nite festival&lt;/a&gt; that developer Epic held earlier this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jEmHzi"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.epicgames.com/fortnite/en-US/news/short-nite-2-watch-web-shorts-on-the-big-screen-in-fortnites-party-royale"&gt;According to Epic&lt;/a&gt;, Short Nite 2 will feature “a series of animated, online shorts by up-and-coming-creators,” which, like the original event, will air on the game’s combat-free Party Royale mode. Short Nite 2 will kick off on Friday, July 23rd, at 2PM ET, and last for about 40 minutes. If you can’t make the debut, the short films will continue to play nonstop until 2PM ET on July 25th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="aQopTL"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Another short film festival is on its way&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bsJzAf"&gt;The developer hasn’t announced the full list yet, but it’s highlighting that the stream will feature two Gildedguy animated shorts, including a debut of a new short film in the series, &lt;em&gt;Gildedguy Gets Up!. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yjmf8S"&gt;To celebrate, Epic is also releasing Gildedguy as a character skin in &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; itself — it’ll be available to purchase from the item shop starting July 22nd at 8PM ET. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qVfw1F"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Get ready for another round of animated shorts on the Big Screen&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Short Nite 2 comes to Party Royale starting at 2 PM ET on July 23 &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Catch online shorts made by up-and-coming creators from around the world including the premiere of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GildedguyArt?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@GildedguyArt&lt;/a&gt; Gets Up!&lt;a href="https://t.co/s4wqQ3aplv"&gt;https://t.co/s4wqQ3aplv&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/NMXqa9QdzA"&gt;pic.twitter.com/NMXqa9QdzA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Fortnite (@FortniteGame) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FortniteGame/status/1417515005554135042?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 20, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585705/fortnite-short-nite-2-film-festival-party-royale-july-23rd"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585705/fortnite-short-nite-2-film-festival-party-royale-july-23rd</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
