<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2022-01-04T06:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-04T06:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-04T06:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Ford says it will double production of electric F-150 Lightning to 150,000 trucks per year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SWE9qnivzhRAKSa3ig9rDn1D9Pc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70345002/akrales_20210526_4595_0008.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zYy5xW"&gt;Ford says its planning to double production of its upcoming electric pickup truck, the F-150 Lightning, to 150,000 vehicles per year by 2023. The news comes as the automaker prepares to start making and shipping its new EV in the first half of 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mj2v6i"&gt;Production of both the F-150 Lightning and F-150 Lightning Pro for commercial customers has entered its final pre-build stage this week at the company’s Rouge Electric Vehicle Center in Dearborn, Michigan. Deliveries of the first trucks are expected to start in the spring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1TseoZ"&gt;The number of electric F-150s Ford planned on making in its first few years of production has been a bit of a shifting target. At first, the company was only targeting 40,000 vehicles annually, eventually telling suppliers it expected that capacity to rise to 80,000 by early 2023, &lt;a href="https://www.autonews.com/retail/ford-caps-f-150-lightning-reservations-near-200000-production-nears"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Automotive News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Now, that number has risen dramatically to 150,000 trucks by mid-2023, a spokesperson said. (As to how many it will make in its first year of production, the spokesperson said more details would be shared later.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="fI81ec"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Ford has not disclosed how many electric trucks it plans to make in its first year of production&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iymFxj"&gt;Ford also recently announced that it was tripling production for the Mustang Mach-E, with the expectation that it will reach over 200,000 units per year by 2023. Ford’s electric delivery van, the E-Transit, also goes on sale early this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ti1UNl"&gt;Ford also announced that starting January 6th, the first reservation holders will be able to start selecting the options and trim levels for their trucks. The company is using a “wave-by-wave reservation process” to inform customers when they can go online to spec out their Lightnings. Ford recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22826469/ford-f150-lightning-ev-deposits-reservations-closed"&gt;stopped taking reservations&lt;/a&gt; after having collected 200,000 refundable $100 deposits for the Lightning since it debuted in May 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q3Wjfq"&gt;The F-150 Lightning starts at $39,974 but can more than double in price depending on which version people buy. Some Ford dealers are reportedly taking advantage of strong demand for the Lightning &lt;a href="https://jalopnik.com/f-150-lightning-orders-havent-even-started-but-the-truc-1848232090"&gt;by marking up the price&lt;/a&gt; by as much as $30,000. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MmsI8T7o0idNhg1SQ5mS_mK_fG0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22638201/akrales_20210526_4595_0115.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="yi4Gsk"&gt;That base model is supposed to offer around 230 miles of range and has a more bare-bones interior, including a 12-inch landscape touchscreen display. Higher trims will come with the same 15.5-inch vertical touchscreen from the Mustang Mach-E, and there’s an extended range battery option that can push the range to around 300 miles. Towing capacity ranges between 7,700 and 10,000 pounds, depending on the configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4kvNBq"&gt;As long as they start shipping on time, Ford will join Rivian and GMC as the only automakers with an electric pickup truck on the market. (Rivian started &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774403/rivian-ipo-debut-evs-12-billion-amazon-tesla-valuation"&gt;shipping its R1T pickup in October&lt;/a&gt;, while the first &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/18/22843805/gm-ev-hummer-pickup-truck-delivery"&gt;Hummer EVs reached customers&lt;/a&gt; at the end of the year.) Tesla’s long-promised Cybertruck &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/8/22615539/tesla-cybertruck-production-delayed-2022-elon-musk"&gt;has been pushed to next year&lt;/a&gt;, and CEO Elon Musk has said his company won’t start making them in large volumes until 2023.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22865664/ford-f150-lightning-double-production-150000-annual"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22865664/ford-f150-lightning-double-production-150000-annual</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-03T21:59:32-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-03T21:59:32-05:00</updated>
    <title>Verizon, AT&amp;T reverse course and will delay 5G expansions for two weeks as the FAA requested</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Verizon CEO Hans Vestberg" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iuFRTAf0PHNydVwYcJ9mEWFLDsw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70344446/vzw-042.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Verizon CEO Hans Vestberg | Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WJ8yHk"&gt;In a standoff that’s pitting Verizon, AT&amp;amp;T, and the FCC versus the FAA and the airline industry over the two carrier’s plans to upgrade their 5G wireless services, the mobile companies now say they’ve reached an agreement with the Department of Transportation. For Verizon, delaying the launch of the “C-band” spectrum means canceling a celebration scheduled for 1PM ET on Tuesday, marking the beginning of its spectrum upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="4PKeGY"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Tune in to the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/UltraShow?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#UltraShow&lt;/a&gt; on 1/4 at 1PM ET and see where streaming, gaming, and the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NFL?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@NFL&lt;/a&gt; are going. Hosted by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ElizabethBanks?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@ElizabethBanks&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/terrycrews?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@TerryCrews&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; more!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;❤️ this tweet for   updates, a HUGE reveal, and exclusive content!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Coming    &lt;a href="https://t.co/X3p9TpOm2l"&gt;https://t.co/X3p9TpOm2l&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/RnrMvwG5p5"&gt;pic.twitter.com/RnrMvwG5p5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Verizon (@Verizon) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Verizon/status/1477293571917037569?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 1, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="13Jh1R"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verizon&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="rMYxwM"&gt;We’ve agreed to a two-week delay which promises the certainty of bringing this nation our game-changing 5G network in January, delivered over America’s best and most reliable network&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="IuoOgm"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="S6Cpgi"&gt;At Secretary Buttigieg’s request, we have voluntarily agreed to one additional two-week delay of our deployment of C-Band 5G services. We also remain committed to the six-month protection zone mitigations we outlined in our letter. We know aviation safety and 5G can co-exist and we are confident further collaboration and technical assessment will allay any issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="e5TVMG"&gt;FAA Communications deputy assistant administrator Jeannie Shiffer provided a statement to The Verge saying, “Safety is the core of our mission and this guides all of our decisions. The FAA thanks AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon for agreeing to a voluntary delay and for their proposed mitigations. We look forward to using the additional time and space to reduce flight disruptions associated with this 5G deployment.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bFugOD"&gt;She also says that the agreement will see the companies use mitigations similar to those already in place in European countries. The deal will see those mitigations put in place around 50 airports for six months, and now the FAA says, “While U.S. standards and operating environments are unique, we believe this could substantially reduce the disruptions to air operations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3F09yQ"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T CEO John Stankey and Verizon CEO Hans Vestberg wrote, “Agreeing to your proposal would not only be an unprecedented and unwarranted circumvention of the due process and checks and balances carefully crafted in the structure of our democracy, but an irresponsible abdication of the operating control required to deploy world-class and globally competitive communications networks that are every bit as essential to our country’s economic vitality, public safety and national interests as the airline industry.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1amsgq"&gt;The companies said they would not give in to the FAA and DOT’s request to delay their (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22763502/verizon-att-cband-5g-faa-delay-safety-aircraft"&gt;already delayed by 30 days&lt;/a&gt;) C-band spectrum upgrades for an additional two weeks. The executives continued to propose mitigations like the ones used in France, creating a buffer zone around certain airports and lowering power levels nationwide.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bh1Ukl"&gt;According to the FAA, the controversy exists because of “concerns that the 5G signal could interfere with the accuracy of an airplane’s radio altimeter, without other mitigations in place,” according to the FAA. Those altimeters are crucial for automated landings, and the FAA claims that rolling out the changes could disrupt air travel or impact safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NXV9sV"&gt;Earlier this year, an FCC auction &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299903/fcc-cband-auction-results-verizon-att-tmobile"&gt;sold the two carriers rights to use so-called “C-band” frequencies at a price of nearly $70 billion&lt;/a&gt;. Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T are eager to roll it out so that in addition to offering ultra-fast 5G connectivity in specific areas using high-band millimeter-wave technology and much slower 5G over low-band frequencies, the new spectrum will provide in-between performance over much wider areas. T-Mobile &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/26/22746708/att-5g-plus-expansion-tmobile"&gt;currently uses mid-band spectrum that isn’t in the C-band&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mMGE1k"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 3rd, 9:59PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added a statement from FAA, information about the agreement, and confirmation that Verizon has canceled its launch event.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22866098/faa-dot-verizon-fcc-att-5g-c-band-delay-airplane-safety"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22866098/faa-dot-verizon-fcc-att-5g-c-band-delay-airplane-safety</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-03T21:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-03T21:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Galaxy S21 FE officially joins Samsung’s crowded midrange lineup</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BwdK3tp4I1yjbLPPi9iSg7d79c4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70344380/ajohnson_220102_4951_0006.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The less-expensive Fan Edition of the S21 includes a 6.4-inch 120Hz display.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yWTBNU"&gt;After a year of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22532816/samsung-galaxy-s21-fe-production-reportedly-halted"&gt;will-they-or-won’t-they speculation&lt;/a&gt;, Samsung has, at last, announced the Galaxy S21 FE. Like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21506470/samsung-galaxy-s20-fe-review-camera-processor-price"&gt;the 2020 Galaxy S20 FE&lt;/a&gt; (the FE stands for Fan Edition), this device features most of the flagship-level specs of the Galaxy S21, including a Snapdragon 888 chipset and 120Hz display, at a lower price: $699 for the 128GB base model. With the S21’s nearly midrange price tag and a compelling upper-midrange option in the Galaxy A52 5G, it’s yet another addition to an already crowded spot in Samsung’s lineup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3q4q6Q"&gt;The Galaxy S21 FE offers a 6.4-inch display, slightly larger than the S21’s 6.2-inch panel. Outside of that size difference, the S21 FE has a whole lot in common with the S21. Its screen is a 1080p OLED panel with 120Hz like the S21’s. Even the design language is consistent, with the camera bump blending into the phone’s side rails. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jIOLTVTm2NWjrnGvIuBEYYNbNc8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23142239/ajohnson_220102_4951_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The camera bump is matte plastic rather than metal like the S21’s.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="OVfhHi"&gt;The FE includes a flagship-worthy 5nm chipset (Qualcomm Snapdragon 888 in the US, Samsung’s own Exynos elsewhere) and a 12-megapixel f/1.8 main camera with optical stabilization, same as the S21. It even does one better on battery capacity, with a 4,500mAh cell compared to the S21’s 4,000mAh (though its slightly bigger screen likely evens out battery performance). Fast 25W wired charging, 15W wireless charging, an IP68 weather-resistance rating, and both flavors of 5G (sub6-GHz and speedy mmWave) are all carried over from the S21. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0oA7eh"&gt;So what does paying more for the S21 get you? More RAM — 8GB in the base configuration versus the S21 FE’s 6GB — and a higher-res telephoto camera. Aside from the previously noted screen and battery size differences, that’s about it. The Galaxy S21 FE will sell for $699 with 6GB of RAM and 128GB of storage or $769 for 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage. It ships with Samsung’s Android 12-based One UI 4.0 installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="g4AI1u"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Samsung Galaxy S21 review: nice for the price","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22252460/samsung-galaxy-s21-review-price-camera-processor"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="gmLQPC"&gt;I’ve had the S21 FE in my hands for a few days, and it feels to me like a device that rides the ever-muddled line between a flagship and a midrange phone. The back is composite plastic with a matte finish, which feels midrangey to me, but the screen is big and bright with all the buttery smoothness of its 120Hz refresh rate — flagship territory for sure. Overall performance feels flagship-worthy, too, with the exception of a little lag in the camera’s portrait mode live preview. Oh, and there’s no charger in the box, which is a flagship thing now, too.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Prj0nwwxLY04hOolUfQvKdyDKFQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23142237/ajohnson_220102_4951_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The S21 FE ships with Android 12.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ZE3LuI"&gt;Samsung introduced the S20 FE last year as a lower-cost, full-featured alternative to the S20. Also priced at $699, there was a bigger gap between it and the $999 base model S20, which made it a heck of a deal. Things are a little different this time around, with the S21 coming down in price to $799. There’s also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22399456/samsung-galaxy-a52-5g-review-camera-screen-specs-price"&gt;the Galaxy A52 5G&lt;/a&gt;, one of Samsung’s higher-end budget phones for $499. And don’t forget that Samsung lowered the price of admission for its foldables — with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22631125/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-3-review"&gt;Galaxy Z Flip 3&lt;/a&gt; priced at $999, it’s part of the conversation, too.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0XIB8PEBtXEXQztEVE6Y4gfJVFM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23142241/ajohnson_220102_4951_0005.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The S21 FE features a gently curved metal rail. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Ifze6E"&gt;It’s more than a little confusing, but it’s not a new strategy for Samsung. As &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-G04G95B9fc"&gt;Dieter noted in his overview of the S20 lineup&lt;/a&gt;, Samsung takes this “a phone at every price point” approach because it can. It also happens to be really good at mixing and matching features for different price points, and a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295639/samsung-galaxy-device-2019-four-years-security-updates"&gt;solid support policy&lt;/a&gt; backing most devices makes its budget and midrange phones tough to beat. With the S21 FE, Samsung is taking yet another cut into a market that it’s happily slicing thinner and thinner.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22860324/samsung-galaxy-s21-fe-screen-camera-specs-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22860324/samsung-galaxy-s21-fe-screen-camera-specs-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-03T21:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-03T21:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>LG announces its largest and smallest OLED TVs ever as part of 2022 lineup</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LSmOMhb0pFyII5K6zQhcMrm0kIE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70344381/cwelch_211209_4929_0028.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Plus multiuser profiles for webOS&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="lRupSz"&gt;It’s a new year, and that means today LG is announcing its latest series of OLED TVs. For 2022, the company is adding new screen sizes, ratcheting up the brightness (again) on the G series, and bringing some additional features — like multiuser profiles — to the webOS software that runs on its TVs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eZ3BbY"&gt;Now on the fifth generation of its A9 processor, LG says 2022 TVs will include better 4K upscaling, improved tone mapping, and a greater sense of depth through foreground object enhancement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ubCm15"&gt;As for the TVs themselves, after debuting its higher-brightness OLED “Evo” panel on the G1 in 2021, this year Evo will be featured in both the G2 and more mainstream C2. LG says the G2 will deliver higher peak brightness numbers than the C2 through a combination of brightness booster algorithms and better heat dissipation from the TV’s components. But the C2 should still outperform something like the CX from two years ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qgPBo3"&gt;Expanding Evo to the C series makes a lot of sense: LG claims that line is the bestselling “premium TV series” — priced above $1,500 — in the United States. For both the G2 and C2, LG says it’s using a new composite fiber material in their construction that makes these TVs significantly lighter; for example, the 65-inch C2 is nearly half the weight of the C1. That should result in a less stressful unboxing and mounting experience for these very thin, fragile displays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5uM8LVDiAll5XIv01OAY3hvGLx8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23128707/cwelch_211209_4929_0030.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;LG’s G2 (left) shown next to last year’s C1 OLED (right), which isn’t exactly the right comparison.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sJBBR8"&gt;At a press briefing in New Jersey ahead of CES, LG lined up the new G2 side by side with the C1 to show off the brightness gains. A more helpful comparison to demonstrate year-over-year improvements would’ve been putting it against the G1’s Evo display, but no such luck. The G2 definitely looked better than the C1, but this was a staged demo — so take the stark difference you see with a grain of salt. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hxGXaGP6zyU2c_bYjZgpRvlGSds=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23128709/cwelch_211209_4929_0032.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;LG’s C2 OLED TVs will include the company’s brighter “Evo” panel.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3ydSRDa23gWaRpP6RiJIgFQKigA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23128690/cwelch_211209_4929_0013.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;They’ll still have the perfect blacks for which OLEDs are known.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="La7NxK"&gt;LG is also adding new screen sizes at both extremes. The C series is getting a new 42-inch OLED that the company thinks will be a perfect fit for small bedrooms, offices, or gamers in tight spaces. (Previously, the smallest LG OLED was 48 inches.) And there’s an enormous 97-inch 4K model that’s joining the G series. LG has offered 83-inch 4K and 88-inch 8K TVs in the past, but there’s a new giant OLED in town.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AlwL_oQcjdP17xFJe9jfsu7I1UE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23128704/cwelch_211209_4929_0027.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;LG’s 2022 OLED lineup includes a 42-inch model that could be perfect as a gaming monitor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ZNIaQI"&gt;As usual, every HDMI port on both the G and C series will offer full HDMI 2.1 capabilities — and this time LG really means it. Whereas the company’s TVs have been limited to about 40Gbps of HDMI bandwidth in recent years, for 2022 it’s using the whole 48Gbps pipeline. You’ll also still be getting the usual 120Hz 4K gaming, variable refresh rate, auto low latency mode, and so on. It’s worth noting that LG is already being surpassed in a few of these areas, however; some of Samsung’s just-announced 2022 TVs support VRR up to 144Hz for PC gamers. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sRSq1xqVZNfGsZ6hf78c915GHnc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23128713/cwelch_211209_4929_0036.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 97-inch G2 OLED is a true mammoth — and will certainly have a price to match.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="wNyZsD"&gt;That doesn’t mean LG isn’t making its own improvements for gamers. The game dashboard will put more information at the top layer so you’ll avoid extra clicks and can adjust key settings without jumping into the full game optimizer menu. There’s also a new fifth preset for sports games and a dark room gaming mode in picture settings. In recent months, LG has rolled out support for GeForce Now and Google Stadia cloud gaming services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="myG61F"&gt;The lower-tier A series will also remain part of LG’s OLED family in 2022, though it’s primarily intended for movie and TV watching since it lacks HDMI 2.1 and gaming-centric features. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wBopCc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LG G2 OLED: &lt;/strong&gt;available in 97-, 83-. 77-, 65-, and 55-inch sizes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LiuDwx"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LG C2 OLED:&lt;/strong&gt; available in 83-, 77-, 65-, 55, 48-, and 42-inch sizes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NWgRfVgxnNDsOVOSYZxgdcoYfNU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23128688/cwelch_211209_4929_0011.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mQeL2i"&gt;LG joined the Mini LED bandwagon in 2021, and this year it’s rolling out another wave of its terribly named “QNED” TVs that use the technology for vastly better contrast and black levels than the company’s older LCD sets. It’s not &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; black and infinite contrast like an OLED, but you can’t get much closer — and Mini LED TVs can crank higher than OLED when it comes to overall brightness. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h413No"&gt;But confusingly, LG is already muddying up what the “QNED” branding means, since not all of the TVs that carry it in 2022 will include Mini LED. The entry-level QNED80 model will have traditional, less precise local dimming without the miniaturized LED backlighting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hO5O1RkbPxggn70-sE6HNAw0kIg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23128683/cwelch_211209_4929_0006.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mini LED brings LG’s QNED TVs closer to the contrast of OLED — with better brightness.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VDycvv"&gt;The underlying webOS software on LG TVs is also seeing some tweaks this year. First off, the latest version will be “webOS 22” to match the year of its release. That’s a little more straightforward than before. The company is also adding support for multiple user profiles, with each person getting their own personalized recommendations and the freedom to customize the homescreen to their liking. I asked LG if TV picture settings could be customized and saved for each user (in case someone in your home really loves the soap opera effect), but profiles don’t extend that far. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EuNNGS"&gt;LG is also promising a feature called “room to room share” that will be able to “temporarily” send the feed from one TV (where a cable box or other component might be plugged in) to another in a different room. You’ll supposedly be able to change channels and do other actions in this mode. But room to room share won’t roll out until after the TVs ship, so there aren’t a ton of details right now. Last is a new-for-2022 “Always Ready” mode that, when the TV is off, “transforms the screen into a digital canvas for showcasing artwork, keeping track of time, or playing music.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3s7tgmqB59UhlUtOKXGXjN-nvgM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23128686/cwelch_211209_4929_0009.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;webOS now supports different user profiles.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/49sWzdWz08Hx7FG6jBh9XsUO4OM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23128689/cwelch_211209_4929_0012.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;But otherwise it’s the same experience that LG introduced last year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="D4yxZo"&gt;Full pricing and release timeframes for LG’s 2022 TV lineup should be available as they come closer to shipping this spring. It seems like the company is playing things a bit safe this year — especially in light of rumors of QD-OLED TVs being on the horizon. But maybe that’s still enough for LG to maintain its status as the go-to recommendation for an OLED TV that doesn’t demand the premium of Sony’s pricier models. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7blF7d"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22856102/lg-97-42-inch-oled-4k-8k-qned-tvs-announced-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22856102/lg-97-42-inch-oled-4k-8k-qned-tvs-announced-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-03T20:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-03T20:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>This smart collar wants to be an Apple Watch for your dog</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A cute brown dog wearing an Invoxia Smart Dog Collar" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oOa6A3Fw0pFhMxwHi-8HF9XTNpQ=/0x0:6000x4000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70344311/Smart_Dog_Collar_Logo___Invoxia.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Invoxia’s Smart Dog Collar uses miniaturized radars to monitor resting respiratory and heart rate.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Invoxia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iU8QjI"&gt;Pet trackers have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/5/20680991/fi-smart-collar-pet-dog-fitness-tracker-review-price-specs-features"&gt;been around&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2017/1/4/14149086/whistle-3-gps-pet-tracker-price-date-ces-2017"&gt;for ages&lt;/a&gt;, but Invoxia is looking to shake things up at CES 2022 with a new smart collar that can also monitor your dog’s vital signs. And of course, the smart collar also doubles as a GPS and activity tracker for your pooch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1KRraN"&gt;Canine fitness trackers generally rely on a combination of accelerometers and GPS sensors. Invoxia’s approach is a bit different. To monitor vitals like resting respiratory and heart rate, Invoxia says it worked with board-certified veterinary cardiologists to develop deep learning AI that utilizes miniaturized radar sensors — the same type as the Soli radar Google used in its Pixel 4 phones. According to Invoxia CEO Amélie Caudron, the radars are ideal as they’re capable of taking readings regardless of how furry your dog is. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6XyCFV"&gt;“There’s a radar that faces the neck and sends a radio signal, and that signal will not be reflected by the hair,” Caudron told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “So it doesn’t matter how much fur or hair there is, it’ll be reflected by the first layer of skin. So the radar will actually be able to know the speed and movement of the skin right under the collar.” Those movements are then fed into an algorithm that determines heart and respiratory rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tz96Om"&gt;Another plus, Caudron says, is that the collar can sit more loosely and comfortably around the dog’s neck. That’s not the case with the smartwatches and fitness trackers humans use, which require a tighter fit and good skin contact to get accurate heart rate readings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TCXPiO"&gt;Invoxia isn’t the only pet tech out there that tracks dog vital signs. Believe it or not, there are also &lt;a href="https://vetmeasure.com/continuous-heart-rate-monitor/"&gt;continuous heart rate monitoring EKG vests&lt;/a&gt;, as well as the &lt;a href="https://petpace.com/"&gt;Petpace Smart Collar&lt;/a&gt;. However, those are more for veterinarians than regular pet owners and don’t include GPS tracking. (EKG vests may also require you to rub a conductive gel onto your dog, so good luck if you have a fidgety Fido on your hands.) The Invoxia collar stands out by combining a traditional GPS tracker with a noninvasive way to monitor vitals. It’s compatible with Bluetooth, Wi-Fi, GPS, and LTE-M, and features escape alerts and a built-in buzzer. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Screenshots of the Invoxia app next to a blue smart collar" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k0PNu0lqB8_bVxm-m3WH_TqBfnA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23131106/App___Smart_Dog_Collar.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Invoxia&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="VkM9Ci"&gt;As for activity tracking, Invoxia says it already has four years of data collected from its original &lt;a href="https://www.invoxia.com/nl/pet-tracker"&gt;GPS Pet Tracker&lt;/a&gt;. On top of monitoring vitals, the collar can also track daily activity and identify when your dog is walking, running, scratching, eating or drinking, barking, and resting. It also has a removable fabric covering for easier cleaning if your dog happens to like running around in the mud. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cs7nt1"&gt;That said, the Invoxia collar will mostly focus on your individual dog’s baseline. Thus far, continuous vital monitoring on dogs hasn’t really been possible at a large enough scale to customize based on breed — even though some breeds may be more predisposed to heart or respiratory conditions. However, Caudron isn’t ruling out that may be a possibility with more data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="emxxwX"&gt;As for why you might even want to know your dog’s vital signs, Invoxia says it could be useful for pets post-surgery, monitoring how pets might respond to medication, or for keeping an eye on those with known cardiac and respiratory illnesses. She also noted that often, owners notice something is wrong with their pets too late. Detecting anomalies in a pet’s baseline may help owners and vets catch illnesses early. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FbkgaY"&gt;There is a catch, however. For now, the Invoxia collar is only for medium to large-sized dogs. That’s because it’s hard to miniaturize the radar tech to a size that would be comfortable and lightweight enough for smaller pets, like toy dogs and cats. (And if you’ve ever put &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/i-put-a-fitness-tracker-on-my-lazy-dog-it-did-not-go-a-1844364696"&gt;a large tracker on a small dog&lt;/a&gt;, size and comfort make a huge difference.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5rWqL6"&gt;Invoxia says the collar is expected to be available in summer 2022. It’ll cost an estimated $99 for the collar itself and an additional $12.99 monthly subscription for GPS features. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22857166/invoxia-pet-tracker-smart-collar-heart-rate-dogs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22857166/invoxia-pet-tracker-smart-collar-heart-rate-dogs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Victoria Song</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-03T20:00:06-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-03T20:00:06-05:00</updated>
    <title>Hands off: Moen’s new smart faucet doesn’t even need a handle</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ld0ezaW_0LwtytQGhgwU3Txr-Rg=/0x768:2100x2168/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70343552/Moen_Smart_Faucet_with_Motion_Control___No_Handle___Brushed_Gold.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moen’s newest smart faucet goes handle-free.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Moen&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="A5USWw"&gt;Moen revealed its latest smart faucet at CES this week: the Moen Smart Faucet with Motion Control. The new feature adds completely handle-free operation, using gestures to control temperature as well as flow. But you can still have a handle if you really want one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QOMoQ7"&gt;The idea is you operate the faucet using swipe and push motions in front of the sensor to get hot, warm, or cold water. The Moen Smart Water App should let you set the default temperatures, as well as customize the gestures further.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VnXrZWLpeqflNa3t2uKrjF6sVeA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23133025/Moen_Smart_Faucet_with_Motion_Control___Nio___No_Handle___Chrome.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Moen&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The handle-free design of the Moen Smart Faucet with Motion is a minimalist’s dream.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="4iNciQ"&gt;The new faucet has all the features of the existing Moen Smart Faucet — including voice activation (with Amazon Alexa and Google Assistant). There’s also the ability to dispense precise measurements and temperatures — so you can ask for one cup of 100-degree water, as well as set presets for common commands (such as the right temperature and volume to fill your coffee pot versus your water bottle). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T2fXV3"&gt;There are two handle-free styles at launch and four options that feature the more traditional control option as well. Pricing starts at $675 and varies based on style and finish, and it will be available to buy in April 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WONUfV"&gt;Moen also announced integrations between its smart faucet and other smart water products and its new Smart Water Network, a residential smart water ecosystem centered around Moen’s Flo Smart Water Monitor and Shutoff. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b1rBZVr8cUFhBoZXuDnAa8VJ-K0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23132981/Moen_Smart_Water_Network___Products.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Moen&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moen’s smart devices will all work together as part of its Smart Water Network. From left: Moen Smart Faucet, Smart Leak Detector, Smart Sump Pump Monitor, Flo Smart Water Monitor and Shutoff, Smart Shower controller. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SBiBoU"&gt;If a house has the smart water monitor and a Moen faucet and / or smart shower installed, the devices should soon be able to communicate with each other to help winterize the system and prevent burst pipes by flushing the water lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="50ZdWR"&gt;The Smart Water Monitor installs on a home’s main water supply line and monitors the water flow, pressure, and temperature to notify you of leaks, burst pipes, and other potential issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Aedjc"&gt;When paired with the other Moen products and controlled by the Moen Smart Water app, a homeowner is supposed to be able to tell the system to winterize itself by shutting off water coming into the home and purging the water line via the faucet and shower. When it’s time to get the pipes flowing again, a Health Protect feature should flush the water lines to prevent dirt, debris, or germs from building up in the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZEp6cj"&gt;The system also has a built-in freeze protection feature. When it senses high pressure or low temperatures that could cause a pipe to burst, it can automatically shut off water to the home via the Flo Smart Water Monitor and Shutoff, then purge the water line using the Moen faucet and shower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZKpC8c"&gt;The Moen Smart Water App integration with the smart faucet will launch in 2022, with the smart shower coming to the app in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7cEg7s"&gt;This type of integration currently requires a substantial investment in products from one company, but the whole home approach to protecting and monitoring essential infrastructure in a house is a key part of the possible future of the smart home. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22858262/moen-smart-faucet-motion-control-smart-water-network-ces2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22858262/moen-smart-faucet-motion-control-smart-water-network-ces2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-03T20:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-03T20:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Netgear is turning its connected picture frame into a display for NFTs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HbLeURqJmRdP8_cUZ9buHOGRGS4=/0x2:396x266/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70344209/Screenshot_2021_12_20_143606.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tNsyW5"&gt;Whether you wanted it or not, NFTs are finding ways of creeping into just about every aspect of our lives. Something that began as a curiosity has quickly expanded to include networking giant Netgear and its connected smart frame, Meural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cXi7qZ"&gt;Regardless of how you feel about NFTs, companies like Netgear are capitalizing on this interest by integrating them into products like the existing Meural Frame. With a way to put these works of “art” on display, it allows these commodities to also become decorations for something besides Twitter profiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ocT4xF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"NFTs, explained","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22310188/nft-explainer-what-is-blockchain-crypto-art-faq"},{"title":"The climate controversy swirling around NFTs","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22328203/nft-cryptoart-ethereum-blockchain-climate-change"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="6tlt7T"&gt;While the Meural began its life as a way to display photos, Netgear recently announced that it would begin beta testing integration between the Meural and the MetaMask cryptocurrency wallet starting in January. This partnership is what allows you to upload NFTs to Meural and safely store them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B7Qcv4"&gt;Pretend for a second that you don’t know what an NFT is and you don’t want to. The Meural can still display slideshows and images from your phone locally or remotely. It’s also slated to have access to the world's largest streaming library of art and photography. This library is set to include works from classical and contemporary artists as well as a variety of branded content. This service is available as either a monthly or annual subscription and costs $8.95 and $69.95 respectively. Thankfully, you can also share pictures to the Meural through the dedicated app or through a built-in MicroSD card slot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zW3Qwe"&gt;The Meural Frames are available in a variety of sizes, from a desk-sized 13.5 x 7.5 inches and reaching up to larger wall-mounted options that measure 16 x 24 and 19 x 29 inches. However, none of the frames have a display resolution greater than 1080p, which is a little disappointing in a world where displays like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/18/18147273/samsung-the-frame-serif-4k-hdr-tv-announced-ces-2019-features"&gt;Samsung’s The Frame exists&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l4pwWW"&gt;The smaller photo frame retails for $299.95, and the larger two cost $399.95 and $599.95. All of these models are available in a variety of colorways with varying availability on Amazon or Netgear.   &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22846732/netgear-meural-smart-frame-nft-ces-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22846732/netgear-meural-smart-frame-nft-ces-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-03T20:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-03T20:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Netgear thinks you’ll pay extra for ad blocking on its Orbi routers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r6hC3LB_5OlI8Mdp6IDJkpuAIpI=/68x0:1334x844/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70344210/NETGEAR_Game_Booster_Image_1__1_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The Game Booster service will cost $50 annually&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="sAbTdE"&gt;The demands placed on our home networks are higher than ever, especially when it comes to gaming. Netgear was arguably one of the first router manufacturers to optimize the networking needed for gaming with its Nighthawk line of routers. Now, it's attempting the same thing with its new line of 6E enabled Orbi mesh routers. The Game Booster service largely resembles the Nighthawk Pro Gaming application used to configure their XR line of gaming routers, with one glaring difference: it requires a subscription. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fwENb4"&gt;The Game Booster service for Orbi devices will cost $50 annually, and while this isn’t a massive sum of money, it certainly raises some questions about why Netgear is charging for a service that was previously offered for free on other devices. This decision is made all the more puzzling when you consider how expensive an Orbi system is, with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22716979/netgear-orbi-quad-band-wi-fi-6e-mesh-router-release-date-specs-price"&gt;some larger systems costing as much as $1,500&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J9Q8C5"&gt;Netgear states that Game Booster offers more than a simple quality of service (QoS) optimizer. Besides making QoS easier to use, the Game Booster software, much like the Nighthawk Pro Gaming application, provides you with easy-to-read metrics to help you fine-tune your home network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="454uW8"&gt;Game Booster should allow you to prioritize server connectivity based on ping or location, and allow you to allocate and reserve bandwidth for both downloads and uploads on a per-device basis. However, Netgear has stated that this service is not a VPN or meant to replace your VPN. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lal5powi9apYq56ZYo4mBZFiVog=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23132479/netgear.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The app includes ping heat maps and device throttling.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5B4qvM"&gt;While many of these features are also present in other services, Game Booster will also include an integrated ad-blocker with a regularly updated block list. The blocker will also allow you to fine-tune which devices and domains are blocked, in addition to providing you with updated metrics on its effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MEsnIJeHGlwmV4JwfU0mEYGGhOA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23132512/netgear2.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Integrated ad blockers are one of the new features offered by the Game Booster app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MVmtj5"&gt;Having more granular control over your home network is certainly a good thing, however many of the features offered by this paid service ultimately rely on the assumption of an ideal network environment among other factors. They’re also largely tools that other routers provide for free, or, as in the case of the ad blocker, can be built for a &lt;a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/how-to/set-up-pi-hole-raspberry-pi"&gt;fairly low upfront cost by a savvy user&lt;/a&gt;. This all raises some questions as to whether this paid service will be beneficial enough to merit the subscription in addition to the above-average cost of the hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KsVWBP"&gt;The Game Booster application is set to be available for 750 and 850 series Orbi devices beginning in Q1 2022.   &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22848279/netgear-orbi-game-booster-ad-blocking-ces-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22848279/netgear-orbi-game-booster-ad-blocking-ces-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-03T20:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-03T20:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>OnePlus 10 Pro official teaser shows off triple rear cameras and Hasselblad branding</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The OnePlus 10 Pro" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XKEVQOezKkllKkl0c_JyWzXTT7k=/0x0:6750x4500/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70344224/OnePlus_10_Pro.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EFgjMU"&gt;The rear camera layout of OnePlus’s next flagship, the OnePlus 10 Pro, has been shown off in a teaser image for the smartphone. The handset is due to launch in China on January 11th before coming to the rest of the world later in the year. OnePlus CEO Pete Lau previously confirmed that the phone would be revealed in January in a &lt;a href="https://weibo.com/1110411735/L72FWaAtT#comment"&gt;post on Weibo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g94BHg"&gt;Although the teaser image doesn’t show much more than the rear of the phone, it confirms the 10 Pro will have three rear cameras that will once again carry the Hasselblad branding. OnePlus’s partnership with the Swedish camera manufacturer began with last year’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22338398/oneplus-9-review-specs-price-camera-screen"&gt;OnePlus 9&lt;/a&gt;, where the two companies worked together on the color tuning of the phone’s photos, with generally good results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="MkcZzl"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A three-stage ringer switch is also visible&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SCKlcq"&gt;The image also confirms the phone’s camera bump design, which has previously appeared in leaks from &lt;a href="https://www.91mobiles.com/hub/oneplus-10-pro-specifications-exclusive/"&gt;Twitter tipster @OnLeaks and &lt;em&gt;91Mobiles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Although the specs of these cameras are yet to be officially revealed, reports indicate the OnePlus 10 Pro will feature a 48-megapixel main camera, a 50-megapixel ultrawide, an 8-megapixel telephoto, and a 32-megapixel selfie camera. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lAWlKB"&gt;Internally, it’ll reportedly be powered by a Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 processor paired with 8GB or 12GB of RAM, 128GB or 256GB of storage, and a 5,000mAh battery. There’s also an IP68 rating for dust and water resistance. In the official image released today, we can also see the trademark OnePlus three-stage ringer switch, which in the past has let you easily switch the phone into its vibration and silent modes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6AedmH"&gt;OnePlus hasn’t announced when the OnePlus 10 series might launch outside of China, but &lt;em&gt;91Mobiles &lt;/em&gt;previously reported that a global release could come by April.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22849868/oneplus-pro-china-launch-january-11th-design"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22849868/oneplus-pro-china-launch-january-11th-design</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-03T20:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-03T20:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Withings’ new scale has a retractable handle that measures EKGs and segmented body composition</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A render of the Withings Body Scan" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-nz2Yzvs3sK9a08bpDEetRb1lck=/111x0:3861x2500/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70344228/2021_11_15_CES_main__1_.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Withings Body Scan has a retractable handle that enables 6-lead EKGs and segmented body composition readings&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Withings&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gS63RC"&gt;Withings isn’t a stranger to smart scales, but for CES 2022 the company is taking a much more ambitious take on the gadget. Announced today, the Withings Body Scan will feature six-lead EKG readings, segmented body composition measurements, and the ability to assess foot nerve activity. Basically, it’s the scale for people who want to know how fat is distributed through their body and how that might in turn relate to their heart health. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PHfFGU"&gt;On the surface, the Body Scan looks like your typical scale — albeit with a retractable handle up top. It contains four weight sensors and 14 ITO electrodes in the scale itself, plus an additional four located in the handle. The scale also features a larger 3.2-inch LCD color screen, as well as a battery life of one year. It’ll also integrate with Withings’ smartwatches, on top of Apple HealthKit and Google Fit APIs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vuKwjE"&gt;While the handle is definitely unique visually, it’s also what enables the Body Scan’s more interesting features. Smart scales measure body composition via bioelectrical impedance analysis (BIA). It works by sending a low-level electrical current through your body. Body fat, water, and lean mass all have different resistance levels, so depending on the rate at which the current travels, the scale will estimate your body composition. However, most scales only have two points of contact: your feet. That means you’re really getting an estimate for &lt;a href="https://www.consumerreports.org/body-fat-scales/body-fat-scale-review/"&gt;your lower body only&lt;/a&gt;. Withings says the Body Scan will use “multi-frequency” BIA as the retractable handle provides two extra points of contact, hence, segmented body composition measurements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zzWHZ5"&gt;Withings claims the Body Scan can differentiate between your torso, your right and left legs, and your right and left arms. The scale will also break down body composition into whole-body fat and water percentages, visceral fat, muscle and bone mass, and extracellular and intracellular water. It’s hard to say how accurate the Body Scan will be — &lt;a href="https://www.consumerreports.org/body-fat-scales/body-fat-scale-review/"&gt;smart scales are&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://mhealth.jmir.org/2021/4/e22487"&gt;notoriously&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://v"&gt;inaccurate&lt;/a&gt; — but it’s admittedly nice to see that Withings is attempting to provide extra context. For example, many smart scales don’t differentiate between subcutaneous and visceral fat. While jiggly subcutaneous fat is relatively harmless, invisible visceral fat &lt;a href="https://www.health.harvard.edu/staying-healthy/taking-aim-at-belly-fat"&gt;is the kind that’s actually most dangerous to your health&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K4FI1j"&gt;Body composition has had a recent resurgence in wearables. Samsung introduced BIA analysis on its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22629459/galaxy-watch-4-classic-review-bixby-google-wearos"&gt;Samsung Galaxy Watch 4&lt;/a&gt;, while Amazon also introduced a body fat feature on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/27/21402493/amazon-halo-band-health-fitness-body-scan-tone-emotion-activity-sleep"&gt;its Halo platform&lt;/a&gt;. Each of these companies has emphasized their body fat tools as an alternative to Body Mass Index (BMI), which is &lt;a href="http://v"&gt;a flawed metric for evaluating your overall health&lt;/a&gt;. That said, improperly tracking body fat can also act as &lt;a href="https://www.oregonlive.com/trackandfield/2021/10/women-athletes-allege-body-shaming-within-oregon-ducks-track-and-field-program.html"&gt;a potential trigger for body dysmorphia&lt;/a&gt; and other eating disorders. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JovdxZQKcveB-nSkeF2WDtHQnrQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23128369/2021_11_15_WBS08_CES_PERS34.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Withings&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Body Scan will retail for $279 and come in black and white.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ooJxWF"&gt;“We’ve been looking for a way to do this safely and effectively,” Withings chief medical officer Shikha Anand told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “We can’t solve the way in which the world sees weight, but that said, we will make every effort not to exacerbate it. We will ground in health and not in weight wherever we can. It will always be about how your weight relates to your health.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FmPWpM"&gt;Anand went on to explain that weight is often tied to self-esteem, and that’s part of why Withings wants to repackage its scale as a health station. The idea, Anand says, is to show how your weight relates in context to your overall cardiovascular health, as well as offer more holistic, behavioral insights. Anand also emphasized Withings is testing the Body Scan with a diverse cohort of consumers to ensure the body composition feature is more helpful than harmful. She also said the Withings app would be upgraded with better data visualizations for long-term trends. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cTEw2c"&gt;Aside from body composition, Withings says the Body Scan will provide heart rate, EKG recordings, and vascular age data at each weigh-in. EKG readings can be saved and shared with doctors. Meanwhile, the vascular age feature is meant to show people how their cardiovascular health compares to other people within their age group. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6XVfxx"&gt;While body composition, and even EKGs, make sense for a scale, Withings is taking it one step further with a new nerve assessment feature developed with French medical device maker Impeto Medical. The scale will purportedly measure sweat gland activity in your feet and generate a score. According to Withings, foot nerve activity is currently under investigational use and could potentially show signs of nerve dysfunction. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fHIrFB"&gt;This is all well and good, but like Withings’ other recent gadgets, the Body Scan is subject to FDA and CE clearance. So while Withings says it plans to launch the Body Scan for $279 in the second half of 2022, that’ll all depend on how fast the company can get the regulatory go-ahead. The Withing ScanWatch, for instance, was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/5/21048522/withings-health-monitoring-scanwatch-ecg-afib-heart-sleep-apnea-blood-oxygen"&gt;introduced at CES 2020&lt;/a&gt; and only obtained FDA clearance &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22772984/withings-scanwatch-blood-oxygen-sleep-apnea-watch-fda"&gt;in November 2021&lt;/a&gt;. Despite this, Anand says Withings is optimistic it won’t take quite as long this time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jPxisO"&gt;“We’ve learned a lot with the process of the ScanWatch, and gotten to know the team at the FDA quite a bit better. I feel we’re on the path to have [the Body Scan] on a reasonable time frame.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S9ZJj6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22855714/withings-body-scan-ekg-body-fat-fda-ces-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22855714/withings-body-scan-ekg-body-fat-fda-ces-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Victoria Song</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
