<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-05T10:30:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-05T10:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-05T10:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Lost Judgment is a better sequel with a messy story</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_Hr1YPmnxhg0Fg2EWVtkTM9sF2E=/156x0:1844x1125/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69953729/LJ12.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ii3K4Y"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Yakuza&lt;/em&gt; series is beloved for its uncanny ability to bounce between absurd humor, deep pathos, and brutal violence and making it seem like the most natural thing in the world. Lost Judgment, the sequel to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/25/18744110/judgment-game-review-ps4-yakuza"&gt;2019’s detective-focused spinoff &lt;em&gt;Judgment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, marks a rare misstep in that regard. In many ways it’s much improved on its predecessor and spins a more ambitious story — but it can’t quite deliver on its themes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RTrvpn"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lost Judgment&lt;/em&gt; picks up after the first game with Takayuki Yagami — played in droll, deadpan fashion by Japanese megastar Takuya Kimura — returning to his work as a private detective. Yagami is hired to investigate an incident of bullying at a high school in Yokohama, but soon enough the case becomes entwined with a groping conviction in Tokyo and a murder nearby. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z5OH3c"&gt;The plot is more than a little far-fetched, as is the case with most Japanese crime procedurals, and the inevitable shoehorning in of gang warfare feels like the writers were overly beholden to the &lt;em&gt;Yakuza&lt;/em&gt; series. But it’s told at a briskly entertaining pace and feels more focused than the previous game’s spiraling Big Pharma conspiracy. I generally appreciated the effort to tell a more intimate, smaller-scale story, even though it doesn’t ultimately pay off.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="lost judgment" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7-zjL_dBmSgBGjCO1PRzyHWVCks=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22899878/LJCombat13.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="nldAL4"&gt;The detective elements of the game are much improved. You’ll still have to tail enemies through the streets and go through some pointless on-rails stealth sections, but they mostly serve as palate cleansers rather than points of frustration. With its streamlined talking-heads cutscenes and emphasis on presenting meaningful evidence, &lt;em&gt;Lost Judgment&lt;/em&gt; sometimes feels more like &lt;em&gt;Ace Attorney&lt;/em&gt; than its predecessor, which was essentially &lt;em&gt;Yakuza&lt;/em&gt; with an occasional gumshoe mini-game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Li3QPM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The story deals with some of the darkest subject matter yet seen in the series&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="P887sr"&gt;Speaking of &lt;em&gt;Yakuza&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Lost Judgment &lt;/em&gt;will be worth playing for anyone turned off by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21558093/yakuza-like-a-dragon-review-xbox-series-x"&gt;the series’ shift to turn-based RPG-style combat with &lt;em&gt;Like a Dragon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; The brawling is as smooth and satisfying as it’s ever been, with three distinct combat styles that all have clear uses. It helps that &lt;em&gt;Lost Judgment&lt;/em&gt; is by far the best-looking &lt;em&gt;Yakuza&lt;/em&gt;-adjacent game to date, with a dramatic lighting system, realistic characters, and solid 60fps performance (at least on the PS5 I used for testing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QVbTgG"&gt;Kamurocho has never looked so good, and this time Yagami gets to play in Yokohama, too, with the much larger Ijincho district returning from &lt;em&gt;Like a Dragon&lt;/em&gt;. Unlike most recent &lt;em&gt;Yakuza&lt;/em&gt; games, the original &lt;em&gt;Judgment&lt;/em&gt; only took place in Kamurocho and felt quite cramped as a result; the sequel gives you far more to explore. As ever, Sega’s &lt;em&gt;Yakuza&lt;/em&gt; team does a great job at reusing locations and packing them full of new detail. You’re now able to skateboard on streets to get around faster, for example, and in Yokohama you can take a cute shiba inu for walks and discover side quests in return. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="lost judgment" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7vSJPXKqutgUjYWX2RhCJfG8Vvc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22899879/LJInvestigative03.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="io5ULL"&gt;The breezy vibe is offset by the main storyline, which deals with some of the darkest subject matter yet seen in the series. The plot centers around high school bullying and suicide, which is certainly a topical and contentious issue in Japan; just last week a case involving a sixth-grade girl who died by suicide made news as the school denied that bullying was the cause. But&lt;em&gt; Lost Judgment&lt;/em&gt; takes a flippant approach to the problem, with Yagami resorting to preposterous methods like placing remote speakers under classroom tables to vocally stand up for bullied kids when their classmates won’t. Other characters, meanwhile, get killed off or make jarring heel turns in endless twists that don’t feel earned by the plot, and the game often makes ham-fisted attempts to get you to sympathize with some pretty clearly terrible people. It’s good that Sega tried to highlight the central issue, and I don’t think anyone expects a video game to solve it altogether, but it doesn’t feel like a good match for &lt;em&gt;Lost Judgment&lt;/em&gt;’s otherwise schlocky tone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="upusLF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;I can’t ignore the big leaps this game makes&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="URwt8c"&gt;You can look at &lt;em&gt;Lost Judgment&lt;/em&gt; in two ways: an often clumsy attempt at serious storytelling, or a technically accomplished sequel that much improves on its predecessor. It’s both, really. The plot doesn’t fully land, and I found there to be more awkward moments than in &lt;em&gt;Judgment&lt;/em&gt; or other &lt;em&gt;Yakuza&lt;/em&gt; games. But I also can’t ignore the big leaps this game makes in other areas, and it still keeps up the irreverent charm of the series for much of its running time. Overall, I think this is a much better game than &lt;em&gt;Judgment&lt;/em&gt; and I would like to see where it goes next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BeY7t5"&gt;The future of the &lt;em&gt;Judgment&lt;/em&gt; series is unclear, however. Various rumors suggest that &lt;em&gt;Yakuza&lt;/em&gt; creator and executive director Toshihiro Nagoshi may be leaving Sega, while Kimura’s notoriously protective talent agency Johnny’s is reportedly refusing to allow future games with his likeness due to a dispute over a PC version. I’m hoping none of this stops Sega from working on the next installment, though — while &lt;em&gt;Lost Judgment&lt;/em&gt; would be an unfortunately messy ending, I could see it as the ambitious middle part of a trilogy that finds its feet in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NrScbC"&gt;&lt;small&gt;Lost Judgment &lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;is out now on the PS4, PS5, Xbox One, and Xbox Series S / X.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22708841/lost-judgment-review-ps5-xbox"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22708841/lost-judgment-review-ps5-xbox</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-05T10:11:59-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-05T10:11:59-04:00</updated>
    <title>Everything you need to know from the Facebook whistleblower hearing</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Children’s Online Safety-Facebook Whistleblower" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CpKYuZyJwxMQDy3QzWpvcmPeLdM=/0x0:5239x3493/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69953544/1235709440.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo By Tom Williams/CQ-Roll Call, Inc via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Congress will hear new concerns about child safety on the world’s largest social network&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="mXO6As"&gt;On Tuesday, Facebook whistleblower Frances Haugen is appearing before a Senate Commerce subcommittee in what promises to be one of Facebook’s toughest congressional hearings in years. After serving as a source for a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686364/facebook-oversight-board-xcheck-moderation-exemption"&gt;string&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/15/22675130/facebook-instagram-teens-mental-health-damage-internal-research"&gt;bombshell reports&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;, Haugen &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/3/22707860/facebook-whistleblower-leaked-documents-files-regulation"&gt;went public on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; with concerns about Instagram’s mental health impacts on its youngest users, drawn from internal Facebook reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q5iWnc"&gt;The result has been a new focus on child safety — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22710371/facebook-whistleblower-congress-hearing-instagram-kids-safety-privacy-blumenthal"&gt;a particularly sore point for Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. The company has disputed claims that Instagram exacerbates body issues in teenage girls, but the broader concerns about algorithmic amplification of harmful content have been harder to dismiss. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/1/22704308/finsta-instagram-facebook-privacy-kids-safety-richard-blumenthal-blackburn"&gt;In a hearing last week&lt;/a&gt;, Sen. Richard Blumenthal (D-CT) shared the results of a test in which his own staff was bombarded with Instagram posts related to eating disorders and self-harm after creating a dummy account posing as a teenage girl. Today’s hearing is expected to focus on the same topics, with direct testimony from Haugen on the company’s decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dFIO34"&gt;We’ll be updating this post with everything that happens during the hearing — every question from lawmakers, every important quote, and every piece of new information from Haugen. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="DKVAUl"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZRu93KLU868?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="VJmWF7"&gt;
&lt;p id="mpFIZk"&gt;In his opening remarks, &lt;strong&gt;Sen. Richard Blumenthal (D-CT)&lt;/strong&gt; described how Facebook “has put profits ahead of people.” He noted how the platform’s algorithmic feeds can amplify insecurities in its younger users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qtDYUK"&gt;“I hope we will discuss whether there is such a thing as a safe algorithm,” Blumenthal said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mLjwiF"&gt;Blumenthal also called on &lt;strong&gt;Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg&lt;/strong&gt; to return to Congress to testify on behalf of the &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal’s &lt;/em&gt;recent revelations on child safety. Facebook has vigorously contested many of Haugen’s claims, but has done so through surrogates like global head of safety Antigone Davis or public relations lead Nick Clegg. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LhkTpD"&gt;“Rather than taking responsibility and showing leadership, Mr. Zuckerberg is going sailing,” Blumenthal said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="QZrEB7"&gt;
&lt;p id="l06NNc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sen. Marsha Blackburn (R-TN)&lt;/strong&gt; also tackled Facebook’s business model in her first remarks during the hearing. “Facebook is not interested in making significant changes to improve kids’ safety on their platforms, at least not when that would result in losing eyeballs on post or decreasing their ad revenues,” she said. “Follow the money.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4Z5Xo2"&gt;Following up on last week’s “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/1/22704308/finsta-instagram-facebook-privacy-kids-safety-richard-blumenthal-blackburn"&gt;finsta” discussion&lt;/a&gt;, Blackburn says that Facebook turns a blind eye to this private accounts as a means of boosting its active user numbers. Children can use these private accounts to interact with other people and the platform without their parents’ approval, she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="0GURQZ"&gt;
&lt;p id="gTuHh0"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post will be updated with more information as the hearing progresses — reload the page to see more content.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22710539/facebook-whistleblower-hearing-instagram-child-safety-congress"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22710539/facebook-whistleblower-hearing-instagram-child-safety-congress</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-05T10:10:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-05T10:10:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sora is the final Smash Ultimate character</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TzOqy88uqJESqWOU0tR-ayauLGU=/92x0:1004x608/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69953534/Screen_Shot_2021_10_05_at_10.06.28_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OKqFdk"&gt;The newest &lt;em&gt;Super&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Smash Bros. Ultimate&lt;/em&gt; fighter has been announced, and it is not Waluigi. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oC7v4Y"&gt;Nintendo, during a livestream event, announced Sora from &lt;em&gt;Kingdom Hearts&lt;/em&gt; will join the roster as the 82nd playable character (if we’re not counting the echo fighters).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4Fiacu"&gt;Sora joins the esteemed company of characters from across celebrated Nintendo titles and beyond, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/15/22534874/super-smash-bros-ultimate-kayuza-tekken-dlc-character-fighters-pass-2-e3-2021"&gt;Jin Kazuya&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22168749/next-smash-bros-character-sephiroth-fighters-pass-2"&gt; Sephiroth&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/8/17655942/super-smash-bros-ultimate-nintendo-switch-castlevania-simon-belmont"&gt; a couple of Belmonts&lt;/a&gt;, and&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/16/21065278/super-smash-bros-ultimate-nintendo-switch-dlc-character-byleth-fire-emblem"&gt; entirely too many Fire Emblem characters&lt;/a&gt;. In advance of the &lt;em&gt;Smash&lt;/em&gt; livestream, the internet was alight with speculation as to who the newest character would be. Master Chief from &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; was an early favorite as was &lt;em&gt;Dragonball Z’s &lt;/em&gt;Goku. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W92rff"&gt;Waluigi, however, was one of the most popular guesses as fans have been &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-intersect/wp/2018/06/12/waluigi-was-robbed-and-humiliated-by-nintendo-and-his-fans-are-furious/"&gt;clamoring for his addition&lt;/a&gt; for years. As there will be no more characters added to &lt;em&gt;Smash&lt;/em&gt;, that dream now dies and with it the hopes of his many fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E12q3m"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Smash Ultimate&lt;/em&gt; director &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/12/17453214/super-smash-bros-ultimate-nintendo-switch-masahiro-sakurai-e3"&gt;Masahiro Sakurai&lt;/a&gt; has said this character &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/22553841/super-smash-bros-ultimate-kazuya-release-date-tekken"&gt;will be the last fighter added&lt;/a&gt; to the game. In a tweet, the celebrated Nintendo personality also revealed this will be his last fighter presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="52peaw"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Good morning.&lt;br&gt;The last DLC fighter for Super Smash Bros. Ultimate will be announced shortly.&lt;br&gt;This will also be my final fighter presentation.&lt;br&gt;It'll be sad to say farewell, but I hope you all enjoy it. &lt;a href="https://t.co/gV1B8fgtd6"&gt;https://t.co/gV1B8fgtd6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— 桜井 政博 / Masahiro Sakurai (@Sora_Sakurai) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sora_Sakurai/status/1445382876086902790?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 5, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Zycu0G"&gt;Sakurai frequently joked during presentations that working on &lt;em&gt;Smash&lt;/em&gt; has been tiring and wondered if he’d ever &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fccgHnBQ0YM&amp;amp;t=1906s"&gt;get a break&lt;/a&gt;. With Sora as the last &lt;em&gt;Smash Ultimate&lt;/em&gt; character, Mr. Sakurai can, at last, get some &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/please-for-the-love-of-god-let-masahiro-sakurai-rest-1845241032"&gt;well-deserved rest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22690440/sora-kingdom-hearts-final-smash-ultimate-character-nintendo-switch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22690440/sora-kingdom-hearts-final-smash-ultimate-character-nintendo-switch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-05T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-05T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Will these top Steam games support Steam Deck? We ask their developers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ig2Syrva7PjGa4-kJJqpG7spCK8=/0x0:1620x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69953418/steam_deck.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5YP9VQ"&gt;Valve’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22612886/valve-steam-deck-handheld-gaming-pc-hands-on-preview"&gt;$400 Steam Deck gaming handheld&lt;/a&gt; runs Linux, but it can play Windows games too. Many of them, anyhow! Some of the biggest games on Steam use anti-cheat software that doesn’t play nice with &lt;a href="https://www.protondb.com/"&gt;the Proton compatibility layer&lt;/a&gt; which lets Windows games work. That’s changing this year, with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22690670/epic-eac-anti-cheat-linux-valve-steam-deck-support-games"&gt;both Epic’s Easy Anti-Cheat (EAC) and BattlEye&lt;/a&gt; confirming to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that support is on the way, and Epic says it takes “just a few clicks.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o6tiI3"&gt;But will game developers patch their games to take advantage? Not necessarily! We reached out to every developer of every top EAC and BattlEye game on Steam. While four of them gave us a definite yes, the rest were less committed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KxLTdw"&gt;Here’s what they all had to say. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="FsYmJH"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;7 Days to Die&lt;/em&gt; — No comment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="24vKam"&gt;“We have no comment on it at this time. Our game is still in development. As we are still in Alpha, we are not ready to give a definitive yes or no at this time,” a spokesperson for developer The Fun Pimps tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sMkd7Y"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;/em&gt; — No answer yet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="2yC3Dk"&gt;“We’re checking with the Respawn team on this and will get back to you as soon as we have an update,” a rep told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; on September 28th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="nQA54a"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Ark: Survival Evolved&lt;/em&gt; — Yes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="CZztMr"&gt;“Yes, we plan to update ARK settings to enable Battleye’s anti-cheat tweak for Steam Deck,” a Studio Wildcard rep tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="W5cOel"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Black Desert&lt;/em&gt; — No answer yet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="VMR55I"&gt;“I’m checking with our devs right now and will get back to you with an answer asap,” a Pearl Abyss rep told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;on October 3rd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="rr8tEx"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;DayZ&lt;/em&gt; — Maybe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="rYBtGd"&gt;“At this stage it’s a ‘maybe’ for us – we are still evaluating Proton as a whole and cannot yet commit to anything,” a Bohemia Interactive rep tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="OrdEIb"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Dead by Daylight &lt;/em&gt;— Yes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="GlnkzH"&gt;“I can confirm that we have plans of updating our EAC to support the Steamdeck in the future,” a Behaviour Interactive rep tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="b2aVjT"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Destiny 2&lt;/em&gt; — No answer yet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="AnhvTI"&gt;“We’ve been trying to run this down. We don’t have anything to share right now, today, but we’ll keep at it,” a Bungie rep told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;on October 3rd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="p0NUZv"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Fall Guys &lt;/em&gt;— No comment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="uypZxD"&gt;Even though it’s owned by Epic Games, the company saying EAC support should take “just a few clicks,” Mediatonic would not commit to an update for &lt;em&gt;Fall Guys&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9AX1C6"&gt;“Thanks for reaching out but at this time we won’t be making a comment,” a Mediatonic rep tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="jNGoyZ"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Halo: The Master Chief Collection &lt;/em&gt;— No comment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="i9zNhH"&gt;“I won’t have anything to share here, I’m afraid,” a rep for Microsoft tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="TrLWit"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Hunt: Showdown&lt;/em&gt; — No reply whatsoever&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="wciYkG"&gt;Crytek didn’t respond to repeated requests for comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="s8Ck0U"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Paladins&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Smite&lt;/em&gt; — Maybe, but not this year&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="jRnoR8"&gt;“We don’t currently have a timeline available but hope to provide such support in the near future,” a Hi-Rez Studios rep tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, adding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="NhbGgd"&gt;While we have been actively doing some research on the topic, it is unlikely this support would happen by the Steamdeck launch in December. Even though our games do share some similarities, each one of them requires its own implementation that is significantly more delicate than changing some settings in the SDK. Hi-Rez is proud to have its games available on multiple platforms and consoles, so we hope to be able to provide such support in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="64yre1"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;PUBG&lt;/em&gt; — No comment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="HBEUje"&gt;“The team does not have a comment for this,” a rep for Krafton tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="jOGwGO"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Rainbow Six: Siege &lt;/em&gt;— No comment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="N2bOky"&gt;“We don’t have anything to share at this time,” a Ubisoft rep tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="qWKf3u"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Rust&lt;/em&gt; — Yes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="zttq2h"&gt;“Yeah we’re working on it. Hoping to be done by the time the Deck comes out, if not it’ll be really soon after,” Facepunch Studios founder Garry Newman tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="qxevgr"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;War Thunder&lt;/em&gt; — Yes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="4YOIKk"&gt;“Yes, we’re planning to do everything we can to make sure that War Thunder works on Steam Deck,” Gaijin Entertainment co-founder Anton Yudinsev tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="alUKY0"&gt;&lt;em&gt;We’ll update this story as more top games offer a yes or no on support for anti-cheat on Linux/Proton generally, and the Steam Deck specifically. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="GdYoKB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Valve Steam Deck hands-on: the Nintendo Switch of PC gaming","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22612886/valve-steam-deck-handheld-gaming-pc-hands-on-preview"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22709918/valve-steam-deck-supported-games-anti-cheat-proton-eac-battleye-epic"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22709918/valve-steam-deck-supported-games-anti-cheat-proton-eac-battleye-epic</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-05T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-05T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Fortnite’s ‘Fortnitemares’ Halloween event will include a spooky short film festival</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QSzQ6v9T3JuXPThy0aTTVRbXXaM=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69953414/1.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LhiP7B"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; is hosting its third short film festival as part of its annual “Fortnitemares” Halloween event, but with a seasonal twist: the latest Short Nite show will focus on &lt;em&gt;spooky&lt;/em&gt; animated short films, dubbed “Shortnitemares,” because there’s nothing people love more than a good portmanteau. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rOgGvb"&gt;Shortnitemares follows up on the previous &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585705/fortnite-short-nite-2-film-festival-party-royale-july-23rd"&gt;two Short Nite film festivals&lt;/a&gt; (held over the summer and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22278892/fortnite-film-festival-short-nite-party-royale"&gt;in February&lt;/a&gt;), although the latest iteration is getting a bit of an upgrade: instead of airing in a nonstop loop on the combat-free Party Royale island, Shortnitemares will get a custom-made movie theater from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/quantumbuilds?lang=en"&gt;Quantum Builds&lt;/a&gt; (which specializes in creating custom &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; maps for brand activations) that will offer individual theaters for each short to watch on-demand, in addition to a main room that will show the entire lineup on loop. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gvyK6X9qBvnuncH5lJAudtuiZq0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22902279/18BR_FNMRS_Pumpkin_Outfits.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="nVhhVM"&gt;Epic hasn’t announced which films or creators will be featured in Shortnitemares (or even a specific date for the event outside of sometime at the end of October), but it promises that it’ll have more news soon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AgOjLF"&gt;Epic is also emphasizing the Halloween event much more than usual this year, with new content in the game every day of the month of October. This includes Halloween-themed maps and modes that members of the community created and a slew of classic monster movie costumes like &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Mummy&lt;/em&gt; to purchase in the store. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="la5zkt"&gt;The event will also tie into the storyline of the ongoing season, which already veered toward the spookier side of things with the invasion of the mysterious cubes and a &lt;em&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/em&gt;-esque “Sideways” dimension. Fortnitemares will launch a new weapon, additional quests, and a limited-time game mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SdfBuy"&gt;There’s also whatever this skin is, which appears to allow players to dress up as the sinister cubes and use a chunk of the island itself as a weapon: &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/09RebjfYowXMaipLq4IItb0sIMw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22902263/18BR_FNMRS_Geometrik_Outfit.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="2bRd3I"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22710510/fortnite-fortnitemares-halloween-event-spooky-short-film-festival-epic-games"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22710510/fortnite-fortnitemares-halloween-event-spooky-short-film-festival-epic-games</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-05T09:52:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-05T09:52:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google Nest’s latest security cameras are now on sale</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xUIT3MoRk5DPayL078ZisjLJaug=/0x423:5225x3906/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69953138/Nest_Cam_with_floodlight_US_Keyword_Blog.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google Nest’s first floodlight security camera is available to buy today.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Google Nest&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SzmOg0"&gt;Following its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22609444/google-nest-cam-indoor-floodlight-doorbell-price-specs-news"&gt;announcement of an all-new Nest Cam&lt;/a&gt; lineup this summer, Google has made the last of the four cameras it announced available in its &lt;a href="https://store.google.com/product/nest_cam_floodlight_wired?hl=en-US"&gt;Google Store&lt;/a&gt;: the Google Nest Cam wired ($99.99) and the Google Nest Cam with floodlight ($279.99). The cameras join the new Nest Cam battery, an indoor / outdoor camera, and the Nest Doorbell battery that went on sale in August. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vFwBAm"&gt;The Nest Cam wired is the budget camera in the lineup and is much smaller than the indoor / outdoor Nest Cam, which can be wired or work off its built-in battery. The indoor model dispenses with a built-in battery and isn’t weatherproofed, helping make it cheaper and smaller. It keeps the same 16:9 aspect ratio, with 1080p video at up to 30fps, plus it has a 135-degree field of view and 6x digital zoom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1EUyxR"&gt;One unique feature about the Nest Cam wired is that it comes in four colors — white, pink, beige, or green — a first in the smart home security camera space. There’s also a wooden base available for the pink (sorry, “sand”) version of the camera for a further aesthetic flourish and a price hike to $119.99. Interestingly, Google is keeping the original black &lt;a href="https://store.google.com/product/nest_cam_specs?hl=en-US"&gt;indoor Nest Cam&lt;/a&gt; around for $129.99. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Mq7UyA5umlBA7xVx1zbTALJp__k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22902056/NestCam_wired__Colors_Snow_SandMaple_Linen_Fog_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google Nest&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nest Cam wired comes in four color choices.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="wGMNCr"&gt;The Nest Cam with floodlight is essentially the indoor / outdoor Nest Cam attached to a 2,400 lumen floodlight. It streams 1080p video with HDR, with a 1/2.8-inch, 2-megapixel sensor, 130-degree diagonal field of view, and a 6x digital zoom. It requires permanent power and has to be wired into your home’s wiring through a standard outdoor junction box. The floodlight is rated IP65 for weatherproofing and the camera itself is IP54. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FyNsn9"&gt;The key feature here is that the floodlight cam uses on-device intelligence to detect people, animals, and vehicles rather than just relying on a motion sensor, as most floodlight cams do. This should mean you’re not constantly illuminating the garden when tree branches blow in the wind.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YSAtbhJ_SNsrdCft5MG4TXCi_j0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22902059/Nest_Cam_with_Floodlight_night_far_front_view.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google Nest&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nest Cam with floodlight is Google’s first hardware foray into any kind of smart lighting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="HqHa6i"&gt;All the new Nest cameras use built-in intelligence and on-device processing, which means less reliance on the cloud — so no fees for animal, vehicle, and person detection. You can also create Activity Zones for free and get three hours of event-based video without a subscription. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yjXaL0"&gt;Local storage on the cameras will record up to an hour of footage (about a week’s worth of events) if the power or internet go out. For more than three hours of video clips, or to enable 24/7 recording on the Nest Cam wired and Nest Cam with floodlight, you need to pay for a Nest Aware subscription, starting at $6 a month. This also enables Nest’s Familiar Faces feature that will tell you which person it’s seen as opposed to just that it’s seen a person. The Nest Cams use the Google Home app and do not work with the Nest app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k0HbHI"&gt;However, this isn’t the last we’ll see of new Nest Cams. Google recently announced that it’s planning to release a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22700859/google-nest-doorbell-wired-2nd-gen-launching-2022"&gt;new Nest Cam Doorbell wired&lt;/a&gt; in 2022, presumably to replace the excellent but aging Nest Hello video doorbell. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O7nGNw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l8lmyL"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 9:52AM ET, October 5th: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added details of the weatherproofing ratings for the Nest Cam with floodlight.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22709633/google-nest-indoor-cam-floodlight-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22709633/google-nest-indoor-cam-floodlight-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-05T09:32:53-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-05T09:32:53-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft’s new Surface pen feels like it’s alive</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5pqEXgU4WZXgIDQ0cIzl2eztw2s=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69953278/bfarsace_211004_4777_0057.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new Surface Slim Pen 2.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="swIBF8"&gt;Microsoft’s new Surface Pro 8 has a gorgeous 120Hz display and updated internals, but it’s really the new Surface Slim Pen 2 that has caught my attention. Microsoft has added haptics features to its stylus for the first time, thanks to a new custom chip inside. It has transformed inking &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22709876/microsoft-surface-pro-8-review"&gt;on the Surface Pro 8&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D8xpoI"&gt;I thought the haptic feedback would be a gimmick until I started testing it this weekend. In the Sketchable Windows app, you can select from a variety of drawing tools, like brushes, pencils, markers, inking nibs, and even chalk. They all feel totally different now, thanks to the haptics in the Surface Slim Pen 2.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/X4jeMcAJBhcHhKYQPIKXdAwzV-Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22902126/gaupgOb.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apps like Sketchable support the new Surface pen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="y7oRXN"&gt;This isn’t the buzzy haptic feedback you’re probably used to from a phone, the haptics are more subtle here and adjust to give you a slightly different sensation of drawing depending on the tool selected. It’s difficult to describe without feeling it yourself, but the chalk feels... chalky, and the inking nib has the slight bit of tension you’d expect to feel on real paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vjf2Hj"&gt;This tactile feedback moves beyond just drawing tools, though. In Microsoft Office, you can feel subtle vibrations through the pen that let you know when gestures are detected, like drawing shapes and then having them automatically converted. There are subtle haptics that let you know an action has been taken or when you’re selecting objects. It’s very understated in Sketchable, but it’s a welcome improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Surface Pro 8 open, up close, with the keyboard pulled out and the stylus visible. The screen displays a blue swirl on a white background." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/H6rtt3RL8l3yWXf6gCoSZAqSD4w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22900773/bfarsace_211004_4777_0021.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Surface Slim Pen 2 sits inside the Surface Pro 8 keyboard.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7tiHrn"&gt;Unfortunately, not every app supports this haptic feedback yet. Developers will need to update their apps to include support, and so far I’ve only been able to get it working in Excel, Whiteboard, and Sketchable. I was expecting to see it prominently in Microsoft’s note-taking app, OneNote, but it’s strangely absent. Microsoft says &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fp%2Fliquidtext-reading-note-taking-better-than-paper%2F9n9z9nsv47fl%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%3Aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;LiquidText&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fp%2Fshapr3d%2F9n4k9qfv4xfc%3Factivetab%3Dpivot%3Aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Shapr3D&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fp%2Fjournal-a-microsoft-garage-project%2F9n318r854rhh%23activetab%3Dpivot%3Aoverviewtab" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Journal&lt;/a&gt; all include support for the haptic feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ZiBYTv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Microsoft Surface Pro 8 review: the best of both worlds ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22709876/microsoft-surface-pro-8-review"},{"title":"Windows 11 review: a familiar home that’s still being renovated ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22708762/microsoft-windows-11-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="DfsSaK"&gt;The Surface Slim Pen 2 also has a slight redesign over the original, with a sharper and longer tip. I’ve only had a short time to try this out and I’m certainly not a digital artist, but overall it feels a little more responsive and accurate than the Slim Pen that shipped with the Surface Pro X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6eyy46"&gt;The big drawback to the Surface Slim Pen 2 is its price, at $129.99 or as part of the new Surface Pro Signature keyboard priced at $279.99. The regular keyboard is $179.99, so if you really want the Surface Slim Pen 2, then the bundle saves you $30 on an already expensive purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22710381/microsoft-surface-slim-pen-2-hands-on"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22710381/microsoft-surface-slim-pen-2-hands-on</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-05T09:23:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-05T09:23:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google is about to turn on two-factor authentication by default for millions of users</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/B77qHu-O8DqFE617gk2iWDpoG2c=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69953232/acastro_191014_1777_google_pixel_0004.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gigfqC"&gt;In May, Google announced plans &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22422778/google-accounts-enabling-two-step-verification-default"&gt;to enable two-factor authentication (or two-step verification as it’s referring to the setup) by default&lt;/a&gt; to enable more security for many accounts. Now it’s Cybersecurity Awareness Month, and Google is once again reminding us of that plan, &lt;a href="https://blog.google/technology/safety-security/making-sign-safer-and-more-convenient/"&gt;saying in a blog post&lt;/a&gt; that it will enable two-factor for 150 million more accounts by the end of this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w46AU6"&gt;In 2018, Google said that &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/2018/1/23/16922500/gmail-users-two-factor-authentication-google"&gt;only 10 percent of its active accounts were using two-factor authentication&lt;/a&gt;. It has been pushing, prodding, and encouraging people to enable the setting ever since. Another prong of the effort will &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TeamYouTube/status/1429868034508787714?s=20"&gt;require&lt;/a&gt; more than 2 million YouTube creators to turn on two-factor authentication to protect their channels from takeover. Google says it has partnered with organizations to give away more than 10,000 hardware security keys every year. Its push for two-factor has made the technology readily available on your phone whether you use &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/10/18295348/google-android-phone-fido-webauthn-phishing-two-factor-authentication"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/15/21066768/google-iphone-ios-security-key-2-factor-authentication"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SxVyxk"&gt;A tool that also helps users keep their accounts secure is using a password manager, and Google now says that it checks over a billion passwords a day via its built-in manager for Chrome, Android, and the Google app. The password manager is also available on iOS, where Chrome can autofill logins for other apps. Google says that soon it will help you generate passwords for other apps, making things even more straightforward. Also coming soon is the ability to see all of your saved passwords directly from the Google app menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="00IfVj"&gt;Last but not least, Google is &lt;a href="https://security.googleblog.com/2021/10/google-protects-your-accounts-even-when.html"&gt;highlighting its Inactive Account Manager&lt;/a&gt;. This is a set of decisions to make about what happens to your account if you decide to stop using it or are no longer around and able to make those decisions. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Google Inactive Account Manager" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/l4Hm-E--zwutZSZ_97lbaGvkyhk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22902176/inactive_accountmanager.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google Inactive Account Manager&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="A0QE1M"&gt;Google added the feature in 2013 so that you can &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/account/inactive"&gt;set a timeout period for your account&lt;/a&gt; between three and 18 months of disuse before the Inactive Account Manager protocols take effect. Just in case you only switched accounts or forgot about your login, Google will send an email a month before the limit is up. At that point, you can choose to have your information deleted or have it forwarded to whatever trusted contacts you want to have handling things on your behalf. Google’s blog post notes that an inactive account led to the massive Colonial Pipeline attack earlier this year, and just for security’s sake, you probably don’t want your digital life simply hanging around unused for whatever hackers are bored in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22710421/google-security-2fa-inactive-account-management"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22710421/google-security-2fa-inactive-account-management</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-05T09:19:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-05T09:19:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>Another one (Gimlet podcast) bites the dust (goes exclusive)</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RTYkL0S2QjDC90t8Ug_aVektF0A=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69953222/acastro_190927_1777_3693_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Images provided by Spotify / Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rNVWv7"&gt;Hello again, welcome to the first week of October. I’m loving the spooky vibes and strong pumpkin energy the fall has wrought, although it was a little steamy here in NYC this past weekend. Summer’s last gasp. But I’m not complaining! I put the heat on in my car for approximately three minutes last week and was sad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CkY606"&gt;Enough about my SAD, though, and more on audio. In today’s newsletter we discuss the fan reaction to Spotify’s latest exclusive move, along with Patreon looking to make its own original podcasts, and more. Off we go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y1CeOh"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gimlet’s &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heavyweight &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;is becoming a Spotify exclusive, and the fans are mad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uT6353"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Heavyweight&lt;/em&gt;, one of the longest-running Gimlet Media shows, is becoming a Spotify exclusive next month, five years after it began and two years after the Spotify / Gimlet acquisition. Host Jonathan Goldstein made the announcement (through a dynamically inserted ad for people listening outside the app) within the first couple minutes of the new season premiere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O8RmkY"&gt;“I get that when you find something working for you, you don’t want to rethink it,” he says. “But that said, I’ve also made the change over to Spotify, and it’s super intuitive, it’s easy to use, and I really like it. So if you enjoy the show and you want to support us and the work that we do, I truly do hope that you’ll join us on Spotify.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cGFcQS"&gt;As is sometimes the story with these moves, the fans are upset, and perhaps because of the seemingly Very Online listenership for this specific show, they’re tweeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CGEPXP"&gt;I’m embedding a couple tweets here, so you can gauge the reaction for yourselves, but broadly speaking, they aren’t so warm and fuzzy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="09xlJH"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;One of favorite podcasts (Heavyweight) is going &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Spotify?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Spotify&lt;/a&gt; exclusive. I thought I could finally just switch all my podcasts there. But turns out they don’t support private RSS feeds like patreon or slate plus. So staying with Pocketcasts. Very annoying.&lt;/p&gt;— Paola (@Paopalinaa) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Paopalinaa/status/1444754401898422281?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 3, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="KjTwjj"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Love Heavyweight, but do know that the exclusive thing is not just a matter of using a different app. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Spotify?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Spotify&lt;/a&gt; podcasts are not available in many countries (Ukraine in my case), so Heavyweight will essentially disappear in a month for me. Hope the money’s worth it. &lt;/p&gt;— Vladimir Agafonkin (@mourner) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mourner/status/1444065920637456389?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 1, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="vma3di"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/heavyweight?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@heavyweight&lt;/a&gt; podcast is, in my view, perfect. It’s the dictionary definition of podcasting. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/J_Goldstein?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@J_Goldstein&lt;/a&gt; is a genius and his team are so talented. It’s my favourite podcast. &lt;br&gt;But, now making it exclusive to Spotify? Sorry, but that’s a dealbreaker.&lt;/p&gt;— KDP (@kerrydupont) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kerrydupont/status/1443864686873571330?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 1, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="u7VmRv"&gt;There’s plenty more — feel free to check them out &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=heavyweight%20exclusive&amp;amp;src=typed_query&amp;amp;f=live"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I reached out to Spotify for clarification on why &lt;em&gt;Heavyweight&lt;/em&gt; is going exclusive and what the goal is with this move, and a spokesperson referred me to &lt;a href="https://newsroom.spotify.com/2021-08-19/making-spotifys-exclusive-content-inclusive-to-creators-and-listeners/"&gt;this August blog post&lt;/a&gt;, which posits to offer an explanation but says basically nothing. The clearest sentence that could pass as an explanation is maybe this one: “We believe that streaming is the future of all audio listening and that our technology can provide the opportunity for the podcast ecosystem to grow, innovate, and ultimately create more opportunities for creators across the globe.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S674Rx"&gt;Reading between the lines here: Spotify doesn’t want you to download episodes and therefore receive either baked-in podcast ads or dynamically inserted ones. Instead, it wants to own the entire advertising pipeline, which it can only do if you stream on Spotify. I assume you readers are familiar with its Streaming Ad Insertion tech, which you can read more about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/8/21056336/spotify-streaming-ad-insertion-technology-ces-launch"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, but essentially, it targets ads on the fly as individual listeners stream, and this ad targeting relies on Spotify data about listeners. Therefore, if you’re listening on Apple Podcasts or Pocket Casts or anywhere else, Spotify misses its opportunity to leverage the data it collects to not only serve better ads, but in the case of Gimlet shows, also sell more of them. Plus, you listening on Spotify means it also has a better chance of converting you into a paying subscriber, or at the very least, it begins your personal data trail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h1gdtp"&gt;The open question is whether angering some fans is worth the tradeoff, and for Spotify, the answer appears to be yes. I’m sure &lt;em&gt;Heavyweight&lt;/em&gt; will lose some listenership  — even Joe Rogan, who was never on the platform before going exclusive and thereby could have stood to gain some audience from his deal, might &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22632213/joe-rogan-experience-spotify-exclusive-audience-reach"&gt;have lost&lt;/a&gt; a substantial chunk of his listenership. In this case, Spotify’s trading in some of &lt;em&gt;Heavyweight&lt;/em&gt;’s listeners for the opportunity to make some cash. Unfortunate for those who don’t want to switch, but this is just how the industry operates right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5yIdA2"&gt;Speaking of Spotify...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2bSKfX"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Twitch and Warner Music Group will launch exclusive music channels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uD8n6I"&gt;This bit of news happened last week, but I wanted to be sure to mention it here. Warner Music Group and Twitch &lt;a href="https://www.wmg.com/news/warner-music-group-and-twitch-announce-first-its-kind-partnership-35781"&gt;reached an agreement&lt;/a&gt; that’ll bring some of the music giant’s artists to Twitch through new channels, as well as exclusive original programming on the livestreaming platform. Per Oana Ruxandra, chief digital officer and EVP of business development at WMG, in the press release: “It’s clear that Twitch is an indispensable space for all types of creators to connect with their fan communities. Our partnership creates an on-ramp for artists to come onto the service with strong support from Twitch, opening up an entirely new source of incremental revenue.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GOxGYw"&gt;Of course, music is audio, but why do we care about this move here? Well, for one, multiple platforms see livestreaming audio as a business opportunity. Amazon itself is reportedly working on some sort of live audio product apart from Twitch, while Greenroom, Spotify’s live social audio app, was billed at launch as a place for musicians, podcasters, and creators more broadly to connect with fans for exclusive experiences. This Twitch deals trips up Spotify’s whole dream. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TcIkcV"&gt;Not only does Twitch appeal to a much-desired demographic — young people — but it’s a massive, global platform. Much of this audio war is about being the main place people spend their time, whether it be listening to a podcast, having a conversation with a respected professional, or streaming music. Spotify could, of course, still have WMG musicians on Greenroom, which I assume will eventually be an in-app experience, but an exclusive content deal with Twitch doesn’t make that as easy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rL6k73"&gt;I’ll also point out here just how essential it is that these platforms figure out monetization. Twitch creators sell subscriptions to their channels, collect tips, and distribute ads, of course while getting a cut of it all. Meanwhile, Spotify’s still figuring out how to help creators monetize at every level. It’s looking to sell more podcast ads for more people, and Greenroom appears to factor into this strategy, too. All of which is to say, I have a feeling Spotify wasn’t happy to see this deal announced, and I’ll be watching how it and other platforms react to the news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JAHhdD"&gt;Of course, when we’re talking about the creator economy we have to mention Patreon, and it also has a bit of news this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LIl1lA"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patreon seeks original podcasting content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wuo3Ke"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-09-30/creator-economy-patreon-invests-in-original-content-to-compete-with-big-tech?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; late last week that Patreon, which has historically allowed creators to sell subscriptions to their work, is apparently now looking to finance its own original content. The strategy appears to be windowing the content for an exclusive period of time to Patreon itself. Now, unfortunately, this is all we have in the way of details, so I’ll leave this one short and hope we hear more in the coming weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="InlguJ"&gt;I got a few more short ones and then we’ll wrap up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="pYU7n0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10776720"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Hspmdq"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NPR workers negotiate a new contract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v9kR5u"&gt;NPR staffers have ratified a new collective bargaining agreement with the company. The union &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/wemakenpr/status/1443996701178671111?s=20"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; the highlights, but among them are the guarantee that NPR will advertise the salary for in-union jobs on listings; increased salary minimums; and an agreement to improve its policies when it comes to addressing online harassment. I look forward to seeing the full contract! I imagine it’ll serve as a reference point for future podcast / audio unions’ negotiations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NtXP0T"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Athletic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; has been burning through cash&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wp3RrQ"&gt;We’ve been tracking &lt;em&gt;The Athletic&lt;/em&gt; here at &lt;em&gt;Hot Pod&lt;/em&gt; given its &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/the-athletic-launches-podcast-network-65f115a8-da39-409b-98df-80d74a325966.html"&gt;ambitious podcast strategy&lt;/a&gt; that involves multiple localized and national shows. According &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/the-athletic-burned-through-95-million-between-2019-and-2020?shared=22f60909d3b98ff0"&gt;to &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;yesterday, however, the company burned through $95 million between 2019 and 2020. This, the publication says, surpassed its $73 million in revenue during that time period. It apparently has enough cash to cover its costs for the next eight months, which could explain why it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/the-athletic-hires-liontree-to-find-buyer-at-price-of-more-than-750-million"&gt;been trying to find&lt;/a&gt; an acquirer at a price of more than $750 million. Best of luck, and I hope these podcasters land on their feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aCXfUO"&gt;Now, finally, I don’t typically cover content deals but sometimes the extraordinary happens...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JoX9Tk"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lindsay Lohan is becoming a podcaster&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7pk2bG"&gt;The early aughts are back, and apparently, it comes with a podcasting twist. First, Paris Hilton invested in the unfortunately named Podz, which sold to Spotify, and now, here comes Lindsay Lohan with a Studio71-made podcast. The unnamed show will be released in late 2021 or early 2022, and Studio71 says it’ll be the place she shares her “authentic voice” while listeners will “get a chance to experience a never-before-seen side of the megastar.” I thought I heard her authentic voice on &lt;em&gt;Speak&lt;/em&gt;, her debut album, but I suppose I can accept a podcast, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mNECbE"&gt;Alright, a bit of a long one today, but I’ll be back on Thursday for our paying subscribers. As always, if you’d like to keep up with all the audio and podcasting news, scoops, and analysis, &lt;a href="https://hotpodnews.com/subscribe/"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;. See you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uxiXqX"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rMvXtG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22710438/heavyweight-podcast-gimlet-exclusive-spotify-hot-pod"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22710438/heavyweight-podcast-gimlet-exclusive-spotify-hot-pod</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-05T09:15:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-05T09:15:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Waymo co-CEO Tekedra Mawakana on how to get self-driving taxis to the mall</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uHKbl377zC4lOCEhIpgu0kejquA=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69953203/VRG_Decoder_TekedraMawkana_s.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Grayson Blackmon / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;It’s harder than it looks&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="XLicYg"&gt;Waymo is working on self-driving taxis, which is a huge deal. Ride-sharing apps like Uber and Lyft have remade cities, allowed people to give up their cars, and generally connected the buttons you push on your phone to real things happening in the world more directly than almost any other app. Just this week, Bank of America’s trading desk sent out an investor note saying Uber was the most &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/carlquintanilla/status/1444722440836304896?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1444722440836304896%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=about%3Asrcdoc"&gt;transformational thing to happen to the phone in the past decade&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Oim4vk"&gt;But simply getting a car to show up where you want isn’t the endgame. The endgame is to make a robot show up to your house — a self-driving car. Self-driving cars promise to even more radically remake cities and suburbs, decrease overall car ownership, and let commuters take back hours of their time as they travel. It’s a big dream, and we’ve talked to a bunch of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22627847/argo-ai-bryan-salesky-decoder-interview-lyft-self-driving"&gt;tech and&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22444294/ford-f150-lightning-pickup-truck-jim-farley-interview"&gt;car CEOs&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;em&gt;Decoder&lt;/em&gt; about it in the past year. All of them are working on self-driving, but no one’s really close yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bvOZk7"&gt;But then there’s Waymo. Waymo has been quietly testing self-driving minivans in Phoenix for a few years now, and they are about to launch a pilot program in San Francisco. These are basically heavily modified Chrysler Pacifica minivans and Jaguar I-Pace SUVs that can drive themselves. Many Waymo rides happen without anyone else in the car — no safety driver, nothing. Just you and the robot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HOEXGy"&gt;I talked to Tekedra Mawakana, co-CEO of Waymo, about expanding Waymo’s service to other cities, the hurdles in place, and how she thinks the company will make money over time. We also talked about the regulatory issues the industry faces as it tries to roll out self-driving more broadly, and whether things like Tesla’s “full self driving” are confusing the issue or helping it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t1WJq8"&gt;This was a really fun conversation made even better because we recorded it live, onstage at Code Conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="z3ipxE"&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="200" scrolling="no" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm?e=VMP4404553418" width="100%"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6dYe77"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This transcript has been lightly edited for clarity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ASXdt1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m very pleased to be talking to Tekedra Mawakana, the co-CEO of Waymo. Welcome, Tekedra. Hello.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rfk3j8"&gt;Hi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="er20lz"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are you doing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a5P3av"&gt;Great, thank you for the warm welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dm5Ozq"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yeah, doing this in front of a live audience is very exciting. Alright, Waymo. Self-driving cars, what’s taking so long?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fd8koM"&gt;We’ve been at it for a while. I would say it’s the engineering challenge of our generation. That is what’s taking it so long. To do it, and do it well, I think means two things. One, that safety is at the core of everything we do. And safety takes time. And secondly, we actually have to learn along the way. It’s like a process of discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PQS7AW"&gt;What’s funny to me is when I think back to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/2/22364317/waymo-ceo-john-krafcik-stepping-down-self-driving-cars-google-alphabet"&gt;when I joined Waymo almost five years ago&lt;/a&gt;. And I remember thinking, “Oh, product market fit’s probably done. It’s ready to commercialize.” And I realize, no, you actually have to put the technology into the real world and that’s how you get it ready. That’s what we’ve been focused on doing, and learning, and receiving feedback from, now, riders in Phoenix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9bWDee"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m very curious to ask how that feedback’s going. But first, you’re new to the co-CEO role. You only started in April.  And a co-CEO used to be an unusual arrangement; now it’s kind of a trendy arrangement. What’s the split with you and your co-CEO?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F4rFsu"&gt;My co-CEO, Dmitri Dolgov, is one of the founders of Waymo. He’s one of the people who has been working on this problem for his whole career. He was the CTO before this role. I was the COO. And so we still focus primarily on the two areas that we know the best. I think about how you commercialize, deploy the technology, introduce it to communities, and he focuses on building the Waymo Driver. Then we come together to figure out what’s the best strategy: How do you sequence it? What’s going to be the rollout plan? And so far it’s going great. We have very different and complementary skill sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="94Ps45"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I think there’s the capability, what the technology can do, and then there’s what you’re allowed to do with it, which seems challenging at this point in time. I ask this question of every executive that comes on &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decoder&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, which is a plug, how do you make decisions?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r72QvN"&gt;How do I make decisions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8igA8Q"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your strategy for making some of the complicated decisions you have to make?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZsOYlo"&gt;It’s something that I’ve had to relearn in my time at Waymo. I like using data to make decisions. And I think when you’re introducing a new technology, introducing a new business model, introducing consumers to an experience that’s never existed before, it’s really about getting comfortable knowing when you have enough data and also getting comfortable with your own gut. And so I say one of the things at Waymo that people get out of it is this reinforced sense of your own internal guide. That’s what I use a lot now because it’s pioneering. There isn’t a playbook. No one’s done it before. We’re figuring it out as we go along. It requires a lot of humility and a lot of openness around learning. And so I learn, I listen, I make a decision. If it’s not the right decision we pivot, and we keep going. And so really having the mindset that this is a learning journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s9tYu1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The stakes are really high in this particular learning journey.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2BO7N7"&gt;Absolutely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="95MLFg"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’ve got people in robot cars, going places, taking rides. I want to talk about the technology and then I want to talk about what kind of business you’re going to build with it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DOFpk5"&gt;Yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wnh8ob"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s start with the tech, is the Waymo Driver ready? Could you just deploy it and give people rides right now? Is the bottleneck regulation and safety, or are you still working on it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="djLhKL"&gt;The Waymo Driver is in the world as we speak today. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/5/18126103/waymo-one-self-driving-taxi-service-ride-safety-alphabet-cost-app"&gt;We have a service called Waymo One&lt;/a&gt;, it’s in Phoenix, Arizona, and anyone who goes there can download the app and hail a ride to take them from point A to point B. When the car shows up, it’s empty. There’s no one in the car. There’s not a person in the car who’s not driving. There’s no one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="tg0hrG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9545330"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Pte9OM"&gt;The wonderful thing about the service in Phoenix, Arizona, is people get to have their own space. They’re in there, they get to have conference calls, do whatever they want to do. So it’s happening. I want to say that: the future is already happening. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y29WBo"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In a tiny part of Phoenix, Arizona.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NpKUke"&gt;In a 50-square-mile territory, which is also the size of San Francisco, so I’m not going to concede that it’s tiny. Yes, it is a specific jurisdiction that we’re working in, but that’s the way to do it safely. Also, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/24/22639226/waymo-san-francisco-rides-self-driving-service"&gt;we have launched a trusted tester program in San Francisco&lt;/a&gt;. So now residents of San Francisco are having the chance to try out our service too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UB6r4j"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you think your core technology stack is done and it can be deployed at scale? Or are you still learning and testing that part of the system?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gYpgiN"&gt;I think that’s one of the ways in which this is quite different. It’s not a one-and-done, and it’s also not, get the technology up to a certain point and now we’re ready to deploy it everywhere. Geographically, street lights are different, weather is different, there’s a lot about each domain that’s quite different. What you’ll see us do, and what you’ve seen us do now that we’re operating in two fairly different environments, that gives our tech stack the opportunity to learn. We’ve driven over 20 million miles on public roads, autonomously, across 25 cities. Over 20 billion miles in simulation, which is quite important. And so this is the way the Waymo Driver learns and all of that learning is shared across the fleet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vaimEx"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That area in Phoenix, which I grant you is quite large—&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TPz0xT"&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jonW1e"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;—the boundaries of that area have not expanded inside of Phoenix for quite some time. You’re starting to launch in San Francisco. Should we see a faster ramp of market expansion now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mUMJ5s"&gt;I think the question is, what is the goal? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EAskIW"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I just push a button and a robot comes and gets me?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zPG0ww"&gt;Yeah, well that is the goal for the customer. Our goal in Phoenix was to learn. Malls have seven to 12 entrances; which one do you expect to be picked up at? The reality is when you give us that address, we may not be at the same entrance you are and when there’s not a human in the car for you to call, or to call you. So what are the operational challenges associated with actually having a fully autonomous service? That’s what we’ve been doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="b2hr2F"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Malls are a difficult challenge for autonomous cars&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gBDDGS"&gt;We haven’t been expanding, we’ve been taking the feedback from our riders and making the service more and more delightful. That’s what we’re also doing in San Francisco. Now, we have riders, some have lived in the city for a really long time, and they’re excited to provide feedback to bring this technology to market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i85QBv"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You said 20 million miles, which is Waymo’s favorite statistic. You have driven more miles than anybody else, but the problem you’re describing is very local. It’s very small, you could get 100 million miles and you still might not know where the exit of the shopping mall is. Is that a challenge that you’re splitting? Are you attacking that differently?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EbUVA8"&gt;Yes, so when we talk about the number of miles that we’ve driven, that’s across all 25 cities, and that’s really important. We’ve tested rain, we’ve tested heat in Sun Valley, snow. Those miles are training the Driver for scenarios that we’re not currently operating a service in. When I talk about pickup and drop-offs, or the chaos in a parking lot, those are very specific to the service that we’re offering and the feedback that we’re getting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lojECe"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are a lot of self-driving companies on various parts of the stack. Some of them are deeply integrated with cars. Some of them are far away and they’re just selling a sensor. You have a line, right? The main bulk of your fleet is modified Chrysler Pacificas. Now you’ve got I-Paces. Do you think that you have a challenge of how the car itself changes once it can drive itself? Or are you happy to leave the cars to someone else?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IK5mLS"&gt;We’re really happy to partner with OEMs for the cars. Like you said, we partnered with Stellantis and JLR. They’ve been building cars for over 100 years. We actually think figuring out how to make the Driver safer is a really exciting challenge and so that’s what we’re focused on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NQZq9u"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you think about the actual wheels, drivetrain, crash impact stuff, or is that kind of a commodity to you? Can you swap those in and out?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4Pc8be"&gt;I think the underlying base vehicle is in and of itself an evolving platform. I think that’s the way to think about it. Right now we see all of this innovation around EVs and despite 100 years of internal combustion engines trying to become more efficient — gasoline engines are only about 25 percent [efficient] and diesel about 33 percent. Now that we have EVs, they are over 95 percent. That’s an innovative platform. It’s just not the one we’re focused on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9e4EhI"&gt;The one we’re focused on, I’d say, has three sides of innovation. First is building the Driver. Can you actually take the human out and have the car drive itself? Yes, we’re doing that and it’s very exciting. Second is what are the business models that unlock once you can do that? And so we’re focused on deploying the Waymo Driver across three main lines of business today. That’s Waymo One, which is ride-hailing, as well as Waymo Via, which is long-haul trucking as well as local delivery. Eventually we will also focus on personal car ownership, which is when you license the technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KA3WhZ"&gt;But then the third part of this innovation is actually being less comfortable with 40,000 people being killed on our roadways every year. Really deciding that if 94-ish percent, give or take, of those are caused by human error, then we have the opportunity to innovate and remove the human from the equation. Which means you don’t rely on the human to be alert at any point. You don’t need a driver’s license. You get in a car and the Waymo Driver takes you where you need to go safely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jhXwVr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are on stage after Elon Musk was on stage. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/26/22693610/tesla-opens-full-self-driving-beta-software-more-customers"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tesla has something called full self-driving&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, which is Level 2-plus on this complicated scale of self-driving that no one understands. You’re Level 4. You want to go to Level 5. Do you think that the full self-driving, driver assist stuff where people tune out, is poisoning the well of the self-driving conversation at all?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o37dye"&gt;In the early days, I guess 2013, the Google self-driving car project [before it spun out into Waymo] focused on auto assist technology. What we learned in our experience is people trust the technology beyond its capabilities. We witnessed employees actually shaving, and sleeping, and plugging into the backseat, even though we told them that was beyond the capability. And so I think the problem is, we’re human. When we get in the car we have other stuff to do. We’re leaving home and we need to get to work but we have three emails we meant to send, but the cat ran out, or whatever. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="sB8Ogp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I think the problem is, we’re human...you have to give people the chance to just do what they want to do, which is not focus on driving.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tSW8US"&gt;And so I think the problem is you have to give people the chance to just do what they want to do, which is not focus on driving. And so what we’re focused on, the reason we’re focused on Level 4 is that we believe it is the only way to safely deploy this technology in a way that improves road safety. And that is the mission that we’re built on. It’s a very different business model when you’re talking about driver assist. I have that in my car. It makes me stay in the lane. It’s delightful for what it is, but it isn’t something that allows me to tune out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d2W3SQ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You mentioned that one of the business models you’ll pursue in the future is licensing the technology. Is that something you’re actively going to pursue with carmakers? Buy the Waymo stack, put it on your cars, take the steering wheel out, sell the cars? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="93XeXs"&gt;Yes, we have already announced partnerships that we have along those lines, but we’ve been very open that obviously if you buy a car, you want it to go everywhere, right? You want us to be able to say it’s Level 5 and you can go everywhere and you can face any conditions. So it’s naturally later, it’s not soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JHefVS"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you competitive in that market? You’re going to have some partnerships, but are other companies focused on partnering too? Are you winning those deals or is everyone just signing the, “Hey, we have to have a bunch of suppliers. Let’s see who wins this stage of that market.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z0TIFX"&gt;I think that until people create a Level 4 system, it’s really hard to start negotiating viable deals about a Level 5 capability. I can’t speak to what people might be doing, but I know that there isn’t anyone else offering a public service today with Level 4 technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TigVuF"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Would you license the Level 4 system? There are Chrysler Pacificas, and Jaguar I-Paces, is there some reason I can’t buy a hot-rodded self-driving Chrysler Pacifica today?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UXRaPa"&gt;We would not license that. One, because as I said, we’re in the process of learning. Two, we’re operating it as a fleet. We’re not licensing the technology. And then three, there is a map. You, yourself, said it’s a particular jurisdiction. I think carmakers would say to us that that’s not really a viable product for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bKjTcJ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’ve got a market of at least one. I bet quite a few people in this room — who doesn’t love the Chrysler Pacifica? Let’s talk about the actual business, which is Waymo One and then the trucking business. Is that business baked, the revenue models set, you understand how it’s going to scale? What have you learned operating it at the scale you have that you’re going to need to change as you expand?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pv6LPs"&gt;I think one of the reasons that we do the early rider — in Phoenix we had an early rider program, now we have the riders in San Francisco — is actually learning, what do people care about? Everyone’s thinking about sustainable cities; “What’s the city of the future and how will EVs help shape that?” When you think about the trade-offs, we want transportation on-demand, when we want it. The reality is that will lead to more congestion. So will people make trade-offs? Will people say I’ll take an additional eight minutes to get that car if it means it’s not idling and congesting my city? And so we have a lot to learn about these business models and that’s what we’re testing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ztZMCB"&gt;I’m not going to sit here and say, we’ve figured out all of the various commercialization opportunities for the next 20 years. We’re actually listening and seeing how people will value the service accordingly. That’s testing pricing, all of the normal corporate strategies, but really, really having customers at the center of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r8JUJE"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Out of the data you’ve collected so far in Phoenix, what has surprised you the most about what customers want and what is the change you were not expecting to make?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8AA20S"&gt;I think one of the surprises for me has been the communities of people who feel very excluded from transportation today. I’ll just give two examples that are on two different ends of the spectrum. One are people who’ve had to have their keys taken away because they’re older. Now those families are like, “Oh my goodness, we get to avoid that conversation.” That’s a tough time. And then on the other end, we partner with the Foundation for Blind Children. These are kids whose 16th birthday doesn’t mean the same thing as everyone else. And so really giving people independence where they don’t need mom, or dad, or girlfriend, or boyfriend to carry them around has been a delightful surprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vlcPAk"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you had to adjust pricing? Are people willing to pay what you thought they were going to pay?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TBt0e0"&gt;People are willing to pay. We have a lot of demand. We don’t use our entire fleet for customer service. We’re still using some of the fleet also to advance the Waymo Driver. And so we have demand beyond the supply that we’re offering in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KAwiLt"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the reasons I ask about the pricing question is, and I’ve briefly talked about this before on &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decoder&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, once you get to self-driving cars — and if you’ve ever ridden in one, it is remarkably boring, by design — but once you get to that stage, what is going to differentiate you from every other self-driving robo-taxi service that exists?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JhJ6CU"&gt;Value proposition, right? We, as consumers, we go to the experience that’s the one we think is the best. It’s certainly not only because there’s one. That’s some of what we’re thinking about right now. When people get into Waymo One, one of the early observations we made, despite the fact that you can get into a ride-hailing service and take over their music, people don’t. It’s a very small percentage of people who want to do that. It’s your car that I’ve just entered. I’m sitting in the back seat, you’re in the front seat. You’re driving me. I’m only going to be in your car for three minutes. People get in the Waymo One, they immediately start playing their own music. Why? Because it’s their space and they have this privacy. They can get on a phone call. They’re not speaking cryptically, etc. And then for people who want to safely get their kids home after they’ve been pub crawling in Chandler, they’re able to do so. Their 21-plus-year-old kids, just to be clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="euW5o3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But at the end of the day, if this technology is available for sale from you or other suppliers, Uber will have it, Lyft will have it; the drunk kids coming home from Chandler, they’re just going to take a car home, right? What will make them pick you? What will keep your price high relative to everybody else?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MJQQbV"&gt;I think one of the premises of your question is that everyone will have it because everyone will have solved this problem. Versus everyone will have it because a few companies will solve this problem, and then those will be our partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nGHTx3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There we go.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jqbAMC"&gt;I would think of this as, one, how will we win? We will actually figure out how to scale this Driver. And once you figure out how to scale this Driver, the question will be, will we try to solve every mobility opportunity directly, or will we partner? We’ve already shown an appetite for partnering in Phoenix. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/7/18536003/waymo-lyft-self-driving-ride-hail-app-phoenix"&gt;We have a partnership with Lyft&lt;/a&gt; and we’ve put some of our cars in their fleet. That’s giving us the chance to see the difference between when someone opens a Waymo app and they know they’re going to receive our service, versus when someone opens a Lyft app and then they’re told, “Hey, there may be this opportunity to take this ride. Are you open for that? Yes or no?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H3ndHf"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I want to keep pushing this a little bit. That moment is still surprising. You open the Lyft app. One of the greatest innovations in the past decade is you can summon a Toyota Camry at will, anywhere in the world. When that experience turns into the robots coming to get you, obviously that’s surprising. If you look 10 years from now and the robot’s always coming to get you, how do you solve that challenge?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u3wvDw"&gt;You make me think about a time when I was in law school and I lived in New York and my mom was in Atlanta. When we talked on the phone I paid long-distance phone bills — and maybe that’s just really dating myself, but it was a lot of phone bills. I thought about this recently; nothing’s really changed about the phone, right? Obviously now they’re smartphones, but the reality is the entire business model now is about how do I just stay connected to loved ones with my smartphone without monthly charges, without long-distance charges, without these limitations? I think the question that you’re asking is, how do you make sure that what you’re creating is delightful enough that it feels like a change and it feels like an innovation? That’s what we’re focused on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EMX9Kj"&gt;When I’m in a Waymo car, it’s a consistent experience. We own the fleet. I get in the Jaguar I-Pace, it’s a beautiful ride. It’s clean. I know exactly what to expect. I play my own music. If we look ahead however many years, what is that car going to tell me about me when I get in, because I’ve been using it so often? What does it know about my route? Where do I tend to go on Friday nights? What do I like in my coffee? There’s so much to think about from a commercialization perspective and it’s really what keeps me excited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c1mcoj"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So there’s an exciting version of that. I’m duty bound to ask you about the other version. Which is, the car rolls up, it has no steering wheel. It’s full of screens and advertising is playing at you. Is this all an effort to just make more Google advertising inventory?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iv15vw"&gt;That’s certainly not what I spend any of my time focused on. We are heads down, focused on this and the business model. When I think about the vehicle form factors of the future, I’m thinking about us doing Code Conference in a car where we’re facing each other over a dining room table. That’s exciting to me and so [advertising is] not what I’m spending my time thinking about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rfe3qf"&gt;I love that you’re duty bound to ask, so thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iSQMR3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Waymo is part of Alphabet. What is that relationship to Google like?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xew8XW"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/12/13/13936782/google-self-driving-car-waymo-spin-off-company"&gt;The week Waymo spun out from Google&lt;/a&gt; was the week that I interviewed. They said, “Alphabet’s going to be here. We’re going to support you.” That has been my experience since joining. Obviously they’re our lead investor. We took external funding last year for the first time, and again this year. Even having these world-class investors that have expressed confidence in us, having Alphabet as our primary investor and supporter has been invaluable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wdQG7T"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So obviously Sundar Pichai is now the CEO of Alphabet and Google. When was the last time Larry [Page] and Sergey [Brin] came by and just checked in on Waymo?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cYVj51"&gt;Larry and Sergey drop by whenever they’d like, but we’ve all been sheltering. We’ve all been sheltering so it’s not as common an experience as it was before COVID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8ZWSzX"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are they taking an active interest in the business?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7q9mY0"&gt;Always.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mn4mY0"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I want to ask you about regulatory issues. We’re both ex-lawyers so I made sure we didn’t burn the whole 25 minutes on regulation. What are the blockers right now? Are governments ready for this? Do they have the frameworks in line to do this right?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4JNrDa"&gt;Yeah, I think at every level of government they’re figuring it out. In the US, I think, NHTSA [National Highway Traffic Safety Administration] has had a voluntary framework primarily. At the state level, every state is a little different, but most of them are motivated to figure out how to do [self-driving], how to enable it, how to enable it safely with varying degrees of concern. And same thing at the city and local level. In Arizona, for example, we had an executive order that we were operating under for those initial years. And then in the legislative session this year, Waymo and the policy team led the charge to get that through the legislature and codified into law. That’s just one state, but there are a lot of examples like that. And I think, there’s a sort of bipartisan recognition that this train is pulling away from the station. The question is how, not whether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tOfnld"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You mentioned NHTSA, &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22555666/nhtsa-autonomous-vehicle-crash-report-data"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;they’ve got a proposed standard for crash reporting out of autonomous vehicles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;. Do you think that goes far enough? Do you think that needs to be standardized? Is that a differentiator for you if everyone’s talking about how safe their cars are?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0jhKFI"&gt;I think that a holistic approach to how companies are able to establish their safety case would be ideal. And I say that because all of our technology’s going to be different. To some degree, if you put a multiplier and you say you have to report how you are assessing safety within your technology and make it available to the public — that’s what we’ve done. Last October, we issued information about the crashes that we’ve had in Phoenix. The reason we did that is we wanted to build not only confidence, but also show that our technology performs better than humans under those same scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iMz4tC"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cars and tech are pretty male-dominated fields. You now run one of the leading self-driving car companies. You’re trying to change regulations to enable your business to succeed. How has this been for you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eVJRx2"&gt;It’s been the ride of a lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fp6rXc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’re done. Good night, everybody. I tried my best.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pMZe2m"&gt;Sorry, I just couldn’t help myself. No two days are the same. It’s really, really creative problem-solving, which is something I love. It’s a fantastic team of people who want to make a difference in the world and so it’s a great way to spend the days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2xSX4K"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For you personally, you think the space is opening up to be more inclusive?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FwiTqs"&gt;I think we have work to do, and we’re focused on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4zXEYp"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Very cool. Alright, let’s see if we have any questions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="51DzAt"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hi, Charlene Chang from Vox Media. You’re in Phoenix and San Francisco, are there other markets you guys are looking to test in and are you looking to test different terrains, climates, things like that?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3JASU0"&gt;Yeah, we have tested other places. So we’ve tested, like I said, some snow in Detroit, as well as thunderstorms in Miami, but we haven’t launched an actual service that riders would be able to use in any of those jurisdictions yet. And we haven’t made any public announcements about what’s coming next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3SJgXt"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let me follow up on that. Do you think you can run this thing in Denver in the snow? Have you tested that stuff such that you’re confident you can do it when it’s time?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pi9REt"&gt;No, it’s early days for that. It’s early days; it’s a vehicle platform question also. That’s why you don’t see us putting riders in the cars in those jurisdictions yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7aqfHr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Okay. Thank you very much. It was delightful talking to you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0iOIfw"&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="xodfve"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Decoder with Nilay Patel","description":"A podcast from The Verge about big ideas and other problems.","label":"Subscribe now!","url":"https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/decoder-with-nilay-patel/id1011668648"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22708676/waymo-tekedra-mawakana-self-driving-interview"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22708676/waymo-tekedra-mawakana-self-driving-interview</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nilay Patel</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
