<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2022-01-20T11:32:37-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-20T11:32:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-20T11:32:37-05:00</updated>
    <title>Messenger Kids’ new internet safety games are mostly teaching kids how to use Messenger </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="In this photo illustration a Facebook Messenger logo seen displayed on a smartphone and Meta Platforms logo in the background" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VGvwjGQiw3Fqe7lhiTMWh9V-Zas=/0x209:5000x3542/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70412323/1237277727.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Meta Messenger for Kids is adding new games to teach online safety | Photo Illustration by Igor Golovniov/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UaXlZy"&gt;Facebook parent company Meta has launched new activities on its Messenger Kids platform aimed at teaching internet etiquette to children. According to &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2022/01/teaching-internet-safety-on-messenger-kids/"&gt;a blog post&lt;/a&gt; by Erik Michael Weitzman, director of product management at Messenger Kids, the new gamified activities will “help kids learn how to use the internet safely and practice making healthy decisions online.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PmhiMP"&gt;Pledge Planets is based on what Weitzman says are the tenets of the Messenger Kids Pledge: be kind, be respectful, be safe and have fun. The first episode titled “Be Kind” includes two games that will help kids “learn and practice how to act with kindness,” the company says: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="TcbVbq"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rough Reviews:&lt;/strong&gt; Players must help the owner read through the reviews and match the correct online response to each one. This game teaches kids to recognize kind and unkind behavior and become familiar with tools like blocking and reporting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XMA0Bg"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Order Up:&lt;/strong&gt; Players build a sandwich order by selecting the emojis that best respond to the customer’s mood. This game teaches kids how to read people’s emotions online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ts4suXC_nmlxfovM_jpH7aThSKY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23181979/01_Be_Kind_Episode.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Meta&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Messenger Kids introduced two new games to teach online safety and awareness to children&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="TBzEdB"&gt;Weitzman writes that the company developed the pledge and the Pledge Planets activities with guidance from experts in online safety and child development. Meta / Facebook first &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/4/16725494/facebook-messenger-kids-app-launch-ios-iphone-preview"&gt;introduced Messenger Kids in 2017&lt;/a&gt;, a scaled-down version of its Messenger app that links to a parent’s Facebook account. But &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696039/facebook-instagram-kids-app-pause-development-criticism"&gt;last year, Facebook shelved&lt;/a&gt; plans for a planned &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22338911/facebook-instagram-kids-privacy-coppa"&gt;kids’ version&lt;/a&gt; of its Instagram photo-sharing platform after widespread criticism. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iO9Mxq"&gt;Setting aside the question of whether Facebook / Meta / Messenger is qualified to offer guidance on healthy decisions and internet safety, what these two games are &lt;em&gt;really &lt;/em&gt;doing is teaching kids how to use Messenger. Bear with me a second, but the first thing I thought of was (the much more well-intentioned and genuine) Sesame Street, arguably the &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2014/11/17/7228353/sesame-street-changed-world"&gt;first TV show designed to help teach preschoolers&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YiHCJa"&gt;While Sesame Street is rightly lauded for having a positive impact on kids’ learning skills and for its diverse, multicultural cast of characters, many have also noted that the show did a great job teaching kids &lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/education/archive/2015/07/the-1960s-experiment-childrens-tv/398681/"&gt;how to watch television&lt;/a&gt;, keeping them engaged and entertained through play learning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="JKaWqW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Inside Facebook’s struggle to keep young people","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22743744/facebook-teen-usage-decline-frances-haugen-leaks"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="6cIljI"&gt;Meta’s platforms, however, have something of a troubled history when it comes to child safety online; internal documents from whistleblower Frances Haugen suggested Facebook / Meta was aware that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22816730/mosseri-testimony-instagram-senate-hearing-haugen-child-safety-facebook-meta"&gt;Instagram can be “toxic”&lt;/a&gt; for teenage users and that its algorithms could direct kids to content that may encourage self-harm. And a study last May by online child safety advocacy organization Thorn found that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/12/22432863/child-safety-platforms-thorn-report-snap-facebook-youtube-tiktok"&gt;children receive abuse and harassment&lt;/a&gt; on social platforms, including Facebook, Instagram, and Messenger, at much higher rates than previously believed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qIyuMp"&gt;And, recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22743744/facebook-teen-usage-decline-frances-haugen-leaks"&gt;revealed internal documents show&lt;/a&gt; that Meta is hemorrhaging younger users, with one projection finding Meta would lose 45 percent of its teenage users over the next two years. Most kids don’t see Facebook as a platform meant for them, and while Instagram has remained popular with teen users, it too has lost ground in recent years both to bullies on its app and to competitors like TikTok. So Meta teaching a whole new generation how to use one of its products would seem right in line with its need to get younger users and keep them playing along. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kjl310"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22893059/messenger-new-kids-internet-safety-games-facebook-meta"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22893059/messenger-new-kids-internet-safety-games-facebook-meta</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-20T11:08:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-20T11:08:37-05:00</updated>
    <title>UK company behind Tom Cruise space film unveils plans to launch space movie studio</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Fp7gJ1rtxEOeQYwq7O0fZDG4WjM=/385x0:2815x1620/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70412212/01see.5.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An animation of the SEE-1 module attached to Axiom’s space station on the ISS.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Axiom/S.E.E.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1bisFN"&gt;On Thursday, a UK-based company that claims to be producing Tom Cruise’s upcoming film in space said it plans to attach the first-ever space movie studio and sports arena to the International Space Station as early as 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BXqrHf"&gt;Called Space Entertainment Enterprise, or S.E.E., the company also announced it is working with commercial space station builder Axiom Space, which has its own partnership with NASA to build and attach an experimental space station to the ISS. That station is called Axiom Station, and Axiom hopes to launch its first module, called Axiom Hub 1, to the ISS by 2024. The company will then build out the space station before eventually separating it from the ISS in 2028 and making it a free-flying vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="P0zp75"&gt;&lt;q&gt;S.E.E. plans to attach its own module to the new growing space station in December of 2024&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3j3cqm"&gt;But while Axiom Station is attached to the ISS, S.E.E. plans to attach its own module to the growing space station in December of 2024. Dubbed SEE-1, the module will be available to individuals who want to film or live stream content in space, “including ﬁlms, television, music, and sports events,” according to a press release announcing the news. Animated videos and images of SEE-1 &lt;a href="https://www.seespacearena.com/"&gt;on the company’s website&lt;/a&gt; show the module as a giant white sphere, though there were no available designs of what the interior will look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lRZ6mW"&gt;Though the module will belong to S.E.E., it is being built by Axiom Space. According to the S.E.E. press release, it will be an inflatable module that will stretch up to 6 meters, or nearly 20 feet, in diameter. S.E.E. says that it will allow third parties to also use the studio for their own projects. No costs or estimated budgets were provided for the project, nor did S.E.E. detail how much it would charge others to use the studio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mxwtwK"&gt;“Adding a dedicated entertainment venue to Axiom Station’s commercial capabilities in the form of SEE-1 will expand the station’s utility as a platform for a global user base and highlight the range of opportunities the new space economy offers,” Michael Suffredini, Axiom’s CEO, said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="dwTIuA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;S.E.E. also revealed itself to be the production company behind Tom Cruise’s mystery space movie&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4nYbQU"&gt;With today’s announcement, S.E.E. also revealed itself to be the production company behind Tom Cruise’s mystery space movie. In 2020, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/5/21248460/nasa-tom-cruise-movie-international-space-station"&gt;NASA announced that it was working with the famous actor&lt;/a&gt; to potentially send him to the International Space Station to film a project. The actor’s ride to space is reportedly SpaceX’s Crew Dragon capsule, which is used to ferry NASA astronauts to and from the ISS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ba0xCu"&gt;Later, NASA confirmed in a podcast that &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/06/everything-we-know-and-dont-about-tom-cruises-plans-to-film-a-movie-in-space/"&gt;Axiom was going to be involved in getting Tom Cruise to orbit&lt;/a&gt;. While Axiom builds space stations, it has also contracted with NASA and SpaceX to buy rides on SpaceX’s Crew Dragon to send private individuals to the ISS. Axiom’s first private astronaut mission on a Crew Dragon, called Axiom-1, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22785888/axiom-space-ax-1-science-experiments-spacex-crew-dragon-iss"&gt;is scheduled to take flight in March&lt;/a&gt;. However, there’s no set date or confirmation for Tom Cruise’s flight. As for what Cruise plans to film up in the cosmos, all that’s been reported so far is that director Doug Liman is involved and that the film will not be a &lt;em&gt;Mission: Impossible&lt;/em&gt; movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iYAFG4"&gt;S.E.E. was co-founded by producers Elena and Dmitry Lesnevsky. Their company boasts an impressive list of consultants of former Viacom and HBO executives. The company says it’s currently looking for investors on the Tom Cruise space project, which &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/video/tom-cruise-movie-shot-in-space-budget-deadlinenow/"&gt;Deadline reported in 2020&lt;/a&gt; would have a budget of at least $200 million. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wakHeD"&gt;However, it’s possible the budget could be even higher, given how much going to space costs. Just one seat on SpaceX’s Crew Dragon is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/26/22250327/space-tourists-axiom-private-crew-iss-price"&gt;thought to run around $55 million&lt;/a&gt;, plus &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/7/18656280/nasa-space-station-private-astronauts-commercial-business"&gt;NASA charges additional fees for private astronauts using the space station’s facilities&lt;/a&gt; while in orbit. S.E.E. says it plans to conduct a fundraising round soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nWEhSX"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22893066/see-1-tom-cruise-space-movie-studio-axiom-iss-spacex"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22893066/see-1-tom-cruise-space-movie-studio-axiom-iss-spacex</id>
    <author>
      <name>Loren Grush</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-20T10:52:41-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-20T10:52:41-05:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix’s Chicken Run sequel will be a three-piece family deal</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GZq47WGR9OoxZ6B6ru_jM1-cS-A=/500x0:5900x3600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70412098/CR2_PR_Still_Egg_Leg_16_9.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Aardman / NETFLIX&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="m4qkyv"&gt;After years of &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/animation-cartoons/2020/6/23/21300251/chicken-run-2-sequel-netflix-story-plot-details"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chicken Run&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;fans wondering whether the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/8/18/12500814/laika-studios-behind-the-scenes-kubo-and-the-two-strings-video"&gt;stop-motion&lt;/a&gt; classic would ever be back for a sequel, Netflix finally answered last summer with a resounding “yes,” but was tight-lipped about key details like who all might be coming back to reprise their roles and &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2020/film/news/mel-gibson-controversies-career-1234696080/"&gt;who might not&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dmxsON"&gt;Though we’re still a ways out from director Sam Fell’s &lt;em&gt;Chicken Run: Dawn of the Nugget’&lt;/em&gt; premiere, Netflix has just shared a cache of new information about the sequel along with our first look (sort of) at the movie’s central hero. Set some time after the first film, &lt;em&gt;Dawn of the Nugget &lt;/em&gt;finds Ginger (Thandiwe Newton) and Rocky (Zachary Levi) settling into new lives on an idyllic island completely devoid of humans where they feel safe enough to finally start a family. Though the chickens are delighted by the birth of the daughter Molly (Bella Ramsey), the young chick’s wanderlust soon puts her at odds with her parents after her curiosity about the mainland is piqued by rumors about the dangerous things that happen there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xch0Vr"&gt;Though Newton, Ramsey, and Levi are all newcomers to the &lt;em&gt;Chicken Run &lt;/em&gt;franchise, they’ll be joined by Jane Horrocks, Imelda Staunton, and Lynn Ferguson, who voiced the chickens Babs, Hunty, and Mac, respectively, in the first film. Rounding out the cast are Josie Sedgwick-Davies as Edie, David Bradley as Fowler, Romesh Ranganathan as Nick, Daniel Mays as Fletcher, and Nick Mohammed as Dr. Fry.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oSB4rUMPBXjiK_RFY9e3k-0Ojd0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23182041/Screen_Shot_2022_01_20_at_10.31.31_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Netflix&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Nick park, creator and director of Wallace &amp;amp; Gromit.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="52Osfc"&gt;Along with the &lt;em&gt;Chicken Run &lt;/em&gt;news&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;Netflix also announced that it’s moving forward with another &lt;em&gt;Wallace &amp;amp; Gromit &lt;/em&gt;feature co-directed by Wal&lt;em&gt;lace &amp;amp; Gromit &lt;/em&gt;creator Nick Park and Merlin Crossingham. A press release about the currently unnamed &lt;em&gt;Wallace &amp;amp; Gromit &lt;/em&gt;movie describes its story as focusing on what happens when Wallace’s latest invention — a “smart gnome” — seems to gain sentience and begin wreaking havoc upon its creator’s and Gromit’s quiet lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BR5QJO"&gt;While there are currently no details on when to expect the next &lt;em&gt;Wallace &amp;amp; Gromit &lt;/em&gt;feature, &lt;em&gt;Chicken Run: Dawn of the Nugget &lt;/em&gt;is slated to hit Netflix in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22893091/netflix-chicken-run-sequel-dawn-of-the-nuggets"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22893091/netflix-chicken-run-sequel-dawn-of-the-nuggets</id>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Pulliam-Moore</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-20T10:33:48-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-20T10:33:48-05:00</updated>
    <title>Many of the best Xbox backward-compatible games are discounted</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Red Dead Redemption" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qlLdwo-p9OfvLJERwvdwaZEEuLk=/141x0:1019x585/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70412023/gallery-1458823402-red-dead-redemption-2-does-it-star-john-marston-s-son-out-for-revenge-red-dead-redempti-424515.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Y2sYA8"&gt;Microsoft is hosting steep discounts on backward-compatible digital games from the original Xbox and Xbox 360 eras, as it does occasionally. If you agree with the opinion that being able to play older games on the Series X or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Xbox-S/dp/B08G9J44ZN/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Series S&lt;/a&gt; (or even the Xbox One) is one of their most appealing features, you’ll probably find at least one game that you’ll want to pick up during this sale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m1JVxX"&gt;If you haven’t explored the depths of the Xbox backward-compatible game catalog before, it can be daunting. And in case you don’t really have an idea of what might interest you, we’ve pulled a smattering of deals out of the sale to highlight. Notably, these games currently are not available through Game Pass.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/N01qPZqVEGyKScJURIdsChCaC5o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22528183/new_timesplitters_game_580x334.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Free Radical Design&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;TimeSplitters 2 got amazing cover art outside of the US.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XoABVa"&gt;Into first-person shooters? Check out the &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=vergexboxBCdeals012022&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-us%2Fgames%2Fstore%2Ftimesplitters-2%2F9NJBX726M8J9" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;TimeSplitters 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($2.49) and &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=vergexboxBCdeals012022&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-us%2Fgames%2Fstore%2Ftimesplitters-future-perfect%2F9N51S9QZMSB6" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;TimeSplitters Future Perfect&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($2.49), two games made by Free Radical Design that have a similar feel (in terms of gameplay and mission objectives) to &lt;em&gt;Goldeneye &lt;/em&gt;on the N64, but they’re a lot weirder. They’re charming in their oddity, in the way that a lot of early 2000s stuff was, and if you have some friends around for local multiplayer, it didn’t get much better than what this game offered back in 2002.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L3GJoa"&gt;You can catch up on the &lt;em&gt;Red Dead&lt;/em&gt; franchise with &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=vergexboxBCdeals012022&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-us%2Fgames%2Fstore%2Fred-dead-revolver%2F9NP7Q2SSS81W" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Red Dead Revolver&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for the original Xbox ($8.99), which is essentially an arcade game compared to its two open-world sequels. Speaking of its sequels, you can snag &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=vergexboxBCdeals012022&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-us%2Fgames%2Fstore%2Fred-dead-redemption%2FBWKLFHWT7DHC" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Red Dead Redemption&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for the Xbox 360 for $9.89 — one of the best open-world games made to date (it’s even better than &lt;em&gt;Red Dead Redemption 2&lt;/em&gt; — fight me).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/45CT5_ld0BnJ7ua3rl4OzqurQ5U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23181899/midnightclub_losangeles.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A still taken from Midnight Club: Los Angeles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="nahyf3"&gt;Depending on your age, there’s a slight possibility that you might not know that Rockstar Games used to make surprisingly good racing games, among other things. &lt;em&gt;Midnight Club&lt;/em&gt; competed with the likes of the &lt;em&gt;Fast and Furious&lt;/em&gt;-inspired &lt;em&gt;Need for Speed: Underground&lt;/em&gt;, focusing solely on street racing. While &lt;em&gt;Midnight Club 3: DUB Edition&lt;/em&gt; is usually regarded as the best in the series, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=vergexboxBCdeals012022&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-us%2Fgames%2Fstore%2Fmidnight-club-los-angeles-complete%2FBV6WLXGS887C" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Midnight Club: Los Angeles&lt;/em&gt; ($10.04) certainly isn’t bad&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bcgZce"&gt;&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=vergexboxBCdeals012022&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-us%2Fgames%2Fstore%2Frockstar-table-tennis%2FBVZ4H08BMQ3H" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rockstar Games Presents: Table Tennis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, one of the best graphical showcases for the Xbox 360 in the early days of the console, still holds up as a great sports game for $5.99. &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=vergexboxBCdeals012022&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-us%2Fgames%2Fstore%2Fbully-scholarship-edition%2FC3WX803ZX8SD" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bully: Scholarship Edition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, another well-regarded Rockstar Games title that hasn’t seen a follow-up, is discounted to $5.99. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o0ejg5"&gt;Sega released a bevy of interesting games as Xbox exclusives following the failure of its Dreamcast console that have become, at the very least, cult classics, including &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=vergexboxBCdeals012022&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-us%2Fgames%2Fstore%2Fpanzer-dragoon-orta%2FC3LNP2Q4422J" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Panzer Dragoon Orta&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($4.99) and &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=vergexboxBCdeals012022&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-us%2Fgames%2Fstore%2Fgunvalkyrie%2F9MZ08F46GC5Z" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gunvalkyrie&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;($5.99). &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Ninja Gaiden Black" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9TLOd7H--AMbIRgxvT-UZmMkH8c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22397952/8bc003df_2fc2_4cd1_8f1f_ffa84b3c7573.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An Xbox easter egg hidden in Ninja Gaiden Black.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7Fw7XG"&gt;This one’s out of Sega’s realm, but I highly recommend picking up &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=vergexboxBCdeals012022&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-us%2Fgames%2Fstore%2Fninja-gaiden-black%2Fc17kks83s9gs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ninja Gaiden Black&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for $9.99. Originally released for the Xbox, its responsive, satisfying gameplay holds up well to today’s standards, and compared to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/25/22350928/ninja-gaiden-master-collection-koei-tecmo-black-game-preservation-data-loss"&gt;recent &lt;em&gt;Ninja Gaiden&lt;/em&gt; trilogy released in 2021&lt;/a&gt;, this is the definitive version of the &lt;em&gt;Ninja Gaiden&lt;/em&gt; remake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jZMvDU"&gt;I have praise for a lot more games, but I, unfortunately, can’t wax nostalgic about this all day. Here are some others that I’d recommend checking out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="J4nUMj"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=vergexboxBCdeals012022&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-us%2Fgames%2Fstore%2Fprey%2FBVPGZMMDDZ0M" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;(2006) is $3.99&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hUiH92"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=vergexboxBCdeals012022&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-us%2Fgames%2Fstore%2Fthe-darkness%2FC035L0NS3SQN" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Darkness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (the first-person shooter released by Starbreeze Studios following its ambitious &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=vergexboxBCdeals012022&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fmarketplace.xbox.com%2Fen-US%2FProduct%2FAssault-on-Dark-Athena%2F66acd000-77fe-1000-9115-d802494707ee%23" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Chronicles of Riddick: Escape from Butcher Bay&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) is $3.99&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PcbaES"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=vergexboxBCdeals012022&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-us%2Fgames%2Fstore%2Fresident-evil-code-veronica-x%2FBQW8J8XM62JW" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Resident Evil Code: Veronica X HD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is $3.99&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8JZQzN"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=vergexboxBCdeals012022&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-us%2Fgames%2Fstore%2Fburnout-revenge%2FBZ6XWGQZK45H" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Burnout Revenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the finest car-smashing game in the &lt;em&gt;Burnout &lt;/em&gt;franchise behind &lt;em&gt;Paradise&lt;/em&gt;, is $4.99&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yirftf"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=vergexboxBCdeals012022&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-us%2Fgames%2Fstore%2Fasuras-wrath%2FBPN103KDBX2H" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Asura’s Wrath&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a weird but nevertheless impressive button-mashing QTE action game from Capcom, is $3.99.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="iNukCd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2022/1/20/22892969/xbox-games-360-original-backward-compatible-digital-sale-deal-microsoft"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2022/1/20/22892969/xbox-games-360-original-backward-compatible-digital-sale-deal-microsoft</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-20T10:27:53-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-20T10:27:53-05:00</updated>
    <title>Save $250 on iRobot’s poop-avoiding Roomba j7 Plus vacuum</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7Cq_tpOpSomBEq1ewcYpYx3Z1tI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70411998/vtuohy_211029_4963_0014.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;iRobot’s Roomba j7 Plus and its auto-empty base.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Jennifer Pattison Tuohy / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jwLVDK"&gt;Let’s get down to the dirty business of things and keep it professional. Here’s a deal on a robot vacuum that detects doo-doo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XuIaiE"&gt;The iRobot Roomba j7 Plus is one of the newest models from the most recognizable brand in the robot vacuum world. It’s currently on sale for $599 ($250 off) at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cgsdlcHrsIu" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/iRobot-Roomba-Self-Emptying-Robot-Vacuum/dp/B094NYHTMF?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://shareasale.com/r.cfm?b=1264455&amp;amp;u=1225169&amp;amp;m=83747&amp;amp;urllink=www%2Ewellbots%2Ecom%2Fproducts%2Firobot%2Droomba%2Dj7%2Dself%2Demptying%2Drobot%2Dvacuum&amp;amp;afftrack=vergedailydeals012022" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Wellbots&lt;/a&gt;. This one has the kinds of fancy features you may come to expect from a fairly expensive robo-vac, like room mapping with keep-out zones, spot cleaning, and automatic bin-emptying. It also has an ace up its sleeve: the ability to detect pet waste and (ideally) not run over it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zXJnW8"&gt;Our resident smart home expert and reviewer, Jennifer Pattison Tuohy, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22880352/irobot-roomba-j7-plus-samsung-jet-bot-ai-plus-robot-vacuum-review-comparison-test" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;recently tested the Roomba J7 Plus against the Samsung Jet Bot AI Plus&lt;/a&gt;, and the Roomba scored higher with its better price-to-performance value compared to the pricier Samsung model. Though it did run over the fake poop she laid out for it one time out of the dozen tests she ran — so just like with actual pets, accidents happen. Though if it does make a smeary mess of fecal matter on your floor in the first year of ownership, then iRobot will replace the vacuum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="J2hHUB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10986398"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8274Xa"&gt;All right now, let’s not be party-poopers for this entire post. The JBL Charge 5 is a Bluetooth speaker that gets loud, can go anywhere, and can keep your phone juiced up while you’re vibing to tunes. &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-8836598-13527013?sid=vergedailydeals012022&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Felectronics.woot.com%2Foffers%2Fjbl-charge-5-bluetooth-speaker-7" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Woot has it for $149.99&lt;/a&gt; in black, teal, red, and green color options. That’s about $30 off the usual new cost, and it’s the best price around right now. We have not tested this exact model yet, but the JBL Charge line has found its way into &lt;em&gt;The Verge’s&lt;/em&gt; list of best Bluetooth speakers in the past. The Charge 5 ups the waterproofing and dustproofing with an IP67 rating, so it is perfect for socially distant outdoor events. You’ll be prepared for the summer beaches already, and it’s only January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PuwcWm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10986441"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DL2VqB"&gt;Keyboards are a very personal thing, and I’m about to get a little personal with a somewhat spicy take: full-size mechanical keyboards from the big accessory brands like Razer and Corsair are usually overpriced for what you get. Since they’re marketed to gamers, these companies know that, generally speaking, they’re often willing to spend extra on extravagant features, like RGB lighting (hey, I’m guilty of it on occasion, too, so I’m also putting myself on blast).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y7doyo"&gt;And yet, here’s a good Logitech mechanical keyboard that seems to be priced &lt;em&gt;just &lt;/em&gt;right for what it offers. &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cgsd3nEFn81" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Its G413 in silver&lt;/a&gt; is just $49.99 ($20 off) at Best Buy. It uses Logitech’s own &lt;a href="https://logitech.cfzu.net/c/482924/499820/8585?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.logitechg.com%2Fen-us%2Finnovation%2Fmechanical-switches.html&amp;amp;subid1=VergeDealsRoundup012022" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Romer-G&lt;/a&gt; tactile mechanical switches. While it lacks RGB lighting, its white key backlighting is more than serviceable, and the subdued look lends it the ability to blend in at an office or just about anywhere. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nBTk6f"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10986471"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="I8ozmS"&gt;Remember when I said let’s not be suckers for superfluous things like colorful lights? Yeah, hold that thought while we get nerdy about some colorful smart lights because Nanoleaf is running a big sale on its &lt;a href="https://press.nanoleaf.me/2022/01/19/saying-goodbye-to-nanoleaf-light-panels/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;original light panels&lt;/a&gt; that are being phased out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AOVl1J"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://us-shop.nanoleaf.me/products/light-panels-smarter-kit-30-panels" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nanoleaf Light Panels Rhythm 30-pack smarter kit is about $260 off&lt;/a&gt;, knocking the price down to $419.99 from its original $679.97. Yes, that’s a &lt;em&gt;lot &lt;/em&gt;of money for lighting, but 30 panels is enough to make some really unique designs on your wall and really light up a small space. Nanoleaf has some other kits of light panels and accessories for &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fnanoleaf.me%2Fen-US%2Fproducts%2F%3Fproduct%3Dlight-panels%26type%3Dall&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2022%2F1%2F20%2F22891218%2Firobot-roomba-j7-plus-vacuum-jbl-charge-5-logitech-keyboard-nanoleaf-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;up to 50 percent off&lt;/a&gt;, and while these models are being discontinued, the company is promising to maintain their current functionality in its app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="g2ZoJ4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10987303"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="QRjVtT"&gt;Some other deals that don’t stink:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="jIy8KN"&gt;Anker’s handy dual-port USB-C 40W 521 Charger is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Anker-Charger-Durable-Compact-Included/dp/B09C5SC9FW?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;15 percent off on Amazon&lt;/a&gt; when you click the on-page coupon, bringing it down to $30.59.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="CnrVW7"&gt;While not its best price, the Sony 75-inch X85J LED 4K UHD TV is &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cgsuEYfhOFN" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$1,299.99 ($300 off) at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. Notably, it supports a native 120Hz refresh rate, a feature you don’t typically see on TVs this big for this low of a price. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="s4xuPt"&gt;Need a microSD card for a Switch, phone or some other device? The SanDisk 400GB Ultra microSDXC is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/SanDisk-128GB-MicroSDXC-Memory-Adapter/dp/B08GYG5SVQ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$43.49 on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, only about $5 away from its all-time lowest price we saw during the holidays. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NAOMBx"&gt;Razer’s Battle Bundle consists of its BlackShark V2 X headset, DeathAdder V2 mouse, and Gigantus V2 M mouse pad, and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cgsuH17omTS" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy has it for $69.99&lt;/a&gt; ($80 off). That’s a nice value if you need both a mouse and headset and prefer wired over wireless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="ucEp0M"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2022/1/20/22891218/irobot-roomba-j7-plus-vacuum-jbl-charge-5-logitech-keyboard-nanoleaf-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2022/1/20/22891218/irobot-roomba-j7-plus-vacuum-jbl-charge-5-logitech-keyboard-nanoleaf-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-20T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-20T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Boost Celero 5G review: budget phone with budget battery life</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Boost’s first 5G phone is cheap but unremarkable&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="ukL1pq"&gt;Boost Mobile, the MVNO owned by the Dish Network as a result of the Sprint / T-Mobile merger, is in a tricky spot. Not only does it need to expand its user base for nationwide 5G service, but it also needs to migrate over a million Boost customers from Sprint’s CDMA 3G network to its 4G / 5G service (operated by T-Mobile and AT&amp;amp;T) soon since &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/23/22741762/tmobile-delays-shutdown-sprint-3g-network-dish-boost"&gt;T-Mobile will be shutting down Sprint’s CDMA network by March 31, 2022&lt;/a&gt;. This means the carrier will need to convince its many customers to upgrade to newer 4G or, more preferably, 5G phones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hJv8Us"&gt;That’s where Dish’s first self-branded phone, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22697318/dish-5g-game-279-boost-mobile-exclusive-5g-phone-prepaid"&gt;$279.99 Celero 5G&lt;/a&gt; (though often discounted to less), comes into play. This Android phone with iPhone-like looks works better than you’d expect and takes decent photos in good lighting conditions. Unfortunately, it has the exact same price as the popular and well-reviewed Samsung Galaxy A32 5G that’s also available at Boost, making the Celero a direct competitor. So how does the Celero 5G stack up?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wloz9j"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10954511"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Celero 5G’s silver back cover" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QDWJHBxlyr5CXKDjc9NhGN0OSh8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23098805/gsin_190404_4933_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Celero 5G’s plastic body actually makes the phone more lightweight and comfortable to hold.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Q51CwH"&gt;Celero 5G Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="MjNajL"&gt;Like T-Mobile’s REVVL V Plus 5G and AT&amp;amp;T’s Radiant, the Celero 5G is made by Wingtech Technology and custom-designed for Boost (when you plug the phone into a computer, the phone is named “WT Celero 5G”). At first glance, it looks like an iPhone clone: it has an all-round silver trim, square camera array, and the unmistakable rims around the camera lenses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7tp0or"&gt;While its matte silver back cover is surprisingly smudge-resistant, its smooth surface makes the phone way too easy to slide off tables and hands — you’ll want to get a case to protect it. For a big phone (it measures 6.56 x 3 x 0.33-inch (166.60 x 76.20 x 8.40mm)), the Celero’s all-plastic body and beveled edges make it comfortable to hold, and it’s not too heavy either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Closeup of the Celero 5G’s power button" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZyCvq8Ct59l-U9QZM33Du8cr8ow=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23098806/gsin_190404_4933_0003_cropped.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The placement of the Celero 5G’s power and fingerprint sensor is too low and recessed for easy access.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A closeup of the bottom of the Celero 5G" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2XTbUN1GuPYJSnR21TiXjH36KR4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23098807/gsin_190404_4933_0004_cropped.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Celero 5G’s 3.5mm audio jack is located at the bottom of the phone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KYi1dO"&gt;The power button and integrated fingerprint sensor on the Celero are too low and too recessed to use easily, however. As a result, it takes an extra second to unlock the phone with the fingerprint sensor — because I’m usually fumbling for the power button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="oqrFrR"&gt;Celero 5G Performance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="4zJeD8"&gt;The Celero 5G’s screen is big but dim: you need to set the screen brightness to around 100 percent to use it comfortably indoors (you’ll be squinting at this screen outdoors). It has a large 6.5-inch LCD display that is only 720p in resolution, which means high-resolution photos and videos won’t look the sharpest here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RGKj1j"&gt;For a sub-$300 phone using the &lt;a href="https://www.notebookcheck.net/Dimensity-700-vs-Dimensity-720_13199_12994.247596.0.html"&gt;“fast mid-range SoC” MediaTek Dimensity 700 processor&lt;/a&gt; and 4GB RAM for support, the Celero 5G can handle basic tasks without any significant lag. I was able to cycle between my many opened tabs and apps quickly and could even play a YouTube video while I read an article. Like the Samsung A32, the Celero comes with just 64GB of internal storage, but the Celero has a microSD card slot that can support up to a 2TB card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="g2qLIG"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Celero 5G’s display is dim and low-resolution&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0QbKaI"&gt;I played a round of &lt;em&gt;Pokemon Unite,&lt;/em&gt; and the Celero 5G handled the game like a champ. The responsive touchscreen made it easy to move my Charmander around the battlefield, even as the attack moves became more complicated. When I plugged in my wired headphones into its bottom-facing audio jack, I could hear a vocal track on the game’s theme music that I’d previously missed. Its bottom-firing mono-speaker is passable: it managed to play the demanding “Dance at the Gym: Mambo” from the 2021 &lt;em&gt;West Side Story&lt;/em&gt; soundtrack with clarity, if not a bit too loudly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cY4NzL"&gt;Although I appreciate that this phone is running a mostly unmodified version of Android 11, the Celero is unfortunately full of bloatware. In addition to the usual suspects like a folder worth of Amazon apps, there are two folders called “Lifestyle” and “Games’’ that contain a bunch of app shortcuts that the phone will download if you click on the “Add” button. There is even an App Spotlight app that shows you 24 app shortcuts the carrier is encouraging you to download (including &lt;em&gt;The Epoch Times&lt;/em&gt;). To make matters worse, every time you wake or turn on your phone, you will see three apps doing some sort of configuration in the background, but it’s not clear how to disable those processes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IWoJmE"&gt;As Dish’s first self-branded phone, it’s hard to know if and when the Celero will receive any OS or security updates to extend its lifespan. This is a far cry from more established brands like Samsung, which have a four-year software commitment on the A32.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R3xpRV"&gt;The battery life on the Celero 5G is not as long as its 4,000mAh battery would imply. Although I managed to get about 8 hours and 15 minutes of screen time before I had to recharge it, that was with very moderate use. I was only on Wi-Fi to listen to a couple of podcasts, post on Twitter, check email, and chat with family on Google Hangouts. If you use mostly 4G or 5G on this phone, you’ll probably need to keep the charger or a portable battery close by because the Celero might not last a full day of heavy use. The included 15W charger is not exactly a fast charger either: it took over two hours to fully recharge the battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="A4UaIl"&gt;Celero 5G Camera&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Closeup of the Celero 5G’s rear cameras" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nSiJcKjP46v0jttLhpuJYDH5__o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23098808/gsin_190404_4933_0005_cropped.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Celero 5G’s cameras are pretty basic and not suitable for night or sports photography.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="h3Zgcp"&gt;The Celero 5G’s cameras are the standard fare for its class: it has a 16-megapixel rear camera, a 5-megapixel ultrawide, a 2-megapixel depth sensor, and an 8-megapixel front-facing camera for selfies. With good lighting and the right framing, you should be able to get some good photos with good details to share online. However, I wouldn’t use this phone to take action or night photography because these cameras just aren’t capable enough for more challenging situations. The front camera, on the other hand, can capture relatively bright selfies even in dim lighting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zn42Wa"&gt;Like other budget phones, the Celero’s ultrawide photos tend to skew yellow, especially when you compare a photo taken with the main camera of the same scene. Whether I take outdoor holiday decoration photos or indoors inside a diner, the ultrawide camera has a knack for inexplicably boosting the yellow channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="77JkcT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10954550"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bITS9Q"&gt;Worst of all, the Celero’s camera app is annoying to use. It can take an extra second to switch between the main and the ultrawide cameras or different modes, which might be the difference between you getting or missing the shot. It also takes about two seconds to process a live focus shot, so you’ll need a steady hand and patience when using this mode. When I tried to take a photo that happened to have a QR code, the app kept asking me if I wanted to visit that website, even after I repeatedly tapped “No.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="EPlgm0"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Celero 5G’s silver back cover" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4M0ExMH_y5UcI_d8jbdBZvWTxeY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23098811/gsin_190404_4933_0011.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Celero 5G has tough competition from budget 5G phones from Samsung, Motorola and OnePlus.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cdKDPA"&gt;As much as I enjoyed the $279.99 Celero 5G for its iPhone-like looks and capable performance, I have a hard time recommending it over the same-priced Samsung Galaxy A32 5G. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jzivR5"&gt;For the same money, the Samsung Galaxy A32 5G offers a bigger battery at 5,000mAh, a better 48-megapixel main camera, C-band 5G compatibility, and four years of software support from Samsung. With the Celero, it’s hard to know if it’ll get software support like security updates, from whom and for how long, not to mention its smaller battery and less powerful cameras. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zYk2yt"&gt;Boost also offers the $249.99 Motorola Moto G Stylus 5G, which is $30 cheaper than the Celero, comes with double the internal storage at 128GB, and also features a 48-megapixel camera. The best-in-class OnePlus Nord N200 5G is even cheaper at $239, and it includes a 1080p display with a 90Hz refresh rate, though it’s not clear if this unlocked phone will be compatible on Boost’s network. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="cq9KHM"&gt;I wish Boost would give the Celero 5G a permanent price cut, like its current promotional price of $139.99 or lower. This would make it a whole lot easier to recommend the Celero despite its shortcomings — shorter battery life, more bloatware, untested brand. But without that significant discount, the Celero 5G is not your best bet at Boost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xY6oTC"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by: Gloria Sin / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="62NXyZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10987297"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22837805/celero-5g-review-phone"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22837805/celero-5g-review-phone</id>
    <author>
      <name>Gloria Sin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-20T09:44:35-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-20T09:44:35-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to get your money back for at-home COVID test kits</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GULD0K745HlgEtR2XE-g9bohGOI=/50x0:406x237/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70411785/home_test_hero.2099b1df64ebd24bb68a.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: USPS&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;div id="2nCrDr"&gt;
&lt;script type="application/ld+json"&gt;
{
 "@context": "https://schema.org",
 "@type": "HowTo",
 "name": "How to get your money back for at-home COVID test kits",
 "description": "However, if you’ve got private insurance through an employer or a group, you do have an alternative: you can get a reimbursement for — or pick up free at approved retailers — up to eight FDA-authorized at-home COVID tests per person per month.",
 "step": [
  {
   "@type": "HowToSection",
   "position": "1",
   "name": "How do you take advantage of this? ",
   "itemListElement": [
    {
     "@type": "HowToStep",
     "position": "1",
     "itemListElement": [
      {
       "@type": "HowToDirection",
       "position": "1",
       "text": "Currently, the best way to find out how to get reimbursed for tests you have purchased is to log on to your health insurance site."
      },
      {
       "@type": "HowToTip",
       "position": "2",
       "text": "I checked about six insurance sites, and currently, most are offering claim forms that you can fill out and submit with proof of purchase."
      }
     ]
    }
   ]
  },
  {
   "@type": "HowToSection",
   "position": "2",
   "name": "Some other things to be aware of:",
   "itemListElement": [
    {
     "@type": "HowToStep",
     "position": "1",
     "itemListElement": [
      {
       "@type": "HowToDirection",
       "position": "1",
       "text": "You will have to provide proof of purchase along with your claim form, so if you make the purchase at a local store, don’t lose that receipt.\n"
      }
     ]
    },
    {
     "@type": "HowToStep",
     "position": "2",
     "itemListElement": [
      {
       "@type": "HowToDirection",
       "position": "1",
       "text": "Your insurance company may have a list of approved kits and / or approved retailers that it will accept claims for. "
      },
      {
       "@type": "HowToTip",
       "position": "2",
       "text": "As a result, it’s a good idea to check your insurer’s site before buying."
      }
     ]
    },
    {
     "@type": "HowToStep",
     "position": "3",
     "itemListElement": [
      {
       "@type": "HowToDirection",
       "position": "1",
       "text": "You can buy an FDA-approved kit outside of your insurer’s approved retailer network; your insurance company is required to reimburse those purchases at a rate of $12 per test."
      }
     ]
    },
    {
     "@type": "HowToStep",
     "position": "4",
     "itemListElement": [
      {
       "@type": "HowToDirection",
       "position": "1",
       "text": "If you ordered a COVID test kit online before January 15th but didn’t receive it until after, you may still be covered. Either check with your insurer, or submit the form with proof of purchase and delivery, and hope for the best."
      }
     ]
    },
    {
     "@type": "HowToStep",
     "position": "5",
     "itemListElement": [
      {
       "@type": "HowToDirection",
       "position": "1",
       "text": "The requirement covers eight tests per person — not eight kits. So if your kit contains two or more tests (and many do), then keep that in mind when submitting your claim.\n"
      }
     ]
    }
   ]
  }
 ]
}
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ydgALv"&gt;While it’s nice that the government will be sending us &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889571/free-covid-19-tests-usps-website"&gt;four free at-home rapid COVID test kits a month&lt;/a&gt;, that’s not going to be enough for many households. However, if you’ve got private insurance through an employer or a group, you do have an alternative: you can get a reimbursement for — or pick up free at approved retailers — &lt;a href="https://www.cms.gov/how-to-get-your-at-home-OTC-COVID-19-test-for-free"&gt;up to eight FDA-authorized at-home COVID tests per person per month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ct2JeT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to order free rapid COVID tests from the US government","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22889745/rapid-covid-tests-free-website-how-to"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="XhHXmX"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2022/01/10/biden-harris-administration-requires-insurance-companies-group-health-plans-to-cover-cost-at-home-covid-19-tests-increasing-access-free-tests.html"&gt;Announced back in January&lt;/a&gt;, the new rules state that private health insurers are required to cover these tests without needing approval from a doctor or other medical provider. (If you need more kits, you can also get them covered if it is ordered by a medical provider.) This requirement went into effect on January 15th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xNVdGk"&gt;How do you take advantage of this? That depends on your specific health insurer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t3ozFB"&gt;Currently, the best way to find out how to get reimbursed for tests you have purchased is to log on to your health insurance site. I checked about six insurance sites, and currently, most are offering claim forms that you can fill out and submit with proof of purchase. Eventually, according to the announcement, we should be able to pick up kits at approved pharmacies and stores; however, it’s early days yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DvVEp9"&gt;Some other things to be aware of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="vQtkWn"&gt;You will have to provide proof of purchase along with your claim form, so if you make the purchase at a local store, don’t lose that receipt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BqFMmH"&gt;Your insurance company may have a list of approved kits and / or approved retailers that it will accept claims for. As a result, it’s a good idea to check your insurer’s site before buying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="s8Fhd5"&gt;You &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; buy an FDA-approved kit outside of your insurer’s approved retailer network; your insurance company is required to reimburse those purchases at a rate of $12 per test.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WiPybb"&gt;If you ordered a COVID test kit online before January 15th but didn’t receive it until after, you may still be covered. Either check with your insurer, or submit the form with proof of purchase and delivery, and hope for the best.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="L9pjb7"&gt;The requirement covers eight tests per person — not eight kits. So if your kit contains two or more tests (and many do), then keep that in mind when submitting your claim.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="P862Xd"&gt;Unfortunately, this leaves Medicare and Medicaid health insurance recipients — and those who don’t have insurance — pretty much out in the cold. The government is now providing four free test kits per month per household if you sign up for them, but that isn’t going to go very far if you have more than a couple of people in your household and a need to test frequently. According to the Centers for Medicare and Medicare Services, “State Medicaid and CHIP programs are required to cover FDA-authorized at-home COVID-19 tests,” but the rules can vary by state, and you’ll have to contact your local office for more info. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5UaoEz"&gt;Finally, according to &lt;a href="https://www.hrsa.gov/coronavirus/testing-supplies"&gt;the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA&lt;/a&gt;), HRSA- and Medicare-supported health clinics are being supplied with at-home test kits to distribute; again, you will need to check with your local clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="edOJ6t"&gt;You can find more information for reimbursements from the &lt;a href="https://www.cms.gov/how-to-get-your-at-home-OTC-COVID-19-test-for-free"&gt;Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services&lt;/a&gt; site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sfTFkf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 20th, 11:30AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Information added to clarify the availability of test kits for participants in Medicaid and CHIP programs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="07Niyz"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22891974/covid-test-kits-purchase-reimbursement-insurance"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22891974/covid-test-kits-purchase-reimbursement-insurance</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-20T09:08:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-20T09:08:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>Craig of the Creek’s getting a spinoff, a new movie, and a fifth season</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4xUjQsNR2JVV8YK3gIm9qIcw4Us=/229x0:1545x877/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70411687/Craig_of_the_Creek_Key_Art.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Cartoon Network&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IRsAMT"&gt;Though the newest season of Cartoon Network’s &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/craig-of-the-creeks-world-of-summertime-wonder-is-getti-1834568544"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Craig of the Creek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;only just picked back up earlier this week, the network’s already decided that it wants to see much, much more of Craig, the rest of the Johnson family, and the other Creek Kids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SeKSKL"&gt;In a move that’s sure to calm fans who can never be certain if and when these shows are coming back, Cartoon Network has just announced that &lt;em&gt;Craig of the Creek &lt;/em&gt;has been renewed for a fifth season that will continue to follow the adventures of Craig (Philip Solomon), Kelsey (Noël Wells), and J.P. (H. Michael Croner) as they discover new depths of the creek they call a second home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fO0iVo"&gt;With a whole new half of the Creek suddenly becoming accessible to Craig and the gang in the show’s last season, &lt;em&gt;Craig of the Creek&lt;/em&gt;’s been hinting at the introduction of even more characters with fresh ideas about how best to imagine the shared space as something more than the woods around their neighborhood. Though &lt;em&gt;Craig of the Creek&lt;/em&gt;’s core cast of characters is going to have a hand in how everyone’s understanding of the creek &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/craig-of-the-creek-turned-pokemon-into-an-important-lif-1837669116"&gt;continues to evolve&lt;/a&gt;, the larger &lt;em&gt;Craig of the Creek &lt;/em&gt;franchise is also about to go through a growth spurt thanks to a new spinoff series and origin film.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4S6vDr6uafqFODd-eMV3R7imbxY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23180673/Jessica_s_Big_Little_World_Key_Art.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Cartoon Network&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Key art for Jessica’s Little Big World.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="EUVEoE"&gt;With Craig’s younger sister Jessica (Lucia Cunningham) finally being old enough to go to preschool, she’s also ready to become the star of &lt;em&gt;Jessica’s Little Big World&lt;/em&gt;, her own series co-created and executive produced by Matt Burnett, Ben Levin, and Tiffany Ford that explores the world from Jessica’s unique perspective. Promotional art for &lt;em&gt;Jessica’s Little Big World &lt;/em&gt;appears to depict Jessica alongside a talking version of her beloved stuffed animal, Small Uncle, as well as a curiously different (read: older, and more together) version of the Creek Kid Wren, alluding to how many things about the series are depicted as Jessica sees them rather than as they actually are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AIu6HD"&gt;In addition to &lt;em&gt;Jessica’s Little Big World&lt;/em&gt;, Cartoon Network also announced that &lt;em&gt;Craig of The Creek: The Movie&lt;/em&gt;, an animated feature detailing Craig’s earliest days as the new kid in the neighborhood, has been greenlit for production and is slated to premiere on both Cartoon Network proper and HBO Max. While there’s currently no word on when &lt;em&gt;Jessica’s Little Big World &lt;/em&gt;will debut, both &lt;em&gt;Craig of the Creek: The Movie &lt;/em&gt;and the show’s fifth season are slated to premiere sometime in 2023. &lt;em&gt;Craig of the Creek&lt;/em&gt;’s current season is now airing on Cartoon Network ahead of the whole season coming on HBO Max on February 17th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22892102/craig-of-the-creek-season-5-the-movie"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22892102/craig-of-the-creek-season-5-the-movie</id>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Pulliam-Moore</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-20T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-20T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Mercedes-Benz acquires stake in lidar maker Luminar, will use its sensors for future autonomous vehicles</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="EMBARGO: June 15, 2021, 10:30am ET" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W4d0e8VTfWkLOkvXWNOvDrG_tic=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70411654/VRG05AH_210614_4634_006.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;EMBARGO: June 15, 2021, 10:30am ET | Photo by Andrew J. Hawkins / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wYNLpV"&gt;Mercedes-Benz announced it will integrate Luminar’s lidar sensors into future production vehicles to enable autonomous driving capabilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GBpjRh"&gt;The German automaker is also taking an equity stake in the Orlando, Florida-based company, acquiring a total of 1.5 million shares. Based on Luminar’s share price of $13.45 at market close January 19th, Mercedes-Benz is purchasing approximately $20.2 million worth of shares, or less than 1 percent of the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9TixBq"&gt;Lidar, a key ingredient in autonomous driving, is a laser sensor that uses near-infrared light to detect the shapes of objects. This helps autonomous vehicles “see” other objects on the road, like cars, pedestrians, and cyclists, all without the help of GPS or a network connection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="mOXjOT"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Mercedes-Benz says it plans to integrate Luminar’s lidar sensors into its production vehicles&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ykhdt2"&gt;Mercedes-Benz says it plans to integrate Luminar’s lidar sensors into its production vehicles, but there’s a lot that we still don’t know. The automaker declined to share a timeline for integrating Luminar’s lidar into its vehicles, which models would be getting the laser sensor, or what kind of autonomous capabilities it would enable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IUujp5"&gt;Mercedes-Benz has said that its model year 2023 S-Class and EQS sedans will come with the automaker’s Drive Pilot advanced driver assistance system, which it describes as capable of Level 3 automation. Mercedes claims to be the first to “secure internationally valid system approval for conditionally automated driving (SAE Level 3) – marking a milestone in automotive development.” The feature will &lt;a href="https://www.caranddriver.com/news/a38475565/mercedes-drive-pilot-autonomous-germany/"&gt;only be available in Germany&lt;/a&gt;, though, and not the US.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UYYRoj"&gt;Level 3, as defined by the Society of Automotive Engineers, means the driver’s supervision is not required in a highly controlled setting, like on certain mapped highways. The driver still needs to be ready to take control at a moment’s notice, leaving it somewhere in a nebulous zone between Level 2 advanced driver assist systems, like Tesla’s Autopilot, and Level 4 fully driverless vehicles, like Waymo’s autonomous taxi service in Phoenix, Arizona.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pNvvpY"&gt;A lot of companies are claiming to release Level 3 capable vehicles in the coming years. Volvo, which is also using Luminar’s lidar in its upcoming electric vehicles, said its Ride Pilot will enable its vehicles to drive themselves on certain highways without any human supervision. Thee company plans to enable&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/5/22866190/volvo-ride-pilot-level-3-autonomous-subscription-california"&gt; the feature in California once it receives authorization&lt;/a&gt; from the state’s Department of Motor Vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="eCPAJN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A lot of companies are claiming to release Level 3 capable vehicles in the coming years&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bgyxFH"&gt;Most AV companies, including Waymo, Argo, and Cruise, have said they are skipping Level 3 and working exclusively on Level 4 technology. The reason is that Level 3 is seen as being potentially dangerous, given the likelihood that drivers will be confused about when they need to takeover control of the vehicle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GHLCXL"&gt;There is also a data sharing angle to Mercedes’ new partnership with Luminar. The company’s CEO, Austin Russell, said the ability to collect data from Mercedes’ vehicles will ultimately help improve his company’s autonomous vehicle software. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rDEboV"&gt;Russell noted that Waymo, the AV company under Alphabet, has one of the the largest AV fleet in the world, with hundreds of vehicles operating in suburban Phoenix, Arizona. He said the ultimate goal was to have “hundreds of thousands of vehicles” on the road around the world gathering data on road conditions and traffic, enabling companies like Luminar to launch autonomous vehicle features in a broader range of markets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="SPjzKV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It takes not just hundreds, but hundreds of thousands of vehicles to actually be able to get to the global level of data that’s needed”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9ojzIs"&gt;“It takes not just hundreds, but hundreds of thousands of vehicles to actually be able to get to the global level of data that’s needed, and not just in one specific suburban area,” he said. “Also you don’t have to pay drivers. It’s people that are driving the cars already that allow it to continue to improve and get better and better and better.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OYHnhL"&gt;This isn’t the first time that a Daimler-owned company has bought shares in Luminar. Daimler Trucks, a division of Mercedes-Benz’s parent company, also &lt;a href="https://daimler-trucksnorthamerica.com/PressDetail/daimler-trucks-and-torc-partner-with-2020-10-30"&gt;bought a minority stake&lt;/a&gt; in the company in 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XszUIi"&gt;Luminar has secured commitments from a number of companies to purchase its lidars. In addition to Mercedes-Benz, the company has deals with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/6/21248415/volvo-luminar-lidar-self-driving-highway-pilot-spa2"&gt;Volvo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/18/18144506/audi-self-driving-car-volkswagen-luminar-lidar"&gt;Audi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/4/16849422/toyota-self-driving-car-platform-3-lexus-lidar"&gt;Toyota Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/intel-mobileye-int/mobileye-looks-to-build-its-own-lidar-to-drive-down-self-driving-costs-idUSKBN28P2GW"&gt;Intel’s Mobileye&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/26/22399389/luminar-airbus-lidar-aviation-evtol-partnership"&gt;Airbus&lt;/a&gt;, and two Chinese companies: &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/03/18/saic-motor-to-use-luminar-sensors-in-high-tech-line-of-vehicles.html"&gt;automaker SAIC&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/10/22424726/pony-ai-luminar-lidar-robotaxi-california-china"&gt;AV operator Pony.ai&lt;/a&gt;. Luminar may even have a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/24/22451404/tesla-luminar-lidar-elon-musk-autonomous-vehicles"&gt;partnership with Tesla&lt;/a&gt;, despite Elon Musk’s vocal derision of lidar as a “crutch” and a “fool’s errand.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22891314/mercedes-benz-luminar-equity-stake-lidar-autonomous-vehicles"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22891314/mercedes-benz-luminar-equity-stake-lidar-autonomous-vehicles</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-20T08:28:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-20T08:28:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>Streaming music report sheds light on battle between Spotify, Amazon, Apple, and Google  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MNXTiah7ZXfrebGyDeeM3tupojM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70411565/acastro_200511_1777_youtubeMusic_0001.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Y8KfeM"&gt;Spotify was the largest music streaming service in the world as of the second quarter of 2021 with a market share of 31 percent, with Apple Music in second place at 15 percent, and Amazon Music and Tencent Music each tied at third with 13 percent apiece. That’s according to a &lt;a href="https://www.midiaresearch.com/blog/music-subscriber-market-shares-q2-2021"&gt;report from Midia Research&lt;/a&gt;, a media and entertainment-focused research and analysis agency. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vazr2E"&gt;Although exact subscriber numbers and market shares may have changed in the months since Q2 2021 (the use of older data is because of how long the market analysis process takes, Midia tells me), the report sheds light on how the world’s biggest music streaming services are stacking up against one another. While Spotify releases official subscriber numbers at the end of each quarter (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22746682/spotify-q3-2021-earnings-podcast-music-streaming-financials"&gt;most recently in October last year&lt;/a&gt;), competitors like Apple and Amazon are less forthcoming with exact figures, and the most recent &lt;a href="https://musically.com/2020/07/28/spotify-apple-how-many-users-big-music-streaming-services/"&gt;official figures compiled by &lt;em&gt;Music Ally&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are from 2019 and 2020 respectively. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="VCP899"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple and Amazon Music have reported market shares of 15 and 13 percent&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tGROGm"&gt;Based on Midia’s claim that there were 523.9 million total music streaming subscribers in Q2 2021, this suggests Spotify had just over 162.4 million subscribers paying for its music streaming service (although the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22596155/spotify-earnings-q2-2021-podcasting-investments-acquisitions-subscribers"&gt;official figure for Q2 was 165 million&lt;/a&gt;). Midia’s estimates would then put Apple Music at almost 78.6 million subscribers for the quarter, and Amazon Music and China-exclusive Tencent Music at a little over 68.1 million each. YouTube Music follows up in fifth place with an 8 percent market share corresponding to 41.9 million subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tsukxG"&gt;According to Midia, the music streaming market is continuing to grow, and increased by 26.4 percent to the second quarter of last year. Although Spotify’s commanding lead means it’s unlikely to be overtaken anytime soon, Midia notes that its market share dropped from 33 percent in Q2 2020 to 31 percent in Q2 2021, and its growth was outperformed by Amazon and YouTube Music, with the latter growing by over 50 percent compared to a year earlier. Growth in emerging markets was reportedly also strong, with Yandex, Tencent, and NetEast growing by a combined 37 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iIOwEh"&gt;Given these figures date back to the second quarter of last year, they’re unlikely to show the full impact of the lossless audio streaming changes that were made last year. Apple Music, for example, added &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22523228/apple-music-lossless-spatial-audio-dolby-atmos-features"&gt;lossless-quality and spatial audio streaming features in June&lt;/a&gt;, while &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22440058/amazon-music-hd-price-cut-apple-lossless-audio"&gt;Amazon stopped charging extra for lossless streaming in May&lt;/a&gt;. However despite making a big splash with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295273/spotify-hifi-announced-lossless-streaming-hd-quality"&gt;lossless audio announcement of its own&lt;/a&gt;, Spotify’s new Hi-Fi tier missed its planned 2021 release window.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22892939/music-streaming-services-market-share-q2-2021-spotify-apple-amazon-tencent-youtube"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/20/22892939/music-streaming-services-market-share-q2-2021-spotify-apple-amazon-tencent-youtube</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
