<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-08-19T13:45:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-19T13:45:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-19T13:45:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Call of Duty: Vanguard brings the series back to WWII in November</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LInLV3hYLb8TrXQygLQRMqhFcCU=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69748674/Vanguard_Reveal_04.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EfhRi5"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22627527/call-of-duty-vanguard-teaser-warzone-event-activision"&gt;As expected&lt;/a&gt;, Sledgehammer Games officially announced the next &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt; with the reveal of &lt;em&gt;Vanguard&lt;/em&gt;, which will be launching in November. The new shooter is set during World War II and will feature a “historically inspired” single-player campaign, along with a multiplayer mode and integration with &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Zombies&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Warzone&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="78YPyZ"&gt;The announcement comes as Sledgehammer’s parent company Activision Blizzard, and in particular &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; developer Blizzard, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22597113/activision-blizzard-california-sexual-harassment-lawsuit-discrimination-employee-action"&gt;has come under fire for a culture of sexual harassment&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22588215/activision-blizzard-lawsuit-sexual-harassment-discrimination-pay"&gt;spurred by a lawsuit filed by the state of California&lt;/a&gt;. Since then &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22598410/activision-blizzard-employee-walk-out-protest-sexism-discrimination-lawsuit"&gt;employees have staged a walkout&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/11/22620800/activision-blizzard-departures-lawsuit-diablo-4-director"&gt;multiple high-profile developers at Blizzard have left the studio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22607356/blizzard-president-leaving-harassment-protest-brack"&gt;including president J. Allen Brack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EmUeAq"&gt;During a meeting with press last week, Sledgehammer studio head Aaron Halon opened with a statement regarding the situation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="wQX9qB"&gt;The stories and the pain that have been shared are simply devastating. We love making games, it’s what we do, it’s our life’s work, and we love it. But more importantly we’re humans, we’re here for each other, working side by side, and looking out for one another in good times and in bad. So on behalf of Sledgehammer Games, and all of the team supporting &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Vanguard&lt;/em&gt;, harassment of any kind goes against everything we stand for as a studio. Everyone, regardless of their title, role, gender, orientation, or ethnicity deserves to be treated with dignity, respect, and equality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VQniD6"&gt;While we can’t comment on the lawsuit, what I can say is that as a team we are committed to making sure all team members feel safe, welcome, and respected. So please know that these thoughts and actions are at the top of our minds, and will be going forward. They speak to the core values of who we are and who we wish to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="ij4YXW"&gt;As for the game itself, the core of &lt;em&gt;Vanguard&lt;/em&gt; is its single-player campaign, which focuses on the origin of the special forces and will be told from multiple points of view; in addition to the Sledghammer narrative team, sci-fi writer &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tochi_Onyebuchi"&gt;Tochi Onyebuchi&lt;/a&gt; is also working on the story. Sledgehammer says the narrative will cover “the untold stories of multinational heroes that formed Task Force One, changing the face of history and setting the stage for special forces as we know it.” It’ll feature a cast of characters inspired by real-world personalities, like Lt. Polina Petrova, based on Soviet sniper &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lyudmila_Pavlichenko"&gt;Lyudmila Pavlichenko&lt;/a&gt;, also known as “Lady Death.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="BuPuio"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10709077"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5jzXmT"&gt;Outside of the campaign, there will be multiplayer with 20 maps at launch and game modes including “Champion Hill” where players duel solo or in squads of two or three. There will also be a &lt;em&gt;Zombies&lt;/em&gt; mode developed by &lt;em&gt;Black Ops&lt;/em&gt; studio Treyarch which will connect with the previous undead story from &lt;em&gt;Black Ops Cold War&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KLpGUv"&gt;At the same time, Raven Software is leading development on a &lt;em&gt;Vanguard&lt;/em&gt; map for the battle royale spinoff &lt;em&gt;Warzone&lt;/em&gt;. When the new map launches later this year, it’ll be accompanied by a “new anti-cheat system,” according to Activision. The company describes the crossover as an “all-new metaverse connecting &lt;em&gt;Vanguard&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Black Ops Cold War&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Modern Warfare&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IfU33H"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Vanguard&lt;/em&gt; is launching on November 5th and will be coming to the PS4, PS5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X / S, and PC.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22631315/call-of-duty-vanguard-release-date-trailer-sledgehammer-ps5-xbox"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22631315/call-of-duty-vanguard-release-date-trailer-sledgehammer-ps5-xbox</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-19T13:45:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-19T13:45:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Call of Duty: Warzone and Destiny are making moves to fight cheaters</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r6ksbHC3VCgO7C2Pn9CDlyZaNlk=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69748667/cod_warzone.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nXjsFZ"&gt;Alongside its reveal of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22395356"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Vanguard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Activision Blizzard announced that &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Warzone&lt;/em&gt;, its popular, free-to-play battle royale, will receive an update later this year that weaves a new “multi-faceted” anti-cheat system into the game. It will arrive alongside a brand-new map that’s currently in development by Raven Studios, though the system will work across all of &lt;em&gt;Warzone&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qZKg2Z"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/6/21246229/pc-gaming-cheating-aimbots-wallhacks-hacking-tools-developer-response-problem"&gt;Cheating has been a huge problem for &lt;em&gt;Warzone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;since it launched in early 2020, as it is for almost every online competitive game, yet Activision Blizzard’s attempts to thwart cheaters — particularly in ranked matches — haven’t worked. The company hasn’t detailed exactly how its new system aims to succeed where it hasn’t before, as well as whether it’s being built internally or is licensed, but we’ll likely hear more as we get closer to the feature’s release date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7eNCqC"&gt;While &lt;em&gt;Destiny 2&lt;/em&gt; is no longer operated by Activision Blizzard, Bungie announced today that it, too, will be incorporating an improved anti-cheat service into its game. Specifically, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DestinyTheGame/status/1428377075287662593"&gt;it will be “soft launching” a partnership&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href="https://www.battleye.com/"&gt;BattlEye&lt;/a&gt; when the next season launches. Like &lt;em&gt;Warzone&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Destiny 2&lt;/em&gt; has been plagued by cheaters who ruin the experience for people who want to enjoy and progress through the game. Bungie will likely share more details during &lt;a href="https://www.bungie.net/7/en/Direct/DestinyShowcase"&gt;its next &lt;em&gt;Destiny 2 &lt;/em&gt;Showcase&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday, August 24th at 12PM ET / 9AM PT. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="72NJsO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Activision Blizzard faces lawsuit and employee backlash over sexual harassment: a timeline","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22597113/activision-blizzard-california-sexual-harassment-lawsuit-discrimination-employee-action"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632554/call-of-duty-warzone-vanguard-raven-new-map-destiny-2-anti-cheat"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632554/call-of-duty-warzone-vanguard-raven-new-map-destiny-2-anti-cheat</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-19T13:44:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-19T13:44:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>Quake gets a visual overhaul on Xbox, PlayStation, and Switch for its 25th birthday</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6UbNqP0pjNTusG-obK1AvEIE9cw=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69748663/quake.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="l9Fm5S"&gt;QuakeCon, the annual fan convention for the legendary first-person shooter, was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/31/21201501/quakecon-quake-canceled-bethesda-id-software-25th-anniversary"&gt;canceled last year&lt;/a&gt; during the pandemic, but it’s back today with a nailgun-like bang. Machine Games and id Software have teamed up to create a visually enhanced version of the original &lt;em&gt;Quake &lt;/em&gt;game, after June 22nd marked the 25th anniversary of the game’s release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bfzgSY"&gt;It’s the classic &lt;em&gt;Quake&lt;/em&gt;, run-and-gun combat through medieval mazes with nailguns, grenade launchers, and shotguns, but it’s all in 4K with widescreen support, online multiplayer, and even new expansion packs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oWKzej"&gt;The original version of &lt;em&gt;Quake &lt;/em&gt;is now available on PC, Xbox, PlayStation, and Nintendo Switch, complete with up to 4K support, widescreen resolutions, enhanced models, dynamic lighting, anti-aliasing, depth of field, and lots more visual enhancements.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aj_M1oyZrgmgB4Mgjsc_cnkcrkQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22792969/quakenew.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quake on an Xbox.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Hg0pvC"&gt;Both the original &lt;em&gt;Quake &lt;/em&gt;expansion packs are also available, as well as two expansions developed by Machine Games. A four-player online mode for the campaign is available, or local split-screen co-op. There’s even eight-player multiplayer matches with crossplay support, or four-player split-screen local ones. &lt;em&gt;Quake&lt;/em&gt; will also include support for fan-made mods and missions, including &lt;em&gt;Quake 64.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MN4oDt"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quake &lt;/em&gt;is available on PC, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fp%2FQuake%2F9P1Z43KRNQD4" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xbox&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP1003-CUSA24593_00-QKRMST0000000000/"&gt;PlayStation&lt;/a&gt; for $9.99 (or free as part of Xbox Game Pass Ultimate), and on &lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/quake-switch/"&gt;Nintendo Switch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uOEDIcvZ4c1Rcd2lYsldpydQ6vo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22792973/quakeswitch.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quake on Nintendo Switch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="cpwUaq"&gt;This is a pretty major overhaul of Quake, and it follows &lt;em&gt;Quake II&lt;/em&gt; being improved to run on modern PCs recently. &lt;em&gt;Quake II&lt;/em&gt; was modified to run with ray tracing in 2019, and Nvidia &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/28/18642279/quake-ii-rtx-demo-release-date-hands-on"&gt;released the project as &lt;em&gt;Quake II RTX&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;to demonstrate its RTX line of GPUs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QEfd9J"&gt;You can also still play the original 55MB &lt;em&gt;Quake &lt;/em&gt;on a Windows PC today, but the Steam version doesn’t include high resolution widescreen support and the controls are awkward by today’s standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="noCOX6"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quake &lt;/em&gt;was first released 25 years ago as a successor to &lt;em&gt;Doom&lt;/em&gt;, and it quickly became one of the most popular competitive games in ‘90s. Bethesda and id celebrate Quake every year at QuakeCon, which spawned from a fan IRC server into a dedicated event with LAN tournaments and more.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632110/quake-xbox-playstation-switch-4k-visuals-version-download"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632110/quake-xbox-playstation-switch-4k-visuals-version-download</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-19T13:23:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-19T13:23:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>Justice Department says facial recognition helped end an almost 15-year manhunt</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2S6LM03ccbuACk93pA_cblsKJCg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69748588/acastro_210512_1777_deepfake_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RC4sx6"&gt;A fugitive who &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-sdfl/pr/long-time-fugitive-self-proclaimed-offshore-gambling-operator-sentenced-48-months"&gt;Justice Department officials say&lt;/a&gt; had scammed more than 20 people out of hundreds of thousands of dollars was sentenced to four years in prison on Friday, after being on the run for almost 15 years. Austrian authorities were able to identify Randy Levine, 54, of Boca Raton, Florida, due to a facial recognition system according to the DOJ, after he tried to use an alias to open a bank account, leading to his arrest in June 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GofIN5"&gt;Levine fled the US in 2005, after authorities seized his passport as part of an investigation into an alleged scam he had been running, the DOJ said in a release. According to &lt;a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/docket/12311601/18/united-states-v-levine/"&gt;Levine’s plea agreement&lt;/a&gt;, which he signed in May, he would offer to set up gambling accounts for people if they sent him money. To help sell the idea that he really could help people make bets, Levine reportedly played a recording of casino sounds while he was on calls with victims (which he made using a Las Vegas phone number).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N2lTQH"&gt;Levine came under investigation by the FBI, but was able to get a replacement for the passport that law enforcement officials seized, by claiming the passport had simply been lost. He eventually ended up in Poland, where he was arrested in 2008. There was, however, a legal battle over whether he could be extradited to the US, which continued until late 2011. By the time Polish courts had decided that he could be extradited, Levine had already slipped away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="amLXSo"&gt;After another failed attempt to capture him in Guatemala, the FBI heard from Austrian authorities in May 2020, that a facial ID system had identified someone who looked like Levine, who was trying to open a bank account in the country using a Mexican passport, the DOJ said. Levine was then arrested in June, and extradited to the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MCMYfV"&gt;This isn’t the first time that we’ve seen high-tech systems help end the search for a fugitive — famously, data from a genealogy website &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/26/17288532/golden-state-killer-east-area-rapist-genealogy-websites-dna-genetic-investigation"&gt;helped authorities identify a serial killer&lt;/a&gt; who operated in the 1970s and 80s. Technologies like facial recognition and familial genetics remain controversial, though — for every story like Levine’s where they’re used as intended to crack difficult cases, there are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382398/robert-williams-detroit-police-department-aclu-lawsuit-facial-recognition-wrongful-arrest"&gt;false positives&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/21/22193471/aclu-eff-ftf-facial-recognition-legal-objection-filing-customs-airport-surveillance"&gt;concerns of governmental overreach&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Atd799"&gt;Levine has also been charged by the US with &lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/two-charged-with-duping-investors-out-of-5m-with-bogus-bitcoin-buying-brokerage"&gt;running a cryptocurrency scam&lt;/a&gt;. A &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-sdny/pr/international-fugitive-and-disbarred-attorney-charged-over-5-million-cryptocurrency"&gt;criminal complaint filed against him and an alleged accomplice&lt;/a&gt; accuses him of stealing $5 million from two victims, after promising that he would give them Bitcoin in return. According to prosecutors, he never sent the promised Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22629149/facial-recognition-austria-catches-admitted-offshore-gambling-scammer-cryptocurrency"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22629149/facial-recognition-austria-catches-admitted-offshore-gambling-scammer-cryptocurrency</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-19T13:02:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-19T13:02:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter is testing a newsletter subscription button on profile pages</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Twitter bird logo in white against a dark background with outlined logos around it and red circles rippling out from it." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JPgHpU0KwkE-AM0R3GmnK1hm8w4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69748507/acastro_180827_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YX1O1b"&gt;Twitter is &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/revue/status/1428371221524189186?s=20"&gt;testing a feature&lt;/a&gt; that makes it even more enticing to use its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/26/22250156/twitter-revue-newsletter-acquisition-email-service"&gt;recently acquired Revue newsletter platform&lt;/a&gt;: the ability to subscribe to a newsletter directly from a Twitter profile, without having to follow a link to a separate website. The feature &lt;a href="https://help.twitter.com/en/using-twitter/newsletter-subscribe"&gt;can be enabled by all Revue newsletter writers&lt;/a&gt;, but the button is initially only being shown to a test group of Twitter users on Android and the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G0lE99"&gt;The subscribe button has to be turned on in Revue’s settings before it can show up on Twitter. Visually, the new button and newsletter card appear underneath your Twitter bio almost like a pinned tweet, populated with the title of your Revue newsletter, a photo, a short description, and the actual subscribe button. Tapping the button pulls up a dialog box reminding you what you’re getting in to (this person you follow on Twitter will now have your email) and lets you read a sample issue of the newsletter and then subscribe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xc6Ti7"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;It’s here  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Today, we’re starting to test a feature that allows people to subscribe to your Revue newsletter directly from your Twitter profile. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It's available to all Revue creators immediately. To start though, your newsletters will show only for a test group on Twitter. &lt;a href="https://t.co/YDa1aOGeLM"&gt;pic.twitter.com/YDa1aOGeLM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Revue (@revue) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/revue/status/1428371221524189186?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 19, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DuVGPX"&gt;It’s a super simple feature, but possibly a very meaningful one for someone considering starting a newsletter — or transitioning to Twitter’s platform. While writing a newsletter can theoretically be successfully done by anyone, financially successful newsletters are often written by people with an established writing career, an established following, or both. Twitter’s now made it dramatically easier to convert a following into subscribers with a few taps. That’s a lot less clunky than having a Substack link in your profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9qhK0p"&gt;Easy newsletter subscriptions are just the latest offering in Twitter’s rapidly expanding suite of features, several of which are also hosted on the profile page. The company began experimenting with collecting direct payments with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423583/twitter-tip-jar-feature-sending-money-venmo-cashapp"&gt;a Tip Jar feature in May&lt;/a&gt;. It’s also enabled &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22597576/twitter-shopping-module-pilot-gamestop-arden-cove-brands"&gt;a shopping “carousel”  for select brands&lt;/a&gt; that lets you buy products without leaving Twitter. The profile page is a space often used by creators to link to competing newsletter and subscription products, but if Twitter gets its way, you might never leave its app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4V2mO7"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632414/twitter-newsletter-subscription-button-revue-profile"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632414/twitter-newsletter-subscription-button-revue-profile</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-19T13:00:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-19T13:00:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Razer Hammerhead True Wireless (2021) review: ANC with a colorful light show</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Razer did the Razer thing and put RGB lighting on its latest earbuds&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="KlnqWU"&gt;Razer is suddenly becoming a seasoned earbuds brand: the new $130 Hammerhead earbuds are the company’s third pair of true wireless buds. They follow the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/29/20937068/razer-truly-wireless-headphones-hammerhead-bluetooth-5-earbuds-android-gaming-mode-price"&gt;original Hammerheads released in 2019&lt;/a&gt; and the Hammerhead True Wireless Pros that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22272549/razer-hammerhead-true-wireless-pro-review-specs-price"&gt;I reviewed earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;. The latest set is more “Pro” than not in both looks and features: they offer active noise cancellation, a low-latency gaming mode, and have switched to a in-ear design with silicone tips. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oEX0we"&gt;But these days (and at this price), those features are no longer enough to stand out from a hugely crowded field. So Razer decided to add something to its new earbuds that’s impossible to miss: RGB lighting. Just like many of the company’s laptops and gaming accessories, the 2021 Hammerhead True Wireless include Razer’s full Chroma RGB system, which lets you pick from 16.8 million colors and a variety of flashy effects that shine through the snake logo on each earbud. It makes for what Razer calls “the ultimate wireless earbud flex.” But it’s a flex that only other people will see: it’s not like you’ll ever notice the RGB glow when you’re wearing the earbuds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Z8Bcs5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10709325"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0h52yq"&gt;By default when first paired with your phone, the Hammerhead True Wireless buds use a “spectrum” effect that smoothly transitions through a variety of colors. If you want to switch up the lighting, you’ll need to install the Razer Chroma RGB app for Android and iOS — separate from the Razer Audio app that’s used for EQ adjustments and customizing the touch controls. Two apps for a single pair of earbuds? Really? Surely Razer could just replicate the RGB functionality in the main audio app to reduce clutter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3pNE3D"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audio meter:&lt;/strong&gt; the RGB lighting reacts to the music being played. You can choose to have this effect work with a single color — where it honestly just looks like the light is on the fritz — or rapidly cycle through an endless array of different hues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FdgXwx"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breathing:&lt;/strong&gt; a slow pulsating effect where the RGB lighting repeatedly brightens and dims. In this mode, you can set two different colors to switch between with each “breath” or have the earbuds pick a different color every time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VnICIv"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spectrum:&lt;/strong&gt; the earbuds smoothly switch between a wide range of different colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4bup63"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Static:&lt;/strong&gt; the RGB lighting will stay on whichever color you choose.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bhRxOasBQhockYmATGcrc2rJdzU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22792489/DSCF4670_Edited_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The earbuds now slot into the case vertically, whereas the original Hammerheads laid flat.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="rEpsYT"&gt;Out of the box, the lighting is set to 50 percent brightness, which is enough to draw attention — especially if you’re wearing them at night. And let me tell you, those lights will prove very useful should you drop an earbud onto the floor since they’re so easy to spot. Razer says the RGB lighting is optimized for a minimal impact on battery life, but it still takes a toll. With both ANC and the lighting turned off, the Hammerhead True Wireless can hit 6.5 hours of listening time. Using the RGB feature cuts off an entire hour, and the estimate drops to 5.5 hours. Add ANC to the equation and you’re left with only four hours of continuous playback. (With RGB off and ANC enabled, they’ll last up to 4.5 hours.) Those numbers lined up with my experience, and I imagine most people will keep the lights on unless they’re on a long flight or other scenarios where battery life is a priority. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ENoC8RiQow2mxzzdicNVIT-rilo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22792450/Screen_Shot_2021_08_18_at_2.52.19_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Razer&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The RGB lighting does have a detrimental impact on battery life.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="KMYXPo"&gt;The Razer Audio app includes equalizer controls: you can pick from presets like “enhanced bass” or “vocal,” but it also gives you full control over the EQ range if you want to adjust every slider to your liking. The app is where you can remap the touch controls, which by default are fairly standard: tap once to play / pause, twice to skip tracks, three times to go back, or press and hold to toggle ANC. But Razer gets a little over-ambitious beyond that. I’m all for customizable controls, but “double tap and hold” is where you start to lose me. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fwh6BfjsUYUNLq7gCVcsor2MX9Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22792576/app.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Razer audio app includes EQ customization and control remapping.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="vb1j4W"&gt;Whether it’s user error or imprecise touch sensors, it’s too easy to mess up that gesture and skip to the next song when you didn’t mean to. The earbuds went into pairing mode once or twice when I didn’t get it just right. And by default, that’s how you control volume — something you’ll want to do often! Frustratingly, you can’t assign volume to the simpler hold gesture (or any of the others). There were also times when the touch controls stopped responding until I cased the earbuds and pulled them out again, so Razer has more work to do with firmware updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/554f_oPpcafDrLOsEC5xWpYqKmg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22792467/DSCF4641_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Depending which RGB mode you choose, the earbuds might be different colors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wMKeq8"&gt;Design-wise, the Hammerhead True Wireless are very similar to the company’s pricier Pro model. They’ve got the same overall long-stemmed shape, and their cases are practically identical. (Neither set supports wireless charging.) But there are subtle differences when you look closer: the Pros are more matte, while the lower-cost earbuds are all glossy. Razer includes a deluge of tips with the Pros (including Comply foam tips), but you only get the typical S / M / L trio of silicone options with these. And there’s also a large mic inlet on the Hammerhead Pros for their hybrid ANC, whereas the regular model uses a smaller mic that’s better concealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="e4DHYB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10709377"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fUVrSq"&gt;Like the Pros, the second-gen Hammerhead True Wireless had a solid fit in my ears and felt both lightweight and comfortable. The large tips made for a nice seal and good noise isolation, which helped boost the noise cancellation and made it feel more effective than it otherwise would. Like a lot of earbuds in this price range, Razer will cut out some of the hums and rumbles of everyday life, but they can’t knock out as much of the surrounding world as premium options like Sony’s WF-1000XM4 or the AirPods Pro. But these earbuds will cancel enough noise to keep you focused on your &lt;em&gt;PUBG Mobile&lt;/em&gt; session at the coffee shop without constant distractions. They’re also rated IPX4 for water and sweat resistance, making them a feasible option for runs and other workouts. If you’re on an evening jog, having lights in your ears could be yet another visibility measure to help keep you safe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1Mbuxj5OdJvZId3pvKYdYSwxyzc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22792478/DSCF4633_Edited.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The RGB lighting is quite noticeable even at 50 percent brightness.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6EXDe4"&gt;Gaming mode on the Hammerheads cuts audio latency down to 60ms, which is enough to avoid any sync issues that could quickly pull you out of the action. But when it’s enabled, you’ll need to stay closer to your device than normal for optimal performance; Razer recommends keeping within two feet. The buds have Bluetooth 5.2 and didn’t exhibit any problematic cutouts or other bugs in my time testing them so far. And despite lacking the “THX certification” that the Hammerhead True Wireless Pros have, their sound quality is quite pleasing for the price. They aren’t as detailed or full-bodied as earbuds in the $200-300 tier, and the recent $150 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22619305/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-review-specs-price-features"&gt;Samsung Galaxy Buds 2&lt;/a&gt; outperform them with more dynamic sound. But Razer gave the 10mm drivers a nice, even-handed tuning that spans genres well — and those comprehensive EQ controls always help if you want to tinker. They’re neither brilliant nor bad and are right in that place where $130 earbuds so often land. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="Am4LTj"&gt;The Razer Hammerhead True Wireless earbuds aren’t going to be a fit for everyone’s taste: I’m perfectly happy with low-key earbuds that don’t emit a light show whenever I’m wearing them. But by adding RGB lights to its latest earbuds, Razer is doing the obvious Razer thing, and it’s a unique trick that might appeal to some of the company’s diehard fans. I’d sooner recommend something like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22619305/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-review-specs-price-features"&gt;Galaxy Buds 2&lt;/a&gt; to people looking for an everyday, under-$150 pair of wireless earbuds. But those won’t get people looking at you quite the same way that these do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="loBwqS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Epgge"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22632338/razer-hammerhead-true-wireless-earbuds-2nd-gen-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22632338/razer-hammerhead-true-wireless-earbuds-2nd-gen-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-19T12:59:13-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-19T12:59:13-04:00</updated>
    <title>HP Pavilion Aero 13 review: budget Envy</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;It’s not your typical HP Pavilion&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="8HaF8c"&gt;The Pavilion label on the HP Pavilion Aero 13 is misleading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0CStvR"&gt;The rule of thumb with HP’s consumer laptops is: Pavilions are cheap, Envys are midrange, Spectres are expensive. But the Pavilion Aero 13 is much nicer (and a bit more expensive) than your typical budget laptop, with plenty of features — like a 16:10 screen, a 10-hour battery life span, and a mind-blowingly light chassis — that are typically reserved for premium Windows devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pAfdjf"&gt;While testing this device, I’ve been having flashbacks to my review of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21319378/hp-envy-x360-2020-amd-review-price-specs-features"&gt;Envy x360 13&lt;/a&gt; last summer. I remarked that it felt a lot more like a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22264792/hp-spectre-x360-14-laptop-stylus-oled-review-price-specs-features"&gt;Spectre&lt;/a&gt; than an Envy, and that many of the Spectre’s best features appeared to have trickled down. The same appears to have happened here. This Pavilion feels like an Envy — and it’s priced like one, with models &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hp.com%2Fus-en%2Fshop%2FConfigureView%3FurlLangId%3D%26catalogId%3D10051%26langId%3D-1%26storeId%3D10151%26catEntryId%3D3074457345619966818%26quantity%3D1&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22632318%2Fhp-pavilion-aero-13-2021-amd-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;starting at $749.99&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hp.com%2Fus-en%2Fshop%2Fpdp%2Fhp-pavilion-aero-laptop-13-be0097nr&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22632318%2Fhp-pavilion-aero-13-2021-amd-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$999.99 as tested&lt;/a&gt;). It looks like HP has released the first premium Pavilion, and it’s surprisingly great.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iTQhdb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10709242"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uPkufS"&gt;Perhaps the biggest contributor to the Aero’s excellence is its processor. My model has AMD’s eight-core Ryzen 7 5800U, which is one of the fastest U-series processors (the ones in thin and light laptops) you can buy. Models with this processor start at $869.99. It makes the Aero one of the lightest laptops you can buy with eight cores. (My review unit also has 16GB of RAM and 512GB of storage.) The 5800U is positioned to compete with Intel’s flagship Core i7-1165G7 (which is available in the much more expensive &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hp.com%2Fus-en%2Fshop%2Fpdp%2Fhp-spectre-x360-laptop-14t-ea000-touch-1q881av-1&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22632318%2Fhp-pavilion-aero-13-2021-amd-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Spectre x360 14&lt;/a&gt;), but it’s proven itself &lt;a href="https://www.notebookcheck.net/AMD-Ryzen-7-5800U-Processor-Benchmarks-and-Specs.510374.0.html"&gt;significantly faster&lt;/a&gt; in multicore performance. The Aero is also available with a six-core Ryzen 5 5600U, which we wouldn’t expect to be a big step down in performance. The entire Ryzen 5000 line is fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ki05Zt"&gt;Having raved about the 1165G7-powered Spectre x360 14 not too long ago, I think the Aero was about on par with that machine in everyday use. It blew through my typical workload of around a dozen Chrome tabs with Slacking, Spotify streaming, and Zoom calls over top with no issues. But the battery life — AMD’s true strength — is the real standout here. I averaged 10 hours and 49 minutes of continuous work with the screen around medium brightness. That’s much longer than we saw from last year’s Envy x360 13, and even a bit better than the Spectre x360 14. I also didn’t see any difference in quality on the Battery Saver profile — most people should be fine using that for some extra juice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The HP Pavilion Aero 13 seen from the right, half open, on a red picnic table." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/msWLm_GmmE957RdBWX325wwwxP0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22785985/mchin_191108_47150006.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The USB-A ports have little covers on the bottom.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The HP Pavilion Aero 13 webcam." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DzitOWHeVcUucSASLufsZVEAs70=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22785986/mchin_191108_47150007.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;No privacy shutter or on / off switch for the camera.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="geNm9u"&gt;AMD’s Radeon graphics did a decent job with gaming as well, though the company isn’t as dominant over Intel in this area. I was able to run &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt;, on native resolution, at an average of 66fps on medium and 52fps on high at the screen’s native resolution, or 80fps and 58fps respectively at 1080p. Those results are fairly comparable to what we saw from last year’s Envy x360 13 with a Ryzen 4000 processor. That’s expected, since there hasn’t been a significant integrated graphics update between those generations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0hSzy1"&gt;If you use creative software a lot, though, you may be better served with Intel machines, which take advantage of Intel’s Quick Sync feature for faster encoding and decoding. The Aero took 15 minutes and 44 seconds to export a five-minute, 33-second 4K video in Premiere Pro. That’s certainly better than last year’s Envy, which took over an hour, but isn’t a great result among recent machines I’ve used. The past few Core i7 devices we’ve run that test on have completed the task in under nine minutes, and even the ZenBook 13 OLED, powered by the same 5800U processor, was over a minute faster. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="SZpvL9"&gt;&lt;q&gt;AMD’s Radeon graphics did a decent job with gaming&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ihWnlw"&gt;The Aero also scored a 147 on the Puget Systems benchmark for Premiere Pro, which tests live playback and export performance at 4K and 8K (and the program crashed a few times before I could even get a result). That’s good for a budget laptop (beating, for example, the &lt;a href="https://www.pugetsystems.com/benchmarks/view.php?id=37358"&gt;Acer Swift 3&lt;/a&gt;), but not exceptional across the board — the likes of the &lt;a href="https://www.pugetsystems.com/benchmarks/view.php?id=34801"&gt;Spectre x360 14&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.pugetsystems.com/benchmarks/view.php?id=16041"&gt;XPS 13&lt;/a&gt; score better (and it doesn’t approach &lt;a href="https://www.pugetsystems.com/benchmarks/view.php?id=50554"&gt;Apple’s MacBook Air&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P79Uzc"&gt;The cooling was impressive, though. The Aero’s keyboard never got uncomfortably hot, and I never saw the CPU jump anywhere near concerning temperatures during gaming or benchmark testing. The fans weren’t usually audible, even under heavy loads. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The HP Pavilion Aero 13 closed seen from the left on a red picnic table." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RDd_ykCbbdLJ-IRw5jbXH-stzvA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22785987/mchin_191108_47150008.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wi-Fi 6 is optional.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SEPDaW"&gt;It’s not just the number of cores that makes this laptop exciting — it’s the cores per pound. The Aero 13 HP’s lightest consumer laptop, weighing 2.1 pounds. While that means it’s not the lightest Windows laptop you can buy — as far as I know, that honor still belongs to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22239215/asus-expertbook-b9450-review-design-specs-price-features"&gt;Asus ExpertBook&lt;/a&gt; — it’s certainly one of the lightest at this price point. I’m used to describing Pavilions as clunky, so that’s a pleasant surprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yj7lPF"&gt;The downside of the thin frame is that the Aero feels a bit flimsy — which remains a significant differentiator between this device and the very sturdy Envy line. There was noticeable flex in my unit’s screen and across its keyboard deck. On the plus side, the magnesium aluminum chassis didn’t pick up any scratches or fingerprints during my testing period. The hinge is also sturdy, with no screen wobble to be seen, and it’s easy to raise and lower with one hand. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wmrmhk"&gt;Looks-wise, the Aero is unobtrusive and minimalist. It’s less refined than an Envy, due in part to the plastic bezels around the screen. The silver finish on my test unit is somewhat school-laptop-cart-y, but you can get a few nice-looking hues — pale rose gold, warm gold, and ceramic white — for $20 more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="qA4vBi"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Aero is unobtrusive and minimalist&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="b4YDjm"&gt;It does have a more modern look than past Pavilions, and part of that is the display. This is HP’s first 13.3-inch laptop with a 16:10 aspect ratio. It has a 90 percent screen-to-body ratio, which is comparable to that of much more premium devices — the Envy x360 has an 88 percent ratio. In other words, the Aero is taller, with smaller bezels, than plenty of more expensive devices, and it provides more vertical screen space without adding much size to the chassis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dnbJrK"&gt;The 1920 x 1200 display itself is quite bright, easily surpassing 400 nits at maximum brightness. That makes the Aero’s screen one of the brightest I’ve tested this year. That’s surprising to see on a budget laptop — the Spectre doesn’t even break 300. I could use the device outside in bright sunlight and didn’t see any kind of glare. Colors and contrast were good as well. I would wager this is one of the brightest screens you can get at the Aero’s price point.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The HP Pavilion Aero 13 on a red picnic table open, seen from above. The screen displays a black desktop background with a multicolor cloud in the center." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3mZoRLqwnC66HhxPhjJER8ewwB4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22785988/mchin_191108_47150009.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ten percent more vertical viewing space than 16:9 models, HP says.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ZkUZij"&gt;Everything else about the chassis is good, but not quite great. The touchpad — 23 percent larger than the touchpads of previous Pavilions — isn’t my favorite, with a bit of a coarse texture and buttons that require a firm press, but it works. The keyboard is also fine, though backlighting costs $20 extra. It’s fine to type on, but neither as comfortable nor as quiet as the Envy’s keyboard (which is one of my favorites on the market). Like other HP devices, the Aero has a row of hotkeys down the left side including Home, Page Up, Page Down, and End. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="66H95c"&gt;There’s no Thunderbolt support — AMD CPU, after all — but you do get two USB Type-A, a USB Type-C, an HDMI, and a headphone / microphone combo jack. It’s convenient to have a USB-A port on each side. The only thing I wish it had was an SD slot, a feature that’s appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21375183/hp-pavilion-x360-lte-2020-laptop-review"&gt;older Pavilion models&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="CaKnnH"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10709254"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="V9fN98"&gt;I only hit one real disappointment during my testing period, which was the speakers. The sound quality is not great, and the bass is particularly weak. There was some distortion that wasn’t a huge problem — I could only hear it if I was leaning close to the laptop — but also didn’t go away until the volume was below 50 percent. You can swap between audio presets in Bang &amp;amp; Olufsen’s audio control center for music, movies, and voice, but they didn’t make much of a difference. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TVL4Bz"&gt;And a final note: There’s bloatware. My unit came with all kinds of garbage preinstalled, including multiple McAfee programs, ExpressVPN, and various games. I was getting peppered with popups until I could uninstall everything. While bloatware isn’t as egregious on budget laptops as it is on premium devices (cough cough, Spectre), I’m still frustrated to see it on a device that costs $1,000 (which my unit does). &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The lid of the HP Pavilion Aero 13 on a red picnic table seen from above." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EVuX8dPNehQSEwiRjwbbedsdbU0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22785989/mchin_191108_47150010.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’d go for the gold one, myself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="yZ2993"&gt;If I were shopping for a device under $800, the base Pavilion Aero 13 is what I’d buy. The main things I see as compromises are the chassis quality, the bad audio, and the lack of backlit keyboard for the base price. If those are issues for you, you can improve upon them for a similar price (depending on discounts) if you go for an Envy instead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="xCotL1"&gt;But some of the Pavilion’s most exceptional traits — the brightness, the weight, and the battery life — are difficult to beat, even at much higher price points. Despite the Aero’s drawbacks, those things alone make it seem like a no-brainer over budget competitors like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21377208/acer-swift-3-review-2020-14-inch-laptop-specs-features-price"&gt;Acer Swift 3&lt;/a&gt;, which has the same build and audio issues without those standout benefits. And there are plenty of bonus features — the 16:10 screen, the surprisingly quiet fans, and the powerhouse eight-core processor — to ice the cake. All in all, the Pavilion Aero is an appealing package. Despite its moniker, it’s much more Envy than Pavilion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KrNcqz"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22632318/hp-pavilion-aero-13-2021-amd-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22632318/hp-pavilion-aero-13-2021-amd-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-19T12:55:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-19T12:55:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Toyota to reduce production in Japan and North America due to chip shortage</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="COVID-19’s Impacts The Automotive Industry" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zKcRPUIm_VKxMNIrN1RugevkSFI=/0x0:6000x4000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69748442/1230549913.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Toyota’s supply chain has been disrupted | Photo by Artur Widak/NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="K5Dv2a"&gt;Toyota said Thursday that it would &lt;a href="https://global.toyota/en/newsroom/corporate/35741389.html"&gt;reduce production&lt;/a&gt; in Japan and North America due to a shortage of semiconductor chips, a sign that even the best-run supply chains are being affected by the shortage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qKGkL0"&gt;In Japan, the automaker will reduce production by 40 percent later this month and into September, which will affect most of its production lines, the &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/toyota-succumbs-to-chip-shortage-and-shuts-factories-11629372702"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt;; planned reductions in North America will be between 40 and 60 percent in August. The reductions mean Toyota will produce between 60,000 and 90,000 fewer vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1epYY8"&gt;“Due to COVID-19 and unexpected events with our supply chain, Toyota is experiencing additional shortages that will affect production at most of our North American plants,” the company said in a statement. “While the situation remains fluid and complex, our manufacturing and supply chain teams have worked diligently to develop countermeasures to minimize the impact on production.” The company does not expect the disruptions in production to affect staffing levels. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NG6awS"&gt;“We sincerely apologize for the inconvenience caused to our customers and suppliers,” the company said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="xRZbmw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The chip shortage will likely get worse before it gets better ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547826/chip-shortage-cars-playstation-5-gpus-semiconductors-time-foundaries-tsmc"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="highcharts-trriauc-0"&gt;Toyota is the latest automaker to alter its production plans because of the semiconductor shortage caused by COVID-19 related slowdowns at chipmakers’ plants. &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/vw-says-might-have-cut-production-further-due-chip-shortage-2021-08-19/"&gt;Volkswagen also said Thursday&lt;/a&gt; it may have to cut production because of the chip shortage, and both &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/04/08/gm-cutting-production-at-several-plants-due-to-chip-shortage.html"&gt;Ford and General Motors said&lt;/a&gt; in the spring that they were idling or extending shutdowns at several of their North America plants. Tesla, meanwhile, said in July that it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/26/22595060/tesla-chip-shortage-software-rewriting-ev-processor"&gt;rewriting its vehicles’ software&lt;/a&gt; to support alternative chips. But Tesla CEO Elon Musk said during an earnings call that “the global chip shortage situation remains quite serious.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Kmf901"&gt;Toyota had been mostly shielded from the chip shortage up to this point; as the &lt;em&gt;WSJ &lt;/em&gt;noted in May, &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/auto-makers-retreat-from-50-years-of-just-in-time-manufacturing-11620051251?mod=article_inline"&gt;Toyota made adjustments&lt;/a&gt; to its famously efficient supply chain to try to adapt. But with the delta variant of the coronavirus leading to an increase in infections globally, chip production will likely remain slow.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632330/toyota-production-japan-north-america-chip-shortage-ford-tesla-gm-vw"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632330/toyota-production-japan-north-america-chip-shortage-ford-tesla-gm-vw</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-19T12:25:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-19T12:25:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google secretly had a giant gaming vision that includes bringing games to Mac</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8e0lvTg4_7XY1PRHup94yeOgtro=/0x0:1211x807/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69748239/google_gameplan_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zaoG72"&gt;Apple’s Mac has long been an afterthought for the video game industry, and few think of Google as a games company — despite running Android, one of the biggest game platforms in the world. But Google had a plan to change those things in October 2020, according to an explicitly confidential 70-page vision document dubbed “Games Futures.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="RrPgnN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Sweetheart deals and plastic knives: all the best emails from the Apple vs. Epic trial","url":"https://www.theverge.com/e/22375277"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Iraou7"&gt;The “need-to-know” document, which was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22375277"&gt;caught up in the discovery process&lt;/a&gt; when Epic Games hauled Apple into court, reveals a tentative five-year plan to create what Google dubbed “the world’s largest games platform.” Google imagined presenting game developers with a single place they can target gamers across multiple screens including Windows and Mac, as well as smart displays — all tied together by Google services and a “low-cost universal portable game controller” that gamers can pair with any device, even a TV.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mZy9GLr6fCUNgghkErs3OX53uB0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22791941/google_gameplan_3.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vFQrG7E0LzrmFGqhDXNZL7B7op0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22789006/universal_controller_mobile_google.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="3OwgTi"&gt;There’s some reason to be skeptical that this document reflects Google’s true direction: “Brought to you by ‘partially funded’ and ‘i have a dream’ productions,’” an early slide reads. And we know that Google lost some of its gaming ambition this February, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22260994/google-stadia-platform-white-label-option"&gt;when it decided to pull the plug on its original game studios&lt;/a&gt; for Google Stadia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8sUaId"&gt;And yet, the heavily redacted document suggests that to start down this path, Google would first bring “emulated, native and streamed games” to Windows, something that no longer sounds far-fetched: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/24/22548428/microsoft-windows-11-android-apps-support-amazon-store"&gt;Microsoft just announced in June that Android apps are coming to Windows 11&lt;/a&gt;, admittedly with Amazon’s Appstore as the initial partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OXm8DU"&gt;If Google is actually going in this direction, you can get a glimpse of what to expect in the full 70-page document embedded below. It includes how Google would try to establish its Play Games brand as an “indie game destination,” bring roughly 100 of “the best of Android mobile games” to PC, require developers to support controllers and multiple platforms, and mandate minimum prices so it can attract “super-premium” games to the platform. There’s a lot that hasn’t been redacted, and it’s ambitious stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="AgOw0J"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/21044018-2025-2021-google-vision-game-plan-multiplatform/?embed=1&amp;amp;responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="2025-2021-google-vision-game-plan-multiplatform (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="920" style="border: 1px solid #aaa; width: 100%; height: 800px; height: calc(100vh - 100px);" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WPcOJB"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GSimNR"&gt;And if you’d like more where that came from, you can find &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22375277"&gt;our whole list of the best emails from the &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;/em&gt; trial right here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gK6mbQ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vMJaps"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VUwYyq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NBHoBD"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22631907/google-gaming-vision-android-windows-mac-cross-screen-controller"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22631907/google-gaming-vision-android-windows-mac-cross-screen-controller</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-19T12:16:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-19T12:16:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s new Foundation trailer has some serious ‘Game of Thrones but in space’ energy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/htOt2NDjRXJQdtwzpsiCqOGmHiw=/0x32:1828x1251/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69748186/Screen_Shot_2021_08_19_at_8.52.49_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="miQG7D"&gt;Apple has released &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X4QYV5GTz7c"&gt;a new trailer for &lt;em&gt;Foundation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, its upcoming epic sci-fi show for Apple TV Plus based on Isaac Asimov’s series of novels, and I’m getting some serious “&lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones &lt;/em&gt;but in space”&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;energy from it. There are vast (space) vistas, a sweeping soundtrack, numerous shots of people making very serious faces, and dramatic proclamations that wouldn’t be out of place in an early episode of &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="B82vBj"&gt;“Wars will be endless.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="OZiHUh"&gt;“Martyrs tend to have a long half-life.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DRso2D"&gt;“Change is frightening. Especially to those in power.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="DDrqms"&gt;And you know what? That’s fine with me. For me, nothing has replicated the excellence of the first few seasons of &lt;em&gt;Game of&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Thrones. &lt;/em&gt;Their gripping action, shocking twists, and captivating power struggles made every episode feel important, and I eagerly anticipated each one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RovptT"&gt;Based on this trailer &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/28/22553852/foundation-trailer-apple-tv-plus-premier-date"&gt;and the last one&lt;/a&gt;, Apple seems to be going for a similar vibe with &lt;em&gt;Foundation&lt;/em&gt;, and I’m looking forward to watching the show for myself to see if it recaptures that &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt; magic. (If you’re looking for a short explainer about the &lt;em&gt;Foundation&lt;/em&gt; novels, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/11/17223728/apple-foundation-trilogy-isaac-asimov-tv-show-david-goyer-josh-friedman"&gt;we’ve got one in this article&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="918P0x"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Foundation&lt;/em&gt; premieres on Apple TV Plus on September 24th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632413/foundation-apple-tv-plus-trailer-game-of-thrones-energy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632413/foundation-apple-tv-plus-trailer-game-of-thrones-energy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
