<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2022-01-14T15:33:35-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T15:33:35-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T15:33:35-05:00</updated>
    <title>The FTC is reportedly investigating Meta’s VR division for antitrust violations</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6G1BwqQWMlJbfwXgfs_gWzZVHok=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70391096/acastro_211101_1777_meta_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DvSStx"&gt;The US Federal Trade Commission and at least three states are investigating Meta for antitrust violations in its virtual reality division, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-01-14/meta-s-oculus-unit-faces-ftc-led-probe-of-competition-practices?srnd=technology-vp"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The report says the FTC and attorneys general from New York, Tennessee, and North Carolina began speaking last year with third-party VR developers who have concerns about Meta’s business practices. It’s one of multiple probes into Meta’s dominance in the small but growing market of VR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CoFoxu"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; report references &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21455665/facebook-oculus-vr-indie-developers-power-monopoly-concerns"&gt;well-known controversies&lt;/a&gt; around Meta (formerly Facebook) and its VR division (formerly Oculus). Regulators have reportedly asked developers if the Oculus app store discriminates against third-party apps whose features overlap with its own offerings, and they’ve apparently questioned Meta’s strategy of selling the Meta Quest (formerly Oculus Quest) headset at a $299 price point that heavily undercuts the price of other VR headsets. The FTC declined to comment on &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;’s&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cwMFXL"&gt;The FTC has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22840635/ftc-opens-antitrust-probe-meta-deal-vr-fitness-app-supernatural"&gt;allegedly already opened a probe&lt;/a&gt; into Meta’s acquisition of Within, the company behind VR fitness app Supernatural. The US Justice Department also &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-12-03/facebook-accused-of-squeezing-rival-startups-in-virtual-reality"&gt;reportedly investigated similar claims&lt;/a&gt; in late 2020. German regulators &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167509/germany-fco-investigation-facebook-oculus-account-requirements-competition"&gt;publicly announced&lt;/a&gt; an investigation around the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f6QjAJ"&gt;So far, VR has still gotten little attention compared to other Meta divisions. The FTC is currently pursuing an antitrust lawsuit against the company over its acquisition of Instagram and WhatsApp; after a setback last year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/11/22878808/ftc-meta-facebook-lawsuit-ruling-revised-complaint-discovery"&gt;a judge revived the suit&lt;/a&gt; earlier this week. But as Meta has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22588022/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-ceo-metaverse-interview"&gt;begun emphasizing its role&lt;/a&gt; as a steward of a VR-heavy “metaverse,” the area may invite more legal scrutiny as well.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22884198/ftc-state-ag-investigating-meta-facebook-vr-oculus-antitrust"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22884198/ftc-state-ag-investigating-meta-facebook-vr-oculus-antitrust</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T15:15:59-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T15:15:59-05:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix raises prices on all plans in US</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nyxncmndfLi0VleZNgfm9mp1WXU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70390996/acastro_211025_1777_netflix_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="C16tBa"&gt;Netflix is &lt;a href="https://help.netflix.com/en/node/24926"&gt;raising prices across all of its plans in the US&lt;/a&gt; today. The company’s standard plan will rise to $15.50 per month from $14, while the 4K plan will rise to $20 per month from $18. The basic plan, which doesn’t include HD, is also rising to $10 per month from $9. Prices are rising in Canada as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k9wQhb"&gt;The price hikes go into effect immediately for new subscribers. For existing subscribers, the changes will be rolled out “gradually,” with Netflix promising to email members 30 days before the price hike goes into effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SC4OM0"&gt;Prices for a Netflix plan have steadily gone up in recent years. In late 2020, the standard plan went to $14 per month, after previously rising from $11 to $13 in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E5t1o2"&gt;The price hikes come during a successful but challenging moment for Netflix. The company already has a wealth of subscribers across the US, and adding more is a challenge — making price hikes an obvious answer for how it can make more money. At the same time, Netflix is now competing with several other serious streaming services for attention, including Disney Plus and HBO Max, and it’s been spending big on content to keep up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l6t0E6"&gt;“We’re updating our prices so that we can continue to offer a wide variety of quality entertainment options,” a Netflix spokesperson &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/exclusive-netflix-raises-monthly-subscription-prices-us-canada-2022-01-14/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “As always we offer a range of plans so members can pick a price that works for their budget.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22884263/netflix-price-increases-2021-us-canada-all-plans-hd-4k"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22884263/netflix-price-increases-2021-us-canada-all-plans-hd-4k</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T14:17:32-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T14:17:32-05:00</updated>
    <title>Eero could be close to launching a Wi-Fi 6E mesh networking system</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lL0gzvn1wIbpwbygomaFJ1hJkqU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70390601/dseifert_201213_4337_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eero might be upgrading its Pro line to support Wi-Fi 6E.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GtDfNT"&gt;Amazon-owned Eero seems to be close to announcing new routers sometime soon, as new FCC filings appeared this week for devices that appear to be called the &lt;a href="https://fccid.io/2AEM4-41123474"&gt;Eero 6 Plus&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://fccid.io/2AEM4-71213573"&gt;Eero Pro 6E&lt;/a&gt;. That 6E branding for the Pro could indicate it will support &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/23/21231623/6ghz-wifi-6e-explained-speed-availability-fcc-approval"&gt;Wi-Fi 6E&lt;/a&gt;, meaning it can take advantage of 6GHz spectrum for faster connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LLMjFE"&gt;Router makers have slowly been introducing Wi-Fi 6E-capable mesh routers, though some have been quite expensive, such as this &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22716979/netgear-orbi-quad-band-wi-fi-6e-mesh-router-release-date-specs-price"&gt;$1,500 Orbi system from Netgear&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.linksys.com%2Fus%2Fwhole-home-mesh-wifi%2Flinksys-atlas-max-6e-tri-band-mesh-wifi-6e-system-3-pack%2Fp%2Fp-mx8503%2F%3Fclickid%3D36b3a%253A2PexyIUh4UCrRRW3yQUkG3CmQ9RxvqzA0%26utm_campaign%3DOnline%2520Tracking%2520Link%26utm_medium%3Daffiliate%26utm_source%3Dimpactradius&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2022%2F1%2F14%2F22884043%2Feero-pro-6e-6-plus-fcc-filings-wi-fi-support" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Linksys’ $1,200 option&lt;/a&gt;. While we don’t know how much Eero’s 6E-capable system could cost, it could be more affordable than those options, given that a 3-pack for the Eero 6 Pro launched at $599.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ITyDXG"&gt;The new router names show up on labels Eero included in the filings. On the labels, the Eero 6 Plus has a &lt;a href="https://fccid.io/2AEM4-41123474/Label/Label-Info-5598273"&gt;model number of R010001&lt;/a&gt;, while the Eero Pro 6E’s &lt;a href="https://fccid.io/2AEM4-71213573/Label/2AEM4-71213573-Label-Sample-5595249"&gt;model number is S010001&lt;/a&gt; — both of which didn’t show up as currently available devices when I googled them. The new names suggest these routers might be more iterative upgrades or get slotted in alongside the currently available &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/24/21451035/amazon-new-eero-mesh-wi-fi-gear-wifi-6-price-release-date"&gt;Eero 6&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22193059/eero-pro-6-review-mesh-router-wifi-6-test-speeds-network"&gt;Eero Pro 6&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_pm-QUQPQug9GV7nAZacfEt-VBY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23169297/Screen_Shot_2022_01_14_at_10.35.12_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://fccid.io/2AEM4-41123474/Label/Label-Info-5598273" target="_blank"&gt;FCCID.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s the label for the Eero 6 Plus.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2d4OJdwPUohCjViuh66PzsDJIRc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23169301/Screen_Shot_2022_01_14_at_10.35.21_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://fccid.io/2AEM4-71213573/Label/2AEM4-71213573-Label-Sample-5595249" target="_blank"&gt;FCCID.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;And the one for the Eero Pro 6E.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ZiH5iW"&gt;Amazon and Eero didn’t immediately reply to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22884043/eero-pro-6e-6-plus-fcc-filings-wi-fi-support"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22884043/eero-pro-6e-6-plus-fcc-filings-wi-fi-support</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T13:55:48-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T13:55:48-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s Sonos lawsuit dodge might let other phone makers do what Pixel cannot</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5ajKVKUMVra79RRM9HiIk0WMZY0=/58x156:1666x1228/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70390428/cwelch_191016_3737_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WFtwxZ"&gt;You might think a Google phone would be the best choice to control your Google-branded speakers, but that’s not &lt;em&gt;necessarily&lt;/em&gt; true: Google’s actions have potentially opened the door for other manufacturers to do what the Pixel legally cannot, &lt;a href="https://blog.esper.io/android-12-cast-volume-changes-explained"&gt;writes Android sleuth Mishaal Rahman at Esper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GIuYbl"&gt;Last week, we wrote how “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/6/22871304/google-home-speaker-group-volume-control-changes-sonos-patent-decision"&gt;Your Google home speakers are about to get slightly worse because Sonos sued and won&lt;/a&gt;.” If you’re using a Google Pixel, that’s true — among other things, you won’t be able to control the volume of a multi-zone Google Cast speaker group. That’s because the US International Trade Commission &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/6/22871121/sonos-google-patent-itc-ruling-decision-import-ban"&gt;ruled that Google copied Sonos’ technology and threatened to block imports&lt;/a&gt; unless Google implemented five specific software tweaks. One of the Sonos patents specifically dealt with controlling volume of a multi-zone speaker group. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AnRml7"&gt;But when Rahman dug into the Android 12 code, he found that the &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; Google disabled remote speaker group volume control is incredibly basic: Google simply set a single value from “true” to “false” on its own Pixel phones. Rahman writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="Ns5C8p"&gt;the second patch seems tailored to allow Google to ship Pixel phones without the ability to control the volume of remote speaker group sessions. But it also leaves an easy way for OEMs to ship their own devices with the feature enabled. All an OEM would have to do is build AOSP with GMS and leave the default value (‘true’) for the config_volumeAdjustmentForRemoteGroupSessions flag in place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="rOt9Xi"&gt;It sounds like if Samsung or Xiaomi (currently the world’s top two Android manufacturers) want their phones to control the volume of an entire speaker group (something a Google Pixel can no longer do as of the latest update), they don’t have to lift any additional fingers. They just have to avoid intentionally turning it off. And Rahman says that — at least in beta — the upcoming Android 12L works this way as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ziko65"&gt;(For the uninitiated, “build AOSP with GMS” simply means to take &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/4/22708992/android-12-aosp-available-download-install"&gt;the basic version of Android&lt;/a&gt; that Google offers free to manufacturers, with the Google services &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/26/21194803/android-google-play-services-huawei-china"&gt;that the company generally licenses with it&lt;/a&gt;, which is what most Android phone makers do anyhow before they skin Android with additions of their own.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pcfDuW"&gt;None of this means that any phone maker will necessarily take Google up on this possibility. For all I know — I am not a lawyer — Sonos could just turn around and sue them, too, using its victory against Google as precedent. But it’s all very intriguing to think about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Utgq9u"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Google’s Android 12 update has been the rockiest in years","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22881882/android-12-google-pixel-6-pro-bugs-oneplus-oxygenos-12-samsung-one-ui-4-update"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="dSjzWH"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22883982/google-sonos-ban-workaround-speaker-groups-aosp-volume-control"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22883982/google-sonos-ban-workaround-speaker-groups-aosp-volume-control</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T13:44:12-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T13:44:12-05:00</updated>
    <title>Mark Zuckerberg and Sundar Pichai were involved in ad collusion plot, claims court filing</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eidkBoifkb2n3GlyrtR921n_UyU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70390288/acastro_201005_1777_googleAntiTrust_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hkPnkv"&gt;On Friday, a coalition of state attorneys general led by Texas Attorney General Ken Paxton released a new antitrust complaint (&lt;a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/21179902-3rd-complaint-for-texas-google-antitrust-case"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;) against Google, giving more details into the company’s alleged collusion with Facebook in programmatic ad markets. The filing was &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/01/14/facebook-google-ad-market-lawsuit-527108"&gt;first reported by &lt;em&gt;Politico&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dXiiGx"&gt;First filed in November, the initial complaint (&lt;a href="https://www.texasattorneygeneral.gov/sites/default/files/global/images/TAC%20-%20Redacted%20Version%20(public).pdf"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;) alleged broad collusion between the two companies, particularly in a collaborative project codenamed “Jedi Blue” that saw the companies joining together to limit header bidding practices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="z62agv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“this is a big deal strategically”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UxdnJU"&gt;Drawing on internal emails, Friday’s complaint shows that the Jedi Blue deal was reviewed at the highest levels of both companies, with personal involvement from Sundar Pichai, Sheryl Sandberg, and Mark Zuckerberg. In one email to Zuckerberg, Sandberg told the CEO “[t]his is a big deal strategically.” Notably, the filing refers to Zuckerberg and Sandberg by their job titles but redacts their name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jJqIva"&gt;The legal implications of the allegations are still contested, and the distinction between normal business practices and anti-competitive behavior will be hotly debated in court. Still, the state attorneys general succeed in digging up a number of moments where the two ad giants seem to be settling into a collaborative duopoly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uoulbT"&gt;In one particularly uncomfortable passage, the complaint quotes a 2015 email in which “Google employees expressed fear that Google’s exchange might ‘actually have to compete’ with other exchanges at some point in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dDvvgN"&gt;Much of the case rests on the concessions Google allegedly made to Facebook in the wake of the Jedi Blue arrangement, including lower fees and longer timeout limits in exchange bidding. One newly unredacted portion of the complaint claims that the concessions gave Facebook a clear advantage in winning auctions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="oVO8KI"&gt;One Facebook study in 2019 found that Facebook’s bids for in-app impressions won more frequently in Google-run auctions than they did on any other platform. At the same time, the average price Facebook paid per in-app impression was lower in Google-run auctions than it was on any other platform. This would be a puzzling result, to say the least, if Facebook faced the same competition for inventory across auction houses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="r8hmxJ"&gt;The case comes amid a range of antitrust actions against Google, including parallel antitrust cases focusing on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22186994/google-search-antitrust-lawsuit-colorado-nebraska-state-ags"&gt;search manipulation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22567532/google-play-store-antitrust-lawsuit-state-ag-app-fees"&gt;its management of the Google Play Store&lt;/a&gt;. But the complaint led by Texas is arguably the most important for the company, focusing on the programmatic ad networks that have long provided the bulk of the company’s revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ukrunR"&gt;Google did not immediately respond to a request for comment but described the complaint as “full of inaccuracies and lacks legal merit” in a statement to &lt;em&gt;Politico&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22883987/mark-zuckerberg-sundar-pichai-ad-collusion-tx-ag-paxton-complaint"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22883987/mark-zuckerberg-sundar-pichai-ad-collusion-tx-ag-paxton-complaint</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T12:56:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T12:56:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>Bethesda will follow up Fallout 4’s real-life Pip-Boy with this Starfield smartwatch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/n3ZK6m271U7-6Ja1pGr-pwDGhiw=/168x0:1461x862/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70389610/Screen_Shot_2022_01_13_at_17.57.35.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="egqIB3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Starfield&lt;/em&gt;, Bethesda’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/13/22531868/starfield-bethesda-game-xbox-pc-november-11-2022-release"&gt;upcoming space-themed game&lt;/a&gt;, may feature an in-game smartwatch that you’ll be able to get and wear in real life, based on an early copy of a manual &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Starfield/comments/s2qbap/new_images_of_the_watch_i_found_along_with_draft/"&gt;found by Reddit user SquiddyVonn&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://manuals.plus/the-wand-company/lpv6-chronomark-smartwatch-manual"&gt;The manual&lt;/a&gt; details the real-life watch’s functions, which include showing the weather and step tracking, and it even includes pictures that give us a good look at the interface. It also shows us that the watch is being made by a well-known replica company that’s &lt;a href="https://gear.bethesda.net/collections/wand-company"&gt;worked with Bethesda in the past&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="58VtHk"&gt;According to “The Wand Company LPV6 Chronomark Smartwatch User Manual,” the watch will be able to receive forecast information from a phone, display notifications, and show various sets of information on a series of watch faces. It also shows the watch’s “About” menu, which contains the line “©2022 Bethesda Softworks, a ZeniMax Media company.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BuVuPLw6po_NPRlQmGHz37mZ5h0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23167912/THE_WAND_COMPANY_LPV6_Chronomark_Smartwatch_FIg_4.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image via Manuals plus&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The watch’s “Sunrise, sunset and moon phase” screen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="KCh3AQ"&gt;If the name “The Wand Company” rings a bell, it may be because of its work on other replicas — taking something that exists in a game, movie, or TV show and making a real-life version of it is kind of its thing. The company has made &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/7/11/8933329/star-trek-tos-bluetooth-communicator-hands-on-sdcc-2015"&gt;Star Trek communicator replicas&lt;/a&gt; that you can use to make calls (though they use a Bluetooth connection to your phone, rather than far-future tech) and poké ball models that light up when you get your hand near them (but that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/30/21726725/pokemon-pokeball-collectible-metal-motion-activated-do-not-throw"&gt;you &lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; throw&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e3LYE4alehDPDLnS7553G2byBbU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23167858/Screen_Shot_2022_01_13_at_17.44.25.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Bethesda&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A screenshot of the watch from Bethesda’s video.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Z4TFIj"&gt;While the manual gives us a good look at the watch, it’s not the first time we’ve seen it. &lt;a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/a-manual-and-images-of-a-starfield-collectors-edition-watch-have-been-spotted/"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;VGC&lt;/em&gt; points out&lt;/a&gt;, it also made a brief appearance in &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/Wun9up_M87E?t=91"&gt;a behind-the-scenes video from Bethesda&lt;/a&gt;, which was posted in June 2021 (it’s featured right around the 1:33 mark). The video version looks pretty much identical to the one seen in the manual, and the box it comes in appears to be a replica of a box found in the game’s teaser trailer — that could be another hint that the watch will have some sort of role in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4hv6Zl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10977258"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="beGfDj"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Starfield&lt;/em&gt; is currently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/13/22531868/starfield-bethesda-game-xbox-pc-november-11-2022-release"&gt;slated to launch on November 11th&lt;/a&gt; for the PC and Xbox Series consoles. If the watch is set to be part of a collector’s edition, we’ll probably hear more about it before then.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22882988/starfield-smartwatch-collectors-item-manual-leak-bethesda-the-wand-company"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22882988/starfield-smartwatch-collectors-item-manual-leak-bethesda-the-wand-company</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T12:56:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T12:56:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Peacemaker actually knows how to exist in a cinematic universe</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CeHMHh4rk-GegRF9UED-AIph5nQ=/106x72:1918x1280/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70389602/john_cena_3.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Warner Bros,&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UWZYap"&gt;Warner Bros. went out of its way to make sure that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/26/22352484/the-suicide-squad-trailer-james-gunn-hbo-max"&gt;James Gunn’s &lt;em&gt;The Suicide Squad&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;wasn’t exactly looked at as a direct sequel to David Ayer’s &lt;em&gt;Suicide Squad&lt;/em&gt; even though that’s what it was. In the case of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/23/21452994/peacemaker-hbo-max-spinoff-series-suicide-squad"&gt;HBO Max’s new &lt;em&gt;Peacemaker&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;spinoff series, though, the studio’s taking a much different approach to addressing the connections between its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22202992/dc-films-multiverse-batman-wonder-woman-aquaman-hbo-max-dceu-marvel-disney-plus"&gt;rather messy cinematic universe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XplUy0"&gt;It’s become commonplace for spinoff superhero series informed by the events of big superhero movies — Marvel’s latest batch of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22777033/marvel-disney-plus-agatha-spider-man"&gt;Disney Plus series&lt;/a&gt; all come to mind — to dance around the specific details of how they fit into the larger picture until about halfway through the season. Though you can usually infer that these sorts of shows are set after the events of the features that preceded them, they tend to feel as if you’re only meant to think about those details to a point and in the abstract until they can conveniently be pulled into the foreground mid-season for emotional impact. The obvious reason for this is that studios want their tie-in shows to feel like stories that can stand on their own and don’t want audiences to be scared off if they haven’t seen every single project within a franchise. But this approach to worldbuilding often comes at the cost of shows seeming as if they’re slightly out of place and time or as if they don’t know how to acknowledge significant events that their characters should be talking about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mDugvr"&gt;While Warner Bros. likely had these concerns about &lt;em&gt;Peacemaker &lt;/em&gt;as well, the show’s first episode immediately establishes its connections to &lt;em&gt;The Suicide Squad &lt;/em&gt;with a level of straightforwardness that’s refreshing and something that more of these shows might want to consider. Before &lt;em&gt;Peacemaker &lt;/em&gt;properly gets going, it actually opens up with a full-on recap of &lt;em&gt;The Suicide Squad &lt;/em&gt;that clocks in at just over a minute and does an astonishingly solid job of getting you up to speed on a handful of key characters and moments from the film. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mOtqkg"&gt;It’s not immediately obvious from the recap alone which of &lt;em&gt;The Suicide Squad&lt;/em&gt;’s narrative threads &lt;em&gt;Peacemaker &lt;/em&gt;intends to pick up. But what’s very clear is how Peacemaker’s time working for Amanda Waller has impacted the arc of his near future. It’s interesting to consider whether Warner Bros. would have been comfortable giving &lt;em&gt;The Suicide Squad &lt;/em&gt;the “previously on” treatment if the movie hadn’t ended up premiering on HBO Max last summer due to the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic. While &lt;em&gt;The Suicide Squad &lt;/em&gt;also had a theatrical release, it — along with the rest of Warner Bros.’ 2021 release slate — dropping day and date on a streaming service raised eyebrows and concerns last year as directors and cinema nerds bemoaned what that strategy might portend for the future of the industry. Mixed in with concerns about how streaming might hurt theaters was the common implication that any movie to premiere on a streaming platform was being made less than just by existing alongside content originally created to live on those services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wbCCw1"&gt;While studios obviously have a financial motivation to put their features up on pedestals that way, it can work against their interests when their interconnected franchises grow to be as big as the ones that Warner Bros. and Marvel have built out. Though Marvel still seems like it isn’t always sure how to talk about &lt;em&gt;Avengers: Endgame &lt;/em&gt;in a way that feels organic and interesting, Warner’s in a somewhat different position simply because it hasn’t yet had that sort of massive event, and &lt;em&gt;Peacemaker &lt;/em&gt;is its first live-action superhero spinoff series to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yrmtwH"&gt;Whether the handshake between &lt;em&gt;The Suicide Squad &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Peacemaker &lt;/em&gt;will end up factoring into the show’s first season being a success isn’t yet clear, but it’s the kind of move the studio might want to consider more in the future as it continues to release features both theatrically and &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-news/bad-boys-for-life-filmmakers-to-direct-batgirl-movie-for-warner-bros-exclusive-1234950696/"&gt;on HBO Max&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oZA1lB"&gt;&lt;small&gt;Peacemaker&lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt; is now streaming on HBO Max with new episodes dropping every Thursday.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22882051/peacemaker-hbo-max-the-suicide-squad"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22882051/peacemaker-hbo-max-the-suicide-squad</id>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Pulliam-Moore</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T11:55:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T11:55:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s long-in-the-works VR / AR headset may not launch until 2023</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0FiP4hL1n8YKsPjdsWKSjVKPCns=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70389013/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="P1QRr9"&gt;Rumors have swirled for years about Apple releasing some kind of virtual reality / augmented reality headset. While reports had pegged a possible 2022 release for the company’s first mixed reality headset, the device is hitting some development snags and may not release until 2023, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-01-14/apple-s-hotly-anticipated-headset-risks-being-delayed-until-2023?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AHJRsu"&gt;Apple planned to reveal the headset at this year’s Worldwide Developers Conference, but “development challenges related to overheating, cameras and software have made it harder to stay on track,” &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reports. The issues mean the reveal may happen at the end of the year — or even later — with the headset going on sale in 2023. And Apple had apparently, at one point, planned to reveal the device even earlier; &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reports the company wanted to announce it in 2021 and ship it in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1vb9Lo"&gt;Apple didn’t immediately reply to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PRU5Pg"&gt;This first headset is expected to be high end, with Apple considering prices above $2,000. &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; says it will have two processors, and at least one will be “on par” with the new M1 Pro chip that’s available with the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22751921/apple-macbook-pro-14-16-inch-2021-m1-pro-max-review"&gt;refreshed MacBook Pros&lt;/a&gt;. Analyst Ming-chi Kuo has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/26/22802981/apple-ar-headset-m1-processor-release-date-specs"&gt;also reported&lt;/a&gt; that the device will have two chips with one being M1-adjacent. Previous reports have also said that the headset will have two 4K OLED microdisplays, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22825675/apple-ar-headset-hand-tracking-controllers-kuo-report"&gt;3D sensors for hand tracking&lt;/a&gt;, among other advanced components, all of which could be contributing to the rumored high price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tpb5hc"&gt;Apple is also still working on a set of AR glasses, though they might be a long ways off. The company plans to introduce them “later this decade,” &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reports.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22883790/apple-virtual-augmented-mixed-reality-ar-vr-headset-launch-2023"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22883790/apple-virtual-augmented-mixed-reality-ar-vr-headset-launch-2023</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T11:01:31-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T11:01:31-05:00</updated>
    <title>Russia’s FSB says it has taken down REvil hacker group at US request</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/t2N5vavZf9EutGAe3NvlKVWUYEs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70388599/akrales_161208_1298_A_0060_play.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nQYPPO"&gt;Russia’s domestic security service, the FSB, has &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/russia-arrests-dismantles-revil-hacking-group-us-request-report-2022-01-14/"&gt;arrested numerous members of the REvil hacking group&lt;/a&gt; at the request of the US government, the FSB said on Friday. The move, which marks an unusual degree of cooperation between Russian and US agencies, comes amid increasingly aggressive Russian military activity on the Ukrainian border and tense diplomacy as the United States attempts to prevent armed conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B1jXZn"&gt;Reporting by the Russian &lt;em&gt;Interfax&lt;/em&gt; news agency claimed that the FSB &lt;a href="https://www.interfax.ru/russia/815466"&gt;seized 426 million rubles&lt;/a&gt; ($5.6 million) in a raid against 14 members of the group, along with more than $600,000 worth of cryptocurrency and 20 luxury cars. The FSB told &lt;em&gt;Interfax&lt;/em&gt; that it was acting at the request of US authorities and had informed them of the results of the operation. The operation effectively dismantled REvil as an entity, the FSB said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1MzfNS"&gt;The Biden administration has long &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/10/13/politics/white-house-ransomware-meeting/index.html"&gt;called on Russia to do more&lt;/a&gt; to crack down on ransomware gangs operating within the country, though with limited success until now. Analysts have tied Russian groups to extensive ransomware operations in Europe and the US, often without interference from local law enforcement. With no extradition treaty in place, the Russian government has been &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/oct/11/russia-and-nearby-states-are-origin-of-most-ransomware-says-uk-cyber-chief"&gt;accused of sheltering cybercriminals&lt;/a&gt; provided they do not attack domestic targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ulrtqD"&gt;US agencies have intensified their pursuit of REvil after the FBI linked it to the hack that shut down the Colonial Pipeline in May 2021. REvil was also behind a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22463621/jbs-cyberattack-russia-largest-meat-supplier"&gt;cyberattack against meat supplier JBS&lt;/a&gt;, also in May 2021, which shut down the company’s meat processing plants across the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ealgdI"&gt;One alleged member of REvil was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22770701/revil-ransomware-arrest-kaseya-crypto-europol-cybersecurity"&gt;arrested by Polish authorities&lt;/a&gt; in November 2021 after being indicted by the US. According to reporting in &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;, a source close to the case said that the FSB would not hand over REvil group members with Russian citizenship to the United States after the latest arrests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vTAFiC"&gt;The US Department of Justice had not responded to a request for comment by time of publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gKHSPX"&gt;The news of the operation against REvil comes on the same day that the government of Ukraine suffered a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22883400/ukraine-government-websites-cyber-attack-russia"&gt;major cyber attack&lt;/a&gt;. Many government websites were disabled Friday morning, with spokespeople for both the Ukrainian government and the EU pointing the finger toward Russia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xlW5IK"&gt;As the US continues to negotiate with Russia over its military activities on the Ukraine border, the FSB’s actions could be an offering linked to the talks, said Nina Jankowicz, a global fellow at the Wilson Center and specialist in Russian affairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Aveygx"&gt;“The FSB’s takedown of REvil might be Russia trying to throw the US a bone after negotiations on the mounting tensions on Ukraine’s border this week,” Jankowicz said. “But it doesn’t mean much when the rubber hits the road — Russia still has over 100,000 troops on the border and this morning, Ukraine’s government experienced a massive cyberattack.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="odd2MH"&gt;Though the Ukraine cyberattack has not yet been attributed to Russia, Jankowicz said, the mode of operation was similar to attacks carried out in advance of conflict in Georgia in 2008 and the annexation of the Crimean peninsula in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22883675/russia-fsb-revil-hacker-group-ransomware-us-request-fbi-doj"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/14/22883675/russia-fsb-revil-hacker-group-ransomware-us-request-fbi-doj</id>
    <author>
      <name>Corin Faife</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-14T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-14T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Clean energy tech needs to be designed for recycling, experts say  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Wind energy" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dBOu-No5hJvUkNqUS303y_j3qZU=/0x124:5020x3471/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70388572/1237396065.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Patrick Pleul/picture alliance via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JeXA0B"&gt;Companies like Apple and Samsung aren’t the only ones making high-tech devices that are hard to take apart and recycle. So are the manufacturers of critical clean energy technologies like solar panels, wind turbines, and electric vehicle (EV) batteries — and unlike the consumer tech industry, which is &lt;a href="https://grist.org/technology/apple-finally-admits-its-products-are-difficult-to-repair/"&gt;slowly&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://grist.org/accountability/bowing-to-investors-microsoft-will-make-its-devices-easier-to-fix/"&gt;starting&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787336/apple-right-to-repair-self-service-diy-reason-microsoft"&gt;to&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22832895/dell-luna-sustainable-laptop-concept-repairability-recyclable-environment"&gt;reverse&lt;/a&gt; some of its unsustainable design practices, there isn’t much being done about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9ecafo"&gt;Batteries, solar panels, and wind turbines are all essential tools for combating climate change. However, these technologies take considerable energy and resources to make, and the best way to ensure we can keep making more of them sustainably is to recycle those resources at end of life. But today, clean energy recycling is limited by design choices that hinder disassembly, including the widespread use of ultra-strong adhesives. That could change, experts say, if the companies manufacturing supersized batteries for EVs and rare earth magnets for wind turbines shifted toward new adhesives that can be “de-bonded” using light, heat, magnetic fields, and more, or toward glue-free designs.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RSfdHp"&gt;“Design for recycling hasn’t really come to that market yet,” says &lt;a href="https://www2.le.ac.uk/departments/chemistry/people/academic-staff/andrew_p_abbott"&gt;Andy Abbott&lt;/a&gt;, a professor of chemistry at the University of Leicester who recently co-authored a &lt;a href="https://pubs.rsc.org/en/content/articlepdf/2021/gc/d1gc03306a"&gt;review paper&lt;/a&gt; on de-bondable adhesives and their potential use in clean energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bvil54"&gt;Instead, Abbott says, manufacturers tend to “overengineer” their products for safety and durability. Take EV batteries, which are composed of anywhere from dozens to thousands of individual, hermetically-sealed cells glued together inside modules and packs. While the heavy use of adhesives helps ensure the batteries don’t fall apart on the road, it can make them incredibly difficult to take apart in order to &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/a-recycling-renegade-is-out-of-prison-and-ready-to-tack-1840417556"&gt;repurpose individual cells&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nationalgeographic.com%2Fenvironment%2Farticle%2Felectric-vehicles-take-off-recycling-ev-batteries&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22882287%2Fclean-energy-tech-design-recycling" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;recycle critical metals&lt;/a&gt; like lithium, cobalt, and nickel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="icRKiM"&gt;“At the moment, because everything is bonded together, lots of batteries end up getting shredded,” study co-author &lt;a href="https://www.birmingham.ac.uk/staff/profiles/physics/harper-gavin.aspx"&gt;Gavin Harper&lt;/a&gt;, an EV battery recycling expert at the University of Birmingham in the UK, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “The material is mixed together, which makes subsequent steps in the recycling process more complicated.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lbyeAM"&gt;Solar panels and wind turbines are also designed for durability in ways that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/29/22857157/solar-recycling-new-better-method"&gt;make recycling challenging&lt;/a&gt;. Most solar panels are composed of silicon cells coated in layers of polymer sealants that bind the cells to weatherproof glass and plastic covers. While this electronic sandwich design means the panels can spend decades on a rooftop exposed to the elements, the adhesives and sealants used throughout the panel make it hard to separate the components cleanly at end of life. The rare earth magnets inside wind turbine generators, meanwhile, are coated in resins and glues that can create significant contamination for anyone looking to reclaim and reuse the material. A single wind turbine can contain &lt;a href="https://ewi.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/2-Major-Industrial-Uses-S.pdf"&gt;hundreds of pounds&lt;/a&gt; of rare earth elements, and demand for these metals is &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41893-019-0252-z"&gt;set to skyrocket&lt;/a&gt; as the world builds more EVs and more turbines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LljPPz"&gt;Abbott says manufacturers are just starting to wake up to the fact that recovering the critical materials inside clean energy technologies is important for shoring up long-term supplies — and that new design approaches are needed to facilitate that. “Really only in the last 18 months or so, that conversation has started to raise its head,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F5dF3f"&gt;Abbott and Harper’s new paper lays out a number of potential paths toward a more recyclable clean tech sector. While solar manufactures are unlikely to eliminate adhesives any time soon, the authors suggest manufacturers could move toward adhesives and sealant materials that can be unstuck using chemicals, magnetic fields, or even a high-frequency sonic pulse. For wind turbine magnets, an adhesive that loses its stickiness in the presence of a strong magnetic field won’t work, but one that could be melted away using heat, or de-bonded when exposed to ultraviolet light, might be viable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YwlWsR"&gt;Designs that use fewer adhesives could help improve EV battery recycling immensely. If batteries were easier to take apart down to the individual cells, Harper says it could make it easier to recover critical materials inside the cathode, including lithium, which is rarely recycled today. And at least one company is already commercializing an adhesive-free battery design: In 2020, Chinese battery manufacturer BYD announced a new “&lt;a href="https://www.automotiveworld.com/news-releases/byd-blade-battery-set-to-revolutionise-ev-market/"&gt;Blade Battery&lt;/a&gt;,” which features long, skinny cells that &lt;a href="https://www.dcbel.energy/2021/08/23/next-gen-batteries-leading-the-green-energy-charge/"&gt;clip into the main battery pack&lt;/a&gt; without the use of glue. “In terms of disassembly, it’s trivial,” Abbott says. “The cells just clip out.”&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KnUuOS"&gt;For EV battery makers who don’t want to ditch glue-based designs, there are “a huge number of methods out there” that could lead to a more de-bondable adhesive, says Jenny Baker, a battery storage expert at Swansea University in the UK. The challenge, in her view, will be developing adhesives that can be unstuck quickly, in a process that can be done on an industrial scale.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ibEWJ5"&gt;“The thing is now to take some of the science and try and move it into the engineering side so that we can get it ready for really large-scale recycling because we know there’s going to be a lot of these batteries coming through,” Baker says. Based on &lt;a href="https://iea.blob.core.windows.net/assets/24d5dfbb-a77a-4647-abcc-667867207f74/TheRoleofCriticalMineralsinCleanEnergyTransitions.pdf"&gt;projected growth&lt;/a&gt; in EV and energy storage markets, Harper &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nationalgeographic.com%2Fenvironment%2Farticle%2Felectric-vehicles-take-off-recycling-ev-batteries&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22882287%2Fclean-energy-tech-design-recycling" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;has estimated&lt;/a&gt; that by 2040, there could be about 8 million metric tons of battery waste in need of recycling around the world. A &lt;a href="https://www.irena.org/-/media/Files/IRENA/Agency/Publication/2016/IRENA_IEAPVPS_End-of-Life_Solar_PV_Panels_2016.pdf"&gt;similar amount of solar e-waste&lt;/a&gt; could flood recycling plants by 2030.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ylCPjd"&gt;To convince manufacturers (and consumers) to adopt more recycling-friendly adhesives and adhesive-free designs, Baker says they will need assurances that the alternatives don’t compromise product durability or lifespan, which in the clean tech sector is often measured in decades. She suspects that many new designs will have to be “road tested” in products with a shorter lifespan where premature failure is “less of a risk.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3MKF04"&gt;That could include consumer technology markets, where sustainability-oriented companies like Framework and Fairphone are already rolling out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22587205/framework-laptop-review"&gt;modular&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.fairphone.com%2Fen%2F2020%2F01%2F17%2Fgoing-against-the-grain-to-design-a-sustainable-phone%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22882287%2Fclean-energy-tech-design-recycling" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;adhesive-free&lt;/a&gt; laptops and phones intended to be taken apart easily. Even industry titans like Apple and Dell have recently announced &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/behind-the-hype-of-apples-plan-to-end-mining-1833045476"&gt;ambitious goals&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22832895/dell-luna-sustainable-laptop-concept-repairability-recyclable-environment"&gt;product concepts&lt;/a&gt; focused on recyclability. Abbott has already had preliminary talks with a phone manufacturer about glues that can de-bond a screen much more easily, although he says the company hasn’t yet embraced the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rnC72m"&gt;Ultimately, manufacturers may be forced to overcome their reluctance to tweak product designs for recycling if policymakers start to mandate it or if the world faces shortages of the metals and minerals needed to build these technologies. As the clean energy transition causes &lt;a href="https://www.iea.org/reports/the-role-of-critical-minerals-in-clean-energy-transitions/mineral-requirements-for-clean-energy-transitions"&gt;demand for high-tech metals to spike&lt;/a&gt;, Baker says that companies are going to have to start getting more creative about where they source from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8Dn6Cm"&gt;“If you can get [a resource] but it’s a really high price, that’s bad, but you can pass the price onto the consumer,” Baker says. “If you can’t get it at all, you have no business.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22882287/clean-energy-tech-design-recycling"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22882287/clean-energy-tech-design-recycling</id>
    <author>
      <name>Maddie Stone</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
