<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-11-12T22:38:21-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-12T22:38:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-12T22:38:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>Steam Deck: Five big things we learned from Valve’s developer summit</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ahrsCSpl8owL09zX3z49lICb94k=/48x0:1271x815/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70136394/steam_deck_developer_summit.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Purp.”&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Valve&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XSFmdY"&gt;On Friday, PC gaming giant Valve &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22776897/valve-steam-deck-developer-conference-amd-apu"&gt;invited the developer community&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22612886/valve-steam-deck-handheld-gaming-pc-hands-on-preview"&gt;Steam Deck&lt;/a&gt;, a $400 handheld gaming PC with a comparatively powerful AMD chip. It’s akin to the Nintendo Switch of gaming PCs, and there’s a lot we already knew about the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22774888/steam-deck-delayed-two-months-february-2022-launch-shipping"&gt;delayed handheld&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578783/valve-steam-deck-gaming-handheld-pc"&gt;its announcement&lt;/a&gt;, our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22612886/valve-steam-deck-handheld-gaming-pc-hands-on-preview"&gt;trip to Valve’s headquarters&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/6/22713075/valve-steam-deck-teardown-repair-open"&gt;an official teardown&lt;/a&gt;. But today, we learned even more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UJL2HI"&gt;Here are the highlights — unless, of course, you’d like to &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P6CUQeHIxDA"&gt;watch Valve’s entire livestream&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/SteamworksDev/videos"&gt;breakout sessions&lt;/a&gt; for yourself. That’s fine too! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="7nEJlm"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aerith lives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R4kjq2oamtRtoC1Jr9leF5c78lM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23010966/chrome_23TO2cUhXJ.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="iUYIUn"&gt;The AMD chip inside the Steam Deck has a name: it’s the Aerith SOC, a clear reference to the famous &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aerith_Gainsborough"&gt;Aerith from &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;It’s an APU with a power envelope of between 4 and 15 watts, and it contains both an 4-core, 8-thread AMD Zen 2 CPU that runs between 2.4-3.5GHz, and 8 AMD RDNA 2 compute units worth of graphics clocked between 1 and 1.6GHz, for a total of 1.6 teraflops of raw graphical compute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t6Fgpr"&gt;Here’s the Steam Deck’s entire block diagram, so you can see how the whole system comes together around that chip:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wPgTKVmvi7GntyHT_5qWM3GYiIg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23010880/chrome_TLfpafLS3X.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5FLrE9"&gt;It interfaces with 16GB of unified LPDDR5 memory, with a total of 88GB/s of bandwidth. While there’s only 1GB of dedicated video memory, Valve says the GPU can access up to 8GB of that shared memory as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="kX7uPT"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“If you’re in Florida in July, you may run out of thermal headroom”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4i2y8O"&gt;Valve says the chip’s designed to run continually and consistently at its quoted clockspeeds: “The performance your game gets in the first ten seconds is likely to be the same performance you get two hours from now, or even indefinitely if you’re plugged into the wall,” says Valve’s Yazan Aldehayyat, adding that the system’s designed to perform the same docked, undocked, charging or not, even while downloading games or at an elevated temperature. “If you’re in Florida in July, you may run out of thermal headroom,” he says, but even then Valve says it’ll try to throttle downloads and transfer speeds before it throttles your game performance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jvPPKX"&gt;Valve does warn that developers may need to avoid pushing the GPU too hard if they want longer battery life. “We didn’t place any artificial limits on how much power the APU can consume.” As one specific tactic, Valve’s suggesting that games cap their framerate to save battery. That could make a big difference: “You can play &lt;em&gt;Portal 2 &lt;/em&gt;for four hours on this thing. If you limit it to 30 FPS, you’re going to be playing for 5-6 hours,” &lt;a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/steam-deck-valve-faq-big-questions-answered"&gt;Valve told &lt;em&gt;IGN&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in August. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hOIX73"&gt;Another optimization: Valve revealed today that developers can upload versions of their games with lower-fidelity texture packages to Steam’s Depot to improve performance and reduce the amount of storage and time it takes a user to download a game. That’s similar to Microsoft’s Smart Delivery system for the Xbox One, Xbox One X and Xbox Series X/S, which routes the proper version of a game to each console. (But where Xbox developers are likely targeting 1080p, 1440p and near-4K respectively, the portable Steam Deck runs at 720p and 800p resolution.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="QX7TQR"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Designed to dock and stream&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tkoo4Dn4FDuNkTfknVhqH8HMZj0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23010965/chrome_TeXCstTWuk.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="VwAcLu"&gt;With a 45-watt power supply, Valve says the Steam Deck can charge and play at the same time, and power a 7.5-watt worth of external peripheral. The USB-C port also offers external display support for up to two 4K monitors at 60Hz (using Display Stream Compression), and Valve says it’ll offer USB 3 Gen 2 “if you opt for half the display bandwidth.” The optional dock (which has yet to be pictured or go on preorder) will also offer Gigabit Ethernet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EyOIAQ"&gt;And if you opt to play on a TV or monitor, you’ll probably be happy to hear the first full confirmation that Valve is supporting &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/22/22545441/amd-dlss-fidelityfx-super-resolution-fsr-supersampling-tests-benchmarks"&gt;AMD’s FidelityFX Super Resolution (FSR)&lt;/a&gt; upscaling with the Steam Deck. In fact, AMD representatives on the stream confirmed that not only does the Steam Deck work with FSR in games that support it — potentially making them look a bit better on the big screen — but that the Steam Deck will natively support FSR at an operating system level with a future update. AMD says it’s working on drivers that will enable &lt;a href="https://www.khronos.org/blog/streamlining-render-passes"&gt;the recently announced Vulkan Dynamic Rendering&lt;/a&gt;, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HYWARa"&gt;There’s no USB 4 or Intel-proprietary Thunderbolt here, obviously, and you’re only getting 802.11ac (Wi-Fi 5) instead of Wi-Fi 6 or 6E, but Valve says the Deck is optimized for “reliability and robustness even in congested environments.” That way, Valve can offer a “first-class Remote Play experience” to beam games from their desktop PC to the Deck inside their own homes, while using less battery than games natively running on the Deck’s hardware itself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kfgiwe"&gt;Valve did an great job with Wi-Fi engineering when it built &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/11/19/18103672/valve-discontinues-steam-link-streaming-set-top-box"&gt;the Steam Link HDMI puck&lt;/a&gt;, so I’m  excited to test that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="vnk9uF"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scant slowdown over SD (and eMMC)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="6blqfI"&gt;The entry level $400 Steam Deck only comes with 64GB of comparatively slow eMMC storage and a microSD card slot for expansion — you’ll have to pay notably more for the faster models with NVMe SSDs, and even then they’ll be fairly easy to fill with a decent-sized Steam library of games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IGNrjH"&gt;But today, Valve assured developers that eMMC and SD aren’t &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; much slower: roughly 12 percent and 18 percent slower respectively when it comes to loading games. (Yes, the Y-axes are either mislabeled or don’t line up with the bar graphs.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TypOgG"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Valve says games 64GB eMMC Steam Deck might be 12 percent slower at loading a game and 25 percent slower booting, compared to the NVMe model. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;18 percent slower loading a game from SD card. &lt;a href="https://t.co/X6HfKusY2X"&gt;pic.twitter.com/X6HfKusY2X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Sean Hollister (@StarFire2258) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/StarFire2258/status/1459257145237540864?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 12, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pla1Ih"&gt;Boot times are 25 percent slower, but I suppose we’ll have to see how long they are in reality — Valve didn’t specify an actual number of minutes or seconds it takes for the Steam Deck to boot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="q5OevW"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valve’s changing how cloud saves work so you can pick up and play&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="2zbDD9"&gt;But Valve is also thinking of the Steam Deck as an always-on device, one where you won’t always &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to boot and launch games from scratch: there’s a suspend and resume feature built into the Steam Deck that should let you quickly pause games like you do on a Nintendo Switch.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MtknXYMT7MxFic3cd-KJiuujKlg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23011029/chrome_U7BMoOov6t.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="R7upgN"&gt;Valve’s changing how Steam’s cloud save system works as a result: Where today’s Steam generally syncs your cloud saves &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; you’ve quit out of a game, the company’s offering new cloud APIs so developers can get their games to sync in the background at the time you suspend the title. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1pAtHk"&gt;Theoretically, that could also mean you could pause a game you’re playing on the Steam Deck and quickly pick it up on your desktop PC, or vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="cm0zOl"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;There’s a white Steam Deck right out of &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Portal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, but you can’t have it&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Valve’s Greg Coomer picks up a white Steam Deck prototype and shows it off. It’s got an Aperture logo on the back." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rewNBzu2KshOwnvT4fPMcFget-s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23010853/white_steam_deck_valve_prototype_aperture_portal.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s not for sale.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="0bBe8F"&gt;During the entire Steam Deck presentation, the backgrounds were &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/StarFire2258/status/1459258255260094468"&gt;filled with intriguing hints at Valve’s prototyping process&lt;/a&gt;, and many onlookers noticed a &lt;em&gt;white Steam Deck&lt;/em&gt; among them — one straight out of Valve’s hit game &lt;em&gt;Portal&lt;/em&gt; right down to the Aperture logo around back. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Xyecde0Qe2uDFHMhS9wbaRNNISQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23011042/chrome_oPvnvcwcLG.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="FyAgAi"&gt;Unfortunately, it’s not for sale: “This is a prototype only. We love it too, but we’re not able to bring it to market at the same time we’re shipping the Steam Deck,” said Valve’s Greg Coomer, adding that the company intends to “look at other color options in the future, but that’s really down the road.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="19E5Uc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other tidbits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="NC8sNy"&gt;Here are some other random things we learned:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="666akN"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;It’s not made for VR. &lt;/strong&gt;“We definitely didn’t design and build the device for VR,” says Valve’s Lawrence Yang, while admitting that gamers will almost certainly try anyhow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="r7MChd"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;There are still no plans for 5G or LTE configurations&lt;/strong&gt;. You can tether it to a phone, Valve says. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="54sob0"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Valve is working to bring the Steam Deck to Japan and Australia in particular.&lt;/strong&gt; Other territories as well. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="QEpZLN"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Steam Deck has factory calibrated audio. &lt;/strong&gt;“Every single Steam Deck has been calibrated at the factory for best performance” and includes a dedicated amp and DSP for the stereo speakers. It supports multichannel audio over HDMI (via USB-C). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DoTXGF"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Once Big Picture Mode on desktop Steam gets replaced by the Deck UI, it’ll get updated more often. &lt;/strong&gt;There’s no timeframe yet for the switchover, but it’s good news for uniformity. “We can add new features to Steam and you’ll see them almost immediately on Deck.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nUkiTb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valve will share keyboard APIs with multiple IMEs, multiple languages, and emojis. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="z8ti2I"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;We got our first look (I think!) at the Steam Deck notifications center and the new controller configurator to map your games to Steam Deck’s controls. &lt;/strong&gt;More of that &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8NG_Uus8HIA"&gt;in this session&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="lzl4KD"&gt;In fact, we’ll leave you with whole bunch of Steam Deck user interface screenshots — we haven’t seen much of this before now. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y_a7bhi-4gYPXSJ1xyg8kbZNQgE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23011055/chrome_g3xH5fE9JG.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The controller configurator lets you map and bind the Steam Deck’s considerable array of controls.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GOQj5GAVqNZSymIggUh14-dBSRA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23011056/chrome_FXQAJ6FYDF.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’ll look the same across Steam desktop and Deck.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dV2Q2pb0SjcgghHMPQWx7lcEUMY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23011059/chrome_HGtpWA91Zb.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notifications will have a dedicated button on Deck.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vrmMkNj7n0w7KdA09Q5LhIsUWNI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23011057/chrome_zwHoFOqs43.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pivuajslkat3jnVkYMC5RdFWNiU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23011060/chrome_LdaciB03wy.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZZB0u8D7yZEatNwUSLkfSpWUTaM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23011058/chrome_uSEJhZEfN5.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Universal search works across all of Steam, not just games.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;aside id="cIHRtO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Valve Steam Deck hands-on: the Nintendo Switch of PC gaming","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22612886/valve-steam-deck-handheld-gaming-pc-hands-on-preview"},{"title":"Why the Steam Deck won’t flop like Valve’s Steam Machines","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/18/22579747/valve-steam-deck-steam-machines-editorial"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="GooHge"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Steam Deck: a Switch-like portable gaming PC|103274" data-volume-uuid="2d2697872" data-volume-id="103274" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-477" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1e4irM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mnKaOJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22779252/steam-deck-things-we-learned-from-valve-developer-summit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22779252/steam-deck-things-we-learned-from-valve-developer-summit</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-12T21:01:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-12T21:01:26-05:00</updated>
    <title>The best deals on true wireless earbuds right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EMA4Er2sFrxHrUuDpHfpSH0b1VM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68898291/bfarsace_201130_4322_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="USGxSy"&gt;When it comes to true wireless earbuds, there are a ton of brands and products to choose from. Whether you enjoy the unconventional design of Samsung’s Galaxy Buds Live or prefer Jabra’s compact Elite 75t, there’s a pair of wireless earbuds for just about everyone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AsWVXq"&gt;Regardless of which brand you prefer, we’ve compiled some of the best deals on wireless earbuds available right now, some of which are featured in our guide to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22759214/black-friday-early-deals-best-headphones-laptops-gaming-tvs-tech-sale"&gt;best early Black Friday deals&lt;/a&gt;. Of course, if you want to do more research before making a buying decision, we also encourage you to read our guide to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds"&gt;best wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt;, which can help you determine which pair of earbuds are right for you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="LnNBDm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best AirPods deals you can get right now ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals"},{"title":"The best deals on 4K TVs ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22371561/best-4k-tv-deals-sale-lg-samsung-sony-tcl"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Apple’s second-generation AirPods" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/H4c7403UDVQ2p-JvX1pB9iSnj8U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15993021/akrales_190327_3315_0012.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="c27rNd"&gt;Apple AirPods deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="2vr3VH"&gt;If you own an iPhone or multiple Apple products, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt; are likely the best true wireless earbuds on the market for you. Unlike the base AirPods, the Pro variant offer better sound quality and feature active noise cancellation, not to mention seamless integration with iOS and a MagSafe-compatible charging case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ftMREv"&gt;The AirPods Pro tend to go on sale frequently, and we often see them drop to as low as $200. Right now, for instance, you can get a new pair for &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-Pro%2F520468661&amp;amp;subid1=VergeBestAirPodsDeals02262021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$190 at Walmart&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MWP22AM-A-AirPods-Pro/dp/B07ZPC9QD4?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kPY6Vk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="X9766m"&gt;Alternatively, you can buy a pair of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;second-generation AirPods&lt;/a&gt; — now the entry-level model — with either a wired or wireless charging case. The base AirPods normally retail for $160, but currently, you can get the version with the wired charging case for &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/994132/9383?subId1=VergeBestAirPods030121&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Charging-Case-Latest-Model%2F604342441%3F&amp;amp;veh=aff" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$89 at Walmart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="DcXNMK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eJgls2"&gt;If you prefer a little more convenience, you can also get a new pair of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;AirPods with a Qi-compatible wireless charging case&lt;/a&gt; for a few dollars more. At their regular price of $200, they aren’t as good of a value, but you’ll rarely find yourself paying the usual price. At the moment, you can get them for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Wireless-Charging-Latest/dp/B07PYLT6DN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$160 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/1066108/9383?subId1=VergeDeals&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Wireless-Charging-Case-Latest-Model%2F482532021&amp;amp;veh=aff" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iGBbls"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9507432"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GvE4V_5ezL8yYRQFDA0uPj1WyN8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21700189/IMG_0628_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung Galaxy Buds Live.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="HGCqrw"&gt;Samsung Galaxy Buds Deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="v5RLzc"&gt;Samsung has a few different wireless earbuds to choose from, including its latest flagship wireless earbuds, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22231848/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-review"&gt;Galaxy Buds Pro&lt;/a&gt;. These earbuds include active noise cancellation and some of the best sound quality of any Samsung earbuds to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pyxi2K"&gt;Right now Amazon is offering the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Samsung-Wireless-Cancelling-Charging-Included/dp/B08MWZHHKP?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Galaxy Buds Pro for more than $50 off&lt;/a&gt;, bringing the price down to around $150 — nearly an all-time low — in select colorways. They’re also available in all three color configurations for $150 at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfWifJWOA7P" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfYRiPIEn1F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WZ42v1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10401237"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="x23GrZ"&gt;Samsung released the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22619305/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-review-specs-price-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Galaxy Buds 2&lt;/a&gt; — a good-sounding pair of earbuds with active noise cancellation, wireless charging, and a subtle design — back in August, and we’re already starting to see some discounts at retailers like Woot and Amazon. Right now, for instance, you can get them at &lt;a href="https://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8836602-13140759?url=https%3A%2F%2Felectronics.woot.com%2Foffers%2Fsamsung-galaxy-buds2-true-wireless-anc-earbuds" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Woot for $100&lt;/a&gt; and at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Wireless-Cancelling-Bluetooth-Lightweight/dp/B0942DM32W/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon for just shy $130&lt;/a&gt;, their lowest price to date. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Eo52gY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10707231"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jQroWm"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/24/21147654/samsung-galaxy-buds-plus-review-wireless-earbuds-sound-quality-battery-life" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Galaxy Buds Plus&lt;/a&gt; were our top pick last year for the best wireless earbuds overall, but have since been discontinued with the arrival of the Galaxy Buds 2. A successor to the original Galaxy Buds, the Plus model extends the battery life by up to 11 hours and, unlike AirPods, comes in an assortment of colors. Right now, you can buy the Galaxy Buds Plus in black for &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSAMSUNG-Galaxy-Buds-Cosmic-Black-Charging-Case-Included%2F255407922" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$79 at Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, which is the lowest price we’ve seen in the last several months and likely one of the last major discounts we’ll see before the earbuds become unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MjZMZR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10368022"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mPBmzD"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21356260/samsung-galaxy-buds-live-review-wireless-earbuds-beans-design-specs-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Galaxy Buds Live&lt;/a&gt; are some of the more unconventional wireless earbuds on the market right now, but don’t let their bean-shaped design fool you. The Buds Live is a good option if you want earbuds that produce powerful sound and showcase marathon battery life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="52C6bu"&gt;Right now, you can purchase a pair of the Galaxy Buds Live in a multitude of colors for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Samsung-Wireless-Cancelling-Charging-Included/dp/B089B658NP/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$100 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fsamsung-galaxy-buds-live-mystic-black%2F-%2FA-80785946%3Fclkid%3D8f237b25N38d111eca5f31be93c0cebf1%26lnm%3D81938%26afid%3DVox%2520Media%26ref%3Dtgt_adv_xasd0002&amp;amp;subid1=VergeBestWirelessHeadphoneDeal110521" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, a roughly $70 discount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xJfsfQ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10685823"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a2Ol0J-O6sW1PwuvoXPBBDrB7Pc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/18279734/cwelch_190702_3528_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="i2Ah0B"&gt;Sony WF-1000XM4 deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="HggHzb"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22523584/sony-wf-1000xm4-wireless-earbuds-headphones-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sony’s WF-1000XM4&lt;/a&gt; are the true wireless headphones to beat, and improve on their excellent predecessor in several ways. Sony’s latest earbuds include better battery life and noise cancellation, as well as superior sound quality and IPX4 water resistance. Normally $280, they’re currently receiving a small discount at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WF-1000XM4-Industry-Canceling-Headphones/dp/B094C4VDJZ/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1743035238017039291" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fsony-wf-1000xm4-noise-cancelling-true-wireless-earbuds-silver%2F-%2FA-82691014%3Fref%3Dtgt_adv_XS000000%26AFID%3Dgoogle_pla_df_free_online%26CPNG%3DElectronics%26adgroup%3D8-7%26clkid%3D8f237b25N38d111eca5f31be93c0cebf1%26lnm%3D81938%26afid%3DVox%2520Media%26ref%3Dtgt_adv_xasd0002&amp;amp;subid1=VergeBestWirelessHeadphoneDeal110521" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, bringing them down to around $248. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lZIzyj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10600158"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="UMsK59"&gt;Sony WF-1000XM3 deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="haWqZJ"&gt;The predecessor to the WF-1000XM4, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/5/20682334/sony-wf-1000xm3-wireless-earbuds-hands-on-preview-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;WF-1000XM3&lt;/a&gt;, remain a terrific pair of earbuds that routinely go on sale. Like the most recent model, the WF-1000XM3 feature phenomenal sound quality and considerable battery life, a small feat for a pair of true wireless earbuds. They also manage to deliver noise cancellation in a sleek, copper-adorned package, one that’s both attractive and professional. Unfortunately, Sony’s last-gen WF-1000XM3 are only available at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WF-1000XM3-Industry-Canceling-Wireless/dp/B07T81554H/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1747336499962657708#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; right now for around $200, their typical asking price and a far cry from the best price we’ve seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8F3h1H"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9563643"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="9wJvFX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Verge Deals on Twitter","description":"Join our 40,000 followers, and keep up with our best daily tech deals with @vergedeals","label":"Follow us!","url":"http://bit.ly/2JzR5Ud"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="1TXXf4"&gt;Other true wireless earbuds deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="58GOfq"&gt;Compared to the competition, Jabra’s wireless earbuds have a rare feature that has yet to become standard in the true wireless earbud market: the ability to connect to two devices concurrently. Ideally, this is great for users who switch between two devices often (like, say, a phone and a laptop).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="P0sP2n"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Jabra overhauls true wireless earbuds lineup with three new models","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22649800/jabra-elite-7-pro-active-3-features-price"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="vJ5wIC"&gt;Last year, Jabra released the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549587/jabra-elite-85t-review-features-specs-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Elite 85t wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt;, which are the highest-tier model in Jabra’s lineup. They offer more advanced noise cancellation than the 75t, however, they also feature less bass and an inferior fit. You can currently buy the Jabra Elite 85t for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Jabra-Wireless-Bluetooth-Earbuds-Titanium/dp/B08HR78C46?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$150 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfDfB2WVItB#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, their best price to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="L8bJWl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10355180"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LacpUE"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/15/21066947/jabra-elite-75t-review-wireless-earbuds-airpods-alternative" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Elite 75t&lt;/a&gt; are also a good option for wireless earbuds that have multi-point Bluetooth connectivity. The Jabra 75t are currently selling for &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfDfEmv2ecW" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$150 at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Jabra-Elite-75t-Earbuds-Comfortable/dp/B07X9VG6ZJ/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, and they remain a solid alternative if you don’t want to buy AirPods. However, the current sale on the aforementioned Elite 85t brings them down to the same price, so we’d recommend waiting for a more substantial sale before picking up the 75t — which is likely to happen, given Jabra intends to phase them out by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OvElfP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10386608"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mqq7gj"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22753158/beats-fit-pro-earbuds-review-apple" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Beats Fit Pro&lt;/a&gt; are the latest fitness earbuds from Apple, and offer a sportier design and better sound than the Airpod Pro, according to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22753158/beats-fit-pro-earbuds-review-apple" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;our review&lt;/a&gt; by Chris Welch. Sadly, these shiny new earbuds are currently only available for their full price of $200. As soon as we see a price break on these, we’ll be sure to let you know. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OvwTzC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10844241"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PJ3wLT"&gt;If you’re currently in the market for a reliable pair of wireless earbuds for your workouts, you also can’t go wrong with the predecessor to the Studio Buds, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/10/18563329/apple-powerbeats-pro-review-wireless-fitness-headphones-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Beats Powerbeats Pro&lt;/a&gt;. These earbuds have an over-ear hook that keeps them in place while exercising; they’re also IPX4 sweat- and water-resistant, so you don’t have to worry about ruining them should your workout get intense. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aryAiB"&gt;Currently, there are a few different discounts available for the Powerbeats Pro. The lowest we see right now is at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Powerbeats-Pro-Totally-Wireless-Earphones/dp/B088KTR418/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://goto.target.com/2rKXO0" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, which are selling the earphones in a handful of colorways for just under $150.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0RcdxX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10058925"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="11vDvx"&gt;Like their &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/29/20937559/amazon-echo-buds-wireless-earbuds-review-features-bose-noise-reduction-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;first-gen predecessor&lt;/a&gt;, the 2021 edition of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22432633/amazon-echo-buds-2021-review-features-specs-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Echo Buds&lt;/a&gt; are a great value. Amazon’s latest true wireless earbuds offer improved comfort and better noise cancellation, along with a terrific passthrough mode that ensures you can always hear what’s going on around you. The $120 earbuds also feature hands-free Alexa support and sound that’s remarkably satisfying, with more bass than the AirPods Pro and an appropriate amount of restraint when it comes to the high end. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cb3iGA"&gt;The second-gen Amazon Echo Buds are often discounted at most retailers. Currently, however, you can only get the latest Echo Buds with either the wired or wireless charging case at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/All-new-Echo-Buds/dp/B085WV7635?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfYSsVV4J8B" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; for $120, the full retail price. The same goes for the version with the wireless charging case, which are available for $140 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B085WTWYS4/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfWiFOTCoYJ" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. However, we should note that &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/All-new-Echo-Buds/dp/B085WV7635?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon offers an additional 25 percent discount&lt;/a&gt; if you trade in select devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PgPi8b"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10600144"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="lHzCNl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10861234"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="de2M6w"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22307388/wireless-earbuds-deals-airpods-galaxy-buds-powerbeats"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22307388/wireless-earbuds-deals-airpods-galaxy-buds-powerbeats</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-12T20:29:59-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-12T20:29:59-05:00</updated>
    <title>The best early Black Friday deals you can get right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1Ysdobu3Dq5hfr7-QRZnyVxadrk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70079139/Early_Black_Friday_Deals.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7vZvx2"&gt;Black Friday officially starts on November 26th, however, we’re already starting to see significant discounts on some of this year’s most popular pieces of tech. Starting in October, many retailers — including Amazon, Best Buy, Target, and Walmart — began lowering prices on goods ranging from Apple’s AirPods to LG’s C1 OLED as a part of their early Black Friday sales. The great news is these stores are now starting to drop prices even more aggressively as we approach the big day, and many of them &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570383/price-matching-policy-apple-google-microsoft"&gt;have price-matching policies&lt;/a&gt; that guarantee you’ll get the lowest price. Below we’ve compiled some of the best early Black Friday deals available so far, along with some information about upcoming Black Friday sales so you can prepare and score a great deal before it sells out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="noa6oq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to find the best deals during Black Friday and Cyber Monday 2021","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21587765/black-friday-cyber-monday-best-deals-how-to-find"},{"title":"Know the holiday shipping and return policies for Apple, Google, Microsoft, and others","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21570161/holiday-shipping-return-policy-apple-google-microsoft-amazon"},{"title":"The Verge Holiday Gift Guide 2021","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22759813/holiday-gift-guide-best-tech-gadget-unique-ideas"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="fUcNXl"&gt;Amazon Black Friday deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="wDZo4M"&gt;Amazon began publishing its Black Friday deals earlier than most retailers, launching mostly single-day sales starting on October 4th. So far, we’ve seen significant deals on Apple products, TVs from Samsung and Sony, Kindles, and more. The retailer continues to launch early Black Friday deals on its &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/events/earlyblackfriday"&gt;Early Black Friday deals event page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eOYFV4"&gt;Note that if you’re not already an Amazon Prime member, you can also save a little more money and enjoy two-day shipping when you sign up for a free, month-long trial of Prime. The membership will also give you access to Amazon’s Lightning deals, which are discounts that often only last for a few hours or a single day. After the trial ends, however, you’ll pay $13 a month — unless you’re a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-Student/b?ots=1&amp;amp;slotNum=3&amp;amp;imprToken=92bdf01b-6da1-28cb-387&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;node=668781011"&gt;student&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/58f8026f-0658-47d0-9752-f6fa2c69b2e2/qualify"&gt;receive qualifying government assistance&lt;/a&gt;, in which case you’ll pay either $6.49 or $6, respectively — so be aware of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lwMndD"&gt;Right now, Amazon is discounting all sizes of one of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22399437/best-gaming-tv-playstation5-ps5-xbox-series-x-s"&gt;best TVs for gaming&lt;/a&gt;, the LG C1, and throwing in a six-month subscription to HBO Max. The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08WFK81RH/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;48-inch model&lt;/a&gt; is on sale for $1,097 instead of $1,297, while the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/LG-OLED65C1PUB-Alexa-Built-Smart/dp/B08WFV7L3N/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;55-inch is selling for $1,297&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08WG4HKKY/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;65-inch for $1,797&lt;/a&gt;. Regardless of which configuration you choose, all sport several features gamers will love, including a 120Hz refresh rate, Dolby Vision HDR compatibility, and support for HDMI 2.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MqKN84"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10833105"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dfpgis"&gt;A great companion to any streamer or podcaster, the Blue Yeti microphone is on sale at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Blue-Yeti-USB-Microphone-Blackout/dp/B00N1YPXW2?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon for $100&lt;/a&gt;, matching one of its best prices to date. The Yeti can conform to a number of recording environments thanks to the Blue VO!CE software, which allows you to change pickup patterns, modulate, and otherwise fine-tune your audio. The mic comes packaged with its own stand but is also compatible with a wide variety of booms and mic arms if that's more your style. The current discount applies to the black, blue, grey, and silver models, meaning you’ve got a variety of styles to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XEhlAt"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10650797"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fDTpC7"&gt;Typically $400, Amazon is currently selling the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21345733/best-noise-canceling-headphones"&gt;best-sounding noise-canceling headphones&lt;/a&gt; for non-Apple users — the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08B3MJBW8/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sennheiser Momentum 3 Wireless&lt;/a&gt; — in white for $249. That’s one of the lowest prices Amazon has ever sold them for. As noted in our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/5/20843395/sennheiser-momentum-wireless-3-review-release-date-news-specs-features-noise-cancelling-headphones"&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;, we found that the comfortable headphones offer detailed, bass-rich sound while providing 17 hours of playback per charge. They even come outfitted with a USB-C port and a compact, foldable design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="aWXUjn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10361637"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="E5gVG7"&gt;Amazon is also discounting various sizes of Samsung’s The Frame, a unique kind of TV that functions both as wall art and an HDR-compatible QLED. Right now, for example, you can buy the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08VW898FS/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;65-inch model for $1,798&lt;/a&gt; instead of $2,000, and the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-55-Inch-Class-Frame-Built/dp/B08VWPBBTF/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;55-inch for $1,398&lt;/a&gt; instead of $1,500. The TV offers a decor-friendly design while also displaying customizable images when somebody’s in the room. When turned on, however, it transforms into a smart 4K TV with Amazon’s Alexa built-in and a 120Hz refresh rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jNcvZm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10711541"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qcHKiS"&gt;The latest Roku Streaming Stick 4K, which just launched in September, is selling at Amazon at a record low. Normally $50, the retailer is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09BKCDXZC/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;offering the streaming device for just $29&lt;/a&gt;. The 2021 model is faster, comes with improved Wi-Fi performance, and supports Dolby Vision and HDR10 Plus. Roku’s players also now support AirPlay 2, which means you can use your iPhone, iPad, or Mac to easily cast content to the device. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22727963/roku-streaming-stick-4k-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PuNKYt"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10828277"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DOJQiS"&gt;If you’re looking to add some storage space to your PC, Amazon is currently discounting Western Digital’s 2TB and 4TB My Passport models in a variety of colors. Typically $380, you can buy the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Passport-External-Portable-Drive-WDBAGF0020BGY-WESN/dp/B08F1VVBL9?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2TB SSD&lt;/a&gt; for $230, or the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Passport-External-Portable-Compatible-systems/dp/B08RX3TWJZ/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;4TB model&lt;/a&gt; for $550. Western Digital claims up to sequential read / write speeds of 1,050MB/s and 1,000MB/s, respectively, and the deal also includes a USB Type-A adapter in the box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GlKjia"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10371540"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="aubBFX"&gt;Other notable deals:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Dqr58c"&gt;Amazon is currently offering some &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/deal/4998f143?ots=1&amp;amp;slotNum=26&amp;amp;imprToken=c2be8a99-20b2-dfab-0c4&amp;amp;showVariations=true&amp;amp;ref=dlx_early_gd_dcl_img_8_4998f143_dt_sl5_f1&amp;amp;ascsubtag=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22541018%5Bt%5Dw%5Br%5Dtheverge.com/good-deals%5Bd%5DD"&gt;excellent savings on a variety of Shure microphones&lt;/a&gt;. These include some of the heavy-hitters of the podcast world, like the broadcast-quality SM7B and its newer offspring: the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Shure-Microphone-Podcasting-Voice-Isolating-Technology/dp/B08G7RG9ML?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MV7&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Shure-Microphone-Podcasting-Voice-Isolating-Technology/dp/B09BZZCGC8?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MV7X&lt;/a&gt;. All three mics are discounted, with, for example, the Shure SM7B going for $359 instead of $399 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Shure-SM7B-Cardioid-Dynamic-Microphone/dp/B0002E4Z8M?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wcr0Gl"&gt;Naturally, Amazon is also offering some great discounts on its own products, taking between $140 and $150 off the Omni Series (&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08T6F8YBH?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;50-inch&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08P3QVFMK?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;55-inch&lt;/a&gt;) and 4-Series 4K Fire TVs (&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/amazon-fire-tv-50-inch-4-series-4k-smart-tv/dp/B08SVZ775L?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;50-inch&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/amazon-fire-tv-50-inch-4-series-4k-smart-tv/dp/B08P3QB66R?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;55-inch&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="eAZDRm"&gt;Amazon is hosting a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/promotion/psp/A2NEKY0JEA1965"&gt;buy two, get one free promotion&lt;/a&gt; on a notable selection of books, movies, video games, and other products. Highlights include everything from Marvel’s &lt;em&gt;Black Widow &lt;/em&gt;and the latest Call of Duty title to the classic board game &lt;em&gt;Catan&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="u3IApI"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Wolverine-Gaming-Controller-Wireless-Headset-Bundle/dp/B08NGCT6B1?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Razer’s Wolverine V2 wired gaming controller&lt;/a&gt;, which is essentially an affordable version of the Xbox Elite controller, is on sale at Amazon as part of a bundle with a Kaira Pro gaming headset. Normally $250, you can pick up both peripherals for $190 for a limited time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9kKV5j"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Samsung-Chromebook-Celeron-Processor-Gigabit/dp/B07XL4JHXR?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung’s 11.6-inch Galaxy Chromebook 4&lt;/a&gt; is now on sale for $215 instead of $250 at Amazon. This particular model includes 4GB of RAM and 64GB of onboard storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="FfgzdG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Verge Deals on Twitter","description":"Join our over 40,000 followers, and keep up with our best daily tech deals with @vergedeals","label":"Follow us!","url":"http://bit.ly/2JzR5Ud"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="ejfdaH"&gt;Best Buy Black Friday deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="E7iGos"&gt;Best Buy started rolling out big savings in a number of categories on October 18th with Black Friday price protection, meaning the retailer will refund the price difference of any item with this guarantee if it drops before November 26th. While anyone can cash in on the current savings, the Black Friday price guarantee only applies to Best Buy Totaltech and My Best Buy members. Best Buy is also offering &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfZfEpiMWAR" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;free shipping&lt;/a&gt; on any purchase greater than $35, and same-day delivery is available in certain ZIP codes if you submit your order by 3PM local time. Restrictions apply to certain larger items, however, most of which will require you to schedule a delivery time after making your purchase. If you want to knock out some of your holiday shopping early this year, we’ve collected some of our favorite deals so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="DPV4yv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best laptop you can buy in 2021","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21250695/best-laptops"},{"title":"Best Buy stores will soon offer Samsung foldable repairs","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744407/best-buy-authorized-samsung-foldable-repairs"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="nl3yNN"&gt;Best Buy is offering the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfWewqARCyb" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;same discounts on LG’s C1 OLED&lt;/a&gt; as Amazon, while adding other perks in addition to the six-month subscription to HBO Max. These include 30 days of FuboTV Pro, as well as the option to save $90 on Facebook Portal TV, a camera accessory that brings wide-angle video chats directly to your TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="rzBPD3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10853257"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sFXHWz"&gt;As expected, Best Buy is also offering the same discounts as Amazon on a range of other products. For example, the retail giant is currently selling various sizes of &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfWeAej60sy" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The Frame&lt;/a&gt; at the same discounted prices as Amazon. However, Best Buy is also including 30 days of FuboTV Pro as well as the option to save $90 on Facebook Portal TV. Best Buy is even offering free delivery, much like Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qb4m6s"&gt;Moreover, Best Buy is currently selling &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1743035238017039291" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sony’s WF-1000XM4&lt;/a&gt;, our top pick for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;best wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt;, for $248 instead of $280. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22523584/sony-wf-1000xm4-wireless-earbuds-headphones-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="T59Y6S"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10847966"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="CO0Wc6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10600158"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="m_7721606980660150198sIzbeu"&gt;Right now, you can pick up the &lt;a href="https://link.theverge.com/click/25573468.9424/aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cudGhldmVyZ2UuY29tLzIxMzA5ODIwL2Jlc3Qtd2lyZWxlc3MtZWFyYnVkcw/60da2c65b2311314d2514a03B6ac3219c" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;best wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt; that iPhone owners can buy at an all-time low. Typically $249, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfWeHk1ZE7M" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; is currently selling the MagSafe-ready AirPods Pro for $220. Like the &lt;a href="https://link.theverge.com/click/25573468.9424/aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cudGhldmVyZ2UuY29tLzIyNzQ0Njg2L2FwcGxlLWFpcnBvZHMtdGhpcmQtZ2VuLXJldmlldw/60da2c65b2311314d2514a03Be70b5668" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;third-gen AirPods&lt;/a&gt;, the 2021 AirPods Pro come with a new charging case that &lt;a href="https://link.theverge.com/click/25573468.9424/aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cudGhldmVyZ2UuY29tLzIwMjEvMTAvMTgvMjI3MzMxODMvYXBwbGUtbWFnc2FmZS1jaGFyZ2luZy1jYXNlLWFpcnBvZHMtcHJvLXFp/60da2c65b2311314d2514a03Bd83707a1" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;works with Apple’s MagSafe magnetic charging system&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re interested in cheaper models, however, Best Buy is also discounting the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfWeKJeBIMt" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;second-gen AirPods&lt;/a&gt;, selling them for $130 instead of $160. &lt;a href="https://link.theverge.com/click/25573468.9424/aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cudGhldmVyZ2UuY29tLzIxMzA5ODIwL2Jlc3Qtd2lyZWxlc3MtZWFyYnVkcw/60da2c65b2311314d2514a03C6ac3219c" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our AirPods Pro review&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WUs7A8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10847972"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="c5Ol71"&gt;The Lenovo Yoga 9i remains one of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22687992/microsoft-surface-laptop-studio-pro-8-hp-spectre-macbook-air-creator-laptops-compare-specs" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;our favorite alternatives to the Microsoft Surface line of ultrabooks&lt;/a&gt; and, right now, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfThlWBLJhS" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy is offering the slick 2-in-1&lt;/a&gt; for $1,350. While this model received a similar discount a couple of months ago, it still remains a solid value. The foldable laptop boasts some impressive specs, too, with an 11th Gen Core i7 CPU, 512GB of storage, and Iris Xe integrated graphics. This hardware, paired with a 4K touchscreen display and a garaged stylus, makes the 9i a great choice for creators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nisc5P"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10689258"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mExVb6"&gt;This 70-inch LG TV may only feature midrange specs, but Best Buy has brought it down to its lowest price ever. The &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfTimnyrsb7" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;LG NanoCell 75 series TV is down to just $1,100&lt;/a&gt; for a limited time, a healthy $100 off the list price. The 4K panel is powered by LG’s WebOS smart platform, which offers a solid array of streaming services and includes HDR10 for vivid picture quality. The 75 Series also comes equipped with three HDMI ports and ARC compatibility, as well as Apple’s AirPlay 2, which allows you to cast content from your Apple device to your TV. It may not be as impressive as an OLED TV, but $1,100 for a 70-inch panel is still a solid value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="tL6nXD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10835005"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="LReI5f"&gt;A few other hot deals at Best Buy:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="wxld6d"&gt;Google’s lozenge-shaped Nest Mini is &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfTkAfStZ60" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available for $25 at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, half off the original price tag. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/21/20921173/google-nest-mini-echo-dot-assistant-smart-speaker-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;In his review&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;staffer Cameron Faulkner called the smart speaker a great sounding upgrade over the last-gen Home Mini.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AhcBZ8"&gt;This 38-inch soundbar from Samsung is &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfTkK7MFOaD" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently available for $280 at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, its lowest price to date. The 7.1 soundbar comes packaged with a wireless subwoofer and rear-channel speakers, too, helping keep cable clutter to a minimum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qpKNCt"&gt;The Fitbit Charge 5 is on sale at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfZdTHWvNft" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; for $130 instead of $180, its lowest price to date. We praised the tracker’s marathon battery life and color display in our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22680300/fitbit-charge-5-review-fitness-tracker" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;review,&lt;/a&gt; however, we also felt frustrated with its software and lack of physical buttons. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="wijGQu"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="OWSS8m"&gt;B&amp;amp;H launched its annual holiday sale, which includes early Black Friday and Cyber Monday deals, earlier this week, slashing prices on everything from cameras to Apple products. B&amp;amp;H also has an extended return policy for the holidays. Any purchases you make from the site from now through January 2, 2022, can be returned or exchanged through February 1, 2022. The retailer will continue to add new items to its &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fholiday-shopping%2Fdeals&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22759214%2Fblack-friday-early-deals-best-headphones-laptops-gaming-tvs-tech-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;”Holiday Head Start” page&lt;/a&gt; leading up to Black Friday, but you can also check out some of the most notable deals below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7OxW8A"&gt;First and foremost, if you need a powerful iPad with plenty of storage and a gorgeous display, B&amp;amp;H is selling the Wi-Fi version of the latest &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1636230-REG%2Fapple_mhnh3ll_a_12_9_ipad_pro_wifi.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22759214%2Fblack-friday-early-deals-best-headphones-laptops-gaming-tvs-tech-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;12.9-inch iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt; with 256GB of storage for its lowest price to date. Normally $1,199, the retailer is selling it for $1,099 for a limited time. &lt;a href="https://link.theverge.com/click/25603205.13772/aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cudGhldmVyZ2UuY29tLzIyNDQyMDg0L2lwYWQtcHJvLTIwMjEtcmV2aWV3LWZlYXR1cmVzLXNjcmVlbi1taW5pLWxlZC1tMS1wcm9jZXNzb3I/60ca3952dba83e591470a57aB376c5282" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;In Dieter Bohn’s review&lt;/a&gt;, he deemed this model to be the nicest iPad available, even with its strange camera placement. The 2021 iPad Pro is also a speed demon thanks to Apple’s M1 chip, and comes with welcome features such as a Mini LED display, Thunderbolt connectivity, Wi-Fi 6 support, and Face ID, which allows you to unlock the device with just a glance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3zmNuJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10848332"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6WQkzQ"&gt;The latest GoPro, the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1658382-REG%2Fgopro_chdhx_101_hero10_black.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22759214%2Fblack-friday-early-deals-best-headphones-laptops-gaming-tvs-tech-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GoPro Hero10 Black&lt;/a&gt;, is currently selling at its lowest price ever. Normally $500, B&amp;amp;H is now selling the popular action cam for $450. The Hero10 Black boasts all the amazing features found on its predecessor — which we once called the “biggest, baddest action camera out there” — and more, like a new processor that allows it to shoot in higher frame rates and upload videos to the cloud while charging. It’s also compatible with Hero9 accessories, meaning those looking to upgrade won’t necessarily need to purchase new add-ons. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22675560/gopro-hero10-action-camera-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="AuzgvG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10848365"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="yD4GfA"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo is starting to release several deals on cameras from Sony, Canon, Nikon, Olympus, Fujifilm, Panasonic, and more. This includes the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1670051-REG%2Fcanon_canon_eos_r_mirrorless.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22759214%2Fblack-friday-early-deals-best-headphones-laptops-gaming-tvs-tech-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Canon EOS R mirrorless camera&lt;/a&gt;, which is selling for $1,599 instead of $1,800. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/30/18200083/nikon-z7-z6-canon-eos-r-full-frame-mirrorless-camera-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our Canon EOS R review.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZZr7KF"&gt;Sony’s ZV-1 point-and-shoot camera is currently &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1566753-REG%2Fsony_sony_zv_1_digital_camera.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22759214%2Fblack-friday-early-deals-best-headphones-laptops-gaming-tvs-tech-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on sale for $746&lt;/a&gt; with a vlogger accessory kit at B&amp;amp;H, a savings of $150. The bundle includes the 20MP, 4K-capable camera as well as a wireless shooting grip and a 64GB memory card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="L8hVRE"&gt;Dell Black Friday Deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="chwtCT"&gt;The home computer experts at Dell have started rolling out sales ahead of the shopping holiday, and while it naturally includes laptops, there are also plenty of deals to be had on desktops, headphones, and other accessories. Dell will likely have more to offer on Black Friday but has been releasing a steady drip of deals as part of a &lt;a href="https://www.dpbolvw.net/click-8836602-12105225?url=https%3A%2F%2Fdeals.dell.com%2Fen-us%2Fmember" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;sneak peek&lt;/a&gt; we’ll be highlighting here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DiX1hd"&gt;Just about anything you buy on the Dell website comes with free shipping, though, delivery times can vary based on the product. If you’re pressed for time, however, Dell does offer a number of expedited shipping options in addition to a delivery estimate based on your ZIP code. If you’re not happy with your purchase, Dell has kept its standard return policy in place, which affords you 30 days upon receipt, with a potential 15 percent restocking fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Jv2SvB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best laptops to buy in 2021","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21250695/best-laptops"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="eNqjUh"&gt;First off, the Dell XPS 15 ultrabook is currently enjoying a solid discount. &lt;a href="https://www.dpbolvw.net/click-8836602-14349898?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dell.com%2Fen-us%2Fwork%2Fshop%2Fcty%2Fpdp%2Fspd%2Fxps-15-9510-laptop%2Fsmx15w11p1c6700p%3Fpreview%3Doff" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Dell has reduced the price of this particular configuration to $2,199&lt;/a&gt;, taking $396 off the usual price tag. This is the best deal we’ve seen on this laptop so far, with some retailers charging as much as $2,600 for the same configuration. This model boasts some impressive specs with an 11th Gen Core i9 CPU and an RTX 3050 Ti graphics card, not to mention 32GB of RAM and a 1TB SSD. Our reviewer, Monica Chin, liked the 16:10 display and snappy keyboard, even though the XPS 15 tended to get a little hot under load. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21296277/dell-xps-15-2020-review-design-specs-price-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our full review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="G5or8D"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10842148"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vAdouM"&gt;The latest model of the Dell XPS 13 takes what made last year’s model so great, and makes it better. During its Black Friday sale, &lt;a href="https://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8836602-12578053?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dell.com%2Fen-us%2Fwork%2Fshop%2Fdell-laptops-and-notebooks%2Fxps-13-laptop%2Fspd%2Fxps-13-9310-laptop%2Fsmx13w11p2c3100p" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Dell has marked down this configuration to $1,369&lt;/a&gt;, taking about $260 off the regular MSRP. While not quite the same configuration, aforementioned reviewer Monica Chin described the Dell XPS 13 as the company’s “best-in-class 13-inch ultraportable laptop.” This particular configuration comes equipped with an Intel Core i7-1195G7, 16GB of RAM, and a 512GB SSD. While the integrated Iris Xe GPU doesn’t have enough juice for gaming, this lightweight laptop is remarkably versatile and remains a powerful choice in the 13-inch laptop class. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/21310825" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TALLIn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10845789"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="xgjs1u"&gt;Target Black Friday deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="VmdQS9"&gt;Target began releasing some of its first Black Friday deals on October 10th and has been running similar deals every week since. The retail store also officially launched its weekly &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/1187778/2092?subId1=VergeEarlyBlackFridaySales111221&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fc%2Ftop-deals%2F-%2FN-4xw74" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;“Holiday Best” deals&lt;/a&gt; on October 31st, which run every Sunday online and in-store. Target will also be price matching items purchased between October 10th and December 24th &lt;a href="https://help.target.com/help/subcategoryarticle?childcat=Price+Match+Guarantee&amp;amp;parentcat=Policies+%26+Guidelines&amp;amp;searchQuery=search+help" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;with some exclusions&lt;/a&gt;. With all that said, below are some notable deals we already know will take place in the next few weeks that you should keep an eye out for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="RjbN8y"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best noise-canceling headphones to buy right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21345733/best-noise-canceling-headphones"},{"title":"The best cheap wireless earbuds to buy in 2021","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21575716/best-cheap-wireless-earbuds-budget"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="kGsRxP"&gt;Probably the best deal Target has going for it right now is its &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/1187777/2092?subId1=VergeBestEarlyBlackFridayDeals111121&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fc%2Fbuy-2-get-1-free-mix-match%2F-%2FN-93tfb" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Mix and Match sale&lt;/a&gt;, which allows you to buy two items from an approved list and get a third for free. The list of items the sale covers is robust, and includes everything from board games, to craft supplies, to some of the latest video games. If you can think of a faster way to fill your stockings this holiday, we’d like to hear it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CcA5Vj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10860156"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="agQ676"&gt;Regularly $300, Target is also currently selling the &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fbose-quietcomfort-35-noise-cancelling-wireless-headphones-ii%2F-%2FA-52955552&amp;amp;subid1=VergeEarlyBlackFriday111221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Bose QuietComfort 35 Noise Canceling Wireless Headphones II&lt;/a&gt; for $180 through the end of today. If you miss out on the deal, Target will likely still be selling it for $200, as it has been doing since launching its holiday sales earlier this month. Released in 2017, these wireless, noise-canceling headphones can seamlessly switch between two paired devices and, unlike their predecessor, support both Alexa and Google Assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="QWrlAQ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10833603"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aNi8WR"&gt;Apple’s discontinued &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/1141873/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fbeats-solo-wireless-headphones%2F-%2FA-79437096&amp;amp;subid1=VergeEarlyBlackFridayDeals111221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Beats Solo 3&lt;/a&gt; are on sale for $100 right now, $100 off the original price tag. Although they’re beginning to show their age, we initially praised the comfortable headphones in our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/12/22/14051984/beats-solo-3-review-apple-headphones" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2016 review&lt;/a&gt; and noted how well they isolate exterior noise. They also offer great wireless performance and come in two colorways: black and rose gold. Target’s current discount was supposed to expire on November 6th, however, it remains active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CRz9fL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10757348"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6bMV4g"&gt;If you’re looking for a solid gaming mouse, the latest iteration of the Razer Viper is &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Frazer-viper-8-khz-ambidextrous-wired-optical-gaming-mouse-8000-hz-polling-rate%2F-%2FA-82718043&amp;amp;subid1=VergeEarlyBlackFriday111221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on sale at Target for $50&lt;/a&gt;, its lowest price to date. The latest model retains the same lightweight and ambidextrous chassis that made the original so good, but ups the ante with a 20K DPI sensor and a polling rate of 8000Hz. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Ey6aVw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10859951"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="G60grT"&gt;Other notable Target deals:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="1BiPh2"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fhp-15-6-34-laptop-with-windows-home-in-s-mode-intel-core-i3-11th-gen-processor-8gb-ram-memory-256gb-ssd-storage-silver-15-dy2035tg%2F-%2FA-82457999&amp;amp;subid1=VergeEarlyBlackFriday111221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;HP’s 15.6-inch laptop with Windows Home in S. Mode&lt;/a&gt; is on sale at Target for $430 instead of $540. This particular model features 8GB RAM, a 256GB SSD, and an Intel 11th Gen Core i3 processor. Like the Beats Solo 3 deal, the discount was supposed to expire on November 7th, meaning its duration is up in the air.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="h64IP9"&gt;Walmart Black Friday deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="zULrcm"&gt;The big blue supercenter recently revealed its vertical for its Black Friday deals, which began November 3rd online and November 5th in stores. While some of these deals will remain live until November 17th, some of them expire soon. Wherever possible, we’ve noted the window of specific deals so you’ll know exactly when to jump on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NTwNOz"&gt;Like most online retailers, Walmart offers free two-day shipping on orders over $35, as well as next-day delivery in certain ZIP codes at no extra charge. As an additional perk, Walmart has also extended its standard return policy during the holiday season, with many items purchased between November 1st and December 25 receiving extended return dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MmpJFc"&gt;Below, we’ve collected a handful of deals that piqued our interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Q59sms"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best deals on true wireless earbuds right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22307388/wireless-earbuds-deals-airpods-galaxy-buds-powerbeats"},{"title":"The best wireless earbuds to buy right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="g565Bi"&gt;Right now, you can grab Apple’s second-gen AirPods at &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/994132/9383?subId1=VergeBestAirPods030121&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https://www.walmart.com/ip/Apple-AirPods-with-Charging-Case-Latest-Model/604342441?&amp;amp;veh=aff&amp;amp;subId2=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22538272%5Bt%5Dw%5Br%5Dtheverge.com/good-deals%5Bd%5DD" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart for just $89&lt;/a&gt;, matching their lowest price to date. This model typically costs around $120, however, it includes the wired charging case as opposed to the Qi- or MagSafe-compatible version. The second iteration of Apple’s ubiquitous white earbuds weren’t a massive step forward compared to their predecessor either, but our reviewer was still happy with their wireless performance and overall reliability. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our full review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vHxLrh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wDwLVX"&gt;The Samsung Galaxy Buds Plus, the improved version of the original Galaxy Buds, are &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSAMSUNG-Galaxy-Buds-Cosmic-Black-Charging-Case-Included%2F255407922" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available at Walmart for $79&lt;/a&gt;. This deal brings them well below their typical $100 price tag, making them an excellent value. In &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/24/21147654/samsung-galaxy-buds-plus-review-wireless-earbuds-sound-quality-battery-life" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;our review&lt;/a&gt;, we noted their drastic improvement in battery life as well as their comfortable fit. While Samsung has since improved on this design with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22619305/samsung-galaxy-buds-2-review-specs-price-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Galaxy Buds 2&lt;/a&gt;, adding noise cancellation among other features, the higher price point makes them a slightly tougher sell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qzr2Kf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10368022"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DJDOSq"&gt;The GoPro Hero8 Black often retails for $300 on its own, but &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FGoPro-HERO8-Black-Dual-Battery-Charger-Bonus-Battery%2F199369934&amp;amp;subid1=VergeEarlyBlackFriday111221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart will be offering a bundle that includes the popular 4K action cam for just $249&lt;/a&gt; through November 14th. The bundle also includes a dual battery charger and a total of three batteries, so you’ll never run out of juice. This rugged digital camera is perfectly suited for capturing fast-moving action wherever and whenever it happens. The HyperSmooth technology provides an amazing level of image stabilization, while the LiveBurst feature automatically records anything that happens two seconds before and two seconds after your shot. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/1/20891984/gopro-hero8-black-review-action-camera-image-stabilization-price-specs-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our full review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="q7R0XL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10319874"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NwKlAu"&gt;One of our favorite budget tablets from last year just got a little cheaper. The Samsung Galaxy Tab A7 is &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSAMSUNG-Galaxy-Tab-A7-32GB-10-4-Wi-Fi-Gray-SM-T500NZABXAR%2F882296471&amp;amp;subid1=VergeEarlyBlackFriday111221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on sale at Walmart for $139&lt;/a&gt; through November 14th. This brings it well below the lowest price we’ve seen for this particular model, which features 32GB of internal storage and a 10.4-inch display. In &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22150980/samsung-galaxy-tab-a7-tablet-review-price-specs-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;our review&lt;/a&gt;, we noted how impressed we were with the vibrant display and sturdy build quality of this unassuming tablet. It’s not going to rival, say, the latest iPad Air or Mini, but it remains a solid entertainment device, especially if you plan to consume Amazon content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="k2O7Rx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9581085"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="DC2Mly"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="zAwjwU"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22759214/black-friday-early-deals-best-headphones-laptops-gaming-tvs-tech-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22759214/black-friday-early-deals-best-headphones-laptops-gaming-tvs-tech-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-12T19:59:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-12T19:59:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Nvidia’s GeForce Now has been quietly capping its founders’ frame rates</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Nvidia geforce now chromebook on a table next to flowers" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lpNVU0_fMhJhzn0fqUHdxMGysAs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70135399/cfaulkner_200817_4151_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pkvQQ3"&gt;Nvidia’s GeForce Now cloud gaming service &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22750246/nvidia-geforce-now-rtx-3080-google-stadia-cloud-gaming"&gt;just leapfrogged Google Stadia in performance&lt;/a&gt;, with a new $200-a-year tier that practically gives you the power of an RTX 3080 desktop graphics card in the cloud. But if you’re grandfathered into the original $4.99 a month “Founders” tier, or pay $100 a year for “Priority” access, you may not be getting &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; what you expected — because Nvidia has quietly revealed it’s capping the frame rates of 12 specific games to ensure consistent performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hh1pm1"&gt;Nvidia now has &lt;a href="https://nvidia.custhelp.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/5260/"&gt;an official support page&lt;/a&gt; (via &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/11/12/geforce-now-60fps-streaming-block/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) explaining the practice, after &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GeForceNOW/comments/qn6djd/premium_users_are_no_longer_guaranteed_60fps_and/"&gt;Redditors&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nme.com/news/gaming-news/geforce-now-appears-to-lock-some-in-game-frame-rates-below-60-3090271"&gt;others&lt;/a&gt; revealed that a variety of games were locked to frame rates lower than 60fps. It appears that Nvidia’s been doing this for quite a while but only for a handful of demanding games. I did a little searching, and &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GeForceNOW/comments/kb76cw/cyberpunk_2077_60fps_troubles/"&gt;some people were already complaining&lt;/a&gt; about being locked to 45fps in &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077 &lt;/em&gt;in December 2020, just as Nvidia admits here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yI46Qv"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Assassin’s Creed Odyssey &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Immortals Fenyx Rising&lt;/em&gt; are the other games that have sub-50fps frame rates, while others run a bit higher. Here’s the full list of games where frame rates are being limited:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lKbzWM0qHSTc95V-HTSl9-s6efY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23010332/geforce_now_capped_framerate.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7dPxxO"&gt;While it’s not a good look for Nvidia to retroactively reveal something like this, the company says the vast majority of games do run at 60fps or higher, and it does have an explanation for the limits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="V0NvFY"&gt;For our Priority Members, the maximum frames rendered per second is generally set to 60, or higher, for most of the 1,100+ games we’ve onboarded so far. There are some exceptions that we determined do not run well enough at 60 FPS on the GPUs used by Priority members. So the default OPS for these specific graphics-intensive games cannot be overridden. This is to ensure all Priority members are running a consistent, high-quality experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="OKei30"&gt;I just find it a little strange that Nvidia chose to impose this instead of giving its users the choice between frame rate and graphical quality — even many PlayStation and Xbox console games allow you to choose. But I suppose part of cloud gaming’s pitch is that it can be more frictionless. Maybe you don’t want to think about graphical settings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="drE9Ni"&gt;Nvidia tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that its RTX 3080 tier doesn’t currently have any framerate caps, but kept open the possibility that it might add some someday: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="JcEpfS"&gt;We currently do not cap frame rates on RTX 3080 tier because of the performance gains over the previous generation server. While we do not foresee needing to do this in the future, it is impossible to anticipate the demands of unreleased games and the impact they might have on the server hardware.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Ld8Ne6"&gt;In a briefing last month, GeForce Now boss Phil Eisler promised that the 3080 tier would be a different class of experience. “With the 3080 tier, it’s exclusive access to 3080 — every time you play, you get a 3080, even if you’re running at 300 frames per second.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3c1Rgv"&gt;That’s not true of GeForce Now’s free tier, which can use virtual GPU techniques to split one physical GPU in the cloud between two users. That can make the service more cost-effective. Nvidia wasn’t able to immediately answer whether its mid-range Priority tier ever splits a GPU in two. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="85mkyQ"&gt;By the way, if you’re a founder and do want to upgrade to the RTX 3080 tier, you don’t lose your “founders for life” benefit, even if you decide to switch back later, so long as you keep paying. Nvidia addresses this extensively &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-us%2Fgeforce-now%2Ffaq%2F%23founders-memberships&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F11%2F12%2F22778693%2Fnvidia-geforce-now-cloud-gaming-framerate-cap-fps-cyberpunk" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;in an FAQ&lt;/a&gt;. You’ll be paying a &lt;em&gt;lot &lt;/em&gt;more for that tier, of course, but there is a 10 percent discount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CbtF77"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, 7:59PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added Nvidia’s comments on whether the new RTX 3080 tier might see capped framerates, and a mention of the founders for life benefit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22778693/nvidia-geforce-now-cloud-gaming-framerate-cap-fps-cyberpunk"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22778693/nvidia-geforce-now-cloud-gaming-framerate-cap-fps-cyberpunk</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-12T19:54:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-12T19:54:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>AMC Theaters now lets you buy movie tickets with Bitcoin</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yFuYmZ7huXxb82kvwe5cF5KEKa4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70136071/acastro_210813_1777_amc_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Y7XG7N"&gt;AMC Theaters, which is perhaps &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465198/amc-meme-stock-popcorn-wsb"&gt;the king of the memestocks&lt;/a&gt;, promised in August that you’d be able to pay for tickets and concessions &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22617594/amc-bitcoin-memestock-apple-google-pay"&gt;with Bitcoin by the end of the year&lt;/a&gt;, and now, you can do just that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qHInOl"&gt;Bitcoin isn’t the only cryptocurrency you’ll be able to use; AMC is also accepting Ethereum, Bitcoin Cash, and Litecoin for online purchases, according to a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CEOAdam/status/1458974884609019916?s=20"&gt;tweet from CEO Adam Aron&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/amc-theatres-debuts-online-bitcoin-payments-after-months-of-teasing"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;CoinTelegraph&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). He also says you can pay online with Apple Pay, Google Pay, and PayPal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="oLjSW3"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Big newsflash! As promised, many new ways NOW to pay online at AMC.  We proudly now accept: drumroll, please… Bitcoin, Ethereum, Bitcoin Cash, Litecoin. Also Apple Pay, Google Pay, PayPal. Incredibly, they already account for 14% of our total online transactions! Dogecoin next. &lt;a href="https://t.co/a7pqYBm7HB"&gt;pic.twitter.com/a7pqYBm7HB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Adam Aron (@CEOAdam) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CEOAdam/status/1458974884609019916?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 12, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SxeJGP"&gt;Note that Aron only highlights payment methods for &lt;em&gt;online&lt;/em&gt; purchases, so it doesn’t sound like you can use crypto to buy anything in-person at a theater. Aron also says the new payment methods “already account for 14 percent of our total online transactions,” but it’s not clear if that number refers to cryptocurrencies or is inclusive of all of the methods listed in his tweet. AMC didn’t immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xFhDxw"&gt;I don’t own cryptocurrency, so I can’t personally verify how to use it to buy things online with AMC. However, at checkout on AMC’s website, PayPal is listed as a payment method with the note that it “supports cryptocurrencies.” Presumably, that means you’ll have to log in with your PayPal account and select any cryptocurrency that’s accessible there to pay for tickets or concessions. PayPal appears to be the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; way to pay with cryptocurrency at AMC for the moment, so if you would prefer to use a different method, you might be out of luck right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kM1Jul"&gt;And if you want to pay with Dogecoin? That’s “next,” Aron says. The company is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22771149/amc-shiba-inu-cryptocurrency-bitcoin-litecoin-dogecoin"&gt;exploring the Shiba Inu cryptocurrency, too&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22779137/amc-theaters-movie-tickets-cryptocurrency-bitcoin-cash-ethereum-litecoin"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22779137/amc-theaters-movie-tickets-cryptocurrency-bitcoin-cash-ethereum-litecoin</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-12T18:47:34-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-12T18:47:34-05:00</updated>
    <title>Some Echo speakers can now detect people</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dKV6CuAXYYkgZ-rGRmE8z-0P_ZA=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70135910/dseifert_201025_4263_00014.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Echo Dot speakers just got the ability to detect if there’s motion in a room.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jVWbWu"&gt;Starting this week, newer Echo and Echo Dot speakers can use ultrasound to detect occupancy in your home and turn on and off other connected devices such as lights or your Fire TV. First mentioned at &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22690309/amazon-fall-hardware-event-rumors-news-announcements"&gt;Amazon’s fall hardware event in September&lt;/a&gt;, the Echo and Echo Dot fourth-gen speakers can now emit an “inaudible ultrasound wave” to detect if there are people present in a room. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eZGbWQ"&gt;You can enable or disable this feature in the Alexa app, where you can also set up occupancy routines to use this new capability to do things like turn on lights when you enter a room and then off again when the room is empty. You could also have Alexa play music or a radio station when motion is detected near an Echo device during a set time and then shut down the tunes once you’ve left. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A5SIZP"&gt;The function is listed under Motion Detection in the Alexa app settings for each compatible Echo device, and here you can toggle the capability on or off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AvGf8a"&gt;This feature is similar to the motion-sensing newer Echo Show devices have, but those rely on their cameras to tell if there are people in the room. The Echo speakers don’t have cameras, so instead, the device detects movement by emitting an inaudible ultrasound wave that reflects off nearby objects before traveling back to the device’s microphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Lpikc"&gt;Google also uses &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/googlenest/answer/9509981?hl=en#zippy=%2Cnest-wifi-point%2Cgoogle-nest-displays"&gt;ultrasound in its Nest smart displays&lt;/a&gt; and Nest Mini speakers to detect how close a person is to the display or speaker and offer up different interfaces. For example, on the Mini speakers, it will show volume controls. Currently, you can’t use ultrasound sensing to trigger Google Home Routines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jjG28x"&gt;There are a number of stand-alone motion sensors that work with Alexa to trigger Routines — including those made by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/16/21289352/philips-hue-brighter-bulb-a21-announced-price-lightstrip-bloom-lamp"&gt;Philips Hue&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22523877/aqara-smart-home-review-m2-hub-homekit-alexa-google-assistant"&gt;Aqara&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Centralite-Motion-Sensor-SmartThings-platforms/dp/B0713STYJQ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Centralite&lt;/a&gt;. This new function means that, in theory, you won’t need to rely on one of these extra gadgets to turn on your lights or music. It also furthers Amazon’s vision of the ambient smart home, one where your home responds automatically to its occupants with minimal prompts from them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v3zZD3"&gt;To get here, however, Amazon will need to put some more effort into the Alexa app. Setting up Routines to turn lights on at the correct brightness based on time of day then off again when the room is empty still requires a lot of patience and a fair amount of technical know-how.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22779044/amazon-echo-speakers-ultrasound-people-detection"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22779044/amazon-echo-speakers-ultrasound-people-detection</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-12T18:14:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-12T18:14:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>Meta CTO thinks bad metaverse moderation could pose an ‘existential threat’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Vpg8FjV1PqnjoxyiOYZwDWuiAl4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70135736/acastro_211101_1777_meta_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5OBRem"&gt;Meta (formerly Facebook) CTO Andrew Bosworth warned employees that creating safe virtual reality experiences was a vital part of its business plan — but also potentially impossible at a large scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PUhkiC"&gt;In an internal memo &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/d72145b7-5e44-446a-819c-51d67c5471cf?utm_source=dlvr.it&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter"&gt;seen by &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Bosworth apparently said he wanted Meta virtual worlds to have “almost Disney levels of safety,” although spaces from third-party developers could have looser standards than directly Meta-built content. Harassment or other toxic behavior could pose an “existential threat” to the company’s plans for an embodied future internet if it turned mainstream consumers off VR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R4tgCu"&gt;At the same time, Bosworth said policing user behavior “at any meaningful scale is practically impossible.” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MsHannahMurphy/status/1459221091553984512"&gt;&lt;em&gt;FT&lt;/em&gt; reporter Hannah Murphy later tweeted&lt;/a&gt; that Bosworth was citing &lt;a href="https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20191111/23032743367/masnicks-impossibility-theorem-content-moderation-scale-is-impossible-to-do-well.shtml"&gt;Masnick’s Impossibility Theorem&lt;/a&gt;: a maxim, coined by &lt;em&gt;Techdirt&lt;/em&gt; founder Mike Masnick, that says “content moderation at scale is impossible to do well.” (Masnick’s writing notes that this isn’t an argument against pushing for better moderation, but large systems will “always end up frustrating very large segments of the population.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="fx5Xdq"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Virtual worlds could have “a stronger bias towards enforcement”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YffEMr"&gt;Bosworth apparently suggests that Meta could moderate spaces like its Horizon Worlds VR platform using a stricter version of its existing community rules, saying VR or metaverse moderation could have “a stronger bias towards enforcement along some sort of spectrum of warning, successively longer suspensions, and ultimately expulsion from multi-user spaces.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5rHUng"&gt;While the full memo isn’t publicly available, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=43993&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oculus.com%2Fblog%2Fkeeping-people-safe-in-vr-and-beyond%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Bosworth posted a blog entry alluding to it&lt;/a&gt; later in the day. The post, titled “Keeping people safe in VR and beyond,” references several of Meta’s existing VR moderation tools. That includes letting people block other users in VR, as well as an &lt;a href="https://www.roadtovr.com/facebook-horizon-privacy-monitoring-moderation/"&gt;extensive Horizon surveillance system&lt;/a&gt; for monitoring and reporting bad behavior. Meta has also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696578/facebook-metaverse-ar-vr-fund-research-definition"&gt;pledged $50 million for research&lt;/a&gt; into practical and ethical issues around its metaverse plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="szeAl2"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;FT&lt;/em&gt; notes, Meta’s older platforms like Facebook and Instagram have been castigated for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22740969/facebook-files-papers-frances-haugen-whistleblower-civic-integrity"&gt;serious moderation failures&lt;/a&gt;, including slow and inadequate responses to content that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/3/22707860/facebook-whistleblower-leaked-documents-files-regulation"&gt;promoted hate and incited violence&lt;/a&gt;. The company’s recent rebranding offers a potential fresh start, but as the memo notes, VR and virtual worlds will likely face an entirely new set of problems on top of existing issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HNiHg5"&gt;“We often have frank conversations internally and externally about the challenges we face, the trade-offs involved, and the potential outcomes of our work,” Bosworth wrote in the blog post. “There are tough societal and technical problems at play, and we grapple with them daily.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22779006/meta-facebook-cto-andrew-bosworth-memo-metaverse-disney-safety-content-moderation-scale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22779006/meta-facebook-cto-andrew-bosworth-memo-metaverse-disney-safety-content-moderation-scale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-12T18:08:52-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-12T18:08:52-05:00</updated>
    <title>Metaverse, schmetaverse — take me to the Icelandverse</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TXrmnx6L6jLQ2WHMiNFhkXup5cY=/52x0:2454x1601/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70135710/Screen_Shot_2021_11_12_at_2.45.46_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Icelandverse looks great.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Inspired by Iceland&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5L2QA5"&gt;Mark Zuckerberg’s extensive video about Facebook / Meta’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22745234/facebook-new-name-meta-metaverse-zuckerberg-rebrand"&gt;pivot to the metaverse&lt;/a&gt; has become &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/facebook-changes-name-to-meta-the-funniest-memes-and-jokes/"&gt;something of a meme&lt;/a&gt;, but perhaps the best parody of the presentation was done this week by, of all places, the country of Iceland. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jz0Jrn"&gt;In a nearly two-and-a-half-minute video, a man who is identified as Chief Visionary Officer Zack Mossbergsson begins a discussion about “a revolutionary approach on how to connect our world without being super weird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="azgmCF"&gt;“Some said it’s not possible,” he continues. “Some said it’s out of reach. To them, we say, it’s already here.” He then gestures in the general direction of a beautiful, snow-covered Icelandic landscape that stretches as far as the eye can see. “Seriously, look, it’s right here.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ma0fKF"&gt;The rest of the video is a hilarious pitch for the “Icelandverse,” which he describes as an “enhanced, actual reality without silly-looking headsets.” I don’t want to spoil much more, but expect a lot of beautiful shots of Iceland and some corny but good jokes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GfHIBH"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Some said an open-world experience this immersive wasn’t possible. But it’s already here. And you don’t even need silly VR headsets. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Introducing, ✨Icelandverse✨&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/icelandverse?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#icelandverse&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/b1cf1REKl9"&gt;pic.twitter.com/b1cf1REKl9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Inspired by Iceland (@iceland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/iceland/status/1458757245441822731?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="f1Gedi"&gt;The thing is, even though this is a parody, it’s actually an &lt;em&gt;incredible&lt;/em&gt; sales pitch for the country of Iceland. Which makes sense, as the video was made by an organization &lt;a href="https://www.inspiredbyiceland.com/about/"&gt;whose mission is to promote the country&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g8eo2i"&gt;Metaverse, schmetaverse. I’m ready to go to the Icelandverse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VcCicm"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/11/12/22778984/facebook-meta-metaverse-parody-video-iceland-icelandverse"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/11/12/22778984/facebook-meta-metaverse-parody-video-iceland-icelandverse</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-12T17:16:06-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-12T17:16:06-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google says a fix is coming for update that erased major Pixel 6 feature</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qAZ-1KCcusee49erWj4-_sIKw1Q=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70135494/akrales_211022_4802_0839.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SX3YdU"&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/thread/135090859/magic-eraser-was-there-to-use-until-this-morning-now-gone-%F0%9F%A4%B7%E2%80%8D%E2%99%80%EF%B8%8F?hl=en"&gt;reports from some users&lt;/a&gt;, an update to Google Photos removed one of the Pixel 6’s big features: the Magic Eraser tool that lets you remove unwanted objects or people from your photos. If your Pixel downloaded the affected version (5.67, &lt;a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/google-magically-erases-magic-eraser-latest-google-photos-update"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Android Central&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), fear not: Google says it’s working on a fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rj0Dcp"&gt;While the version of Photos with the Magic Eraser erased doesn’t appear to be available in the Play Store anymore, its &lt;a href="https://www.apkmirror.com/apk/google-inc/photos/"&gt;presence on APK Mirror&lt;/a&gt; confirms that it was at one point (though we wouldn’t recommend downloading it). According to one user, the broken version displayed a tip about the object removal feature, despite it no longer being accessible in the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="iaijh6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Google says a fix is coming&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fSbyUs"&gt;Google spokesperson Alex Moriconi told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the company “identified an issue early in the rollout of [its] latest Photos update and are providing a fix shortly.” Google also says that the issue didn’t affect everyone, which reflects our experience — two &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; staff with Pixel 6s said that they didn’t have any Google Photos updates available and that they were still able to use Magic Eraser. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3viRbA"&gt;While it seems like the update is no longer spreading, it’s still understandable why the users that got it would be shocked to find Magic Eraser missing — it was one of &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/8YiEmekf_34?t=114"&gt;Google’s main selling points&lt;/a&gt; when it launched the phone around a month ago. Plus, the missing feature being designed to delete things adds dramatic irony, as &lt;em&gt;Android Central&lt;/em&gt;’s “Google magically erases Magic Eraser” headline pokes fun at. Given the relatively small number of posts about the issue, though, it hopefully won’t affect you too much. If it does, keep your eyes peeled for an update to Google Photos; help is apparently on the way. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22778869/google-pixel-6-pro-magic-eraser-feature-gone-photos-update-fix"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22778869/google-pixel-6-pro-magic-eraser-feature-gone-photos-update-fix</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-12T16:56:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-12T16:56:01-05:00</updated>
    <title>Rittenhouse trial judge still baffled by pinch-to-zoom</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Kyle Rittenhouse Trial Continues In Kenosha, WI" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_ZRp1eJWDGDRsvDOEwxypppFmuQ=/472x487:4865x3416/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70135398/1236522232.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&amp;nbsp;Judge Bruce Schroeder takes a moment to take a personal call as the court waits for and evidence video to be played as Kyle Rittenhouse, left, and his attorney Mark Richards look on at the Kenosha County Courthouse on November 12, 2021 in Kenosha, Wisconsin | Photo by Sean Krajacic-Pool/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="83Tq5c"&gt;The prosecution and defense continue to argue over evidence in the trial of Kyle Rittenhouse for killing two people during a protest in Wisconsin, with a surprising amount of confusion from both the defense and Judge Bruce Schroeder about what happens when you pinch-to-zoom on a touchscreen device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sLND8s"&gt;On Wednesday, Schroeder &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22775580/kyle-rittenhouse-trial-judge-apple-ai-pinch-to-zoom-footage-manipulation-claim"&gt;stated it was up to the prosecution to prove that zooming on a video in with an iPad&lt;/a&gt; doesn’t alter or manipulate the footage. “iPads, which are made by Apple, have artificial intelligence in them that allow things to be viewed through three-dimensions and logarithms,” the defense said as part of its objection, adding that the iPad “uses artificial intelligence, or their logarithms, to create what they believe is happening. So this isn’t actually enhanced video; this is Apple’s iPad programming creating what it thinks is there, not what necessarily is there.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ru18F3"&gt;Judge Schroeder let the objection stand after giving prosecutors only 20 minutes to find an expert witness to explain how pinch-to-zoom on an iPad worked. (It should be noted, of course, that iPads do not have any “logarithms” that allow video to be viewed in three dimensions or “recreate” parts of an image that are not there.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3ODrit"&gt;During arguments over jury instructions &lt;a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/nation/watch-live-kyle-rittenhouse-lawyers-and-judge-discuss-jury-instructions-as-trial-for-kenosha-shooting-continues-day-9"&gt;broadcast live today&lt;/a&gt;, the judge went further, pulling out his own smartphone to demonstrate his continuing bafflement at pinch-to-zoom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tyLxan"&gt;Specifically, the judge saves texts from his friends by taking screenshots and emailing them to himself. He showed one such screenshot to the courtroom today, noting that “some of them are pretty long” and “show up in my email like this, like a little ribbon,” so he zooms on them and “it’s just a blur.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="maNtzk"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“it’s just a blur”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="r27KD2"&gt;According to the judge (talking to the prosecution), “You were talking the other day... about it’s just like a cellphone where you can expand a picture and make it bigger. But it’s not making it any bigger; it’s just a blur. Well, it’s not making it any bigger...it’s making it bigger, but it’s nothing but a blur.” He then questioned, “how that can be reliable... because it isn’t reliable for me and getting my messages on my phone.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uBcwBz"&gt;The prosecutor responded, “I think you’re taking the picture wrong on your phone. I’m not tech support, but...” The judge replied, “I’m not surprised,” prompting laughter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vaz2Yr"&gt;Let’s explain what’s going on here. Judge Schroeder appears to be using a Samsung Galaxy 20. That means he’s likely activating “scroll capture,” a Samsung screenshot feature that produces long images of an entire window — in this case, the entire text conversation. So those screenshots show up as long skinny images on his screen in order to fit. When he emails (or texts) that image to himself, the image is then &lt;em&gt;compressed&lt;/em&gt; to a smaller resolution and file size, so when he tries to zoom in on it, it’s blurry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="aG4dmh"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Judge Schroeder appears to be activating scroll capture on his Galaxy S20&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vNWu6O"&gt;None of this is useful evidence in support of the defense’s objection about iPad pinch-to-zoom. First of all, a Galaxy S20 runs Google’s Android operating system with various Samsung customizations, while the defense’s specific objections were about Apple’s “logarithms” on an iPad. So from the start, whatever a Samsung phone is doing is not relevant to an objection about how an Apple device works. Secondly, the defense’s objection is about those Apple logarithms &lt;em&gt;adding&lt;/em&gt; data to an image such that it can be viewed in three dimensions or recreate what is not there. Here, Judge Shroeder’s phone is plainly not adding any data to the image: it remains &lt;em&gt;blurry&lt;/em&gt;. If anything, his experience supports the &lt;em&gt;prosecution’s &lt;/em&gt;ability to zoom a video. But again: different software from different companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U39FA9"&gt;The judge closed the conversation by failing to silence his phone.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22778801/kyle-rittenhouse-bruce-schroeder-screenshot-zoom-in"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22778801/kyle-rittenhouse-bruce-schroeder-screenshot-zoom-in</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
