<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-06-01T15:35:04-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-01T15:35:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-01T15:35:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to opt out of (or into) Amazon’s Sidewalk network</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3qZWy9qI2FAu0Zua6SZjatjLyR8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69373399/acastro_181114_1777_amazon_hq2_0006.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QToc8K"&gt;Do you own an Echo Studio, an Echo Dot, or a Ring Floodlight Cam? If so, Amazon is about to introduce your device to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/21/21448926/amazon-sidewalk-ring-echo-tile-wifi-mesh-ble-location-tracking"&gt;a new type of network it calls Sidewalk&lt;/a&gt;, which is meant to help extend the range of its low-bandwidth devices (so that if your network goes down, for example, your Dot can piggyback on your neighbors’), and also to make location devices such as Tile more efficient. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i6Nqu5"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/devices/amazon-sidewalk-a-new-way-to-stay-connected"&gt;According to Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, Sidewalk will use Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE), the 900MHz spectrum, and other frequencies “to simplify new device setup, extend the low-bandwidth working range of devices, and help devices stay online and up-to-date even if they are outside the range of home Wi-Fi.” It will do this by essentially sharing the connectivity of your compatible devices with that of your neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0snNGQ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/devices/echo-tile-and-level-devices-join-amazon-sidewalk"&gt;Amazon says that&lt;/a&gt; Sidewalk will get switched on this coming June 8th (Tile functionality will be enabled June 14th), and that it plans to automatically opt in all the eligible devices. The company’s published &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Amazon-Sidewalk/b?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;node=21328123011"&gt;list of devices&lt;/a&gt; includes: Ring Floodlight Cam (2019), Ring Spotlight Cam Wired (2019), Ring Spotlight Cam Mount (2019), Echo (third gen and newer), Echo Dot (third gen and newer), Echo Dot for Kids (third gen and newer), Echo Dot with Clock (third gen and newer), Echo Plus (all generations), Echo Show (all models and generations), Echo Spot, Echo Studio, Echo Input, Echo Flex. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gVsh1L"&gt;Questions have been raised as to how this could impact the privacy of your data. &lt;a href="https://m.media-amazon.com/images/G/01/sidewalk/final_privacy_security_whitepaper.pdf"&gt;Amazon has made a white paper available&lt;/a&gt; that lays out how customer information is being protected. But if you are still not reassured by this and would rather not participate in Amazon’s good neighbor program — as it were — you can opt out before Sidewalk gets switched on. Here’s how:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="THgMF0"&gt;In your Amazon Alexa app, select the “More” icon at the lower right hand corner of the screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8DuPji"&gt;Go to “Settings” &amp;gt; “Account Setting” &amp;gt; “Amazon Sidewalk.” (Just a note: if you’re not connected to any Echo or Ring devices, you will probably not see this option.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lyxIMA"&gt;Use the toggle to disable Sidewalk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="It’s easy to toggle Sidewalk off or on" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0XBLN4eB_lRoVjRX-0WTFig1grI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22552821/Screenshot_20210601_131401.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s easy to toggle Sidewalk off or on.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can also choose to just toggle Community Finding off" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AH5K-v3n80pzIw6l3CKkKYaDmdA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22552823/Screenshot_20210601_143801.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can also choose to just toggle Community Finding off.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OujlbQ"&gt;And that’s it! Opting out will not (according to Amazon) in any way affect the current function of your devices. But if you decide you do want to opt back in, or you want to opt out sometime in the future, you can come back to the “Amazon Sidewalk” page and use the toggle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B2ECJP"&gt;Note that in the same page you’ll see a setting for “Community Finding,” which will share the approximate location of the devices connected by Sidewalk in order to make location-dependent items like Tile more accurate. If you want, you can leave Sidewalk active but disable “Community Finding” by selecting the “Community Finding” link at the bottom of the “Amazon Sidewalk” page and then toggling it off.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22463257/amazon-sidewalk-privacy-how-to-opt-out"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22463257/amazon-sidewalk-privacy-how-to-opt-out</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-01T15:17:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-01T15:17:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft mistake suggests PS5 or Nintendo Switch may support more Dolby tech</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rpp22pH9-NdUKCbnIEpaVhHWNZQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69373305/vpavic_201103_4275_0163.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="p9XqxU"&gt;On Monday, Microsoft published a &lt;a href="https://news.xbox.com/fr-fr/2021/05/31/decouvrez-dolby-vision-et-dolby-atmos/"&gt;now-deleted blog post&lt;/a&gt; on Xbox Wire France that claimed Dolby Vision and Atmos will be Xbox console exclusives for two years. (You can read &lt;a href="https://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:z42kKLEFz88J:https://news.xbox.com/fr-fr/2021/05/31/decouvrez-dolby-vision-et-dolby-atmos/+&amp;amp;cd=2&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ct=clnk&amp;amp;gl=au"&gt;a cached version of the blog here&lt;/a&gt;.) On Tuesday, however, Microsoft said the post had inaccurate information and that there actually &lt;em&gt;isn’t&lt;/em&gt; an exclusivity deal in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ONDNit"&gt;“A blog post was mistakenly published by a local Xbox team that included inaccurate information regarding exclusivity of Dolby Atmos and Dolby Vision on Xbox Series X|S,” a Microsoft spokesperson tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “There is no exclusivity agreement of either tech on Xbox. We are proud to partner with Dolby to offer Dolby Atmos and Dolby Vision to gamers on Xbox and will have more to share about the general availability of Dolby Vision on Xbox Series X|S soon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pxc18w"&gt;Microsoft’s statement is carefully worded in such a way that suggests, without confirming, that rival platforms like the PS5 and Nintendo Switch could get the advanced surround sound and HDR tech in the future. Technically, the PS5 &lt;em&gt;already&lt;/em&gt; supports Dolby Atmos, &lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2020/11/09/ps5-the-ultimate-faq/#3daudio"&gt;but just for Blu-ray movies&lt;/a&gt;. While Nintendo has traditionally only offered limited support for surround sound or advanced display output, the company’s expected to release &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/7/22315790/nintendo-switch-pro-4k-oled-upgraded-what-we-want"&gt;an upgraded “Switch Pro”&lt;/a&gt; as soon as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/27/22456160/new-nintendo-switch-release-date-september-e3-announcement"&gt;this September&lt;/a&gt;, where Dolby’s tech might be a better fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="9U7dkh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"What we actually want from an upgraded Nintendo Switch","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/7/22315790/nintendo-switch-pro-4k-oled-upgraded-what-we-want"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="wzLzNM"&gt;The Xbox Series X and S already support Dolby Atmos, and support for Dolby Vision could roll out broadly soon — Microsoft began testing of Dolby Vision on the Xbox Series X and S with testers in the Xbox Insider “alpha ring” group &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/14/22435864/microsoft-dolby-vision-xbox-series-x-s-test"&gt;in mid-May&lt;/a&gt;. Microsoft also offered Dolby Vision &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/12/17563670/microsoft-xbox-one-dolby-vision-support"&gt;on its Xbox One S and One X consoles&lt;/a&gt;, but it wasn’t really used for games; Dolby has advertised since September 2020 that the Xbox Series X and Series S would be the first consoles to support both while gaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HAnCCS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22463541/microsoft-xbox-dolby-vision-atmos-ps5-nintendo-switch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22463541/microsoft-xbox-dolby-vision-atmos-ps5-nintendo-switch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-01T13:49:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-01T13:49:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon’s serious injury rate at warehouses was still nearly double the rest of the industry in 2020</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TrKNpqbz7XXwowugil0JHTFQI1A=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69372762/acastro_181114_1777_amazon_hq2_0007.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YMjgSl"&gt;Amazon’s serious injury rate at its warehouses was nearly twice as high as the rest of the industry in 2020, newly released Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) data shows in reports from both &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/06/01/amazon-osha-injury-rate/?utm_source=feedly&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=wp_business-technology"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://thesoc.org/amazon-primed-for-pain/"&gt;Strategic Organizing Center&lt;/a&gt; (a collection of unions that represent over 4 million workers around the country). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6H0l9p"&gt;According to both groups’ analyses of the OSHA data, which spans 2017 through 2020, Amazon workers suffered 5.9 “serious” injuries — defined as incidents where workers received time off or a change in work responsibilities while recovering — per 200,000 hours worked (a metric that encompasses 100 workers working full time for the year). That’s compared to 3.3 injuries for that same metric across the rest of the warehousing industry. Walmart, one of Amazon’s largest retail competitors, had a rate of 2.5 serious injuries per 200,000 hours, more than half of Amazon’s rate of serious injury. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MRfUiv"&gt;On the one hand, the new data represents an improvement from 2019, when a report from &lt;a href="https://revealnews.org/article/how-amazon-hid-its-safety-crisis/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reveal &lt;/em&gt;from the Center for Investigative Reporting&lt;/a&gt; showed that Amazon had an overall rate of 7.7 serious injuries per 100 employees. And that lower rate is despite the surge in overall Amazon shipping in 2020 caused by the COVID-19 pandemic, a potentially promising trend to see. In fact, the 5.9 serious injuries per 100 employee rate — while still nearly twice as high as the rest of the industry — is actually Amazon’s best year in some time, considering that &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Reveal&lt;/em&gt; noted that the company had markedly higher overall injury rates in 2017, 2018, and 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BXuiEW"&gt;In a statement, Amazon spokesperson Kelly Nantel commented that “while any incident is one too many, we are continuously learning and seeing improvements through ergonomics programs, guided exercises at employees’ workstations, mechanical assistance equipment, workstation setup and design, and forklift telematics and guardrails—to name a few.” Nantel also noted that Amazon invested over $1 billion in new safety measures last year, while expanding its health and safety team. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IVy5mB"&gt;But it’s particularly telling that even at its lowest serious injury rate in years, Amazon’s warehouses still have a dramatically higher injury rate than the rest of the industry. As one Amazon worker complained to &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;, the company set “unrealistic expectations” in pushing workers to meet productivity rates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ojZBjv"&gt;Last fall, Amazon &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/30/21494381/amazon-rising-injury-rates-reveal-report"&gt;contested the original report&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;em&gt;Reveal&lt;/em&gt;, arguing that the interpretation of the OSHA data used to classify a “serious” injury — which, in the various reports here, is defined as those that require time off or work reassignments — is skewed by what the company claims is more generous recovery time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ax5iYc"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22463132/amazon-injury-rate-warehouses-osha-data-report"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22463132/amazon-injury-rate-warehouses-osha-data-report</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-01T13:28:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-01T13:28:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google union pushes company to drop deadnames from ID badges</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Fi99nO1Se4c3Kjt44NdIgVKnnRI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69372657/acastro_191014_1777_google_pixel_0005.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="AsNB2z"&gt;The Alphabet Workers Union &lt;a href="https://dropthedeadnames.org/#petition"&gt;launched a campaign&lt;/a&gt; Tuesday to push Google to allow employees to use their chosen names on ID badges. The move comes after Phares Lee, a transgender man who works at a Google data center in South Carolina and is employed by security subcontracting firm G4S, asked to have his deadname removed from his badge and was denied. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t2Kbjs"&gt;Lee came out as transgender during his initial interview with G4S. “I was assured [Google] was inclusive, yet when I asked about a badge in my preferred name I was told that my badge had to reflect my legal name,” he says in an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “After arriving on site and being issued the badge with my dead name, I noticed there were many people on site, both cis and transgender, whose badges did not reflect their legal names.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qqJxdI"&gt;Lee’s experience reflects a growing sentiment within Google’s contract workforce, that TVCs (temporary, vendor, and contract employees) &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/28/technology/google-temp-workers.html"&gt;do not have the same rights and benefits as full-time Google staff&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mAt5hL"&gt;In 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/21/technology/google-forced-arbitration.html"&gt;Google ended a long-time policy&lt;/a&gt; that forced employees to settle workplace disputes in private arbitration with the company. Yet the change did not extend to Google’s third-party contractors. “Contracting companies, like G4S, are allowed to make rules for their employees that directly contradict [Google’s] commitment to inclusion,” Lee explains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JGCatR"&gt;Lee says that when he arrived at the data center, he was the only transgender security officer on site. In an attempt to connect with other LGBTQ individuals, he tried to join one of Google’s employee resource groups, which are designed for underrepresented communities. He says G4S management told him these groups were a “privilege” to which contractors were not entitled. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KY3bAq"&gt;Now, the Alphabet Workers Union is circulating a petition asking Google and G4S to adopt a chosen name policy for TVCs and full-time staff. The policy should ensure “publicly displayed names reflect a chosen name where it differs from their legal name; allows pronoun stickers to be displayed on name badges, and protects the right to privacy of dead names,” according to the letter. The union also wants Google and G4S to allow contractors to participate in employee resource groups. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zSbXzu"&gt;The petition currently has 165 signatures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3Yi8RD"&gt;Neither Google nor G4S responded to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ra1Hn1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22463267/google-union-g4s-subcontractor-deadname-id-badge"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22463267/google-union-g4s-subcontractor-deadname-id-badge</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-01T13:16:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-01T13:16:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>Discovery announces new name of WarnerMedia merger: Warner Bros. Discovery</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/X7df69AASTjmp7Z2UiRDS4adu2w=/63x0:738x450/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69372600/Discovery.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The new logo and slogan for Warner Bros. Discovery | Image: Discovery&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QVGFEg"&gt;Discovery is merging with WarnerMedia, and it’s &lt;a href="https://ir.corporate.discovery.com/news-and-events/financial-news/financial-news-details/2021/Discovery-Inc.-Announces-Warner-Bros.-Discovery-As-New-Name-For-Proposed-Leading-Global-Entertainment-Company/default.aspx"&gt;now announced&lt;/a&gt; a new name for the combined company: Warner Bros. Discovery. &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/warner-bros-discovery-will-be-name-of-media-colossus-formed-in-merger-11622567102"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the name was first revealed during a staff meeting today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RPlaCJ"&gt;The merger was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439964/at-t-warnermedia-discovery-merger-spin-off"&gt;announced last month&lt;/a&gt;. AT&amp;amp;T said it would spin off WarnerMedia — the entertainment giant containing Warner Bros., HBO, DC Comics, and CNN, among many others — and that Discovery would take over the new company. But they didn’t have a new name prepared on the day the deal was announced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VT6VKq"&gt;Discovery CEO David Zaslav will be in charge of the merged group. WarnerMedia is by far the bigger company though, with around three times the 2020 revenue and a roster of iconic characters and properties. Discovery brings to the table a huge archive of reality TV shows and a growing news and sports business in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j9w3TS"&gt;“We believe it will be the best and most exciting place in the world to tell big, important and impactful stories across any genre – and across any platform: film, television and streaming,” Zaslav said in a statement today. The combined company is borrowing a line from the Warner Bros. classic &lt;em&gt;The Maltese Falcon &lt;/em&gt;for its slogan, “The stuff that dreams are made of.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y8Nb5e"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T and Discovery expect the merger to wrap up in mid-2020, assuming it clears regulatory hurdles. AT&amp;amp;T shareholders will own 71 percent of the new company, so it’s really more like WarnerMedia is being freed from AT&amp;amp;T and picking up Discovery along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dliZyY"&gt;The hope is that the combined entertainment giant can &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/19/22444031/warnermedia-discovery-merger-hbo-max-streaming-giant"&gt;become an even bigger player in streaming&lt;/a&gt; than the two are independently today. WarnerMedia runs HBO Max, which has been fairly successful so far, though it remains smaller than Netflix and Disney Plus. Discovery only recently launched Discovery Plus. Zaslav has said the combined company will put $20 billion per year toward new content, a number rivaling Netflix and exceeding Disney Plus, and that he hopes to eventually reach 400 million homes.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22448140/warner-bros-discovery-warnermedia-new-name-merger-att"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22448140/warner-bros-discovery-warnermedia-new-name-merger-att</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-01T12:59:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-01T12:59:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>AMD’s new Radeon RX 6800M delivers respectable performance at a respectable price</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The AMD Radeon RX 6800M seen from above on a marble surface." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/A-5hJYKaxfDvtryFamHIEyuQSL8=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69372483/AMD_Radeon_RX_6800M_and_Radeon_RX_6700M_GPU_1__1_.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This chip right here.&lt;/em&gt; | AMD&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VFDcvM"&gt;AMD has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/31/22457181/amd-radeon-rx-6000m-series-release-date-rdna2-rog-strix-g15"&gt;announced its Radeon RX 6000 series&lt;/a&gt; of mobile GPUs. The company claimed that the new chips, built on its RDNA 2 architecture, deliver the best performance we’ve ever seen from AMD graphics. It made particularly ambitious claims about its flagship Radeon RX 6800M, which it claimed would run modern AAA games at frame rates comparable to or better than those of Nvidia’s mobile RTX 3080. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DcUoyT"&gt;Company claims are just company claims, of course. I’ve been testing a system with a Radeon RX 6800M for the past few days. The results I’ve seen so far are a mixed bag, and while the RX 6800M doesn’t decisively outperform Nvidia’s top RTX chips, it’s doing a better job than I’d expect at the price range we’ve been given. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aQjAyI"&gt;To see how the RX 6800M performed, I was sent an Asus ROG Strix G15, one of the first laptops announced that will include the new GPU. My test system includes an eight-core AMD Ryzen 9 5900HX and 16GB of RAM. I’ll be publishing a full review of this device as soon as Asus finalizes the price of this build, which it hasn’t as of this writing. (The Strix G15 is expected to cost between $1,549 and $1,699, depending on configuration.) In the meantime, here are my benchmark results to give you an idea of the frame rates you can expect from this chip on a few different games. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Asus ROG Strix G15 half open facing away from the camera, angled to the right. " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iRg9geDr_U5SLdf6vpnNcYGDqbY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22552370/11_StrixG_15.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;AMD&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s the ROG Strix G15.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="q49WU4"&gt;I’ll start by talking about the thing that impressed me most about this chip: on-battery gaming. I only got an hour of gaming out of one charge, which is a fairly short life span. However, this system delivered the best on-battery gaming experience I’ve ever seen. I’m used to seeing unplugged gaming rigs chug along around 20fps (if that), descend into stutter-y territory 30-40 minutes in, and become unplayable with around 10 percent battery remaining. The unplugged Strix G15 ran &lt;em&gt;Red Dead Redemption 2 &lt;/em&gt;steadily between 30fps and 40fps for almost the entire hour, dropping to the high 20s around 12 percent. The game never even stuttered. Despite the Strix G15’s short stamina, I’d still recommend it to people who want to game on battery over some longer-lasting models due to the large amount of actually playable time you get. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The HP Omen 16 open seen from the front, angled to the left. The screen displays the Omen logo on a white background." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gqpSPtC8PG_TSyy4GLWS57IQo4k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22552427/OMEN_16_Laptop___2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: AMD&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The upcoming HP Omen 16 will also include AMD’s new GPUs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="jy8Si0"&gt;But there were some games where the Strix G15 didn’t blow me away (when it was plugged in). I ran &lt;em&gt;CS:GO &lt;/em&gt;with all settings maxed and averaged 252fps. That means the 6800M can certainly take advantage of a 300Hz screen on some lighter fare like this. (Games were tested at native resolution, with all sliders maxed out.) The result is actually fairly close to that of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/30/21197761/asus-rog-zephyrus-g14-review-gaming-laptop-specs-features-price"&gt;2020 Zephyrus G14&lt;/a&gt; (216fps in our testing), which had a last-gen RTX 2060 Max-Q, and quite close to what we saw from last year’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22195676/asus-rog-strix-scar-15-review-gaming-laptop-specs-features-price"&gt;Strix Scar 15&lt;/a&gt; (248fps), which had an RTX 2070 Super. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321471/asus-rog-zephyrus-g15-gaming-laptop-review"&gt;Zephyrus G15&lt;/a&gt; with an 80W RTX 3070 averaged 178fps running the title in QHD — I would hope to see a bigger gap since the Strix G15 has just a 1080p display. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YEYkh3"&gt;The Strix G15 averaged 87fps on &lt;em&gt;Horizon Zero Dawn&lt;/em&gt;, which barely beats the &lt;a href="https://www.notebookcheck.net/Asus-ROG-Zephyrus-G15-laptop-review-Eye-catcher.517789.0.html"&gt;Zephyrus G15 with a 100W RTX 3080&lt;/a&gt; and soundly beats the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22276367/asus-tuf-dash-f15-2021-intel-core-i7-nvidia-rtx-3070-review-gaming-laptop-specs-price"&gt;TUF Dash F15&lt;/a&gt; with an 85W RTX 3070, but doesn’t beat the 130W RTX 3070 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22244409/msi-gp66-leopard-gaming-laptop-review-price-specs-features"&gt;MSI GP66 Leopard&lt;/a&gt; (which averaged 96fps). The RX 6800M also did a fine, but not mindblowing, job with ray tracing. It averaged 69fps on &lt;em&gt;Shadow of the Tomb Raider &lt;/em&gt;with ray tracing on ultra, which is playable but worse than we’d expect from both the GP66 and the G15. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Yuu3YN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The RX 6800M is great at ‘Red Dead Redemption 2’&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OLALXR"&gt;The one exception here was &lt;em&gt;Red Dead Redemption II&lt;/em&gt; — for whatever reason, the RX 6800M is &lt;em&gt;great &lt;/em&gt;at that game. It averaged 77fps, which beats every system mentioned here, including the GP66 (which averaged 75fps). The 6800M also clearly has a large amount of raw power, even if it doesn’t translate to every game: it also beat all of these systems on the 3DMark Time Spy benchmark. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8OjSPQ"&gt;Given these results, the outlook for this card seems good. It’s performing worse than we’d expect from (or comparably to, in the case of &lt;em&gt;Red Dead&lt;/em&gt;) a similarly clocked RTX 3070, but it is mostly outperforming expectations for a lower-clocked RTX 3070 system. Pricing will certainly vary by manufacturer and model, but the G15’s expected price of $1,549.99 to $1,699.99 is more affordable than we typically see for a laptop with this kind of performance. The Strix G15 with an RTX 3070 is &lt;a href="https://store.asus.com/us/item/202102AM190000003/STRIX-ASUS-ROG-Strix-G15-%282021%29-Gaming-Laptop%2C-15.6%E2%80%9D-300Hz-IPS-Type-FHD-Display%2C-NVIDIA-GeForce-RTX-3070%2C-AMD-Ryzen-R9-5900HX%2C-16GB-DDR4%2C-1TB-PCIe-NVMe-SSD%2C-RGB-Keyboard%2C-Windows-10%2C-G513QR-ES96"&gt;$100 more&lt;/a&gt;, which makes this AMD GPU look like quite a good deal in comparison. These are just early benchmarks, of course, so it remains to be seen whether driver and compatibility issues pop up down the line. But so far, the RX 6800M looks to be a competitor, which isn’t something AMD has had in the mobile GPU front in a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6DYrPC"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="klfn7m"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22458829/amd-radeon-rx-6800m-mobile-gpu-gaming-laptops-asus-rog-strix-g15"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22458829/amd-radeon-rx-6800m-mobile-gpu-gaming-laptops-asus-rog-strix-g15</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-01T12:41:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-01T12:41:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>Instacart’s reported plan to automate its workforce seems a lot like bluster</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Personal Shopping Delivery Service Instacart Adds Thousands To Their Workforce As Demand For Shoppers Skyrockets During Coronavirus Pandemic" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LJRbVPPBe1lOiya8PPoD1RltlBQ=/2x0:4202x2800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69372328/1221480935.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Michael Loccisano/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oCQXLx"&gt;Instacart has big plans to automate parts of its grocery delivery business, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-06-01/instacart-looks-to-use-robots-over-people-to-do-grocery-shopping"&gt;reports &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but the company’s schemes look as much like bluster as ambition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6OHXHW"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;details a plan for the gig-work grocery-delivery network to build “automated fulfillment centers around the US, where hundreds of robots would fetch boxes of cereal and cans of soup while humans gather produce and deli products.” Some centers would be built next to grocery stores while others would be “standalone” operations. Instacart would partner with a supermarket chain to handle inventory, contract out the automation side of things to a robotics firm, and take care of processing orders and deliveries itself. If it works, the system would automate out huge portions of the company’s freelance workforce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hiroL4"&gt;It doesn’t seem like Instacart is making much progress, though. &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; notes that although the company has been working on these plans for more than a year, it “has yet to sign up a single supermarket chain” and has fallen behind schedule in developing its fulfillment centers. Meanwhile, another report &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/364a0f74-f016-4862-9cc3-a7be58a10772"&gt;from the&lt;em&gt; Financial Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in February suggested the company planned to open as many as 50 centers “in about a year.” The clock is definitely ticking on that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZPfSaL"&gt;There are certainly real reasons Instacart would want to automate. The company’s current business model relies on paying hundreds of thousands of gig workers to do customers’ shopping for them. This approach has found plenty of customers as it’s convenient and allows supermarkets to offer online shopping and delivery without creating their own service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="apDHbm"&gt;But this setup has problems, too. As &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; notes, shopping with Instacart is expensive. The company’s delivery fees, tips, and markups add 25 percent to order costs, according to data from consulting firm MWPVL International Inc. Another source of tension is that supermarkets don’t want Instacart stealing their business in the long run. They’ve been happy to partner with the company when they had no other way to offer online shopping and delivery, but that’s changing, says &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;, with new options for delivery offered by startups and existing food delivery businesses expanding their reach. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7IV4t5"&gt;Both of these factors put pressure on Instacart, and that’s particularly bad at a time when the firm wants to go public, either &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-instacart-directlisting-exclusive-idUSKBN2AX13F"&gt;through a direct listing or an IPO&lt;/a&gt; (originally rumored for early this year and now reportedly pushed &lt;a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/instacart-may-delay-ipo-until-121347561.html#:~:text=In%20early%20March%2C%20Instacart%20announced,%2C%20Fidelity%20Management%20%26%20Research%20Co."&gt;back to the end of 2021&lt;/a&gt;). Making big plans to automate its business seems like a way of allaying some of these pressures — giving investors hope that the company can lower costs and find a new way to work with supermarkets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DazzTP"&gt;Certainly, automating grocery shopping is not out of the question in the long term. Grocery firm Ocado, for example, has huge operations that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/8/17331250/automated-warehouses-jobs-ocado-andover-amazon"&gt;use both robots and humans to pack orders&lt;/a&gt; and is &lt;a href="https://www.supermarketnews.com/technology/kroger-debuts-first-ocado-automated-fulfillment-center"&gt;partnering with chains&lt;/a&gt; in the US that want to leverage that tech. But using robots in this way is still in its infancy: it requires huge investment and patience to work out the kinks and can’t just be tacked onto a business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iRwF1T"&gt;Meanwhile, it’s not clear how sustainable Instacart’s current business really is. As a private firm, we don’t know how much money it’s making or losing, but &lt;em&gt;The Information &lt;/em&gt;reported that it only made its first profit in early 2020 &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/instacart-swings-to-first-profit-as-pandemic-fuels-surge-in-grocery-delivery"&gt;thanks to booming pandemic sales&lt;/a&gt;. Meanwhile, the company has been repeatedly accused of exploiting its workforce in an unsustainable manner, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21267669/instacart-shoppers-sick-extended-pay-quarantine-leave-coronavirus"&gt;particularly during the pandemic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cOLekb"&gt;Overall, the situation feels similar to that of Uber, where the company repeatedly promised that its loss-making, gig economy business would become sustainable when it developed self-driving cars to replace all those pesky humans. And we all know how that ended: the taxi firm sold its self-driving team in December &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/7/22158745/uber-selling-autonomous-vehicle-business-aurora-innovation"&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22463023/instacart-plans-automation-grocery-shopping-business-model"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22463023/instacart-plans-automation-grocery-shopping-business-model</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-01T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-01T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter’s Fleets are getting Stories-like ads</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JHrKf5qYnPmmSZBcysPspHhY9pk=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69371942/Disney_Fleets.001.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Twitter is adding ads to its disappearing Fleets beginning June 1st. | Twitter&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pitMo2"&gt;Twitter said Tuesday it will start adding full-screen ads to Fleets, its disappearing tweets that sit in a row at the top of users’ mobile Twitter interface. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21570368/twitter-fleets-disapeating-tweets-stories-launch-available-now"&gt;Introduced last November, the Fleet&lt;/a&gt; format — a clone of Instagram and Snap’s Stories — has apparently been successful enough that Twitter now wants to try to make money from it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OGRgtX"&gt;“Fleet ads are full-screen billboards for advertisers,” Twitter senior product manager Justin Hoang and global product marketing manager Austin Evers wrote in a post announcing the ads. It’s partnering with a “handful” of advertisers in what it calls an “experiment,” making the Fleet ads visible to a limited group of US users on iOS and Android. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cgzfVZ"&gt;The ads support images and video in 9:16, and videos can be up to 30 seconds long. Brands can choose to add a “swipe up” call-to-action and will be able to access standard Twitter ad metrics, including impressions, profile visits, clicks, website visits, and other information. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WXsAqB7xQ7oYzhClSPPZtZFMB3k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22549504/Wendys_Fleet_Ad___Image.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Twitter&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Example of a Fleet ad from Wendy’s.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="cOpTqC"&gt;In April, &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/twitter-announces-first-quarter-2021-results-301280671.html"&gt;Twitter reported &lt;/a&gt;that its ad revenue grew 32 percent year over year to $899 million, and total ad engagement rose 11 percent. Expanding its ads beyond users’ timelines, where people can easily scroll past without engaging, seems like the logical next step. Instagram, after all, has had &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2017/1/11/14232408/instagram-stories-ads-video"&gt;ads in its Stories since 2017&lt;/a&gt; and started putting &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22396841/instagram-reels-ads-stickers-video-facebook"&gt;ads in its TikTok clone Reels&lt;/a&gt; last month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xdvtix"&gt;Twitter CEO &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.fool.com%2Fearnings%2Fcall-transcripts%2F2021%2F04%2F29%2Ftwitter-inc-twtr-q1-2021-earnings-call-transcript%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F1%2F22461070%2Ftwitter-fleets-stories-ads-monetize-instagram-snap" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jack Dorsey said during April’s Q1 earnings call&lt;/a&gt; with analysts that the company was still learning about who uses Fleets. “We started this product not to build a storage product within Twitter, but to solve the problem of people not wanting to tweet because they appear to be staying around too long,” he said, adding “we certainly have seen a different audience than we normally see, but we still have much to learn and a lot to figure out in terms of like, where it goes from here.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dz87UK"&gt;Twitter is planning to closely study how vertical full-screen ads perform, not just for Fleet ads but possible future iterations of other full-screen formats, according to Hoang and Evers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kjNqsO"&gt;“We also believe that ads should be non-intrusive and bring value to people, so we’re focused on learning more about how people feel about and engage with this new placement,” the blog post states, adding that the company is planning to launch more Fleet updates soon to stickers and backgrounds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ofasvJ"&gt;Twitter has been on a tear announcing new features this spring, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22420586/twitter-offensive-tweet-warning-prompt-updated-success-rate"&gt;updating its warnings&lt;/a&gt; for potentially offensive tweets, improving its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421574/twitter-crop-issue-bigger-images-rollout"&gt;photo cropping algorithm&lt;/a&gt; to allow “taller” images, adding the ability for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22434936/twitter-dm-search-android-expanding"&gt;Android users to search&lt;/a&gt; their direct messages, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423583/twitter-tip-jar-feature-sending-money-venmo-cashapp"&gt;rolling out a Tip Jar feature&lt;/a&gt; for donations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k1vjfL"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22417852/twitter-buying-scroll-subscription-service-news-revue-newsletter"&gt;Twitter also acquired Scroll&lt;/a&gt;, the $5-per-month subscription service that removes ads from participating websites. And its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/31/21349644/twitter-subscription-service-survey-undo-sent-analytics-feature-ideas"&gt;long-awaited&lt;/a&gt; paid subscription service &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/15/22437690/twitter-blue-subscription-service-299-undo-tweets"&gt;Twitter Blue may&lt;/a&gt; be coming soon as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Br7KEn"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22461070/twitter-fleets-stories-ads-monetize-instagram-snap"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22461070/twitter-fleets-stories-ads-monetize-instagram-snap</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-01T11:11:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-01T11:11:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>What’s on your desk, Brandon Widder? </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cxqaVYEE4fsxe0IbKH_ZhXy-FsE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69371542/bwidder_20210524_4602_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Some great tech, along with a mood light and a bobcat skull&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="myZQWm"&gt;As we slowly emerge from the pandemic, many companies are figuratively shaking themselves off, taking stock, and hiring for new types of positions. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; is no different; it has recently hired Brandon Widder to be its senior commerce editor, a brand-new title for our next chapter. We asked Brandon if we could take a look at his home workspace, and this is what he showed (and told) us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gUN2DR"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me a little about yourself. What is your background, and what do you do at &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Verge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cCcGks"&gt;Great question! I recently started at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; as its first senior commerce editor. As of right now, I’m fixated on improving our deals, buying guides, gift guides, and any other type of content with commerce potential. If it’s an article with a product recommendation — laptop, headset, what have you — there’s a good chance I’ll be looking at it at some point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CS9BuS"&gt;Before starting at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, I worked a number of years helming similar types of evergreen content for &lt;em&gt;Digital Trends&lt;/em&gt;, another consumer tech site. I also used to routinely freelance for an alt-weekly in Portland, Oregon, where I currently live with my partner and our two cats. I mostly wrote about local and touring bands, with some outdoorsy stuff sprinkled in here and there.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Louise Desk Chair came with the territory" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WquN_swIvQSkYuN3uQquY-gs1WM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22545811/bwidder_20210525_4602_0031.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Louise Desk Chair came with the territory.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5Yq9qo"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you decide where and how to set up your workspace?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Go5A3e"&gt;Well, “decide” is a strong word. My partner and I were forced to work from home as a result of the pandemic. We feel extremely fortunate that we were able to do so, but we didn’t have a dedicated space for us both to work in the beginning. Fortunately, when the unexpected desk shortage of 2020 subsided, I was able to set one up in the corner of our guest room, directly next to the window where I could watch the rain. It’s small and probably doesn’t have much in the way of feng shui, but, honestly, I enjoy how cozy it is. Space is overrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YB8lZ4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me a little about the desk itself.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vueHiE"&gt;The desk is the &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-8836598-13720150?sid=VergeWOYDBrandonWidder052821&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.wayfair.com%2Ffurniture%2Fpdp%2Fcorrigan-studio-munguia-desk-w005270388.html%3Fpiid%3D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Munguia Desk&lt;/a&gt; from Wayfair. I actually didn’t pick it out... let’s just say I inherited it when my partner and I traded work spaces at home. As much as it pains me to admit it, I do like it, namely because it’s relatively sturdy and affords me just the right amount of cubby space. It’s not particularly wide, but it also has a single drawer where I can stash my &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MWP22AM-A-AirPods-Pro/dp/B07ZPC9QD4?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt; and all the cables I probably should have thrown away a decade ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="fAuQVY"&gt;
&lt;div id="6YIjzq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10523553"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="XN9dnD"&gt;
&lt;p id="3JgJqR"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And how about your desk chair?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9hSp14"&gt;Like my desk, the &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-8836598-13720150?sid=VergeWOYDBrandonWidder052821&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.wayfair.com%2Ffurniture%2Fpdp%2Fkelly-clarkson-home-louise-task-chair-w003318245.html%3Fpiid%3D6833205" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Louise Desk Chair&lt;/a&gt; came with the territory when I took over the office. We were looking for something to match the brass guest bed shoved into the corner of the room, and despite it being a little too glam for my taste, it’s extremely comfortable and meshes well with the rest of the decor. Apparently, it’s “hand-curated by Kelly Clarkson,” which is something I just figured out while looking at the product listing. I just wish it could tilt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f3joQN"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You have a rather simple setup compared to some of your Verge compatriots. Could you tell us a bit about your tech?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qu8ixG"&gt;Clutter can really get to me, so I try to keep things clean. For work, I use the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5LNQCX/ref=sr_1_1_sspa?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=macbook%2Bair&amp;amp;qid=1622050268&amp;amp;sr=8-1-spons&amp;amp;spLa=ZW5jcnlwdGVkUXVhbGlmaWVyPUEyM080VVhUVVMzOVI4JmVuY3J5cHRlZElkPUEwNzg5NDQ0MVpLT0syNVFOSUVLTiZlbmNyeXB0ZWRBZElkPUEwMzg4MDE1MkREMVpISEc0MjdXTSZ3aWRnZXROYW1lPXNwX2F0ZiZhY3Rpb249Y2xpY2tSZWRpcmVjdCZkb05vdExvZ0NsaWNrPXRydWU&amp;amp;th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;M1 MacBook Air&lt;/a&gt;, but you wouldn’t know it given that it’s housed in the cubby beneath my desk. It’s a great machine, one that Dieter and the team &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"&gt;have already gushed over&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="q5n9JV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10523564"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="helivd"&gt;On the peripheral front, I recently sprung for the &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/Verge/type/dlg/sid/VergeWOYDBrandonWidder052821/https://www.dell.com/en-us/work/shop/dell-ultrasharp-27-4k-usb-c-monitor-u2720q/apd/210-avjv/monitors-monitor-accessories" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Dell UltraSharp U2720Q&lt;/a&gt;, a fantastic 4K display that affords me a bit more screen real estate than the Air and simultaneously charges my laptop via USB-C. I also have Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Keyboard-Wireless-Rechargable-English/dp/B016QO64FI/ref=sr_1_1_sspa?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=magic+keyboard&amp;amp;qid=1622050179&amp;amp;sr=8-1-spons&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;spLa=ZW5jcnlwdGVkUXVhbGlmaWVyPUEyS0U3TVVLV0ZLRVU4JmVuY3J5cHRlZElkPUEwNzIzNTUxMUdaMVIzTkFMQ0JUWSZlbmNyeXB0ZWRBZElkPUEwODExNjA2MU5OSjIzVEtLSlRVOCZ3aWRnZXROYW1lPXNwX2F0ZiZhY3Rpb249Y2xpY2tSZWRpcmVjdCZkb05vdExvZ0NsaWNrPXRydWU%3D&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Magic Keyboard&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Magic-Trackpad-Wireless-Rechargable/dp/B07BRF3ZQD/ref=sr_1_3?crid=2B9L8DKHKSWGV&amp;amp;dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=magic%2Btrackpad%2B2&amp;amp;qid=1622050188&amp;amp;sprefix=magic%2Btrack%2Caps%2C240&amp;amp;sr=8-3&amp;amp;th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Magic Trackpad 2&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve never been a huge fan of desktop mice, so when I picked up an external monitor, the trackpad just made sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XtLJmN"&gt;Elsewhere on my desk, I have one of &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0756Z8X82/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Anker’s wireless Qi charging pads&lt;/a&gt; for my iPhone X and a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sonos-One-Gen-Controlled-Built/dp/B07NJPXRBC?ref_=ast_sto_dp&amp;amp;th=1&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sonos One&lt;/a&gt;. I listen to everything from political post-punk to the gorgeous instrumental work of Icelandic composer Ólafur Arnalds, but everything in the Sonos lineup really shines regardless of the genre. I’m a sucker for the entire ecosystem, especially given its simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="t1pfow"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10523576"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="pGNfZ8"&gt;
&lt;p id="DMjQoQ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell us about the interesting wood piece that you have on your desk. And the — jawbone?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dw7rIz"&gt;When I’m not working, I tend to spend a lot of time outside. I love hiking and backpacking, and I’m really involved with Pacific Northwest Search and Rescue, one of our local SAR outfits. The driftwood is from the shores of the San Juan Islands; the rock from a small peak in Sun Valley, Idaho. My fascination with the natural world extends to bones — morbid, I know — which is why I have a bobcat skull sitting on my desk. It’s a bit in shambles at this point, though, having succumbed to my cats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A bobcat skull, a little worse for wear" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NtF_Fjf0Ie_S2hO50K4qPa9vW6A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22545809/bwidder_20210524_4602_0026.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A bobcat skull, a little worse for wear.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Driftwood from the shores of the San Juan Islands" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CpKRnx1-G5ohKGZtpHnXKjvASMA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22545803/bwidder_20210524_4602_0016.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Driftwood from the shores of the San Juan Islands.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Mood lighting for the home office" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3qqAoK2cCTNt1CPoY1Scmr_cgFA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22545802/bwidder_20210524_4602_0015_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mood lighting for the home office.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WNfnpc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m fascinated by the old-fashioned lightbulb you have next to the plant.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gsotu5"&gt;That would be my so-called mood lighting. There’s a small-ish company out of Portland called &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fgrovemade.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22458437%2Fhome-office-desk-macbook-dell-brandon-widder-tech-editor" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Grovemade&lt;/a&gt;, which manufactures an assortment of desk accessories out of wood and leather. Most of them run on the pricey side, but the quality is great. I picked up the now-discontinued walnut lamp a few years back and, more recently, the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fgrovemade.com%2Fproduct%2Fleather-desk-pad%2F%3Finitial%3D547&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22458437%2Fhome-office-desk-macbook-dell-brandon-widder-tech-editor" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;leather pad&lt;/a&gt; on which my keyboard and trackpad rest. It’s basically me trying to bring more natural elements into the fold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ujGaCb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And you have a notebook and pen by your keyboard.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PtFMpO"&gt;Yes! Like most people at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, I probably have more spreadsheets and Google Docs than I care to admit. The notebook allows me to jot down quick notes and keep them close at hand. It also just feels really good to physically write every once in a while, which is something I think a lot of us can appreciate. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07V5SQ6Q2/ref=redir_mobile_desktop?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;aaxitk=85a771eb1a014108995c19f32725f01c&amp;amp;hsa_cr_id=2895318650401&amp;amp;pd_rd_plhdr=t&amp;amp;pd_rd_r=2921f872-3cff-4acd-bcce-35efdaaf6aef&amp;amp;pd_rd_w=Mpdtv&amp;amp;pd_rd_wg=kYtdu&amp;amp;ref_=sbx_be_s_sparkle_mcd_asin_2_img&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Field Notes&lt;/a&gt; are great because they come in all shapes and sizes, some of which are waterproof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S5zY00"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything else about your work space that we haven’t covered?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ErgenS"&gt;Not really! The only other thing worth noting is my backlighting, which, if you live in an area that gets as much rain as I do, is crucial during the wetter months. For me, I’ve found the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07QV9XB87/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Philips Hue color lightbulbs&lt;/a&gt; to work best, partly because I’m tapped into the Hue network. If I want bright lights for a Zoom call or something more moody for after-hours work, all I have to do is say the word to Alexa. It’s super convenient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="EEcMoD"&gt;Also, go read &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Hunger-Makes-Me-Modern-Girl/dp/0399184767/ref=sr_1_2?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=carrie+brownstein&amp;amp;qid=1622050875&amp;amp;sr=8-2&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Carrie Brownstein’s autobiography&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Black-Leopard-Wolf-Dark-Trilogy-ebook/dp/B07DP5W1LT/ref=sr_1_1?crid=LCC3B8H6JIMM&amp;amp;dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=black+leopard+red+wolf&amp;amp;qid=1622050899&amp;amp;sprefix=black+leap%2Caps%2C244&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Black Leopard, Red Wolf&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;by Marlon James, both of which are sitting on my desk at the moment. You won’t be disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hGHj9F"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TBEhEE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22458437/home-office-desk-macbook-dell-brandon-widder-tech-editor"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22458437/home-office-desk-macbook-dell-brandon-widder-tech-editor</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-01T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-01T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple TV app comes to Nvidia Shield</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BrmdMSUmEmfe5XeeI4AfSn-_QU8=/130x0:1150x680/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69371440/Apple_TV_on_SHIELD.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The Apple TV app on Shield. | Image: Nvidia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JTbS6V"&gt;Apple’s streaming TV app is coming to another platform today: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/28/20935215/nvidia-shield-tv-2019-review-streaming-stick-dolby-vision-4k-price-specs-features"&gt;Nvidia’s Shield&lt;/a&gt;. Shield owners will &lt;a href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/2021/06/01/shield-apple-TV/"&gt;now be able to access&lt;/a&gt; Apple TV Plus, rent movies through Apple’s store, and access subscriptions to premium channels like Showtime and Starz that were set up through Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TC3WbI"&gt;The biggest hook is finally getting access to Apple TV Plus. Apple needs the streaming service to be accessible in as many places as possible in order to expand viewership. And viewers need to be able to access the service on whatever device is hooked up to their TV, if Apple wants to make sure people use it and stay signed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RJxtSG"&gt;Apple TV Plus is already available through &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fapple-tv-app%2Fdevices%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F6%2F1%2F22462960%2Fapple-tv-app-nvidia-shield-now-available" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;many of the most popular&lt;/a&gt; streaming devices. It’s offered through Roku and Fire TV streaming devices, available on recent PlayStations and Xboxes, and supported on many Vizio, Sony, Samsung, and LG TVs. The app came to Google’s latest Chromecast in February, and it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287905/apple-tv-app-now-available-chromecast-google-tv"&gt;supposed to expand to other Android TV devices&lt;/a&gt; — like the Shield — sometime after that. The service will support Dolby Vision and Dolby Atmos on Shield devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N8OVrH"&gt;The timing is good for Apple. Free trials for Apple TV &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394404/apple-tv-plus-free-trial-july-2021-ted-lasso-second-season-timing"&gt;are about to lapse&lt;/a&gt; for the service’s earliest users. And the second season of the service’s biggest (and pretty much only) hit, &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394062/apple-tv-ted-lasso-season-2-trailer-premiere-date"&gt;debuts July 23rd&lt;/a&gt;. The more places Apple TV Plus can be accessed, the better odds Apple has of getting some actual paying subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="88NcKJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22462960/apple-tv-app-nvidia-shield-now-available"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22462960/apple-tv-app-nvidia-shield-now-available</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
