<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-08-10T14:01:52-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-10T14:01:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-10T14:01:52-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon will pay up to $1,000 in damages caused by defective products</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qiCQJtBiZNh_uccze1G0tNs8Xto=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69705542/acastro_190920_1777_amazon_0001.0.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FpTvxA"&gt;Amazon &lt;a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/how-amazon-works/new-a-to-z-guarantee-better-protects-amazon-customers-and-sellers"&gt;has announced&lt;/a&gt; a new policy to pay customers directly for claims of property damage or personal injury under $1,000 caused by defective products. The new policy begins on September 1st and will apply to all products sold on &lt;a href="http://Amazon.com"&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/a&gt; regardless of who sells them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bPXSJJ"&gt;Previously, if you wanted to file a similar type of claim, you had to work with the seller — which has raised questions of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/28/21080720/amazon-product-liability-lawsuits-marketplace-damage-third-party"&gt;who’s really at fault&lt;/a&gt; for defective problems sold on the platform. But when this policy kicks in, Amazon customer service will help facilitate claims between a customer, the seller, and the seller’s insurance provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FslO7K"&gt;The $1,000 figure accounts for “more than 80 percent of cases,” according to Amazon. The company won’t ask sellers for reimbursement for these payouts, though Amazon says it will keep sellers “informed at every step.” And in some situations, the company could pay more; Amazon “may step in to pay claims for higher amounts if the seller is unresponsive or rejects a claim we believe to be valid,” it says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X97SUA"&gt;Amazon is also announcing the Amazon Insurance Accelerator, a new initiative to help sellers get product liability insurance, which is required to sell on the platform. Sellers don’t have to use a provider in the Accelerator, but the resource could be a helpful tool for those shopping for insurance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hwaVjn"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rokOSA"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22618418/amazon-pay-property-damage-personal-injury-claims-insurance"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22618418/amazon-pay-property-damage-personal-injury-claims-insurance</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-10T13:53:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-10T13:53:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter shares analysis of racist abuse that followed Euro 2020 final</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Twitter bird logo in white against a dark background with outlined logos around it and red circles rippling out from it." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZC-JWP5z-ioR9qW4mFjzrPke_oY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69705478/acastro_180827_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CPPEvG"&gt;Twitter claims identity verification wouldn’t have prevented the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/12/22574082/black-players-england-italy-football-soccer-racist-instagram-twitter-telegram"&gt;torrent of racist abuse&lt;/a&gt; against Black players on England’s football team, which followed the team’s loss in the Euro 2020 championship game last month. According to an &lt;a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_gb/topics/company/2020/combatting-online-racist-abuse-an-update-following-the-euros"&gt;update posted by Twitter UK&lt;/a&gt; today, the majority of the accounts suspended for abusive content during the tournament were not anonymous.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="evEi8h"&gt;“Of the permanently suspended accounts from the Tournament, 99 percent of account owners were identifiable,” said Twitter. The company also said that, while the racist tweets came from around the world, the majority originated from the United Kingdom. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nZFv3E"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Our data suggests that ID verification would have been unlikely to prevent the abuse from happening - as of the permanently suspended accounts, 99% of account owners were identifiable.&lt;/p&gt;— Twitter UK (@TwitterUK) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterUK/status/1425035343708016641?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="08oTRl"&gt;According to Twitter, its automated tools identified and removed 1,622 racist tweets during the match and in the 24 hours after. Of the removed tweets, only 2 percent were viewed more than a thousand times, says Twitter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="92knRl"&gt;Twitter has had a long-standing problem with abuse on the platform. Following a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/14/16410348/twitter-boycott-new-rules-enforcement-aggressive-stance-harassment-jack-dorsey"&gt;boycott in 2017&lt;/a&gt;, CEO Jack Dorsey pledged that Twitter would take a “more aggressive stance” in the enforcement of its rules. Since then, the company has rolled out more granular features in attempts to curb abuse, like letting people &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/19/20874847/twitter-feature-launch-us-japan-rollout-hide-replies"&gt;hide replies&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575998/twitter-tweet-change-who-can-reply-after-you-post"&gt;limit who can reply&lt;/a&gt; to their tweets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Zxm3R"&gt;Twitter continues to work on ways to prevent abusive tweets from being sent, including rolling out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22420586/twitter-offensive-tweet-warning-prompt-updated-success-rate"&gt;reply prompts&lt;/a&gt; that ask people if they’re sure about using potentially harmful language. Twitter is also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301388/twitter-auto-block-mute-abusive-accounts-safety-mode"&gt;developing a feature&lt;/a&gt; that “temporarily autoblocks accounts using harmful language, such that they’re stopped from being able to interact with your account.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22618500/twitter-analysis-racist-abuse-euro-2020-identification"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22618500/twitter-analysis-racist-abuse-euro-2020-identification</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kait Sanchez</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-10T13:44:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-10T13:44:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>Here’s why Apple’s new child safety features are so controversial</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L8aonSnsyj7CRHujfw7YFDDk_38=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69705443/acstro_190902_apple_event_0004.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Encryption and consumer privacy experts break down Apple’s plan for child safety&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="IsDfmF"&gt;Last week, Apple, without very much warning at all, announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611721/apple-csam-child-abuse-scanning-hash-system-ncmec"&gt;a new set of tools built into the iPhone designed to protect children from abuse&lt;/a&gt;. Siri will now offer resources to people who ask for child abuse material or who ask how to report it. iMessage will now flag nudes sent or received by kids under 13 and alert their parents. Images backed up to iCloud Photos will now be matched against a database of known child sexual abuse material (CSAM) and reported to the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children (NCMEC) if more than a certain number of images match. And that matching process doesn’t just happen in the cloud — part of it happens locally on your phone. That’s a big change from how things normally work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kGCO04"&gt;Apple claims it designed what it says is a much more private process that involves scanning images on your phone. And that is a very big line to cross — basically, the iPhone’s operating system now has the capability to look at your photos and match them up against a database of illegal content, and you cannot remove that capability. And while we might all agree that adding this capability is justifiable in the face of child abuse, there are huge questions about what happens when governments around the world, from the UK to China, ask Apple to match up other kinds of images — terrorist content, images of protests, pictures of dictators looking silly. These kinds of demands are routinely made around the world. And until now, no part of that happened on your phone in your pocket. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Riana Pfefferkorn and Jen King, from Stanford, in the the Decoder art style" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sci2ZRqVPfK84REZCRLuSAbN_FM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22773381/VRG_ILLO_Decoder_King_Apple_alt_s.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo Illustration by Grayson Blackmon / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Riana Pfefferkorn and Jen King&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cvYmzL"&gt;To unpack all of this, I asked Riana Pfefferkorn and Jennifer King to join me on the show. They’re both researchers at Stanford: Riana specializes in encryption policies, while Jen specializes in privacy and data policy. She’s also worked on child abuse issues at big tech companies in the past. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6bjvBx"&gt;I think for a company with as much power and influence as Apple, rolling out a system that changes an important part of our relationship with our personal devices deserves thorough and frequent explanation. I hope the company does more to explain what it’s doing, and soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="UP7DUJ"&gt;
&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="200" scrolling="no" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm?e=VMP7739805133" width="100%"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5wAaCG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following excerpt has been lightly edited for clarity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7iVdJd"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It feels like one enormous aspect of this entire controversy is the fact that the scanning is being done on the device at some point. That’s the Rubicon that’s been crossed: up until now, your local computer has not scanned your local storage in any way. But once you hit the cloud, all kinds of scanning happens. That’s problematic, but it happens. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l8Y8oQ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But we have not yet entered the point where law enforcement is pushing a company to do local scanning on your phone, or your computer. Is that the big bright line here that’s causing all the trouble?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eBXBPb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Riana Pfefferkorn:&lt;/strong&gt; I view this as a paradigm shift, to take where the scanning is happening from in the cloud, where you are making the &lt;em&gt;choice&lt;/em&gt; to say, “I’m going to upload these photos into iCloud.” It’s being held in third-parties’ hands. You know, there’s that saying that “it’s not the cloud; it’s just somebody else’s computer,” right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="enCuGo"&gt;You’re kind of assuming some level of risk in doing that: that it might be scanned, that it might be hacked, whatever. Whereas moving it down onto the device — even if, right now, it’s only for photos that are in the cloud — I think is very different and is intruding into what we consider a more private space that, until now, we could take for granted that it would stay that way. So I do view that as a really big conceptual shift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o7wehY"&gt;Not only is it a conceptual shift in how people might think about this, but also from a legal standpoint. There is a big difference between data that you hand over to a third party and assume the risk that they’re going to turn around and report to the cops, versus what you have in the privacy of your own home or in your briefcase or whatever. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Kovszk"&gt;I do view that as a big change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OmcQMR"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jen King:&lt;/strong&gt; I would add that some of the dissonance here is the fact that we just had Apple come out with the “asks apps to not track” feature, which was already in existence before, but they actually made that dialog box prominent to ask you when you were using an app if you want the app to track you. It seems a bit dissonant that they just rolled out that feature, and then suddenly, we have this thing that seems almost more invasive on the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XmyI1r"&gt;But I would say, as someone who’s been studying privacy in the mobile space for almost a decade, there is already an extent to which these phones aren’t ours, especially when you have third-party apps downloading your data, which has been a feature of this ecosystem for some time. This is a paradigm shift. But maybe it’s a paradigm shift in the sense that we had areas of the phone that we maybe thought were more off-limits, and now they are less so than they were before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yvTIDZ"&gt;The illusion that you’ve been able to control the data on your phone has been nothing more than an illusion for most people for quite a while now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5qjBAF"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The idea that you have a local phone that has a networking stack that then goes to talk to the server and comes back — that is almost a 1990s conception of connected devices, right? In 2021, everything in your house is always talking to the internet, and the line between the client and the server is extremely blurry to the point where we market the networks. We market 5G networks, not just for speed but for capability, whether or not that’s true.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ASTMGA"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But that fuzziness between client and server and network means that the consumer might expect privacy on local storage versus cloud storage, but I’m wondering if this is &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;actually&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; a line that we crossed  — or if just because Apple announced this feature, we’re now perceiving that there &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;should&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; be a line.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hjBJAx"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RP: &lt;/strong&gt;It’s a great point because there are a number of people who are kind of doing the equivalent of “If the election goes the wrong way, I’m going to move to Canada” by saying “I’m just going to abandon Apple devices and move to Android instead.” But Android devices are basically kind of just a local version of your Google cloud. I don’t know if that’s better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="98hWr9"&gt;And at least you can fork Android [although] I wouldn’t want to run a forked version of Android that I sideloaded from some sketchy place. But we’re talking about a possibility that people just don’t necessarily understand the different ways that the different architectures of their phones work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="nOYbQz"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“People’s rights, people’s privacy, people’s free expression — that shouldn’t depend upon a consumer choice.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4hx0gp"&gt;A point that I’ve made before is that people’s rights, people’s privacy, people’s free expression, that shouldn’t depend upon a consumer choice that they made at some point in the past. That shouldn’t be path-dependent for the rest of time for whether or not their data that they have on their phone is really theirs or whether it actually is on the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z0u387"&gt;But you’re right that, as the border becomes blurrier, it becomes both harder to reason about these things kind of from arm’s length, and it also becomes harder for just average people to understand and make choices accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RlOfAA"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JK: &lt;/strong&gt;Privacy shouldn’t be a market choice. I think it’s a market failure, for the most part, across industry. A lot of the assumptions we had going into the internet in the early 2000s was that privacy could be a competitive value. And we do see a few companies competing on it. DuckDuckGo comes to mind, for example, on search. But bottom line, many aspects of privacy shouldn’t be left up to the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VDNIHc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Full transcript coming soon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="jA4WOx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Decoder with Nilay Patel","description":"A podcast from &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;The Verge&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; about big ideas and other problems.","label":"Subscribe now!","url":"https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/decoder-with-nilay-patel/id1011668648"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="K5cfwt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q2om1A"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="flYo2u"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22617554/apple-csam-child-safety-features-jen-king-riana-pfefferkorn-interview-decoder"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22617554/apple-csam-child-safety-features-jen-king-riana-pfefferkorn-interview-decoder</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nilay Patel</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-10T13:43:26-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-10T13:43:26-04:00</updated>
    <title>A24 will stream The Green Knight for one night on August 18th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bxuS9aA_OOPvqUCtPGb9lyrCu08=/67x0:1476x939/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69705439/dev_patel.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sS6ksY8xWCY&amp;amp;ab_channel=A24" target="_blank"&gt;A24&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="q9uKzR"&gt;&lt;a href="https://screeningroom.a24films.com/"&gt;A24’s &lt;em&gt;The Green Knight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; will make its virtual debut much earlier than expected — on August 18th, you’ll be able to buy a $20 ticket to stream the film through A24’s Screening Room platform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xx1qTD"&gt;The one-night-only stream isn’t a full streaming release for rental or purchase, given that &lt;em&gt;The Green Knight&lt;/em&gt; is still otherwise exclusive to theaters. (A regular digital release will come later on in the theatrical cycle.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HwbOvl"&gt;As such, the screening is also far more limited than a typical rental: once you’ve purchased a $20 ticket, you’ll be able to stream the film during a four-hour window on August 18th starting at 9PM ET. The stream does come with a bonus Q&amp;amp;A with the cast and crew after the film, however. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fmw3g7"&gt;Based on the classic epic poem, &lt;em&gt;The Green Knight&lt;/em&gt; stars Dev Patel as the would-be knight who answers an ill-fated challenge to the titular Green Knight on Christmas day. The film was originally planned for a May 29th, 2020 release, but was delayed until this summer due to the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="m4NK8y"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;One. Knight. Only.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A24 Screening Room presents &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TheGreenKnight?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#TheGreenKnight&lt;/a&gt; AUGUST 18. Get tickets ⟶ &lt;a href="https://t.co/958s0zbXys"&gt;https://t.co/958s0zbXys&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/52HBOSrYuH"&gt;pic.twitter.com/52HBOSrYuH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— A24 (@A24) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/A24/status/1425139944083922947?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5oMQg5"&gt;Once you’ve bought a ticket, A24 offers three ways to watch the film: through a web browser, through the Apple TV app, or through the Roku app. Unfortunately, though, A24 is only screening &lt;em&gt;The Green Knight&lt;/em&gt; for US viewers — international film fans won’t be able to join.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ww6sUL"&gt;The move marks the latest blurring of the line between theatrical and streaming releases. At $20, the price of a streaming ticket is comparable to seeing &lt;em&gt;The Green Knight &lt;/em&gt;in theaters (especially if shared with multiple friends or family members), with the added bonus that A24 won’t have to share that ticket price with theaters. It’s a similar balancing act that has driven moves like Disney Plus’ Premiere Access films, which have offered the option of simultaneous $30 digital purchases and theatrical releases for films like &lt;em&gt;Black Widow&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Jungle Cruise&lt;/em&gt;. HBO Max has also taken a similar approach, offering simultaneous digital debuts for its 2020 slate at no extra cost to streaming subscribers alongside theatrical debuts. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22618625/a24-the-green-knight-screening-room-streaming-august-18th"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22618625/a24-the-green-knight-screening-room-streaming-august-18th</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-10T13:36:26-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-10T13:36:26-04:00</updated>
    <title>OnePlus is trying to jump on Samsung’s folding phone hype</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="OnePlus ‘dual-screen’ teaser image" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5_wBN9mK5EfG6ULRq7xn5lL5NfA=/0x12:1600x1079/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69705402/oneplus_dual_screen_tease.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: OnePlus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DVOBgU"&gt;Samsung’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22608535/samsung-unpacked-event-date-time-galaxy-z-fold-flip-earbuds-watches"&gt;August Unpacked event&lt;/a&gt; is scheduled to take place tomorrow with foldables and wearables tossed about, but it appears that OnePlus has a thirst for attention that simply can’t wait. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vF5RFu"&gt;The company tweeted out this &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CSZhpf1C9WW/"&gt;brief video clip&lt;/a&gt; with some kind of two-screened mobile device, although it’s unclear exactly what we should expect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MfkICq"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/CSZhpf1C9WW/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="13" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"&gt;&lt;div style="padding:16px;"&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CSZhpf1C9WW/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"&gt; &lt;div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;"&gt; &lt;div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="padding: 19% 0;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"&gt;&lt;svg width="50px" height="50px" viewbox="0 0 60 60" version="1.1" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"&gt;&lt;g stroke="none" stroke-width="1" fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd"&gt;&lt;g transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)" fill="#000000"&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="padding-top: 8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;"&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin-left: 8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin-left: auto;"&gt; &lt;div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CSZhpf1C9WW/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank"&gt;A post shared by OnePlus➕ (@oneplus_usa)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jin057"&gt;LG has already done the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/17/21225118/lg-v60-thinq-5g-review-dual-screen-specs-features-price"&gt;second-screen phone case thing&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/30/20939655/lg-g8x-thinq-dual-screen-review"&gt;more than once&lt;/a&gt;), so if that’s all OnePlus has up its sleeve it could be disappointing. That said, the durability of Samsung’s early foldable devices has been disappointing and this could be a way for OnePlus to poke the bear on its big day. Or maybe it won’t be much of anything at all, and we’ll all move on to the next Galaxy without even thinking about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8XjCDG"&gt;If you’re going to go head-to-head with the Korean giant, you’ll need the hardware to back it up. We’ll see what’s real and what’s hype at 10AM ET on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22618252/dual-screen-oneplus-samsung-unpacked-foldable"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22618252/dual-screen-oneplus-samsung-unpacked-foldable</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-10T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-10T13:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>OpenAI can translate English into code with its new machine learning software Codex</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EAMbPR4Q3qXnrFgCKTXyBuyC7XU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69705201/acastro_181017_1777_brain_ai_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LMzy72"&gt;AI research company OpenAI is releasing a new machine learning tool that translates the English language into code. The &lt;a href="https://openai.com/blog/openai-codex/"&gt;software is called Codex&lt;/a&gt; and is designed to speed up the work of professional programmers, as well as help amateurs get started coding. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZYczzl"&gt;In demos of Codex, OpenAI shows how the software can be used to build simple websites and rudimentary games using natural language, as well as translate between different programming languages and tackle data science queries. Users type English commands into the software, like “create a webpage with a menu on the side and title at the top,” and Codex translates this into code. The software is far from infallible and takes some patience to operate, but could prove invaluable in making coding faster and more accessible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="v62ERC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It takes people who are already programmers and removes the drudge work.” &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="s7Uli2"&gt;“We see this as a tool to multiply programmers,” OpenAI’s CTO and co-founder Greg Brockman told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Programming has two parts to it: you have ‘think hard about a problem and try to understand it,’ and ‘map those small pieces to existing code, whether it’s a library, a function, or an API.’” The second part is tedious, he says, but it’s what Codex is best at. “It takes people who are already programmers and removes the drudge work.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZnVXx8"&gt;OpenAI used an earlier version of Codex to build a tool called &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22555777/github-openai-ai-tool-autocomplete-code"&gt;Copilot&lt;/a&gt; for GitHub, a code repository owned by Microsoft, which is itself a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/22/20703578/microsoft-openai-investment-partnership-1-billion-azure-artificial-general-intelligence-agi"&gt;close partner of OpenAI&lt;/a&gt;. Copilot is similar to the autocomplete tools found in Gmail, offering suggestions on how to finish lines of code as users type them out. OpenAI’s new version of Codex, though, is much more advanced and flexible, not just completing code, but creating it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QfdZLw"&gt;Codex is built on the top of GPT-3, OpenAI’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21346343/gpt-3-explainer-openai-examples-errors-agi-potential"&gt;language generation model&lt;/a&gt;, which was trained on a sizable chunk of the internet, and as a result can generate and parse the written word in impressive ways. One application users found for GPT-3 was generating code, but Codex improves upon its predecessors’ abilities and is trained specifically on open-source code repositories scraped from the web. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vktCLC"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="OpenAI Codex demo: Hello World|103409" data-volume-uuid="b8ffc0647" data-volume-id="103409" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-277" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9rR7xD"&gt;This latter point has led many coders to complain that OpenAI is &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/github-commercial-ai-tool-built-open-source-code/"&gt;profiting unfairly from their work&lt;/a&gt;. OpenAI’s Copilot tool often suggests snippets of code written by others, for example, and the entire knowledge base of the program is ultimately derived from open-source work, shared to benefit individuals, not corporations. The same criticisms will likely be leveled against Codex, though OpenAI says its use of this data is legally protected under fair use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="iouPD0"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The real net effect is a lot of value for the ecosystem”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="D9qq0b"&gt;When asked about these complaints, Brockman responds: “New technology is coming, we do need this debate, and there will be things we do that the community has great points on and we will take feedback and do things differently.” He argues, though, that the wider coding community will ultimately benefit from OpenAI’s work. “The real net effect is a lot of value for the ecosystem,” says Brockman. “At the end of the day, these types of technologies, I think, can reshape our economy and create a better world for all of us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sdrjtr"&gt;Codex will also certainly create value for OpenAI and its investors. Although the company started life as a nonprofit lab in 2015, it &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/03/11/openai-shifts-from-nonprofit-to-capped-profit-to-attract-capital/"&gt;switched to a “capped profit” model&lt;/a&gt; in 2019 to attract outside funding, and although Codex is initially being released as free API, OpenAI will start charging for access at some point in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iq4yWw"&gt;OpenAI says it doesn’t want to build its own tools using Codex, as it’s better placed to improve the core model. “We realized if we pursued any one of those, we would cut off any of our other routes,” says Brockman. “You can choose as a startup to be best at one thing. And for us, there’s no question that that’s making better versions of all these models.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="zEb1Dt"&gt;What is Codex actually like to use?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="MyLydu"&gt;Of course, while Codex sounds extremely exciting, it’s difficult to judge the full scope of its capabilities before real programmers have got to grips with it. I’m no coder myself, but I did see Codex in action and have a few thoughts on the software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="460Qpo"&gt;OpenAI’s Brockman and Codex lead Wojciech Zaremba demonstrated the program to me online, using Codex to first create a simple website and then a rudimentary game. In the game demo, Brockman found a silhouette of a person on Google Images then told Codex to “add this image of a person from the page” before pasting in the URL. The silhouette appeared on-screen and Brockman then modified its size (“make the person a bit bigger”) before making it controllable (“now make it controllable with the left and right arrow keys”). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="SaXNaf"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Giving Codex the right instructions is as much an art as a science&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Fg5DL6"&gt;It all worked very smoothly. The figure started shuffling around the screen, but we soon ran into a problem: it kept disappearing off-screen. To stop this, Brockman gave the computer an additional instruction: “Constantly check if the person is off the page and put it back on the page if so.” This stopped it from moving out of sight, but I was curious how precise these instructions need to be. I suggested we try a different one: “Make sure the person can’t exit the page.” This worked, too, but for reasons neither Brockman nor Zaremba can explain, it also changed the width of the figure, squashing it flat on-screen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Yo0i8U"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="OpenAI Codex demo: Game development|103414" data-volume-uuid="e45bc7194" data-volume-id="103414" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-734" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hmLgWd"&gt;“Sometimes it doesn’t quite know exactly what you’re asking,” laughs Brockman. He has a few more tries, then comes up with a command that works without this unwanted change. “So you had to think a little about what’s going on but not super deeply,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7URA6d"&gt;This is fine in our little demo, but it says a lot about the limitations of this sort of program. It’s not a magic genie that can read your brain, turning every command into flawless code — nor does OpenAI claim it is. Instead, it requires thought and a little trial and error to use. Codex won’t turn non-coders into expert programmers overnight, but it’s certainly much more accessible than any other programming language out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="Kns7RH"&gt;The future of programming&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="5NEyoW"&gt;OpenAI is bullish about the potential of Codex to change programming and computing more generally. Brockman says it could help solve the programmer shortage in the US, while Zaremba sees it as the next step in the historical evolution of coding. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="nm1R43"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Codex is bringing computers closer to humans, letting them speak English rather than machine code”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nGXrGv"&gt;“What is happening with Codex has happened before a few times,” he says. In the early days of computing, programming was done by creating physical punch cards that had to be fed into machines, then people invented the first programming languages and began to refine these. “These programming languages, they started to resemble English, using vocabulary like ‘print’ or ‘exit’ and so more people became able to program.” The next part of this trajectory is doing away with specialized coding languages altogether and replacing it with English language commands. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wpEBJP"&gt;“Each of these stages represents programming languages becoming more high level,” says Zaremba. “And we think Codex is bringing computers closer to humans, letting them speak English rather than machine code.” Codex itself can speak more than a dozen coding languages, including JavaScript, Go, Perl, PHP, Ruby, Swift, and TypeScript. It’s most proficient, though, in Python. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="AOJuG6"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="OpenAI Codex demo: Talking to your computer|103413" data-volume-uuid="92b8c5f5f" data-volume-id="103413" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-367" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cxcgO5"&gt;Codex also has the ability to control other programs. In one demo, Brockman shows how the software can be used to create a voice interface for Microsoft Word. Because Word has its own API, Codex can feed it instructions in code created from the user’s spoken commands. Brockman copies a poem into a Word document and then tells Word (via Codex) to first remove all the indentations, then number the lines, then count the frequency of certain words, and so on. It’s extremely fluid, though hard to tell how well it would work outside the confines of a pre-arranged demo. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QaVije"&gt;If it succeeds, Codex might not only help programmers but become a new interface between users and computers. OpenAI says it’s tested Codex’s ability to control not only Word but other programs like Spotify and Google Calendar. And while the Word demo is just a proof of concept, says Brockman, Microsoft is apparently already interested in exploring the software’s possibility. “They’re very excited about the model in general and you should expect to see lots of Codex applications be created,” he says. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22618128/openai-codex-natural-language-into-code-api-beta-access"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22618128/openai-codex-natural-language-into-code-api-beta-access</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-10T12:59:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-10T12:59:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>NASA’s new space suits are delayed, making a 2024 Moon landing ‘not feasible’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Artemis Generation Spacesuit Event" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cdOilpqQNokV7z6MfseLZnkzcno=/1413x0:5792x2919/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69705198/1176110120.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The person in the white suit is wearing a prototype of NASA’s new xEMU in 2019, whose development has been delayed, an inspector general report found.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Joel Kowsky / NASA via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qbIPpa"&gt;NASA’s development of new astronaut space suits will be nearly two years late and nix its effort to land humans on the Moon by 2024, an inspector general report released on Tuesday found. Those delays compound a daunting set of schedule challenges NASA already faces — from the development of its new human-rated lunar lander to getting its massive Space Launch System rocket off the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="is97ll"&gt;An audit from the agency’s Office of Inspector General said NASA is on track to spend more than $1 billion on space suit development by the time its first two suits are ready, which would be “April 2025 at the earliest,” the &lt;a href="https://oig.nasa.gov/docs/IG-21-025.pdf"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; said. “Given these anticipated delays in spacesuit development, a lunar landing in late 2024 as NASA currently plans is not feasible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="my5pO4"&gt;NASA is trying to return astronauts to the surface of the Moon for the first time since 1972 under its Artemis program that was spawned by the Trump administration in 2019. The program, as set by former Vice President Mike Pence, called for a crewed lunar landing in 2024 — a deadline that President Biden’s transition team &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22323621/trump-moon-program-artemis-biden-nasa-timeline"&gt;deemed unrealistic&lt;/a&gt;. But NASA continues to embrace the date, with administrator Bill Nelson insinuating delays are likely because &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/6/29/8863121/spacex-falcon-9-rocket-explosion-excuses"&gt;“space is hard.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="T8URKN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;NASA’s space suit design has changed with shifting space priorities, driving up costs and delays&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zkDD8P"&gt;NASA has already spent $420 million on space suit development since 2007, before the advent of its Artemis program, and it plans to “invest approximately $625.2 million more” through 2025, the report said. The space suit’s design and purpose have changed repeatedly over the years as NASA’s priorities in space teeter between new administrations. A new Artemis-tailored space suit design, called xEMU, was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/15/20916106/nasa-artemis-moon-space-suits-xemu"&gt;unveiled in 2019&lt;/a&gt;. Current suits worn by astronauts on the International Space Station are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/21/20920790/nasa-first-all-female-spacewalk-christina-koch-jessica-meir-spacesuit-design-bias"&gt;restrictive, haven’t been upgraded in decades&lt;/a&gt;, and aren’t designed for long walks on the Moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gZbONs"&gt;The xEMU program anticipated development delays by allotting 12 months of wiggle room on its path to meet the 2024 Artemis deadline. But that schedule margin has already disappeared after NASA ran into funding shortfalls, closures to NASA centers during the COVID-19 pandemic, and more technical challenges, the report found. NASA slashed the space suit program’s planned $209 million budget by $59 million after Congress gave the agency 77 percent of what it requested for its Gateway Program in 2021, under which space suits are developed. That set the program back three months, the report said.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="U.S.-WASHINGTON D.C.-NASA-NEW SPACESUITS-LUNAR LANDING" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uTmoYZ5Ulgxj3FvaLYh6rTN7evg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22773878/1176165285.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Xinhua / Liu Jie via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;NASA space suit engineer Kristine Davis models a prototype of the agency’s new lunar space suit in 2019.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="8cVvB6"&gt;Intermittent closures to NASA’s Johnson Space Center during the pandemic caused at least three more months of delays, the report said. Then there were the hardware problems. Design upgrades and other changes caused production issues with the suit’s Display and Control Unit — the screen astronauts will use to control the suit’s critical functions. Circuit boards within a key part of the suits’ life support system, needed “rework” to ensure communications between the suit and the astronaut — and other astronauts — worked right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="efOehI"&gt;The program was hit with another delay when NASA halted testing for the suit’s assembly process. The team caused an unspecified “component failure” after “staff used the wrong specifications to build a complicated” life support system interface. When auditors interviewed NASA personnel about this flub, they blamed schedule pressure, among other issues. Additional factors included “a communication breakdown among the team” and the team’s rapid growth, “including the addition of inexperienced personnel.” An “unreleased drawing” and old hardware used during tests were also to blame, personnel told auditors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EmvcBB"&gt;Currently, 27 different entities are pitching in to build different parts of the space suit, the report notes. NASA previously contracted with just two companies, Hamilton Standard and ILC Dover, to build the space suits it currently uses on the ISS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="g5K27q"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Seems like too many cooks in the kitchen&lt;/p&gt;— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1425100378459279370?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pIuoBh"&gt;“Seems like too many cooks in the kitchen,” SpaceX CEO Elon Musk opined on Twitter in response to the news, adding in another tweet: “SpaceX could do it if need be.” It’s unclear whether SpaceX has an active space suit development program; government astronauts who have flown the company’s Crew Dragon capsule wear SpaceX-designed flight suits, not long-duration space suits. Some private companies are already planning to design their own space suits, including Axiom Space, which, this month, posted &lt;a href="https://app.trinethire.com/companies/31021-axiom-space-inc/jobs/41213-senior-space-suit-hardware-engineer"&gt;new jobs for space suit engineers&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mRo0iU"&gt;NASA’s space suit woes aren’t the only threat to its 2024 goal. The agency’s inspector general, Government Accountability Office, and NASA’s aerospace safety panel have all expressed concern that development delays in NASA’s human lunar lander and Space Launch System programs — the core organs of the Artemis program — will make a 2024 landing nearly impossible, with the safety panel raising fears that the hastened landing date could lead to schedule pressure among engineers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hFb3dQ"&gt;In response to the report, NASA’s human exploration chief Kathy Lueders said the agency plans to rejig its space suit development schedule and carry out a space suit test on the ISS by June 2022, before the first crewed Artemis mission poised for sometime in 2023. For that mission, astronauts will fly around the Moon in NASA’s Orion capsule without a lunar landing. The next mission, Artemis III, will have the Moon landing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KeRUw8"&gt;“Demonstration and testing of [the space suits] on ISS are a priority,” Lueders said.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22618275/nasa-spacesuits-delay-inspector-general-report-2024-artemis"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22618275/nasa-spacesuits-delay-inspector-general-report-2024-artemis</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-10T12:13:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-10T12:13:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>Senate approves $1 trillion infrastructure package as crypto worries loom</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Senators Meet For Weekly Policy Luncheons" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9YQvUcyd1eNLjrH1zh9Vxb1od9Y=/0x2:8192x5463/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69704897/1332193432.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3Luv5h"&gt;After weeks of negotiations, the Senate approved a bipartisan &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605917/senate-negotiators-bipartisan-infrastructure-broadband-electric-vehicles-cryptocurrency"&gt;$1 trillion infrastructure&lt;/a&gt; package Tuesday authorizing over $500 billion in new spending to improve roads, bridges, and other physical infrastructure like broadband and EV charging. It’s the largest domestic spending bill in over a decade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RQqDH8"&gt;“It’s taken quite a while. There have been a lot of bumps in the road,” Majority Leader Chuck Schumer (D-NY) said Tuesday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="jnecAr"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s taken quite a while”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hBVcus"&gt;Aside from more traditional infrastructure spending like roads, the bill seeks to bolster US broadband networks with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22598636/white-house-infrastructure-broadband-package-bipartisan"&gt;an additional $65 billion&lt;/a&gt;. It also makes permanent a pandemic-era internet subsidy program called the Emergency Broadband Benefit fund, renaming it the Affordable Connectivity Fund. The fund offers low-income families $30-a-month subsidies to go toward their internet bills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TpMmh4"&gt;The package also includes &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/30/22600226/bipartisan-infrastructure-plan-ev-charging-climate-change"&gt;$7.5 billion to build &lt;/a&gt;over half a million EV charging stations across the US to help encourage EV adoption. A more reliable charging network could incentivize people to purchase more EVs over the next ten years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ELGfah"&gt;Still, controversial language regarding cryptocurrency tax reporting remains in the bill. Lawmakers sought to set off some of the infrastructure spending by extending cryptocurrency tax reporting requirements, raising an estimated $28 billion in revenue. The digital assets community and lawmakers like Sen. Ron Wyden (D-OR) argued that the language was too vague and would make wallet developers and miners subject to reporting. After days of negotiations, an amendment aimed at fixing that problem &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22617055/infrastructure-cryptocurrency-deal-reporting-lummis-wyden-schumer"&gt;failed on the floor&lt;/a&gt; after Sen. Richard Shelby (R-AL) objected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nd1tJV"&gt;Now, the House is set to begin debate on the infrastructure bill before it receives final approval and heads to President Biden’s desk. It’s unclear how long the process will take before the language is finalized. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ETrBY4"&gt;In a letter to every House lawmaker, members of the bipartisan &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RepTomEmmer/status/1424845416697323522?s=20"&gt;Blockchain Caucus raised concerns&lt;/a&gt; over the Senate’s cryptocurrency provision. “Left unchanged, this provision will have sweeping implications for crypto investors in our country and further regulate innovation out of the United States,” they wrote. The House has an opportunity to amend the bill to fix these issues before it’s moved for a floor vote.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22618448/senate-bipartisan-infrastructure-package-schumer-broadband-cryptocurrency"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22618448/senate-bipartisan-infrastructure-package-schumer-broadband-cryptocurrency</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-10T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-10T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nvidia’s tiny RTX A2000 GPU can fit inside a small form factor PC</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HOb9bsO2gcl5dmf9NteyDVCPTmI=/271x0:3201x1953/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69704774/NVIDIA_RTX_A2000_5.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nvidia’s A2000 is nearly half the size of the RTX 3090.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Nvidia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="sz6TNb"&gt;Nvidia is launching its new RTX A2000 GPU today, designed for professional workstations. It’s Nvidia’s smallest Ampere-based GPU so far and can easily squeeze into small form factor workstations. Like Nvidia’s old Quadro cards, the RTX A2000 is designed primarily for professionals who want to leverage ray tracing and Nvidia’s AI capabilities, and it’s the latest in a &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-gb%2Fdesign-visualization%2Fdesktop-graphics%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F8%2F10%2F22618030%2Fnvidia-rtx-a2000-gpu-workstation-specs-features-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;line of A-series GPUs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T4hvv7"&gt;The RTX A2000 can deliver 8 teraflops of GPU performance, coupled with 3328 CUDA cores, 6GB of GDDR6 memory with ECC, and a memory clock of 6001Mhz. That makes it look more capable on paper than something like Nvidia’s RTX 3050 laptop GPU. It also only consumes 70 watts of power, so it’s very power-efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YcmWhGvYIqN9RTuKTMYiCSFMTzE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22773088/NVIDIA_RTX_A2000_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Nvidia&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nvidia’s lineup of A-series GPUs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="2gmwY4"&gt;The RTX A2000 is based on Nvidia’s latest Ampere architecture and is designed to boost performance in 3D modeling and rendering software like Blender, Autodesk 3ds Max, and more. It includes second-generation RT cores, third-generation tensor cores for AI tools, and PCIe 4 support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="llI2ak"&gt;Its compact, low-profile design includes a single blower and four DisplayPort 1.4 ports at the rear, making it ideal for workstations with multiple monitors. Nvidia is aiming the RTX A2000 at those working remotely, helping power 3D design, thanks to a form factor that can slot into workstations big and small. It’s just 2.7 inches tall and 6.6 inches long, matching the size of a &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamesn.com/nvidia/rtx-3060-mini-itx-gpu"&gt;miniature RTX 3060&lt;/a&gt;. Overall, the RTX A2000 is almost half the size of the giant RTX 3090.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cNU0yU"&gt;Nvidia is working with a variety of partners to make the RTX A2000 available in workstations from Asus, Dell, HP, Lenovo, and many more. The RTX A2000 should debut from Nvidia partners in October, priced at around $450.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22618030/nvidia-rtx-a2000-gpu-workstation-specs-features-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22618030/nvidia-rtx-a2000-gpu-workstation-specs-features-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-10T11:16:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-10T11:16:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>COVID-19 misinformation is increasing amid US virus surge </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An illustration of several vaccine vials over a pink and purple background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ht9To0KPqyjWMZag6kErnXMTaF8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69704559/acastro_210309_1777_vaccine_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UyCQXm"&gt;The surge in COVID-19 cases around the United States, driven by the highly contagious and fast-moving delta variant of the coronavirus, is accompanied by a similar surge in virus misinformation, &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/10/technology/covid-delta-misinformation-surge.html?smid=tw-share"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8AAZfY"&gt;Rates of misinformation about COVID-19 and the COVID-19 vaccines increased dramatically from June to July, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/10/technology/covid-delta-misinformation-surge.html?smid=tw-share"&gt;according to Zignal Labs&lt;/a&gt;, which tracks mentions of phrases on social media and by news outlets. False claims, including statements saying that the vaccines don’t work, immunity from infections is better than vaccination, and vaccines cause miscarriages, skyrocketed. The falsehood&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;that the vaccines don’t work is up 437 percent, the analysis found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aONVIY"&gt;The spike comes after a lull in misinformation during May and June, when COVID-19 cases were low in most places in the US. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rfjyRY"&gt;Russian-aligned disinformation campaigns are also contributing to the spread of falsehoods, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/05/us/politics/covid-vaccines-russian-disinformation.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; last week. Those actors are spreading false messaging about side effects of the gene-based COVID-19 vaccines made by Pfizer / BioNTech and Moderna, and suggesting that the Biden administration will force people to get vaccinated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EJvB0c"&gt;The uncertainty around the delta variant created an environment for this type of misinformation to take hold. “Disinformation thrives in an information vacuum,” Lisa Kaplan, the chief executive of the Alethea Group, which helps corporations guard against misinformation, told &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;. “Knowing how the Russians typically play those situations, it wouldn’t surprise me they are trying to take advantage of it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Po0Xg0"&gt;The spread of vaccine-related falsehoods comes at a key time in the COVID-19 vaccination campaign. Public health officials are working to convince unvaccinated people to sign up for a shot in order to curb the transmission of the delta variant. Only &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2020/us/covid-19-vaccine-doses.html"&gt;59 percent of people&lt;/a&gt; in the US eligible for the vaccine are fully immunized, which isn’t nearly enough to contain the virus. In states and counties in the Southeast where coverage is low, hospital systems are overwhelmed with COVID-19 patients, the majority of which are unvaccinated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VDqO6r"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22618249/covid-misinformation-surge-delta-russia-vaccine"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22618249/covid-misinformation-surge-delta-russia-vaccine</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
