<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-07-19T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-19T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-19T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Android TV is swiping some of Google TV’s best features</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ggj7dJKrYRBSdelq2onkOVEHvtw=/74x0:865x527/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69601117/image003.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android TV is finally getting a watchlist.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iq02td"&gt;Android TV is swiping some of the best content discovery tools from the Google TV platform, including a watchlist and more finely tuned recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FN0vfU"&gt;Beginning this week, Android TV users will be able to add titles to a watchlist that will populate as a row in the Discover tab. To add movies and series to this section, users can either select “watchlist” from a title’s details page or long-press on a title from the Discover tab and select “add to watchlist.” Additionally, users will be able to add shows to this section from their other gadgets with Google search or by using the Google TV mobile app. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xXJ1Ib"&gt;Google TV also features the ability to refine the kinds of titles that a user is recommended with a card-swiping tool. This feature is now making its way to Android TV, allowing users to decide whether they’d like to see titles more or less like the one being recommended. This tool can also be found in the Discover tab or in settings by selecting Device Preferences, Home Screen, and then Content Preferences.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1aIBjCUwXpUT63tMW1zvVnFrTSM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22722646/image004__1_.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android TV users can now swipe on content they want to see more or less of.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="8P2nUI"&gt;Lastly, trailers will play automatically on detail pages if they’re available. If that’s not your thing, the feature can be turned off in settings by navigating to Device Preferences and then Home Screen under “Enable video previews.” The changes follow a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/3/22263131/android-tv-software-update-ui-interface-menus-google-chromecast-refresh"&gt;previous update&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year to Android TV’s interface. Like these latest features, that one similarly made the Android TV experience feel more like the one you get with Google TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YJZ5Yo"&gt;A spokesperson said users will begin to see these features appear on their Android TV interfaces starting this week.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22580720/android-tv-watchlist-google-tv-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22580720/android-tv-watchlist-google-tv-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-19T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-19T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>WhatsApp will let you join group calls after they start</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UN40B3fSEjucZOIMmZ9Kvi6_U0c=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69601120/acastro_210119_1777_whatsapp_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rwnvyT"&gt;WhatsApp is rolling out a new joinable calls feature which will let you hop onto group calls after they’ve started, the Facebook-owned company announced Monday. The new feature means you’ll be able to join a call with your friends and family when you’re ready, kind of like what you can do with a group Zoom or Google Meet call right now. Given the massive popularity of WhatsApp, this could be a useful feature for many people who communicate over the messaging service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ery3rN"&gt;You can get an idea of how the interface for hopping onto calls works in the image below — it looks like you’ll just need to tap a join button.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xvcMjnAVdufZgj1wkMamoKvJJqo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22726277/JC_Blog_Asset.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: WhatsApp&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;WhatsApp’s interface for joinable calls.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="HOFHtK"&gt;There’s also a new call info screen so that you can see who is currently on the call and who is invited but hasn’t joined yet. Joinable calls will &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/4/5/11370106/whatsapp-messenger-end-to-end-encryption-open-whisper"&gt;still be end-to-end encrypted&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ArBtTF"&gt;The new joinable calls feature starts rolling out on Monday. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583640/whatsapp-joinable-calls-join-after-started-group"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583640/whatsapp-joinable-calls-join-after-started-group</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-19T11:27:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-19T11:27:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>Lidar maker Velodyne loses its CEO amid internal chaos</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Yandex NV Trials Driverless Taxis" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-ieisByKbyX78a2tvfUOcz-Q2Qw=/0x0:4000x2667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69600900/1164317768.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="sbOLO4"&gt;Velodyne, a leading manufacturer of lidar laser sensors, announced that CEO Anand Gopalan would be stepping down. The news comes as the sensor company has been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453138/velodyne-david-hall-spac-letter-board-removal"&gt;embroiled in a bitter war&lt;/a&gt; between its founder, David Hall, and the company’s board of directors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JnUWhs"&gt;Gopalan, who previously served as Velodyne’s chief technology officer before taking the reins from Hall in January 2020, is stepping down as both CEO and a member of the board effective July 30th, the company said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7uVYij"&gt;But rather than name a replacement, Velodyne is setting up something called “Office of the Chief Executive” comprised of several members of the company’s leadership team, including chief operating officer Jim Barnhart, chief financial officer Drew Hamer, head of human resources Kathy McBeath, and chief commercial officer Sinclair Vass. The move may be temporary, though, as the board is also retaining an executive search firm to find a replacement for Gopalan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="t3PgWp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;But rather than name a replacement, Velodyne is setting up something called “Office of the Chief Executive”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5saFcU"&gt;For the last several months, Velodyne has been a company at war with itself. In April, the board ousted &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295550/velodyne-founder-lidar-david-hall-marta-investigation-board"&gt;Hall as chair of the company’s board, and his wife, Marta Thoma Hall, as its chief marketing officer&lt;/a&gt;, citing “inappropriate behavior” by the couple. Marta Hall remains a member of Velodyne’s board of directors, while David Hall resigned his position on March 2nd. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nU3G8w"&gt;The following month, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453138/velodyne-david-hall-spac-letter-board-removal"&gt;David Hall called for the resignation&lt;/a&gt; of two of the company’s SPAC-appointed board directors, whom he blames for Velodyne’s “poor financial performance.” He accused the board of financial misdeeds, including padding Gopalan’s compensation “despite knowing the company would miss its 2020 projections.” And he claimed that he and his wife were ousted from their positions over “frivolous claims.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qEo8oX"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/18/16491052/velodyne-lidar-mapping-self-driving-car-david-hall-interview"&gt;Hall has long been revered in the world of autonomous vehicle technology&lt;/a&gt; as a pioneer in the use of laser sensors to enable AVs to “see” the world around them. Lidar, which stands for “light detection and ranging,” uses thousands of laser beams to sense objects and measure their distance. The cone- or cylindrical-shaped sensor perched on the roof of a vehicle has become synonymous with self-driving cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LppUC4"&gt;In June 2020, Velodyne struck a deal with special acquisition company (SPAC) Graf Industrial Corp., with a market value of $1.8 billion. It was part of a wave of companies in the transportation technology space choosing to go public via SPAC and thus avoiding a lot of the scrutiny that comes with a more traditional IPO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eOjO2p"&gt;But Velodyne contends that its financial outlook remains “unchanged” despite Gopalan’s resignation. The company, which expects its 2021 revenue to be between $77 million and $94 million, will report its second quarter earnings on August 5th. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583535/velodyne-ceo-resignation-anand-gopalan-lidar"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583535/velodyne-ceo-resignation-anand-gopalan-lidar</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-19T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-19T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Warby Parker can renew glasses and contact lens prescriptions with its updated app</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RqFCqZpvxisTNYZtREXMPphrj4Q=/168x0:1419x834/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69600721/Screen_Shot_2021_07_16_at_10.44.40_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Warby Parker&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="86i0B9"&gt;Warby Parker is updating its Prescription Check iOS app on Monday with a new name and the ability to renew glasses &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; contact lens prescriptions on the iPhone 6S and up (the company currently doesn’t offer an Android app). Like its predecessor, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.warbyparker.com%2Fvirtual-vision-test&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F7%2F19%2F22580166%2Fwarby-parker-contact-lens-glasses-prescription-renewal" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the new Warby Parker Virtual Vision Test&lt;/a&gt; isn’t a substitute for an actual optometrist visit, but being able to snag a new prescription for $15 without having to schedule an appointment should be very handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZNCCxj"&gt;With Virtual Vision Test downloaded, you’ll be taken through some intake questions, not unlike what you might fill out in a normal optometrist visit (“Do you regularly get headaches?” etc.). Warby Parker requires you to meet some basic criteria as well, like being 18 years of age or older, not having any “eye health concerns,” using a single-vision distance prescription, and seeing well with your current glasses or contacts. With those taken care of, the app guides you through a simple vision test, reading off letters that appear on your phone’s screen, and alternating covering your eyes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XLH3yy"&gt;Warby Parker says it takes about 48 hours for a new prescription to be written, but it won’t charge you $15 unless you’re approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nOyCPd"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZC_xVikK5Zw?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JyJeui"&gt;Prescription Check used a laptop and a phone to measure out your eyes’ distance from the test and to enter in prompts, but Virtual Vision Test makes things a bit easier. Warby Parker says the updated app uses a new “proprietary distance estimation algorithm” and a software framework exclusive to Apple devices called &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/vision"&gt;Vision Framework&lt;/a&gt; in order to keep everything contained on your phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nQP5xU"&gt;Vision Framework covers a wide swath of possible use cases in iOS, from scanning bar codes to enabling the head tracking used in AR filters, but Warby Parker says that combined with its algorithm it makes the process of taking a vision test less complicated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="1Ei92t"&gt;Because the tool is able to measure distance and tell a user when they’re at the correct distance to take the vision test, the possibility of human error while measuring is reduced. Overall, this results in an even simpler and more efficient user experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="spx6Z6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A proprietary distance estimation algorithm&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="I8n54E"&gt;That’s helpful because this is the first time the company’s also offering the ability to renew a contact lens prescription online. Warby Parker’s Scout line of contact lenses &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2019-11-19/warby-parker-launches-scout-daily-contact-lenses-at-440-a-year"&gt;launched in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, but never made it to the older Prescription Check app until now. Warby Parker hasn’t said if any of the technical changes it’s made to its app make it easier to account for a contact prescription, but they do require different measurements and considerations than traditional glasses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qr1YuG"&gt;Ultimately, all of this high-tech convenience is to push you to buy new glasses frames or contacts directly from Warby Parker, and the company’s leveraged Apple tech to make that as fun and interactive as possible. If you have a iPhone X or newer, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/4/18205654/warby-parker-ar-iphone-face-id-mapping-glasses-try-on-app"&gt;you can virtually try on the company’s frames&lt;/a&gt; right from its app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v4UymL"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MmqgrJ"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22580166/warby-parker-contact-lens-glasses-prescription-renewal"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22580166/warby-parker-contact-lens-glasses-prescription-renewal</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-19T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-19T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>GDC will return to an in-person event in 2022</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-IT-INTERNET-GAMES-GDC" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BBDEokpQA_QK8ckUAUDWiyuFI2c=/0x37:4728x3189/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69600740/465197440.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Josh Edelson/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="E2uYjJ"&gt;An all-virtual version of the annual Game Developers Conference kicks off on July 19th, but the organizers say that next year the event will be in person once again. GDC 2022 “will return as a physical conference at the Moscone Center in San Francisco,” the organizers say, with the conference taking place from March 21st to the 25th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wIu73X"&gt;While not a major public-facing event, GDC has long been an important week for the games industry, with professionals from all over the world gathering together in one spot. (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/19/18271702/google-stadia-cloud-gaming-service-announcement-gdc-2019"&gt;Sometimes platforms like Stadia are even announced there&lt;/a&gt;.) The 2020 edition was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/28/21156037/gdc-2020-canceled-coronavirus-gaming-event-san-francisco"&gt;one of the first large-scale gaming events to be put on hiatus due to the pandemic&lt;/a&gt;, and while this year’s GDC was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/12/21365498/gdc-2021-game-developers-conference-event-physical-hybrid-coronavirus-july-san-francisco"&gt;expected to have an in-person element&lt;/a&gt;, it eventually shifted to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22290109/gdc-digital-only-masterclass-showcase-2021"&gt;a completely virtual format&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bFKOtW"&gt;For those who registered, GDC 2021 runs from July 19th through the 23rd, with a few notable talks and presentations, including &lt;a href="https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/events/see-our-full-developer-day-schedule-for-gdc-2021"&gt;the latest tech demo of Epic Games’ UE5 game engine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583372/gdc-2022-in-person-san-francisco-moscone-center"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583372/gdc-2022-in-person-san-francisco-moscone-center</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-19T10:47:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-19T10:47:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>Zoom buys Five9 for $14.7 billion to ‘deliver even more happiness’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NveWo3hf2kOi215vt_AW6nrBbB4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69600648/acastro_200331_1777_zoom_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Zoom buys Five9 for $14.7 billion to ‘deliver even more happiness’&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FFMUAJ"&gt;Videoconferencing platform Zoom is acquiring cloud contact center software company Five9 for $14.7 billion, the &lt;a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2021/07/19/2264531/0/en/Zoom-to-Acquire-Five9.html"&gt;company announced&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H9qbcO"&gt;“We are continuously looking for ways to enhance our platform, and the addition of Five9 is a natural fit that will deliver even more happiness and value to our customers,” Zoom CEO Eric Yuan said in the announcement. He added that the deal will add more business clients to Zoom’s customer base, and that Five9 is “complementary” to its &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fzoom.us%2Fpricing%2Fzoom-phone&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F7%2F19%2F22583371%2Fzoom-buys-five9-14-7-billion-videoconferencing-lockdown" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Zoom Phone&lt;/a&gt; cloud system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r9kEEG"&gt;Under the terms of the deal, Five9 will become an operating unit of Zoom, and CEO Rowan Trollope will become a president at the company reporting to Yuan. In 2020, Five9’s full-year &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/ix?doc=/Archives/edgar/data/0001288847/000128884721000029/fivn-20201231.htm#iac51b890630c488aa40d29fada3e7e16_115"&gt;revenue&lt;/a&gt; was up 33 percent year over year to $435 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8p4sLr"&gt;Five9 is Zoom’s first billion-dollar acquisition, and it comes at a time when the company is looking to try to continue the momentum it has gained during the coronavirus pandemic, as people have been working and schooling remotely during lockdowns. Now, many are heading back to offices at least part of the time. “The trend towards a hybrid workforce has accelerated over the last year, advancing contact centers’ shift to the cloud and increasing demand by customers for customized and personalized experiences,” Yuan said in a &lt;a href="https://blog.zoom.us/zoom-to-acquire-five9/"&gt;separate blog post&lt;/a&gt; about the deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aVaHsf"&gt;Zoom’s stock price has more than tripled since pandemic lockdowns started last year, but that growth has started to slow slightly. Its &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/07/19/zoom-is-buying-cloud-contact-center-provider-five9-for-14point7-billion.html"&gt;revenue rose 326 percent&lt;/a&gt; in 2020, but in the first quarter of 2021, Zoom reported growth of &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/zoom-to-buy-five9-in-all-stock-deal-valued-at-14-7-billion-11626662804"&gt;about 191 percent&lt;/a&gt; to $956 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r6fONf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Oo2VU7"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583371/zoom-buys-five9-14-7-billion-videoconferencing-lockdown"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583371/zoom-buys-five9-14-7-billion-videoconferencing-lockdown</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-19T10:29:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-19T10:29:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>Uber expands grocery delivery to 400 cities, including NYC and San Francisco</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="In this photo illustration, Uber Eats logo of a US online..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7laCw9YKTdIVz5IxnIrbF-Y7d8w=/0x5:3874x2588/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69600558/1233279060.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Pavlo Gonchar/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9V6Qth"&gt;Uber has more than doubled the number of cities where it delivers groceries, marking the &lt;a href="https://investor.uber.com/news-events/news/press-release-details/2021/Uber-Accelerates-National-Grocery-Availability-Across-the-U.S/default.aspx"&gt;first major expansion&lt;/a&gt; of the new service since its launch last year. The company’s on-demand and scheduled grocery delivery is now available in 400 cities, including key markets like New York City, San Francisco, and Washington, DC. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3OkoHV"&gt;Uber’s grocery delivery service got turbo-charged by a partnership with Albertsons Companies, the publicly traded owner of major grocery brands like Safeway, Vons, Jewel-Osco, Shaw’s, Acme, Tom Thumb, Randalls, United Supermarkets, Pavilions, Star Market, Haggen, Carrs, Kings Food Markets, and Balducci’s Food Lover’s Market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LtPVAV"&gt;The ride-hailing company (which is quickly becoming more of a delivery company) expects to be able to offer grocery delivery to customers nationwide by the end of the year. Still, Uber will have its work cut out for it as it seeks to compete with major players in the grocery delivery space, including Amazon and Instacart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="9PMSHi"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Uber’s core ride-hailing business tanked as a result of lockdown orders&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OmDjwO"&gt;During the pandemic, Uber’s core ride-hailing business tanked as a result of lockdown orders. In response, the company quickly pivoted to food delivery and later to groceries, as it sought to find new revenue streams. Today, Uber is still relying heavily on cash from its delivery products as it struggles to make up for a nationwide driver shortage. Of course, delivery won’t work without drivers either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fHFYw9"&gt;To help fuel its grocery delivery expansion, Uber has acquired a number of smaller startups in recent months, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/6/21312447/uber-postmates-acquisition-announced-food-delivery"&gt;Postmates&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/7/21315159/uber-grocery-delivery-launch-cornershop-latin-america-canada"&gt;Cornershop&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://investor.uber.com/news-events/news/press-release-details/2021/Uber-to-Acquire-Drizly/default.aspx"&gt;Drizly&lt;/a&gt;, as it seeks to expand its delivery options. In addition to Albertsons, Uber is also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419461/uber-gopuff-grocery-delivery-expansion"&gt;partnering with delivery startup Gopuff&lt;/a&gt;, which specializes in delivering “essential” or “instant need” items, like liquor, beauty and pet products, snacks, and over-the-counter medication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NiU5xb"&gt;Using Uber the old-school way, to get a ride somewhere, is more expensive than it’s ever been. Fares are up by as much as 40 percent, with Uber CEO Dara Khosrowshahi &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/07/16/style/uber-ceo-dara-khosrowshahi.html"&gt;admitting to &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in a recent interview that price is “not where it needs to be right now.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SFd8QR"&gt;It remains to be seen how the shortage is effecting prices on its grocery delivery plans. (Uber is promising free delivery on orders of more than $30 for its Uber Pass subscription members.) Khosrowshahi said that the company’s second quarter margins, which are scheduled to be reported August 4th, will be “hurt” by the company’s efforts to lure drivers back with financial incentives. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583397/uber-grocery-delivery-expansion-cities-safeway-acme"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583397/uber-grocery-delivery-expansion-cities-safeway-acme</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-19T10:19:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-19T10:19:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>Anker batteries, cables, and chargers are discounted on Amazon</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Hhf5SW9nBAUQf8gubSWmEhhqkf4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69600509/vpavic_190409_3354_0034.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="azmsgz"&gt;Whether you’re gearing up for the back-to-school season or just looking for some extra charging kits to make your vacation go a little smoother, Anker’s latest discounts at Amazon might have what you’re looking for. There are a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/deal/e735e735?showVariations=false&amp;amp;ref=deals_deals_deals-grid_slot-15_69e1_dt_dcell_vai_1_e735e735"&gt;handful of products&lt;/a&gt; on sale, including &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Anker-Lightning-Powerline-Certified-Compatible/dp/B08G8NTVQ7?ref_=Oct_DLandingS_D_e735e735_60&amp;amp;smid=A294P4X9EWVXLJ&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a three-pack of iPhone cables&lt;/a&gt; (USB-A-to-Lightning) for $19.49 instead of $30, and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Anker-Delivery-PowerPort-Outlets-White_Cable/dp/B08B7P7CJX?ref_=Oct_DLandingS_D_e735e735_62&amp;amp;smid=A294P4X9EWVXLJ&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a clever power strip with two outlets and three USB ports&lt;/a&gt; (two USB-A ports and one USB-C 18W PD port) for $26 instead of $36. There’s also &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Anker-Wireless-Charger-Fast-Charging-Adapter/dp/B07YD77RKC?ref_=Oct_DLandingS_D_e735e735_65&amp;amp;smid=A294P4X9EWVXLJ&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a 15W Qi wireless charging pad available for $20 instead of $30&lt;/a&gt;, but it doesn’t include a power adapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CwOL8O"&gt;The niftiest device that’s discounted today is Anker’s Powercore Fusion wall charger-meets-battery pack. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Anker-PowerCore-Portable-10000mAh-Delivery/dp/B08GKL41V4?ref_=Oct_DLandingS_D_e735e735_61&amp;amp;smid=A294P4X9EWVXLJ&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The black-colored GaN charger with a 10,000mAh battery within costs $34.50 today instead of $46&lt;/a&gt;. With it, you can charge devices up to 20W via USB-C or up to 15W when you use that port and the USB-A simultaneously, whether you’re connected to the wall or using the Fusion as a battery pack. It probably won’t be powerful enough to charge your laptop while you use it (unless you use something like a Chromebook), but it seems great for smaller devices and accessories. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/11/18306269/anker-powercore-fusion-usb-c-power-delivery-battery-charger-review"&gt;Check out Dieter Bohn’s review right here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="G0RohD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10658582"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HGfqfNUpkQIqqzKnv6M2f13zTSo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22529636/DSCF3948_4.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="oUySO1"&gt;In case you wanted to snag Apple’s new and improved Siri Remote for the Apple TV streaming boxes, Verizon has it available for $10 less than Apple’s price. &lt;a href="https://www.dpbolvw.net/click-8836598-14066852?sid=VergeDeals&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.verizon.com%2Fproducts%2Fapple-siri-remote-apple-tv%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;You can get one for $50 right here&lt;/a&gt;. You don’t need to have purchased one of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22454960/apple-tv-4k-2021-review"&gt;new Apple TVs&lt;/a&gt; to use it; it’s compatible with previous models that run Apple’s tvOS software, including the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1361939-REG%2Fapple_mqd22ll_a_tv_4k_32gb.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F7%2F19%2F22583300%2Fanker-batteries-cables-chargers-apple-siri-remote-tv-4k-airpods-pro-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;last-gen Apple TV 4K that costs $120&lt;/a&gt; at B&amp;amp;H Photo today, down from $180. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="rn95re"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10509961"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2wpIpM"&gt;There are some other great deals happening today, even if their discounts are small:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="qBG9yb"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1598683-REG%2Fapple_aphomepmsg_homepod_mini_space_gray.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F7%2F19%2F22583300%2Fanker-batteries-cables-chargers-apple-siri-remote-tv-4k-airpods-pro-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple HomePod Mini costs $90&lt;/a&gt; at B&amp;amp;H Photo (normally $100).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lp8NsT"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8836598-13142092?sid=verge&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Felectronics.woot.com%2Foffers%2Fgoogle-pixel-stand-fast-wireless-charger-3%3Fref%3Dw_cnt_wp_3_1" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Google Pixel Stand wireless charger (the only Qi charger to provide the fastest wireless charging speeds for the Pixel 3, 4, 5)&lt;/a&gt; is $37 at Woot (usually $80).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PnvqqN"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MWP22AM-A-AirPods-Pro/dp/B07ZPC9QD4/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple’s AirPods Pro wireless earbuds are $190&lt;/a&gt; at Amazon, which is the most affordable price online for a new set.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="nnd9gM"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/7/19/22583300/anker-batteries-cables-chargers-apple-siri-remote-tv-4k-airpods-pro-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/7/19/22583300/anker-batteries-cables-chargers-apple-siri-remote-tv-4k-airpods-pro-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-19T10:07:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-19T10:07:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>CNN plans to launch CNN Plus streaming service, but won’t say how much it will cost</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="CNN" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eN0Xib76RTF6B2x6z2I7IhrgdGE=/0x0:3438x2292/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69600462/1211180725.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Thomas Trutschel/Photothek via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="v1cn97"&gt;Cable news behemoth CNN said Monday it is joining the ever-crowded streaming marketplace, adding its CNN Plus service sometime in the first quarter, according to a press release. The new service “complements the core CNN linear networks and digital platforms to serve CNN superfans, news junkies and fans of quality non-fiction programming.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="giGL1n"&gt;Conspicuously missing from the press release was any mention of how much the service will cost, and a spokeswoman declined to provide further details. According to &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/digital/news/inside-cnn-plus-a-first-look-at-the-new-streaming-service-exclusive-1235022517/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the company is still determining the price for CNN Plus, but there will be no ad-supported version of the service at launch. It will launch in the US only, and CNN expects to hire 450 people over the next six to nine months, &lt;em&gt;Variety &lt;/em&gt;reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4bq5oY"&gt;The company says CNN will continue to have a single app where CNN Plus subscribers will be able to access CNN Plus programming. The app will include CNN’s linear television feeds, available to paid TV subscribers. If those subscribers want to “maximize their experience, they can also subscribe to CNN Plus, to access the full CNN Plus programming all in one place,” the release says. A CNN spokeswoman clarified that CNN Plus subscribers do not have access to the TVE feeds of CNN’s cable channels, and CNN Plus is a standalone direct-to-consumer product. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hY5FtH"&gt;CNN Plus will have original, live, on-demand, and interactive programming separate and distinct from CNN’s linear channels, the company says. At launch the service will have a “deep library of non-fiction, long form programming,” that includes past seasons of CNN shows like&lt;em&gt; Anthony Bourdain: Parts Unknown&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Stanley Tucci: Searching for Italy&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;This is Life with Lisa Ling&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;United Shades of America&lt;/em&gt; with W. Kamau Bell. The service will add new original programming to be announced later this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uZEcsN"&gt;Andrew Morse, CNN Worldwide chief digital officer, will be the executive in charge of CNN Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9Et7lh"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Spwoev"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583424/cnn-plus-launch-streaming-service-first-quarter"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583424/cnn-plus-launch-streaming-service-first-quarter</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-19T09:56:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-19T09:56:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nvidia paves the way for RTX GPU Chromebooks with new Arm demo</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FYQCbZdKiyNVk5a0yMHHmTgwrdg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69600347/acastro_180529_1777_nvidia_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OJpi77"&gt;Nvidia is working on expanding its RTX GPU support in a big way, &lt;a href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/2021/07/19/geforce-rtx-arm-gdc/"&gt;with a new demo at GDC 2021&lt;/a&gt; showcasing high-end gaming technologies like DLSS and ray-traced lighting running on Arm hardware for the first time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B1h9wx"&gt;Specifically, the demo shows off &lt;em&gt;Wolfenstein: Youngblood&lt;/em&gt; and Nvidia’s “&lt;em&gt;The Bistro&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;demo running on an RTX 3060 GPU paired with a MediaTek Kompanio 1200 Arm processor (&lt;a href="https://corp.mediatek.com/news-events/press-releases/mediatek-announces-new-mt8192-and-mt8195-chipsets-designed-for-next-generation-of-chromebooks"&gt;MediaTek’s flagship-level processor&lt;/a&gt; planned for a new wave of more powerful Chromebooks). Obviously, an RTX 3060 can run those demos on its own — but it’s the groundwork here that Nvidia is building that’s important because it’s offering the drivers and support necessary for them to run on Arm hardware specifically. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="43iAe3"&gt;In total, Nvidia says that its ported five RTX technologies to Arm and Linux: DLSS, RTX Direct Illumination, RTX Global Illumination, RTX Memory Utility, and Nvidia’s Optix AI-Accelerated Denoiser. SDKs for those tools for Arm with Linux and Chromium are either available now or will be available soon for developers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QsgPqE"&gt;And while it’ll still likely be some time before you’re able to buy a Chromebook with an Arm chip and an RTX 3080 GPU, today’s news is an important proof of concept establishing that it’s both possible to add that support and that Nvidia is actually interested in building the tools and software necessary to do so. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C8GMgc"&gt;Of course, Nvidia &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; have a newly vested interest in making sure its GPUs play nicely with popular Arm-based systems like Chromebooks in the future, given its (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22391744/nvidia-arm-acquisition-uk-competition-regulator-cma-investigation-national-security-grounds"&gt;still pending&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/14/21435890/nvidia-arm-acquisition-40-billion-ai-cloud-edge-why"&gt;purchase of Arm for $40 billion&lt;/a&gt; last year. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583376/nvidia-gdc-2021-demo-rtx-gpu-ray-tracing-dlss-arm-chromebook"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583376/nvidia-gdc-2021-demo-rtx-gpu-ray-tracing-dlss-arm-chromebook</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
