<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2020-12-09T17:34:44-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-09T17:34:44-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-09T17:34:44-05:00</updated>
    <title>Ratatouille: The TikTok Musical to become an actual one-night Broadway-style show</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pavg5LXanwee5B9zvJ97iRNlwHQ=/44x0:607x375/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68487423/Seaview_Work_Featured_Images_Ratatouille_650x375.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="d3pgHB"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vulture.com/2020/11/ratatouille-musical-tiktok.html"&gt;TikTok’s fan-made crowdsourced &lt;em&gt;Ratatouille&lt;/em&gt; musical&lt;/a&gt; is making the jump from social media to the stage. &lt;em&gt;Ratatouille: The TikTok Musical&lt;/em&gt; is going to debut as an actual show for a one-night-only concert on January 1st, which will benefit The Actors Fund. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JmByGX"&gt;The streamed show will be produced by &lt;a href="https://seaviewprods.com/work/ratatouille-the-tiktok-musical/"&gt;Seaview Productions&lt;/a&gt; (best known for producing &lt;em&gt;Slave Play&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/10/15/theater/tony-award-nominations.html"&gt;most Tony Award-nominated show&lt;/a&gt; in Broadway history) and is being presented “in association with TikTok.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KMKWIG"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/culture-features/ratatouille-tiktok-musical-oral-history-1091547/"&gt;so-called &lt;em&gt;Ratatouille&lt;/em&gt; musical&lt;/a&gt; — based on the 2007 Disney / Pixar film — has been percolating over the past several months on TikTok. What started as a one-off bit has slowly snowballed into a massive undertaking, with bored Broadway fans, composers, set designers, costume makers, choreographers, and more working together to build bits and pieces of the (until now) fictional show. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="KluXDL"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="tiktok-embed" cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@danieljmertzlufft/video/6885475193410620678" data-video-id="6885475193410620678" style="max-width: 605px;min-width: 325px;"&gt; &lt;section&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" title="@danieljmertzlufft" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@danieljmertzlufft"&gt;@danieljmertzlufft&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p&gt;Remy: The Musical OG Song @e_jaccs add. Vocals @cjaskier &lt;a title="remy" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/remy"&gt;#remy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="ratatouille" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/ratatouille"&gt;#ratatouille&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="musicaltheatre" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/musicaltheatre"&gt;#musicaltheatre&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="broadway" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/broadway"&gt;#broadway&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="singer" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/singer"&gt;#singer&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="musical" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/musical"&gt;#musical&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="disney" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/disney"&gt;#disney&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="fyp" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/fyp"&gt;#fyp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="disneymusicals" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/disneymusicals"&gt;#disneymusicals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" title="♬ original sound - danieljmertzlufft" href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/original-sound-6885475237366926086"&gt;♬ original sound - danieljmertzlufft&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/section&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async="" src="https://www.tiktok.com/embed.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4jUXiA"&gt;There aren’t many details yet on what the actual show will look like, although the musical promises to “celebrate the delectable crowd-sourced creation by giving it the full high-kicking, lip-smacking Broadway treatment.” Just what that means in terms of the scope of the show is, as of yet, unclear. The cast and creative team have similarly not yet been announced, although some of “Broadway’s biggest and brightest talents” are apparently involved. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hafpIQ"&gt;Many of the viral TikTok stars that have helped contribute to the crowdsourced show in the past few months are involved in the production, too. &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@blakeyrouse?lang=en"&gt;Blake Rouse&lt;/a&gt; (the composer behind two of the more popular songs on TikTok, “&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VjU_p3uvlkU"&gt;The Rat’s Way of Life&lt;/a&gt;” and “&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MvI0Lg8JmPQ"&gt;Ratatouille Tango&lt;/a&gt;”) tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that his songs will be featured in the show. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tinymallet/status/1327652187980312579"&gt;Jess Siswick&lt;/a&gt; — another TikTok creator — is having her &lt;a href="https://www.playbill.com/article/presenting-the-official-fake-ratatouille-playbill"&gt;mocked-up Playbill program&lt;/a&gt; for the show appear as the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.todaytix.com%2Fx%2Fnyc%2Fshows%2F22803-Ratatouille--The-TikTok-Musical&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2020%2F12%2F9%2F22166215%2Fratatouille-the-tiktok-musical-broadway-show-todaytix-streaming-one-night-date-viral-disney#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;actual promotional artwork&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WGdFSw"&gt;Two of the &lt;em&gt;Ratatouille&lt;/em&gt; musical’s original creators also appear to be involved, or at least approve of the project: both &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/anEmilyJacobsen/status/1336789469018681344"&gt;Emily Jacobsen&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@e_jaccs/video/6859521038418447622?referer_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.playbill.com%2F&amp;amp;referer_video_id=6859521038418447622"&gt;@e_jaccs&lt;/a&gt;), who wrote the original “&lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@e_jaccs/video/6859521038418447622?referer_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.playbill.com%2F&amp;amp;referer_video_id=6859521038418447622"&gt;Remy the Ratatouille&lt;/a&gt;” song for TikTok, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/danieljmertz/status/1336765015911768069"&gt;composer Daniel Mertzlufft&lt;/a&gt;, whose viral &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@danieljmertzlufft/video/6885475193410620678?referer_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.playbill.com%2F&amp;amp;referer_video_id=6885475193410620678"&gt;theatrical arrangement of that song&lt;/a&gt; helped kickstart the &lt;em&gt;Ratatouille&lt;/em&gt; frenzy, have both tweeted about the project. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bGlIPL"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;SOOOO wild! &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ratatouillemusical?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#ratatouillemusical&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ratatousical?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@ratatousical&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/xgGdUSU5nB"&gt;https://t.co/xgGdUSU5nB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Emily Jacobsen (@anEmilyJacobsen) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/anEmilyJacobsen/status/1336789469018681344?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 9, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uWJphu"&gt;Most importantly, though, the project appears to have Disney’s blessing: “Although we do not have development plans for the title, we love when our fans engage with Disney stories. We applaud and thank all of the online theatre makers for helping to benefit The Actors Fund in this unprecedented time of need,” notes a Disney statement provided to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n0tckV"&gt;The show will stream through &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.todaytix.com%2Fx%2Fnyc%2Fshows%2F22803-Ratatouille--The-TikTok-Musical&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2020%2F12%2F9%2F22166215%2Fratatouille-the-tiktok-musical-broadway-show-todaytix-streaming-one-night-date-viral-disney#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;TodayTix&lt;/a&gt; on January 1st at 7PM ET, with tickets ranging from $5 to $50 (depending on the desired donation); following the premiere, the show will be available to watch on demand for 72 hours. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22166215/ratatouille-the-tiktok-musical-broadway-show-todaytix-streaming-one-night-date-viral-disney"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22166215/ratatouille-the-tiktok-musical-broadway-show-todaytix-streaming-one-night-date-viral-disney</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-09T17:29:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-09T17:29:26-05:00</updated>
    <title>The pandemic turned the volume down on ocean noise pollution</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Humpback Whale, Mother and Calf, Megaptera novaeangliae, Socorro, Revillagigedo Islands, Mexico" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZRynkAygy9J6YN0Mb7QvWM_V-T4=/0x0:5315x3543/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68487402/550595891.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Humpback whales, mother and calf, near Socorro, Revillagigedo Islands, Mexico.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Reinhard Dirscherl / ullstein bild via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tnNvUL"&gt;The economic fallout from COVID-19 has temporarily muted some of the noise coming from maritime traffic. That’s given scientists a rare opportunity to study what happens to marine life when humans quiet down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qxZpZU"&gt;Humans today pollute oceans with whirring ship propellers and booming air guns searching for oil and gas deposits. Seeing whales and other creatures’ behavior now that the pandemic has quieted things down is like a peek into what marine life was like before humans drastically turned up the volume over the past 200 years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="kRh3wP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Once in a lifetime opportunity to study whale communication in natural quiet”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GfPG9I"&gt;“It’s like this horrible pandemic confined us humans into really small spaces but gave the whales back a lot of room to grow, both physically and acoustically,” Christine Gabriele, a wildlife biologist at Glacier Bay National Park and Preserve, said in a press briefing. “I’m lucky actually to take this once in a lifetime opportunity to study whale communication in natural quiet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Soiwsr"&gt;Without the presence of cruise ships and tour boats that bring hundreds of thousands of visitors to Glacier Bay, Alaska, each year, humpback whales had a chance to take up more space and relax. Researchers observed them socializing and even taking naps out in the middle of channels that typically would have been loud and busy with vessels. Median daily sound levels in the bay in 2020 were 50 percent quieter than they were at the same time last year, according to Gabriele. It was so quiet, Gabriele was able to &lt;a href="https://www.nps.gov/glba/learn/nature/soundclips.htm"&gt;listen in&lt;/a&gt; on what she believed was a long exchange between a mother and calf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VWWa3J"&gt;Gabriele and other researchers are tuning into a network of hydrophones, which are basically underwater microphones, to document these changes. She was one of several scientists with the National Park Service, National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), and Texas A&amp;amp;M University at Galveston who shared preliminary findings from their research today. They held a briefing on ocean noise during the annual American Geophysical Union Fall meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lrl4dU"&gt;Along the coastlines of the Pacific Northwest and British Columbia, ocean noise levels dropped by about 30 percent this spring, thanks to fewer vessels. Human-created noise off the shorelines of California and Massachusetts also decreased, researchers said during the briefing. They’re still conducting their studies and have yet to publish much of their work. They plan to collaborate with scientists from other regions of the world to get a better global picture of the pandemic’s effects on ocean soundscapes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="0Gwiwy"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Research can inform policies and technological advances&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PuMafw"&gt;The researchers will also continue watching humpback whales closely. They’ll take biopsy samples from the whales to see if there are any differences in their stress hormones this year and next year. And they’re listening in on how the whales’ communication might change. They’re curious about whether whales’ vocalizations get more complex when they can hear each other better and vice versa. Studies in the past have found that whales raise their voices as ambient noise increases — just like humans might in a noisy environment — which doesn’t usually make for drawn-out exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VgS2X5"&gt;There are plenty of &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/01/22/science/oceans-whales-noise-offshore-drilling.html"&gt;other ways&lt;/a&gt; that diverse sea life depends on sound to navigate their worlds, find food, and avoid becoming food for something else. Scientists are scrambling to make the most out of this quiet reprieve to better understand all that. The hope is that some of this research can inform policies and technological advances that might be able to keep the ocean clamor down to bearable levels in the future, even as economic activity picks back up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J2klJc"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vYxnNa"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22166314/covid-19-pandemic-ocean-noise-pollution"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22166314/covid-19-pandemic-ocean-noise-pollution</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-09T16:50:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-09T16:50:16-05:00</updated>
    <title>At his last Space Council meeting, Mike Pence announces new cadre of lunar astronauts</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/D5mza40o0O3iXglhta8Wv9ezXtI=/135x0:1494x906/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68487186/Screen_Shot_2020_12_09_at_2.48.14_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EydK9M"&gt;On Wednesday, Vice President Mike Pence hosted his last meeting of the National Space Council in Florida, using the opportunity to announce a list of NASA astronauts who will be considered for future missions to the Moon as part of NASA’s Artemis program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xIRPPY"&gt;This cadre of astronauts — &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/specials/artemis-team/"&gt;dubbed the Artemis Team&lt;/a&gt; — includes 18 astronauts, some with past flight experience and some who have yet to fly to space. The list includes some notable names, such as Christina Koch and Jessica Meir, the two women who made history by performing the first all-women spacewalk. Two of the astronauts, Victor Glover and Kate Rubins, are currently living on board the International Space Station. Five of the 18 made an appearance at the National Space Council meeting today at NASA’s Kennedy Space Center in Florida: Meir, Jessica Watkins, Anne McClain, Matthew Dominick, and Joe Acaba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ArWqn6"&gt;With no flight assignments made yet, it’s unclear which of the nine women in the group will be the first chosen to fly to the Moon — a goal that NASA has been touting since the creation of the Artemis program. And it’s possible that this group will change, according to NASA administrator Jim Bridenstine. “This is the first cadre of our Artemis astronauts,” he said at the meeting. “I want to be clear, there’s going to be more.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="LGlhe6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s unclear which of the nine women in the group will be the first chosen to fly&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NNsXoE"&gt;The meeting didn’t just focus on the astronauts. Pence also announced that President Trump released a new National Space Policy, a &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/National-Space-Policy.pdf"&gt;32-page document&lt;/a&gt; laying out the president’s space vision for the executive branch. “It emphasizes that space is critical to our security and our way of life, and lays out the fundamental principles to put America first in space,” Pence said of the policy. The previous National Space Policy was issued in June 2010 under the Obama administration. Pence also announced today that the administration would be renaming two Air Force bases — the Patrick Air Force Base and the Cape Canaveral Air Force Station — to Space Force bases. Another base will also be named after the pioneering aviator Chuck Yeager, who died at the age of 97 on December 7th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="do7fxm"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oG2JwwOphLQ?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6xCjb1"&gt;The astronaut announcement, in particular, is an interesting statement to make as the country prepares for a new administration. In the past, transitions have resulted in abrupt changes to space policy. Under the Obama administration, NASA had been focused on putting people on Mars, but in 2017, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/11/16761862/nasa-moon-mission-mars-donald-trump"&gt;President Trump signed a space policy directive&lt;/a&gt; tasking NASA with returning people to the Moon. Ever since then, NASA has been hard at work crafting a program to get astronauts to the lunar surface, using a mixture of hardware that’s long been in development as well as spacecraft that still needs to be built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2oag1H"&gt;In 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/26/18282598/nasa-mike-pence-vice-president-space-policy-lunar-landings-2024-gateway-sls-orion"&gt;Pence famously challenged NASA&lt;/a&gt; with achieving its first lunar landing under the Artemis program by 2024, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/18/18629403/nasa-artemis-moon-program-funds-hardware-apollo-11-anniversary"&gt;an incredibly ambitious deadline&lt;/a&gt; that would be difficult to meet. Bridenstine has worked hard to secure extra funding, lobbying Congress to spend an extra $3.4 billion next year to help fund lunar landers that will take humans to the surface of the Moon. So far, lawmakers have drafted legislation that would partially fund these landers, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/10/21558572/nasa-senate-appropriations-artemis-program-moon-landers"&gt;but they seem reluctant to provide the full amount&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="NGVMjH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;An interesting statement to make as the country prepares for a new administration&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TkVvhR"&gt;With President-elect Joe Biden set to take office in January, the future of the Artemis program is even more uncertain. No officials associated with the incoming Biden administration have provided any hints of what the new president’s space agenda will look like, especially in regards to the human exploration program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uCIUF1"&gt;But for now, NASA is still working toward its Moon goal. The Space Launch System — the giant rocket that the space agency plans to use to send people to the Moon — is about to undergo a key test in Mississippi ahead of its first uncrewed flight, scheduled for late 2021. Early next year, NASA also plans to select two companies to move forward with creating new lunar landers. And now, NASA has a distinct group of astronauts it can pick from when it’s time to actually fly people to the Moon again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k65vxB"&gt;With all of these pieces in place, it may make it more difficult for the new administration to cancel the Artemis program. But it’s possible that some significant changes are still in store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="58grB4"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fwam7K"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22166077/nasa-artemis-astronauts-18-first-woman-moon-mike-pence-space-council"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22166077/nasa-artemis-astronauts-18-first-woman-moon-mike-pence-space-council</id>
    <author>
      <name>Loren Grush</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-09T16:40:28-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-09T16:40:28-05:00</updated>
    <title>Boeing’s 737 Max is back in service</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="BRAZIL-US-AVIATION-BOEING" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jdw9sSgu21299JEe-etOiSejNgI=/0x26:2518x1705/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68487125/1230028671.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Silvio Avila / AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DPYGdc"&gt;Boeing’s troubled 737 Max made its first commercial flight since March 2019 today, marking the end of a 20-month grounding following two deadly crashes that killed 346 people. Brazil’s Gol Airlines was the first in the world to put paying customers on the plane again since the Federal Aviation Administration &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/18/21573113/boeing-737-max-cleared-fly-grounding-faa-crashes"&gt;approved its return to flight in November&lt;/a&gt;. A 737 Max 8 ferried passengers from Sao Paulo to Porto Alegre, &lt;a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/business/boeing-737-max-back-in-air-2-years-after-grounded-by-crashes/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Associated Press&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9I7rRc"&gt;Gol Airlines told the publication it plans to use the 737 Max in regular service starting later this month, and passengers who don’t want to fly on the plane will be able to exchange their tickets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cLrAbJ"&gt;Other airlines are getting ready to bring the plane back into their fleets, too. American Airlines &lt;a href="http://news.aa.com/news/news-details/2020/Return-of-the-Boeing-737-MAX-to-service-OPS-DIS-11/default.aspx"&gt;has said&lt;/a&gt; it plans to reintroduce the 737 Max to its fleets by first flying without passengers and then slowly restoring commercial service starting at the end of the year. Southwest Airlines, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/23/20927213/boeing-737-max-southwest-planes-crash-budget-airlines-grounded-cost-maintenance"&gt;made the biggest bet on the 737 Max&lt;/a&gt; when it was introduced a few years ago, says it will restart commercial flights &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.southwest.com%2F737-max%2F%23return-to-service-plan&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2020%2F12%2F9%2F22165956%2Fboeing-737-max-flight-brazil-gol-airlines#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;no sooner than the second quarter of 2021&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YuMCKq"&gt;One thing holding up a wholesale return to the skies for the 737 Max is airlines must put pilots through new &lt;a href="https://aviationweek.com/air-transport/safety-ops-regulation/how-much-time-will-new-boeing-737-max-pilot-training-take"&gt;FAA-approved training specific to the problem that doomed the flights in 2018 and 2019&lt;/a&gt;. Planes that were in storage also need to be “&lt;a href="https://aviationweek.com/aerospace/how-long-will-flight-crew-training-take-boeing-737-maxs-return"&gt;depreserved&lt;/a&gt;,” or brought back into flying shape, and &lt;a href="https://aviationweek.com/aerospace/how-long-will-flight-crew-training-take-boeing-737-maxs-return"&gt;updated with new wiring and software&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AnjCVX"&gt;The two deadly crashes in late 2018 and early 2019 were caused in part because Boeing originally obscured the need for training on a tricky new piece of the 737 Max’s software. While trying to keep pace with rival Airbus’ fuel-efficient A320neo aircraft, Boeing had redesigned the prior 737 to use bigger, more economical engines. But the placement of those engines could cause a stall in certain takeoff situations. So Boeing developed software known as Maneuvering Characteristics Augmentation System (MCAS), which counteracted the stall by automatically pushing the plane’s nose down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sx8VGP"&gt;In an effort to save time and money, though, the company didn’t tell the FAA or customers about MCAS. That meant the pilots of the two fatal crashes were &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/2/18518176/boeing-737-max-crash-problems-human-error-mcas-faa"&gt;fighting a system they didn’t even know existed&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22165956/boeing-737-max-flight-brazil-gol-airlines"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22165956/boeing-737-max-flight-brazil-gol-airlines</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-09T16:25:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-09T16:25:01-05:00</updated>
    <title>Adobe just released the last Flash update ever</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Adobe Flash Logo" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bHLBA_dPBaAcuHeGoZ0f7QnExOw=/0x23:600x423/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68487031/adobe-flash-logo.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rEA041"&gt;Adobe has released the final scheduled update to its Flash Player plugin, weeks before Flash’s official retirement. As noted &lt;a href="https://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/release-note/fp_32_air_32_release_notes.html"&gt;on Adobe’s site&lt;/a&gt;, yesterday marked the last update for Flash outside mainland China, which has a separate version of the software. Adobe will stop supporting Flash on December 31st, 2020, and it will block Flash content from running on January 12th, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ietqEh"&gt;Adobe offered a brief farewell in its release notes. “We want to take a moment to thank all of our customers and developers who have used and created amazing Flash Player content over the last two decades,” the note says. “We are proud that Flash had a crucial role in evolving web content across animation, interactivity, audio, and video. We are excited to help lead the next era of digital experiences.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Arpp2a"&gt;Flash has been on the chopping block since 2017 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/7/25/16026236/adobe-flash-end-of-support-2020"&gt;when Adobe announced&lt;/a&gt; it would finally end support. Flash was already being phased out in major web browsers, and Adobe had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/12/1/9827778/stop-using-flash"&gt;urged developers&lt;/a&gt; in 2015 to switch to newer standards like HTML5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v60Kxh"&gt;There were good reasons to disable Flash, including frequent and numerous security holes. But it threatened the survival of countless old games and animations — a problem for web preservationists and anyone who fondly remembers platforms like Newgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4b5bV9"&gt;Fortunately, we’ve seen numerous efforts to keep Flash media alive. An open-source emulator &lt;a href="https://ruffle.rs/#"&gt;called Ruffle&lt;/a&gt; will enable old Flash files through a desktop app or web browser. The Internet Archive is using Ruffle to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/19/21578616/internet-archive-preservation-flash-animations-games-adobe"&gt;preserve over 1,000 games and animations&lt;/a&gt; on its site. And Flash mega-portal Kongregate &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/2/21311318/kongregate-stops-accepting-new-game-submissions-flash-discontinued-layoffs"&gt;partnered with a museum&lt;/a&gt; to preserve its library of projects. But Adobe is about to finally say goodbye for good.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22166160/adobe-last-flash-player-update-support-ending-december"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22166160/adobe-last-flash-player-update-support-ending-december</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-09T16:23:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-09T16:23:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>Privacy group files complaint against five online test-proctoring services</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="BULGARIA-HEALTH-VIRUS-EDUCATION" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jDc4iFRX5-C5HCeIUarEdxOmL20=/4x0:4713x3139/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68487023/1229868184.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Kamen, 9, attends an online class at his home in Sofia, Bulgaria. | Photo by NIKOLAY DOYCHINOV/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XNOamV"&gt;The Electronic Privacy Information Center (EPIC) has &lt;a href="https://epic.org/privacy/dccppa/online-test-proctoring/EPIC-complaint-in-re-online-test-proctoring-companies-12-09-20.pdf"&gt;filed a complaint&lt;/a&gt; with the DC Attorney General’s office against five online test-proctoring services: Respondus, ProctorU, Proctorio, Examity, and Honorlock. EPIC claims that the firms violate the privacy rights of students. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5waCJ0"&gt;The five companies sell software designed to prevent cheating in online tests and exams. Some are designed to track applications that are running on test-takers’ computers or restrict access to certain programs during the testing period. Others track students’ activity during the test via their webcams and microphones and flag potentially suspicious behavior to their instructor, using either algorithms or live monitoring. In some cases, test-takers need to show a proctor their surroundings and verify their identity with personal information before the test can begin. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gnPNDO"&gt;These methods — the collection of personal information and the use of “secret algorithms” — amount to “unfair and deceptive trade practices,” EPIC argues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JNn1wT"&gt;“Respondents’ collection of sensitive personal information, including biometric data, is unjustified, excessive, and harmful to students who have no meaningful opportunity to opt out of such systems,” the complaint further reads. “Forcibly collecting personal information from test-takers, including sensitive biometric data, is inherently invasive.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="fzkf0p"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Respondents’ collection of sensitive personal information, including biometric data, is unjustified, excessive, and harmful.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DFaegV"&gt;The use of remote test-proctoring services has skyrocketed with this year’s rise in online instruction at all grade levels. So, too, has scrutiny on its providers. Proctorio (one of EPIC’s targets, which over 400 universities use) &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/22/21526792/proctorio-online-test-proctoring-lawsuit-universities-students-coronavirus"&gt;came under fire&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year for its suite of “machine learning and advanced facial detection technologies,” which monitor the position of a student’s head while they take their test and flags possible signs of cheating. Critics called the service discriminatory, anxiety-provoking, and an invasion of privacy. Thousands of students have signed &lt;a href="https://www.change.org/p/amy-klobuchar-stop-the-use-of-online-proctoring-exams-at-the-university-of-minnesota?recruiter=1147745069&amp;amp;recruited_by_id=81b9d6d0-f2d4-11ea-8282-0d71d6651892&amp;amp;utm_source=share_petition&amp;amp;utm_medium=copylink&amp;amp;utm_campaign=petition_dashboard"&gt;petitions&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.ams.ubc.ca/news/open-letter-regarding-the-usage-of-proctorio/"&gt;open letters&lt;/a&gt; calling on their schools to get rid of the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vBQQmS"&gt;Examity, which provides live proctors who watch test-takers through their webcams, has also been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/29/21232777/examity-remote-test-proctoring-online-class-education"&gt;unpopular on some campuses&lt;/a&gt;. “Every student I know finds this the creepiest thing ever,” one University of Arizona student said of the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yfcjcR"&gt;The attorney general will need to act on EPIC’s complaint for it to result in any charges. But the group has made clear that it’s not backing down. It’s also &lt;a href="https://epic.org/privacy/dccppa/online-test-proctoring/index.html#legal"&gt;sent letters&lt;/a&gt; to all five companies warning them that it’s prepared to sue unless they agree to “limit their collection of personal data, comply with basic requirements for trustworthy AI, and submit to annual third-party audits.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22166023/epic-proctorio-examity-privacy-online-testing-school-lawsuit-proctoring"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22166023/epic-proctorio-examity-privacy-online-testing-school-lawsuit-proctoring</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-09T15:54:49-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-09T15:54:49-05:00</updated>
    <title>Redbox’s free ad-supported streaming service adds on-demand movies</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CdgtUgPjI-7e-kiobNLquLt98n8=/55x34:2334x1553/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68486727/image0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uP5sOn"&gt;Redbox has added on-demand movies to its free ad-supported streaming service in a section called Free On Demand (via &lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/redbox-streaming-free-movies-tv-shows-video-on-demand-205208288.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Engadget&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Last February, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/14/21138485/redbox-free-live-tv-ad-supported-streaming-platform-launch-rollout"&gt;the company launched Free Live TV&lt;/a&gt;, with ad-supported live TV channels from specific publishers like Tastemade and curated channels based on genres. Free movies now make that offering a bit more enticing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="USHNjc"&gt;Redbox is still best known for its red kiosks for renting DVDs and Blu-rays, but free streaming and its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/14/16775778/redbox-on-demand-streaming-service"&gt;digital rental service&lt;/a&gt; now allow the company to reach customers who might not have a kiosk in their area or don’t own a DVD or Blu-ray player. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pTYqRh"&gt;The selection in Free On Demand lacks some of the big blockbusters and classics that you might expect from a streaming service, but there are a few notable cult hits. You can currently watch director Rian Johnson’s second film &lt;em&gt;The Brothers Bloom&lt;/em&gt;, a dubbed version of the cyberpunk anime &lt;em&gt;Ghost in the Shell&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Kicking and Screaming&lt;/em&gt;, the feature debut of Noah Baumbach. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tJ1rSB"&gt;Redbox’s service joins several other free streaming options like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/23/18194071/viacom-pluto-tv-acquisition-340-million"&gt;Pluto TV&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/17/21184294/fox-tubi-acquisition-streaming-wars-news-sports-xumi-comcast-pluto-viacomcbs"&gt;Tubi&lt;/a&gt; in what’s quickly becoming a crowded market. Other than a connection to Redbox’s brand name and a theoretically curated catalog, there’s not a clear difference between Free On Demand and any other ad-supported streamer. But if you have the Redbox app already downloaded, you now have a new avenue for free content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="787Awd"&gt;Free On Demand is currently available in the Redbox app on the iOS, Android, Android TV, Roku, and Vizio SmartCast platforms. The service will come to more devices like Xboxes and Samsung TVs soon.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22165692/redbox-ad-supported-free-streaming-movies"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22165692/redbox-ad-supported-free-streaming-movies</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-09T15:29:09-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-09T15:29:09-05:00</updated>
    <title>Watch SpaceX fly a prototype of its Starship rocket to its highest altitude yet</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/izSE1T1styfUSfanRx1Gt8cG_90=/0x0:3840x2560/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68478163/SN8_20201110.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qIK1iO"&gt;Sometime today, SpaceX hopes to conduct a pivotal test flight of its next-generation Starship rocket, flying a prototype of the vehicle to its highest altitude yet. The company plans to launch the massive rocket to a height of nearly 8 miles, or 12.5 kilometers, up above SpaceX’s facility in Boca Chica, Texas, before landing the vehicle back down on the ground again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YISOcP"&gt;The test is meant to prove out Starship’s capability of launching and landing upright, something the spacecraft will be expected to do both on Earth and on other worlds. SpaceX aims to use Starship to send cargo and people to deep-space destinations like the Moon and Mars. A test like this will help demonstrate Starship’s ability to perform a controlled flight and see if the rocket’s hardware — particularly the three main Raptor engines — functions as expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="HFXPd7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Launch and landing are just part of the test today&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Ej2px2"&gt;Launch and landing are just part of today’s test. On its website, SpaceX claims the Starship prototype will actually perform “a landing flip maneuver, which would be a first for a vehicle of this size.” There aren’t many details about the maneuver publicly available, but it’s a risky test that could easily go wrong, with SpaceX CEO Elon Musk &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1331388984023461888?s=20"&gt;only giving the flight a “1/3 chance” of success&lt;/a&gt;. SpaceX itself is also deemphasizing the possibility that the test will pull off a perfect launch and landing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0UA3Gf"&gt;“With a test such as this, success is not measured by completion of specific objectives but rather how much we can learn, which will inform and improve the probability of success in the future as SpaceX rapidly advances development of Starship,” &lt;a href="https://www.spacex.com/vehicles/starship/index.html"&gt;SpaceX wrote about the flight on its website&lt;/a&gt;. But if all goes well, the flight will put the company on course to attempt even more ambitious tests in the future, eventually culminating in Starship’s first launch to orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P30HAF"&gt;For this test, SpaceX plans to provide a live stream of the flight, which will go live just ahead of takeoff. However, it’s hard to give a solid time for when that will happen. The Federal Aviation Administration released flight restrictions for the airspace around Boca Chica from 9AM to 6PM ET, and there are flight restrictions in place for Thursday and Friday of this week, too. “The schedule is dynamic and likely to change, as is the case with all development testing,” SpaceX writes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cUCPgz"&gt;SpaceX attempted a launch on Tuesday but aborted just a second before liftoff. Now it seems the company is targeting this afternoon for a flight test. The company will &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SpaceX"&gt;provide updates through Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, so be sure to follow SpaceX throughout the day to catch a glimpse of this rocket’s flight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3Pdviu"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update December 8th, 5:45PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; SpaceX counted all the way down to launch on Tuesday afternoon, but at 1.3 seconds to liftoff, the Raptor engines initiated an abort, and the Starship prototype didn’t take flight. The company will provide updates about its next launch opportunity &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SpaceX"&gt;&lt;em&gt;on its Twitter account&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163104/spacex-starship-prototype-test-flight-boca-chica-altitude"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163104/spacex-starship-prototype-test-flight-boca-chica-altitude</id>
    <author>
      <name>Loren Grush</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-09T15:24:14-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-09T15:24:14-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google CEO Sundar Pichai apologizes for Timnit Gebru controversy but not her firing</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Google Hosts Its Annual I/O Developers Conference" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e8y0PpKnweLynxwQaS-Ykurap2k=/0x0:5472x3648/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68486474/1147600084.jpg.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Justin Sullivan/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rkD4rh"&gt;Google CEO Sundar Pichai addressed the controversial departure of AI ethics researcher Timnit Gebru in an email to staff on Wednesday. “We need to accept responsibility for the fact that a prominent Black, female leader with immense talent left Google unhappily,” he wrote. News of the email was &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/sundar-pichai-memo-timnit-gebru-exit-18b0efb0-5bc3-41e6-ac28-2956732ed78b.html"&gt;first published by &lt;em&gt;Axios&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xZAAar"&gt;While Pichai did not say Gebru was fired as she and many others have claimed, he promised to review the steps that led to her leaving the company. “We need to assess the circumstances that led up to Dr. Gebru’s departure, examining where we could have improved and led a more respectful process,” he wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3jzOSM"&gt;He also apologized for how Gebru’s departure had “led some in our community to question their place at Google” and promised to consider “de-escalation strategies” for the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RTayc1"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/timnitGebru/status/1336758639785365506"&gt;On Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, Gebru wrote the note was far from an apology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JMH4hW"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Finally it does not say "I'm sorry for what we did to her and it was wrong." What it DOES say is "it seeded doubts and led some in our community to question their place at Google." So I see this as "I'm sorry for how it played out but I'm not sorry for what we did to her yet." 4\&lt;/p&gt;— Timnit Gebru (@timnitGebru) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/timnitGebru/status/1336758639785365506?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 9, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Psk5PP"&gt;Last week, Gebru tweeted that the company had abruptly fired her &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/3/22150355/google-fires-timnit-gebru-facial-recognition-ai-ethicist"&gt;over an email she sent to the Brain and Women Allies listserv&lt;/a&gt;. In the email, she voiced frustration at the company trying to get her to &lt;a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2020/12/04/1013294/google-ai-ethics-research-paper-forced-out-timnit-gebru/"&gt;retract a research paper on the risks of large language processing models&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nPdGaj"&gt;The email led to a conversation between Gebru and higher-ups at Google Research. Gebru asked for certain conditions to be met in order for her to stay at the company, including knowing the details of who had asked for her paper to be retracted. One of the managers, Megan Kacholia, said the company couldn’t meet those conditions and preemptively accepted her resignation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1beK1w"&gt;Google’s head of AI, Jeff Dean, &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1f2kYWDXwhzYnq8ebVtuk9CqQqz7ScqxhSIxeYGrWjK0/edit"&gt;published a note&lt;/a&gt; explaining why Gebru’s paper hadn’t met the company’s standards. He said it had been submitted for review a day before the deadline when the company typically requires two weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wVttCr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/7/22158501/timnit-gebru-team-google-public-statement-fired"&gt;But Gebru’s own team pushed back on this assessment&lt;/a&gt;, writing in a blogpost that the publication review policy was applied “unevenly and discriminatorily.” An internal analysis reviewed by &lt;em&gt;The Verg&lt;/em&gt;e showed that most publication approvals happen right before the deadline, and 41 percent happen after the deadline. “Numerous papers are approved for publication submission without meeting this ‘requirement,’” the team wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Uq6qZR"&gt;On December 4th, the Google Walkout Medium account &lt;a href="https://googlewalkout.medium.com/standing-with-dr-timnit-gebru-isupporttimnit-believeblackwomen-6dadc300d382"&gt;published a petition protesting Gebru’s firing&lt;/a&gt;. It was signed by 2,278 Google employees and 3,114 industry allies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tuVykl"&gt;Read Pichai’s full email here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="xiVr69"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lRkcD6"&gt;&lt;em&gt;One of the things I’ve been most proud of this year is how Googlers from across the company came together to address our racial equity commitments. It’s hard, important work, and while we’re steadfast in our commitment to do better, we have a lot to learn and improve. An important piece of this is learning from our experiences like the departure of Dr. Timnit Gebru.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CXcHrN"&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve heard the reaction to Dr. Gebru’s departure loud and clear: it seeded doubts and led some in our community to question their place at Google. I want to say how sorry I am for that, and I accept the responsibility of working to restore your trust.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9AwR6h"&gt;&lt;em&gt;First - we need to assess the circumstances that led up to Dr. Gebru’s departure, examining where we could have improved and led a more respectful process. We will begin a review of what happened to identify all the points where we can learn — considering everything from de-escalation strategies to new processes we can put in place. Jeff and I have spoken and are fully committed to doing this. One of the best aspects of Google’s engineering culture is our sincere desire to understand where things go wrong and how we can improve.  &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gBHCZ5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Second - we need to accept responsibility for the fact that a prominent Black, female leader with immense talent left Google unhappily. This loss has had a ripple effect through some of our least represented communities, who saw themselves and some of their experiences reflected in Dr. Gebru’s. It was also keenly felt because Dr. Gebru is an expert in an important area of AI Ethics that we must continue to make progress on — progress that depends on our ability to ask ourselves challenging questions. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dEjy5h"&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s incredibly important to me that our Black, women, and underrepresented Googlers know that we value you and you do belong at Google. And the burden of pushing us to do better should not fall on your shoulders. We started a conversation together earlier this year when we &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="http://goto.google.com/kw-progress-on-racial-equity"&gt;&lt;em&gt;announced&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; a broad set of racial equity commitments to take a fresh look at all of our systems from hiring and leveling, to promotion and retention, and to address the need for leadership accountability across all of these steps. The events of the last week are a painful but important reminder of the progress we still need to make.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fadS6I"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a top priority for me and Google leads, and I want to recommit to translating the energy that we’ve seen this year into real change as we move forward into 2021 and beyond. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="htJgAK"&gt;&lt;em&gt;— Sundar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="JaKNi1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22165983/google-ceo-sundar-pichai-apology-timnit-gebru-exit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22165983/google-ceo-sundar-pichai-apology-timnit-gebru-exit</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-09T15:05:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-09T15:05:30-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s privacy labels are coming to all apps, including its own</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/v5ROCKsp-0ZY7kaAJwf6endUcPM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68486285/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9NOW6I"&gt;Apple has clarified that its &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/app-store/app-privacy-details/"&gt;mandatory app privacy “nutrition labels”&lt;/a&gt; program will apply to all apps, whether they’re from third-party developers or Apple’s own. It’s an apparent response to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22165152/whatsapp-privacy-apple-first-third-party-app-store-nutrition-labels"&gt;criticism from WhatsApp earlier today&lt;/a&gt; that the program unfairly favored Apple’s services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pxSXLx"&gt;That means Apple’s apps on the App Store will receive similar privacy labels when the program rolls out later this year as third-party apps. And for the few iOS apps that aren’t available in the App Store — like Messages, a particular point of contention for WhatsApp — they will have the same privacy information available on Apple’s website. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HHNjJM"&gt;The statement follows a complaint from WhatsApp from earlier today in which the messaging service claimed that Apple’s system was unfair, as it would only impact third-party services but not Apple’s preinstalled apps. For its part, Apple had never announced any policy to indicate that its apps would be exempt from the privacy label requirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="s3ZRWC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;All apps will get privacy labels&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="L1C0P7"&gt;“We think labels should be consistent across first and third party apps as well as reflect the strong measures apps may take to protect people’s private information,” WhatsApp &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/whatsapp-apple-privacy-label-requirements-cc0d5edd-ab2f-4549-b9d7-ea3c97184056.html"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Axios&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;in a statement earlier today. “While providing people with easy to read information is a good start, we believe it’s important people can compare these ‘privacy nutrition’ labels from apps they download with apps that come pre-installed, like iMessage.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OUG1Fg"&gt;Apple first introduced the privacy labels as part of its WWDC announcements earlier this year. The labels — likened to nutrition facts found on food products — will appear in the App Store and give users easy, glanceable breakdowns of the data that developers can collect and track. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/5/21551926/apple-privacy-developers-nutrition-labels-app-store-ios-14"&gt;Developers were required&lt;/a&gt; to start submitting labels for their apps starting on December 8th, and the labels themselves are expected to start appearing “&lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/app-store/user-privacy-and-data-use/"&gt;later this year&lt;/a&gt;.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22165959/apple-privacy-nutrition-labels-all-apps-preinstalled-messages-web"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22165959/apple-privacy-nutrition-labels-all-apps-preinstalled-messages-web</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
