<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2022-01-19T19:30:52-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T19:30:52-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T19:30:52-05:00</updated>
    <title>Disney is putting a Disney Plus exec in charge of Hulu </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Disney Plus ESPN Plus Hulu bundle" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OWj2KRl76cUpfmyhyd8hNxrkF2M=/0x55:1396x986/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70410341/disney_plus.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gVfAKR"&gt;Disney has named Joe Earley, a former EVP of its tentpole streaming service Disney Plus, to the position of president of Hulu. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T7cVQ2"&gt;Earley previously served as EVP marketing and operations at Disney Plus and is headed to its sister service after joining the company in January of 2019. In the new role at Hulu, Earley will be tasked with building on the service’s brand and will liaise with its various content studios. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eZTmjK"&gt;The announcement comes as &lt;a href="https://thewaltdisneycompany.com/the-walt-disney-company-creates-international-content-group-to-expand-pipeline-of-local-content-and-continue-to-grow-its-global-direct-to-consumer-business/"&gt;part of a reorganization&lt;/a&gt; as Disney continues to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21514728/disney-streaming-reorganization-plus-espn-hulu-studios-movies-network-tv-shows-pandemic"&gt;rally resources&lt;/a&gt; around its streaming business. Earley will report to Michael Paull, who the company has appointed to the role of president of Disney’s overall streaming business. In this newly created position, Paull will oversee the company’s ESPN Plus, Hulu, Disney Plus, and Star Plus streaming services. Paull will report to Kareem Daniel, chairman of the Disney Media and Entertainment Distribution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="kCH5S1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Disney is reshuffling the leadership for its streaming business.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ii8lFJ"&gt;In addition to Earley and Paull’s expanded roles, the company announced that Rebecca Campbell was named as chairman of its international content business, having previously served as chairman of international operations and direct-to-consumer. The new role reports directly to Disney boss Bob Chapek. Campbell has held various roles with the company for nearly 25 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ffTLm3"&gt;As part of the executive shuffle, Disney will need to find a replacement to fill Paull’s old role leading Disney Plus. Having joined Disney through its acquisition of Bamtech Media, at which he was chief executive, Paull was integral to the growth of Disney’s streaming business. He formerly held an executive role with the Channels arm at Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JntCby"&gt;“Michael Paull has deep experience in the world of streaming and is an accomplished leader with a passion for this business and a proven track record of building and expanding our streaming operations,” Daniel said in a statement. “Bringing Disney’s streaming platforms together under Michael’s expert leadership will allow us to create an even more compelling value proposition for consumers.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22892271/disney-plus-hulu-reorganization-joe-earley-michael-paull-rebecca-campbell"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22892271/disney-plus-hulu-reorganization-joe-earley-michael-paull-rebecca-campbell</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google launches beta of Android games on Windows PCs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ALBSbxdQ_pJBjaKE0lONx1hpxuw=/162x0:1886x1149/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70410225/googleplaygames.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iEZCX6"&gt;Google is launching a limited beta of its app to bring Android games to Windows PCs. Google Play Games will be available in beta in Hong Kong, South Korea, and Taiwan today, allowing Windows PC owners to play popular Android games like &lt;em&gt;Mobile Legends&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Summoners War&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;State of Survival&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Three Kingdoms Tactics.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nSwl7J"&gt;Players in Hong Kong, South Korea, and Taiwan will be able to &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/googleplaygames?pcampaignid=PR-Global-oo-gpgbeta-DevBlog"&gt;sign up to access the beta&lt;/a&gt; and access Google’s standalone app on Windows PCs. Google is promising “seamless gameplay sessions between a phone, tablet, Chromebook, and Windows PC,” suggesting that you’ll be able to easily resume games between multiple devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Eh6Pub"&gt;“Players can easily browse, download, and play their favorite mobile games on their PCs while taking advantage of larger screens with mouse and keyboard inputs,” says Arjun Dayal, group product manager for Google Play Games. “No more losing your progress or achievements when switching between devices; it just works with your Google Play Games profile!”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W8y4M0bgsjP9LgOERaQy-PWUNdQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23178854/googleplaygames.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google Play Games syncs gameplay sessions across multiple devices.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="QMGKoo"&gt;Google Play Games will also include Play Points that can be earned while playing Android games on PCs. Google only &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22827037/google-android-games-windows-pc-google-play-games"&gt;announced its plans to bring Android games to PCs&lt;/a&gt; a month ago, but it’s still not clear what technology the company is using to get Android games running on Windows PCs. The Google Play Games app will be a native Windows app that won’t involve game streaming, though, and Google is &lt;a href="https://developer.android.com/games/playgames"&gt;opening up a developer site today&lt;/a&gt; that should start to provide more information for game developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Uzth3r"&gt;Google’s announcement comes months after Microsoft &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22736528/microsoft-android-apps-windows-11-test"&gt;started testing Android apps on Windows 11 PCs&lt;/a&gt;. Microsoft has built an underlying Windows Subsystem for Android, which is capable of running Android apps from a variety of sources. Microsoft uses it in partnership with Amazon to allow native installs of games and apps from the Amazon Appstore on Windows, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22748319/google-play-store-windows-11-android-apps-microsoft"&gt;despite workarounds&lt;/a&gt;, Google Play isn’t officially supported yet.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891046/google-play-games-android-games-windows-pc-beta-launch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891046/google-play-games-android-games-windows-pc-beta-launch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T18:00:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T18:00:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple TV Plus teases its WeWork series with Jared Leto</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Qaqc5gTRluquHR5cZVdYm-1xw40=/0x0:4664x3109/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70410005/Apple_TV_WeCrashed_key_art.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JTUWwi"&gt;A new trailer gives us a glimpse of Apple TV Plus’ &lt;em&gt;WeCrashed&lt;/em&gt;, an upcoming miniseries about the real-life buildup and dramatic downfall of WeWork, the coworking space with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/15/20806366/we-company-wework-ipo-adam-neumann"&gt;weirdly bombastic public filing&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/21/20975831/wework-layoffs-ipo-adam-neumann-softbank"&gt;laid off&lt;/a&gt; thousands of employees while later giving its brash CEO a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/22/20926583/wework-founder-adam-neumann-softbank-takeover-payout"&gt;huge golden parachute&lt;/a&gt;. The script practically writes itself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="urg8uV"&gt;Jared Leto stars as WeWork’s former eccentric CEO, Adam Neumann, while Anne Hathaway takes on the role of his wife, Rebekah Neumann, who served as the company’s chief brand and impact officer and was former CEO of WeGrow. The trailer opens with Leto reimagining a run-down building as a vibrant office space — and then making that vision a reality. Leto and Hathaway are then seen leading a “WeWork” chant in front of a crowd, emphasizing the almost hypnotic energy of the company and its leaders. The company managed to secure a $47 billion valuation before ultimately plummeting to just $9 billion as the company went public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YQ1hC4"&gt;The series is based on the &lt;a href="https://wondery.com/shows/we-crashed/"&gt;Wondery podcast &lt;em&gt;WeCrashed: The Rise and Fall of WeWork&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and is set to debut on Apple TV Plus on March 18th, with new episodes airing every Friday until April 22nd. Last year, Hulu created a documentary that followed the WeWork rollercoaster ride, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/2/22358602/wework-documentary-adam-neumann-hulu"&gt;called &lt;em&gt;WeWork: Or the Making and Breaking of a $47 Billion Unicorn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="fe9Z1y"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xEQP4VVuyrY?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PwKHAI"&gt;Also coming to Apple TV Plus is &lt;em&gt;Severance&lt;/em&gt;, a series that depicts the ultimate balance between work and home. Adam Scott plays Mark Scout, a manager at Lumon Industries, who undergoes a procedure called “severance.” The procedure splits Scout’s (and his co-workers’) personal and work-related memories — when he’s at the office, he has no memory of his home life and vice versa. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OLrnjA"&gt;The trailer shows what seems to be Scout’s verbal acknowledgment of the procedure’s risks. It also previews the robotic interactions that take place between him and co-workers, as well as hints at a darker mystery brewing inside the workplace. &lt;em&gt;Severance&lt;/em&gt; premieres on February 18th and is produced by Ben Stiller.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891975/apple-tv-plus-wework-jared-leto"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891975/apple-tv-plus-wework-jared-leto</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T17:20:41-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T17:20:41-05:00</updated>
    <title>The battle between the FAA, AT&amp;T, Verizon, and airlines over 5G</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Z-Xzg8u4OPAGaRV_gkHXYUO1OyU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70409844/acastro_180430_1777_5G_0001.0.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;C-band’s rollout has endured months of controversy&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="u8qDaU"&gt;When AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon spent &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299903/fcc-cband-auction-results-verizon-att-tmobile"&gt;tens of billions of dollars&lt;/a&gt; for the rights to use the C-band spectrum for their 5G service, the carriers saw it as a way to expand their networks and make them faster. Those plans, however, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22867221/att-verizon-5g-midband-spectrum-faa-air-safety-delay-cband"&gt;sparked a feud&lt;/a&gt; with the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), which warned that the cell signals could interfere with the altimeters that pilots use to land in conditions with low visibility. (&lt;em&gt;Could&lt;/em&gt; is a keyword — if everything is working correctly, there shouldn’t be problems, but with jets that can hold hundreds of people, it’s understandable why the FAA and airlines would want a lot of wiggle room.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RSD8JL"&gt;Before the carriers activated their C-band equipment, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822875/5g-faa-rule-c-band-landing-airport-bad-weather-visibility"&gt;FAA created rules around&lt;/a&gt; how airplanes could land in low-visibility conditions. The carriers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22763502/verizon-att-cband-5g-faa-delay-safety-aircraft"&gt;agreed to delay their rollouts in November 2021&lt;/a&gt;, pushing the date to January 5th, and also said they’d &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/24/22801008/verizon-att-midband-5g-c-band-lower-power-six-months"&gt;run their equipment at lower power around airports for six months&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/8/22873765/faa-verizon-att-airport-5g-carriers-buffer-zone"&gt;creating buffer zones&lt;/a&gt; and allowing the regulator more time to analyze the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mFrZ9z"&gt;Then, the FAA requested another delay. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/2/22863964/faa-fcc-verizon-att-c-band-5g-airports-proposal-rejected"&gt;The carriers initially rejected it&lt;/a&gt; before &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22866098/faa-dot-verizon-fcc-att-5g-c-band-delay-airplane-safety"&gt;cutting a deal&lt;/a&gt; to push the date back to January 15th. As that deadline neared, there was a flurry of activity. A coalition of airlines and shipping companies &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889141/us-airlines-united-american-delta-5g-c-band-disruption-radar-altimeter"&gt;claimed that the rollout could cause “catastrophic disruption”&lt;/a&gt; if it went through, and the carriers announced that they &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889664/att-5g-limits-c-band-expansion-airports-further-carrier-airline"&gt;put further limits on their rollout around airports&lt;/a&gt; but lambasted the FAA in their statements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SH2ca3"&gt;The same day, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22890080/5g-flight-cancel-att-verizon-c-band-emirates-air-india-ana-japan"&gt;several international airlines announced&lt;/a&gt; that they were canceling flights to certain airports in the US. (The president of Emirates &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/01/19/business/emirates-5g-quest/index.html"&gt;had some scathing remarks&lt;/a&gt; about how the situation was handled, calling the rollout “one of the most delinquent, utterly irresponsible issues [...] I’ve seen in my aviation career” and saying that the airline didn’t have vital information until a few days before the rollout.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9p4oBF"&gt;On the 19th, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891286/att-5g-rollout-select-metro-areas-faa-delay"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891284/verizon-c-band-5g-ultra-wideband-now-available"&gt;Verizon&lt;/a&gt; activated their cell networks, and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891725/faa-radar-new-altimeter-clearance-5g-c-band-rollout-airlines-boeing-777"&gt;FAA cleared additional altimeters&lt;/a&gt;, saying that it should allow “an estimated 62 percent of the U.S. commercial fleet to perform low-visibility landings at airports where wireless companies deployed 5G C-band.” The story is continuing to evolve as airlines announce delays or that they’ll be continuing service. You can follow the story as it continues to unfold here.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891634/faa-att-verizon-5g-c-band-rollout-battle-airlines-buffer-zones"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891634/faa-att-verizon-5g-c-band-rollout-battle-airlines-buffer-zones</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T16:27:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T16:27:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>Crypto.com CEO confirms hundreds of accounts were hacked, hedges on other details </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9ulIH2UG6mRv0JWDnAJ0QX3b-yk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70409618/acastro_190204_1777_privacy_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BpexxI"&gt;The CEO of cryptocurrency exchange Crypto.com, Kris Marszalek, has finally confirmed that hundreds of user accounts were indeed compromised by hackers and had funds stolen as a result, though details of the exact method of breach remain unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PongJw"&gt;Marszalek &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BloombergLive/status/1483841347824099330"&gt;acknowledged the hack&lt;/a&gt; in an online interview with &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; Wednesday, stating that around 400 customer accounts had been compromised. He also told &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; that he had &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-01-19/crypto-com-ceo-says-regulators-haven-t-reached-out-after-hack"&gt;not received any outreach from regulators&lt;/a&gt; since the attack was first disclosed but would share information if official inquiries were made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jtkN8e"&gt;Previous statements from Marszalek and other communications from Crypto.com have been criticized for being vague and unclear. Official messaging from the company &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/qjb3zq/cryptocom-says-alleged-dollar15-million-hack-was-just-an-incident"&gt;referred to a security “incident,”&lt;/a&gt; and an early Twitter post mentioned only that a small number of users were “&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cryptocom/status/1482936866001207296"&gt;reporting suspicious activity on their accounts&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2GRKK7"&gt;Marszalek followed up by tweeting that “no customer funds were lost” — a statement some commentators interpreted as meaning that the exchange would take the financial hit rather than passing it on to customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="RaKyYp"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Some thoughts from me on the last 24 hours:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- no customer funds were lost &lt;br&gt;- the downtime of withdrawal infra was ~14 hours &lt;br&gt;- our team has hardened the infrastructure  in response to the incident&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We will share a full post mortem after the internal investigation is completed.&lt;/p&gt;— Kris | Crypto.com (@Kris_HK) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Kris_HK/status/1483277350683185155?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 18, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GGBgzN"&gt;Shortly afterward, security company PeckShield posted a tweet claiming that, in reality, Crypto.com’s losses &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/peckshield/status/1483246262371557378"&gt;amounted to around $15 million in ETH&lt;/a&gt; and were being sent to Tornado Cash to be “washed.” Tornado Cash is a cryptocurrency privacy tool known as a “mixer” that can hide the final destination of ether being sent into it: a service that has legitimate uses but can easily be used to launder the proceeds of theft and other crypto-related crime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pVxU2v"&gt;The Crypto.com exchange has become one of the most recognizable brands in the cryptocurrency world due to a number of prominent sponsorship deals with sports teams, notably a $700 million deal that renamed the Los Angeles Lakers’ stadium — formerly known as the Staples Center — to the Crypto.com Arena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HxpUhg"&gt;The exchange has also inked deals with the UFC fight league, the Philadelphia 76ers NBA team, the NHL’s Montreal Canadiens, and, most recently, &lt;a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/australian-women-s-football-team-secures-75m-deal-with-crypto-com"&gt;with the Australian Football League&lt;/a&gt;, deals worth as much as $1.5 billion in sponsorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4fQSXC"&gt;As the size and user base of the cryptocurrency industry continues to grow, exchanges remain some of the most high-value targets for hackers to compromise. According to NBC News, there were more than 20 exchange hacks &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/security/bitcoin-crypto-exchange-hacks-little-anyone-can-do-rcna7870"&gt;where the hacker escaped with more than $10 million&lt;/a&gt; in profit over the course of 2021, with six cases exceeding $100 million.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891949/crypto-ceo-confirms-hundreds-accounts-hacked-bloomberg-ethereum"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891949/crypto-ceo-confirms-hundreds-accounts-hacked-bloomberg-ethereum</id>
    <author>
      <name>Corin Faife</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T16:23:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T16:23:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>New Meta Quest update lets you access some settings with a pinch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gPWte3X0qjI-VWNuJrDUtsiiYig=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70409597/akrales_200904_4160_0265.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update v37 adds many new features.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wPBHtq"&gt;Meta is adding a new feature to its Quest virtual reality headsets that lets you pinch your fingers to access the Quick Action menu, according to a &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=43993&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oculus.com%2Fblog%2Fapple-magic-keyboard-support-link-sharing-an-organized-home-and-more-in-latest-quest-software-update%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;blog post published Wednesday&lt;/a&gt;. The Quick Action menu functions similarly to the Control Center on iOS, so this new feature should give you an easier way to access some top-level settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sRpOra"&gt;To do the gesture while using hand tracking on the Quest, “hold your hand palm-up, then make a pinching motion, and you’ll be able to call up a shortcut menu that will make it easier to take screenshots, activate voice commands, and more,” Meta said. The company also made a handy GIF to show the gesture:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/v9k-9bHR457P7iZB4hiRRyOukWM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23180006/ezgif_3_ca6e762df9.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="wjLLy1"&gt;This new gesture is arriving with v37 of the Quest software, which is rolling out beginning Wednesday and adds a few other useful updates. One lets you send a link from your Android device to your VR headset via the Oculus mobile app, making it that much easier to check out a website in VR. iOS support will be added in the “near future.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0RTKxj"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r1uaq6CAUMo"&gt;Here’s a video of how it works&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="cHHL7g"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/r1uaq6CAUMo?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="E61f81"&gt;And for Apple’s Magic Keyboard users, Meta is making it possible to see a virtual representation of your hands and the keyboard when paired to the Quest 2. Meta first supported this virtual keyboard feature with the Logitech K830 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382805/oculus-quest-2-facebook-wireless-pc-streaming-120hz-infinite-office"&gt;in April&lt;/a&gt;. To turn it on, you’ll need to pair your Apple Magic Keyboard with your Quest in the Experimental Features menu and enable hand tracking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R0IiKm"&gt;You can read the full list of updates on &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=43993&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oculus.com%2Fblog%2Fapple-magic-keyboard-support-link-sharing-an-organized-home-and-more-in-latest-quest-software-update%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Meta’s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891825/meta-quest-update-v37-quick-action-pinch-link-sharing-apple-magic-keyboard"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891825/meta-quest-update-v37-quick-action-pinch-link-sharing-apple-magic-keyboard</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T15:56:41-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T15:56:41-05:00</updated>
    <title>Halo Infinite gets a hotfix to address Big Team Battle problems, but it hasn’t helped</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Halo Infinite multiplayer" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7RkfmNGt4VGQYSe3rM6rme-pw7Q=/182x0:2342x1440/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70409454/Halo_Infinite_Multiplayer_4_4K_3840x2160_scaled.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite multiplayer&lt;/em&gt; | Image: 343 Industries&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yghErv"&gt;Microsoft’s latest Halo game has finally arrived, and as we’ve seen, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/6/22820011/halo-infinite-campaign-review-xbox-series-x"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Infinite&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;campaign mode delivers. But for players already missing features like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22791487/halo-infinite-campaign-co-op-season-2-may-2022-forge"&gt;campaign co-op&lt;/a&gt; and Forge customizations, ongoing issues with the &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; Big Team Battle matchmaking have been another source of disappointment. A little over a week ago, the developers at 343 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/10/22877515/microsoft-halo-infinite-big-team-battle-matchmaking-fix-343"&gt;said a hotfix was on the way&lt;/a&gt;, and now it has arrived. But there’s bad news — it doesn’t seem to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Irczw0"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://support.halowaypoint.com/hc/en-us/articles/4412306622356"&gt;size of the update varies by platform&lt;/a&gt;, but players report it comes in at about a gigabyte on Xboxes and 110MB for PC players via Steam. If you’ve been online the whole time, you may need to restart your game to download it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="adyKQH"&gt;&lt;a href="https://forums.halowaypoint.com/t/halo-infinite-update-btb-and-more-updated-jan-19/490385"&gt;Here’s 343 on what’s happening:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="PeaBPj"&gt;Hey everyone - The Hotfix was deployed at 10AM PT today for Xbox and PC and included a fix for an issue with Oddball but also was hoped to address the ongoing matchmaking issues affecting Big Team Battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e3oN7p"&gt;Unfortunately it looks like today’s patch did not fully resolve the BTB matchmaking problems. The team is continuing to investigate and while we believe there may be some minor improvements, matchmaking is still not working as expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="28hevD"&gt;Many people worked hard to get this fix out the door and it’s naturally very disappointing we’re not seeing the desired and expected results. We know this is an ongoing source of frustration and the team will continue to work towards a resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YXe8Qt"&gt;We’ll continue to provide updates as we have them. In the meantime, we greatly appreciate your patience and understanding as we navigate this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CxHMSg"&gt;The aforementioned grants of 5 XP boosts and Challenge Swaps also went live at 10AM today. Log in any time between now and 10AM PT on Feb. 16 and they’ll be automatically added to your inventory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vmS3Ct"&gt;Thank you and our sincere apologies that today’s update did not go as we’d hoped. More to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="L7NH6s"&gt;Their data is showing the same thing &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/halo/comments/s7wjqt/halo_infinite_patch_january_19th_2022_discussion/"&gt;commenters on Reddit report&lt;/a&gt; — Big Team Battle is still a bit of a mess, with games that too frequently fail to start or drop many of the players before they get going. Now that accelerating these fixes from a planned mid-February patch has failed to fix things, it’s unclear what’s next for one of our favorite Halo modes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ItKOd7"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/HaloInfinite?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#HaloInfinite&lt;/a&gt; hotfix is now live with updates to Oddball and minor matchmaking improvements for BTB. If you're currently playing, close and relaunch Halo Infinite to install (1GB or less). More info in the January 19 update section of our release notes.&lt;a href="https://t.co/EFJ0w03eXM"&gt;https://t.co/EFJ0w03eXM&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/bmYhv78idr"&gt;pic.twitter.com/bmYhv78idr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Halo Support (@HaloSupport) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HaloSupport/status/1483876581873385475?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 19, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891256/halo-infinite-multiplayer-big-team-battle-patch-update-problems"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891256/halo-infinite-multiplayer-big-team-battle-patch-update-problems</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T15:53:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T15:53:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>Half of internet-connected devices in hospitals are vulnerable to hacks, report finds</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An IV medication drip." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4JAPJsccg6j6G2yrqhpdkJecxc4=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70409446/HH_IV_3.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PFgK4h"&gt;Over half of internet-connected devices used in hospitals have a vulnerability that could put patient safety, confidential data, or the usability of a device at risk, according to a &lt;a href="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5d2ad783e06f4c19469d363a/61e70fd9286e1d6d68a86ba8_A%20Cynerio%20Report%20-%20The%20State%20of%20IoMT%20Device%20Security%202022.pdf?__hstc=40021757.4448268d52e298f28d5bc2dbbc585809.1642605620912.1642605620912.1642605620912.1&amp;amp;__hssc=40021757.1.1642605620913&amp;amp;__hsfp=2234910243"&gt;new report&lt;/a&gt; from the healthcare cybersecurity company Cynerio. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ADAtQ"&gt;The report analyzed data from over 10 million devices at over 300 hospitals and health care facilities globally, which the company collected through connectors attached to the devices as part of its security platform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZnclJb"&gt;The most common type of internet-connected device in hospitals was an infusion pump. These devices can remotely connect to electronic medical records, pull the correct dosage of a medication or other fluid, and dispense it to the patient. Infusion pumps were also the devices most likely to have vulnerabilities that could be exploited by hackers, the report found — 73 percent had a vulnerability. Experts worry that hacks into devices like these, which are directly connected to patients, could be used to hurt or threaten to hurt people directly. Someone could theoretically access those systems and change the dosage of a medication, for example. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="46yKEn"&gt;Other common internet-connected devices are patient monitors, which can track things like heart rate and breathing rate, and ultrasounds. Both of those types of devices were in the top 10 list in terms of numbers of vulnerabilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6whdG0"&gt;Health care organizations are now a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/4/18293817/cybersecurity-hospitals-health-care-scan-simulation"&gt;major target for hackers&lt;/a&gt;, and while a direct attack on internet-connected medical devices doesn’t seem to have happened yet, experts think it’s a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686000/medical-device-cybersecurity-hack-minnesota"&gt;possibility&lt;/a&gt;. The more active threat is from groups that break into hospital systems through a vulnerable device and lock up the hospital’s digital networks — leaving doctors and nurses unable to access medical records, devices, and other digital tools — and demand a ransom to unlock them. These attacks have escalated over the past few years, and they slow down hospital functions to the extent that it can &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632378/pandemic-ransomware-health-risks"&gt;hurt patients&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YJtQni"&gt;Cynerio’s report notes that most of the vulnerabilities in medical devices are easily fixable: they’re due to weak or default passwords or a recall notice that the organization hasn’t acted on. Many healthcare organizations just don’t have the resources or personnel to keep systems up to date and might not know if there’s an update or alert concerning one of their devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jgR3vz"&gt;But reports like this one, combined with the growing frequency of ransomware attacks, is pushing more health care organizations to invest in cybersecurity, experts say. “I think this is reaching a level of criticality that is getting the attention of CEOs and board rooms,” Ed Gaudet, CEO and founder at cybersecurity company Censinet, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696097/hospital-ransomware-cyberattack-death-rates-patients"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; this fall.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GcFEkY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mKn1J2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891440/internet-connected-medical-devices-vulnerable"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891440/internet-connected-medical-devices-vulnerable</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T15:47:44-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T15:47:44-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to file for a tax extension</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="irs (ray tsang flickr)" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a2ynZbODfdQPeDxbr_PmeP8MlI8=/0x3:1100x736/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70409425/irs.1419979791.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;irs (ray tsang flickr)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="NDMozI"&gt;When, in 2020, the IRS pushed the due date for federal income taxes from April 15th to July 15th because of the upheaval brought about by COVID-19, a lot of taxpayers must have breathed a sigh of relief. Depending on where we lived, many of us were dealing with product shortages, layoffs, sudden isolation, and trying to figure out how to cope with the new normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vj3xwD"&gt;Time marches on, however, and two years later, the tax deadline is back to mid-April (April 18th for most states, April 19th in Maine and Massachusetts). So if you won’t be able to file your taxes by then, what do you do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="6XZzpl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to file and pay your 2021 taxes online ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22889295/taxes-irs-file-pay-online-2021-how-to"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="6Wly7i"&gt;One thing you don’t do is panic. You can still file for an extension — and it won’t take long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AavhkF"&gt;If you’re an individual (and let’s assume you are), you can file for an extension easily online by &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-pdf/f4868.pdf"&gt;filling out Form 4868&lt;/a&gt; using the &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/forms-pubs/extension-of-time-to-file-your-tax-return"&gt;IRS’s Free File program&lt;/a&gt;. (Filing an extension is free no matter what your income level is.)  Some things to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="ZQPI3A"&gt;When you go to the page on the IRS site offering the Free File extensions, you’ll be faced with several possible choices of services. It might be worth it to take a glance at all of them since they handle forms differently, and you might feel more comfortable with one specific service. Whichever you choose, it will be free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nVgDj0"&gt;You may also need to file a state extension form. Some of the services in the IRS Free File program should handle that as well; if not, you can check with your state tax authority to find out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="e21nh8"&gt;Once you file an extension, you will have until October 17th to file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="aEYQuh"&gt;You will still have to approximate how much you owe the government and pay the amount due.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RIC0SG"&gt;If you know you will owe taxes and decide to pay them all or in part through &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/payments/direct-pay"&gt;Direct Pay&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/payments/eftps-the-electronic-federal-tax-payment-system"&gt;Electronic Federal Tax Payment System (EFTPS)&lt;/a&gt;, or a &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/payments/pay-taxes-by-credit-or-debit-card"&gt;credit or debit card&lt;/a&gt;, you can indicate that the payment is for an extension and you won’t even have to file a separate form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qQ9y00"&gt;If you’d rather mail a hard copy form, you can find a PDF to print out &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-pdf/f4868.pdf"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. You’re on time as long as it is postmarked by April 18th (April 19th if you’re from Maine or Massachusetts).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="stTUjQ"&gt;Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nMAXPg"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 19th, 2022, 3:20PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article was originally published on July 14th, 2020, and has been updated to change dates and other information for tax year 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HGxaAN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22891931/taxes-file-extension-deadline-irs-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22891931/taxes-file-extension-deadline-irs-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T15:14:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T15:14:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google will make free ‘legacy’ G Suite accounts pay for its office apps starting in July</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MdztgNtxkdnN7bqzWzgll7xoTqg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70409289/acastro_180508_1777_google_IO_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oKuC5o"&gt;If you’re part of a business or school that is a G Suite legacy free edition user, your organization will &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/a/answer/60217#faq"&gt;soon have to sign up for a paid subscription&lt;/a&gt; to continue using Google Workspace (via &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2022/01/19/g-suite-legacy-free-edition/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Google will automatically upgrade free plans to a Google Workspace subscription “based on the features you currently use” if your organization doesn’t sign up for a paid plan by May 1st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LecFM7"&gt;The free edition was initially available in &lt;a href="http://googlepress.blogspot.com/2006/08/google-launches-hosted-communications_28.html"&gt;Google’s first iteration of Workspace&lt;/a&gt;, called Google Apps, which launched in 2006. &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/29/google-rebrands-its-business-apps-as-g-suite-launches-team-drive-upgrades-apps/"&gt;Google Apps rebranded as G Suite&lt;/a&gt; in 2016, before &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/6/21503649/google-workspace-g-suite-gmail-chat-meet-docs"&gt;becoming the Google Workspace we know today in 2020&lt;/a&gt; by bundling Gmail, Docs, Meet, Sheets, and Calendar along with some extra perks. Google &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/a/answer/2855120"&gt;stopped offering the legacy free edition&lt;/a&gt; as of December 2012 but still allowed existing users to access its services for free as a courtesy. Unfortunately, it looks like this grace period has finally come to an end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="q2Fyj0"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Legacy free edition users won’t be charged for a subscription until July 1st&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AdbxT0"&gt;According to Google, the company is giving legacy free edition users until May 1st to sign up for a subscription, &lt;a href="https://workspace.google.com/pricing.html"&gt;which consists of four tiers&lt;/a&gt;; otherwise, Google will choose a plan that suits users’ needs based on the features they use. There’s no option for a free plan, with only some &lt;a href="https://edu.google.com/intl/ALL_us/products/workspace-for-education/"&gt;educational institutions&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/nonprofits/answer/3367223?hl=en"&gt;non-profit organizations&lt;/a&gt; eligible for a plan at no cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B0JxaC"&gt;Administrators will have until July 1st to enter payment information into Google (if they haven’t already), and Google won’t start charging a subscription fee until July 1st. If no payment information is entered, Google will suspend the account for 60 days, after which users won’t be able to access Workspace’s “core services,” like Gmail, Calendar, and Meet. You can find out more about how to upgrade to a paid plan or export your organization’s data &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/a/answer/60217#faq"&gt;on Google’s support page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8uC6Vf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891509/g-suite-legacy-free-google-apps-workspace-upgrade"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891509/g-suite-legacy-free-google-apps-workspace-upgrade</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
