<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-05-08T00:12:13-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-08T00:12:13-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-08T00:12:13-04:00</updated>
    <title>TiVo’s first Android TV dongle also appears to be its last</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0Ja3j4Nh2Tm67PIsOBbj4HcjZFA=/0x1:1043x696/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69255798/streamer_horizontal_media_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aZMaKW"&gt;Last May, TiVo attempted to muscle in on Roku and Amazon with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/7/21250348/tivo-stream-4k-release-date-news-features-streaming-dongle-hdmi"&gt;an HDMI streaming dongle of its own&lt;/a&gt; — the $70 TiVo Stream 4K, which traded in the company’s traditional live TV + DVR functionality for the likes of Sling TV, Netflix, HBO and YouTube. It now appears that attempt was so unsuccessful, the company’s planning to abandon its Android TV dongle efforts entirely. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="koXBuF"&gt;Xperi Holdings CEO Jon Kirchner explained &lt;a href="https://seekingalpha.com/article/4424831-xperi-holding-corporation-xper-ceo-jon-kirchner-on-q1-2021-results-earnings-call-transcript"&gt;in an earnings call&lt;/a&gt; (via &lt;a href="https://zatznotfunny.com/2021-05/tivo-to-leave-android-tv/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zatz Not Funny&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) that it no longer feels it can compete using Android TV — the company likes to think its differentiator is a content guide that surfaces and lets you search for shows and movies across a variety of apps, but now that Google’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/29/21494298/chromecast-google-tv-preview-android-features"&gt;already baked something like that&lt;/a&gt; into &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/30/21492549/google-tv-app-play-movies-name-change-chromecast"&gt;its new “Google TV” layer on top of Android TV&lt;/a&gt; and sells it for just $50, TiVo doesn’t see much of a future there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p7YtJV"&gt;Here’s Kirchner, as transcribed by &lt;a href="https://seekingalpha.com/article/4424831-xperi-holding-corporation-xper-ceo-jon-kirchner-on-q1-2021-results-earnings-call-transcript"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seeking Alpha&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="5HMQqr"&gt;Sure, so originally as we approached the combination, we have done a lot of planning around kind of a three phase approach, starting with the Stream 4K product, which is a dongle that attaches to TVs, moving into an embedded application, where we’ll be let’s say the preferred user interface choice on a broader platform but originally around the notion that it would live on top of Android TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iLEPg7"&gt;And then thirdly, going all the way into a much deeper embedded solution, embedded OS where we’re a bigger provider, where we’re really the sole primary interface for the broader content search and discovery and engagement. What has changed is last fall, Google came out and said that they intend to go beyond their core OS level offering and really get into the UX business, and in so doing it eclipses one’s ability to I think reasonably be an alternative that might otherwise live on their lower level platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="1JSvzh"&gt;Instead, says Kirchner, he wants to embed TiVo smarts directly in TVs — a strategy &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22220330/roku-tv-number-one-smart-os-us-canada-2020"&gt;that’s worked pretty dang well for Roku&lt;/a&gt;, and where Amazon has been competing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/20/18693634/amazon-fire-tv-dolby-vision-toshiba-announced-features"&gt;with Fire TV Edition sets&lt;/a&gt; for a few years, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b7n7xu"&gt;Here’s the thing, though: while the Stream 4K was well-reviewed, &lt;em&gt;it wasn’t the user interface&lt;/em&gt; that reviewers liked. Some of its most glowing reviews called it &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/reviews/tivo-stream-4k"&gt;cluttered&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/reviews/tivo-stream-4k-review/"&gt;confusing&lt;/a&gt; compared to the competition, and most concluded that it was just fine compared to slicker offerings from Roku and Amazon at or under that price. TiVo dropped the starting price of the Stream 4K &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/7/21250348/tivo-stream-4k-release-date-news-features-streaming-dongle-hdmi"&gt;to $50 at launch&lt;/a&gt;, and reduced it to $39 in December after Google’s $50 Chromecast had arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ceNcBP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best streaming device to buy right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21375098/best-streaming-device"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="brQpR3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/8/22425753/tivo-stream-4k-dongle-android-tv-no-more-jon-kirchner"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/8/22425753/tivo-stream-4k-dongle-android-tv-no-more-jon-kirchner</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-07T22:07:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-07T22:07:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple is using Itch.io’s ‘offensive and sexualized’ games as a cudgel against Epic</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tT0Hd1dfQt_ZVA89FAixcczFMnY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69255493/acastro_20200818_1777_epicApple_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CCK048"&gt;Shortly before the &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;/em&gt; trial, Epic Games made an interesting announcement: it would &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22395997/epic-games-store-pc-apps-windows-store-brave-discord-itch"&gt;offer the indie game storefront Itch.io&lt;/a&gt; as an app on its own Epic Games Store. The &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; publisher was going to trial with the aim of making Apple offer competing app stores on its iPhone and iPad, so the move showed that Epic was willing to open up its own store in the same way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IvW3Gj"&gt;On the fifth day of court, however, Apple tried to turn Itch.io into a liability — by telling Epic Games Store general manager Steven Allison about “so-called adult games” that were “so offensive we cannot speak about them here.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A0dcRl"&gt;Itch.io is one of relatively few non-game apps on the Epic Games Store, along with software like the Brave browser. It’s also, as we’ve previously &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/29/18118217/itchio-steam-leaf-corcoran-pc-games-indie"&gt;described it at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, “small and weird.” (Granted, it’s not &lt;em&gt;quite &lt;/em&gt;as small as Epic seems to think; CEO Tim Sweeney said it had “at least hundreds” of games, while the real number is &lt;a href="https://itch.io/blog/108659/there-are-200000-games-on-itchio-heres-how-to-find-your-new-favorite"&gt;upwards of 200,000&lt;/a&gt;.) Epic hasn’t reviewed all these games, and Apple noted that its standards are different from the Epic Games Store’s. The list includes, per Apple’s attorney, a game called &lt;em&gt;Sisterly Lust &lt;/em&gt;that includes “a list of fetishes which include many words that are not appropriate for us to speak in federal courts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Rln4m"&gt;Apple is notoriously wary of sexual or even debatably offensive content in its App Store. Until mid-2016, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/1/16/3879194/apple-app-store-guidelines-tell-game-developers-to-avoid-serious-themes"&gt;it told game developers&lt;/a&gt; that “if you want to criticize a religion, write a book. If you want to describe sex, write a book or a song, or create a medical app.” Epic is suing for the right to sideload alternative app stores like the Epic Games Store onto iOS. Today, Apple essentially warned Judge Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers that this would mean forcing Apple to indirectly allow a sexualized visual novel about incest (I’d call it a game, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425774/epic-apple-roblox-fortnite-store-game-trial-day-5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;/em&gt; witnesses&lt;/a&gt; have offered several conflicting definitions of that) onto the iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eYA5QQ"&gt;That’s probably not great for Epic. Judge Rogers seemed to take the concern seriously, asking Allison to explain whether Apple was correct. Allison demurred, although he later pushed back on Apple’s veiled suggestion that Epic kick Itch.io off the Epic Games Store. “Itch.io is an incredible community for developers that we support fully,” Allison said, “they have an open platform, and therefore have different moderation standards than the Epic Games Store.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OEfE3p"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;guys, Apple's lawyers just called. They said we need to turn off ALL the games   &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Games Are Now ILLEGAL&lt;/p&gt;— itch.io (@itchio) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/itchio/status/1390782877416054794?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kHsFvU"&gt;But regardless of what happens in court, Itch.io is an independent entity with little direct stake in the trial, and its users are largely indie game designers who are often skeptical of both Epic and Apple. (It’s got a lot of content that’s not safe for work, but it’s also by far the easiest place to publish experimental interactive media. It’s where I post my own small text-based games, and there’s a thriving indie tabletop role-playing game community, among other genres.) Some people were upset at Apple going after a platform that’s particularly favored by queer developers offering depictions of sexuality you won’t find in big-budget games. Others simply found it very, very funny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1hngVg"&gt;Soon after the exchange, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/itchio/status/1390782877416054794"&gt;Itch.io’s Twitter feed&lt;/a&gt; jokingly claimed that Apple’s lawyers called and said to “turn off ALL the games,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/itchio/status/1390788835991113730"&gt;then said&lt;/a&gt; Itch.io was renaming its “sensitive content” filter to “Unspeakable Games.” As I write this, one Itch.io user has announced a game jam called the &lt;a href="https://itch.io/jam/the-unspeakable-jam"&gt;“Unspeakable Jam”&lt;/a&gt; that will run until June 12th; all entries must follow Apple executive &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thedextriarchy/status/1390417956308459531"&gt;Trystan Kosmynka’s instruction&lt;/a&gt; that “games have a beginning and end; there’s challenges in place.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8mMro5"&gt;In the interest of offering the clearest possible context for this exchange, I went back and transcribed the entire portion of testimony involving Itch.io’s unspeakable games, just to make sure it was as over-the-top as I remembered. Reader, it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Ts6xbc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple attorney:&lt;/strong&gt; On April 22nd of this year, Epic Games Store added the Itch.io app to its store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="89qtkG"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steve Allison, Epic Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2ezCyp"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attorney:&lt;/strong&gt; You’re aware of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ijeffL"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison:&lt;/strong&gt; I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v7NmoF"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attorney: &lt;/strong&gt;And you’re aware that Itch.io is a third-party app store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2nXnzc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison: &lt;/strong&gt;I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AyUFoj"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attorney: &lt;/strong&gt;And the court has also heard that Itch.io was added without reviewing all the games. You’re aware of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JEjxet"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison: &lt;/strong&gt;Yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s2VrCF"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attorney: &lt;/strong&gt;And are you aware, sir, that Itch.io includes so-called adult games, such as a game called &lt;em&gt;Sisterly Lust&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rZngZV"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison: &lt;/strong&gt;I am not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5oqlv8"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attorney: &lt;/strong&gt;You may not be aware then, but the description of that game includes a list of fetishes which include many words that are not appropriate for us to speak in federal courts. Are you aware of that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SHsHcj"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison: &lt;/strong&gt;I am not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UQbsJ8"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attorney: &lt;/strong&gt;And the list goes on. There are many games on Itch.io, I won’t even read the names out loud, but they are both offensive and sexualized. You are not aware of that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="64kwmj"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison: &lt;/strong&gt;Itch.io is an app store that is not the Epic Games Store. Itch is distributing Itch.io games. Epic is only distributing the App Store Itch.io.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gOFA9Z"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attorney: &lt;/strong&gt;And Itch.io is now available as an app on the Epic Games Store, correct?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KSosfg"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison: &lt;/strong&gt;Yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ftpv05"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attorney: &lt;/strong&gt;And those apps on Itch.io have not gone through any review process whatsoever. Correct?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wrtBgm"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison: &lt;/strong&gt;They are subject to whatever process Itch.io puts in front of their devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bk2toZ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attorney: &lt;/strong&gt;Right. So Epic Games, you’re sure, is on the hook for whatever process Itch.io puts in place to review these games that are so offensive we cannot speak about them here, correct?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="68FnwN"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison: &lt;/strong&gt;I disagree with that statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TOwb2U"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Judge Rogers:&lt;/strong&gt; So can you or can you not access those apps through your app store?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NNK2ax"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison: &lt;/strong&gt;You cannot access those apps through the Epic Games Store, no. You can access those apps through their application, which that is what we are downloading: Itch.io, which is an app store. [Users] have their own account with them, and you use their store and are subject to their end user agreement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rDXFZs"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Judge Rogers: &lt;/strong&gt;So if I have a phone and your app store was on that phone, that other store could be downloaded which has all of this offensive material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bqWNLu"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison: &lt;/strong&gt;Not on your phone. The app could be downloaded onto your PC and you could access their app on your PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WRNHf9"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Judge Rogers: &lt;/strong&gt;But that’s what you want to do on a phone too. That’s what I understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LtmmE6"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison: &lt;/strong&gt;I don’t know that we would want to do that with Itch.io [on a phone].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PGrVlT"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Judge Rogers:&lt;/strong&gt; But you’re doing it now, so I could access it on my PC, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yN5aLd"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison: &lt;/strong&gt;Yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7leXtM"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Judge Rogers: &lt;/strong&gt;And this lawsuit’s about your ability to do it on your phone, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MsVqSM"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison: &lt;/strong&gt;Yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UGwlB2"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attorney: &lt;/strong&gt;And just so we’re clear, sir, you can go to Epic Games Store, click Itch.io, and download the offensive games. Are you aware of that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xvMnvK"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison: &lt;/strong&gt;You can go to the Epic Game Store launcher, and you can launch Itch.io, which takes you out of the Epic Games Store and launches their application. You are then subject to their user agreement and you are in the Itch.io ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EmyDlQ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attorney: &lt;/strong&gt;And you said to the court just a second ago that you wouldn’t want to do that with Itch.io, you wouldn’t want to put Itch.io on the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rW037U"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison: &lt;/strong&gt;I don’t know that we would or we wouldn’t. I don’t even know that it’s available as a mobile application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pr8QyY"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attorney: &lt;/strong&gt;Because the reason that you said that to the court is because you’re recognizing that this is offensive and sexualized conduct that can be accessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2rsQgH"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison: &lt;/strong&gt;I disagree with that statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="tOLriT"&gt;(After digressions into some other topics, Apple’s attorney returned to the question.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="DVkDL6"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attorney: &lt;/strong&gt;Now that you know there are offensive and sexualized apps on Itch.io, as the head of the Epic Games Store, do you plan to do anything about that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q7F9Pa"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison: &lt;/strong&gt;I don’t have an answer for you. I will dig in when we get back. But I don’t have an answer for you. I’m not sure. These apps were on Itch.io, not the Epic Games Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FrsqBU"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attorney: &lt;/strong&gt;Epic has been been advertising putting these apps in the store. Mr. Sweeney put up a tweet about Itch.io, and now you seem to be distancing yourself from Itch.io because you realized there are apps in there that you have not reviewed and cannot stand by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K5InhB"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison: &lt;/strong&gt;I disagree with what you’re saying. Itch.io is an incredible community for developers that we support fully, they have an open platform, and therefore have different moderation standards than the Epic Games Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vYBFr7"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attorney: &lt;/strong&gt;I was just wondering, sir, if you support fully the offensive and sexualized content that is available there when people go to the Epic Games Store and download Itch.io.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9FekTV"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allison: &lt;/strong&gt;I don’t support sexualized content of any sort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425759/epic-apple-trial-app-store-itch-io-offensive-sexualized-unspeakable-games-day-5"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425759/epic-apple-trial-app-store-itch-io-offensive-sexualized-unspeakable-games-day-5</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-07T21:36:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-07T21:36:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>In Epic v Apple, everybody is losing at the game of defining games</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/v6rP_07pLVGQ8lJPWdgw6kegrhc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69255433/acastro_210429_1777_epicApple_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Is Roblox a game or not?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="gtxVrE"&gt;If you have ever wanted to see a bunch of mumbly nerds struggle to define what constitutes a “game,” well, is &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;/em&gt; the trial for you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0pAOnA"&gt;What is the difference between an “app” and a “game?” This sounds like a stoner question but instead occupied a fair amount of the morning in Epic v. Apple. Roblox, explained Apple’s marketing manager Trystan Kosmynka, was an app. See, games have a beginning, an end, and challenges. “There’s experiences within Roblox that we did not look at as a game,” Kosmynka said. We did establish that Minecraft is a game, though, so that’s nice for Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="This screenshot of the App Store clearly shows that Roblox is classified as a “game” — despite what Kosmynka testified." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zLdCxWBQjWfGbbE5HTUm8p4fD6I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22499994/Screen_Shot_2021_05_07_at_5.30.43_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A screenshot of Roblox on the Apple App Store, as of May 7 at 8PM ET&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7a5dp9"&gt;Judge Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers did not understand this distinction and neither did I. But here’s the problem for Apple: if Roblox &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a game, then it’s fairly easy for Epic to compare Fortnite to it. Also, looking up Roblox in the App Store after Kosmynka testified, it is categorized as a “game.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QYDWHr"&gt;Roblox is free, with in-app purchases. Since apparently no one can define what a game is, I can’t tell whether it’s fair to say that Roblox is a platform with games on it, but it sure looks that way when I log on. Scrolling through, there are a number of small squares where I can join a game, and each appears to have different rules. (The app calls these “worlds.”) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ar2T1j"&gt;And when Kosmynka doesn’t get the category on Roblox right, well. That’s an own goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="6ZQypK"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I’ve always looked at Fortnite as a game.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Ky1rqQ"&gt;Anyway, Kosmynka noticeably shrank when Epic’s Lauren Moskowitz began asking questions on the redirect. Were Snapchat’s bunny ear filters games? What about TikTok challenges? (The manner in which this question was asked convinced me that I was possibly the only person in the room on TikTok.) Things got worse for Kosmynka during a speed-run of questions. Had he used Fortnite? Yes. Had he attended a concert there? No. “Fortnite is a virtual world where you build a character, correct?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UImbUr"&gt;“I wouldn’t refer to Fortnite as a world. I’ve always looked at Fortnite as a game,” Kosmynka replied. Had he done Battle Royale? Yes. Party Royale? No. Creative mode? No. He knew that Fortnite held concerts but didn’t know it streamed movies. In the context of “What is a game,” it made Kosmynka sound like he didn’t know what he was talking about. It was a tense, and rather devastating, line of questioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xAE7pG"&gt;At one point, Judge Gonzalez Rogers said she didn’t understand why Minecraft was a game and Roblox was not. (Again, per the App Store: Roblox is &lt;em&gt;absolutely &lt;/em&gt;a game.) She asked Kosmynka for an industry definition for a game. Turns out, there isn’t one — although, my colleague Adi Robertson notes, game developers and academics will happily talk you under the table about magic circles, meaningful choices, and the works of Johan Huizinga if you ask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="nresF0"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It seemed like Epic was attempting to establish that Apple is inconsistent&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Ep3QIM"&gt;Later, Matthew Weissinger, VP of marketing at Epic Games, explained that Fortnite is a metaverse. “It’s one of the remarkable things about Fortnite, we’re building this thing called the metaverse, a social place,” he murmured softly. (All of the men we heard from today would benefit greatly from elocution lessons.) “One of the ways I’ve tried to explain it is, think about all of us in lockdown, and how we try to stay socially connected. Some of the most meaningful experiences I’ve had were logging into Zoom and we had our friends and parents and we celebrate grandpa’s birthday.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eLXukC"&gt;We also discover that Roblox has a “battle royale” mode, just like Fortnite. Honestly the question to me now is not &lt;em&gt;Is Roblox a game&lt;/em&gt; but &lt;em&gt;Is Roblox a metaverse.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kvpt6q"&gt;Throughout this line of questioning, it seemed like Epic was attempting to establish that Apple is inconsistent — and passing the buck. Kosmynka testified that developers get to pick what category they belong to, not Apple, making his Roblox digression even weirder. The Roblox thing made Apple look slipshod, and the further testimony about the App Store review didn’t help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9lRdIg"&gt;The process behind App Store review is unbelievably boring unless you are a developer who is trying to pass review. We went through it in &lt;em&gt;exhaustive&lt;/em&gt; detail. Apple gets 100,000 app store submissions per week, Kosmynka testified. But only 500 people actually do the “human review” — a lot of the rest of the work is automated. It’s impossible to judge how good an automated process is by listening to someone describe it in abstract in the courtroom. Kosmynka seemed confident when he was being questioned by Apple’s attorney, but when Epic got a crack at him, his voice got softer and softer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="v132mG"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“One of the problems with limiting competition is that you don’t get innovation.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="f5EWrL"&gt;We heard about apps Apple had mistakenly allowed on the store: ones that carried malicious ad fraud code, apps that copycatted Headspace, a “school shooting game,” a game of shooting cannons at protestors, several inappropriate apps (the funniest of which was “Ganja Farm: Weed Empire”) and more. In emails, Kosmynka said, “We are making critical errors.” In reference to the school-shooting game, Kosmynka said he was “dumbfounded at how this could be missed.” These specifics were more damning than the abstract walk-through of the app review process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G4jSsK"&gt;At one point, Judge Gonzalez Rogers wondered if anyone was doing better than Apple at app store moderation. Kosmynka punted on this answer. “One of the problems with limiting competition is that you don’t get innovation,” said Judge Gonzalez Rogers. “One of my concerns is that if you aren’t letting parties compete on these topics, things won’t improve.” She then asked if Apple hired third party reviewers. It does not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d1Ij7k"&gt;There is an implicit contrast here — the Epic Games Store. Steve Allison, VP and General Manager of the Epic Game Store, testified that there have been no known instances of malware or pirated content on the Epic Game Store, though there has been some fraud. It was hard not to notice the contrast. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RmwA1Y"&gt;Apple’s lawyer, who did not introduce herself, took us through an excruciating narration of the Epic Games website as part of her intensely chaotic cross-examination of Allison. I understand that a lot of things need to be narrated for the court record, but this was silly. We determined that there were a lot of games in the Epic Games Store. We also determined that there were 25 games in the “top 20” games section, which felt kind of bitchy. The first non-game app, Spotify, came to the store in December 2020. Fine, but this didn’t seem to make Epic look bad? Or at least, not the way she’d been hoping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="QxHyvr"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Are you aware that itch.io includes so-called adult games such as a game called “Sisterly Lust?”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="413UDZ"&gt;She lingered on the store-within-a-store on Epic Game Store: Itch.io,a store for indie games that Epic added to its store in April. You can download itch.io’s store from Epic. “Are you aware that itch.io includes so-called adult games such as a game called “Sisterly Lust?” Apple’s lawyer asked. Some of the games on itch.io are “so offensive we cannot speak about them here,” she sniffed. This was a more successful line of argument — it essentially explained why Apple didn’t want stores within its own store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xoXImk"&gt;Of course, the big contrast between the Apple App Store and the Epic Game Store was economic. The 30/70 split that Epic finds so objectionable began with retail — you used to have to buy games at Wal-Mart or GameStop or something, when they were physically packaged, Allison said quietly. As retailers moved away from PC games in favor of console games, Valve created Steam, which mimicked the 30/70 split from traditional retail — but it was viewed as an improvement among developers, since they didn’t have to pay for discs and packaging and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7wPd2d"&gt;That is, until Minecraft self-published, in Allison’s telling. Then someone taking 30 percent looked steep. In 2018, Epic launched the Epic Games Store, which took only a 12 percent cut. (In order to assuage developers who might fear losing revenue from Steam when they took exclusive deals with Epic, Epic agreed to pay them a minimum guarantee.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MJ7DDu"&gt;Significantly, developers don’t have to use the Epic in-app payment system — they can use their own, meaning that Epic can theoretically get &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; money on in-app purchases. Wizards of the Coast, the publisher of Magic the Gathering Arena, and Ubisoft, with multiple titles, use their own payment systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="8GFI1t"&gt;Still, I find myself returning to the question that began the day: What is a game? It’s shocking to me that so many people who specialize in apps and games can’t really answer this question. But I guess in some sense, you could imagine the trial is one — it’s got a beginning, a middle, and an end. Lots of money at stake. A winner and a loser. Plus, when the verdict is appealed — as it almost inevitably will be — we’ll get a sequel. Sure, Epic played well today, but you need more than one good turn to win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="wM5VHz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple antitrust trial kicks off with Tim Sweeney’s metaverse dreams","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22417697/apple-epic-fortnite-app-store-antitrust-trial-day-1"},{"title":"Epic says there’s an App Store payment lockout — but Apple just sees friction","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419894/apple-epic-fortnite-app-store-antitrust-trial-day-2"},{"title":"Epic v. Apple turns into Windows v. Xbox","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421570/epic-apple-trial-iphone-xbox-console-specific-general-purpose-pc-testimony-day-3"},{"title":"Epic needs to tarnish Apple’s App Store halo ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423567/apple-epic-app-store-policies-fortnite-trial-day-4"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425774/epic-apple-roblox-fortnite-store-game-trial-day-5"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425774/epic-apple-roblox-fortnite-store-game-trial-day-5</id>
    <author>
      <name>Elizabeth Lopatto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-07T20:36:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-07T20:36:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google Stadia has figured out a way to ditch the fancy gamepad for TV play</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/U1EoUjfzMAjkBj7ch_OKQiN27A8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69255222/akrales_191113_3779_0309.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Pj1JKE"&gt;Today, there’s only one official way to play Google’s Stadia game streaming service on your 4K TV — the last-gen Chromecast Ultra, connected to the company’s proprietary Stadia Controller over Wi-Fi. That’s because Google hasn’t yet brought Stadia &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21495609/google-chromecast-2020-review-streaming-remote-control"&gt;to the new-and-improved $50 Chromecast&lt;/a&gt;, and its predecessor didn’t support Bluetooth, meaning the only way to pair a controller was to loop through Google’s servers in the cloud. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mCsHaY"&gt;But Google now has a workaround,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/05/07/stadia-3-15-phone-tv-controller/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;. There’s a new “bridge mode” hidden in the latest version of the Stadia app on Android that should let you send controller signals from your phone — letting you play Stadia with your phone’s touchscreen, or even connect another gamepad to your phone. You’ll be able to use your phone to change your TV’s volume, too, according to text snippets buried in the APK. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T9dVHTLpnFjk73dMgEweNxzQ75Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22499911/bridge.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google spotted this graphic in the APK to promote bridge mode.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="VVwaDo"&gt;The original Stadia Controller has been something of a thorn in the company’s side ever since Stadia launched on November 19th, 2019, so it wouldn’t be surprising if Google decides to move on. It took many months for buyers to be able to use Google’s wireless controller wirelessly with anything &lt;em&gt;except&lt;/em&gt; the Chromecast Ultra — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/5/21248769/google-stadia-controller-wireless-computers-desktop-laptop"&gt;desktop web browsers&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/30/21308374/google-stadia-controller-wireless-android-mobile-support"&gt;Android phones&lt;/a&gt; weren’t supported at first, meaning you had to physically plug in a USB-C cable. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/1/21497850/google-stadia-controller-usb-c-support"&gt;USB-C audio took a while too&lt;/a&gt;, and Bluetooth audio via the controller still has yet to materialize. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pDLIXv"&gt;Thankfully, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/10/21215395/google-stadia-controller-how-to-pair-bluetooth-support-ps4-xbox-consoles"&gt;third-party controller support was quite robust&lt;/a&gt; on those other platforms, letting you easily sync a PlayStation or Xbox gamepad to play, and it’s unlikely you’ll even need this new Bridge Mode to play Stadia on the 2020 Chromecast whenever it arrives; the new Chromecast &lt;em&gt;does &lt;/em&gt;support Bluetooth game controllers. Judging by a few Steam Link and GeForce Now sessions with my 8BitDo gamepad, Bluetooth gamepad support may work just fine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="7ns3R6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to use your own controllers to play Google Stadia","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/10/21215395/google-stadia-controller-how-to-pair-bluetooth-support-ps4-xbox-consoles"},{"title":"Our unannounced Google Chromecast didn’t come with Stadia, but it sure does work","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/29/21494161/google-chromecast-stadia-cloud-gaming-streaming-support"},{"title":"The writing’s on the wall for Google Stadia","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22260994/google-stadia-platform-white-label-option"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="5lpTY5"&gt;Right now, it’s just a little unclear how much Google cares about Stadia; after it axed all its in-house game studios in February, I argued that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22260994/google-stadia-platform-white-label-option"&gt;the writing was on the wall&lt;/a&gt;; since then, Stadia has &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/05/stadias-vp-and-head-of-product-leaves-google/"&gt;lost its head of product&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/articles/2021-05-05-six-additional-staff-leave-stadia-to-join-haven-studios"&gt;at least six additional staffers&lt;/a&gt;, and been the subject of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/26/22303496/google-stadia-struggle-wired-bloomberg-reports-studios"&gt;two reports about its internal struggles&lt;/a&gt;. Apparently, Google had to pay tens of millions of dollars to publishers like Ubisoft, per game, just to get games ported to Stadia.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425678/google-stadia-controller-bridge-mode-chromecast-google-tv"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425678/google-stadia-controller-bridge-mode-chromecast-google-tv</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-07T17:53:40-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-07T17:53:40-04:00</updated>
    <title>Listen to what we’ve learned from Epic v. Apple this week</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/q6m6ZHJynyqZUvyqzPqpL79zPZQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69254669/acastro_20200818_1777_epicApple_0004.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="NXmO8B"&gt;Every Friday, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; publishes our flagship podcast, &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/the-vergecast"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, where co-hosts Nilay Patel and Dieter Bohn discuss the week in tech news with the reporters and editors covering the biggest stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AKDtL1"&gt;This week on &lt;em&gt;The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;, Nilay and Dieter talk with &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; senior reporter Adi Robertson and senior editor Tom Warren about the first week of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22410877/epic-games-apple-app-store-antitrust-trial-lawsuit-news"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Epic Games v. Apple&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; trial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hulilM"&gt;Adi and Tom are among the group of &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; newsroom staff who are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/policy"&gt;reporting&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thedextriarchy/status/1390688458658652165"&gt;live-tweeting&lt;/a&gt; important moments from the ongoing trial, so they join the podcast to discuss their takeaways and discoveries throughout the week from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423567/apple-epic-app-store-policies-fortnite-trial-day-4"&gt;questioning&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22424668/epic-apple-antitrust-lawsuit-microsoft-xbox-profitability-lori-wright"&gt;testimonials&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22418828/apple-app-store-commission-30-percent-phil-schiller-2011-epic-lawsuit"&gt;documents&lt;/a&gt; in court. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OwLYbX"&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="200" scrolling="no" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm?e=VMP3776429920&amp;amp;light=true" width="100%"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6FbmP1"&gt;You can listen here or in &lt;a href="https://pod.link/430333725"&gt;your preferred podcast player&lt;/a&gt; to hear the full discussion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FXZJhV"&gt;Further reading: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="llMsDv"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22412899/epic-apple-trial-rules-investment-app-payment"&gt;Why Epic is burning its own cash to cook Apple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="XVdk14"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22417697/apple-epic-fortnite-app-store-antitrust-trial-day-1"&gt;Apple antitrust trial kicks off with Tim Sweeney’s metaverse dreams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="REWrAw"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22417347/epic-games-apple-fortnite-trial-public-call"&gt;The Epic Games v. Apple trial kicks off with kids screaming ‘free Fortnite’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="oYf0Bs"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22417725/apple-vs-epic-full-trial-slideshows-opening-arguments"&gt;Here are Apple’s and Epic’s full slideshows arguing why they should win at trial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0Nsbam"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419134/apple-epic-games-fortnite-trial-youtube-discord-streamers"&gt;I watched the Epic v. Apple trial on Discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="U5QCYv"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419618/tim-sweeney-email-tim-cook-wwdc-2015-ios-open-platform-antitrust"&gt;Tim Sweeney emailed Tim Cook personally to call for open app sales after WWDC in 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZMjRGJ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22418828/apple-app-store-commission-30-percent-phil-schiller-2011-epic-lawsuit"&gt;Apple exec suggested cutting App Store commission to 20 percent as early as 2011&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lf8K93"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421570/epic-apple-trial-iphone-xbox-console-specific-general-purpose-pc-testimony-day-3"&gt;Epic v. Apple turns into Windows v. Xbox &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dJRpEU"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419894/apple-epic-fortnite-app-store-antitrust-trial-day-2"&gt;Epic says there’s an App Store payment lockout — but Apple just sees friction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wnHYyo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423567/apple-epic-app-store-policies-fortnite-trial-day-4"&gt;Epic needs to tarnish Apple’s App Store halo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JRaQOf"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22421912/iphone-web-app-pwa-cloud-gaming-epic-v-apple-safari"&gt;Why the bad iPhone web app experience keeps coming up in Epic v. Apple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="OKwbeJ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22422691/microsoft-xbox-consoles-profit-software-services-revenue-apple-epic-games-trial"&gt;Microsoft would like to remind you the Xbox definitely makes money&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PeJKOz"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22424668/epic-apple-antitrust-lawsuit-microsoft-xbox-profitability-lori-wright"&gt;After Xbox testimony, Apple tells Microsoft to put up or shut up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="uxsXRT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"The Vergecast","description":"The podcast you need to make sense of the week in tech news","label":"Subscribe","url":"https://pod.link/430333725"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22424947/apple-v-epic-trial-week-1-vergecast-podcast-451"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22424947/apple-v-epic-trial-week-1-vergecast-podcast-451</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Marino</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-07T17:36:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-07T17:36:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>Instagram’s head apologizes for bug that deleted activists’ stories</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xl6UwwaCyRqIXfZfQwPNa0cU-i0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69254588/acastro_190919_1777_instagram_0002.0.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YQFHcq"&gt;Head of Instagram Adam Mosseri &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mosseri/status/1390764512521768960?s=20"&gt;has tweeted an apology&lt;/a&gt; about a bug that deleted users’ story posts on Thursday. The timing was unfortunate for activists trying to raise awareness about missing Indigenous women, with organizations Red Dress and National Day of Awareness of Missing and Murdered Indigenous Women and Girls (MMIWG, abbreviated by some as MMIWG2S to include two-spirit people) &lt;a href="https://indiancountrytoday.com/news/mmiwg-movement-erased-online"&gt;questioning whether their posts&lt;/a&gt; had somehow been erased deliberately. According to Instagram, however, the bug affected stories, archives, and highlights of Instagram users across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lD8DCx"&gt;Mosseri and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/InstagramComms/status/1390376354332487681"&gt;Instagram’s statement&lt;/a&gt; about the deletions say this isn’t the case and that the stories were not removed because of anything content-related. He specifically addressed the Indigenous people’s concerns. “This day is incredibly important to raise awareness of this critical issue and support our Indigenous community on Instagram,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mosseri/status/1390764511808737283?s=20"&gt;Mosseri tweeted&lt;/a&gt;. “We apologize to all those who felt like they could not bring attention to these incredibly important causes, and many others around the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="QClRa0"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Many people thought we were removing their content because of what they posted or what hashtag they used, but this bug wasn’t related to the content itself, but rather a widespread issue that has now been fixed.&lt;/p&gt;— Adam Mosseri   (@mosseri) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mosseri/status/1390764510378532864?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="y1naSV"&gt;The issue of &lt;a href="https://indiancountrytoday.com/news/known-and-not-forgotten"&gt;the high rates of violence against Indigenous people&lt;/a&gt; — especially women, girls, and two-spirit people — isn’t one that often gets a spotlight outside of reservations, so spreading awareness is especially important, activists say. &lt;a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/indigenous/instagram-stories-vanish-mmiwg-red-dress-day-1.6017113?cmp=rss"&gt;Speaking to CBC News&lt;/a&gt; about the importance of days like May 5th, community organizer Kakeka Thundersky said that “[e]veryone’s just stuck at home on their phone, unable to gather and able to go to the rallies, unable to talk to face to face with people,” making online platforms like Instagram a key tool for activists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ikA81A"&gt;Emily Henderson, an Inuk arts and culture writer, said that “[t]he digital space in general is really, really important right now just for maintaining community connections or connections.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425415/instagram-delete-activist-stories-bug-apology-mmiwg2s"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425415/instagram-delete-activist-stories-bug-apology-mmiwg2s</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-07T17:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-07T17:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>What would a billionaire do on SNL?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="elon-musk-asa-mathat-02" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yaTXxXu4Zhdg2miU5t_Cbl8f-xc=/0x0:2592x1728/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69254543/REC_ASA_CODE2016-20160601-211928-4028.0.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Asa Mathat/Recode&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CzdmWR"&gt;Tesla CEO Elon Musk — the first or second richest man in the world, depending on the phase of the Moon — will host &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/24/22401253/elon-musk-hosting-saturday-night-live-miley-cyrus-tesla-spacex"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Saturday Night Live&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; this weekend (the first or second funniest show that airs on Saturday evenings, depending on if anything else is on TV). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ZMe6U"&gt;The event is a strange confluence of things that &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;covers: a powerful tech leader with ambitions that are as huge as his blind spots, and someone destined to barrage you with so many dad jokes that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388609/wolf-collar-camera-fish-voyageurs-minnesota"&gt;one is bound to land at some point&lt;/a&gt;. Plus maybe &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22387486/dogecoin-run-valuation-cryptocurrency-spike-elon-musk"&gt;Dogecoin&lt;/a&gt;? (A meme gone so awry that it’s shaping the actual landscape of the physical world is definitely some &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; shit.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fzSP6h"&gt;So what can we expect when Musk takes the stage late on Saturday evening? Using a bit of algorithmic trickery and some advanced machine learning (aka &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; staff typing eagerly into a shared Google Doc), we’ve made our best predictions of what this episode of &lt;em&gt;SNL&lt;/em&gt; is likely to bring. And because we’re a little deranged from spending the week &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22373826/epic-games-v-apple-fortnite-app-store-antitrust-lawsuit"&gt;covering &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we also decided to turn it into a game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r6xILB"&gt;Behold: Elon &lt;em&gt;SNL&lt;/em&gt; Bingo!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/N6XPnoRXERrLY2wamK2H_GA6h2w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22499097/VRG_ILLO_ELONMUSK_BINGO_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Illustration by Grayson Blackmon / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22424877/elon-must-snl-bingo-game-saturday-night-live"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22424877/elon-must-snl-bingo-game-saturday-night-live</id>
    <author>
      <name>Verge Staff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-07T17:18:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-07T17:18:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google childcare workers ask for commute stipend in new petition</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LnCBo7IkVZd4ycMtfFKPVKgTX5A=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69254490/acastro_180508_1777_google_IO_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eUqK53"&gt;More than 200 Alphabet employees have &lt;a href="https://justiceforgcc.org/"&gt;signed a petition&lt;/a&gt; from Google childcare workers asking for a commute stipend. The petition calls for workers to be given an extra $1,500 per month to help pay for ride-shares, car rentals, or other transportation costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wZGIFd"&gt;Google is asking childcare workers and educators to return to in-person work on Monday, May 10th, while the company’s shuttle service remains suspended. Some make as little as $25 an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dAIPSR"&gt;“Transportation isn’t just a nice-to-have for us, it’s fundamental if we want to do our job,” said Denise Belardes, a childcare worker, in a press release. “We’re not the ones making hundreds of thousands of dollars every year. We do not have the option to work from home as other Googlers. We need this stipend.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="To5FFX"&gt;Google maintains four childcare centers in the Bay Area, where workers help educate and care for the children of Google and Alphabet employees. Many of the workers employed there don’t live close to the office due to the prohibitively high cost of housing, so transportation is a particularly vital issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TYT33l"&gt;During the pandemic, the workers began meeting with children over Google Meet, which made the transportation stipend unnecessary. But now, as &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/03/31/google-speeds-partial-office-reopening-and-puts-limits-on-remote-work.html#:~:text=Google%20employees%20will%20begin%20returning,will%20need%20to%20formally%20apply."&gt;Google starts to slowly bring employees back to the office&lt;/a&gt;, they’re being asked to return to in-person work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jpy5MV"&gt;In the petition, workers say Google did not respond well to the initial request. “When workers raised this issue, the corporate response was ‘transportation is just a perk, not a benefit,’” they wrote. “Shifting this cost to essential workers, who earn far less than the Googlers whose children they care for, is unacceptable. Google must do better.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rBFzGs"&gt;The petition, which is addressed to CEO Sundar Pichai as well as other executives, is backed by the Alphabet Workers Union. Google did not immediately respond to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ppWJNl"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VlnJeJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425388/google-childcare-workers-commute-stipend"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425388/google-childcare-workers-commute-stipend</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-07T17:15:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-07T17:15:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s Nest Mini is only $19 at Adorama</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-xpoTfF92Qtq4xTE5D_ODlNDAzY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69254470/cwelch_191016_3737_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google’s Nest Mini hits an all-time low — at least price-wise.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tWtukP"&gt;Whether you’ve fully committed to the smart home ecosystem or are just dabbling in the space for the first time, picking up a smart speaker is a no-brainer for most people. If you haven’t yet grabbed an Amazon or Google smart speaker, however, &lt;a href="https://adorama.rfvk.net/c/482924/1062332/1036?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.adorama.com%2Fga00638us.html"&gt;Adorama is taking $31&lt;/a&gt; off the Google Nest Mini as part of its latest flash sale through Sunday, May 9th. Simply use the promo code &lt;strong&gt;EXTRAOFF11 &lt;/strong&gt;at checkout to knock an additional $11 off the listed sale price and receive free shipping. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PTeMeC"&gt;Like its predecessor, the second-gen &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/21/20921173/google-nest-mini-echo-dot-assistant-smart-speaker-review"&gt;Google Nest Mini&lt;/a&gt; offers a range of voice-activated features, only with bolder sound, capacitive touch zones, and an improved design that allows you to hang the device on your wall. At the core of the fabric-lined puck is Google Assistant, which allows you quickly set reminders, stream music, control your smart lights, and carry out a range of other tasks with nothing more than a quick “Hey, Google.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ye17xF"&gt;The sound isn’t as robust as, say, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21501300/google-nest-audio-assistant-smart-speaker-review-price-specs-features"&gt;Google Nest Audio&lt;/a&gt;, but this marks the lowest price we’ve seen on the Nest Mini this year. It’s even available in two colors, chalk or charcoal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="j7wJhr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9736399"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zmZoJf"&gt;If you’re looking for additional &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22358371/mothers-day-gifts-ideas-best-mom-tech-gadgets"&gt;Mother’s Day gift ideas&lt;/a&gt; — and don’t mind opting for in-store pickup — we’ve also rounded up a set of eclectic ideas, from bath balms and AirPods to a classic pair of sandals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CgVKOA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10443858"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="x8GrJY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425265/google-nest-mini-smart-speaker-deal-sale-adorama"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425265/google-nest-mini-smart-speaker-deal-sale-adorama</id>
    <author>
      <name>Brandon Widder</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-07T14:58:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-07T14:58:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Impossible Foods eyes schools for new customers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="2nd China International Import Expo (CIIE) - Day 5" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VRIV5LrRvrcoS5w6deNAM8vlbbw=/0x0:4896x3264/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69253559/1186664879.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Impossible Burgers sit on a tray at the Impossible Foods Inc. booth on day five of the 2nd China International Import Expo (CIIE) at the National Exhibition and Convention Center on November 9, 2019 in Shanghai, China. | Photo by Gao Yuwen/VCG via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HhKWO4"&gt;Impossible Burgers will be making their way onto school menus across the US. The meatless burger just received the Child Nutrition Label from the USDA, which could make it easier for public schools to serve the product because the Impossible Burgers will be eligible for national school lunch funding. Impossible Foods hopes to offer up protein-packed lunches that don’t generate as much greenhouse gases as red meat. But slapping branding on foods served up to kids can still be harmful, even if the meals might be better for the environment.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Kv8XkD"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Companies should really keep their branding out”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7Gxjz7"&gt;“Just on principle, we believe that schools should be commercial free,” says Marlene Schwartz, director of the Rudd Center for Food Policy and Obesity at the University of Connecticut. “Companies should really keep their branding out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OwEwuu"&gt;Adults can carry loyalties to brands that they’re exposed to as kids, &lt;a href="https://arizona.pure.elsevier.com/en/publications/how-childhood-advertising-exposure-can-create-biased-product-eval"&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; has shown. That’s not great for their health if they’re developing a taste for junk food, so advocates have pushed for more nutritious options, including plant-based foods, in schools. Impossible Burgers are plant-based and have gotten the green light from the Food and Drug Administration to be sold in grocery stores (despite some activists’ &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22418036/impossible-foods-legal-battle-key-ingredient-heme-fda"&gt;concerns over its key genetically engineered ingredient&lt;/a&gt;, heme, that the company says makes its burgers “taste like meat”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rEspOV"&gt;The problem that Schwartz sees with Impossible Foods’ move into schools has more to do with its branding than with its product. (She’s unable to comment on whether Impossible Burgers are any better or worse than other foods.) If schools want to serve meals with less meat and a smaller carbon footprint, then they should serve the meatless patties without the Impossible trademark, she says.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ANtFA"&gt;“When you allow a giant corporation to use that setting to get their brand in front of kids … It’s completely in conflict with the purpose of schools in the first place and I just think it’s completely unfair,” Schwartz says. “There’s something sacred about the school environment, that it should be a place where students aren’t being pressured to buy particular products.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="ueMGVv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Impossible™ Frito Pie”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="s1DFCu"&gt;Schools in Palo Alto, California; Aberdeen, Washington; Edmond, Oklahoma; and Union City, Oklahoma, will start pilot programs serving Impossible Burgers this month. The product won’t just appear in a bun, either. There will be “Impossible™ Street Tacos,” “Impossible™ Frito Pie,” and “Spaghetti with Impossible™ Meat Sauce.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ilOsfR"&gt;Impossible Foods seems to want to take more schools by storm soon. “Making Impossible™ products available everywhere people consume meat, which for kids often includes schools, is key to the mission of the company,” Pat Brown, CEO and Founder of Impossible Foods, said in a &lt;a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210506005414/en/Impossible-Foods-Secures-Child-Nutrition-Label-for-Impossible%E2%84%A2-Burger-Launches%C2%A0-Insights-Report-on-Kids-Climate-Change"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wgbgk6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xTMQRr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425006/impossible-foods-burgers-school-lunch-marketing-kids"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425006/impossible-foods-burgers-school-lunch-marketing-kids</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
