<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-08-22T17:31:32-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-22T17:31:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-22T17:31:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>New Trailers: Eternals, Foundation, The Hand of God, and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FZA6fBrBg944SdQPWFo-MkE_NSI=/604x0:1756x768/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69761277/angelina_jolie.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Angelina Jolie stars in Eternals, coming to theaters November 5th. | &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x_me3xsvDgk&amp;amp;ab_channel=MarvelEntertainment" target="_blank"&gt;Marvel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SAp5H3"&gt;I think I have found the max number of streaming shows I can keep up with/commit to at once and that number is three and a half. I just added &lt;em&gt;Manifest&lt;/em&gt; back into the rotation because Netflix dropped season three and &lt;em&gt;The White Lotus&lt;/em&gt; ended. Good timing, thanks, streaming channels! A few quick recaps of the past week’s shows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GWaPsu"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The White Lotus&lt;/em&gt; finale. While the theme song will forever haunt me, this deeply unsettling show remained unsettling to the very end. I didn’t love it but I can’t stop thinking about it, so figure that out for me. Kathryn VanArendonk has an interesting &lt;a href="https://www.vulture.com/article/the-white-lotus-finale-mike-white-interview-departures-ending.html?utm_medium=s1&amp;amp;utm_campaign=vulture&amp;amp;utm_source=tw"&gt;interview in &lt;em&gt;Vulture&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; with WL creator Mike White who says he accepts the criticism of the show. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iZHANn"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt; episode 5 (official title: &lt;em&gt;Rainbow&lt;/em&gt;): If it makes me a sap, fine, but I loved this rom-communism/Roy Kent-centric episode. Yes, the show has left some fairly significant plot threads (Jamie Tartt, the Dubai Air protest, the team’s financial state) simmering on the back burner for two episodes in favor of its Christmas episode and this latest one, but I don’t think it means they’ve forgotten about those plots (and I have not seen any screeners so I’m coming to each episode the same time as everyone else). And, the latest episode accomplished a very significant plot point with the aforementioned Roy Kent that should add some spiciness to the back half of the season. Just believe, you guys. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5dyyXZ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Good Fight&lt;/em&gt;: While Wanda Sykes is a very welcome addition to the show and her character is fascinating, the &lt;em&gt;Good Fight&lt;/em&gt; is starting to feel a tiny bit overstuffed with quirkiness. And Wackner’s court is heading in a sinister (and illegal!) direction, which hopefully the show is going to bring full circle soon. Still, Audra McDonald and Christine Baranski make the show worth watching (and Sarah Steele needs a Marissa spinoff, imo). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vX4Ah4"&gt;On to this week’s trailers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="f8JLv8"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/x_me3xsvDgk?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="NEFeb1"&gt;Eternals &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="irSMyY"&gt;Why didn’t the Eternals help the Avengers fight Thanos? Because they were “instructed not to interfere in any human conflicts unless Deviants were involved,” Gemma Chan’s Sersi explains in this trailer. Now the Eternals have to get the band back together to stop the Deviants and they only have seven days. Richard Madden, Brian Tyree Henry, Selma Hayek, Angelina Jolie, Kumail Nanjiani, Barry Keoghan, Lia McHugh, Ma Dong-seok, and Lauren Ridloff star in &lt;em&gt;Eternals&lt;/em&gt;, directed by Chloe Zhao. It comes to theaters November 5th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wf5Ti4"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X4QYV5GTz7c?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="MtKXmj"&gt;Foundation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="3DWsZd"&gt;As my colleague Jay Peters &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632413/foundation-apple-tv-plus-trailer-game-of-thrones-energy"&gt;put it&lt;/a&gt;, this trailer for the upcoming science-fiction series based on the Asimov novels has some “&lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt; but in space” vibes. I actually got a “more serious, scarier &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; with no light-sabers” vibe personally but let’s not have that argument on the internet. Jared Harris stars as Dr. Hari Seldon, who has predicted the fall of the Empire (see?) , and brings a band of loyal followers to the edge of the galaxy to try to rebuild civilization via The Foundation. Lee Pace, Lou Llobell, Leah Harvey, Laura Birn, Terrence Mann, Cassian Bilton, and Alfred Enoch also star. The first two episodes of &lt;em&gt;Foundation&lt;/em&gt; premiere on Apple TV Plus on September 24th, with the remaining eight episodes arriving weekly after that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="AQeQuJ"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CFUVnhUsNws?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="hz6JEJ"&gt;The Hand of God&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="vO27CJ"&gt;Directed by Oscar-winning Italian filmmaker Paolo Sorrentino, The Hand of God is the story of a young boy in Naples in the 1980s, who is saved from a tragic accident by soccer superstar Diego Maradona. Several years ago Sorrentino told &lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt; the story of how Maradona inadvertently &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2015/film/global/paolo-sorrentino-on-making-youth-and-why-maradona-has-a-special-place-in-his-heart-1201660014/https://variety.com/2015/film/global/paolo-sorrentino-on-making-youth-and-why-maradona-has-a-special-place-in-his-heart-1201660014/"&gt;saved his life&lt;/a&gt;, and has called &lt;em&gt;The Hand of God&lt;/em&gt; his most personal film. Naples looks just beautiful in this trailer, you’ll be unsurprised to hear.  Filippo Scotti, Toni Servillo, Teresa Saponangelo, and Marlon Joubert star in &lt;em&gt;The Hand of God,&lt;/em&gt; which is coming soon to Netflix and theaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MraTAE"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aQO16k5Vdow?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="WRTHPu"&gt;Nightbooks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="u4W0Vw"&gt;Krysten Ritter looks like she is having the time of her life in this trailer, as a witch who orders a young boy trapped in an enchanted (not in the good way) apartment to write scary stories for her every night, OR ELSE. Based on the young adult novel of the same name,&lt;em&gt; Nightbooks&lt;/em&gt; stars Winslow Fegley and Lidya Jewett as two resourceful kids trying to figure out how to defeat the witch once and for all. It comes to Netflix on September 15th. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/22/22632136/new-trailers-eternals-foundation-hand-of-god-nightbooks-apple-tv-netflix-marvel"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/22/22632136/new-trailers-eternals-foundation-hand-of-god-nightbooks-apple-tv-netflix-marvel</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-22T12:55:27-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-22T12:55:27-04:00</updated>
    <title>Go read this story about Ehtesab, a crisis alert app giving Afghans on-the-ground news</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AvspZQqAI8n3Imm1pkveWdB-BbU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69760436/acastro__171016_1777_0001_v2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pCs4TL"&gt;As conditions in Afghanistan continue to deteriorate and the Taliban gain control of its major cities, it’s been a challenge for its citizens to get accurate information about what’s happening from moment to moment. &lt;a href="https://restofworld.org/2021/kabul-based-crisis-alert-app-struggles-to-protect-its-own-employees/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rest of World&lt;/em&gt; tells the story&lt;/a&gt; of Kabul-based startup &lt;a href="https://www.ehtesab.af/"&gt;Ehtesab&lt;/a&gt;, which relies on crowdsourced reports from vetted users to track everything from electricity outages to bombings to traffic jams, and feeds the information to its app, which then sends out push notifications. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="cJKQUw"&gt;Ehtesab means “accountability” in Dari and Pashto, and the app, formally launched in March 2020, offers streamlined security-related information, including general security updates in Kabul to its users. With real-time, crowdsourced alerts, users across the city can track bomb blasts, roadblocks, electricity outages, or other problems in locations close to them. The app, which generates push notifications about nearby security risks, is supported by 20 employees working out of the company’s Kabul office, according to [founder Sara] Wahedi. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="wN5xsd"&gt;Wahedi and her staff are currently working remotely for their safety — she tells &lt;em&gt;Rest of World&lt;/em&gt; even they were surprised by how quickly the Afghan government collapsed — and Ehtesab avoids mentioning the Taliban in its security updates, providing information in a “discreet” way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="nMzSAE"&gt;For instance, a roadblock may indicate that there might be danger, but of course we can’t directly say that there is danger. If we are accused of constructing a narrative against the government, then we can assert that we provided information about a roadblock and nothing else, since it affects people’s movement. That is the strategy we are adopting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="z3OySX"&gt;It has become more and more difficult to get information in and out of Kabul in recent days, but Wahedi said she felt a responsibility to Afghanistan’s younger generation, who “have grown up in war.” Silence, Wahedi says, “gives the Taliban an upper hand.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O0YX8R"&gt;&lt;a href="https://restofworld.org/2021/kabul-based-crisis-alert-app-struggles-to-protect-its-own-employees/"&gt;Go read this story&lt;/a&gt; about what it’s like collecting and disseminating crucial information amidst the chaos in Afghanistan.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/22/22636642/go-read-this-afghanistan-app-ehtesab-news"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/22/22636642/go-read-this-afghanistan-app-ehtesab-news</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-22T11:27:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-22T11:27:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>US orders six commercial airlines to provide planes to transport Afghans and Americans in Middle East</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An American Airlines plane prepares for takeoff" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/upt-VFsD6C032aDgJ4i2vuyXoqc=/0x35:3000x2035/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69760233/1323906507.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;American Airlines is one of six commercial airlines ordered to assist with evacuations from Afghanistan | Photo by Joe Raedle/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="AaJQvC"&gt;Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin III on Sunday activated stage 1 of the Civil Reserve Air Fleet (CRAF), ordering six commercial airlines to provide passenger planes to help evacuate people from US military bases in the Middle East, the Department of Defense said in a &lt;a href="https://www.defense.gov/Newsroom/Releases/Release/Article/2741564/department/"&gt;news release. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W6Rjmv"&gt;The planes won’t fly in or out of the Kabul airport in Afghanistan, but will help transport Afghans and US citizens who have arrived at bases in Bahrain, Qatar, and the United Arab Emirates. The plan calls for 18 planes total; four from United Airlines, three each from American Airlines, Atlas Air, Delta Airlines, and Omni Air, and two from Hawaiian Airlines. The DoD said in the release it doesn’t expect the CRAF activation to have a major impact on commercial flights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gyKMne"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2021/08/22/afghanistan-kabul-taliban-live-updates/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; officials said Sunday that the planes would help move Afghans from the bases in the Middle East to places in Europe, and some to the US. The bases have seen the arrivals of thousands of Afghans trying to flee as the Taliban take over Afghanistan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="htjWGO"&gt;According to the DoD, Sunday is the third time CRAF has been activated; it was first activated during the war in the Persian Gulf in (from August 1990 to May 1991), and during the Iraq war (from February 2002 to June 2003).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AeJFPP"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/22/22636608/us-orders-six-commercial-airlines-planes-help-evacuate-afghanistan-kabul"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/22/22636608/us-orders-six-commercial-airlines-planes-help-evacuate-afghanistan-kabul</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-22T09:42:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-22T09:42:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook releases shelved content transparency report after criticism it wasn’t being transparent</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="facebook stock art" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lid9krPFThHD16u7231T65uUSUU=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69759942/acastro_180928_1777_facebook_hack_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Facebook has released a content transparency report it initially withheld | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GQfDZZ"&gt;Facebook released a &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/ixy9meh6vari4lf/Q1-Content-Transparency-Report-V0-US-internal-copy%20%281%29.pdf?dl=0"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; (.pdf) late Saturday about its most-viewed posts in the first quarter of 2021 that it had initially shelved reportedly because it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22634841/facebook-most-viewed-content-report-look-bad"&gt;made the company look bad&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ehuzFH"&gt;As first &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/20/technology/facebook-popular-posts.html"&gt;reported by the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;/a&gt; which obtained a copy of the Q1 report before Facebook released it, the most-viewed link on Facebook between January and March of this year was a since-updated news story that suggested a Florida doctor’s death may be linked to the COVID-19 vaccine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="id__w3jh76vv54l"&gt;Facebook policy communications manager Andy Stone &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/andymstone/status/1429208057947561987?s=20"&gt;tweeted Saturday&lt;/a&gt; that the criticism Facebook received for not releasing the report “wasn’t unfair,” but tried to unpack the complexities of how it handled that most-viewed link: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WICBf2"&gt;“News outlets wrote about the south Florida doctor that died. When the coroner released a cause of death, the Chicago Tribune appended an update to its original story; NYTimes did not. Would it have been right to remove the Times story because it was COVID misinfo?” Stone tweeted. “Of course not. No one is actually suggesting this and neither am I. But it does illustrate just how difficult it is to define misinformation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lzTytJ"&gt;Stone said Facebook had withheld the January-March report “because there were key fixes to the system we wanted to make.” He didn’t elaborate further on what those fixes were, but tweeted a link to the Q1 report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WlEHpi"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;On the question of the unreleased report from earlier this year and why we held it. We ended up holding it because there were key fixes to the system we wanted to make.&lt;/p&gt;— Andy Stone (@andymstone) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/andymstone/status/1429209741130096647?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 21, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Mxsua0"&gt;What Facebook released on August 18th was a report showing the &lt;a href="https://transparency.fb.com/data/widely-viewed-content-report/"&gt;most-viewed content in its public News Feed from April to June&lt;/a&gt;, its second quarter. It offers a rosier picture of the company; the most-viewed post in Q2 was a word puzzle that invited users to pick out the first three words they saw. The second most-viewed Facebook post between April and June asked users over 30 to post a picture of themselves if they looked young. The most-viewed domains included YouTube, UNICEF, Spotify, and CBS News. Among the top ten most-viewed links on Facebook in Q2 were a &lt;a href="https://64.media.tumblr.com/2d32d91bcdfa6e17f18df90f1fada473/6094b00761d82f16-76/s400x600/f0383899ecb1484b10e3420a368d871d7dc68f91.gifv"&gt;GIF of kittens&lt;/a&gt;, and a &lt;a href="https://www.unicef.org/coronavirus/unicef-responding-covid-19-india"&gt;UNICEF response page for India’s COVID-19 crisis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bi4GJA"&gt;It’s not totally clear why Facebook decided to release these reports of popular content at all, but criticism of the platform’s handling of misleading COVID-19 information has been mounting in recent weeks. The Biden administration has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578431/white-house-surgeon-general-facebook-youtube-twitter-covid-19-misinformation-vaccines"&gt;urged Facebook and other social media&lt;/a&gt; platforms to do a better job at dealing with misleading or false information about COVID-19 vaccines on their sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9lmvaL"&gt;Another possible motivation for Facebook’s new “transparency” reports is likely the work of &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; tech columnist Kevin Roose&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FacebooksTop10"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;who last year began using Facebook-owned content analytics platform &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FacebooksTop10"&gt;CrowdTangle to compile and publish daily lists&lt;/a&gt; of the top-performing US Facebook pages, lists which frequently included pages dedicated to former President Trump, and right-leaning pundits like Ben Shapiro and Dan Bongino. The lists were reportedly a &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/07/14/technology/facebook-data.html"&gt;source of irritation for Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DrSuVz"&gt;Facebook did not immediately reply to a request for comment on Sunday morning. You can read the full Q1 content transparency report below. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zB1bCx"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/21046967-q1-content-transparency-report-v0-us-internal-copy-1/?embed=1&amp;amp;responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="Q1-Content-Transparency-Report-V0-US-internal-copy (1) (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="905" style="border: 1px solid #aaa; width: 100%; height: 800px; height: calc(100vh - 100px);" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/22/22636508/facebook-releases-shelved-content-transparency-report-content-coronavirus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/22/22636508/facebook-releases-shelved-content-transparency-report-content-coronavirus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-21T18:07:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-21T18:07:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>CEO of Saygus smartphone company that never released a phone charged with fraud</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Saygus V2" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wN1KWnwmKkqG1SP0Vy-Bx0_CLRA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69758490/saygus-v2-ces-2015-DSC07637.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;This is the Saygus V2, which authorities say was never released.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uz7zUV"&gt;A Utah man who touted a revolutionary new smartphone for several years but failed to produce one, has been charged by the US Attorney’s office in Utah with securities fraud. a new filing shows. Chad Leon Sayers solicited approximately 300 investors to invest $10 million in Saygus, promising “imminent billion-dollar success,” &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-ut/united-states-vs-chad-leon-sayers"&gt;according to the Justice Department.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yWj0id"&gt;Instead of using the funds he raised to create the promised smartphone, he paid personal expenses and debts, and paid older investors with funds he raised from newer ones, which the US Attorney’s office in Utah called “Ponzi-like.” Sayers allegedly spent $2.17 million of the money raised on office rent, about $800,000 of the funds to settle other lawsuits, $500,000 on legal fees, $145,000 on shopping, entertainment, and personal care, and about $30,000 on his personal credit card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jqGNED"&gt;According to the US Attorney’s office, Sayers began soliciting the funds in 2006, and used emails, social media &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Saygus/status/689204286484398081?s=20"&gt;including Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, and investor newsletters to persuade people to invest in the phone and provide “updates” about the phone’s launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OC6So7"&gt;Saygus touted its &lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/2009-11-10-saygus-vphone-to-bring-video-calls-and-a-bit-of-chub-to-android.html"&gt;first VPhone&lt;/a&gt;—which boasted a sliding keyboard— in 2009, and showed off what it said was the Saygus V2 at the International Consumer Electronics Show (CES) in 2015. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/1/6/7505955/saygus-v-squared-super-smartphone-ces-2015"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;got a peek&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="7rMWhx"&gt;It’s not necessary to say something is “great on paper.” Saygus has created what it’s called a “super smartphone,” and in many ways it feels like they looked at a spec sheet and said, “we can make this look really good.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9qmhux"&gt;The Saygus V2 has a 5-inch, 1080p display and features a 2.5GHz quad core Snapdragon processor with 3GB RAM, powering Android 4.4.4 KitKat. Saygus says the V2 designed for the media junkie, which is to say it boasts up to 320GB of storage — 64GB internal with two MicroSDXC slots. It’s got a 21-megapixels rear (with dual-LED flash) and 13-megapixel front-facing camera. The V2 also has Harman Kardon speakers, a biometric fingerprint scanner, built-in Wireless Qi charging, root access for developers... look, there’s a &lt;em&gt;lot &lt;/em&gt;to love&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;in this phone. The design isn’t particularly inspired, but the frame is fairly small and robust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="AgsVB2"&gt;But that phone never came to pass, either. &lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt; has been keeping a close eye on the Saygus saga for several years (they even have a separate Saygus section!), and their &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/tags/saygus/"&gt;archives have many of the twists and turns&lt;/a&gt; of this very weird tale. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ceDDbO"&gt;A jury trial for Sayers is scheduled to begin August 30th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="DBy8zZ"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/21046936-us-doj-chad-leon-sayers-saygus/?embed=1&amp;amp;responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="US DOJ Chad Leon Sayers Saygus (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="905" style="border: 1px solid #aaa; width: 100%; height: 800px; height: calc(100vh - 100px);" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/21/22635779/ceo-saygus-smartphone-company-fraud"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/21/22635779/ceo-saygus-smartphone-company-fraud</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-21T17:08:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-21T17:08:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung Pay wallet now lets you store a digital version of a COVID-19 vaccination card</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/idlwCwlobGjIDo6q4rKnNr1hE2I=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69758362/acastro_190503_1777_samsung_0004.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Samsung now lets you store your vaccine card in Samsung Pay | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yUujrc"&gt;Samsung devices that support Samsung Pay can now store digital versions of users’ COVID-19 vaccination cards, through a partnership with healthcare nonprofit The Commons Project, the smartphone company &lt;a href="https://www.samsungmobilepress.com/pressreleases/the-commons-project-foundation-introduces-smart-health-cards-within-samsung-pay"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YksKRt"&gt;Users have to first download the free CommonHealth app from the Google Play store, and follow the instructions to access their COVID-19 vaccine record, from participating pharmacies, health systems, and health providers (not all providers are connected to the system yet). Once the user has access to their COVID-19 credential within the CommonHealth app, they can add it to their Samsung Pay wallet. The Covid-19 Vaccine Pass will then be available on the Samsung Pay app home page. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gVU9vGq0Ng49wTkAPy8c3QDMaUM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22797510/01_health_pass_feature_on_samsung_pay.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Samsung Pay lets users store their COVID-19 vaccination pass &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Qcu7II"&gt;For restaurants, schools, offices, or other places that are requiring proof of vaccination, it’s not clear yet whether they’ll accept these electronic versions, or whether you’ll have to show your paper COVID-19 vaccination card. And Samsung Pay still has a very &lt;a href="https://www.emarketer.com/content/us-payment-users-will-surpass-100-million-this-year?ecid=NL1016"&gt;small market share&lt;/a&gt; of the mobile payments market, where Apple Pay dominates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8DejzO"&gt;The electronic COVID vaccine card has been a bit slow to catch on, but there’s been some progress. In June, Google opened up Android’s built-in passes system to &lt;a href="https://developers.googleblog.com/2021/06/google-updates-passes-api-to-save-covid-testing-and-vaccination-information-on-Android-devices.html"&gt;let Android users store a digital vaccine card&lt;/a&gt;, on their phones. Available first in the US, it will rely on support from healthcare providers, or other organizations authorized to distribute COVID vaccines. And some states, like &lt;a href="https://epass.ny.gov/home"&gt;New York&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://publichealth.lacounty.gov/acd/ncorona2019/vaccine/vaccinationrecords/"&gt;California&lt;/a&gt;, have introduced their own digital vaccine cards.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/21/22635740/samsung-pay-wallet-digital-covid-vaccination-proof"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/21/22635740/samsung-pay-wallet-digital-covid-vaccination-proof</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-21T15:21:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-21T15:21:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Go read this story of why Aaliyah’s ‘One in a Million’ album took 20 years to come to streaming </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Aaliyah File Photos" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/F6kbonQoqK7_vawZ6aETL45uKbg=/0x141:2512x1816/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69758022/119974698.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Aaliyah attends the 2000 MTV Movie Awards | Photo by Kevin Mazur/WireImage&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eWoKb7"&gt;The 1996 album “One in  a Million,” by Aaliyah finally came to streaming platforms on Friday, almost 20 years after the singer’s death in a 2001 plane crash. A huge star in the 1990s and early 2000s, much of Aaliyah’s music has been missing from streaming platforms for the past two decades. As &lt;a href="https://www.billboard.com/articles/news/9610793/aaliyah-music-return-streaming-services-blackground-empire/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Billboard&lt;/em&gt; magazine reported&lt;/a&gt; in a lengthy feature earlier this month, Aaliyah’s uncle, music producer Barry Hankerson, and her estate, controlled by her mother Diane Haughton and brother Rashad Haughton, have been at odds for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="scB1w1"&gt;According to&lt;em&gt; Billboard,&lt;/em&gt; Hankerson has made a distribution deal to release the entire catalog of Blackground Records— which includes Aaliyah’s music as well as recordings from other artists including Timbaland &amp;amp; Magoo, and Toni Braxton— to streaming starting this month. He told &lt;em&gt;Billboard&lt;/em&gt; he had not released Aaliyah’s recordings previously because he was trying to respect his sister’s wishes. &lt;em&gt;Billboard&lt;/em&gt; reports that’s up for debate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="vk1iGU"&gt;That claim, however, is under some dispute. But regardless of the reason, over the years the catalog has sat on the shelf, untouched, as Hankerson says he waited for the tenor of the conversation to change. From time to time an artist or label would inquire about sampling or covering one of the songs in the catalog, but with the path to success unlikely, one source says that rarely did anyone try very hard. The early, low monetary returns from streaming in the first part of the 2010s did little to encourage a reversal, and with the record business in financial freefall, there seemed little to be gained from the endeavor but backlash.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="RJAvLa"&gt;At the same time the news was breaking that Aaliyah’s past albums and some previously-unreleased music would be coming to streaming starting this month, the estate &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AaliyahHaughton/status/1423091902962876420?s=20"&gt;released a statement&lt;/a&gt;, saying that protecting the singer’s legacy “is and will always be, our focus.” The statement made reference to “shadowy tactics of deception” and called the plan to release her music an “unscrupulous endeavor,” but added that the plan “compels our hearts to express a word— forgiveness.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HvaCWT"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.billboard.com/articles/news/9610793/aaliyah-music-return-streaming-services-blackground-empire/"&gt;Go read this &lt;em&gt;Billboard&lt;/em&gt; report&lt;/a&gt; that tells the inside story of how Aaliyah’s music has been in limbo for two decades, and why it’s finally available. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/21/22635598/aaliyah-music-20-years-streaming-one-in-a-million"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/21/22635598/aaliyah-music-20-years-streaming-one-in-a-million</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-21T12:08:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-21T12:08:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>China passes new privacy law aimed at protecting users’ personal data</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/C1NLD5enDX5U3iHqPk8YBievkvs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69757533/acastro_170629_1777_0008_v2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;China has passed a user data privacy law | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hcOkeU"&gt;China has passed a new privacy law aimed at protecting users’ personal data, state media &lt;a href="http://m.news.cctv.com/2021/08/20/ARTIwr19ckRZu9Bhobw4k5wp210820.shtml"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;. The new law comes as Chinese tech firms have come under renewed scrutiny in the country, and sets rules around how companies handle users’ information. The law takes effect on November 1st. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EGNemt"&gt;The law—formally called the Personal Information Protection Law— was passed by China’s legislature on Friday, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-passes-new-personal-data-privacy-law-take-effect-nov-1-2021-08-20/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt;, and calls for companies to get users’ consent before collecting personal data, and has rules for how companies should ensure users’ data is protected when it’s transferred outside of China. Tech companies that handle personal information must have a designated person tasked with overseeing its protection, and companies must conduct regular audits to be sure they’re complying with the law. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ET5Bvf"&gt;In addition, companies handling personal user data have to have clear and reasonable purpose for doing so, and must limit it to the “minimum scope necessary to achieve the goals” of handling said data, according to &lt;em&gt;Reuters. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6rLjQu"&gt;In an op-ed in the Chinese state media outlet People’s Court Daily, the National People’s Congress lauded the new legislation, &lt;em&gt;Reuters &lt;/em&gt;reported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9NupbI"&gt;“Personalization is the result of a user’s choice, and true personalized recommendations must ensure the user’s freedom to choose, without compulsion,” the op-ed piece read. “Therefore, users must be given the right to not make use of personalized recommendation functions.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/21/22635404/china-privacy-law-protect-users-personal-data"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/21/22635404/china-privacy-law-protect-users-personal-data</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-21T11:37:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-21T11:37:16-04:00</updated>
    <title>Clubhouse removed personal info from users’ accounts in Afghanistan as a safety measure</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pBTR5hvEEJNWLHkXV3vaCZzMjhE=/548x0:3548x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69757451/clubhouse_graphic.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Clubhouse has removed some info from users in Afghanistan as a safety measure | Clubhouse&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9fE9RP"&gt;Social audio app Clubhouse has joined other social platforms in taking steps to protect the privacy and safety of its users in Afghanistan. Earlier this week, the platform reset tens of thousands of its Afghan users’ bios and photos, and made their accounts more difficult to discover in search. A spokesperson for Clubhouse said the actions didn’t affect the users’ followers, and all of the changes can be reversed if a user prefers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wHI3A7"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;A message form &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Clubhouse?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Clubhouse&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Afghanistan?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Afghanistan&lt;/a&gt;’s users. &lt;a href="https://t.co/CpS4iz0L1J"&gt;pic.twitter.com/CpS4iz0L1J&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Zaki Daryabi (@ZDaryabi) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ZDaryabi/status/1428233850296184836?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 19, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IYjbVF"&gt;Clubhouse has also been reminding its Afghan users that it does allow pseudonyms for human rights or safety purposes. The company consulted with free expression and violent extremism experts to help craft its approach, the spokesperson said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xRsJfd"&gt;As the Taliban have regained control of the country,  many &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/taliban-violence-drives-afghans-wipe-social-media-profiles-rcna1731"&gt;people in Afghanistan have tried to delete photos&lt;/a&gt; from their social media accounts and phones that could show a connection to the West, or the former Afghan government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NvEbcs"&gt;And despite bans on many social platforms, the Taliban has been able to push its messaging on social media, becoming as &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/08/18/taliban-social-media-success/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; wrote, sophisticated at social media tactics in an attempt to change its image. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="35Fx2I"&gt;On Thursday, Facebook said it had added &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ngleicher/status/1428474000611573762?s=20"&gt;security measures for users in Afghanistan&lt;/a&gt;, including hiding “friends” lists and adding a tool to quickly lock down accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uEjH2W"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/21/22635378/clubhouse-removes-personal-info-user-accounts-afghanistan-taliban-safety"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/21/22635378/clubhouse-removes-personal-info-user-accounts-afghanistan-taliban-safety</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-21T09:36:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-21T09:36:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>Judge rules California Prop 22 gig workers law is unconstitutional</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="App-based drivers from Uber and Lyft protest in a caravan in front of City Hall in Los Angeles on October 22, 2020 where elected leaders hold a conference urging voters to reject on the November 3 election, Proposition 22, that would classify app-based drivers as independent contractors and not employees or agents" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2KVUW0SAtiJlqu_PjrEb68tXysc=/396x0:4404x2672/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69756985/1229223235.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Drivers held a protest against Prop 22 in October. The measure passed in November, however. | Photo by FREDERIC J. BROWN/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="awPxLG"&gt;California’s gig workers law, which allows companies like Uber and Lyft to treat workers as independent contractors— not employees— has been ruled unconstitutional and unenforceable by a judge. Voters &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/4/21546037/prop-22-california-uber-lyft-ballot-measure-result"&gt;approved the law as ballot initiative Proposition 22&lt;/a&gt; in November, with companies like Uber, Lyft and DoorDash spending more than $200 million to campaign for the measure. Labor organizations, including the Service Employees International Union, opposed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l4QeG9"&gt;California Superior Court Judge Frank Roesch ruled Friday that the law illegally “limits the power of a future legislature to define app-based drivers as workers subject to workers’ compensation law,” adding that “The entirety of Proposition 22 is unenforceable.” He also ruled that it was unconstitutional to that the law required any future amendments to have a seven-eighths vote of approval to pass the legislature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j8dvV9"&gt;In January, a group of Uber and Lyft drivers, along with the SEIU, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227042/uber-lyft-prop-22-lawsuit-overturn-drivers-california"&gt;filed a lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; seeking to have the measure overturned. The law exempts gig employers from providing benefits and protections to workers, but requires that they offer healthcare subsidies and minimum hourly earnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="iK2jnN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It appears only to protect the economic interest of the network companies...”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8UxWYr"&gt;Roesch took issue with the part of the law that requires any future California state law concerning collective bargaining for gig workers to comply with the Prop 22 law. “It appears only to protect the economic interest of the network companies in having a divided, ununionized workforce, which is not a stated goal of the legislation,” he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MTi0rp"&gt;Geoff Vetter, a spokesperson for the Protect App-Based Drivers &amp;amp; Services &lt;a href="https://protectdriversandservices.com/about/our-coalition/"&gt;Coalition&lt;/a&gt; (PADS), which includes Uber, Lyft, DoorDash, and Instacart, said in a statement emailed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that they plan to appeal. The judge “made a serious error by ignoring a century’s worth of case law requiring the courts to guard the voters’ right of initiative,” Vetter wrote, noting that a majority of California voters had approved the measure. “All of the provisions of Prop 22 will remain in effect until the appeal process is complete.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BMuQFF"&gt;Bob Schoonover, president of SEIU California State Council praised the judge’s ruling in a statement emailed to The Verge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AgoODQ"&gt;“The gig industry-funded ballot initiative was unconstitutional and is therefore unenforceable. Companies like Uber and Lyft spent $225 million in an effort to take away rights from workers in a way that violates California’s Constitution,” Schoonover wrote. “They tried to boost their profits by undermining democracy and the state constitution. For two years, drivers have been saying that democracy cannot be bought. And today’s decision shows they were right.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mC5jXB"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update August 21st 12:16PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Adds statement from SEIU&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wm62KJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DW21rR"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XwWR45"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/21046905-prop-22-unconstitutional/?embed=1&amp;amp;responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="prop 22 unconstitutional (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="905" style="border: 1px solid #aaa; width: 100%; height: 800px; height: calc(100vh - 100px);" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/21/22635286/judge-rules-california-prop-22-gig-workers-law-unconstitutional"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/21/22635286/judge-rules-california-prop-22-gig-workers-law-unconstitutional</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
