<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-13T18:08:59-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-13T18:08:59-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-13T18:08:59-04:00</updated>
    <title>LittleBigPlanet online security issues blamed for permanent server shutdown on PS3 and Vita</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/B9nBxJAE9xssD8jDY3PZGpx26bM=/124x0:2188x1376/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69854067/Screen_Shot_2021_09_13_at_1.25.37_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="if6FU4"&gt;Sony has permanently shut down the servers for the original three &lt;em&gt;LittleBigPlanet&lt;/em&gt; games on Playstation 3 and the handheld &lt;em&gt;LittleBigPlanet&lt;/em&gt; on the Playstation Vita, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LittleBigPlanet/status/1437415883752845318?s=20"&gt;according to a tweet&lt;/a&gt; posted by the official LittleBigPlanet account on Monday (&lt;a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/little-big-planet-1-2-3-ps3-vita-online-servers-shutting-down"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;IGN&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c2BHav"&gt;The new status quo leaves the originally PS3 trilogy of &lt;em&gt;LittleBigPlanet&lt;/em&gt; games and the Vita version playable &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LittleBigPlanet/status/1437422130711379970?s=20"&gt;as offline single-player or co-op experiences only&lt;/a&gt;, with purchased and already downloaded DLC also usable. Any user-created content — the most intriguing aspect of Sony and original developer Media Molecule’s famous action-platforming series — will only be accessible &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LittleBigPlanet/status/1437418106591268866?s=20"&gt;on the newly updated Playstation 4 version of &lt;em&gt;LittleBigPlanet 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The server shutdown also means that anyone stuck with older PS3 versions of the games is also unable to upload or download new user-created levels from now on,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CsXZnV"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;An update on the LittleBigPlanet server and online services: &lt;a href="https://t.co/vUrvHcZvIs"&gt;pic.twitter.com/vUrvHcZvIs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Sackboy: A Big Adventure | LittleBigPlanet (@LittleBigPlanet) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LittleBigPlanet/status/1437415883752845318?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 13, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IRChsL"&gt;“We have no doubt the news will come as a big disappointment to a lot of you,” Sony wrote in the statement. “Ultimately this is the best way to protect the &lt;em&gt;LittleBigPlanet&lt;/em&gt; community and to help ensure that our online community environment remains safe.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U3jr9t"&gt;Suddenly closing up shop on &lt;em&gt;LittleBigPlanet&lt;/em&gt;’s servers appears to be motivated by Sony's ongoing difficulties with the games’ online component. In March 2020, the games’ servers were temporarily taken down due to DDoS attacks, &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2021-03-12-littlebigplanet-servers-offline-as-fans-report-ddos-attack"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eurogamer&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt;. Players &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/littlebigplanet/comments/ni6r6z/warning_hackers_can_display_offensive_messages/"&gt;have also reported&lt;/a&gt; offensive messages appearing in-game, seemingly placed there by hackers. &lt;em&gt;LittleBigPlanet&lt;/em&gt;’s developers attempted to address some of the server issues with security updates in April of this year, &lt;a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/littlebigplanet-devs-break-silence-with-promise-to-restore-servers-as-soon-as-we-can"&gt;&lt;em&gt;IGN&lt;/em&gt; writes&lt;/a&gt;. Still, the problem appears to be larger than something a small update can fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lns6tM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22672201/littlebigplanet-servers-shutdown-hacks-offensive-messages"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22672201/littlebigplanet-servers-shutdown-hacks-offensive-messages</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-13T18:05:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-13T18:05:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Stop and update your iPhone to iOS 14.8 right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Apple" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tD4CoZE3XDP5N7N3rFYqvkgwSSM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69854057/acastro_170731_1777_0003_v6.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vNbyFA"&gt;Apple has released a suite of new updates for &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT212807"&gt;iOS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT212804"&gt;macOS&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT212806"&gt;watchOS&lt;/a&gt; to fix a bug that &lt;a href="https://citizenlab.ca/2021/09/forcedentry-nso-group-imessage-zero-click-exploit-captured-in-the-wild/"&gt;security researchers at Citizen Lab&lt;/a&gt; say was very likely exploited to allow government agencies to install spyware into the phones of journalists, lawyers, and activists. The researchers say the bug allowed for a “zero-click” install (meaning the target didn’t have to do anything to be infected) of the Pegasus spyware, which is reportedly capable of stealing data, passwords, and activating a phone’s microphone or camera. You can read &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22589942/nso-group-pegasus-project-amnesty-investigation-journalists-activists-targeted"&gt;our explainer of Pegusus here&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ghtgyJ"&gt;Given the severity of the exploit, you should update to iOS 14.8, macOS Big Sur 11.6, and watchOS 7.6.2 as soon as you can. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="gDzdFG"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple’s update page says it’s “aware of a report that this issue may have been actively exploited.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="11sjdQ"&gt;We heard about the exploit in August, &lt;a href="https://citizenlab.ca/2021/08/bahrain-hacks-activists-with-nso-group-zero-click-iphone-exploits/"&gt;when Citizen Lab reported&lt;/a&gt; that it had been successfully used against phones running iOS 14.6 (released in May). Citizen Lab also said the vulnerability, which it codenamed “ForcedEntry,” seemed to match the behavior of an exploit Amnesty International &lt;a href="https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/research/2021/07/forensic-methodology-report-how-to-catch-nso-groups-pegasus/"&gt;wrote about in July&lt;/a&gt;. At the time, the security researchers wrote that it was made possible by a bug in Apple’s CoreGraphics system, and happened when the phone tried to use a function related to GIFs, after it received a text message containing a malicious file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GY3uHD"&gt;However, even with that info, it could be difficult to pin down exactly what was happening without access to the infected files themselves. &lt;a href="https://citizenlab.ca/2021/09/forcedentry-nso-group-imessage-zero-click-exploit-captured-in-the-wild"&gt;According to Citizen Lab&lt;/a&gt;, they discovered files while re-analyzing a backup from an activist’s hacked phone. The files appeared to be GIFs sent as SMS attachments, but were actually PSDs and PDFs. (&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT212807"&gt;Apple’s update notes&lt;/a&gt; say that the issue occurred when processing a maliciously crafted PDF.) Citizen Lab suspected they could’ve been related to Pegasus, so it sent the files to Apple on September 7th. Apple quickly released the software updates patching the bug on September 13th, and thanked Citizen Lab in a statement for “completing the very difficult work of obtaining a sample of this exploit.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="IweTQR"&gt;&lt;q&gt;iOS 14.8 is seemingly only focused on security&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TEuK8F"&gt;Some of Monday’s updates also fix a second security issue with WebKit for iOS and macOS Big Sur (it isn’t mentioned in the release notes for Catalina). While it’s unclear if it’s related to NSO’s exploits — its discovery is attributed to “an anonymous researcher” instead of Citizen Lab, and it’s in a different part of the system — Apple still says that it “may have been actively exploited.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LWQTAy"&gt;Such an urgent security issue explains why we’re seeing a new update to iOS just a day before an Apple event, where it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22663715/apple-iphone-13-event-rumors-announcements-california-streaming"&gt;expected to announced new phones&lt;/a&gt; that will probably never run this version of the OS. Still, there have been rumors about an iOS 14.8 release &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/08/09/ios-14-8-release-date-information-rumor/"&gt;since early August&lt;/a&gt;, but given that Monday’s release seems to only deal with the security issues discovered in September, it’s possible we’ll see at least one more iOS 14 release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="55m3eu"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Keep your devices up-to-date&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eLzesV"&gt;CoreGraphics’ PDF rendering seems to have been problematic recently when it comes to security. &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT212601"&gt;iOS 14.7 also included a fix&lt;/a&gt; for a seemingly separate issue with the system, which could also lead to arbitrary code execution. WebKit has also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/26/22251149/iphone-update-14-4-fixes-exploited-security-vulnerabilities"&gt;recently had&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/26/22251149/iphone-update-14-4-fixes-exploited-security-vulnerabilities"&gt;few updates&lt;/a&gt; to fix security issues that Apple says “may have been actively exploited.” When news of the CoreGraphics exploit broke in August, &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/24/nso-pegasus-bahrain-iphone-security/"&gt;Apple told &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; it was working on improving security for iOS 15.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IaocFK"&gt;All of this serves as a reminder about how important it is to keep all your devices up-to-date. While you hopefully never find yourself on the bad side of a government using advanced spyware, it’s still a good idea to make sure that your device isn’t vulnerable to widely-reported security exploits. Thankfully, Apple is &lt;a href="https://www.droid-life.com/2021/06/07/apple-introduces-android-fragmentation-with-ios-15/"&gt;planning on letting&lt;/a&gt; users install security updates for iOS 14 without having to upgrade to iOS 15, which could be useful for any future fixes. For the time being, though, get all your devices updated as soon as you can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c1LRoB"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 13th, 7:10PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added quote from Apple’s statement thanking Citizen Lab.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22672352/apple-spyware-gateway-iphone-software-update-nso-pegasus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22672352/apple-spyware-gateway-iphone-software-update-nso-pegasus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-13T18:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-13T18:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sennheiser’s latest true wireless earbuds offer noise cancellation for less</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fjAYCKwPOpEDNgmdPQY9H4PLPLI=/0x0:1200x800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69854024/ezgif_7_8ac862e63642.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The earbuds will be available later this month in either black or white.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Sennheiser&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="atFaDc"&gt;Sennheiser’s CX Plus true wireless earbuds aren’t its first pair to offer noise cancellation, but it’s the first time the feature has appeared on its more affordable CX range. At $179, the CX Plus are more expensive than the $129 &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fen-us.sennheiser.com%2Fcx-true-wireless&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F13%2F22671228%2Fsennheiser-cx-plus-true-wireless-earbuds-noise-cancellation-release-date-news-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CX True Wireless announced&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year, but they’re affordable compared to the flagship $300 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/22/21230931/sennheiser-momentum-true-wireless-2-review-earbuds-headphones-sound-specs-battery-life-price"&gt;Momentum True Wireless 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wYBndB"&gt;Beyond noise cancellation, the CX Plus also include a transparent hearing mode, which uses their microphones to pass through audio from the outside world when you need to be aware of your surroundings. It’s got an IPX4 resistance to splashing water, two microphones on each earbud, and battery life that stands at a total of 24 hours when the buds are topped up from the charging case (compared to 27 hours for the cheaper CX, and 28 for the Momentum 2). &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w-FVwIXm1Px8ZqWBXcmu9rGbfHA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22846302/CX_PLUS_TW_Mood_Image_Black.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Sennheiser&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Combined with the charging case, the earbuds offer 24 hours of listening.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ymVpsx"&gt;In terms of codecs, the earbuds support SBC, AAC, AptX, and AptX Adaptive. You control the buds with touch controls, which like the EQ settings, are customizable. Interestingly, Sennheiser says both the left and right earbuds can be used individually, whereas only the right Momentum 2 earbud could be used on its own. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8j2wi8"&gt;While $179 for a pair of noise cancelling true wireless earbuds is affordable for Sennheiser, it’s still expensive compared to some other brands. Most notably, the recently released &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22598920/nothing-ear-1-earbuds-review-features-specs"&gt;Nothing Ear 1 earbuds&lt;/a&gt; offered noise cancellation for just $99 (albeit not at the same level of quality as their more expensive competition). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lwRj1Z"&gt;Sennheiser’s CX Plus earbuds will go on sale on September 28th, when they’ll be available in either black or white. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DKSGfq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fGvC3j"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671228/sennheiser-cx-plus-true-wireless-earbuds-noise-cancellation-release-date-news-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671228/sennheiser-cx-plus-true-wireless-earbuds-noise-cancellation-release-date-news-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-13T17:45:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-13T17:45:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>The best deals on MacBooks right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hZX5JfVeNbOPhxgT-vEb8Xev40E=/2x0:2039x1358/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69195507/vpavic_4291_20201113_0337_Edit.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacBook Air (late-2020).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YgkMYN"&gt;With multiple configurations and various models to choose from, including some equipped with Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/19/21574057/apple-m1-chips-laptop-performance-intel-qualcomm-competition"&gt;new M1 processor&lt;/a&gt;, finding a deal on a MacBook or Mac Mini is not all that difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i5kEtb"&gt;Here, we’ll run through the discounts that are currently available for the latest MacBook models, as well as any deals to be had on the Mac Mini. Of course, there are also frequent discounts available for older Intel-based configurations — which will be compatible with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22557880/apple-macos-public-beta-facetime-safari-updates"&gt;macOS Monterey&lt;/a&gt; upon its release in the fall — and we’ll highlight those when we find them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7QDx7u"&gt;Alternatively, purchasing refurbished is another way to save money on an Apple computer. &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1022323/7613?sharedid=VergeBestDealsAppleMacbook042721&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Frefurbished%2Fmac" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple’s refurbished store&lt;/a&gt; provides a one-year warranty on all products and generally has discounts of 15- to 20-percent off the price of a new model. Two other retailers to look at for refurbished MacBooks are &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1738963691650209208#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/certified-refurbished-apple-macbook/s?k=certified+refurbished+apple+macbook" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. For now, however, these are the best MacBook and Mac Mini deals you can take advantage of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="15A2tS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best Apple Watch deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21289209/best-apple-watch-deals"},{"title":"Here are the best iPad deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21280354/best-ipad-deals-apple"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="EVXzol"&gt;The best MacBook Air deals &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="FJU3RG"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MacBook Air&lt;/a&gt; is Apple’s entry-level laptop. It’s best suited for typical productivity work, with a comfortable keyboard, excellent trackpad, and all-day battery life. The most recent model includes the Apple-designed M1 processor and lacks a fan for quiet, efficient performance. It ticks all right boxes when it comes to performance and price, which is why it’s our number one pick for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21250695/best-laptops" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;best laptop of 2021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iF2kto"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9737407"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LZawtk"&gt;The base MacBook Air with the M1 chip has 8GB of RAM and a 256GB SSD. It typically sells for $999, however, it’s currently available at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08N5LNQCX?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; for $850 once you add it to your cart, where additional savings will automatically apply. This matches the all-time low for this popular entry-level laptop. The 512GB configuration is also on sale at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5LFLC3?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; in all three colorways for $1,100, a discount of $150 that automatically applies at checkout. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZRJZQQ"&gt;Although retailers like &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1747531561997035408#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1604825-REG%2Fapple_mgn63ll_a_13_3_macbook_air_with.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22399419%2Fapple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt; are selling the base 256GB MacBook Air and upgraded, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1747532219045612135#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;512GB&lt;/a&gt; model at regular price, we have seen them drop the pricing in the past to match Amazon’s discounts. These deals can come and go quickly, though, we expect more to come as the holiday shopping season draws near.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="DTHGG6"&gt;The best MacBook Pro deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="JByVWG"&gt;The touch bar-equipped &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt; comes in more sizes and options than the Air, and it’s geared more toward demanding use cases. The base model is the 13-inch, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;M1-powered variant&lt;/a&gt;, which includes a brighter screen, longer battery life, and an internal fan designed to maintain performance under increased workloads. The M1 MacBook Pro 13 normally starts at $1,299, but the base model with 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage is on sale for $150 off at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5N6RSS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1738975458064148072#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; — bringing it down to $1,150.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="afDps1"&gt;The upgraded version of the 13-inch M1 MacBook Pro with 8GB of RAM and a 512GB SSD is also $150 off at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08N5LH3F7/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1747532652589677821#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; for a final sale price of $1,350.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tjmE4B"&gt;While there have been rumors throughout the year of a r&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/6/9/22526584/apple-m1x-macbook-pro-wwdc-2021-youtube-tags" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;edesigned MacBook Pro, one with an M1X processor and additional ports&lt;/a&gt;, we might not see it until further into the fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Ue6Q0U"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9733800"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="44XxWs"&gt;Of course, you can also buy some older MacBook Pro models, including the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21256520/apple-13-inch-macbook-pro-2020-review-keyboard-specs-price-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;13-inch, mid-2020 model&lt;/a&gt;. The older device features four Thunderbolt ports, Windows bootcamp-ready Ice Lake processors, the current scissor-switch keyboard, increased RAM, and various storage configurations. Right now, the 13-inch model is available in two configurations at Amazon: one with a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-Pro-10th-Generation-Quad-Core/dp/B08DTPQ9XB/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;10th Gen i7 Intel processor and 512GB of storage&lt;/a&gt; for $1,999, and one with &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-Storage-Keyboard/dp/B08821TJLG?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;1TB of storage and a 2.0GHz 10th Gen Intel Core i5 processor&lt;/a&gt; for $1,600.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hij1MQ"&gt;If you want a bigger laptop with more horsepower, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/21/20974649/apple-macbook-pro-16-inch-laptop-review-keyboard-test-specs-price-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2019 MacBook Pro 16&lt;/a&gt; is the top-of-the-line model. Compared to its predecessor, it has a better keyboard, newer processors, and improved speakers. Amazon is currently offering the space gray configuration with an Intel Core i7 CPU and 512GB of storage &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-16-Inch-512GB-Storage/dp/B081FZV45H/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on sale for $2,285&lt;/a&gt;, a $114 discount. There are other configurations available with more storage and speedier processors — you can also get the 16-inch model with an Intel Core i9 CPU and 1TB of storage &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-16-Inch-512GB-Storage/dp/B081FTNGNC/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;for $2,645 at Amaz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-16-Inch-512GB-Storage/dp/B081FV1Y57/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on&lt;/a&gt;, for instance — but deals are few and far between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zjWXtS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10469149"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="LYpjlZ"&gt;The best Mac Mini deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Un7j7n"&gt;While it is not an Apple laptop, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21570046/apple-mac-mini-2020-m1-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Mac Mini&lt;/a&gt; is an affordable desktop computer with macOS. It does not include a display, keyboard, or mouse (so you’ll have to supply your own), but this compact machine is an excellent performer if you aren’t concerned about portability. It’s fast, efficient, and comes outfitted with Wi-Fi 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O9PC7b"&gt;Like the MacBook Air and MacBook Pro 13, the Mini features Apple’s new M1 processor. It starts at $699, with the price varying based on your RAM and storage configurations. The outright best deal on the base Mac Mini is at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08N5PHB83/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, where you can pick up the 256GB model for a historical low of $600 (discount applies at checkout).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CpqfyJ"&gt;As for the 512GB model, we have seen retailers such as &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08N5P7TLW/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1604800-REG%2Fapple_mgnt3ll_a_mac_mini.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22399419%2Fapple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt; offer it for $100 off its usual $899 price point, but there are currently no sizable discounts to be found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="RPnQwi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9712859"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="APBdOd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22399419/apple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22399419/apple-macbook-air-pro-mac-mini-imac-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
      <name>Brandon Widder</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-13T17:17:27-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-13T17:17:27-04:00</updated>
    <title>SpaceX is about to send its first crew of private citizens to space</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0Ts1Rky-Y1-ul08wHa_H5iytV3g=/0x0:3840x2560/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69853738/E_I1GNOUcAY2E4x.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;SpaceX&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="AGzBt4"&gt;Four people are set to launch to space Wednesday night aboard a SpaceX capsule, and none of them are professional astronauts. Jared Isaacman, a billionaire entrepreneur and philanthropist, booked the Crew Dragon capsule last year and picked three normal folks to ride with him. It will be the first completely private mission to orbit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JCy7Px"&gt;Dubbed Inspiration 4, the mission is a multimillion-dollar fundraiser for St. Jude Children’s Hospital and — like a lot of recent flights to space these days — an effort to convince those watching from the ground that space won’t be always be exclusive to government officials and the ultra-wealthy. Isaacman’s crew includes Hayley Arceneaux, a cancer survivor and St. Jude physician assistant; Sian Proctor, a geology professor and former NASA astronaut candidate; and Christopher Sembroski, a data engineer at Lockheed Martin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dQM7Pt"&gt;The Inspiration 4 crew is slated to launch Wednesday at 8:02PM ET atop SpaceX’s Falcon 9 rocket, buckled inside the same Crew Dragon capsule that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/15/21565237/spacex-crew-1-dragon-launch-success-falcon-9-nasa"&gt;nearly a year ago&lt;/a&gt; sent a four-person crew of government astronauts to the International Space Station &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/2/22413121/spacex-crew-dragon-resilience-splashdown-nasa-record-iss"&gt;and back&lt;/a&gt;. This mission’s destination is about 80 miles higher than the ISS. In orbit, they’ll view Earth through two windows and a new glass dome that was added to the top of the capsule, where Crew Dragon’s ISS docking door was. The crew will reenter the atmosphere after three days, depending on the weather around Florida, and splash down in the Atlantic ocean. SpaceX recovery teams will likely meet up with the capsule, hoist it onto a ship, extract the crew, and bring them ashore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="RkcSE1"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;A look at Dragon’s Cupola, which will provide our Inspiration4 astronauts with incredible views of Earth from orbit!&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;The crew visited the flight-hardware Cupola in California before it was shipped to Florida for integration with Dragon Resilience. &lt;a href="https://t.co/9ivMZrS1ip"&gt;pic.twitter.com/9ivMZrS1ip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Inspiration4 (@inspiration4x) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/inspiration4x/status/1433192632457564160?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 1, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="E7pGmD"&gt;Isaacman, a trained pilot and the founder of a payment processing company, is the commander of the flight. He has said he wanted to arrange a diverse crew of passengers who weren’t billionaires. He paid for all four seats on Crew Dragon, and dropped the first $100 million of a $200 million fundraiser for St. Jude, a nonprofit research facility and hospital that provides free care to children with cancer. Isaacman reserved two of the seats for St. Jude — one would go to the winner of a fundraising campaign and the other would go to Arceneaux, who works at St. Jude as a physician assistant in Memphis, Tennessee and will serve as the mission’s medical officer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1TeC6S"&gt;Arceneaux, 29, is a childhood cancer survivor who will become the first person with a prosthetic body part to launch to space. Metal rods were placed in the part of her left leg that had a cancerous tumor as a child. Sembroski, the Lockheed engineer, will occupy the seat reserved for the winning participant of the St. Jude fundraising campaign. A friend of Sembroski’s won, but couldn’t go on the trip and passed the ticket to him instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BsVlKe"&gt;The fourth seat went to Sian Proctor, the winner of a contest hosted by Shift4, the payment company owned by Isaacman. Contestants had to create a &lt;a href="https://myspace2inspire.com/"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; using Shift4 software and produce a short &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DrSianProctor/status/1365148498509791234?s=20"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; of themselves explaining why they wanted to go to space. Proctor, 51, taught geology at a community college in Phoenix, Arizona and will become the fourth Black woman, and the first person from Guam, to go to space. In 2009, she got close to becoming a NASA astronaut as one of nine finalists in a monthslong, notoriously difficult selection process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5se8tW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10749753"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="avQt4C"&gt;The crew has been training since March, about seven months before liftoff. That includes centrifuge training to get used to the enormous G-forces of lifting off atop a rocket, a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/inspiration4x/status/1414624789860282372?s=20"&gt;microgravity experience&lt;/a&gt; aboard a Zero-G flight, and weeks of training at SpaceX’s headquarters in Hawthorne, California to familiarize the passengers with Crew Dragon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zijbjY"&gt;Besides the passengers’ personal mementos, like family items and school memorabilia, the mission is full of sponsorships: 66 pounds of hops are on board Crew Dragon that, once returned to Earth, will be used to brew beer by Samuel Adams, “the official beer of Inspiration4,” the mission group said in a press release, adding the brewer made “a maximum $100,000 donation to St. Jude.” All the passengers will wear branded watches, Sembroski will play an onboard ukulele from Martin Guitar, and a bunch of other things on board will get auctioned off once they’re back on the ground as part of the ongoing St. Jude fundraiser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e29McH"&gt;If all goes as planned, Inspiration 4 will mark the first fully private mission for SpaceX, which developed its Crew Dragon spacecraft as part of NASA’s Commercial Crew Program. That program funded development of two competing space capsules — Crew Dragon and Boeing’s CST-100 Starliner — to serve as NASA astronauts’ ride to the ISS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="DFfw2Q"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“like watching your kids graduate from college”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="me7zyV"&gt;For the Commercial Crew Program, NASA is a customer — not an owner — of the spacecraft, much like Isaacman is the main customer for Inspiration4. A core goal behind the program was to help stimulate a market for commercial spaceflight, awarding SpaceX roughly $3 billion and Boeing roughly $5 billion to help get started. Boeing’s Starliner has yet to launch humans. But Isaacman’s mission, which will mark the fourth crewed flight for SpaceX’s Crew Dragon, a key intent of NASA’s program, has come to fruition. As NASA’s human spaceflight chief Kathy Lueders recently said in the &lt;a href="https://www.wmfe.org/category/are-we-there-yet"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are We There Yet?&lt;/em&gt; podcast&lt;/a&gt;, Inspiration 4 “is like watching your kids graduate from college.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="SpaceX Crew-2 Crew Walkout" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kE_eDMx71OVnrOu9bhJ5OCzw6vU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22846091/1232472247.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Aubrey Gemignani / NASA via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Astronauts for SpaceX and NASA’s most recent crewed mission, Crew-2, don SpaceX’s flight suits and prepare to board Crew Dragon in April.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Vd2pjl"&gt;But whether private space tourism will &lt;em&gt;really &lt;/em&gt;be accessible to a larger swath of passengers remains to be seen. A seat on SpaceX’s Crew Dragon costs roughly $55 million, and a seat on Starliner is somewhere around $90 million, according to government watchdog reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yLTVrE"&gt;For a shorter experience, other companies like Virgin Galactic and Blue Origin are offering brief suborbital jaunts to the edge of space — but these are still extremely expensive. Right now, Virgin Galactic &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611847/virgin-galactic-ticket-sales-richard-branson"&gt;charges $450,000&lt;/a&gt; for a seat on its SpaceShipTwo, which flies some &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/11/22572374/richard-branson-virgin-galactic-space-unity"&gt;53 miles high for a few minutes of weightlessness&lt;/a&gt; and views of Earth’s curvature. Blue Origin hasn’t announced prices for a seat aboard its suborbital New Shepard rocket, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22582735/blue-origin-jeff-bezos-space-launch-landing"&gt;launches about 66 miles above ground&lt;/a&gt; for a similar experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Hvx0jw"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“in order to get to the endpoint we want, you have to go through this initial step”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="R15a0u"&gt;With Isaacman footing the multimillion-dollar bill for his three fellow passengers’ tickets to space, and both Blue Origin and Virgin Galactic flying highly publicized back-to-back missions, the space tourism industry is in a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/17/22573791/space-tourism-industry-bezos-branson-musk-billionaire-phase"&gt;phase buoyed by billionaire backers&lt;/a&gt; and ultra-wealthy customers. Getting out of this phase, as industry figures have said, will require drastic drops in the cost of building and launching rockets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zyKbF3"&gt;“We’ve been hearing that for so long, that until it happens, it’s not unusual that people are a little skeptical about that,” says Alan Ladwig, who in the 1980s led NASA’s &lt;a href="https://ntrs.nasa.gov/citations/19860031168"&gt;Space Flight Participant Program&lt;/a&gt;, an initiative to send civilian storytellers like teachers and journalists to space as a way to get the public excited about human spaceflight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2owtpI"&gt;“But in order to get to the endpoint we want, you have to go through this initial step, with the early adopters and paying higher costs to go in order to eventually lower the cost,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22667339/spacex-inspiration4-first-all-civilian-crew-dragon"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22667339/spacex-inspiration4-first-all-civilian-crew-dragon</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-13T16:51:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-13T16:51:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>Litecoin price jumped 20 percent after hoax linked the cryptocurrency to Walmart </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="In this Photo illustration a Litecoin logo " src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OZxsYbU3ciXhRx13tKeVtDscYco=/0x4:5000x3337/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69851585/1234956057.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Litecoin spiked Monday after a false press release claimed Walmart would accept the cryptocurrency | Photo Illustration by Avishek Das/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="H0H7Ov"&gt;The Litecoin cryptocurrency saw its price spike by as much as 20 percent on Monday after a fake press release claimed Walmart would begin accepting Litecoin as payment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MJyULD"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2021/09/13/2295879/0/en/Walmart-Announces-Major-Partnership-With-Litecoin-LTC.html"&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; posted to GlobeNewswire linked to a non-functioning website, and there was no evidence of any Securities and Exchange Commission filing, which would have been expected since Walmart is publicly traded. Walmart’s official newsroom never included the release, and the company typically uses &lt;a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210823005697/en/Walmart-Launches-Walmart-GoLocal-a-New-Delivery-as-a-Service-Business"&gt;Business Wire&lt;/a&gt; to distribute releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yZ1B3A"&gt;Dave Pleiss, vice president, investor and public relations for GlobeNewswire said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;that this has never happened to the company before. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gS2fNr"&gt;“When GlobeNewswire became aware this morning that a fraudulent user account was used to issue an illegitimate press release we promptly withdrew the press release and issued a Notice to Disregard.” Pleiss wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nt1K70"&gt;The company has already put into place “enhanced authentication steps to prevent this isolated incident from occurring in the future,” Pleiss added, and said GlobeNewswire was working with authorities on “a full investigation, including into any criminal activity associated with this matter.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FST50B"&gt;Several news outlets published reports based on the hoax press release, and a short time later &lt;a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/LTC-USD?p=LTC-USD&amp;amp;.tsrc=fin-srch"&gt;Litecoin’s price jumped&lt;/a&gt;, along with those of other cryptocurrencies, before quickly falling back to the previous levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nbuq5b"&gt;It’s not yet clear who may have been behind the hoax press release, but a Walmart spokesperson &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/09/13/walmart-to-accept-payments-with-cryptocurrencies-using-litecoin.html"&gt;confirmed to CNBC&lt;/a&gt; that the news announcement was fake. Walmart didn’t reply to a request for comment from&lt;em&gt; The Verge&lt;/em&gt; on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JjwmH5"&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: September 13th 4:50PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Adds comment from GlobeNewswire spokesperson.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hS5rwH"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671485/walmart-crypto-hoax-litecoin-cryptocurrency"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671485/walmart-crypto-hoax-litecoin-cryptocurrency</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-13T16:24:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-13T16:24:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nvidia leak may reveal unannounced games, including God of War for PC</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5woCgSlCXpCPjkVhuoDcR4z805E=/0x0:1371x914/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69853409/GameofWar.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1HfheJ"&gt;If you made an Nvidia GeForce Now server spit out a confidential list of thousands of games, some never-before-seen, would you think they were legit? Fake? Somewhere in between? That’s not a rhetorical question, because developer Ighor July has &lt;a href="https://ighor.medium.com/i-unlocked-nvidia-geforce-now-and-stumbled-upon-pirates-dc48a3f8ff7"&gt;found such a list&lt;/a&gt; — including games like the PlayStation exclusive &lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt; seemingly coming to Windows PC via Steam. If you’d like to scan it yourself, SteamDB creator Pavel Djundik published &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/xPaw/6a42aafd3c9d19b3ceab2e90b5a37cd2"&gt;a version to GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JsROXh"&gt;Here’s a screenshot of what that looks like in the GeForce Now client, &lt;a href="https://ighor.medium.com/i-unlocked-nvidia-geforce-now-and-stumbled-upon-pirates-dc48a3f8ff7"&gt;according to the developer&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/q2dJ9UjqO_XWtMkG34vwts4shLc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22847842/god_of_war_gfn.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7kQ7Hc"&gt;There are reasons to believe the list is legit. We know graphics giant Nvidia has access to games long before they’re released — and we know Sony in particularly has been banking on &lt;em&gt;banking&lt;/em&gt; on PlayStation games on PC. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455810/sony-ps5-profitable-uncharted-4-pc-investor-presentation"&gt;It quietly revealed &lt;em&gt;Uncharted 4&lt;/em&gt; was coming to PC&lt;/a&gt;, after seeing a 250 percent return on its investment porting &lt;em&gt;Horizon: Zero Dawn&lt;/em&gt; to the platform, and it was just Thursday that Sony announced it would be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22661816/sony-playstation-showcase-uncharted-legacy-of-thieves-collection-ps5-pc"&gt;part of the &lt;em&gt;Uncharted: Legacy of Thieves Collection&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — a name that we’d never heard of before then, but already appears in Nvidia’s list as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uNcnL1"&gt;So too do &lt;em&gt;Demon’s Souls&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XVI&lt;/em&gt; — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/17/21444039/ps5-playstation-5-final-fantasy-xvi-demons-souls-pc-announcement"&gt;the games where Sony had to retroactively retract all mentions of PC&lt;/a&gt; to make them sound like PlayStation exclusives. PS5 exclusive &lt;em&gt;Returnal &lt;/em&gt;appears as well, as does a &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/em&gt; for PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o1N9xu"&gt;And there are codenames for games in here that seem original, ones that bring up zero search results. Is “Platinum” the internal name for Bethesda’s &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones&lt;/em&gt; games? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="GBFper"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Reasons to believe, reasons to disbelieve&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yp1svl"&gt;But there are also a lot of mentions that seem rather out of date or out of place, like a whole host of Facebook-exclusive Oculus Rift titles that would make little sense on Nvidia’s GeForce Now cloud gaming service, or a mention of a “&lt;em&gt;Titanfall 3&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;which clarifies that it’s actually “GAMEapex_legends_-_titanfall,” aka &lt;em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;/em&gt;, the popular battle royale game. And some of them may simply be guesses, like &lt;em&gt;Kingdom Hearts IV&lt;/em&gt;, “BioShock 2022,” and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="64ZQL0"&gt;All of that means you should probably take any given name on the list with a grain of salt — maybe don’t get your hopes up for remasters of &lt;em&gt;Chrono Cross&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; Tactics Ogre&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;Half-Life 2 &lt;/em&gt;quite yet, even if all of those appear in the document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="23Vfo2"&gt;But &lt;em&gt;God of War &lt;/em&gt;for PC does seem more solid than others. It’s one of a handful of titles that specifically mentions Steam. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hmwl2T"&gt;You can peruse &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/xPaw/6a42aafd3c9d19b3ceab2e90b5a37cd2"&gt;the full list for yourself right here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bq0TD3"&gt;Nvidia didn’t immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AtbP21"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction, 6:39PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;While July uncovered the leak, it was SteamDB’s Pavel Djundik that published a copy to GitHub. We regret the error.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22672280/nvidia-leak-geforce-now-playstation-games-god-of-war"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22672280/nvidia-leak-geforce-now-playstation-games-god-of-war</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-13T15:04:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-13T15:04:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon gives the Kindle’s interface a refresh</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cj8gN-5mXTRXQh0xEsOsOcu5ueM=/0x61:1768x1240/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69853091/Header_Jaeger_Decanter_3008x1300.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Amazon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LjD9Up"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/b?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;node=23599449011"&gt;Amazon has announced&lt;/a&gt; that most recent Kindles will be getting a new simpler UI through a software update (&lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/09/a-quick-tour-of-amazons-new-ui-for-kindle-e-readers/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The update mainly focuses on navigation, adding a bar to the bottom of the screen that lets you jump between the Home screen, the book you’re currently reading, and the Library screen. Some &lt;a href="https://blog.the-ebook-reader.com/2021/08/17/new-kindle-software-update-5-13-7-brings-user-interface-changes/"&gt;have had the update for a few weeks&lt;/a&gt;, but Amazon has announced that the update will be rolling out widely over the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k5NtQz"&gt;The way you access the Kindle’s quick settings (which let you turn on airplane mode, adjust brightness, and more) has also changed. You now get access to the menu by swiping down from the top of the screen, instead of tapping a button. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wap7jD"&gt;Amazon says more changes will be coming later this year, with an update that will let you see more recently read books on the Home screen and will refresh the Library’s collection view and filter and sort menus. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EmtiiOZQ0df6u7COCFk-H_LM4E8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22847407/Pack_2_UPDATED_Jaeger_Decanter_Group_1000x1000._CB642431930_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Amazon&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A preview of the Home and Library screens.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="9OxZhr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/b?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;node=23599449011"&gt;Amazon’s webpage&lt;/a&gt; for the redesign says the feature will be rolling out to supported devices (8th Gen Kindle, 7th Gen Paperwhite, and Oasis or above) within the next few weeks. Basically, it includes most Kindles released since 2015, so there’s a decent chance yours will be supported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B4qhO5"&gt;Unfortunately, Amazon hasn’t made the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=GK33S847NN4V6Y83&amp;amp;ref_=hp_lp_help_c_Identify-Your-Kindle-E-Reader"&gt;Kindles’ generation info&lt;/a&gt; easily available until the update that’s currently rolling out. It seems &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/what-generation-of-kindle-do-i-have"&gt;the best way to find out&lt;/a&gt; if your device is eligible is to Google the model number, which should be on the back of the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EHjtwQ"&gt;Like the readers’ E Ink displays, the Kindle interface doesn’t get refreshed very often. Amazon didn’t add the ability to make the lock screen show the cover of the book you’re reading &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22387146/amazon-display-cover-lockscreen-current-book-image"&gt;until earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/em&gt; also reports that the Kindle web browser’s “experimental” label — which has existed for at least 10 years, &lt;a href="https://goodereader.com/blog/kindle/why-do-you-need-to-disable-javascript-on-the-kindle-browser"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;GoodEReader&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — is gone. Unfortunately, &lt;em&gt;Ars&lt;/em&gt; reports not being able to see any changes from the previous (and &lt;a href="https://www.amazonforum.com/s/question/0D54P00007T46Ek/experimental-browser-on-my-kindle-doesnt-work"&gt;not very good&lt;/a&gt;) version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j1r9e3"&gt;The update should automatically install on your Kindle at some point if it’s connected to Wi-Fi, but you can also &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=GFAE5G5UGCYA25DW"&gt;manually update your device using a computer&lt;/a&gt; if you’re looking to get the new UI as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671844/amazon-kindle-e-reader-interface-design-changes"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671844/amazon-kindle-e-reader-interface-design-changes</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-13T15:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-13T15:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>HP ZBook Studio G8 review: works hard, plays harder</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Well-designed, but far too expensive for most people&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="wRKy1r"&gt;There’s usually a clear line that divides any manufacturer’s lineup of gaming and business laptops, but the new ZBook Studio G8 blurs HP’s lines a bit. It aims to be multiple machines at once, including a gaming laptop. And for the most part, it pulls the juggling act off, if you can stomach the cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XKG5dM"&gt;The G8 looks like a high-end Windows machine, and it’s easy to see where it fits in HP’s catalog next to the dashing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22264792/hp-spectre-x360-14-laptop-stylus-oled-review-price-specs-features"&gt;Spectre X360&lt;/a&gt;. This one borrows the glossy trim going around all of its edges, and its blend of aluminum and magnesium build materials looks and feels great. It has a generously sized Windows Precision trackpad, and its keyboard is just as delightful to type on as some of HP’s other recent models we’ve reviewed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XDicJl"&gt;It’s a simple but gorgeous laptop, yet I wouldn’t recommend &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hp.com%2Fus-en%2Fshop%2FConfigureView%3FurlLangId%3D%26catalogId%3D10051%26langId%3D-1%26storeId%3D10151%26catEntryId%3D3074457345620019820%26quantity%3D1&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22671603%2Fhp-zbook-studio-g8-laptop-business-gaming-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;this $4,727 configuration of HP’s ZBook Studio G8&lt;/a&gt; to most people. The price is overkill if all that you want to do is game, and most people likely won’t need the robust suite of privacy and security features (like an Absolute persistence module, TPM 2.0, Bitlocker encryption, HP Power On Authentication, and much more) that are included to accommodate the enterprise crowd. There are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22295181/best-gaming-laptop"&gt;some very good laptops out there suited for creators or gamers&lt;/a&gt; that we recommend. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pgkXkT"&gt;But as an all-in-one entertainment, gaming, and enterprise device (a unique combination, to be sure), the ZBook Studio G8 is a polished, performant effort that delivers powerful specs and many features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3atDdm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10750363"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JRpyUN"&gt;HP’s ZBook Studio G8 is a versatile laptop, but it invites comparisons to other gaming laptops in a few major ways, the most noticeable one being its backlit RGB keyboard with custom per-key backlighting. This is HP’s only business laptop to feature one, and it even has the company’s Omen Gaming Hub in the taskbar by default, where you can adjust the keyboard backlight settings and optimize performance for any games you have installed. You might get some strange looks if you work at a buttoned-up office, but it’s also likely that it’ll just make your ThinkPad-toting colleagues jealous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="VAi0EI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10750299"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UH6HjP"&gt;My review sample has Nvidia’s GeForce RTX 3070 graphics chip (85W maximum graphics power, 1230MHz boost clock), along with other powerful specs including the &lt;a href="https://ark.intel.com/content/www/us/en/ark/products/213798/intel-core-i911950h-processor-24m-cache-up-to-4-90-ghz.html"&gt;Intel Core i9-11950H vPro processor&lt;/a&gt;, 32GB of fast 3,200MHz DDR4 RAM (soldered on, unfortunately), and a 2TB NVMe SSD (replaceable, but unfortunately just one M.2 slot). Other configurations utilize the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-us%2Fdesign-visualization%2Frtx-a5000%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22671603%2Fhp-zbook-studio-g8-laptop-business-gaming-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;RTX A-series graphics chips&lt;/a&gt; and are geared toward full-time creators, engineers, and for others with intensive tasks. But this one was made to be both your workstation and gaming rig. So, of course, I got my game on with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dSOgBZ"&gt;Gaming is a joyous thing to do with the ZBook Studio G8, especially with this configuration that has a 15.6-inch 4K OLED touchscreen that’s covered in Gorilla Glass 6. It looks so brilliant that I almost didn’t mind it topping out at a 60Hz refresh rate. Enthusiast gamers who crave seeing their games playing at 100+ frames per second won’t get that here, at least without plugging an external monitor in. There’s an HDMI 2.1 port, so you can output to 4K at fast refresh rates, if you have a compatible monitor and if you play games that can run well on this laptop. For those who really want fast-moving graphics on the laptop’s screen, HP makes a non-OLED screen option that can go up to 4K IPS instead of OLED at a 120Hz refresh rate, but it naturally won’t look as luscious even if it’s running at a faster clip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="HP ZBook Studio G8" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jYSQ9TVKqI0njI2odPoZNfTEtQA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22810071/cfaulkner_210824_4727_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The colors and contrast on this configuration’s 4K OLED screen look incredible.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="HP ZBook Studio G8" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Mu3ux23v6smDT7goWoPLpbo6fjU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22810068/cfaulkner_210824_4727_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unsurprisingly, the viewing angles are great, too.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="U1j7GB"&gt;As is always the case, performance will vary depending on what games you like to play, but gaming at native 4K resolution in &lt;em&gt;Destiny 2&lt;/em&gt; yielded good results, running at around 45 frames per second on the highest graphical settings. Making a few tweaks to the shadow quality and to the anti-aliasing pushed it up to a steady 60 frames per second. &lt;em&gt;Red Dead Redemption 2&lt;/em&gt; presents more of a challenge for laptops, and the ZBook Studio G8 managed an average of 37 frames per second at 4K resolution with ultra graphical settings turned on. Not bad, and switching on the Nvidia DLSS feature boosted it to a more playable 47 frames per second at 4K resolution. Just a few tweaks later, it felt great to be running this demanding game on a workstation at near 60 frames per second. The G8 isn’t as loud during peak performance as some gaming laptops, but with some games the metal section above the keyboard becomes almost too hot to touch. I didn’t notice any throttling in performance during gaming or otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1XtpIu"&gt;The capable specs in this ZBook Studio G8 let it fly through my everyday work tasks, which usually involve having over a dozen Microsoft Edge tabs open at once, with Slack and Spotify running in the background. Occasionally, I’ll open Affinity Photo to crop photos, too. Most laptops with a good amount of RAM don’t struggle being put through these paces, so I ran a 4K export test in Adobe Premiere Pro to give it more of a workout. It didn’t break much of a sweat here either, sprinting to complete the export of a five-minute, 33-second video in four minutes, 14 seconds. It’s worth keeping in mind that Premiere Pro can work in mysterious ways sometimes, with better specs not necessarily leading to faster export times. We’ve seen some less pricey laptops perform just as well in this test as the ZBook Studio G8, if not better, though this is a good result. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="HP ZBook Studio G8" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mxskvk1bEjuKMG66FXJjLP83Qng=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22810072/cfaulkner_210824_4727_0005.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The speakers are better than I expected, but not the best on a laptop that I’ve ever heard.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="HP ZBook Studio G8" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ld6tM9L-UjlOA0qXSj5kUCD5rh0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22810067/cfaulkner_210824_4727_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;I adore the key layout and performance of the keyboard.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pAydIM"&gt;Outside of performance, I’m happy with most of the design choices that HP made for the ZBook Studio G8. Its keyboard is great, both in layout and the key feel, requiring very little time and few errors for me to adjust. The same goes for its trackpad, which I mentioned before has Windows Precision drivers and is responsive, with a satisfying, tactile click. As for my wishlist for the next iteration, I wish the trackpad’s entire surface was easy to click, like Apple’s MacBook trackpad. The bottom of the trackpad here offers an effortless click, while it gets a little tougher about two-thirds of the way up toward its top. Also, the ZBook’s OLED screen is a treat to look at, but I hope HP employs a taller 3:2 aspect ratio here next time, like it does with the Spectre X360 lineup. Lastly, there are a dearth of ports for a laptop of this size, and for one made to wear so many hats. It has just one USB-A port in total, along with two Thunderbolt 4 ports, HDMI 2.1, a Mini DisplayPort jack, a headphone jack, and a proprietary plug for its 200W power brick (some models use a 150W brick). The brick itself is compact, with a braided cable going to the laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X0K94j"&gt;There’s a Windows Hello-ready webcam and a fingerprint scanner for signing in securely, though using either one is optional. The quality of the 720p IR webcam isn’t stellar, but it gets the job done. (If you care about video quality, though, maybe you’ll find something better in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22652783/best-webcam-camera"&gt;our USB webcam buying guide&lt;/a&gt;.) The speakers are better than I expected for taking video calls with, or for listening to music, though you’ll get better performance out of just about any set of headphones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="HP ZBook Studio G8" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M-zOlh_n-9H3-ansyxYXu7YGCrA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22810073/cfaulkner_210824_4727_0006.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;For a laptop this expensive, there aren’t nearly enough ports.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="HP ZBook Studio G8" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kOKgrhFkPbxzUV1qdI_WjuzCHVE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22810076/cfaulkner_210824_4727_0009.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Though, it does hit the major beats with Thunderbolt 4, Mini DisplayPort, and an SD card reader.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3mGkGy"&gt;This version of the ZBook Studio G8 comes with some other welcome extras. It’s one of a few HP models to ship with Tile functionality and it has the app pre-installed. You’ll be able to track its location via the Tile mobile app, so long as it still has battery life. If photography or shooting videos is a profession or a hobby, you’ll get good use out of this laptop’s full-sized SD card slot. It supports up to 985MB/s transfer speeds with the SD 7.0 spec.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="DawY8k"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10750295"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="o7gnck"&gt;Battery life in gaming laptops has increasingly become less of a joke and, at times, is actually impressive. The longevity of the ZBook Studio G8 can’t hang with laptops that have AMD’s latest Ryzen processors, but I wasn’t too let down by its roughly five-hour battery life. Powering through roughly a half day of work isn’t bad, considering this model is a 4K display, but that won’t cut it for some people who want a laptop that can survive all day. HP says that this laptop’s Thunderbolt 4 ports can be used to charge it, but they can’t pull enough power to both run the machine and charge simultaneously. Though, it could charge the battery while it’s sleeping or off, albeit slower than the stock charger can. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="HP ZBook Studio G8" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r_k_b3oVPIX2hX7aG7k5QiYwfMo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22810074/cfaulkner_210824_4727_0007.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The ZBook Studio G8 looks fantastic for a laptop that’s technically a workstation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UAVsmM"&gt;The HP ZBook Studio G8 is the best enterprise laptop trying to be a gaming laptop, which I recognize is an accolade that doesn’t carry a lot of weight, since it’s really just HP in this niche space. Though, I think if HP iterated on this design and made it a more gaming-focused laptop on the software side, it would have serious potential to take on other chic-looking laptops with real gaming chops, like Razer’s Blade 15 or the MSI GS66 Stealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="SDfbkF"&gt;But for now, I suspect there aren’t many people who’ve been holding onto their cash, waiting for this exact kind of laptop to arrive. If you’re a serious gamer who’s looking for something reliable and great, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321471/asus-rog-zephyrus-g15-gaming-laptop-review"&gt;you should get Asus’ ROG Zephyrus G15 that costs nearly $1,000 less&lt;/a&gt;. It doesn’t have a 4K OLED, but its specs are more balanced for performance and cost efficiency. More games will run more smoothly with its screen’s lower WQHD resolution, and faster, too, with its 165Hz refresh rate. The ZBook Studio G8 is too costly to recommend, but I’m nevertheless excited about the future of this lineup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kozs3J"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22671603/hp-zbook-studio-g8-laptop-business-gaming-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22671603/hp-zbook-studio-g8-laptop-business-gaming-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-13T13:55:58-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-13T13:55:58-04:00</updated>
    <title>A doctor’s quest for more organ emoji</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Emoji for the anatomical heart on the left and the lungs on the right, on a white background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KIwye7bLxS6jjsbBrRvxY3nmbNU=/54x0:881x551/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69852736/ios_anatomical_heart_lungs_new_emoji_2020.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The anatomical heart and lungs emoji, as seen on iOS.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple/&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://blog.emojipedia.org/first-look-new-emojis-coming-to-ios-in-2020/" target="_blank"&gt;Emojipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UtMekI"&gt;The medical world needs more emoji, according to Shuhan He, an emergency medicine physician who &lt;a href="https://www.bostonglobe.com/2020/02/04/metro/this-mass-general-doctor-helped-get-two-new-medical-emojis-approved/"&gt;helped propose&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;the anatomical heart and lungs emoji. Now,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;He and others have laid out the case for an even larger variety of health-related emoji, which they argue could improve communication between doctors and patients.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="atsvvA"&gt;In recent years, emoji related to medicine and health — like stethoscopes, hearing aids, bones, and microbes — have made their way into the Unicode Standard. In &lt;a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2783847"&gt;commentary published&lt;/a&gt; last week in &lt;em&gt;JAMA&lt;/em&gt;, He and his co-authors hope Unicode will approve more emoji that could be used in medical contexts, including emoji for more organs, like the stomach, liver, and intestines, and equipment like an IV bag, CT scan, and pill pack. He also wants more medical professionals to push for such emoji and to establish a standard for emoji usage in medical communication. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9XhIlr"&gt;“We know in medicine that when patients say specific words, that they tend to highly correlate with specific pathology,” says He. People often describe crushing chest pain, for example, as feeling like an elephant is sitting on their chest. “We also consistently always ask people, what is your&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;pain like: sharp, stabbing, dull, or fiery? Those are all emoji that can be represented in pictorial form rather than verbal communication.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="D1fDju"&gt;&lt;q&gt;elephant emoji, heart emoji&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9F1hqa"&gt;Emoji-like images are already widely used in medical settings, He says. The Wong-Baker pain scale shows a smiley face at one end and a grimacing or crying face at the other to signify pain levels. That scale was initially developed for children but is now used in many doctors’ offices and hospitals for patients of all ages. If smiley faces are already a part of medical communication, why not also leverage the visual language that’s standardized across people’s phones?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ilRzFJ"&gt;He sees a range of uses for emoji in medicine. Patients who can’t speak or don’t know English could use emoji to describe their symptoms. For patients who do speak English but don’t have much health literacy, a common, standardized visual language could make it easier for them to understand and follow treatment instructions. The rise of telehealth also provides more opportunities for medical staff to supplement their communications with visuals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KMfw4g"&gt;Jennifer 8. Lee, one of He’s co-authors, is a co-founder of &lt;a href="http://www.emojination.org"&gt;Emojination&lt;/a&gt;, an organization that advocates for more inclusive and representative emoji. Emojination has helped proposals for a number of emoji make it through Unicode’s submission process, including medical emoji like the stethoscope, blood drop, X-ray, and adhesive bandage. (The fight for the blood drop emoji, initially proposed as a menstruation symbol, is included in a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/28/18514833/picture-character-emoji-documentary-movie-unicode-tribeca"&gt;documentary about emoji creation&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oqofne"&gt;“The use of emoji in medicine is really interesting, precisely because in many cases we’re dealing with sort of high stakes, and also very strong cultural practices,” says Lee. “So the more we can move into a curated universal visual medium, the better it can be in the long run.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="Ncokwf"&gt;&lt;q&gt;it’s tricky to get more organs in the mix&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IRUPhv"&gt;Lee is also a vice-chair of the Unicode Emoji Subcommittee. She thinks there’s value in adding more major organ emoji, but she suspects she’s in the minority on that position. Though the brain, anatomical heart, and lungs emoji were all approved, it’s tricky to get other organs in the mix because they’re not necessarily as recognizable and don’t have as much demand, she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2zqo0m"&gt;If medical organizations established a set of important potential emoji and pushed for them to be added, they might have more luck. “I would guess if the industry as a whole, the professional organizations, cared, they could move the needle,” says Lee. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pBLqGu"&gt;Though a few other doctors have expressed desires for more relevant emoji, we don’t know yet how much traction He’s proposal will pick up. There’d likely need to be more studies around patient’s perceptions of emoji before medical associations throw their weight behind any formal efforts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9cz3EW"&gt;It might not seem like emoji should be a big priority in the medical field, but He thinks anything that improves communication between doctors and patients is worthwhile. Being a doctor “means to listen, to hear their pain and hear their struggle, and to hear exactly what they’re trying to go through, and to help them,” He says. “If we can’t communicate, then we can’t be good doctors. And so this is at the very heart of being a good doctor.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22665002/doctors-medical-emoji-organs-health"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22665002/doctors-medical-emoji-organs-health</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kait Sanchez</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
