<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-08-09T17:50:40-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-09T17:50:40-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-09T17:50:40-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitch will give streamers a bit more info on why they were banned</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CtFCbtaaHzgUCgbqSKwGAh0FLi8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69701431/acastro_210115_1777_twitch_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PEQDKt"&gt;Twitch’s suspensions are about to get a little clearer for streamers: starting on Monday, the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/twitchsupport/status/1424777552820846597?s=21"&gt;company announced&lt;/a&gt; that it will include the name and date of the content that violated platform rules when it issues a ban. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zk7ccT"&gt;It’s not quite a clear and simple explanation of what precisely a streamer might have done to get a suspension — Twitch doesn’t seem to be willing to provide that level of detail on any violations of it policies — but it could potentially help streamers figure out what they did wrong and what to avoid in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="sxx9Ba"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt; ️ As of today, enforcement notifications sent to suspended users will include the name of the content and the date of the violation to ensure they have better clarity about what content is being actioned on. &lt;a href="https://t.co/aAnrdEZoyi"&gt;pic.twitter.com/aAnrdEZoyi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Twitch Support (@TwitchSupport) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitchSupport/status/1424777552820846597?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zwUn59"&gt;The new system is more specific than before, when Twitch would just list what rule was violated. But it’s still frustratingly vague for streamers. It points to a single stream, which can consist of hours of content, but it still doesn’t illuminate exactly what it was that crossed a line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ePEMvD"&gt;Twitch has certainly struggled with giving streamers clarity on content issues before. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21562372/twitch-soundtrack-riaa-music-youtube"&gt;Back in 2020&lt;/a&gt;, the company issued waves of DMCA takedown notices to creators without giving specific clarity on which videos were in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/11/21560913/twitch-streamers-dmca-copyright-tools-apology"&gt;violation of copyright&lt;/a&gt;. Monday’s announcement, while not a full solution, at least helps make things a little clearer going forward. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22617270/twitch-banned-streamers-notice-content-reason-suspension"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22617270/twitch-banned-streamers-notice-content-reason-suspension</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-09T17:39:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-09T17:39:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>With the Olympics over, Peacock needs to figure out what’s next</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RNTKvZMOx_eVD24dpWs9hmZZgfU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69701357/acastro_200714_1777_peacock_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Pc7Qfk"&gt;It’s been a rocky couple of weeks for Peacock. NBC positioned its streaming service as the place to go if you wanted to stream the Olympics without a cable subscription — something that should have been an easy win for the upstart platform.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Instead, Peacock’s coverage was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/29/22589928/peacock-2020-olympics-streaming"&gt;wonky and confusing&lt;/a&gt;, and the service hasn’t given viewers much of a reason to stick around after the Games. With its biggest draw behind it and little in the way of internet-breaking titles headed to the platform anytime soon, it’s unclear what comes next for NBCUniversal’s biggest streaming bet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="icHBMm"&gt;Peacock had 54 million sign-ups and 20 million-plus active accounts as of the end of July, just over a year after launch, parent company Comcast said during its second-quarter earnings call. (A spokesperson declined to specify how many of those active accounts are paid.) That’s really tiny — Netflix has surpassed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22238877/netflix-200-million-subscribers-q4-earnings-bridgerton-emily-paris-cobra-kai-queens-gambit"&gt;200 million subscriptions&lt;/a&gt;, by comparison — but it’s a big jump from 42 million sign-ups just a quarter ago, about a third of which the company said were active accounts. The company attributed its growth to the addition of three content exclusives on the platform: Peacock’s “most successful original to date,” &lt;em&gt;Dr. Death&lt;/em&gt;; the day and date release of &lt;em&gt;The Boss Baby: Family Business&lt;/em&gt;; and the 2020 Tokyo Olympics, which ended Sunday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VheUOg"&gt;But even Comcast knows that growth will be tough to keep up. “We are unlikely to replicate such tremendous performance,” Brian L. Roberts, chairman and CEO of Comcast, said during the call. (Disclosure: NBCUniversal is an investor in Vox Media, parent company of &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="boR9DD"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dr. Death&lt;/em&gt; was well-received, and I myself paid up for a premium subscription to finish the series, which stars Christian Slater, Alec Baldwin, and Joshua Jackson in the compelling leading role of Christopher Duntsch. But a closer look at Peacock’s content pipeline shows the service isn’t ready to be a Disney Plus or a Netflix, primarily because Peacock &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2021-07-11/comcast-will-spend-billions-on-peacock-now-it-needs-a-strategy?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;doesn’t appear to be willing&lt;/a&gt; to funnel unfathomable streams of cash into developing high-caliber originals that match the production value of series like &lt;em&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="0Joti8"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Peacock’s content offering and its original strategy look like a broadcast network.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Wb9wd2"&gt;Peacock very much acts like a broadcast network offering users more of the content they might expect to watch on NBC. Richard Broughton, a research director at Ampere Analysis, said that strategy may work for attracting subscribers to the service’s free and ad-supported tier but not necessarily for its premium ones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0dtbNU"&gt;“Peacock’s content offering and its original strategy look like a broadcast network,” Broughton told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “They’ve got a lot of reality shows, they’ve got unscripted and comedy shows. They have relatively few high-end dramas, which have typically been the things that have set groups like Netflix and Disney Plus and HBO Max aside from the broadcast networks. So Peacock’s quite at the moment firmly positioned as, ‘Hey, you like our broadcast channels. Here’s more of the stuff you love from a new streaming perspective.’ And again, that’s fine — potentially. But it’s likely to drive people towards the ad-funded tier as opposed to premium.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jiMtrL"&gt;Peacock’s forthcoming slate includes a series based on Dan Brown’s novel &lt;em&gt;The Lost Symbol&lt;/em&gt;, an Andy Cohen-hosted drama series called &lt;em&gt;Ex-Rated&lt;/em&gt;, and teen murder drama &lt;em&gt;One of Us Is Lying&lt;/em&gt;. It’s too soon to tell whether these series have enough appeal to drive significant subscriber growth, but they lack the kind of splashy pre-premiere fanfare that other services often enjoy prior to the debut of big-budget title releases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WPyavT"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mnclZ_dKXUw?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="909aWl"&gt;Roberts said during the earnings call that the company remains “optimistic” about its future programming slate, which includes the 2022 Beijing Winter Olympics, Monday Night Football, originals, and pay-one streaming rights to Universal films after they debut in theaters beginning in 2022. But even those pay-one exclusives are split with Netflix and Amazon Prime Video. Peacock will get those films first, but they’ll eventually head to two much larger services with diverse content libraries and deeper production pockets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jvsKpD"&gt;Peacock has also grabbed back a lot of the NBC titles that performed exceptionally well on services like Netflix while they were still being licensed out. It also holds exclusive streaming rights to programming from the WWE Network. But no service is going to survive the streaming wars simply by leaning on pro-wrestling, &lt;em&gt;The Office&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Parks and Recreation&lt;/em&gt;. That’s particularly true if Peacock wants anyone to actually pay for its service, and surely it does. Much of its original content is locked away behind its paid tiers. Why invest in producing original shows for the service if nobody’s actually watching them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mOj4ts"&gt;The service’s reliance on Olympics streaming also seems like a strange long-play business strategy, as the Games only come around every two years. Plus, its Olympics coverage won’t even stick around on the service post-Games. Its dedicated Olympics hub will vanish from the service on August 11th, a spokesperson confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;(though originals like &lt;em&gt;Golden&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;For Ball and Country &lt;/em&gt;will stick around long-term).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="LzG1x7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It seems like an interesting strategy to attract viewers based around the Olympics.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2QMvpa"&gt;“It seems like an interesting strategy to attract viewers based around the Olympics. That’s not sustaining in and of itself, even if there was more coverage,” said David Arditi, an associate professor of sociology and anthropology at the University of Texas at Arlington. Arditi wrote the book &lt;em&gt;Streaming Culture: Subscription Platforms And The Unending Consumption Of Culture&lt;/em&gt;, which closely examines the streaming wars. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jt0bop"&gt;Broughton said Peacock is now faced with a decision about whether it wants to compete with the deep-pocketed, major players in streaming like Netflix, Amazon, HBO Max, Disney Plus, and Apple TV trying to grab subscriber dollars, or whether it wants to compete more like price-sensitive but ad-supported services like Hulu. That said, Broughton argued that Peacock’s hybrid model will allow it to experiment with what’s working and “test out a few different strategies without fully committing from day one.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hDWfZn"&gt;Peacock’s content skews more heavily toward old guard network programming rather than the innovative films and series being produced by the likes of Netflix, Disney, and Apple. There might be enough of an appetite for that content to keep the service afloat. But in a world where cultural moments like &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; win viewers, Peacock will need to figure out its strategy — and fast.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22617399/peacock-olympics-streaming-whats-next"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22617399/peacock-olympics-streaming-whats-next</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-09T17:24:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-09T17:24:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s new Titan security key lineup won’t make you choose between USB-C and NFC</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wakVbTySZKtodgjhXmW1NYXOyxk=/296x0:1304x672/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69701269/Copy_of_0204_0099__Titan_Main_KEY_v07_SIMP.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0yVPZn"&gt;Google &lt;a href="https://security.googleblog.com/2021/08/simplifying-titan-security-key-options.html"&gt;announced updates to its Titan security key lineup&lt;/a&gt; on Monday, simplifying it by removing a product and bringing NFC to all its keys. The company will now offer two options: one has a USB-A connector, one has USB-C, and both have NFC for connecting to “most mobile devices.” The USB-A key will cost $30, and the USB-C key will cost $35 when they go on sale on August 10th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mZDUdk"&gt;One of the biggest changes in Google’s new lineup is an updated USB-C key, which has added NFC support. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/14/20913456/google-titan-usb-c-security-key-yubico-yubikey-nfc-bluetooth-fido-os-compatibility"&gt;Google’s previous USB-C option&lt;/a&gt;, made in collaboration with Yubico, didn’t support the wireless standard. Now, the choice between USB-C and A is easy, as there aren’t features that one has that the other doesn’t. It’s simply a matter of what ports your computer has. Google did not immediately respond to a request for comment on whether Yubico was involved with the new key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="w0iCJW"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Security keys can act as second factors to protect you from phishing attempts&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bNLHy3"&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.google.com/titansecuritykey/answer/9115487"&gt;According to Google’s support document&lt;/a&gt;, its Titan security keys can be used to protect your Google account as well as with third-party apps and services that &lt;a href="https://fidoalliance.org"&gt;support FIDO standards&lt;/a&gt;, such as 1Password. They, and other security keys from companies like Yubico, can act as second factors to secure your account even if an attacker obtains your username and password. They also fight back against phishing since they won’t authenticate a login to a fake website that’s trying to steal your credentials. The Titan keys also work with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/17/16488572/google-advanced-protection-phishing-fraud-security-keys"&gt;Google’s Advanced Protection Program&lt;/a&gt;, which is designed to provide extra security to people whose accounts may be targeted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vh2U7H"&gt;Google’s current USB-A security key already includes NFC and sells for $25. The USB-A plus NFC key that Google lists &lt;a href="https://security.googleblog.com/2021/08/simplifying-titan-security-key-options.html"&gt;in its blog post&lt;/a&gt; will sell for $30, but it comes with a USB-C adapter. The USB-A key &lt;a href="https://store.google.com/us/product/titan_security_key?hl=en-US"&gt;currently listed on the store&lt;/a&gt; doesn’t include one, unless bought as part of a (sold-out) bundle, according to Google’s spec page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K5y48u"&gt;Google’s NFC / Bluetooth / USB key, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/30/17797338/google-titan-security-key-2fa-token-store-sale"&gt;which was made available to the public in 2018&lt;/a&gt;, will no longer be sold as part of the updated lineup. It’s already listed as sold out on &lt;a href="https://store.google.com/us/product/titan_security_key?hl=en-US"&gt;Google’s store page&lt;/a&gt;. Google’s blog post says that it’s discontinuing the Bluetooth model so it can focus on “easier and more widely available NFC capability.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Lr1riH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The updated USB-C plus NFC key will work with MacBooks and iPhones without a dongle&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eZyEys"&gt;While the updated Titan Security Key lineup seems to lack a Bluetooth option, it’s nice to see that the USB-C key is getting NFC. If you’re living the MacBook / iPhone lifestyle, you’ll be able to use the updated USB-C plus NFC key without any dongles. Google says in its blog post that the Bluetooth / NFC / USB key will still work over Bluetooth and NFC “on most modern mobile devices.” Google’s Titan Security Key store page currently lists the old models, but Google’s post says the updated lineup will be available starting on August 10th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22617183/google-usb-c-titan-security-lineup-nfc-password-protection"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22617183/google-usb-c-titan-security-lineup-nfc-password-protection</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-09T17:23:15-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-09T17:23:15-04:00</updated>
    <title>The next season of JoJo’s Bizarre Adventure is premiering on Netflix in December</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jTU0wKYd2mklEH5z_1mK4s_F75M=/183x0:1317x756/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69701268/Screen_Shot_2021_08_09_at_1.38.55_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="edWQNP"&gt;The next season of the hit anime &lt;em&gt;JoJo’s Bizarre Adventure &lt;/em&gt;will premiere exclusively on Netflix in December, the company announced on Monday. The premiere month announcement arrives alongside &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EeCX8Y0a278"&gt;a new trailer for the season&lt;/a&gt;, which is officially titled &lt;em&gt;JoJo’s Bizarre Adventure Stone Ocean.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8NK2hA"&gt;The season follows a woman named Jolyne Cujoh, who is sentenced to 15 years at a maximum security prison for a crime she claims she is innocent of. I won’t try to summarize everything else that happens in the wild-looking trailer — I’ve never seen the show or read the manga myself, so I just can’t do it justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KkFtNB"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stone Ocean&lt;/em&gt; is the latest in Netflix’s growing anime slate. &lt;em&gt;Sailor Moon&lt;/em&gt;’s latest movie &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22406600/netflix-pretty-guardian-sailor-moon-eternal-the-movie"&gt;hit the streaming service in June&lt;/a&gt;, and that same month, the company revealed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22527983/netflix-geeked-week-anime-trailers-mobile-suit-gundam-godzilla"&gt;a huge slate of anime series and films&lt;/a&gt; that are in the works. In March, the company said it was planning to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/27/22353848/netflix-launch-anime-ragnarok-zeus-resident-evil-streaming"&gt;launch 40 new anime titles in 2021&lt;/a&gt;. The additional titles will help Netflix stand out against competitors like anime streaming service Crunchyroll, which, as of Monday afternoon, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22617356/sony-crunchyroll-att-funimation-acquisition"&gt;is now officially owned by Sony&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22617292/netflix-jojos-bizarre-adventure-stone-ocean-december-trailer"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22617292/netflix-jojos-bizarre-adventure-stone-ocean-december-trailer</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-09T17:10:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-09T17:10:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sony completes acquisition of Crunchyroll from AT&amp;T</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Yy6ts9txU9z4BE6YBgoLOiaP1zU=/87x0:1038x634/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69701179/CROriginals_16x9.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ykNr6X"&gt;Sony officially owns AT&amp;amp;T’s Crunchyroll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i5lbai"&gt;Sony’s deal to acquire Crunchyroll was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22166585/sony-buy-anime-streaming-service-crunchyroll-at-t-funimation"&gt;first announced&lt;/a&gt; in December 2020 and sees Crunchyroll join Funimation, Sony’s existing anime streaming property, under one roof. The ultimate goal of the unification of the two anime properties under a single roof is to develop “a unified anime subscription experience as soon as possible,” said Tony Vinciquerra, Chairman and CEO of Sony Pictures Entertainment, in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IH9y5c"&gt;The deal is priced at $1.175 billion, and AT&amp;amp;T — which had been reported by &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/at-t-wants-1-5-billion-in-crunchyroll-sale-to-sony"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to be shopping the service around for $1.5 billion — will use the funds to help pay down the debt it amassed from its spending on streaming. In a radical shift away from its streaming strategy, AT&amp;amp;T has since decided to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/24/22451111/att-ceo-stankey-unleash-assets-warnermedia-discovery-hbo"&gt;release its media assets&lt;/a&gt; and focus on its core connectivity business. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R0hqlr"&gt;Meanwhile, Sony plans to use the Crunchyroll service to broaden its already substantial anime streaming footprint. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QM6bKD"&gt;“With the addition of Crunchyroll, we have an unprecedented opportunity to serve anime fans like never before and deliver the anime experience across any platform they choose, from theatrical, events, home entertainment, games, streaming, linear TV — everywhere and every way fans want to experience their anime,” Vinciquerra said.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22617356/sony-crunchyroll-att-funimation-acquisition"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22617356/sony-crunchyroll-att-funimation-acquisition</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-09T17:09:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-09T17:09:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple keeps shutting down employee-run surveys on pay equity — and labor lawyers say it’s illegal</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ePHQrieoO2mNGruhek063Lp3-RU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69701173/acastro_210809_4703_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The company bans surveys that include diversity data&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="auIHVh"&gt;Apple &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/diversity/"&gt;insists&lt;/a&gt; it does not have a problem with pay inequality. Skeptical Apple employees have been trying to verify that claim by sending out informal surveys on how much people make, particularly as it relates to women and underrepresented minorities. But the company has shut down three of those surveys, citing stringent rules on how employees can collect data. Now, multiple labor lawyers tell &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; the company may be violating worker protections: the surveys can be considered a form of labor organizing — &lt;a href="https://www.nlrb.gov/about-nlrb/rights-we-protect/the-law/employees/concerted-activity"&gt;under US law&lt;/a&gt;, employees have the right to discuss pay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W7CVA1"&gt;“Apple cannot bar its employees from discussing pay equity as it relates to protected classes,” says Vincent P. White, a labor lawyer with White, Hilferty &amp;amp; Albanese. “If they were, they could tell people not to talk about pronouns. The logical outgrowth of that doesn’t even track. I view their effort to shut this down as an act of retaliation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rsN1Lf"&gt;The first known survey began in the spring and asked people to volunteer salary information in addition to how they identify in terms of race, ethnicity, gender, and disability. After about 100 responses, Apple’s people team — the company’s name for what is commonly called human resources — asked employees to take the survey down, saying the demographic questions constituted personally identifying information, or PII.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cQiVKd"&gt;Last week, employees tried to start another pay equity survey but were again told to take it down because it included a question on gender. When they created a new survey without the gender question, the Apple people team allegedly said it had to be shut down because it was hosted on the company’s corporate Box account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="At1WUd"&gt;“This is like a 2021 version of a foreman on the docks telling people they can’t compare their wages way back in the 1800s,” says White. “This isn’t new. It’s just the newest version of ‘you can’t talk about your pay.’” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bIIAhw"&gt;The people team also sent employees the following information on “prohibited surveys”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="OXjvmq"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prohibited Surveys&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;The following employee surveys are prohibited in all cases and may not be conducted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Oa604m"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Surveys as Data Collection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JtT1LC"&gt;Surveys are not permitted to be used as a means of collecting identifiable employee data without following the usual process to obtain this data from the People team. This includes any questions about an employee’s address, demographics, and so on, except for collecting country or region, which is permitted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RQfYC6"&gt;Using surveys as a tool to collect health information — including but not limited to health reports, testing results, and vaccination status — is also prohibited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wQWnQK"&gt;All requests for identifiable employee data must be submitted to the People team via the People Report Request Form. If approved, the People team will provide the employee data directly from their systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GcK28s"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Surveys Requesting Diversity Data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;Diversity data is highly sensitive personal data. If you have a need for such information, you must work with your I&amp;amp;D Business Partner and the I&amp;amp;D Insights and Solutions team before collecting any data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="jwlBUn"&gt;“Those rules may themselves violate the protected right to concerted activity — while [Apple] might point to these handbook type rules that you’ve agreed to not do this as a condition of employment, that doesn’t mean they can legally prevent employees from doing what they’re doing,” says Veena Dubal, a law professor at UC Hastings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mhGsbO"&gt;Now, Apple engineer Cher Scarlett has started a new survey on Typeform, which she is paying for out of pocket. “I was looking at levels.fyi (a website that lets people compare salary data across companies) and noticed a few very low salaries in a certain geographic area that were 10 to 15 percent lower compared to other people on the team,” Scarlett says. “Every time I looked at gender, they were women. I’m not going to say that’s a definitive issue, but it’s a prompt for anyone to ask if this is a widespread problem. We should be able to easily find out whether or not that’s the case so we can know whether people are truly being paid fairly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Y2ANx0"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Two pay transparency surveys have been shut down in the past 6 months at Apple. I won't be intimidated. We have the right to collect this data amongst ourselves.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;There's a new survey, voluntary and totally anonymous. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The password is my status in Slack.&lt;a href="https://t.co/fUr1DZ5Df1"&gt;https://t.co/fUr1DZ5Df1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Cher Scarlett (@cherthedev) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cherthedev/status/1423918155185811460?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9N3Xhw"&gt;The new survey, which has nearly 500 entries, asks employees to volunteer information on their salary, level, team, latest RSU grant, tenure at Apple, geographic location, signing bonus, relevant work experience, as well as whether they’re permanently remote, and a member of an underrepresented race or gender. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o4b7VL"&gt;“We want our colleagues and industry peers to have the knowledge of Apple’s pay bands and to give minoritized employees and prospective employees the confidence to negotiate fair wages and bonuses,” the survey reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GbIp9s"&gt;Grace Reckers, an organizer with the Office and Professional Employees International Union, says the fact that this information is all voluntary should protect employees. “This is protected activity — because you’re opting into the survey, I don’t even know how the PII excuse would work or matter.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YMUxCt"&gt;Scarlett says Apple’s response to the surveys has only made employees more suspicious: “I don’t think anyone is going into this saying there for sure is a wage gap, whether that’s gender or race or disability. But it is concerning to everyone that every single time someone tries to create more transparency, Apple shuts it down. It makes it feel like maybe there is a problem, and they’re already aware of it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nlg7KS"&gt;In 2018, Apple’s mean and median gender pay gap for employees in the UK was &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/legal/more-resources/docs/uk-gender-pay-gap-report-2019.pdf"&gt;12 percent in favor of men&lt;/a&gt;. That’s 5 percentage points below the overall gender pay gap in the UK. The company has to publish this data under UK law, but it does not have the same requirements in the US. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y32n17"&gt;Two years earlier, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/02/27/technology/apple-shareholders-show-their-support-for-tim-cook.html"&gt;Apple CEO Tim Cook told investors&lt;/a&gt; that women at Apple made 99.6 cents for every dollar men made, while underrepresented minorities made 99.7 cents for every dollar white employees made. That same year, the company released a diversity report &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/8/3/12371204/apple-diversity-report-pay-gap-hiring-equal-pay"&gt;saying it had fixed the problem&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="tUEk5i"&gt;Apple did not respond to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22609687/apple-pay-equity-employee-surveys-protected-activity"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22609687/apple-pay-equity-employee-surveys-protected-activity</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-09T17:04:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-09T17:04:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>SpaceX to acquire small satellite startup Swarm Technologies</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="SpaceX Launches Transporter-1 Mission" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cl6y9QBP4rqKquzpjGhTyEgOKic=/0x0:4200x2800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69701138/1230770213.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;36 SpaceBee smallsats launch to space aboard SpaceX’s Falcon 9 rocket in January 2021, during SpaceX’s Transporter-1 mission with 107 other satellites on board. | Photo by Paul Hennessy/NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FOIrXr"&gt;Elon Musk’s SpaceX is acquiring the small-satellite data provider Swarm Technologies, scooping up the startup’s roughly 30 employees and its network of 120 tiny satellites. The deal, struck last month, is extremely rare for SpaceX, which normally manufactures its rocket and satellite hardware in-house or hires subcontractors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XnPdp7"&gt;Swarm revealed the acquisition plans in an August 6th filing with the Federal Communications Commission that requested approval to shift ownership of its satellite and antenna licenses to SpaceX. The merger agreement, in which Swarm will become a direct and wholly owned subsidiary of SpaceX, was inked on July 16th, the filing said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Ef8Jxp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;SpaceX benefits from “access to the intellectual property and expertise developed by the Swarm team”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3h5r95"&gt;The acquisition of Swarm marks a rare business maneuver for SpaceX as it deepens its foray into the world of consumer electronics and claws its way out of a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274385/musk-spacex-starlink-deposit-price-satellite-internet"&gt;chasm of unprofitability&lt;/a&gt; with Starlink, with the hopes of eventually turning the network into a cash cow to fund Musk’s massive Starship launch system. It’s unclear, though, what specific opportunity SpaceX sees in Swarm to benefit its broadband network. A spokesperson for Swarm declined to comment on the deal, and SpaceX didn’t reply to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YHb7WE"&gt;The acquisition will strengthen “the combined companies’ ability to provide innovative satellite services that reach unserved and underserved parts of the world,” Swarm wrote in the FCC filing. “SpaceX will similarly benefit from access to the intellectual property and expertise developed by the Swarm team, as well as from adding this resourceful and effective team to SpaceX.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9HeQO9m4VkAMe-OOrzsAAebB1o4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22772207/Mask_Group_1_1024x759.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Swarm Technologies&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;One of Swarm’s SpaceBee satellites.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="8E4gOP"&gt;Founded in 2016, Swarm offers ultra low-bandwidth data services using its tiny sandwich-sized SpaceBEE satellites that talk to smaller consumer antennas on the ground called “Tiles.” Of the 150 planned, 120 satellites are already in orbit, and the tiles can be installed as cracker-sized chips inside, for example, the circuit board of a device. With GPS built in, devices with a tile installed can be tracked, relay sensor data, or do whatever the customer programs it to do using tiny pings of bandwidth to Swarm’s global satellite network starting at $5 a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XXgJCz"&gt;SpaceX’s much different Starlink program aims to beam broadband internet into rural areas that lack fiber or physical internet connections. The company already has more than 1,700 of its initial tranche of 4,409 satellites in low-Earth orbit with nearly 100,000 beta users, most of whom paid $499 for a terminal kit and $99 a month for internet. The network is far ahead of competition from UK-backed OneWeb, which has launched 254 satellites so far for its similar — but smaller-sized — broadband network, and Amazon’s budding Kuiper network, which has yet to deploy any satellites. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="enVFGr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22616894/spacex-elon-musk-starlink-swarm-technologies"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22616894/spacex-elon-musk-starlink-swarm-technologies</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-09T16:21:13-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-09T16:21:13-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix is working on a bunch of new reality shows, and you’re invited </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7JGKQJ0aXd6TwrhRT-_aziWCqcA=/84x0:1029x630/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69700942/Screen_Shot_2020_04_23_at_10.52.46_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="svXsky"&gt;Netflix is tripling down on its reality TV programming by renewing its most popular shows and opening up casting for future programming to anyone over the age of 18 in the US, Canada, United Kingdom, or Ireland, &lt;a href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/announcing-largest-reality-casting-call-ever-plus-new-and-returning-series"&gt;the company announced Monday&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UrxnWe"&gt;Anyone interested who meets that criteria can submit a one-minute video on Netflix’s new &lt;a href="https://www.netflixreality.com/"&gt;dedicated reality TV site&lt;/a&gt;. The application can be used for multiple shows on Netflix’s current slate, from baking competitions like &lt;em&gt;Nailed It!&lt;/em&gt; to saucier romantic options like &lt;em&gt;Love is Blind. &lt;/em&gt;(Netflix also offers the option to apply to all of its shows at once if you prefer a more “spaghetti meets wall” approach.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7CWJb2QT5vv-1WI-F4rVo_49nS8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22772117/screencapture_netflixreality_submit_your_video_2021_08_09_15_52_01.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Netflix will let you apply for shows across a broad spectrum of topics at once.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8hQ48A"&gt;Netflix is also renewing several of its most well-known shows, all the better to fill with the new collection of randos it finds online. Arranged marriage docuseries &lt;em&gt;Indian Matchmaking&lt;/em&gt; and food competition &lt;em&gt;The American Barbecue Showdown&lt;/em&gt; are both getting renewed for second seasons, while &lt;em&gt;The Circle &lt;/em&gt;has been renewed for two more seasons of competitive catfishing. In terms of new reality TV, Netflix is casting for a new series it calls &lt;em&gt;Roaring Twenties&lt;/em&gt; focused on, you guessed it, twenty-year-olds living together. The official, only marginally more informative description follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="q3EWz4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roaring Twenties&lt;/em&gt; is the coming-of-age story of eight twenty-somethings who set out to find success in life and love in Austin, Texas while learning to navigate the ‘new normal’ of 2020’s America. Living together and leaning on each other, they experience the highs and lows that come with being an adult. After all, your twenties are a crazy, weird, and special time in your life, and you only get to live them once.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="HHadJ6"&gt;Leaning in even harder into reality TV seems to make a lot of sense for Netflix. In comparison to a big buzzy, expensive property like &lt;em&gt;The Witcher — &lt;/em&gt;which &lt;a href="https://screenrant.com/witcher-tv-netflix-budget-cost-game-thrones-comparison/"&gt;reportedly cost around $10 million per episode&lt;/a&gt; — reality TV is cheaper to produce but can still stand out from the more basic fare found on network TV due to Netflix’s ad-free experience. The weirdness and specificity of Netflix’s premises is also a strength, &lt;a href="https://www.vulture.com/2020/02/netflix-reality-tv-strategy.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vulture&lt;/em&gt; writes&lt;/a&gt;. It creates some natural buzz (how could something &lt;a href="https://www.vulture.com/2021/06/netflix-sexy-beasts-dating-show-trailer-watch.html"&gt;as odd as &lt;em&gt;Sexy Beasts &lt;/em&gt;not?&lt;/a&gt;) and offers a little something for everyone. With an even broader net for casting, now Netflix can potentially use a little bit of everyone, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="WKO5F3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Netflix makes reality shows exclusively for the extremely online ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/23/21232684/netflix-reality-tv-too-hot-to-handle-love-is-blind-the-circle"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22617087/netflix-reality-tv-casting-call-the-circle-renewed"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22617087/netflix-reality-tv-casting-call-the-circle-renewed</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-09T15:35:37-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-09T15:35:37-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon and GoPro are suing Chinese sellers over counterfeit tripods and grips</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-YJi_2Paescbk6DM6fL4GnsWpMw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69700716/bfarsace_200914_4190_0005.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The camera is not a counterfeit.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hCZoQK"&gt;Last June, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/24/21302114/amazon-counterfeit-crimes-unit-knockoffs-store-online-investigators"&gt;Amazon created a Counterfeit Crimes Unit&lt;/a&gt; to fight the knockoffs plaguing its gigantic storefront, and today, it’s &lt;a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210809005578/en/Amazon-and-GoPro-File-Joint-Lawsuit-against-Counterfeiters"&gt;announcing its first action&lt;/a&gt; against purveyors of fake gadgets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0C5MNi"&gt;Amazon and GoPro have sued seven Chinese nationals and a pair of businesses for distributing hard-to-detect knockoffs of its “Handler” floating camera hand grip and “3-Way” tripod grip, ones that blatantly use GoPro’s own logo, in an April 2021 lawsuit that’s just now being unsealed — because there’s a parallel criminal investigation in China against these same sellers, the complaint reveals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kHKUzw"&gt;While the lawsuit doesn’t say how many people actually bought these counterfeit GoPro accessories, it suggests at least some buyers were fooled by the fake products. One wrote they were “very disappointed it was provided by GOPRO. I will not purchase any more products of this brand from now on.” Others were more skeptical: “[It] can’t be a real GoPro stick because it rusted after two days,” wrote another customer, according to the complaint. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Tripod comparison picture shows a smaller button on the fake, and different patterns of dots." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TvRiqD7w8LsxGzHAcH1c_3IayD8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22771922/amazon_gopro_counterfeit_tripods.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Amazon lawsuit&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Many different GoPro fake handles, showing their logos and darker colored foam compare to a legit one" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rvpwnr6MeLGNEli8vgHK_wz8NrQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22771921/amazon_gopro_counterfeit_handles.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Amazon lawsuit&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="This image shows a handle with a clear GoPro logo on it." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ve3qSagbbnxLCeJE7B6GeK2vq2U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22771920/amazon_gopro_counterfeit_handle.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Amazon lawsuit&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LqtClX"&gt;The differences appear to be fairly subtle: counterfeit tripods, for example, might weigh a little bit less, have a rougher surface, a smaller button, and a different number of “dots” in different places on the arm. The foam might be a slightly darker color, too. It’s not clear why Chinese companies would see the need to counterfeit these products, given that GoPro’s camera mount is an exceptionally easy thing to find third-party attachments for, but perhaps they thought an official logo would help them stand out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="stUTxc"&gt;Amazon says it blocked the entire Amazon seller accounts of these defendants after counterfeits were brought to the company’s attention and that it sent samples of their products to GoPro to help the investigation. Referring these cases to law enforcement is part of the standard procedure, Amazon Counterfeit Crimes Unit head Kebharu Smith &lt;a href="https://www.theglobalipcenter.com/fighting-fakes-5-questions-for-amazons-counterfeit-crimes-unit/"&gt;said earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZyojQH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Amazon’s CCU is composed of former federal prosecutors and investigators&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qnyij0"&gt;While it is the first gadget suit from Amazon’s Counterfeit Crimes Unit, it’s not the first suit it’s filed. We covered a previous suit &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21562758/instagram-influencer-counterfeit-gucci-dior-amazon-fake-listing"&gt;against sellers of fake luxury goods&lt;/a&gt;, and the company says it’s filed joint lawsuits like this GoPro one with other companies, including “apparel manufacturer HanesBrands, Italian luxury brands Valentino and Ferragamo, cosmetics brand KF Beauty, family travel accessory brand JL Childress, cooler manufacturer YETI, family-owned-and-operated card game company Dutch Blitz, and global board game publisher Asmodee.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BPSdgD"&gt;Amazon has a long-running problem with counterfeit goods, and other companies have sued before: Apple claimed in 2016 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/10/20/13343682/fake-apple-chargers-amazon-lawsuit"&gt;that 90 percent of Apple chargers sold on Amazon were fake&lt;/a&gt;, and reporters were able to find quite a few counterfeits &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/30/17301714/amazon-counterfeit-goods-crackdown"&gt;even after Amazon’s subsequent crackdown&lt;/a&gt;. We wrote in 2019 about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/29/20837359/amazon-basics-fake-sellers-imposters-third-party-marketplace"&gt;how Amazon’s own AmazonBasics products were getting knocked off&lt;/a&gt;. I remember purchasing a counterfeit SanDisk SD card from Amazon a while back myself. “Welcome to the era of fake products,” &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/blog/amazon-counterfeit-fake-products/"&gt;wrote &lt;em&gt;Wirecutter &lt;/em&gt;last February&lt;/a&gt;, providing a variety of Amazon examples. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="NCiDto"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Amazon just got Fakespot booted off Apple’s iOS App Store","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580611/fakespot-ios-app-apple-amazon-fake-reviews"},{"title":"Another Amazon-first gadget brand has suspiciously vanished: Choetech","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22567530/amazon-choetech-removed-pulled-aukey-mpow"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="JgKnCF"&gt;Amazon suggests that, thanks to its efforts, the problem might not be as big as suspected: &lt;a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/company-news/amazon-brand-protection-report"&gt;it released a Brand Protection Report this May&lt;/a&gt; that states the company seized and destroyed more than 2 million counterfeits before they were sent to customers, that it blocked 10 billion “suspected bad listings” before they appeared on the store, and that “fewer than 0.01% of all products sold on Amazon received a counterfeit complaint from customers.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2z0BNo"&gt;Amazon doesn’t publicly say how many products it has on its storefront, though, so it’s impossible to tell how large “0.01%” might be, and thus how many goods might have actually made it through. It’s also not clear how many customers would know they’d been sold fake goods, and think to complain, in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kbdJQ6"&gt;GoPro declined to comment for this story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="sAMe34"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/21038850-amazon-and-gopro-sue-counterfeiters/?embed=1&amp;amp;responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="Amazon and GoPro sue counterfeiters (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="905" style="border: 1px solid #aaa; width: 100%; height: 800px; height: calc(100vh - 100px);" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22617120/amazon-gopro-fakes-counterfeit-lawsuit-china-criminal-investigation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22617120/amazon-gopro-fakes-counterfeit-lawsuit-china-criminal-investigation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-09T15:14:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-09T15:14:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>Dish says its will launch wireless 5G service in beta at the end of September</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jj7W-ZCC1g6M24nmInn6CPhDh84=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69700580/acastro_200804_1777_dish_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dish aims to cover 70% of the US population by mid-2023 with wireless service.&lt;/em&gt; | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ct2cfr"&gt;On an earnings call today, Dish Network execs said that its Las Vegas 5G wireless service is in the final phase of construction and will launch in beta by the end of September. That keeps it just in line with the Q3 deployment goal it gave earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EZpGzT"&gt;The beta launch is an important first step toward its commitment to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/26/8931827/dish-carrier-plans-5g-network-tmobile-sprint-us-confirms"&gt;covering 70 percent of the US population by June 2023&lt;/a&gt;, a target that’s looking more ambitious by the day as the company continues to lose wireless customers. It lost 161,000 subscribers in Q1 of this year, and it just &lt;a href="https://ir.dish.com/news-releases/news-release-details/dish-network-reports-second-quarter-2021-financial-results"&gt;reported a net loss of 201,000 wireless subscribers&lt;/a&gt; in Q2. The company stands to lose even more of its remaining 8.9 million wireless subscribers as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22598163/t-mobile-metro-5g-prepaid-boost-cricket-switch-promotion"&gt;T-Mobile has unveiled a generous promotion&lt;/a&gt; aimed at the very customers it was required to sell to Dish as part of the Sprint merger deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TuuRe8"&gt;Dish says the Vegas beta will last a minimum of 90 days, during which it plans to gather customer feedback and troubleshoot issues as its technology transitions from the lab to the real world — chairman Charlie Ergen acknowledges that the network won’t work perfectly at first. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DuO44z"&gt;Dish also recently signed an agreement with AT&amp;amp;T, on which it will rely for the majority of its service as a wireless service reseller (MVNO) while it goes about building its own network. On today’s call, Dish clarified the role that its new partner will play in the beta launch. It says that the majority of network use in its Las Vegas launch will be on its own network, with AT&amp;amp;T and existing partner T-Mobile’s networks providing some roaming support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x1POU7"&gt;Curious to try it out yourself? Anyone interested in testing out the network as part of the beta program can sign up for more information through &lt;a href="https://launch.5gmobilegenesis.com/"&gt;Dish’s Project Genesis website&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e9fq9v"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22617029/dish-network-5g-las-vegas-wireless-service-beta"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22617029/dish-network-5g-las-vegas-wireless-service-beta</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
