<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-18T12:54:32-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-18T12:54:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-18T12:54:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook shows off how you’ll use its neural wristbands with AR glasses</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cY7CP3xWEXZ96hHAhTQ1XbO4Xdk=/0x0:600x400/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68988251/Visual_3.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Kty54B"&gt;Facebook has offered a glimpse inside its plans for a new augmented reality interface, based on technology from CTRL-Labs, the startup it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/23/20881032/facebook-ctrl-labs-acquisition-neural-interface-armband-ar-vr-deal"&gt;acquired in 2019&lt;/a&gt;. In a video, it shows off wristbands that use electromyography (EMG) to translate subtle neural signals into actions — like typing, swiping, or playing games like an archery simulator. The bands also offer haptic feedback, creating a system that’s more responsive than basic hand tracking options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3xQ2RD"&gt;Facebook Reality Labs &lt;a href="https://tech.fb.com/inside-facebook-reality-labs-wrist-based-interaction-for-the-next-computing-platform/"&gt;published a blog post&lt;/a&gt; detailing its work on a prototype of the wristbands. At its simplest, the bands would track basic gestures Facebook calls “clicks,” which are supposed to be reliable and easy to execute. They’re a little bit like the all-purpose Microsoft HoloLens &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dynamics365/mixed-reality/guides/operator-gestures-hl2"&gt;“air tap” gesture&lt;/a&gt; but tracked with the nerve signals that run along your arms, rather than visual sensors mounted on a headset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6H6q0B"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?height=314&amp;amp;href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FTechAtFacebook%2Fvideos%2F1146186389155473%2F&amp;amp;show_text=false&amp;amp;width=560" width="560" height="314" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QfXcOx"&gt;The bands can theoretically do a lot more, though. For instance, they could track the nerve signals your brain sends to your fingers while you’re typing, so you can type on a virtual keyboard without physical buttons. And unlike a normal keyboard, the bands can slowly adapt to the way you type — so they can “learn” the ways your fingers move when you’re making common typos, then automatically correct for them and capture what you probably meant to type instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QQ9lnV"&gt;This would be a huge change in how most people interact with computers, but conceptually, it’s not actually a major update to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/6/17433516/ctrl-labs-brain-computer-interface-armband-hands-on-preview"&gt;how CTRL-Labs described its work&lt;/a&gt; years ago. In fact, the ultimate possibilities for EMG wristbands are much more mind-bending: eventually, you could perform the same typing-style gestures by &lt;em&gt;thinking&lt;/em&gt; about moving your hands instead of actually moving them. Facebook wants to further streamline user interactions by relying on artificial intelligence and augmented reality glasses, which it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/16/21439929/facebook-ar-smart-glasses-ray-ban-announcement"&gt;announced it was working on&lt;/a&gt; last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="sQYUuv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Facebook is experimenting with different haptic feedback prototypes&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OCGMAl"&gt;Even in their simpler iterations, these controllers would offer an interface that you could wear all the time instead of picking up and holding, like the current Oculus Touch VR controllers. The effect could be similar to smaller &lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/mudra-band-ces-2021-041411145.html?guccounter=1&amp;amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAFEITOdCbzc3jOTbXSWqhIMoqC7ca6oAByvZ71mKIv-jgLGrK4DU4r4WtKhLG3K4hfoUONSaOUVNfQfLmJaiYnBMeS4j_Nxq2bosa3R6dnv8owHvckb8_0Rh3CRVN2-Aq6avcMJFFpMLcGkFz-K-mfT-FWIzN6jQmi7Ex606wCJv"&gt;startup offerings like the Mudra Band&lt;/a&gt;, which senses gestures via an Apple Watch band.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t3uNd9"&gt;One major new addition is haptics. Facebook says it’s been implementing various prototypes that could give you subtle feedback using different methods. One, the “Bellowband,” has eight pneumatic bellows placed around each wrist. These can be inflated or deflated in patterns that produce distinct sensations. Another is “Tasbi,” which uses vibrating actuators and a “novel wrist squeeze mechanism.” When they’re paired with visual feedback from an AR headset, they can offer a lot of information through a simple and intuitive interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8rASJ4"&gt;Facebook insists that although the band reads neural signals, “this is not akin to mind reading.” Here’s how it explains the concept:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="kGZv28"&gt;You have many thoughts and you choose to act on only some of them. When that happens, your brain sends signals to your hands and fingers telling them to move in specific ways in order to perform actions like typing and swiping. This is about decoding those signals at the wrist — the actions you’ve already decided to perform — and translating them into digital commands for your device.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="q1ydhz"&gt;CTRL-Labs has still characterized this technology as a brain-computer interface, but it’s a sharp contrast with technologies like Elon Musk’s Neuralink — which reads neural activity directly from the brain through an implant. Implants have unique uses, particularly for people with paralysis or amputated limbs, whose bodies simply can’t send nervous signals to a wristband. But Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319737/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-vr-ar-face-sensors"&gt;recently criticized implants&lt;/a&gt; as a near-term consumer technology, saying that “we don’t think that people are going to want to get their head drilled open in order to use virtual or augmented reality.” Wristbands also don’t have quite the same privacy scare factor as something that reads your thoughts at the source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gHZg4b"&gt;That said, the bands will almost certainly be collecting a lot of data. That might include incredibly fine variations in typing patterns; overall levels of bodily tension; and any biometric information captured by fitness tracking sensors, augmented reality glasses, and other tech that could be integrated with the bands. (Facebook Reality Labs notes that it has a “neuroethics program” examining the privacy, security, and safety implications of AR and neural interface tech.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Aa9oYG"&gt;Like most wearable technology, EMG bands offer an intimate look at how our bodies are moving — and while it’s not quite as creepy-sounding as a band that reads your thoughts, it still requires a lot of trust.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22338008/facebook-reality-labs-emg-wristbands-ctrl-labs-ar-interface-demo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22338008/facebook-reality-labs-emg-wristbands-ctrl-labs-ar-interface-demo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-18T12:16:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-18T12:16:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Biden’s COVID-19 vaccine website builds on a swine flu tool </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mJdcZoYZdIyZrG1HVECidsYZDjo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68987956/acastro_210309_1777_vaccine_0001.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eQrWJn"&gt;The federal COVID-19 vaccine-finding website President Joe Biden &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22326335/biden-white-house-covid-19-vaccine-federal-website"&gt;promised last week&lt;/a&gt; will be an expansion of &lt;a href="https://vaccinefinder.org/"&gt;VaccineFinder&lt;/a&gt;, a website first created during the 2009 swine flu outbreaks to help people locate vaccine providers. On or before May 1st, the website should include information on every COVID-19 vaccine administration site in the country. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3V24uC"&gt;“It’s going to be an improved, federal version of VaccineFinder,” says John Brownstein, chief innovation officer at Boston Children’s Hospital and founder of VaccineFinder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rar73q"&gt;Over the past decade, VaccineFinder compiled information from around the country, showing people where they could find flu shots and other routine vaccines. It runs out of Boston Children’s Hospital in partnership with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BzvZzC"&gt;It has been a part of the CDC’s COVID-19 vaccination plans since last fall. The back-end system is how the agency tracks the number of doses available at every pharmacy, clinic, hospital, or pop-up site administering vaccines. “Every COVID vaccine provider has had to register with us,” Brownstein says. Sites are asked to report the doses on hand every day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JUCJg9"&gt;“The platform itself is collecting data on daily inventory, all the different providers, and then feeding that information back to CDC,” he says. “This is one node in that whole flow of information.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-QVp56EmZ5SUBGPeewWSN_mEXZQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22380055/Screen_Shot_2021_03_18_at_11.18.35_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A screenshot of VaccineFinder showing vaccine availability at pharmacies in Brooklyn, New York.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="D0s7EM"&gt;At the end of February, it &lt;a href="https://www.statnews.com/2021/02/24/cdc-vaccinefinder-covid19-locations/"&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt; a public-facing map showing vaccine stock at just under 30,000 providers across the country. It covers every pharmacy in the country giving vaccinations as part of the federal retail pharmacy program and additional locations in a handful of states, including Alaska, Indiana, Iowa, and Tennessee. Features directing people to non-COVID-19 vaccines are now offline. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j89Qum"&gt;Information from VaccineFinder is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334609/apple-maps-facebook-google-covid-19-vaccine-locations"&gt;also now integrated&lt;/a&gt; into Apple Maps and Facebook’s COVID Information Center. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zqoo6m"&gt;Over the next few weeks, more providers in more states will flip their vaccine supply information over to the public side of VaccineFinder. “That’s a state decision, of when they want to go public. You want to make sure the timing is right,” Brownstein says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TwGs7a"&gt;The team is also working to integrate appointment availability, not just vaccine supply, into the tool. Right now, visitors to the site will see if a location has vaccines in stock and which type of vaccine it has. That doesn’t necessarily mean a site has available appointments for those in-stock doses — people have to click out to the location’s own website to check that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g2Hbkg"&gt;It’s not clear yet if and how people will be able to make appointments directly&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;on the site, instead of having to click out to a site’s own scheduler. “We’re still working through exactly what that would look like,” Brownstein says. “Even right now, the feedback we’re getting has been overwhelmingly positive because it gives people a navigation tool, and a jumping-off point to book an appointment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6G2A3z"&gt;The team is also working to improve the site’s accessibility, Brownstein says. They recently partnered with Univision to make it available in Spanish. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YkTCzp"&gt;The absence of centralized resources to help people track&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;COVID-19 vaccine availability has been a clear gap through the first few months of the US vaccination campaign. In most states, people eligible for vaccination have to bounce around between multiple registration websites for various sites to find open slots. Volunteers built makeshift aggregators in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/31/22256167/covid-vaccine-website-nyc-appointment"&gt;places like New York City&lt;/a&gt; to fill the gap. It has been great to see that innovation, and those tools have been useful solutions, Brownstein says. One benefit to VaccineFinder, he says, is that it has direct access to supply data from vaccination sites. “But we’re happy that there’s an ecosystem.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jcdtTX"&gt;Over the past year, state and federal governments have announced multiple tech solutions to various pandemic-related challenges. Many didn’t live up to the promises. In March 2020, former President Donald Trump announced plans for a nationwide testing website &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/27/21197026/trump-coronavirus-testing-website-plan-google-covid-19"&gt;that didn’t exist&lt;/a&gt;. The website never materialized. A data system to help the states schedule and administer vaccine appointments was abandoned by many after it proved to be &lt;a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2021/01/30/1017086/cdc-44-million-vaccine-data-vams-problems/"&gt;unreliable and buggy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Or87Mz"&gt;When launching a new tool, there’s always the worry that something might go wrong, Brownstein says. But because VaccineFinder has existed for years and is scaling gradually; he’s confident that it’ll work out. “We’ve already been rolling out this tool, it’s growing its user base, and the feedback has been positive — so we’re optimistic.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EQfJep"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22337754/covid-vaccine-availability-website-vaccinefinder-biden"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22337754/covid-vaccine-availability-website-vaccinefinder-biden</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-18T12:13:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-18T12:13:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>Walmart will have PS5 and Xbox Series X restocks available today</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y43Cj26fUgCDXrnNwVBv36Pr3xQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68987932/vpavic_4261_20201023_0068.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Due2Rh"&gt;If you want another shot at trying to buy either an Xbox Series X or a PlayStation 5, you’re in luck. A Walmart spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the retailer will be restocking the consoles online today, March 18th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hp1rKY"&gt;Walmart plans to have inventory for the &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPlayStation-5-Console%2F363472942&amp;amp;subid1=vergenextgenrestocks02252021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;PS5&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-PlayStation-5-Digital-Edition%2F493824815&amp;amp;subid1=vergenextgenrestocks02252021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;PS5 Digital Edition&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FXbox-Series-X%2F443574645&amp;amp;subid1=vergenextgenrestocks02252021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xbox Series X&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FXbox-Series-S%2F606518560&amp;amp;subid1=vergenextgenrestocks02252021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xbox Series S&lt;/a&gt; gaming consoles, with prices ranging from $300 to $500 depending on the model you purchase. The retailer told me that restocks for Xbox Series X / S will begin at 2:30PM ET, while PS5s will be up for purchase beginning at 3PM ET. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vgmvmR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10226823"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nHGLDC"&gt;For those looking to buy a next-gen Xbox console, you may want to consider picking up some other accessories to get the most out of your console. An &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08DF248LD?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;additional controller&lt;/a&gt; is likely a good purchase. And unlike the PS5, you can purchase a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08K3S6WJM?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;1TB SSD expansion&lt;/a&gt; to add to the Xbox’s base storage (512GB on the Series S, 1TB on the X), though it is not cheap. If you are having trouble deciding on what games to buy, you can always buy a subscription to &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Xbox-Game-Pass-Ultimate-Membership/dp/B07TGNFVWV?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xbox Game Pass Ultimate&lt;/a&gt;, which gives you access to a slew of digital games and access to Xbox Live Gold. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="7jDvaI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10226833"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6H8DPb"&gt;If you plan to buy a PS5 console, there are a few additional items you should pick up to get the most out of your new console. I recommend picking up a second &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/DualSense-Wireless-Controller-PlayStation-5/dp/B08FC6C75Y?ots=1&amp;amp;slotNum=5&amp;amp;imprToken=6ebc230d-4687-1a1b-5f1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;ascsubtag=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22059750%5Bt%5Dw%5Br%5Dgoogle.com%5Bd%5DD" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;DualSense controller&lt;/a&gt;, which is necessary for any in-person multiplayer action. I suggest that early adopters also subscribe to &lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=20387&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22059750%5Bt%5Dw%5Br%5Dgoogle.com%5Bd%5DD&amp;amp;ued=https://www.eneba.com/us/psn-playstation-network-card-psn-365-days-usa-psn-key-united-states" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;PlayStation Plus&lt;/a&gt;, which gives you a few perks, such as free games every month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="622RJ4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"PlayStation 5 review: a big, confident step into next gen","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21550146/sony-playstation-5-ps5-review"},{"title":"Xbox Series X review: a next-gen PC","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21548987/xbox-series-x-review"},{"title":"Xbox Series S review: small console, big potential","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21549021/xbox-series-s-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id="vh9R8u"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22338157/playstation-5-xbox-series-x-s-restocks-walmart-time-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22338157/playstation-5-xbox-series-x-s-restocks-walmart-time-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-18T12:07:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-18T12:07:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>5 widescreen videos to watch instead of the 4:3 Snyder Cut of Justice League</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZsGt7QkRczjDMHh9F1VvD6DhMVA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68987901/bananatv_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Sean O’Kane / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TbJ2CM"&gt;Zack Snyder’s cut of &lt;em&gt;Justice League&lt;/em&gt; is finally available to stream on HBO Max, and while the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22334362/zack-snyder-justice-league-fandom-release-cut-star-wars-twitter"&gt;rabid fans who helped make it happen&lt;/a&gt; may have been prepared for its 4:3 format, many people were &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22337756/snyder-cut-aspect-ratio-justice-league-hbo-max-warning"&gt;a little stunned when they pressed play today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9GnF0V"&gt;Listen, I was a fan &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/12/28/7457291/the-wire-hd-screenshot-comparisons"&gt;of &lt;em&gt;The Wire&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I get it. Artistic vision and all that. But a 4:3 aspect ratio simply clashes with most modern devices. So I’ve rounded up five videos that take full advantage of most widescreen-optimized phones, tablets, and TVs. Use them as a palate cleanser when you finish the Snyder Cut or as a visual release valve when you inevitably pause the four-hour-long version of &lt;em&gt;Justice League&lt;/em&gt;. The world is your banana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="vB6F2j"&gt;1. This video of the Banana orbiting the Earth at the same distance as the International Space Station&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div id="KKsB3c"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/paMantiqs54?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NzSqQA"&gt;This video is a few years old, but like all good internet detritus, it was picked up by the undertow of the World Wide Web and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/page_eco/status/1372175858174062594"&gt;resurfaced this week&lt;/a&gt;. It visualizes a simple premise: what if the Banana was the same distance as the ISS? As Obi-Wan Kenobi famously said, “That’s no moon.” Sure isn’t, Obi-wan. And we know that because we can see the Banana in beautiful high-definition widescreen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="zMj86k"&gt;2. This documentary about the frailty of the environment&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div id="9w4TFP"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/paMantiqs54?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HMmm80"&gt;The Anthropocene has done terrible things to the environment, certainly, but we’d &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; be in for it if a Banana the size of North America was orbiting a mere 250 miles above the Earth. This doc expertly uses the widescreen format to help viewers imagine the abject terror they might experience as they look up in awe at the Banana while tsunami sirens blare in the distance. It also really shines on OLEDs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="Rfv853"&gt;3. This art-house film about a child losing his banana&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div id="YEzCSl"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/paMantiqs54?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="F14PFX"&gt;They say loss is nothing but change, and that change is nature’s delight. I say don’t diminish someone’s personal grief, regardless of age. Be sure to watch this one on a backlit screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="2GN7mX"&gt;4. This 90-second spot from the Ad Council about how bananas are, botanically, a &lt;a href="https://recipes.howstuffworks.com/bananas-are-berries.htm"&gt;berry&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div id="83hH05"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/paMantiqs54?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BdHVCo"&gt;Wait, I’m sorry, what? A berry? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C2fTeQ"&gt;I mean...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nVsn5q"&gt;Look, I’m not going to argue with a Banana this big. Just, like... wow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="ySwXm9"&gt;5. And for those who still need their DC Universe fix, this gritty reboot of &lt;em&gt;Superman&lt;/em&gt;, in which the Banana orbits the Earth at a great enough speed to turn back time, thereby erasing humanity from existence.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div id="c6LpKK"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/paMantiqs54?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kc4YiT"&gt;The wind noise really does it for me if I’m being honest.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/3/18/22338021/banana-iss-video-orbit-snyder-cut-justice-leage-ratio"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/3/18/22338021/banana-iss-video-orbit-snyder-cut-justice-leage-ratio</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-18T11:12:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-18T11:12:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>Biden to tap former Senator Bill Nelson as NASA chief</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Bill Nelson" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FhPFCBVLEV2MGImCe3ghkwp_GMo=/0x0:4607x3071/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68987479/507326628.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo By Tom Williams/CQ Roll Call&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yvRV9i"&gt;President Biden has tapped former Democratic Senator Bill Nelson for NASA administrator, according to three people familiar with the decision. Nelson, a politically experienced ally of the administration, would steer the space agency as it races to return humans to the Moon, bolsters its climate research and expands its reliance on a flourishing commercial space industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LBJ57w"&gt;A former congressman and three-term US senator from Florida, Nelson would succeed former president Trump’s NASA chief Jim Bridenstine, whose past experience in Congress proved key in rallying support for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22323621/trump-moon-program-artemis-biden-nasa-timeline"&gt;Artemis&lt;/a&gt; program, an ambitious campaign to use the Moon as a stepping stone for future astronaut missions to Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gFkNiE"&gt;Biden’s decision comes nearly two months after he took office and as the White House remains largely silent on rolling out any space policy agenda. Senate and NASA staffers who were informally briefed this week on Biden’s decision were told that a formal announcement on Nelson’s nomination would come this week, three sources said, speaking under anonymity to discuss private conversations before the announcement is made. Former astronaut Pam Melroy is being considered for Nelson’s deputy, one of the sources said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d1HmDr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BreakingDefense/status/1363950066810171396?s=20"&gt;Rumors&lt;/a&gt; that Biden was considering Nelson to lead NASA had been swirling openly among space industry circles for roughly a month, but it wasn’t until this week that the White House and NASA cemented the choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hCxp46"&gt;Nelson represented Florida’s Space Coast as a state legislator in the 1970s and championed NASA through his time in Congress. He became the second sitting member of Congress to fly to space in 1986 as a payload specialist aboard Space Shuttle Columbia. A moderate Democrat, Nelson served three terms in the Senate until losing his bid for reelection in 2018 to former Florida Governor Rick Scott.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bs4R7P"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22337787/biden-nasa-chief-choice-senator-bill-nelson"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22337787/biden-nasa-chief-choice-senator-bill-nelson</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-18T11:11:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-18T11:11:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook is expanding support for 2FA security keys on mobile devices</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cTCYvGCpcZFMhdxYb8GtsYJdXiA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68987477/acastro_170329_1777_facebook_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5qN19r"&gt;Facebook is expanding its support of physical security keys for two-factor authentication (2FA) on mobile devices, the company said in a &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/03/expanding-support-for-security-keys-on-mobile-devices/"&gt;blog post Thursday&lt;/a&gt;. The social platform has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/1/26/14397276/facebook-two-factor-nfc-security-key-account-hack"&gt;supported security keys for its desktop&lt;/a&gt; version since 2017, but starting today, it will let users on its iOS and Android apps use them to secure their accounts as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QYP6xg"&gt;Two-factor authentication provides another layer of support for online accounts, requiring users to log in with their password and an additional piece of information, usually a numeric code generated by a third-party system. Without both pieces of information, it’s much harder for someone to access your account even if they have your password. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PgvjCt"&gt;“We strongly recommend that everyone considers using physical security keys to increase the security of their accounts, no matter what device they use,” Facebook’s blog post states.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7NipKO082BAWQCmbcwMSpTe7eWw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22379961/2fa_facebook_security_key.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF: Facebook&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SMrJLf"&gt;Physical security keys, which connect to your device using USB or Bluetooth are widely considered the best way to protect online accounts. Other methods, like authenticator apps or SMS alerts, generate codes for users to type in, but the codes could potentially be intercepted by a malicious third party seeking access. Once a user connects the key — which they need to keep on their person or nearby — to their device, it verifies their identity, allowing them to log in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="80OHkR"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22332234/twitter-security-key-2fa-authenticator-privacy"&gt;Twitter said earlier this week&lt;/a&gt; it is planning a future update that will allow accounts with 2FA enabled to use security keys as their sole authentication method. Right now, Twitter users can use a security key plus a second 2FA method as backup. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="C4H9wq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to use a two-factor security key  ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/22/18235288/two-factor-authentication-security-key-how-to"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22337891/facebook-expanding-physical-security-keys-2fa-two-factor-authentication"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22337891/facebook-expanding-physical-security-keys-2fa-two-factor-authentication</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-18T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-18T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla’s co-founder is teaming up with Specialized to solve the problem of e-bike batteries</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_F8xjgBEXs_OzAshyw6tNE4nwuw=/0x0:2000x1333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68987364/Specialized_VadoSL.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Specialized&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Ydsas2"&gt;The growing popularity of electric bikes has raised a lot of exciting possibilities about the future of transportation, but it also presents a number of unique challenges. Chief among them is what to do with all those e-bike batteries when they eventually run out of juice. Rather than send them to a landfill, one major bike manufacturer is teaming up with a co-founder of Tesla to ensure those batteries have a second life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kNWVvZ"&gt;Specialized, the third largest bike maker in the US based on market share, is partnering with a firm called Redwood Materials, which is run by Jeffrey “JB” Straubel, a co-founder and former chief technology officer of Tesla, to figure out a process for recycling the company’s e-bike batteries. Those batteries, which are typically attached to or integrated within the downtube of the bike, activate the motor when the cyclist is pedaling or uses a throttle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RgIMzF"&gt;The bikes are built to last a lifetime, but the batteries typically run out of power after four and six years, said Chris Yu, chief product officer at Specialized. “Generally, the bikes will long outlast the packs for the typical user,” Yu told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “And so it’s always been in the back of our minds: what do we do about them?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="XF8svm"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The bikes will long outlast the packs for the typical user”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3ONSYl"&gt;Enter Redwood Materials. The Carson City, Nevada-based company was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/5/2/15516632/tesla-startup-redwood-materials-recycling"&gt;founded by Straubel in 2017&lt;/a&gt; primarily as a recycler of electric car batteries. In addition to breaking down scrap from Tesla’s battery-making process with Panasonic, Redwood also recycles batteries from Nissan, Amazon, and others. Many of the batteries from those first-wave electric vehicles, like the Nissan Leaf, are just now reaching their end of life and are in need of recycling. Redwood promises that all of its recycling is done domestically — much of the e-waste in the US is shipped to developing countries for smelting — and with an eye toward reuse and recovery. Last year, &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/the-race-to-crack-battery-recycling-before-its-too-late/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wired &lt;/em&gt;referred&lt;/a&gt; to the company as the “anti-gigafactory.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qo_t4Hm1xGqioGxt-duzYlOQFpQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22379764/Specialized_Creo_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Specialized&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A battery being removed from a Specialized electric bike.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ALcIRd"&gt;This is how the partnership will work: Specialized will recover depleted e-bike batteries through its network of retail partners and then ship those batteries to Redwood’s facility in Northern Nevada. The first step will be to figure out how much of the battery is reusable, such as various connectors, wires, plastics, and other components. After that, Redwood will begin a chemical recycling process, in which it strips out and refines the relevant elements like nickel, cobalt, and copper. A certain percentage of that refined material can then be reintegrated into the battery-making process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="AxXanY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We strive to really minimize any separate waste streams”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oMwR9u"&gt;“Usually, there’s not very much else in there that’s very recyclable,” Straubel told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “But we strive to really minimize any separate waste streams.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n2Iaaa"&gt;Specialized says that by the end of 2021, every one of its e-bike batteries will “have a pathway” to Redwood’s recycling facility. Yu explained that means making customers aware through their local Specialized retailer or via diagnostic notifications through the company’s smartphone app about the expected end-of-life date of their e-bike’s battery and what recycling opportunities are available to them. The company has been piloting this process, and so far, 100 percent of the battery packs it collects are going to Redwood. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Tesla Gigafactory" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/C1XPs1EKNELW9-4BMVZBdEzCKnU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6853529/jgolson_160726_1173_0086.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Jordan Golson&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;JB Straubel, center, seen with Tesla CEO Elon Musk in 2016.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="xekAg5"&gt;With e-bike sales booming, there is expected to be a tsunami of dead batteries needing to be recycled in the decades to come — perhaps more so than from electric cars. More &lt;a href="https://www.oicompass.com/market-statistics/ziv-publishes-data-on-german-bicycle-market-2020/87815.article"&gt;electric bikes were sold&lt;/a&gt; in Germany in 2020 than all of the electric cars sold in Europe. Over 547,000 e-bikes were sold in the Netherlands last year, or 54 percent more than the total number of cars, both gas and electric. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/16/21016306/electric-bike-ebike-sales-us-numbers-deloitte-cars"&gt;According to Deloitte&lt;/a&gt;, 130 million e-bikes are expected to be sold globally between 2020 and 2023, making them the most popular battery-powered vehicle on the planet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qjiL5v"&gt;These data points — a faster product life and higher volume of sales — helped convince Straubel to team up with Specialized on this project. He also was friends with Specialized’s founder and CEO, Mike Sinyard, and helped set him up with a Tesla many years ago. But e-bikes, in addition to other lightweight electric vehicles like scooters and mopeds, are a sign of where things are headed for transportation. Straubel said he was surprised by how much of the e-waste that is processed for recycling is comprised of materials from e-bikes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qq3gSZ"&gt;“It’s kind of a bellwether, I think, for passenger EVs,” he said&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; “and that’s been a really fascinating thing.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fzFKc-WRWQfp9pDLa6bc4kg1RbQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22379969/RedwoodMaterials_6877.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Redwood Materials&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A bin of e-waste at Redwood Materials’ recycling facility. &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="T0yCCG"&gt;E-waste recycling is a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/4/20992240/e-waste-recycling-electronic-basel-convention-crime-total-reclaim-fraud"&gt;notoriously shady business&lt;/a&gt;, with companies sending raw materials overseas to developing nations that lack the infrastructure for safe processing. This has caused &lt;a href="https://blogs.ei.columbia.edu/2018/08/27/growing-e-waste-problem/"&gt;a growing ecological disaster&lt;/a&gt;. Straubel insists Redwood is different because it does all of its recycling domestically, not just the separation and aggregation processes. And he aims for maximum transparency, inviting all of his clients to come to the facility and inspect every inch of the process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R8ZLfd"&gt;The gears are shifting in Washington in a way that could have a broad effect on what Specialized and Redwood are hoping to accomplish. A bill was just introduced in the House of Representatives that would &lt;a href="https://electrek.co/2020/03/19/new-us-bill-grants-recycle-batteries/"&gt;incentivize the recycling of lithium-ion batteries&lt;/a&gt;, which are widely used by both electric cars and e-bikes. Another bill would offer a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22295115/ebike-tax-credit-congress-bill-blumenauer"&gt;tax credit for anyone who purchases an e-bike&lt;/a&gt;. Public tax dollars are flowing into the industry in a way that could underscore the importance of Specialized and Redwood’s partnership. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h7IvEa"&gt;“We’ve been working on this for a while. So it was a way to really get in front of it,” Specialized CEO Mike Sinyard told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “People who buy an electric car, but even more, people who buy an electric bike really care about that. And we care deeply about that too.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lt2I5Q"&gt;Straubel agrees, saying it’s a question that’s on the minds of the people who buy these products: what will happen to it when it eventually runs out of power? “They want to make sure that the solution isn’t worse than the problem,” he said. “But to me, this is a story of optimism because these batteries are very highly recyclable, with the right process and method for doing it.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22335988/specialized-redwood-ebike-battery-recycle-straubel-tesla"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22335988/specialized-redwood-ebike-battery-recycle-straubel-tesla</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-18T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-18T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon’s Fire TV is adding local news in many more cities</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QA5U5p09Vv1QUaG0OiJvn8cnzUk=/0x15:831x569/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68987359/FireTV.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Amazon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0RC2Xu"&gt;Back in December, Amazon launched an ad-sponsored news app on its Fire TV platform.  At that time, the app offered local news coverage in 12 cities, including New York, San Francisco, Dallas, Miami, and more. But today, Amazon says it’s expanding local news to “88 major cities” across the US, “including popular local stations from news distributors such as ABC Owned Television Stations, CBSN, TEGNA, Cox, The E.W. Scripps Company, and Altice USA.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zGh3FV"&gt;The news app now comes built into the Fire TV software, and local news gets its own tab in the app. “Amazon’s thoughtful expansion of local news content on its Fire TV devices is a strong testament to the power of local news to keep communities safe and informed through everything 2020 has brought us, and everything ahead in 2021,” Brian Lawlor, Scripps’ president of local media, said in today’s press release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tjJ5oM"&gt;Local news is certainly crucial, but the news app also serves as an easy way to bring in extra advertising dollars. Amazon lets you customize the app to some extent to show your preferred news sources: “When you open the app for the first time, you can select the news that matters most to you from national and local sources. A custom playlist will be generated based on your selections.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qAKDZ4"&gt;At its launch in December, the Fire TV news app already had ABC News Live, CBS News, Reuters, Cheddar, Entertainment Weekly, Black News Channel, and others on board for national news — but expanding local coverage to so many new locations should make the app feel a little fuller and more useful. You can also quickly access local news with an “Alexa, play local news” voice command on the Fire TV remote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cYw0wX"&gt;Roku has also &lt;a href="https://blog.roku.com/free-news-channels-roku"&gt;made live news part of&lt;/a&gt; The Roku Channel, so both leading streaming hardware companies seem to think it’s an important add. The full list of cities where Amazon Fire TV now offers local news includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Ogt1Og"&gt;Atlanta, GA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0N16La"&gt;Austin, TX&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K4uoad"&gt;Bakersfield, CA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vAYJv3"&gt;Baltimore, MD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2zQ71y"&gt;Beaumont, TX&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ElO03b"&gt;Billings, MT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c275pH"&gt;Boise, ID&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="spvKYu"&gt;Boston, MA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Kn7KXX"&gt;Buffalo, NY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w0SN1s"&gt;Butte-Bozeman, MT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CPtKS7"&gt;Charlotte, NC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yv90JS"&gt;Chicago, IL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d69Xd2"&gt;Cincinnati, OH&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dw2OAP"&gt;Cleveland, OH&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vOAEA9"&gt;College Station, TX&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="47ODxF"&gt;Colorado Springs, CO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PrtrA6"&gt;Columbia, SC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rmRA1F"&gt;Columbus, OH&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qFiqdc"&gt;Corpus Christi, TX&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6QDTKP"&gt;Dallas, TX&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TSAzQW"&gt;Davenport, IA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="28d6uZ"&gt;Dayton, OH&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="retGoD"&gt;Denver, CO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zBfSZz"&gt;Des Moines, IA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bsk6P8"&gt;Detroit, MI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uI5Tg2"&gt;Fayetteville, AR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OYLmUq"&gt;Fresno, CA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1IgQQy"&gt;Fort Myers, FL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IfT9Vq"&gt;Grand Rapids, MI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ToGWCR"&gt;Great Falls, MT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FOvM7p"&gt;Green Bay, WI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="clUXf3"&gt;Greensboro, NC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sr4u5d"&gt;Harrisburg, PA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZZs3o1"&gt;Hartford, CT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CxwVtl"&gt;Helena, MT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gce83L"&gt;Houston, TX&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zx9frU"&gt;Huntsville, AL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qAGB58"&gt;Indianapolis, IN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XkFtjT"&gt;Jacksonville, FL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CQ2Kah"&gt;Knoxville, TN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ir1PKb"&gt;Lafayette, LA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="loieKT"&gt;Lansing-Jackson, MI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4qIBbD"&gt;Las Vegas, NV&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lvo9zf"&gt;Lexington, KY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4oN04g"&gt;Little Rock, AR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PgJMhz"&gt;Los Angeles, CA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2JhPdY"&gt;Louisville, KY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="osY1i7"&gt;Macon, GA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IGA8ll"&gt;Memphis, TN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x3dgBN"&gt;Miami, FL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mWRXbS"&gt;Midland, TX&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LJjLNs"&gt;Minneapolis, MN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fiYx7o"&gt;Missoula, MT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ty8AJO"&gt;Moosic, PA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QZ0qWl"&gt;Nashville, TN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qr2tSP"&gt;New Orleans, LA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JPqFXT"&gt;New York, NY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Fl8Yl"&gt;Norfolk, VA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7yCFsp"&gt;Omaha, NE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lNqHD8"&gt;Orlando, FL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f0YiqU"&gt;Philadelphia, PA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1WzGxD"&gt;Phoenix, AZ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8yFCnE"&gt;Pittsburgh, CA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o23283"&gt;Portland, ME&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TjvQ81"&gt;Portland, OR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="peNc8L"&gt;Raleigh, NC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aLpU1u"&gt;Richmond, VA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CcMjn4"&gt;Sacramento, CA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ync8av"&gt;Salt Lake City, UT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fXHP2c"&gt;San Angelo, TX&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UU8yMb"&gt;San Antonio, TX&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tP0MWu"&gt;San Diego, CA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lX3ybW"&gt;San Francisco, CA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="73uhe0"&gt;Santa Barbara, CA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w7vFZ5"&gt;Seattle, WA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yvBpyW"&gt;Spokane, WA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kN77xH"&gt;St. Louis, MI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oNXlw4"&gt;Tallahassee, FL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="teGzbI"&gt;Tampa, FL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RbKxB1"&gt;Temple, TX&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4eSsut"&gt;Toledo, OH&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ahJXgG"&gt;Tucson, AZ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5D70JU"&gt;Tulsa, OK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L1XONM"&gt;Tyler, TX&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sCBNjn"&gt;Waco, TX&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uVAbUU"&gt;Washington, D.C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pg1uvR"&gt;West Palm Beach, FL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22337922/amazon-fire-tv-free-local-news-streaming-app"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22337922/amazon-fire-tv-free-local-news-streaming-app</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-18T10:19:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-18T10:19:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon’s Echo Show 8 smart display is over 40 percent off at several retailers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UOoBZnQJTycx13FURUyjRyhV4Oc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68987023/dseifert_191123_3810_0005.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7CRfvv"&gt;Amazon’s Echo Show 8 is on sale at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PF1Y28C?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724867471427496922#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Famazon-echo-show-8-hd-8in-smart-display%2F-%2FA-81795783%3Fpreselect%3D78656158%26clkid%3D7eebb553N627e11ebb06342010a246e3d%26lnm%3D81938%26afid%3DVox%2520Media%26ref%3Dtgt_adv_xasd0002%26clkid%3D7eebb553N627e11ebb06342010a246e3d%26lnm%3D81938%26afid%3DVox%2520Media%26ref%3Dtgt_adv_xasd0002%26clkid%3D48833994N865a11eb8ae142010a246e3b%26lnm%3D81938%26afid%3DVox%2520Media%26ref%3Dtgt_adv_xasd0002%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;subid1=VegeDailyDeals03182021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt; for $75 right now. While this is not its lowest price ever (the previous best price was only $5 less), it is still an incredible deal on the normally $130 smart display. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="efoU4U"&gt;The Echo Show 8 includes a slightly larger display than the Echo Show 5 and also includes support for videoconferencing apps, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/18/22188551/amazon-echo-group-calling-video-voice-calls-feature-available"&gt;Zoom&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="G2zdlZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9573987"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nDC3T7"&gt;If you’re looking for a good virtual reality headset but are intimidated by the $300 price tag for the relatively affordable Oculus Quest 2, you’re in luck. Over on Oculus’ official website, the company is selling &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=43993&amp;amp;u1=vergedeals&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oculus.com%2Fquest%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a refurbished first-generation Quest for $199&lt;/a&gt;. This “As Good as New” VR headset includes a full one-year warranty. Like its successor, the Quest is a standalone head-mounted display, which allows you to play VR games without additional hardware. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="k6szNa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10375901"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AXkwyA"&gt;Amazon and the Nintendo eShop have some deals on the &lt;em&gt;XCOM 2 Collection &lt;/em&gt;for the Nintendo Switch. You can grab a digital version for &lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/xcom-2-collection-switch/"&gt;$15 at the eShop&lt;/a&gt;. If you are looking for a physical cartridge, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/XCOM-Collection-Switch-Digital-Code/dp/B086BVMVYW?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon has that version on sale for $20&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4sYMYw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10399180"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="4Fi8d0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/3/18/22337767/amazon-echo-show-8-xcom-2-collection-oculus-quest-deal"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/3/18/22337767/amazon-echo-show-8-xcom-2-collection-oculus-quest-deal</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-18T09:59:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-18T09:59:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>You will watch the Snyder Cut in 4:3 aspect ratio because HBO Max respects cinema</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nnbEPeTGQFT9_zzccR8pcA6E0_s=/228x0:2943x1810/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68986833/snyderwarning.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7MYsyZ"&gt;Lest anyone worry that &lt;a href="http://voxmediapartner.go2cloud.org/aff_c?offer_id=2&amp;amp;aff_id=1&amp;amp;source=Verge&amp;amp;aff_sub=SnyderCut031821"&gt;HBO Max&lt;/a&gt; would tarnish Zack Snyder’s auteur work &lt;em&gt;Justice League&lt;/em&gt;, for which the company &lt;a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/hollywood/2021/02/the-true-story-of-justice-league-snyder-cut"&gt;spent $70 million&lt;/a&gt; on reshoots and new digital effects in order to meet the director’s requirements and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22334362/zack-snyder-justice-league-fandom-release-cut-star-wars-twitter"&gt;satisfy years of fan demand&lt;/a&gt; for a better cut of the widely panned movie, the service is prefacing all streams of the film with a short disclosure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="815KjL"&gt;“This film is presented in a 4:3 format to preserve the integrity of Zack Snyder’s creative vision.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="9DaXXJ"&gt;That’s right. HBO will not artificially crop the image just to satisfy your natural demand for widescreen viewing. Nor would it tell Snyder that, hey, &lt;a href="https://www.vulture.com/2021/03/zack-snyder-explains-justice-leagues-first-cow-connection.html"&gt;maybe &lt;em&gt;Justice League &lt;/em&gt;isn’t &lt;em&gt;First Cow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and doesn’t need to be presented in a tight boxy format in which it’s unclear if the entire film was even originally intended to be presented. After three years of demands, this is &lt;em&gt;his &lt;/em&gt;vision, and no one’s going to touch it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9764pm"&gt;Now look, I’m not going to make fun of directors choosing less common aspect ratios (I contend that &lt;em&gt;First Cow&lt;/em&gt;, a quiet movie about a cow, which was also shot in 4:3,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;was robbed of its place on the Best Picture nominees list). But this does mean that HBO Max’s highest-profile film — one that was announced before the streaming service was even available, is exclusive to the service, and is very much meant to bring in new subscribers — is presented in the aspect ratio of a ’90s TV series and leaves about half the screen empty on most modern devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b389vv"&gt;It was known before the movie’s debut this morning that the Snyder cut would be presented in 4:3. So it’s really only HBO’s warning — likely meant as a heads-up to less obsessive fans who may be confused by the crop — that’s a surprise here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DxlMuu"&gt;The film was &lt;a href="https://decider.com/2021/03/18/snyder-cut-justice-league-black-boxes-aspect-ratio/"&gt;supposedly shot for&lt;/a&gt; this boxy format, and if that’s the case, then you’re actually seeing &lt;em&gt;more &lt;/em&gt;on the screen than you did in the 2017 version (which was released in a more traditional widescreen format... and was also two hours shorter). The intention was for the taller footage to be shown on giant IMAX screens, which are close to a 4:3 ratio, though typically only portions of a movie are presented in the larger format. For now, your best bet at watching the film on a device intended for that screen size is to go with something a bit smaller:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9eQCSO1IeU1vnc_kjDGVO8EHKs8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22379774/Screen_Shot_2021_03_18_at_9.34.29_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22337756/snyder-cut-aspect-ratio-justice-league-hbo-max-warning"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22337756/snyder-cut-aspect-ratio-justice-league-hbo-max-warning</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
