<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-22T14:18:40-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-22T14:18:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-22T14:18:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>You can now take Zoom calls from your Amazon television</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Czq4mSXyAz1aKDpjrs-ZvNVOW4Q=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70307113/DSCF6059.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2jARMD"&gt;Amazon launched its own branded Fire TV television sets last month with attractively low price tags &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22785648/amazon-fire-tv-omni-review-alexa"&gt;for a large, if underwhelming, 4K screen&lt;/a&gt; — and today, they’re getting the promised Zoom video calling app so you can chat with family and friends this holiday season (and beyond). While we noted that Zoom was missing at launch and merely “coming soon” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822788/amazon-fire-tv-smart-home-dashboard-alexa-home-theater-now-available"&gt;as of December 7th&lt;/a&gt;, Amazon has managed to roll it out in time for Christmas and New Year’s celebrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0T1mBi"&gt;There’s no camera built into these TVs, of course. &lt;a href="https://amazonfiretv.blog/zoom-now-available-on-fire-tv-omni-series-1aad0b4ec30d"&gt;As Amazon explains in its official blog post,&lt;/a&gt; you’ll need a compatible USB webcam to make it work, one with 720p or 1080p resolution, and the company only specifically lists the Logitech C920, C922x, and C310 as examples. And even if you have a good microphone on that webcam or a set of excellent speakers, you won’t be able to use them: Amazon notes that the Zoom app will use your TV microphone and TV speakers for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="35fODz"&gt;That said, it sounds like an easy way to put your family celebration up on the big screen, compared to the mess of laptop, webcam and cable, HDMI cable, and laptop power cable that I’ve found myself using to do the same thing. The video shows you won’t even need to dig through Amazon’s app store to find the Zoom app; “Alexa, find Zoom” will get you there.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/X_Ws5bBYT8Gi2QNoxSgDum3kM1s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23120761/1_epCIVlfll_Xe4TYjkn1m6Q.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="zV6HEB"&gt;Amazon also brought Zoom &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/29/22599977/amazon-fire-tv-cube-zoom-calls-available"&gt;to its second-gen Fire TV Cube this July&lt;/a&gt;, though not the first-gen Cube. Its Fire TV Sticks don’t have a USB port to plug in a webcam, anyhow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3rW2Jj"&gt;If picture quality isn’t important to you, the sets are on sale now. The two most popular sizes are currently &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08P3QVFMK?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$410 for the 55-inch model&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08T6J1HG8?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$660 for the 65-inch one&lt;/a&gt;. For budget buyers, we’d probably recommend TCL’s 6-Series Roku TVs instead, but Zoom isn’t currently available on Roku, and you’d pay about $100 more for the set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="oRpaYA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Amazon Fire TV Omni review: useful Alexa features, underwhelming picture","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22785648/amazon-fire-tv-omni-review-alexa"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/22/22850298/amazon-fire-tv-omni-zoom-calls"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/22/22850298/amazon-fire-tv-omni-zoom-calls</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-22T14:16:49-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-22T14:16:49-05:00</updated>
    <title>How Marvel Games got its groove back</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/B5xj8T0_eFO7Ncymqv0EKUq3oFE=/0x0:1920x1280/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70307107/marvel_hed.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Kj6jII"&gt;Marvel’s &lt;em&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy&lt;/em&gt; winning Best Narrative was one of the biggest surprises of the 2021 Game Awards. Not only was the category absolutely stacked — featuring serial 10/10 earner &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671207/deathloop-review-ps5-pc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deathloop&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and eventual Game of the Year winner &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22352157/it-takes-two-interview-developer-josef-fares-hazelight-studio-co-op"&gt;&lt;em&gt;It Takes Two&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — but Marvel titles not released by Insomniac Games were known for being critical disappointments. So it was a huge achievement for &lt;em&gt;Guardians &lt;/em&gt;to take the category, beating out games that were far and away easy favorites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lgwYqF"&gt;The win was validation for Jay Ong, EVP of Marvel Games, and his team’s long-term strategy for becoming “the world’s best creative consultancy” by partnering with developers that make games that resonate with fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EU4bHW"&gt;“This was a huge win,” Ong told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “A key thing was that they got the heart right, which is at the center of a lot of the Marvel stories.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q571nm"&gt;For the longest time, Marvel games weren’t known for their quality. In the early aughts, games like &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man 2&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Punisher&lt;/em&gt; were little more than playable versions of Marvel’s blockbuster movies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2e319a"&gt;“[Our] games were tied to movie releases,” Ong said. “One of the things that we realized very early on was that that was a recipe for very subpar games.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IoZwqMVeV-jJTChFxHd2M3DZ--I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23120606/Marvels_Avengers_STORY_2_3.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Despite poor overall reception, Marvel’s Avengers single-player campaign centered on Kamala Khan was the game’s high point.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="qd3RMw"&gt;In 2014, Ong described a sea change that saw the company pivot away from the “inconsistencies” of the past. The team decided to prioritize “quality over other things like monetization or IP,” Ong said. “And so, we completely restructured the business around how to work with the best, most elite talent possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pbjHJZ"&gt;This singular focus on elite talent led to partnerships with Insomniac, developers of &lt;em&gt;Ratchet &amp;amp; Clank&lt;/em&gt;; Firaxis of &lt;em&gt;XCOM&lt;/em&gt; renown; and &lt;em&gt;Deus Ex: Human Revolution&lt;/em&gt; devs Eidos Montreal. Marvel Games would provide the IP and some creative input, but the developers would have the freedom to tell whatever stories they desired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dESeIL"&gt;Ong described attracting these quality developers as a kind of courtship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GxNpdu"&gt;“It’s actually kind of like our secret sauce,” he said. But rather than keep secret the details of how the sauce(sage) gets made, he outlined an elaborate and almost romantic process involving getting to know a studio’s likes, dislikes, and passions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="zcqu0d"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We completely restructured the business around how to work with the best, most elite talent possible”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="m2Zt7P"&gt;“We talk about the creative process,” Ong said. “Do we have the same cultural fit? Do we have the same strategic alignment in terms of what we want this game to be?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i2gMoz"&gt;For Marvel Games, it’s all about finding the right fit between studio and IP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zKxlGa"&gt;“We want to work with partners whose games we want to play,” Ong said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7qlZpt"&gt;For the Disney-owned publisher, it’d be easy for Marvel Games to show up at a dev’s door with the biggest bag of cash and a mandate to make whatever Mr. Mouse desired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZcYraH"&gt;But part of Marvel Games’ new approach centers on a developer-driven relationship in which Marvel offers some input guided by its knowledge of the entertainment world but largely leaves the devs steering the ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7k6iWG"&gt;“We don’t start with ‘Can you make this game?’” Ong said. “It’s more of a ‘What would&lt;em&gt; you&lt;/em&gt; like to do with us?’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cxiDtT"&gt;That’s how&lt;em&gt; Guardians of the Galaxy&lt;/em&gt; came to be. Ong relayed a story of getting “pinged out of the blue” by Eidos Montreal with an idea for a &lt;em&gt;Guardians&lt;/em&gt; game. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ch8hif"&gt;“He had a ton of passion for it,” Ong said of the studio head who approached him with the &lt;em&gt;Guardians &lt;/em&gt;pitch. “He was literally saying, ‘We were made to do this.’”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E2D_WBrkWf2Ssgoce_4n80daerI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23120617/MGG_2021_06_14_scr_04.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;In addition to having a surprisingly heartfelt story, Guardians of the Galaxy is also visually stunning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7RzIQq"&gt;“And we love &lt;em&gt;Deus Ex,&lt;/em&gt;” Ong continued. “We played the heck out of those games. Since we were very familiar with the team and what they do, we thought that would translate really well to &lt;em&gt;Guardians&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J90HIZ"&gt;Indeed, the most common refrain from &lt;em&gt;Guardians&lt;/em&gt;’ reviews, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22747428/marvels-guardians-of-the-galaxy-review-ps5-square-enix"&gt;including &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s&lt;/a&gt;, was that it was a delightful surprise. Eidos Montreal and its partnership with Marvel was able to translate what they loved about&lt;em&gt; Deus Ex&lt;/em&gt; into a critically successful game capable of winning narrative awards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="5AR8HU"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We want to work with partners whose games we want to play.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gqslHD"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Guardians&lt;/em&gt;’ success is the tip of the iceberg of what fans can expect from Marvel games in the future. While Ong wouldn’t share specifics on just what players can look forward to, he did say upcoming games would explore stories and characters beyond X-Men, Spidey, and the Avengers — franchises that have all but dominated Marvel games in the past. Future Marvel games also hold promise of branching out from the typical kind of action games&lt;em&gt; Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Miles Morales&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Guardians&lt;/em&gt; have been. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gg4FR7"&gt;“We want to make games for all the different types of Marvel fans,” Ong said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="feCe5d"&gt;Guided by a set of principles with an eye toward quality talent, Marvel Games’ strategy seems to be working. On top of &lt;em&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy&lt;/em&gt;’s best narrative win, &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt; and its spinoff &lt;em&gt;Miles Morales&lt;/em&gt; are regarded as must-play titles for the PlayStation. Earlier this year, Marvel Games announced &lt;a href="https://skydance.com/news/skydance-new-media-joins-forces-with-marvel-entertainment-to-create-an-all-new-interactive-title/"&gt;its partnership&lt;/a&gt; with former Naughty Dog creative director &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/18/20971217/amy-hennig-skydance-media-studio-streaming-platforms"&gt;Amy Hennig’s game studio&lt;/a&gt; and that a new Wolverine title was in development at Insomniac Games. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rzt2EO"&gt;Players are excited about Marvel games in a way they haven’t been in a long time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ccrwBP"&gt;“It’s validation,” Ong said. “You try and have the right north star, right guiding principles, working with the right partners. Magic happens.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="laJa1W"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ahLyt8"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G0IyW2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d7bKOQ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/22/22848120/marvel-games-evp-interview-guardians-of-the-galaxy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/22/22848120/marvel-games-evp-interview-guardians-of-the-galaxy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-22T13:23:49-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-22T13:23:49-05:00</updated>
    <title>PSA: you can now buy a Nintendo Switch OLED or an Xbox Series S without the hassle</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nEEQ_WC7HBjIdhgNPxjFc_gJYZo=/110x0:1330x813/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70306835/joy_con_01.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The object of your desire can now be yours (if it’s a Nintendo Switch OLED).&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="p10iDr"&gt;When the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/22711889/nintendo-switch-oled-review"&gt;Nintendo Switch OLED Model&lt;/a&gt; launched in the fall, it immediately joined the ranks of the PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, and desktop graphics cards as a sought-after piece of tech that was suddenly out of stock everywhere. While that’s still the case for most of those products that I just mentioned — some are only &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22797788/price-ps5-xbox-nvidia-amd-rtx-gpu-scalpers-ebay-update"&gt;available for close to double their original price&lt;/a&gt; on the secondary market — the Switch OLED is no longer difficult to find in stock. The same goes for Microsoft’s cheaper next-gen console, the Xbox Series S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="qIYgSO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Nintendo Switch OLED review: screentime","url":"https://www.theverge.com/games/22711889/nintendo-switch-oled-review"},{"title":"Xbox Series S review: small console, big potential","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21549021/xbox-series-s-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="ixko8O"&gt;If you’re looking for Nintendo’s high-end console, the chances are very good that you can log onto &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nintendo-Switch-OLED-model-White-Joy/dp/B098RKWHHZ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cgfNjtfnzRI" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FNintendo-Switch-OLED-Model-w-White-Joy-Con%2F910582148&amp;amp;subid1=VergeNintendoSwitchOLED122221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fnintendo-switch-oled-model-with-white-joy-con%2F-%2FA-83887639%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;subid1=VergeNintendoSwitchOLED122221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, and other retail sites right now and find whichever Switch OLED you want available at MSRP ($349.99). This includes both the model with the white Joy-Cons or the classic edition with the neon blue and red Joy-Cons. The $299.99 Xbox Series S is perhaps even more readily available at retailers like &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Xbox-S/dp/B08G9J44ZN/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfRvlrDzyZc" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/1227753/2092?subId1=VergeNintendoSwitchXboxSeriesXPSA122221&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fxbox-series-s-console%2F-%2FA-80790842" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, but keep in mind the digital-only Series S is less powerful than the Xbox Series X, which remains elusive more than a year after making its debut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="H9gi3t"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10929517"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="LjtKQR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9444105"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="H0eAPd"&gt;Buying tech like this has been anything but normal since the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22777216/global-chip-supply-chain-shortage-holidays-christmas-shopping" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;pandemic slowed supply chains to a grinding halt&lt;/a&gt;, with more and more people stuck at home wanting to be entertained — or make a lot of profit flipping tech to people who are struggling to score. To see that you can simply say to yourself, “I want to buy a Switch OLED,” and then do it with no friction is something I wasn’t expecting to see happen in 2021, and I’m thrilled.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FEUW7o0SLmMH0yrqGsPtZ6aOk0A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22013076/vpavic_201103_4275_0252.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unlike the Xbox Series X, the Series S is now readily available at most major retailers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="96DmyU"&gt;So, if you were planning your grand, multi-step strategy for getting a Switch OLED or an Xbox Series S or thinking of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22771984/ps5-restock-xbox-best-buy-walmart-amazon-subscription" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;subscribing to the likes of Amazon Prime, Walmart Plus, or Best Buy Totaltech&lt;/a&gt; to increase your chances of getting either, cast those aside as last resorts for another point in time. At this point in the year, you’ve likely missed out on the chance to have a Switch OLED delivered by the holidays, but a belated gift is better than striking out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="YU2Gi1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/22/22848923/nintendo-switch-oled-model-console-microsoft-xbox-series-s-in-stock-stores-amazon-best-buy-walmart"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/22/22848923/nintendo-switch-oled-model-console-microsoft-xbox-series-s-in-stock-stores-amazon-best-buy-walmart</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-22T13:07:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-22T13:07:38-05:00</updated>
    <title>Asus Zenbook 14X OLED review: a cool but impractical laptop</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;You can get a better OLED notebook for less money&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="6Jl0Tc"&gt;Zenbooks of this size are all usually a pretty similar deal — if you’ve used one, you’ve used them all. Two traits attempt to make the Zenbook 14X OLED, slated for release in early 2022, unique. The first is its OLED display, which is one of the first 90Hz OLED panels to appear in mass production. (Asus’s Vivobook Pro 14 OLED, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22834763/asus-vivobook-pro-14-oled-2022-5900hx-review"&gt;I reviewed earlier&lt;/a&gt;, is another.) The second is that the touchpad is also a screen. Like, it’s literally a tiny touchscreen. You can put windows down there and navigate them as you would with any other touchscreen device. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fLo0Cb"&gt;A bit of a spoiler: both of these features are cool but not quite as cool as they sound, especially considering their impact on battery life. Ultimately, if the Zenbook is a package you’re interested in, you’re better off going for the Vivobook Pro 14 OLED, which has the same OLED screen with an eight-core processor and a better GPU for a couple hundred dollars cheaper. The Zenbook’s target audience is really folks who want something out of the ordinary and are willing to pay for it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="f29NMA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10944078"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="tObLnp"&gt;To start with the OLED screen — it’s neat. It’s 16:10, it’s 2880 x 1800, and it’s a step up in the visual experience from a standard 1920 x 1200 panel. Colors are vivid, and blacks, the trademark of OLED technology, are very, very black. It makes text just a bit more striking, which is fun for me as someone who reads and writes all day. It almost maxes out our colorimeter, covering 100 percent of the sRGB gamut, 99 percent of Adobe RGB, and 100 percent of P3, and reaching 395 nits of brightness. Some glare is visible in a bright office setting, but nothing that interferes with work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q3OYMZ"&gt;The 90Hz refresh rate is quite nice — scrolling is noticeably smoother — but, again, I’m not sure it’s worth the battery life impact. (More on that in a bit). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Asus Zenbook 14X OLED on a wooden table angled to the left. The screen displays a multicolor background with the Asus Zenbook OLED logo. The touchpad displays the Screenpad homepage." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/j1K2TPeV6pOkvfUymHgSmqqPRi4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23084844/akrales_211207_4816_0024.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pretty color scheme.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oJKvoh"&gt;Second, the touchscreen touchpad. This is a similar idea to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/9/21285164/asus-zenbook-duo-review-screenpad-plus-dual-screen-laptop-specs-freatures-price"&gt;Asus’s Zenbook Duo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21431381/asus-rog-zephyrus-duo-15-review"&gt;Zephyrus Duo 15&lt;/a&gt;, and other various dual-screen laptops that the company’s tried. The touchpad essentially functions as a tiny external display — you can drag windows back and forth between it and the primary panel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="88WnRR"&gt;When you don’t have a window open on the touchpad and you’re not actually using it as a touchpad, it’s essentially a secondary desktop with a grid of apps and shortcuts. The most useful one, to me, is the Group button, which allows you to “capture” whatever group of tabs and apps you have open at the time and pull it back up later. You can pull up a number pad and a calculator (which you can also do on the Vivobook’s screenless touchpad, though it doesn’t look as cool). There are shortcuts to open Voice Recorder, Solitaire, and the like on the primary screen (and you can add your apps and webpages of choice). There’s a Handwriting app — scribble on it, and the words will appear as text wherever your cursor is (email, Slack message, whatever). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dQ7VIM"&gt;This technology is very cool, and Asus has done a nice job making its interface attractive and easy to use. I’ll also admit that I still haven’t really found a use case for it. For a while, I tried sticking Slack or Twitter down there to glance at every so often while I worked. But neither was usable on such a tiny screen. This touchpad is the same size as many smartphones, but apps and webpages that you use on your smartphone are designed to be navigated on a tiny screen — apps on the Zenbook are not. Text was tiny, and clicking was clumsy (and I have small fingers). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vL4zga"&gt;The Handwriting app is actually impressive, and the device interpreted my terrible handwriting perfectly. That said, you should understand that this is a text-recognition app, not a full note-taking app — you can’t draw pictures or diagrams and expect the Zenbook to reproduce them. (And it couldn’t recognize Chinese and Korean characters I wrote, at least not with my language set to English.) As a pure handwriting-recognition tool, it is fun, but it does seem mostly to be fun — I’m not sure who actually needs something like this for their job (and folks that do can get &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Wacom-Drawing-Software-Included-CTL4100/dp/B079HL9YSF?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;fine Wacom tablets&lt;/a&gt; for under $100).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MixkDf"&gt;As I noted earlier, the most compelling component for me of the touchscreen touchpad is the grouping feature, especially since the numpad and calculator functions are available in plenty of other Asus laptops. But I don’t think that’s worth a several hundred dollar premium over the Vivobook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e96exK"&gt;It also seemed to confuse my external display a bit — windows I brought over were often too big by default and needed to be resized manually. I’m guessing the Zenbook is considering the touchpad as an extension of the primary screen (rather than a secondary screen), and that’s somehow throwing off its sizing. Regardless, this isn’t a disaster, but it is something I hope Asus can figure out before this ships. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The ports on the left side of the Zenbook 14X OLED." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Oe3nopFFxtFQZa_s9rBwmS3zzxM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23084849/akrales_211207_4816_0067.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lone USB 3.2 Gen 2 Type-A on the left.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The ports on the left side of the Asus Zenbook 14X OLED." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hdR_nIrBWsWBFZGRTTUaKrj79Xg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23084848/akrales_211207_4816_0064.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;All the other portson the right (two Thunderbolt 4 USB-C, one HDMI 2.0, one microSD reader, one audio combo jack).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Asus Zenbook 14X OLED touchpad, displaying the Screenpad homepage." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/180TqsgJh-ccqqrIrIY0PijJUxU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23084845/akrales_211207_4816_0035.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Behold the ScreenPad, running ScreenXpert 2.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="ogk4k7"&gt;Elsewhere, this is Zenbook through and through. It’s a fine-looking device with a nice lustrous lid that you can easily open with one hand and no screen wobble. A warning about Zenbooks, in general, is that the lids are fingerprint magnets — my unit was constantly smudged. The build is a bit plasticky — there’s a small amount of flex in the screen and keyboard, and I saw one small dent in the bottom of the deck after battering the device around in my full backpack for a few days — but a step above budget fodder. There’s a dark gray futuristic-y finish. It’s 0.67 inches (16.9 mm) thick and just over three pounds (1.4 kg) — not a featherweight but portable enough.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5frMed"&gt;Like many Asus laptops, this Zenbook has the Ergolift hinge — the lid folds beneath the deck and lifts the keyboard up a few degrees, conveniently hiding some of the bottom bezels. This is supposed to make typing more ergonomic and help with cooling, but it was also a bit sharp on my lap. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Asus Zenbook 14X OLED webcam." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bhhi2acfmHYCldbGHnmvtsubuZQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23084850/akrales_211207_4816_0079.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s an HD camera, and it’s very tiny.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ttmzu3"&gt;There are two Thunderbolt 4 USB-C ports, one USB 3.2 Gen 2 Type-A, one HDMI 2.0, one microSD reader, and one audio jack. That’s a good mix, though I wish both USB-C ports weren’t on the right side. The Harmon Kardon speakers sound fine but don’t get nearly as much volume as I’d like — I sometimes had to lean far forward to hear my Zoom calls. The keyboard is comfortable with decent travel, and there’s a fingerprint sensor in the power button that didn’t give me any trouble. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lfuewe"&gt;One final thing to be aware of: the webcam isn’t good. Colors are accurate, but it’s grainy and a bit blurry at times — my editor said it looked like someone had smeared Vaseline over it during a Zoom call. I do enough video calls for work now that this would be a concern for me. I also appreciate physical shutters (which this one doesn’t have, though there’s a kill switch on the keyboard) the more I hear about embarrassing Zoom incidents. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Zenbook 14X OLED touchpad displaying the ScreenPad homepage." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4ATQ4aKTD67cQMOjxjNyzAWr-CA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23084842/akrales_211207_4816_0011.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You hit that tiny button in the bottom left corner to turn the Screenpad back into a regular navigable touchpad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="SWSrZL"&gt;Inside is a Core i7-1165G7, 16GB of RAM, and 1TB of storage, in addition to an Nvidia GeForce MX450 discrete GPU. Samsung and Asus gave me a price of $1,400 for this unit but caveated that pricing may change closer to release. If that happens, I will update this review. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2S3bI2"&gt;These specs, to put it bluntly, confuse me. The MX450 is a very entry-level GPU that I wouldn’t even recommend for esports gaming. (Forget about hitting 90 frames per second in modern games with it.) 16GB of RAM (the most you can get in this device) will also not be enough for many professional workloads. I’m happy to see 1TB of storage at this price, but I still can’t see this being a good choice for professionals or for gamers — it still seems primarily slated to be a multimedia machine for people who like OLED screens and smooth scrolling. For those folks, a Zenbook 14x is e-waste — the Vivobook pairs the same screen with an RTX 3050 for (allegedly) $200 cheaper. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="OHZlkK"&gt;&lt;q&gt;These specs, to put it bluntly, confuse me&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Hq2Zdt"&gt;That aside, the Zenbook did a fine job with my daily workload, even in the silent fan profile (called “Whisper Mode” in Asus’ control center) with Battery Saver on. It was sometimes warm but never hot, and I didn’t usually hear any fan noise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MWaj5A"&gt;But there’s a big tradeoff for that: battery life. I’m sure the Vivobook’s longevity isn’t helped by the fact that it’s operating a 90Hz high-resolution panel and &lt;em&gt;also &lt;/em&gt;running a secondary screen. Still, this Zenbook doesn’t last long enough. I only averaged five hours and 38 minutes of continuous office use with this device around 200 nits of brightness. That does slightly beat the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22528646/dell-xps-13-oled-2021-review-screen-specs-price"&gt;Dell XPS 13 OLED&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s less than we’ve seen from all kinds of high-resolution devices like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22790175/huawei-matebook-16-review-price-speces-features-amd-ryzen"&gt;Huawei’s MateBook 16 &lt;/a&gt;or any of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"&gt;Apple’s M1-equipped laptops&lt;/a&gt;. It means I couldn’t go a workday without plugging the device in. For most people (but especially those shopping for a 14-inch device), battery life is going to be more useful than an MX450 and a touchscreen touchpad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5CASrT"&gt;My final note is on bloatware. This device shipped with a big load of annoying software preinstalled, including several McAfee programs that insisted on scanning everything I downloaded before I could open it, and that required me to close all my Chrome tabs and restart the computer in order to be uninstalled. This stuff shouldn’t be on a laptop that costs $1,400 — it just shouldn’t. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Asus Zenbook 14X OLED angled to the right on a wooden table, half open." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_ovVwlzk6plCY57bAErGhZZjBds=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23084847/akrales_211207_4816_0056.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Booo, bloatware.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="rpSBQs"&gt;The Zenbook 14X OLED is a fairly affordable way to pair a 90Hz OLED screen with a GPU. Despite various nitpicks I have, it works well enough as a driver. The problem is that another laptop exists — the Vivobook Pro 14 OLED, with a very similar chassis, a very similar screen, and a better GPU — at a significantly lower price. I’m actually wondering if Asus and Samsung got wires crossed here because it makes no sense that the Zenbook costs so much more, so I’ll be keeping an eye out for any changes as we approach the release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EelwIP"&gt;The main thing that could potentially justify the Zenbook’s price premium is its fancy touchpad. I really do like that Asus is doing this touchpad. I like that there’s a company out there trying things like this that are new and different — and that those things actually work. I can’t tell you how refreshing it is, as someone whose job it is to test a million laptops a week that are all basically the same thing, to know that there’s a company out there trying to figure out where they can do things differently. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="pQWLFS"&gt;I really, really hope there’s a group of people out there who has a perfect use for this touchpad in their life and who will turn out in droves to pay extra for this Zenbook because it’s the first laptop ever made that perfectly suits their needs. I’m not in this group, and I’m skeptical that it exists, but God, I hope it does. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="lBQYqR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10944065"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22850027/asus-zenbook-14x-oled-laptop-review-specs-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22850027/asus-zenbook-14x-oled-laptop-review-specs-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-22T12:41:20-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-22T12:41:20-05:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon’s AWS logs third outage this month, affecting Slack, Epic Games Store, Asana and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tcfUAN03InB_0UTKa7CYDLIq97k=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70305351/acastro_181114_1777_amazon_hq2_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iuvhOy"&gt;Amazon’s crucial web services business AWS is experiencing problems today due to a power outage, affecting services like Slack, Imgur, and the Epic Games store for some users. It’s not looking good if you’re working from home, with some Slack users unable to view or upload images, and work management tool Asana also hit by the outages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kZ6o2o"&gt;At 6:13AM PST, Amazon said it had &lt;a href="https://status.aws.amazon.com/?ascsubtag=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22613821%5Bt%5Dw%5Br%5Ddash.parsely.com%5Bd%5DD"&gt;restored power&lt;/a&gt; to the affected servers, and by 9:28AM PST it had “restored underlying connectivity to the majority of the remaining” systems. However, users may still be experiencing issues as services and servers are relaunched. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jMi62F"&gt;In an &lt;a href="https://status.slack.com/2021-12/a17eae991fdc437d"&gt;incident update&lt;/a&gt;, Slack said its services were “experiencing issues with file uploads, message editing, and other services.” Asana said the problems constituted a “&lt;a href="https://status.asana.com/incidents/xm08pc5v6mlk"&gt;major outage&lt;/a&gt;,” with “many of our users unable to access Asana.” Epic Games Store &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/EpicGames/status/1473644098632441860"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; “Internet services outages” were “affecting logins, library, purchases, etc.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WJBnzJ"&gt;It’s the third time in as many weeks that problems with AWS have had a significant effect on online services. Two incidents &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822332/amazon-server-aws-down-disney-plus-ring-outage"&gt;earlier this month&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22837637/aws-west-is-down-twitch-outage-amazon"&gt;involving AWS&lt;/a&gt; ended up knocking out a huge array of platforms and products, taking out streaming sites like Netflix and Disney Plus as well as smart home devices like security cameras from Ring and Wyze. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gT4U31"&gt;Today’s outages seem less widespread but still notable, with some users unable to access services entirely and others merely experiencing intermittent faults. &lt;a href="http://DownDetector.com"&gt;DownDetector.com&lt;/a&gt; shows reports of issues with the platforms mentioned above, as well as news aggregator Flipboard, online learning site Udemy, dating app Grindr, streaming service Hulu, and IoT services from Honeywell, Life360, and Samsung’s SmartThings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KAowQB"&gt;The official &lt;a href="https://status.aws.amazon.com/"&gt;AWS service health dashboard&lt;/a&gt; blamed the issues on power outages in a single data center, affecting one Availability Zone (USE1-AZ4) within the US-EAST-1 Region. At 6:13AM PST, the company said it had restored power to the data center and was making progress recovering the affected instances. By 9:28AM PST the company said it had “restored underlying connectivity to the majority of the remaining EC2 instance and EBS volumes, but are now working through full recovery at the host level.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K6IIXH"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update Wednesday, December 22nd, 8:36AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated story to add responses from affected services. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GMzrY4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update Wednesday, December 22nd, 9: 34AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated story to note that AWS has restored power to the affected data center. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QXYy5u"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update Wednesday, December 22nd, 12:41AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated with latest from AWS. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/22/22849780/amazon-aws-is-down-outage-slack-imgur-hulu-asana-epic"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/22/22849780/amazon-aws-is-down-outage-slack-imgur-hulu-asana-epic</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-22T12:33:17-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-22T12:33:17-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Xbox Series X is available at Best Buy right now (update: sold out)</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hrWSqQ9_fcsQvWFv7xccRBzC6PU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70306526/vpavic_201103_4275_0182.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8b03dj"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 1:37PM ET, December 22nd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Best Buy has sold out of consoles for now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jqdX7h"&gt;Microsoft’s Xbox Series X keeps coming and going, but the next-gen console remains tricky to get a hold of. We &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/22/22823914/microsoft-xbox-series-x-console-restock-costco-availability"&gt;just saw it go up for sale at Costco&lt;/a&gt; this morning, and as usual, it did not last long before it sold out. Now, another chance has sprung up at Best Buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EI1ZxG"&gt;Right now, you can queue up for the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cggdSQwET4b" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xbox Series X from Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. The retailer is just selling the console — no bundle required — and it is open to anyone, including those who are not Best Buy Totaltech subscribers. Just click the “Add to Cart” button and be patient while you are put in a digital line. As of right now, Best Buy appears to be releasing stock in waves, meaning you may have a second opportunity even if the console appears to be sold out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="L3wZBm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Xbox Series X review: a next-gen PC","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21548987/xbox-series-x-review"},{"title":"Xbox is letting more people test the very latest console features","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22812230/xbox-skip-ahead-alpha-testing-sign-up-open-microsoft"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="7YZCN6"&gt;Also, be ready for Best Buy’s site to ask you to verify your information and, if possible, make sure your account is logged in on another tab while you wait in line. Once you’ve added a console to your cart, you’ll be given about 10 minutes to complete your purchase. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e8NlDK"&gt;These consoles may need to be a late Christmas gift at this point, but, hopefully, you may have some good fortune with a local, in-store pickup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="sDcWMo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10909049"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="CqIeky"&gt;Xbox accessories and games to go with your console&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ZDGCni"&gt;If you did manage to secure Microsoft’s next-gen console, there are a couple of accessories we recommend picking up alongside the Series X, whether you’re looking for a next-gen shooter, a wireless headset, or this year’s best racing title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="fA0VBc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10654449"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="G1YJIg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10907321"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="N2830a"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9532770"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="cIgT7V"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10718694"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="sDNApH"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10847621"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="tVREwz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/22/22826106/microsoft-xbox-series-x-console-restock-availability-check"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/22/22826106/microsoft-xbox-series-x-console-restock-availability-check</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-22T12:23:42-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-22T12:23:42-05:00</updated>
    <title>FDA authorizes first COVID-19 antiviral pill</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3Pdr2vK-iH9CeT9rK0tLkT57rWE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70306483/acastro_200428_1777_coronavirus_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="osVEYg"&gt;On Wednesday, the Food and Drug Administration &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/coronavirus-covid-19-update-fda-authorizes-first-oral-antiviral-treatment-covid-19"&gt;authorized&lt;/a&gt; the first antiviral pill to treat COVID-19, a move that gives doctors another tool to fight the disease. The treatment, made by Pfizer, curbs the risk of hospitalization and death in high-risk patients infected with the coronavirus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l9OPYf"&gt;The drug is authorized for people 12 years of age and older who are at a high risk of getting seriously ill if they contract the virus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Imi7ag"&gt;Called Paxlovid, the treatment includes 30 pills taken at home over five days. It has to be started within a few days of symptoms — which could be &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/11/29/health/covid-pill.html"&gt;a challenge&lt;/a&gt; in the United States, where it may be difficult for many people to get a COVID-19 test, a result, and see a doctor for a prescription in that window. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jAPtSm"&gt;Paxlovid &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/5/22765110/pfizer-antiviral-hospitalization-death-covid"&gt;cut the risk of hospitalization and death by 89 percent&lt;/a&gt; for adults with COVID-19 at high risk of developing severe disease when it was given within three days of symptoms appearing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kt3iSA"&gt;The FDA is also reviewing a second COVID-19 antiviral, called molnupiravir, which is made by pharmaceutical company Merck. That drug appears less effective than Paxlovid — a clinical trial found it only reduces the risk of hospitalization and death from COVID-19 &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/11/26/science/merck-molnupiravir-antiviral-covid-pill.html"&gt;by 30 percent&lt;/a&gt;. France &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/france-cancels-order-mercks-covid-19-antiviral-drug-2021-12-22/"&gt;canceled its order&lt;/a&gt; for molnupiravir on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Le4AQO"&gt;Pills are cheaper and easier to use than monoclonal antibody therapies, which have been a major treatment used for people after they contract COVID-19. Those require an infusion. Pills also &lt;a href="https://www.cidrap.umn.edu/news-perspective/2021/12/pfizer-says-its-pill-may-be-effective-against-omicron-covid-19"&gt;may remain as effective&lt;/a&gt; against the omicron variant of the coronavirus as against other variants, like delta. The drugs target proteins that help the coronavirus make copies of itself — and the newly discovered variant does not have many mutations in that part of the virus. Most monoclonal antibodies appear &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/12/21/health/covid-monoclonal-antibodies-omicron.html"&gt;ineffective&lt;/a&gt; against the omicron variant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jzP97o"&gt;The Biden administration expects to have 250,000 courses of the Pfizer pills available by the end of January, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-12-22/biden-team-plans-4-million-doses-of-covid-treatments-in-january?srnd=premium&amp;amp;sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1XW09l"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/22/22810371/pfizer-merck-paxlovid-covid-antiviral-fda-authorization-omicron"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/22/22810371/pfizer-merck-paxlovid-covid-antiviral-fda-authorization-omicron</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-22T11:59:42-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-22T11:59:42-05:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon reinstates mask mandate for warehouse employees as omicron threat looms</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/43aeKCufiOjP6h4BZILaT8whMQU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70306267/acastro_181114_1777_amazon_hq2_0006.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IQH9r0"&gt;Amazon’s warehouse employees across the US will once again have to wear masks, according to an internal notice obtained by &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/12/22/amazon-revives-mask-mandate-for-warehouse-workers-amid-omicron-threat.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The company reinstated its mask mandate as the omicron variant continues to spread during Amazon’s busiest time of year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="SwnFiN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Amazon has been changing its stance on mask mandates throughout the year&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1F5Upo"&gt;In the message sent to employees, Amazon said that all warehouse workers must wear masks, regardless of vaccination status or local mask requirements. “Your health and safety are of the utmost importance to us,” the notice read. “In response to the rapid spread of the Covid-19 omicron variant in the US and guidance from public health authorities and our own medical experts, face coverings are again required for everyone.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KthCvd"&gt;Amazon has been changing its stance on mask mandates throughout the year. The company initially &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/05/19/amazon-says-vaccinated-workers-can-ditch-masks-starting-next-week.html"&gt;stopped requiring facial coverings in May&lt;/a&gt; and later &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/6/22613542/amazon-warehouse-mask-mandate"&gt;revived the mask mandate in August&lt;/a&gt;. It briefly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/1/22757927/amazon-lifts-mask-mandates-vaccinated-warehouse-employees"&gt;lifted its mask mandate in November&lt;/a&gt; before reinstating it again starting today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZyLxiu"&gt;Companies in the tech industry have been taking very different approaches to COVID-19 safety requirements. While Amazon hasn’t said it will require employees to get vaccinated, Intel and Google have taken things a bit further. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/21/22849074/intel-unvaccinated-employees-unpaid-leave"&gt;Unvaccinated employees at Intel could eventually face unpaid leave&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22836575/google-unvaccinated-employees-mandate-unpaid-leave-termination-remote-work"&gt;those still unvaccinated at Google&lt;/a&gt; may be put on leave or even fired next year. Just like Amazon, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/21/22738265/apple-vaccine-requirement-daily-covid-19-tests"&gt;Apple also isn’t requiring employees to be vaccinated&lt;/a&gt; and has instead asked unvaccinated employees to take tests more frequently — recently, Apple has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22838172/apple-stores-close-retail-covid-19-cases-infections"&gt;closed a&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22826604/apple-store-closed-southlake-texas-covid-19-outbreak-black-friday"&gt;number of stores&lt;/a&gt; due to COVID-19 outbreaks among employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WUEGXz"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; reached out to Amazon with a request for comment but didn’t immediately hear back.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/22/22850036/amazon-mask-mandate-warehouse-employees-omicron-covid-19"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/22/22850036/amazon-mask-mandate-warehouse-employees-omicron-covid-19</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-22T11:39:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-22T11:39:30-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla investigated over reports drivers can play its video games while vehicles are moving</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uUsZKLgoDoPIyR_OuTTgXOSMYKI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70306171/acastro_180430_1777_tesla_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The NHTSA is investigating Tesla vehicles that allow games on their touchscreens | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fAOanM"&gt;The US government says it is investigating more than half a million Tesla vehicles sold since 2017, following reports that drivers can play video games available on its main display screen while driving. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rxRudB"&gt;The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) says it received a complaint in August that said live games and internet web searching — which were supposedly restricted to passenger use only while the car was in motion — could be played by anyone in the vehicle at any time. Its Office of Defects and Investigations &lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23120234/INOA_PE21023_9605.PDF"&gt;said in a report&lt;/a&gt; that it “confirmed that this capability has been available since December 2020 in Tesla ‘Passenger Play’-equipped vehicles.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LCAVaY"&gt;ODI’s preliminary evaluation will include an estimated 580,000 Tesla Model 3, Model S, and Model X vehicles sold between model years 2017 and 2022 “based on reports that Tesla gameplay functionality, which is visible on the front center touchscreen from the driver’s seat, is enabled even when the vehicle is being driven. This functionality, referred to as ‘Passenger Play,’ may distract the driver and increase the risk of a crash,” according to the ODI report. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/45JDKPz1fMdWPxpvnbbALeRqrP0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16352568/tesla_arcade_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Brennan King / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Tesla’s Arcade games&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6cJ1iJ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/12/07/business/tesla-video-game-driving.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reported earlier this month that Tesla updated the playable video games in most of its vehicles in an over-the-air software update this summer. The update allowed some of the games to be played on center touch screens &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22823127/tesla-car-arcade-games-safety-nhtsa"&gt;while the vehicles are in motion&lt;/a&gt;. Prior to the update, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/18/18684297/tesla-arcade-model-3-hands-on-beach-buggy-racing-2-demo-electric-cars"&gt;Tesla Arcade games&lt;/a&gt; could only be played while a vehicle was parked. &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;confirmed that a notification pops up when the games launch, and a user has to tap an “I am a passenger” confirmation button before playing. There’s little to prevent a driver from tapping the button and playing the games, however. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="tVFUUC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Tesla Arcade hands-on: using a Model 3 steering wheel as a game controller","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/18/18684297/tesla-arcade-model-3-hands-on-beach-buggy-racing-2-demo-electric-cars"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="vGeAZ6"&gt;“Why is a manufacturer allowed to create an inherently distracting live video which takes over 2/3 of the screen which the driver relies on for all vehicle information?” the &lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23120243/NHTSA_Safety_Issues.pdf"&gt;complainant asked&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WJxKd8"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; reached out to Tesla for comment on the investigation, but after &lt;a href="https://electrek.co/2020/10/06/tesla-dissolves-pr-department/"&gt;dissolving&lt;/a&gt; its press office in 2020, the company rarely replies to media inquiries. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/22/22849963/tesla-investigation-drivers-play-video-games-vehicles-in-motion"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/22/22849963/tesla-investigation-drivers-play-video-games-vehicles-in-motion</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-22T11:28:20-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-22T11:28:20-05:00</updated>
    <title>Doctor Strange 2’s first trailer goes mad for multiverses</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZZ_Mzu5Xu76r6glm5msw7D0PpQw=/459x0:1932x982/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70306111/Screen_Shot_2021_12_22_at_11.10.10_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dNGEOn"&gt;Marvel’s journey into the multiverse is barreling forward with the first trailer for &lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness&lt;/em&gt;, a sequel to 2016’s &lt;a href="https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/c/482924/564546/9358?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.disneyplus.com%2Fen-gb%2Fmovies%2Fmarvel-studios-doctor-strange%2F4GgMJ1aHKHA2&amp;amp;subid1=VergeDoctorStrange122221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and what promises to be the MCU’s biggest foray yet into the alternate worlds and timelines that installments like &lt;em&gt;Loki&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: No Way Home&lt;/em&gt; have begun to explore. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="1RhYEG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Spider-Man: No Way Home swings big on two decades of fan payoff","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22834061/spider-man-no-way-home-review-tom-holland-marvel-multiverse"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="IieYm3"&gt;It seems that &lt;em&gt;Multiverse of Madness &lt;/em&gt;will be picking up on a breathtaking number of extant story threads in the MCU. It’s a follow-up to Doctor Strange’s (Benedict Cumberbatch) most recent appearance in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22834061/spider-man-no-way-home-review-tom-holland-marvel-multiverse"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: No Way Home&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, where he helped Peter Parker do some &lt;em&gt;mild&lt;/em&gt; tampering with the fabric of reality. It’ll pick up on the revelations around Wanda Maximoff / The Scarlet Witch (Elizabeth Olsen) from &lt;a href="https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/c/482924/564546/9358?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.disneyplus.com%2Fen-gb%2Fseries%2Fwandavision%2F4SrN28ZjDLwH&amp;amp;subid1=VergeDoctorStrange122221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Baron Mordo’s quest to cut down on the number of sorcerers meddling with magic from &lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange&lt;/em&gt;’s post-credit sequence is back in play, as is what appears to be a darker version of Strange himself that previously appeared in the animated &lt;a href="https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/c/482924/564546/9358?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.disneyplus.com%2Fen-gb%2Fseries%2Fwhat-if%2F7672ZVj1ZxU9&amp;amp;subid1=VergeDoctorStrange122221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;What If...?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;on&lt;a href="https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/c/482924/564546/9358?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.disneyplus.com%2F%3Fcid%3DDSS-Search-Google-71700000058993695-%26irclickid%3DVcGXSAwD-xyIW6CSdOVeVx8AUkGwtdwelxjQR00%26irgwc%3D1%26cid%3DDSS-Affiliate-Impact-Content-Vox%2520Media-564546%26gclid%3DCj0KCQiAsqOMBhDFARIsAFBTN3dBoDWJXrDVwzeR5APtVTarczQ4WhI6tkPIVtKwBlFRLhxMopaTyLMaAlj9EALw_wcB&amp;amp;subid1=VergeDoctorStrange122221" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt; Disney Plus. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="XcVmuD"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There’s tons of MCU tie ins here&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dMqDUw"&gt;That’s all in addition to everything new in the trailer, including more of the mind-bending landscapes that made the original Doctor Strange so visually arresting and characters like America Chavez (Xochitl Gomez) and a giant eyeball monster. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WADIGa"&gt;The trailer originally was released as the final post-credit scene for &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: No Way Home&lt;/em&gt; earlier in December, but Marvel has now put it online for everyone to see (pro-tip: this now also means that you don’t have to stick around for the entire credits if you see No Way Home over the next few weeks.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hzlam7"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness&lt;/em&gt; is set to hit theaters on May 6.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/22/22850068/doctor-strange-in-the-multiverse-of-madness-first-trailer-benedict-cumberbatch-marvel"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/22/22850068/doctor-strange-in-the-multiverse-of-madness-first-trailer-benedict-cumberbatch-marvel</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
