<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-01-27T20:01:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-27T20:01:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-27T20:01:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>r/WallStreetBets went private — and now it’s back with a message</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Fm2mk6x45QHtA0YzSyR4-DD0ZYI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68731247/acastro_180413_1777_reddit_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3ygczh"&gt;The r/WallStreetBets subreddit’s own moderators made it private for a little less than an hour on Wednesday evening, Reddit confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;  — but now, it’s back, with a new post from the moderators themselves that doesn’t quite explain why it vanished in the first place. The subreddit has seen a significant increase in attention in recent days following the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22251427/reddit-gamestop-stock-short-wallstreetbets-robinhood-wall-street"&gt;meteoric rise in GameStop’s stock&lt;/a&gt; driven in part by traders on the forum. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zUYnY9"&gt;“We have grown to the kind of size we only dreamed of in the time it takes to get a bad nights sleep,” reads &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/wallstreetbets/comments/l6j4r9/where_do_we_go_from_here_and_who_is_going_to_step/"&gt;a new post from the mods&lt;/a&gt;, one which you can read in its entirety at the bottom of this post in case it disappears. “We’ve got so many comments and submissions that we can’t possibly even read them all, let alone act on them as moderators,” the post continues, addressing how the community &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253251/discord-bans-the-r-wallstreetbets-server"&gt;has also been banned from Discord&lt;/a&gt; and how they believe Reddit’s tools are insufficient to moderate bad behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hu8DFI"&gt;The post also points to a Twitter account, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/wsbmod"&gt;@wsbmod&lt;/a&gt;, which is intended to be the official voice of the moderator team in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="tJr0dS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How r/WallStreetBets gamed the stock of GameStop ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22251427/reddit-gamestop-stock-short-wallstreetbets-robinhood-wall-street"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="KMoVs9"&gt;During the time the subreddit was private, there were a few different messages shown to visitors. When I checked the subreddit at 7:06PM ET, I saw this message:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="ayzF1m"&gt;We are experiencing technical difficulties based on unprecedented scale as a result of the newfound interest in WSB. We are unable to ensure Reddit’s content policy and the WSB rules are enforceable without a technology platform that can support automation of this enforcement. WSB will be back.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/53chGWnjtZM6iC4kB-x7304S_LE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22264496/Screen_Shot_2021_01_27_at_4.07.09_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="L3pwBm"&gt;Before that, the page showed this message: “WallStreetBets is under in tents load and is only for approved submitters. In the meantime, please enjoy some spaghetti,” followed by a link to a NSFW video of a man putting spaghetti all over his body.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JZynvoi3RaHJrANIfD9V2l9UpHQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22264493/Screen_Shot_2021_01_27_at_4.04.06_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="s4RjHK"&gt;And when the r/WallStreetBets was first made private, the message read, “like 4Chan found a Bloomberg Terminal,” which was the description of the subreddit previous to it being made private.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oKYHRCYmMYY31eOCwO-0aCSsnD4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22264483/Screen_Shot_2021_01_27_at_3.46.19_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="08QAtr"&gt;Mysteriously, some people claimed they lost their existing access to r/WallStreetBets when it went private:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="fMzTKm"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Lost access to wallstreetbets &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/wsb?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#wsb&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/y2qsVnC4Zb"&gt;pic.twitter.com/y2qsVnC4Zb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— sunny  (@ytinvestment) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ytinvestment/status/1354575140978212866?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 27, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="YxklKY"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I just got removed from WSB... random. Been on there for half a year&lt;/p&gt;— dawson schrader (@dawson_schrader) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dawson_schrader/status/1354576538264604677?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 27, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="iauUOI"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/wallstreetbets?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@wallstreetbets&lt;/a&gt; hi, somehow I can’t access the page anymore? I’ve been a member since December? What happened?&lt;/p&gt;—  Daam Stevens   (@daamsincome) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/daamsincome/status/1354578019269169153?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 27, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ScRW2f"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Wait did they just take down wallstreetbets??     I can’t access it either    &lt;a href="https://t.co/QH6fvHkLdW"&gt;https://t.co/QH6fvHkLdW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Chris (@TechChris_NC) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TechChris_NC/status/1354576613099397124?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 27, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4eI0fB"&gt;Earlier on Wednesday, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253251/discord-bans-the-r-wallstreetbets-server"&gt;Discord banned the r/WallStreetBets server&lt;/a&gt;. The company said that the Discord was banned for “continuing to allow hateful and discriminatory content after repeated warnings.” Many posts on the subreddit contain offensive language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JUWjLj"&gt;Here is the &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/wallstreetbets/comments/l6j4r9/where_do_we_go_from_here_and_who_is_going_to_step/"&gt;full post&lt;/a&gt; from the r/WallStreetBets moderators:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="zgKoG5"&gt;We have grown to the kind of size we only dreamed of in the time it takes to get a bad nights sleep. We’ve got so many comments and submissions that we can’t possibly even read them all, let alone act on them as moderators. We wrote software to do most of the moderation for us but that software isn’t allowed to read the Reddit new feed fast enough and submit responses, and the admins haven’t given us special access despite asking for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h5nRQi"&gt;We’re suffering from success and our Discord was the first casualty. You know as well as I do that if you gather 250k people in one spot someone is going to say something that makes you look bad. That room was golden and the people that run it are awesome. We blocked all bad words with a bot, which should be enough, but apparently if someone can say a bad word with weird unicode icelandic characters and someone can screenshot it you don’t get to hang out with your friends anymore. Discord did us dirty and &lt;strong&gt;I am not impressed with them destroying our community&lt;/strong&gt; instead of stepping in with the wrench we may have needed to fix things, especially after we got over 1,000 server boosts. That is pretty unethical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CQnTJH"&gt;To add to this, people are co-opting our name on twitter. I won’t mention their accounts, but lots of handles with “wsb” and “wallstreetbets” in them are pretending to speak for us. They’re saying things that we don’t agree with, driving traffic to derivative communities and shitty pixelated merch stores, and generally making it harder for us to define who we are. There’s also too much political bullshit in a community that was never &lt;em&gt;ever&lt;/em&gt; political. The only way I want to occupy Wall St is in a suit myself or rent-free in the mind of a blown up short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I8HoB0"&gt;That is why I’m throwing my support behind the Twitter handle in general. We need a way to PUBLICLY reach out to the staff of the infrastructure that is failing us so the world can see that we aren’t doing anything wrong here if they don’t respond. We need to be able to respond directly to a reporter that is lying to the world about our clubhouse. We can’t be expected to meet any expectations when we aren’t given the tools we need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6F0MF1"&gt;That’s not to say I approve of every message or will even be in the loop for all of them, but it’s clear to me we can’t do nothing and we need a megaphone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nknVqB"&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/wsbmod"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;http://twitter.com/wsbmod&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; aka &lt;strong&gt;@wsbmod&lt;/strong&gt; is the only Twitter handle whose statements are directly from some part of the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ui1eP2"&gt;We’ll do our best not to pretend to speak for you, but to try to speak with the volume our name now seems to command to get shit done for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="kn4Rfo"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 27th, 8:01PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;r/WallStreetBets has reopened, with a message from a moderator, which we have added.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rGUwag"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VMhN3y"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253339/reddit-wallstreetbets-subreddit-private-gamestop"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253339/reddit-wallstreetbets-subreddit-private-gamestop</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-27T19:29:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-27T19:29:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>Reddit vs. Wall Street: the latest in the GameStop saga</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ADs-FfJsFTvWLtM1a13Vcr7iEPw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68731385/acastro_180413_1777_reddit_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The story of r/WallStreetBets&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="FvTBIJ"&gt;Subreddit r/WallStreetBets has been the talk of the Internet this week, as its members have driven GameStop’s stock prices &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22251427/reddit-gamestop-stock-short-wallstreetbets-robinhood-wall-street"&gt;from around $20 to over $300&lt;/a&gt;. The community brands itself as “like 4chan found a Bloomberg Terminal,” and as time has gone on, it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22251964/amc-stock-price-reddit-wallstreetbets-trading-gamestop"&gt;targeted other unlikely stocks&lt;/a&gt; like AMC, Blackberry, and Tootsie Roll. They’ve also been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253251/discord-bans-the-r-wallstreetbets-server"&gt;banned from Discord for hate speech&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D3YeM5"&gt;If you want to read about how the group was able to manipulate the stocks of a massive company like GameStop — and the potential fallout — maybe start &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22251427/reddit-gamestop-stock-short-wallstreetbets-robinhood-wall-street"&gt;with our explainer?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c1mCCo"&gt;Otherwise, you can use this storystream to get caught up on the full story. We’ll be updating it with all the latest twists and turns.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22253363/wall-street-bets-verge-stories-gamestock-reddit-discord"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22253363/wall-street-bets-verge-stories-gamestock-reddit-discord</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
      <name>Elizabeth Lopatto</name>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
      <name>Bijan Stephen</name>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-27T18:29:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-27T18:29:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla’s new Model S will apparently play Witcher 3 on a built-in 10 teraflop gaming rig</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/umELrsZKL6bM1rGQ-mmRGGr1dr0=/0x0:1201x801/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68731081/tesla_model_s_witcher_3_3.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BAwode"&gt;If you can’t find a PS5 or Xbox Series X, how about an $80,000 electric sports car with comparable performance? Tesla just announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22252832/tesla-model-s-redesign-plaid-mile-range-interior-refresh"&gt;its refreshed Model S today&lt;/a&gt;, and a new “Plaid” powertrain isn’t its only performance enhancement — the company claims the car can now compete with next-gen gaming consoles, thanks to a 10-teraflop gaming computer that will apparently come with every new model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TFSUiR"&gt;Assuming that refers to GPU performance and Tesla isn’t wildly exaggerating, that might indeed be competitive with a PS5 or Xbox Series X, which offer 10.28 teraflops and 12 teraflops of raw GPU power respectively. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21718936/xbox-series-x-ps5-performance-game-comparison"&gt;There’s more to performance than teraflops, though&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zoaRUdHMjos_BSVPCoPHChvV2FE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22264387/tesla_model_s_witcher_3_1.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hnqGQ6"&gt;Now, you might ask: who’s going to put a game in your car that might actually take advantage of a gaming PC? For that, I must ask you to look closely at the images above and below. Behold: CD Projekt’s acclaimed sword-slinging adventure &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/5/12/8586515/witcher-3-wild-hunt-review-ps4-xbox-one-game"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Witcher 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;just as Musk foretold: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wc3vE1"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Want to play The Witcher game on your Tesla? (you can already watch the show on Tesla Netflix theater)&lt;/p&gt;— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1219881215156801537?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 22, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ALM8S6"&gt;Here are a number of things we still do not know:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="govTzt"&gt;Is &lt;em&gt;The Witcher 3&lt;/em&gt; actually coming to Tesla, and when? (We’ve asked CD Projekt.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="aLUv3g"&gt;Can you play it on the 17-inch, 2200 x 1300-pixel main display, or only on the 8-inch second row display? Or both?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="mMh3WH"&gt;Will you need a new controller? (Tesla says it has “wireless controller compatibility” but that’s all we know.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xYMsbj"&gt;Who’s making the GPU? (We’ve pinged Nvidia and AMD.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RybmF7"&gt;Who is going to sit in their $80,000 sports car and play a 70+ hour game? (fingers crossed for cloud saves)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ktgx6v"&gt;Why not &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk? &lt;/em&gt;(Okay, this one’s a joke.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/U2_PNft9jF1DDMgDvFH5m_LKfWY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22264385/tesla_model_s_witcher_3_2.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="nGRD56"&gt;You can see the claims for yourself at Tesla’s Model S website, though they’re a little buried: you have to &lt;a href="https://www.tesla.com/models/design#overview"&gt;go to the shop&lt;/a&gt;, scroll down to “Interior” and click on “Feature Details.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GY8bFi"&gt;Tesla’s been bringing games to its cars for a while now: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/18/18684297/tesla-arcade-model-3-hands-on-beach-buggy-racing-2-demo-electric-cars"&gt;we tried out Tesla Arcade on a Model 3 back in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, and both the first level of &lt;em&gt;Cuphead&lt;/em&gt; and a car karaoke mode &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/26/20885822/tesla-software-version-10-now-available-features-netflix-youtube-spotify"&gt;came to the company’s in-car software&lt;/a&gt; later that year. &lt;em&gt;Fallout Shelter &lt;/em&gt;was added to the cars last year.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253258/tesla-model-s-ps5-xbox-series-x-next-gen-10-teraflop"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253258/tesla-model-s-ps5-xbox-series-x-next-gen-10-teraflop</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-27T18:09:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-27T18:09:30-05:00</updated>
    <title>Discord bans the r/WallStreetBets server</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7eIfUrti3enf32l9-XgZmbQ4Eck=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68730932/acastro_200318_1777_discord_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JDsAv0"&gt;Discord has banned the r/WallStreetBets server, the company confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. Reddit’s WallStreetBets subreddit is the driver of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22251427/reddit-gamestop-stock-short-wallstreetbets-robinhood-wall-street"&gt;an unprecedented rally of GameStop stock,&lt;/a&gt; and has received a great deal of attention in the press as the stock continues to soar. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tIgwNu"&gt;Discord says it did not ban the server for financial fraud — rather, it was banned because it continued to allow “hateful and discriminatory content after repeated warnings.” &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;gained access to the server and can confirm the claim that users of the channel were spamming hateful language, including racial slurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AZoNEs"&gt;Here is Discord’s full statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="eBVyJl"&gt;The server has been on our Trust &amp;amp; Safety team’s radar for some time due to occasional content that violates our Community Guidelines, including hate speech, glorifying violence, and spreading misinformation. Over the past few months, we have issued multiple warnings to the server admin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RjRZJQ"&gt;Today, we decided to remove the server and its owner from Discord for continuing to allow hateful and discriminatory content after repeated warnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UIL02D"&gt;To be clear, we did not ban this server due to financial fraud related to GameStop or other stocks. Discord welcomes a broad variety of personal finance discussions, from investment clubs and day traders to college students and professional financial advisors. We are monitoring this situation and in the event there are allegations of illegal activities, we will cooperate with authorities as appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="gO5d2y"&gt;r/WallStreetBets describes itself as “like 4chan found a Bloomberg Terminal,” and many comments on the subreddit contain offensive language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mjLqVf"&gt;Shortly after Discord banned the server, the moderators &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253339/reddit-wallstreetbets-subreddit-private-gamestop"&gt;made the entire r/WallStreetBets subreddit private as well&lt;/a&gt;, taking it dark for nearly an hour. When it returned, the moderators of the subreddit &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/wallstreetbets/comments/l6j4r9/where_do_we_go_from_here_and_who_is_going_to_step/"&gt;had a message about the Discord ban&lt;/a&gt; which you can read below: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="3rM9gx"&gt;We’re suffering from success and our Discord was the first casualty. You know as well as I do that if you gather 250k people in one spot someone is going to say something that makes you look bad. That room was golden and the people that run it are awesome. We blocked all bad words with a bot, which should be enough, but apparently if someone can say a bad word with weird unicode icelandic characters and someone can screenshot it you don’t get to hang out with your friends anymore. Discord did us dirty and &lt;strong&gt;I am not impressed with them destroying our community&lt;/strong&gt; instead of stepping in with the wrench we may have needed to fix things, especially after we got over 1,000 server boosts. That is pretty unethical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="idOBMn"&gt;The bold text was present in the original post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="9M335U"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How r/WallStreetBets gamed the stock of GameStop ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22251427/reddit-gamestop-stock-short-wallstreetbets-robinhood-wall-street"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="sDHhp4"&gt;During the time the Discord server was live, it was chaotic, with messages coming in at a rapid rate and many voices talking over each other simultaneously. Check out &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/1354532238524874753"&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; from my colleague Tom Warren to get an idea of what was like (note: you may want to turn down your volume before clicking play, as the voices are quite loud):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="INdLRU"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;the main Discord call for wallstreetbets is true online chaos    &lt;a href="https://t.co/cq8QOyHj6m"&gt;pic.twitter.com/cq8QOyHj6m&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Tom Warren (@tomwarren) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/1354532238524874753?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 27, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CGvgiS"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 27th, 8:10PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Added comment about the Discord ban from r/WallStreetBets moderators.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253251/discord-bans-the-r-wallstreetbets-server"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253251/discord-bans-the-r-wallstreetbets-server</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-27T17:59:10-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-27T17:59:10-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple says there are now over 1 billion active iPhones</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/o3UqHy4EPlB9VLT0KBhjpSJFYMk=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68730855/cgartenberg_201105_4276_003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PzxQHS"&gt;Apple says there are now more than 1 billion active iPhones, an enormous milestone for the company that speaks to the phones’ continued success and longevity. There are now 1.65 billion Apple devices in active use overall, Tim Cook said during Apple’s earnings call this afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="laKAjl"&gt;The milestone had been approaching for a while. Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/7/27/12302542/apple-billion-iphones-sold"&gt;sold its billionth iPhone&lt;/a&gt; in 2016, and in January 2019, Apple said that it had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/29/18202736/apple-devices-ios-earnings-q1-2019"&gt;hit 900 million active iPhone users&lt;/a&gt;. Apple counts a device as active if it has engaged with an Apple service within the past 90 days, a spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. The stat would suggest that a substantial number of the iPhones ever sold remain in active use, at least by Apple’s definition. &lt;a href="https://www.bnnbloomberg.ca/apple-nears-two-billionth-iphone-sale-13-years-after-launch-1.1371339"&gt;&lt;em&gt;BNN Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;reported last year&lt;/a&gt; that analysts believed Apple would be approaching its 1.9 billionth iPhone sale by the end of 2020, though the company hasn’t announced if it’s passed that milestone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HzIfJ6"&gt;Apple’s announcement came during an enormous quarter for the company, in which it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22252663/apple-q1-2021-earnings-iphone-12-mac-sales"&gt;set an all-time revenue record&lt;/a&gt;. iPhones did particularly well during the final quarter of 2020, with sales of $65 billion, another record (though one that was helped by delays pushing iPhone 12 sales fully into the holiday quarter). And the company saw more iPhone “upgraders” than ever before. Cook also said that a record-setting number of FaceTime calls were made on Christmas 2020 — a milestone that was certainly helped along by the pandemic keeping many families and friends apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ECdPrQ"&gt;While sales are up and usage is at an all-time high, Apple has spent the last several years trying to diversify its product line as iPhone unit sales slow. Analysts have estimated a decline in &lt;a href="https://qz.com/1849696/apples-drop-in-iphone-sales-are-part-of-a-global-demand-shock/"&gt;overall phone shipments&lt;/a&gt; and sales in recent years, and &lt;a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/heres-an-interesting-chart-iphone-unit-sales-have-been-declining-steadily-for-five-years/"&gt;Apple hasn’t been immune&lt;/a&gt; to the trend. But even if fewer iPhones are being put into people’s hands each year, people are evidently hanging on to them for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q59gy9"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 27th, 7:10PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This story has been updated with details on how Apple measures active devices.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253162/iphone-users-total-number-billion-apple-tim-cook-q1-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253162/iphone-users-total-number-billion-apple-tim-cook-q1-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-27T17:30:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-27T17:30:16-05:00</updated>
    <title>Cyberpunk 2077 bans unauthorized Keanu Reeves sex</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dbFcMSPFO0ngfVR6UJMHEQWNolA=/0x45:1570x1092/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68730736/Screen_Shot_2021_01_27_at_4.46.27_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Bt5HZL"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; creator CD Projekt Red would kindly like modders to stop making Keanu Reeves into a sex object. Following a fan mod that allowed players to have sex with Reeves’ character, Johnny Silverhand, the developer told &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/cdpr-shuts-down-cyberpunk-mod-that-let-players-have-sex-with-keanu-reeves/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;that&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;user-generated content cannot be “harmful towards others” — especially when it comes to mods. “In the case of model swaps, especially those that involve explicit situations, it can be perceived as such by the people who lent us their appearance for the purpose of creating characters in &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077,&lt;/em&gt;” the developer said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E4MZP1"&gt;It’s worth noting that Reeves’ character does have an in-game sex scene, though it plays out from his perspective. As Johnny, the player has sex with a blonde woman who inexplicably dumps good liquor onto her white top to a backdrop of guitar riffs, while Johnny bounces her around. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PxxL28"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2021-01-26-people-are-modding-cyberpunk-2077-to-have-sex-with-keanu-reeves"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eurogamer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;first reported on the Nexus Mods files that swapped a sex worker “joytoy” character model for Reeves’ Johnny. In the mod, Johnny — who remains clothed — is now the sexualized character seen through the players’ eyes. It also uses the joytoy’s voice acting throughout the brief scene. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QyOAGJ"&gt;It’s typical for players to personalize their experience through mods, and the&lt;em&gt; Cyberpunk &lt;/em&gt;community has been doing so since the game’s release. CD Projekt Red just released &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22252373/cyberpunk-2077-official-mod-support"&gt;official modding tools&lt;/a&gt;. However, the mod — which has since been &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/cyberpunk2077/mods/990?tab=description"&gt;hidden&lt;/a&gt; by the creator on Nexus Mods — crosses that boundary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AMUAjw"&gt;“For the characters we’ve invented for the game, we broadly permit you to tweak the game at will and just have fun,” CD Projekt Red told &lt;em&gt;PC Gamer&lt;/em&gt;. “When it comes to models of real people whom we’ve asked to participate in the game, we kindly ask you to refrain from using them in any situation that might be found offensive if you don’t have their explicit permission.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253112/cyberpunk-2077-keanu-reeves-sex-mod-ban"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253112/cyberpunk-2077-keanu-reeves-sex-mod-ban</id>
    <author>
      <name>Megan Farokhmanesh</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-27T17:20:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-27T17:20:26-05:00</updated>
    <title>Disney pulls some movies from Disney Plus Kids profiles because they feature racist stereotypes</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gMvvd8u65ArO_Qqmv14YwGuBvoA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68730669/acastro_190411_1777_Disney_Streaming_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8n05bw"&gt;The history of cinema is littered with racist stereotypes. (Call it the long tail of minstrel shows.) As cultural preferences have evolved — which is to say it’s now not cool to be racist — so have our films. In practice, what that means is some stuff just doesn’t hold up, especially when you’re showing it to kids. According to Disney, that includes classics like &lt;em&gt;Peter Pan &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Dumbo. &lt;/em&gt;Disney Plus will now not show those two films and some others to &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/disney-plus/2021/1/27/22252244/disney-plus-removes-peter-pan-dumbo-racist-stereotypes-kids-profiles"&gt;profiles that indicate the viewer is seven years old or younger&lt;/a&gt;. Other blocked movies include &lt;em&gt;Aristocats&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Lady and the Tramp&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Swiss Family Robinson&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Jungle Book.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wgldbm"&gt;It’s a big move, though adult accounts will still be able to access the blocked films. If you do decide to stream those films, there is a warning: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="LOY0lB"&gt;This program includes negative depictions and/or mistreatment of people or cultures. These stereotypes were wrong then and are wrong now. Rather than remove this content, we want to acknowledge its harmful impact, learn from it and spark conversation to create a more inclusive future together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OmDwd1"&gt;Disney is committed to creating stories with inspirational and aspirational themes that reflect the rich diversity of the human experience around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="OcI1gt"&gt;It’s not unprecedented. In fact, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/13/20963014/disney-plus-racism-cultural-disclaimer-dumbo-song-of-the-south-warner-bros-tom-jerry"&gt;Disney added warning labels back in 2019 for different movies on Disney Plus&lt;/a&gt; (though they weren’t as strongly worded). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ls1qCA"&gt;The times, as they say, are a-changing. And if you’re curious, you can read more about Disney’s diversity efforts &lt;a href="https://storiesmatter.thewaltdisneycompany.com/"&gt;right here&lt;/a&gt;, part of its Stories Matter initiative. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253052/disney-racist-films-movies-dumbo-peter-pan-aristocats-jungle-book"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253052/disney-racist-films-movies-dumbo-peter-pan-aristocats-jungle-book</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bijan Stephen</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-27T17:05:45-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-27T17:05:45-05:00</updated>
    <title>Sling TV is raising prices and sweetening the deal with more free DVR space</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Sling TV stock 2040" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Itb9Bj5jWsT0SiawGhi6QqvDAJw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68730556/theverge1_2040.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6VDsHf"&gt;Sling TV, Dish’s live TV streaming service, &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/sling-tv-expands-free-dvr-storage-updates-pricing-for-new-customers-301216392.html"&gt;announced that it’s raising the prices&lt;/a&gt; on its packages and add-ons for new customers starting today. Both the Orange and Blue channel packages from Sling will go up by $5 to $35 per month for new subscribers or $50 per month when bundled together. Because of Sling’s existing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/1/21310302/sling-tv-same-price-guarantee-youtube-tv-att-fubotv"&gt;one-year price guarantee&lt;/a&gt;, current subscribers won’t have to deal with the new prices until August 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NffPWD"&gt;Along with the changes to the packages, Sling TV add-ons are also getting a small price bump. The “Sports Extra” for live sports is going up by $1 to $11 per month for new customers who subscribe to either Sling Blue or Orange. Customers who bundle Blue and Orange together will still pay $15 per month for the sports add-on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aU4kkS"&gt;All other extras and add-ons for comedy, lifestyle, and news channels will be raised by $1 to $6 per month. If navigating all of those add-ons seems like too much, Sling TV’s giant “total TV deal” for every add-on the service offers is available for new Orange or Blue package subscribers for $21 per month ($1 more than before). If you’re bundling Orange and Blue, you can get the deal for $27 per month ($2 more than before).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EryhMc"&gt;In addition to the new higher prices, Sling TV is also throwing in extra hours of DVR space. Customers will now have 10 extra hours, bringing up the total to 50 hours. If you subscribe to Sling’s DVR Plus add-on, your total DVR space will shoot up to 200 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PvqOoR"&gt;Sling last &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/23/21035080/sling-tv-orange-blue-price-increase-subscription"&gt;raised prices in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, but this year’s changes come after a cascade of rising TV subscription costs from competitors like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/30/21308449/youtube-tv-price-increase-64-99-viacom-hbo-new-channels"&gt;YouTube TV&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/16/21570259/hulu-live-tv-price-increase-cable-sports-news-virtual-bundle-disney"&gt;Hulu with Live TV&lt;/a&gt;. At $50 per month for the combined Sling Orange and Sling Blue bundle, Sling TV is still cheaper than YouTube TV at $64.99 a month or Hulu with Live TV for the same price. Sling TV’s various add-ons and packages make it a lot more complicated to navigate, but if you’re looking for core cable channels, you can still get a deal at Sling, albeit a slightly more expensive one.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22252810/sling-tv-price-increase-free-dvr-youtube-hulu"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22252810/sling-tv-price-increase-free-dvr-youtube-hulu</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-27T16:47:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-27T16:47:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook usage has soared during the pandemic, but the company warns of ‘significant uncertainty’ ahead</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HStDhMW9rpARToE36CjcNxmKvUA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68730404/mdoying_180118_2249_facebook_0581_1stills.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Michele Doying / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aPpRYl"&gt;Facebook finished 2020 much stronger financially than at the beginning of the year, proving its business could weather the coronavirus pandemic and even thrive thanks to skyrocketing screen time these past 12 months. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UikNnA"&gt;The company &lt;a href="https://investor.fb.com/investor-news/press-release-details/2021/Facebook-Reports-Fourth-Quarter-and-Full-Year-2020-Results/default.aspx"&gt;reported fourth quarter earnings on Wednesday&lt;/a&gt; of more than $28 billion in revenue with profit of $11.2 billion, respective 31 percent and 53 percent year-over-year increases. As far as usage goes, Facebook is up all around, with more than 1.84 billion people using its main social network at least once a day in December 2020, an 11 percent year-over-year increase. As of December 31st, 2020, more than 2.8 billion people check Facebook at least once a month, a 12 percent jump from the year before. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8vDSQF"&gt;When measuring usage of its bundled family of apps that also includes Facebook Messenger, Instagram, and WhatsApp — a metric the company refers to as “family active people” — the numbers are even better, as usual. More than 2.6 billion people check one of Facebook’s apps every day (up 15 percent from 2019), while more than 3.3 billion check one of the apps at least once a month (up 14 percent). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="0708f7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;More than 3.3 billion people use a Facebook-owned app at least once a month&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SkhwjL"&gt;Facebook’s business was largely unaffected by its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/11/21560969/facebook-political-ad-ban-extended-trump-2020-election-concede-misinformation"&gt;decision in October to temporarily ban political advertising&lt;/a&gt; following the US election. (The company extended the ban by one month in December, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22215067/facebook-ads-georgia-runoff-political-ad-ban-zuckerberg"&gt;exempted advertising for the Georgia Senate races&lt;/a&gt;.) That was to be expected; political advertising pales in comparison to e-commerce, standard retailer, and small business ad spend on the platform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ual4Pc"&gt;Facebook’s “Other” category, which includes its Portal video chat devices and Oculus virtual reality business, also fared quite well last quarter, with a 156 percent jump in revenue to $885 million. Last quarter included the launch of Facebook’s second-generation wireless Quest headset, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21437674/oculus-quest-2-review-features-photos"&gt;Quest 2&lt;/a&gt;, and Portal devices have seen surging sales all year as people shifted to remote work and virtual hangouts at home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dXvtXD"&gt;But it’s not all good news for Facebook looking ahead. The company says it will “continue to face significant uncertainty as we manage through a number of cross currents in 2021” in its earnings report, signaling concerns the company won’t be able to maintain the same pace of year-over-year growth as it enters the second half of 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hqOtX2"&gt;Unsaid in its report are privacy changes from Apple that could have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22180102/facebook-new-newspaper-ad-apple-ios-14-privacy-prompt"&gt;significant consequences for Facebook’s ad business&lt;/a&gt;, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/14/22174017/apple-app-store-new-privacy-labels-ios-apps-public"&gt;new mandated privacy labels&lt;/a&gt; and Apple’s upcoming plan to mandate app makers get user consent to track people on iOS devices. Earlier this month, Facebook’s WhatsApp &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22233257/whatsapp-privacy-policy-update-delayed-three-months"&gt;delayed a new privacy policy update&lt;/a&gt; that was sending users fleeing the app for competitors like Signal and Telegram. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OpWrtm"&gt;“At the same time, in the first half of 2021, we will be lapping a period of growth that was negatively impacted by reduced advertising demand during the early stages of the pandemic,” the company writes. “As a result, we expect year-over-year growth rates in total revenue to remain stable or modestly accelerate sequentially in the first and second quarters of 2021. In the second half of the year, we will lap periods of increasingly strong growth, which will significantly pressure year-over-year growth rates.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WW2smV"&gt;Facebook also continues to weather its fair share of public relations and platform moderation controversies surrounding misinformation, election interference, and the recent &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/21/22242616/facebook-refers-decision-suspend-trump-oversight-board"&gt;banning of former President Donald Trump&lt;/a&gt;. That is in addition to a new wave of US regulatory scrutiny punctuated last month by an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22158483/facebook-antitrust-lawsuit-anti-competition-behavior-attorneys-general"&gt;unprecedented Federal Trade Commission lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; seeking to unwind the company’s pricey acquisitions of Instagram and WhatsApp. But those issues appear to have little effect whatsoever on the company’s bottom line, for now. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253055/facebook-q4-2020-earnings-report-app-usage-record-user-numbers"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253055/facebook-q4-2020-earnings-report-app-usage-record-user-numbers</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-27T16:38:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-27T16:38:26-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla unveils redesigned Model S with new interior and 520-mile range option</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UlpeiW1S3fx-qvr2tnNMT8spIBc=/398x0:3122x1816/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68730354/Screen_Shot_2021_01_27_at_3.26.14_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Images: Tesla&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="l7PM7c"&gt;Tesla has just announced the first major redesign of the Model S since it &lt;a href="https://www.tesla.com/blog/tesla-motors-begin-customer-deliveries-model-s-june-22nd"&gt;launched the electric sedan in 2012&lt;/a&gt;. This new version, which starts shipping in March, has a refreshed exterior, a simplified interior, and the option for a more powerful powertrain that lets the car travel at least 520 miles and go from 0 to 60 miles per hour in under two seconds. Tesla says this makes it the “fastest accelerating production car ever made.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JiKiLU"&gt;Tesla’s Model X is also getting some touchups on the outside and the interior update, and there will be a version with that new powertrain, though the SUV’s refresh is not as extensive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="27sMyg"&gt;The new Model S has some light updates to the exterior of the car, including a standard large glass roof, but the biggest visual change is inside. Tesla has axed the portrait touchscreen in favor of one more like what’s found in the Model 3 and Model Y, though with far smaller bezels (like we’ve seen on the Cybertruck prototype). There’s also a stalkless U-shaped butterfly steering wheel, much like what we’ve seen in the forthcoming second-generation Roadster, and a screen behind the center console for rear-seat passengers. Unlike the Model 3 and Model Y, the new Model S still features a screen behind the steering wheel.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="w4rZ4j"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The first big overhaul since it launched in 2012&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="48aU1W"&gt;The new Model S starts at $79,990 for a “Long Range” dual-motor version that gets 412 miles of range. Or people can spend $119,000 for one with the new, more powerful “Plaid” powertrain that goes 390 miles with that sub-2 second 0–60 time. The “Plaid+” version with 520 miles starts at $139,000. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="NVdFRV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10306471"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="O124Wz"&gt;The Plaid and Plaid Plus versions have top speeds of 200 miles per hour, while the Long Range tops out at 155 mph. Tesla says that the Plaid versions should be able to do five times as many quarter-mile runs as previous Model S sedans, thanks to the new powertrain and the new heat pump that was developed for the Model Y.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nzDl5U"&gt;The new Model X retains the same exterior design but features the new landscape dashboard screen, butterfly steering wheel, and rear passenger screen. The new Model X starts at $89,990 for a Long Range dual-motor spec that has 360 miles of range, a top speed of 155 mph, and a 0–60 time of 3.8 seconds. Tesla is selling a version with the Plaid powertrain for $119,000 that gets 340 miles of range, has a top speed of 163 mph, and can get to 60 mph in just 2.5 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="G1XUJh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10306803"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2XW7ms"&gt;A Model S redesign has been rumored for years, with &lt;a href="https://electrek.co/2018/07/30/tesla-model-s-x-interior-refresh-exclusive-first-look/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Electrek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; posting allegedly leaked renders of the new interior all the way back in 2018. Tesla CEO Elon Musk threw cold water on the idea in 2019, though, when he tweeted “[t]here is no ‘refreshed’ Model X or Model S coming.” Tesla instead was constantly making minor improvements to both vehicles, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IMDwOv"&gt;But that tune started to change once Tesla started testing out a new powertrain in 2019 dubbed “Plaid” — which, much like the “Ludicrous” acceleration mode in Tesla’s cars, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mk7VWcuVOf0"&gt;is a &lt;em&gt;Spaceballs &lt;/em&gt;reference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KMoTmY"&gt;Musk said at Tesla’s Battery Day event in September 2020 that the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/22/21451723/tesla-plaid-model-s-available-2021-specs-price-battery-day"&gt;Plaid Model S would be coming in late 2021&lt;/a&gt;. But aside from the basic specs, and the addition of the car to its website, Tesla didn’t mention anything about a design refresh. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FcEeQK"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22252832/tesla-model-s-redesign-plaid-mile-range-interior-refresh"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22252832/tesla-model-s-redesign-plaid-mile-range-interior-refresh</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
