<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2020-12-29T21:06:49-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-29T21:06:49-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-29T21:06:49-05:00</updated>
    <title>A modder has made a Nintendo 64 that’s smaller than the original’s controller</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lEtrkVpycxjGdqBtAu1eLEJXr3g=/266x0:3095x1886/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68596051/Screen_Shot_2020_12_29_at_5.22.48_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: GmanModz&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4VMZZC"&gt;Taking an old console and making it as small as possible is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/8/29/21406254/nintendo-modder-custom-wii-game-cube-game-boy"&gt;a well-established tradition&lt;/a&gt; in the modding community, and there may be a new victor in the race to shrink the Nintendo 64 as far as possible (&lt;a href="https://www.inputmag.com/gaming/the-worlds-smallest-nintendo-n64-fits-in-your-pocket"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Input&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). GmanModz has cut down an N64 to the point where it’s smaller than a GameCube controller — and only slightly bigger than the cartridges it takes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jSb3T9P990VmOiyz3Wg3PIndG9Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22203745/Screen_Shot_2020_12_29_at_5.22.48_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: GmanModz&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The mod vs an N64 controller&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="IK5wdo"&gt;Yes, cartridges. This isn’t an emulator, this is an actual Nintendo 64 that was cut, soldered, and otherwise modded to fit into a handheld package, complete with screen, battery, and controls (the joysticks are from a Nintendo Switch, chosen for their diminutive size).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cWYQZi"&gt;At three and a half inches, the screen is smaller than what you’d be used to when playing an N64, and it has a resolution of 320 x 240. Making up the shell are two different plastics, with the back being more heat-resistant — an important consideration when you’re using a motherboard designed to be in a roomy home console.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A picture of a Nintendo 64 motherboard sitting inside a small case." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iyMZvkoj1yvSOBB4W5DSfjaXrHc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22203701/Screen_Shot_2020_12_29_at_4.52.24_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: GmanModz&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;In order to fit it into such a small form factor, the N64’s motherboard had to have all non-essential parts cut off.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="FLHDuC"&gt;The modder is no stranger to making portable versions of the console: they’ve also modded it into a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-vg6FyUwRzg"&gt;Game Boy Advance SP-inspired form factor&lt;/a&gt; (twice). For this mod, though, they gave themselves a challenge: don’t custom-design any boards. There are some third-party boards inside that were available on an online modding shop, but they weren’t made specifically for this build. GmanModz says that this was “to be fair” to the previous smallest N64 record holder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dapCXg"&gt;In the video showing off the project, GmanModz admits that it’s not the greatest portable Nintendo 64 experience. But that’s not really the point — the point was to make the smallest portable N64, and they apparently achieved that. “The battery life sucks, it’s uncomfortable to hold, but hey. It fits in my pocket. Does your N64?”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jfLWxk-SxUrZXK5tu_j-mpQwE6g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22203709/Screen_Shot_2020_12_29_at_4.57.28_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: GmanModz&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dB1OUN"&gt;As expected with such a small handheld, the battery only lasts about an hour and a half. But hey, if you’re gunning for &lt;a href="https://www.speedrun.com/sm64/run/yjlxg97z"&gt;a &lt;em&gt;Super Mario 64&lt;/em&gt; speed run record&lt;/a&gt;, that may be all you need.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/29/22205558/new-record-smallest-nintendo-64-mod-gmanmodz-cartridge-sized"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/29/22205558/new-record-smallest-nintendo-64-mod-gmanmodz-cartridge-sized</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-29T20:09:12-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-29T20:09:12-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple pulls iPhone app promoting secret parties during the COVID-19 pandemic</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Promotional screen from Vybe’s now-defunct website." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CsbSWkWPIVeJZdY-MbJIZU7ukNU=/56x0:1883x1218/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68595776/Screen_Shot_2020_12_29_at_6.49.57_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Promotional screen from Vybe’s now-defunct website.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="22RH97"&gt;An iOS app called Vybe Together that promoted private parties during the COVID-19 pandemic has been removed from the Apple App Store, had its account on TikTok banned, and scrubbed most of its online presence. The app’s creators told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that Apple was the one to take it off the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VsrEqQ"&gt;Vybe Together billed itself on TikTok and &lt;a href="https://archive.vn/8hzdS"&gt;its website&lt;/a&gt; as a place to organize and attend underground parties, using the tagline “Get your rebel on. Get your party on.” Organizers would have to approve everyone who wanted to attend, and the ones that got approved would receive the address two hours before the event. Most of these gatherings &lt;a href="https://coronavirus.health.ny.gov/travel-large-gatherings-and-quarantines#large-gatherings"&gt;would have been illegal&lt;/a&gt; under current US pandemic restrictions — which may explain why the app required you to submit a profile for approval before you were allowed on.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QzVH9NHHg-wBqGNIJ-Mvvg2V7cY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22203614/Screen_Shot_2020_12_29_at_7.23.24_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Screenshots from the iOS App Store page.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Y4zKNy"&gt;Calling a phone number on Vybe Together’s site connected &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; with someone who identified themselves as Albin, one of the app’s co-founders. They said that the app had a few thousand users, and that a few thousand additional applicants had requested access to it since the company started putting videos on TikTok. Applying involved submitting your Instagram handle and uploading pictures of you partying to the service, presumably to make sure that you weren’t someone who was going to spill the beans about the events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="USpxbc"&gt;Vybe Together largely had a low profile before today, although it was mentioned in at least one &lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/90s-theme-party-nyu-students-only-byob-rooftop-in-soho-tickets-121224360325#"&gt;EventBrite invitation&lt;/a&gt; to a New York party in September. It received wider exposure after &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; reporter Taylor Lorenz &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TaylorLorenz/status/1343994810714058753"&gt;critically tweeted&lt;/a&gt; screenshots of the website and described it as an app for “finding and promoting COVID-unsafe large, indoor house parties.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vaDIFu"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;They’re currently in the midst of promoting secret NYE ragers in nyc &lt;a href="https://t.co/dEIdwX1DKn"&gt;pic.twitter.com/dEIdwX1DKn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Taylor Lorenz (@TaylorLorenz) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TaylorLorenz/status/1343995285869977600?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 29, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LFeJXK"&gt;Vybe Together’s now-removed FAQ page acknowledged the danger of the pandemic, but it said the app was designed to promote “small gatherings” rather than “big parties.” (Smaller gatherings of people from different households can still spread the coronavirus, creating chains of infection that extend far beyond the original event, putting people who didn’t attend the party at risk.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Screenshot of the site’s FAQ reading “We are aware that Covid is a major health problem to the country, our communities, our friends and family. If we all could just be in isolation this could actually go away. Having large scale parties is very dangerous. That is why we don’t support that. But Vybe is a compromise, no big parties but small gatherings. We could be living, at least a little during these times with Vybe.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vtDgcG_MBxNFymFs33hVBfHOCwU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22203610/image.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="kfpRif"&gt;It’s unknown whether the app substantially contributed to people holding unsafe events, although it promoted “gatherings every weekend” — including an upcoming New Year’s Eve party — in a TikTok video. The Vybe Together app had only 25 ratings before being removed, and its Instagram page has under 1,000 followers. In a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, TikTok said the account on that platform had only 139 followers when it was removed. The app appears to have launched previously under the name Trendies, a name mentioned on its now largely empty Instagram page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o5Vl6Y"&gt;Vybe Together’s website also advertised a “Vybe House” for the 2021 Zamna Festival music event in Tulum, Mexico. The house’s pictures correspond to &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.airbnb.com%2Frooms%2F44358648%3Fsource_impression_id%3Dp3_1609270823_u1tYjuKvRoT1nTcp%26guests%3D1%26adults%3D1&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2020%2F12%2F29%2F22205298%2Fapple-tiktok-vybe-together-pandemic-underground-party-app-removed#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;an Airbnb listing&lt;/a&gt; for a rental called the Casa Remy Villa. However, the listing’s manager couldn’t confirm the existence of a “Vybe House” event to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “We have rented the villa to some influencers,” said the owner, who had “no idea” if any renters were linked to the app. “But they know parties aren’t allowed of any kind as they are forbidden by authorities during [the] pandemic, with the risk of shutting down the property and a huge fine.” The Airbnb host also notes that the Zamna festival was recently postponed to April — not the January dates listed on its website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nWuXh0"&gt;Vybe Together’s Instagram account now contains &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CJZbzlWFfC4/"&gt;a single text post.&lt;/a&gt; “Blown out of proportion by media,” it reads. “We DO NOT CONDONE LARGE GATHERINGS.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pIfgmW"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update December 29, 8:06 ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: The app’s creators have now clarified that Apple was the one to pull the app from the App Store.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/29/22205298/apple-tiktok-vybe-together-pandemic-underground-party-app-removed"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/29/22205298/apple-tiktok-vybe-together-pandemic-underground-party-app-removed</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-29T17:30:41-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-29T17:30:41-05:00</updated>
    <title>McConnell ties full repeal of Section 230 to push for $2,000 stimulus checks</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A backlit Mitch McConnell ominously addresses reporters" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TBhWlFUOKzKG-cMmpYmgupBEGmk=/0x0:4000x2667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68594391/1230144952.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Rod Lamkey-Pool/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ksQvgr"&gt;On Tuesday night, McConnell introduced a new bill tying increased stimulus payments to a full repeal of Section 230, according to &lt;a href="https://beta.documentcloud.org/documents/20438365-mcconnell-stimulus-offer"&gt;bill text obtained by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The bill comes amid new momentum for direct $2000 stimulus payments, and increasing pressure on party leaders to appease President Trump’s escalating demands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lWXpMz"&gt;Democratic party leaders criticized the inclusion of Section 230 repeal as an effort to scuttle stimulus talks. “Senator McConnell knows how to make $2,000 survival checks reality and he knows how to kill them,” Senate Minority Leader Chuck Schumer (D-NY) said in a statement Tuesday. “Will Senate Republicans go along with Sen. McConnell’s cynical gambit or will they push him to give a vote on the standalone [bill]?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2xMGRI"&gt;McConnell’s bid for a full repeal of Section 230 comes amid increasingly chaotic negotiating over the level of direct payments to be included as part of stimulus efforts. On Sunday, President Trump signed into law Congress’ $900 billion COVID-19 relief and government spending package that would provide $600 in stimulus payments to most Americans. &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/statement-from-the-president-122720/"&gt;In a public statement&lt;/a&gt; after signing the bill, Trump urged congressional leaders to hold a standalone vote on increasing direct payments to $2,000. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="6skZcg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:8777491"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SI5Ixc"&gt;By Tuesday morning, many Republicans who previously opposed the increased stimulus checks flipped to support of them alongside Democrats. In particular, both &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21754927/jon-ossoff-tiktok-snapchat-account-influencer-marketing"&gt;Georgia Senate runoff&lt;/a&gt; incumbents, Sens. David Perdue and Kelly Loeffler (R-GA), announced Tuesday that they would vote to approve the additional payments after days of sidestepping the question, creating a difficult position for McConnell. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l8TaJD"&gt;Sen. Josh Hawley (R-MO) said in a tweet Tuesday that the Senate has “got the votes” to approve the increased payments. But later that day, McConnell blocked a House bill that would provide $2,000 in stimulus payments to most Americans, citing the need to tackle higher payments alongside other issues raised by President Trum&lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/statement-from-the-president-122720/"&gt;p&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rcPfpm"&gt;In a floor statement made Tuesday, Senate majority leader Mitch McConnell (R-KY) linked a handful of unrelated policy measures to the future of the increased stimulus checks; amongst them, Section 230 of the Communications Decency Act, a law that shields tech companies like Facebook and Google from legal liability over the content users post on their platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fXMDZU"&gt;“During this process, the president highlighted three additional issues of national significance he would like to see Congress tackle together,” McConnell said Tuesday afternoon. “This week, the Senate will begin a process to bring these three priorities into focus.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CYG9WU"&gt;Even before the bill was introduced, some lawmakers feared the majority leader would use Section 230 as a poison pill to doom the broader package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yrN6LL"&gt;“That is an invitation for this entire effort to fall apart,” Sen. Chris Murphy (D-CT) said on the Senate floor Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c90SrW"&gt;In recent months, Trump has often used Section 230 as a negotiating tool to push forward other policy priorities or tie up unwanted legislation. Last week, Trump &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22197796/trump-ndaa-veto-section-230-defense-bill-facebook-twitter"&gt;vetoed the $740 billion National Defense Authorization Act&lt;/a&gt; (or NDAA), after complaints that the defense bill did not include a provision that would repeal Section 230. Sen. Bernie Sanders (I-VT) threatened Tuesday to block a Senate vote to override Trump’s NDAA veto if McConnell did not agree to open a standalone vote on $2,000 checks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oLWU5E"&gt;“Big Tech must not get protections of Section 230!” Trump said in a statement Sunday. “Voter fraud must be fixed!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4DKZi5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated 12/29/20 at 5:28 PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;A previous version of this article was published at 2:33PM ET under the headline “Section 230 has become a bargaining chip in ongoing stimulus talks.” The article was updated to its current form, including a new headline and timestamp, when full bill text became available.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="UxVdJ9"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/20438365-mcconnell-stimulus-offer/?embed=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="McConnell-stimulus-offer (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="905" style="border: 1px solid #aaa;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5RSkd8"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="TprYJ4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Everything you need to know about Section 230","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21273768/section-230-explained-internet-speech-law-definition-guide-free-moderation"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="EN6DgR"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/29/22204976/section-230-senate-deal-stimulus-talks-checks"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/29/22204976/section-230-senate-deal-stimulus-talks-checks</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-29T16:35:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-29T16:35:37-05:00</updated>
    <title>You can escape this room, but you’ll never escape Google Docs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/v8JsUKxpR7jx98iUokHTZ8kfkgk=/71x21:831x528/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68595059/Screen_Shot_2020_12_29_at_9.13.21_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mDFCyN"&gt;For anyone who’s been lucky enough to spend the majority of the pandemic working from home, the idea of escaping the room (or couch) that’s become a makeshift office is probably a relatable one. Enter this &lt;a href="https://news.avclub.com/escape-your-boredom-with-this-at-home-escape-room-made-1842427574"&gt;series of “escape rooms” built in Google Docs&lt;/a&gt;, that let you do just that, inside web software you’ve probably become far too familiar with. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AnthonyBLSmith/status/1343965296885981184?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1343965296885981184%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=about%3Asrcdoc"&gt;”Part 3” of the game was finally released today&lt;/a&gt;, but you’ll never fully escape using Google Docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D8VyEy"&gt;“Escape: A Game” by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AnthonyBLSmith"&gt;Anthony Smith&lt;/a&gt; is styled as a choose-your-own-adventure game set in a series of interlinked Google Docs. You “wake up” from a mysterious dream in a cabin room filling with smoke, and are tasked with getting out. “Part 2” has you do the same thing in a hotel corridor, and “Part 3” that just released today, I won’t spoil for myself or anyone reading this. We’ve seen &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/15/21324558/google-forms-virtual-escape-rooms-librarians-games-puzzles-homeschooling"&gt;other escape room games built in Google’s software before&lt;/a&gt;, but “Escape” has an odd, creepy charm that’s hard to deny.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Oo3i3AOzkaWQAJcxD_xVY5xeAHA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22203108/Screen_Shot_2020_12_29_at_12.30.11_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The first of many choices in “Escape: A Game”.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="TXRgeM"&gt;As cool as this all is, Google Docs is not the best place to play a game. Clicking links in Docs can require multiple clicks to actually take you somewhere else, and the new tabs quickly add up. I could tell my laptop was straining under the number of tabs I had open for cross-referencing clues and dialing the in-game phone. What is a nice benefit of playing in a collaborative word processor is the possibility to get help solving puzzles. Both “Part 1” and “Part 2” feature pages that pull double duty as guestbooks for people to leave their names, and help each other solve puzzles. You need to request access to edit the page for “Part 1”, but even without live edits, it’s still handy for hints. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5ItmMe"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JR0gwhfHCWg?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=150&amp;amp;start=150" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pi1xj9"&gt;The actual narrative early on in “Escape” is slim, but it leaves plenty of room to fill in the weirder edges with your own connections. For instance, for the entire time I played, I couldn’t shake the similarities between the game’s smoked filled cabin, and &lt;em&gt;Control&lt;/em&gt;’s “Oceanview Motel”. That &lt;em&gt;Control&lt;/em&gt; level featured an escape room-style puzzle and functioned as a liminal space in the game that you returned to multiple times. “Escape” lacks the cool visual aesthetics of &lt;em&gt;Control&lt;/em&gt;, but there’s some shared heritage in their weirdness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ATnO5x"&gt;I spent around an hour working through the first part of “Escape” and ended it with over 50 tabs open and a pretty weird YouTube history. I learned some facts about dentistry, grew frustrated with myself for not remembering all of the 151 original Pokémon, and became increasingly concerned that this was all a trick to get me to better understand how links work in Docs. All in all, it’s not a bad way to spend some time online&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uoqKf9"&gt;“Escape: A Game” can be played for free in Google Docs. &lt;a href="https://t.co/L5JZqy920k?amp=1"&gt;”Part 1“&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://t.co/TLZI1ggQfl?amp=1"&gt;”Part 2“&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1Pxn3DP-w3ohhS6DqWm7WD2zRGYn7Uw-bttUFgzlCNBY/edit"&gt;”Part 3“&lt;/a&gt; are available now for your puzzle solving pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22204917/google-docs-escape-room-game-series"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22204917/google-docs-escape-room-game-series</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-29T16:35:19-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-29T16:35:19-05:00</updated>
    <title>No, NFL player Russell Okung is not being paid in Bitcoin</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Carolina Panthers Training Camp" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kE4eRDFuoPvUOYzwL6ogU1bIhzo=/0x0:3196x2131/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68595057/1268340895.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Grant Halverson/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RXkw8T"&gt;“Panthers’ Russell Okung Becomes First NFL Player to Be Paid in Bitcoin,” &lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/panthers-russell-okung-becomes-first-nfl-player-to-be-paid-in-bitcoin"&gt;the headline proclaimed&lt;/a&gt; — and soon, ones just like it started sprouting up across the web, with sports publications, tech publications, and mainstream media outlets alike jumping to tell how the Carolina Panthers offensive lineman &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RussellOkung/status/1128149326943834113"&gt;finally fulfilled his spoken desire&lt;/a&gt; to get paid in cryptocurrency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="67uDbi"&gt;Unfortunately, the headline isn’t true. “Not accurate,” an NFL spokesperson tells me, adding that “his people are converting some of the money into bitcoin” after he gets paid in US dollars, just like every other NFL player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="gxC3xu"&gt;&lt;q&gt;More like “NFL player decides to spend half his salary on Bitcoin”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8mtSAF"&gt;Okung’s own team, the Carolina Panthers, also confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that teams pay their players in US dollars. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oQuhRW"&gt;By that standard, anyone can get their salary “paid in bitcoin” anytime they want: just go buy some bitcoin with your salary after it arrives, which is probably what the company that Okung is pumping — &lt;a href="https://strike.zaphq.io/"&gt;Zap&lt;/a&gt; — is hoping you’ll do when you see he’s repping it online. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ci2WqJ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Do it, now. &lt;a href="https://t.co/9eAJxcBxLi"&gt;pic.twitter.com/9eAJxcBxLi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— russ (@RussellOkung) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RussellOkung/status/1343941366024433665?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 29, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Kp8kG8"&gt;It’s not clear why Okung chose this particular startup to convert his paycheck (it does accept direct deposit), or why he’s tweeted &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RussellOkung"&gt;fourteen times this afternoon&lt;/a&gt; encouraging his followers to hop on board the bitcoin and Zap train. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="POH3o4"&gt;He doesn’t disclose any kind of relationship with Zap on Twitter, although Zap founder Jack Mallers &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JackMallers/status/1343961558196641796"&gt;does call him a “friend.”&lt;/a&gt; (Mallers didn’t respond to repeated requests for comment.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IybiVh"&gt;But even if Okung doesn’t have a deal of some sort with Zap, he would have some financial incentive simply by being a bitcoin investor — the more people get excited enough to buy gobs of bitcoin, the higher the price and the more his stake is worth. (Okung converted half of his $13 million salary to bitcoin, according to the &lt;em&gt;Coindesk &lt;/em&gt;report.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vHgQSS"&gt;To generate that kind of excitement, it helps to have headlines like “First NFL player to be paid in Bitcoin” spread around the web. It certainly sounds more intriguing than “NFL player decides to spend 50 percent of his salary on Bitcoin,” right? It’ll be interesting to see if any of those headlines change overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jiAvHY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tyUh41"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YfCBfO"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/29/22205181/nfl-russell-okung-not-paid-bitcoin-debunk-carolina-panthers-cryptocurrency"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/29/22205181/nfl-russell-okung-not-paid-bitcoin-debunk-carolina-panthers-cryptocurrency</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-29T16:18:20-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-29T16:18:20-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple loses early challenge in virtualization copyright claim</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WhBlzuFDWgPzYqzREkpMKgKDL4k=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68594967/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bQIxyi"&gt;Apple has lost an early challenge in its lawsuit against Corellium, a security firm that offers a virtualized version of iOS for security testing. &lt;a href="https://beta.documentcloud.org/documents/20438330-20656722-0-117887"&gt;Ruling on a motion for summary judgment&lt;/a&gt;, the judge presiding over the case has dismissed Apple’s copyright infringement claim over Corellium’s software, finding that Corellium’s use of Apple code constituted fair use. The judge deferred ruling on a separate Digital Millenium Copyright Act (DMCA) charge, but the result is still a significant setback for the iPhone manufacturer’s legal case. The news was first reported &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/12/29/apple-corellium-lawsuit/"&gt;by &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6tUUX4"&gt;In particular, the judge found that additional features within Corellium’s tool strengthened its case for fair use, particularly the ability to modify the kernel or observe and halt processes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7vvTFM"&gt;“Corellium makes several changes to iOS and incorporates its own code to create a product that serves a transformative purpose,” the judge wrote in his ruling. “Hence, Corellium’s profit motivation does not undermine its fair use defense, particularly considering the public benefit of the product.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GvbcNn"&gt;Crucially, the court didn’t dismiss all of Apple’s case. Apple has alleged that Corellium circumvented its authentication server and secure boot chain, among other measures, violating the DMCA’s ban on circumventing copy protection measures. Corellium also mounted a fair use defense against the DMCA charges, but the judge did not find it compelling enough to dismiss the DMCA allegations before a full trial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mpF69j"&gt;Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/16/20809109/apple-corellium-startup-company-lawsuit-court-virtual-iphone-software-copy"&gt;began its lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; against Corellium on copyright grounds in August 2019, adding alleged DMCA violations to the case &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/3/21047275/apple-corellium-dmca-lawsuit-copyright-research-jailbreak-security-copyright"&gt;the following January&lt;/a&gt;. Throughout the case, Apple has insisted that its purpose is “not to encumber good-faith security research, but to bring an end to Corellium’s unlawful commercialization of Apple’s valuable copyrighted works.” Still, the lawsuit has been alarming to many security firms who rely on Corellium products for iOS analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="82IFH4"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/6/21504715/google-v-oracle-supreme-court-hearings-android-java"&gt;The Oracle v. Google case&lt;/a&gt; has cast a heavy shadow over the trial, and is referenced several times in the ruling as a preeminent example of successful copyright claim over software. However, the judge ultimately found the case had little bearing on the specific allegations made by Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zqPPET"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/20438330-20656722-0-117887/?embed=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="20656722-0--117887 (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="905" style="border: 1px solid #aaa;" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/29/22205130/apple-corellium-dismissed-copyright-dmca-fair-use"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/29/22205130/apple-corellium-dismissed-copyright-dmca-fair-use</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-29T15:26:53-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-29T15:26:53-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple supplier Lens Technology accused of using forced Uighur labor</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CY-cFBGdj7HTZbhMFWp52ONzTFw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68594678/akrales_190914_3666_0010.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ShKwu3"&gt;A major Chinese supplier of consumer electronics components, Lens Technology, has been accused of using forced Uighur labor workers from the predominantly Muslim region of Xinjiang, China, according to a report from the Tech Transparency Project (TTP) shared with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k0TLGt"&gt;The report says Lens Technology — a gadget glass supplier to companies like Amazon, Apple, and Tesla — has used thousands of such workers as part of the Chinese government’s ongoing detention and forced labor campaign against the Uighur minority. &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/12/29/lens-technology-apple-uighur/"&gt;first reported TTP’s findings on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gZEGmg"&gt;TTP’s investigation cites &lt;a href="http://archive.vn/nCi0d"&gt;media reports from &lt;em&gt;Global Times of China&lt;/em&gt; and government records&lt;/a&gt;, which allegedly show Lens Technology was sent thousands of workers from Xinjiang to work in its factories in the Hunan province as part of a “poverty alleviation” program carried out by the Xinjiang–Suzhou Chamber of Commerce. TTP also cites an online video titled “Lens Tech Uyghurs celebrating National Day,” which shows hundreds of workers sitting on the ground outside a building with banners revealing the workers’ Xinjiang origin and their employment at Lens Technology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="pNj2kp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple has denied any role in or connection to China’s forced labor programs&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pyL02J"&gt;Many of these workers previously lived in indoctrination camps and are often forced to renounce Islam and learn Mandarin before they are transported to various factories throughout China, according to &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/09/24/world/asia/china-muslims-xinjiang-detention.html"&gt;extensive reporting on the crisis&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FCRNHY"&gt;Apple has denied any role in or connection to China’s forced labor practices, saying it regularly investigates its suppliers as part of its auditing process and has seen no evidence that Lens Technology has used such workers on Apple production lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A3wpns"&gt;“Apple has zero tolerance for forced labor. Looking for the presence of forced labor is part of every supplier assessment we conduct, including surprise audits,” Apple spokesperson Josh Rosenstock said in a statement. “Earlier this year we confirmed that none of our suppliers have Uighur workers from ‘pairing programs’ from Xinjiang on any Apple production lines.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4e51Re"&gt;The TTP report is consistent with that claim, as it only purports to show Xinjiang workers at Lens rather than working specifically on Apple components. Still, it’s an unsettling reminder of the limits of supply chain auditing efforts and how little is publicly known about many prominent tech suppliers, especially as the Chinese government resists efforts from outside independent agencies and human rights groups to investigate working conditions and labor practices in the country. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1A2dCY"&gt;Neither Amazon nor Tesla were immediately available for comment regarding contracts with Lens Technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DoIxwt"&gt;A major &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News &lt;/em&gt;investigation &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/alison_killing/xinjiang-camps-china-factories-forced-labor"&gt;published on Monday&lt;/a&gt; further revealed the extent of China’s campaign against the Uighur minority, including a look at the vast network of factories the government has built within its detention camps for putting imprisoned residents of Xinjiang to work. The investigation also cites an &lt;a href="https://www.aspi.org.au/report/uyghurs-sale"&gt;Australian Strategic Policy Institute report&lt;/a&gt; identifying nearly 100 companies with suppliers that have used Uighur workers outside the Xinjiang region who were forcefully relocated and placed in labor camps. The list includes high-profile brands like Apple and Amazon, as well as H&amp;amp;M, Nike, Nintendo, and dozens of others. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qwb1im"&gt;Outside of China, concern has steadily grown over government’s treatment of Uighurs, which began under the pretense of combating foreign extremism and promoting the values of the Chinese Community Party. Activists and human rights watchers have fiercely criticized the detention camps and forced relocation and work programs. More recently, such groups have called on companies like Apple to take more forceful stances against the abuses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cyufeq"&gt;The TTP report also says the focus on Apple is warranted because of the company’s role in allegedly lobbying against the Uyghur Forced Labor Prevention Act, a bill that would sanction US tech companies for connections to the Chinese government’s forced labor campaign, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/11/20/apple-uighur/"&gt;separate report from &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post &lt;/em&gt;published last month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/29/22204920/lens-technology-uighur-forced-labor-xinjiang-amazon-apple-tesla"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/29/22204920/lens-technology-uighur-forced-labor-xinjiang-amazon-apple-tesla</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-29T15:17:45-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-29T15:17:45-05:00</updated>
    <title>Boston Dynamics robots take over the dance floor in latest video</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XbhOcAe8ewo4gH6Sjf7iDPnwcC0=/100x0:1180x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68594629/Do_You_Love_Me.2020_12_29_15_04_30.0.gif" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="puhQG1"&gt;Boston Dynamics’ Atlas and Spot robots can do a lot of things: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/5/10/17341400/boston-dynamics-atlas-spotmini-robots-videos-autonomous-navigation"&gt;sprinting&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/24/20881385/boston-dynamics-atlas-gymnastics-routine-somersaults-split-leap"&gt;gymnastic routines&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2018/10/11/17964912/boston-dynamics-atlas-parkour-video-jumping"&gt;parkour&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/16/16667376/boston-dynamics-atlas-backflip-video-watch"&gt;backflips&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2018/2/12/17005060/boston-dynamics-robot-dog-open-door"&gt;open doors&lt;/a&gt; to let in an army of their friends, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tf7IEVTDjng"&gt;wash dishes&lt;/a&gt;, and (poorly) get &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/19/21144648/boston-dynamics-spot-robot-mass-state-police-trial-issues"&gt;actual jobs&lt;/a&gt;. But the company’s latest video adds another impressive trick to our future robotic overlords’ repertoire: busting sick dance moves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VSmUMh"&gt;The video sees Boston Dynamics entire lineup of robots — the humanoid Atlas, the dog-shaped Spot, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/28/18285923/boston-dynamics-handle-robot-updated-box-stacking"&gt;the box-juggling Handle&lt;/a&gt; — all come together in a bopping, coordinated dance routine set to The Contours’ “Do You Love Me.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gjZ7qGL8PLd1ZHKWOxxc9qoSrOk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22203026/Do_You_Love_Me.2020_12_29_15_04_30.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="kNEYtv"&gt;It’s not the first time Boston Dynamics has shown off &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2018/10/16/17983000/dancing-robot-boston-dynamics-video-spotmini-uptown-funk"&gt;its robots’ dancing skills&lt;/a&gt;: the company showcased a video of its Spot robot doing the Running Man to “Uptown Funk” in 2018. but the new video takes things to another level, with the Atlas robot tearing it up on the dance floor: smoothly running, jumping, shuffling, and twirling through different moves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g2ZdMj"&gt;Things get even more incredible as more robots file out, prancing around in the kind of coordinated dance routine that puts my own, admittedly awful human dancing to shame. Compared to the jerky movements of the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rVlhMGQgDkY&amp;amp;t=80s"&gt;2016 iteration of Atlas&lt;/a&gt;, the new model almost looks like a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1344019835341180930"&gt;CGI creation&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Yc4NHg"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This is not CGI &lt;a href="https://t.co/VOivE97vPR"&gt;https://t.co/VOivE97vPR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1344019835341180930?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 29, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="8KTJes"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Boston Dynamics’ robots are preparing to leave the lab — is the world ready? ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/17/20697540/boston-dynamics-robots-commercial-real-world-business-spot-on-sale"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="3Nmhiz"&gt;Boston Dynamics was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22167835/hyundai-boston-dynamics-aquisition-consumer-robotics"&gt;recently purchased by Hyundai&lt;/a&gt;, which bought the robotics firm from SoftBank in a $1.1 billion deal. The company was originally founded in 1992 as a spin-off from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, where it became known for its dog-like quadrupedal robots (most notably, the DARPA-funded BigDog, a precursor to the company’s first commercial robot, Spot.) It was bought by Alphabet’s X division in 2013, and then by Softbank in 2017. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CmHZDY"&gt;While the Atlas and Handle robots featured here are still just research prototypes, Boston Dynamics has recently started selling the Spot model to any company for the considerable price of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21292684/boston-dynamics-spot-robot-on-sale-price"&gt;$74,500&lt;/a&gt;. But can you really put a price on creating your own personal legion of boogieing robot minions? &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2020/12/29/22205055/boston-dynamics-robots-spot-atlas-handle-dancing-video"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2020/12/29/22205055/boston-dynamics-robots-spot-atlas-handle-dancing-video</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-29T12:53:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-29T12:53:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Brexit deal calls for DNA profiles to use a 20-year-old email app</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_ReXMQ7w1-Vlx5LUE_yEh1J_obw=/0x0:1200x800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68593780/netscape.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="js3fyr"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/25/world/europe/brexit-britain-european-union.html"&gt;mammoth, last-minute deal&lt;/a&gt; that will govern the United Kingdom and European Union’s trade relations going forward post-Brexit has been finalized in the nick of time. But some security researchers have noted some puzzling aspects of the deal, including mentions of the defunct, 23-year old Netscape Communicator email software and recommendations of outdated encryption standards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="rNEDLf"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Just in case you forget what Netscape Communicator 4.0 looked like ... &lt;a href="https://t.co/573xNdN3ZH"&gt;pic.twitter.com/573xNdN3ZH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Prof B Buchanan OBE (@billatnapier) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/billatnapier/status/1342935639663259648?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 26, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zKgRcw"&gt;The mention occurs in a series of regulations concerning “encrypt[ing] messages containing DNA profile information” between countries, which must be done using a &lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/glossary/term/Secure_Multipurpose_Internet_Mail_Extensions"&gt;specific set of encryption protocols&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="RuUFF4"&gt;The open standard s/MIME as extension to de facto e-mail standard SMTP will be deployed to encrypt messages containing DNA profile information. The protocol s/MIME (V3) allows signed receipts, security labels, and secure mailing lists... The underlying certificate used by s/MIME mechanism has to be in compliance with X.509 standard.... The processing rules for s/MIME encryption operations... are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T55DYM"&gt;the sequence of the operations is: first encryption and then signing,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="96WlXf"&gt;the encryption algorithm AES (Advanced Encryption Standard) with 256 bit key length and RSA with 1,024 bit key length shall be applied for symmetric and asymmetric encryption respectively,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sa81SU"&gt;the hash algorithm SHA-1 shall be applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U9Larj"&gt;s/MIME functionality is built into the vast majority of modern e-mail software packages including Outlook, Mozilla Mail as well as Netscape Communicator 4.x and inter-operates among all major e-mail software packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="bSJpBb"&gt;The actual impact of this on major day-to-day operations of either the EU or the UK will likely be small. Netscape Communicator is simply mentioned as an example of a “modern e-mail software package” that supports s/MIME (alongside &lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/office/encrypt-messages-by-using-s-mime-in-outlook-on-the-web-878c79fc-7088-4b39-966f-14512658f480"&gt;Outlook&lt;/a&gt; and Mozilla Mail). However, the use of outdated encryption standards is a bit more concerning, as &lt;a href="https://hackaday.com/2020/12/28/netscape-communicator-and-sha-1-written-into-brexit-agreement/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hackaday&lt;/em&gt; points out&lt;/a&gt; — the SHA-1 hash algorithm has effectively been broken &lt;a href="https://hackaday.com/2017/02/23/shattered-sha-1-is-broken/"&gt;as of 2017&lt;/a&gt;, while 1024-bit RSA encryption is vulnerable to brute force attacks by more powerful modern computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aGl43W"&gt;The language itself may be older than it looks. &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-55475433"&gt;As the BBC reports&lt;/a&gt;, the same text also appears on a 2008 EU document, which seems to indicate that the lawmakers cobbling together the massive 1,256-page treaty may have recycled some old text without reading it too closely. Indeed, as &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/billatnapier/status/1342935639663259648"&gt;professor Bill Buchanan&lt;/a&gt; (one of the first to notice the outdated requirements) commented to the BBC, “this looks like a standard copy-and-paste of old standards, and with little understanding of the technical details.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="odIQlQ"&gt;But even then, it’s not clear why the EU felt that Netscape Communicator 4 (an app last updated in 2002, and succeeded by several generations of Netscape apps by 2008, which had also &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; subsequently been discontinued in March 2008) was a useful email application to cite in a June 2008 bill. It’s entirely possible that the recycled 2008 text was itself borrowed from an even earlier time, back when Netscape was still relevant. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jZ1be9"&gt;None of this will likely shatter the state of the complex geopolitics between the European Union and the United Kingdom. If you’re going to crib old legislation, using outdated cryptographic standards or email apps for something like DNA results seems better than say, trade tariffs. But given the size of the Brexit deal and the impact it’ll have on the UK, the EU, and the entire international community, it’d be nice to see that it was founded on something a little stronger than Netscape Communicator 4. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/29/22204624/brexit-eu-uk-netscape-communicator-4-crytography-email-data-dna-trade-deal"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/29/22204624/brexit-eu-uk-netscape-communicator-4-crytography-email-data-dna-trade-deal</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
