<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-12T10:16:57-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-12T10:16:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T10:16:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s AirPods Pro are down to $200 at B&amp;H Photo and Best Buy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ADVaKJ741skd2nYKH2QlBnCa0F0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68805342/akrales_191030_3763_0446.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XWNZQd"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 12th, 10:05AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; When this was written, Amazon and Walmart were selling the AirPods Pros for $180. While this deal is no longer available, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1513304-REG%2Fapple_airpods_pro_with_wireless.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1731722683585155103" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best Buy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; are selling the devices at the lower price of $200. Also, be sure to check out our roundup of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals"&gt;&lt;em&gt;the best AirPods sales at any given time&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nolzBn"&gt;When it comes to true wireless earbuds, Apple’s AirPods Pro &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds"&gt;are possibly the best option out there&lt;/a&gt;. If you have been holding off on buying the AirPods Pro, hoping for a decent price drop, your time has come: Apple’s flagship wireless earbuds are just $200 at &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1513304-REG%2Fapple_airpods_pro_with_wireless.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1731722683585155103" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; right now. That’s $49 off the usual $249 price tag. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GLpNMN"&gt;While this is not the lowest price we have seen these earbuds go for, the AirPods Pro rarely gets marked down to anything lower than $190. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hm8acq"&gt;Among other advantages, the AirPods Pro offer a customizable fit that includes three different silicone ear tip sizes, making it easier for them to fit in your ears. The standard AirPods come with a “one size fits most” design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="04LGOU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vDBZb6"&gt;If you’re looking for a pair of AirPods but aren’t interested in the Pro model, Amazon currently has one of the better deals on the regular AirPods. For $110, you can grab &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PXGQC1Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a second-generation pair with a wired charging case&lt;/a&gt; (coupon applied at checkout). For $50 more, you can pick up a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PYLT6DN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;pair that includes a wireless charging case&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="uDyAc8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple AirPods Pro review: perfect fit","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"},{"title":"Apple AirPods second-gen review: even more wireless","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id="OOOVcw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278616/apple-airpods-pro-wireless-earbuds-deal-amazon-walmart"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278616/apple-airpods-pro-wireless-earbuds-deal-amazon-walmart</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-12T10:16:45-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T10:16:45-05:00</updated>
    <title>Spotify to let employees keep working remotely and now choose what country they work from</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jpCmHuQMEMTFOBy2bPcKWVFl7ys=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68809498/acastro_180213_1777_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="USol59"&gt;Spotify is jumping on the remote work bandwagon in a big way with an &lt;a href="https://newsroom.spotify.com/2021-02-12/distributed-first-is-the-future-of-work-at-spotify/"&gt;announcement on Friday&lt;/a&gt; that it will let its employees choose where they’d like work, both for their preference of coming into the office or staying mostly at home and their geographic location in the world. Spotify is calling the initiative Work From Anywhere and it describes it as a “new way of collaborating that allows Spotifiers to work from wherever they do their best thinking and creating.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JgfdRj"&gt;“Through this distributed-first mentality, we are giving employees the opportunity to elect a Work Mode—whether they’d prefer to work mostly at home or in the office—as well as their geographic location,” the company’s blog post reads. Spotify says it will implement the new options this summer, and the choice of how often, if ever, an employee returns to the office will be decided by the employee in conversations with their manager and team. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LPWU2S"&gt;As for the freedom to work for Spotify anywhere in the world, the company says it will let employees decide their location “with some limitations to address time zone difficulties, and regional entity laws in the initial rollout of this program,” reads a more &lt;a href="https://hrblog.spotify.com/2021/02/12/introducing-working-from-anywhere/"&gt;in-depth post on the company’s human resources blog&lt;/a&gt;. “If someone chooses a location that is not near a Spotify office, we will support them with a co-working space membership if they want to work from an office.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GqZb9x"&gt;Spotify’s decision comes on the heels of an announcement from Salesforce &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22275304/salesfore-remote-work-9-to-5-workday-is-dead-flex-coronavirus"&gt;earlier this week&lt;/a&gt;, in which the cloud computing giant said it would give employees the choice to work mostly from home from now on and also give workers more flexibility around their daily schedules for taking care of children or attending to personal matters. Scores of other major tech companies, include &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/facebook/2020/5/21/21265699/facebook-remote-work-shift-workforce-permanent-covid-19-mark-zuckerberg-interview"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/9/21508964/microsoft-remote-work-from-home-covid-19-coronavirus"&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;, have similarly announced major commitments to remote work and letting employees make their new COVID-era work environments permanent going forward, if they so choose. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22279951/spotify-remote-work-from-home-employees-choose-announcement"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22279951/spotify-remote-work-from-home-employees-choose-announcement</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-12T10:14:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T10:14:24-05:00</updated>
    <title>Nintendo’s new Mario-themed Switch is available now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bvgRQTxM0NLQWTBSTeifLDgYgTM=/486x0:5736x3500/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68808878/SM3DW_Lead.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Nintendo Switch Mario Red &amp;amp; Blue Edition | Image: Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QwoMeU"&gt;Alongside the release of &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Super-Mario-3D-World-Bowsers-Fury/dp/B08H9M7LDY?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Super Mario 3D World + Bowser’s Fury&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for the Nintendo Switch, several retailers have a Mario Red &amp;amp; Blue Edition Switch game console available for purchase. You can buy one right now at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1732041273955221131" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fnintendo-switch-mario-red-38-blue-edition%2F-%2FA-82242753%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, while supplies last. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vGb5kj"&gt;Similar to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/30/21116081/nintendo-animal-crossing-new-horizons-switch-unique-joy-con-colors"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing: New Horizons&lt;/em&gt;-themed Switch released last year&lt;/a&gt;, this limited-edition console stands out from other models, with the entire Switch and its accompanying accessories based on the outfit typically worn by the mustached plumber. Retailing for $300, the limited-edition Switch features an all-red console, a red dock stand, a pair of red Joy-Cons, a red casing around the screen, and a blue Joy-Con grip. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="AvudIO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10338949"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1HC5Y2"&gt;Additionally, for $300, the Mario-themed Switch also includes a screen protector and a special carrying case that includes various symbols associated with the &lt;em&gt;Mario&lt;/em&gt; franchise at no additional cost. The Nintendo Switch included with the bundle &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/17/20697601/nintendo-switch-new-model-battery-life-improvements"&gt;is the updated model&lt;/a&gt;, which includes two more hours of battery life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jg2C5x"&gt;If you are planning to buy this console, there are a few things to keep in mind. Firstly, the device does not include a copy of &lt;em&gt;Super Mario 3D World + Bowser’s Fury&lt;/em&gt;, despite both products having the same release date. Secondly, these limited-edition Nintendo Switch consoles tend to sell out quickly, and there’s no telling if and when it will be restocked. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="LAAGX7"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Super Mario 3D World + Bowser’s Fury is the best of Mario in one package","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22274990/super-mario-3d-world-bowsers-fury-review-nintendo-switch"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22278494/nintendo-switch-mario-release-date-where-to-buy-amazon-best-buy-gamestop"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22278494/nintendo-switch-mario-release-date-where-to-buy-amazon-best-buy-gamestop</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-12T10:13:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T10:13:16-05:00</updated>
    <title>In WandaVision’s new episode, somebody thinks of the children</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tqUADR4N25dUl1mJgA71HvNaN_E=/219x0:2517x1532/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68809465/Screen_Shot_2021_02_12_at_9.41.02_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Disney / Marvel Studios&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vc88pf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; is moving closer to its endgame, as SWORD clashes with Wanda, Vision continues to question his reality, and the mystery of who is actually behind the Westview Hex grows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cp1IQD"&gt;But as we get closer to getting those answers, &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; has also started to lay the groundwork in this week’s episode for whatever might come next, including hints at a new generation of Marvel superheroes that could pop up in future movies and shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Fucjw"&gt;&lt;em&gt;[&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoilers ahead for WandaVision’s sixth episode.]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="l7XRwj"&gt;Two of a kind&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="a8GAlm"&gt;The show may be called &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;, but taking the spotlight in this episode are the couple’s children Billy and Tommy, who jump to the forefront of the early 2000s &lt;em&gt;Malcolm in the Middle&lt;/em&gt;-style sitcom of the week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LxSkX6"&gt;The twins — born just a few episodes ago — have already aged into preteens and are starting to exhibit their own powers that match their comics counterparts, Wiccan and Speed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dvqNnE"&gt;The comics history of Wanda and Vision’s children is a complex one, to say the least. As my colleague Julia has alluded to in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/22/22243271/wandavision-episode-3-recap-explainer-mephisto-agatha-harkness-tommy-billy-sword"&gt;earlier editions of this column&lt;/a&gt;, Billy and Tommy were originally magical constructs that Wanda managed to bring to life (through a complicated plotline involving fragments of the soul of Mephisto, the Marvel equivalent of Satan). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DH1z5U"&gt;While those construct-children were eventually reabsorbed into Mephisto, Billy and Tommy eventually would return in later comics as members of the Young Avengers. But they weren’t quite the same iterations of the characters. Rather, they were “reincarnated” versions: &lt;a href="https://marvel.fandom.com/wiki/William_Kaplan_(Earth-616)#Powers_and_Abilities"&gt;William Kaplan&lt;/a&gt;, who adopts the name Wiccan and wields magical powers similar to Wanda, and &lt;a href="https://marvel.fandom.com/wiki/Thomas_Shepherd_(Earth-616)#Powers_and_Abilities"&gt;Thomas Shepherd&lt;/a&gt;, who bears similar speed powers as Pietro. (He goes by the rather original hero name of “Speed.”) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MQRurC"&gt;It’s those versions of the characters that &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; is beginning to allude to with its latest episode. Billy’s Halloween costume is a dead ringer for Wiccan’s comic attire, while Tommy’s Quicksilver-like quickness matches the abilities of Speed. Billy’s visions at the end of the episode appear to be hinting at his own magical abilities, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uIdSe9"&gt;That leaves one of the biggest questions surrounding &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;, though: are Tommy and Billy &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt;? &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zsfQNoNpeYRnTk8STxAWmJNCv-4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22299791/Screen_Shot_2021_02_12_at_9.39.07_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Disney / Marvel Studios&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id="nCjfbt"&gt;For the children?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="oVEyBV"&gt;The answer may lie in one of the subtler reveals in this week’s episode: what exactly is happening to the hundreds of inhabitants of Westview when Wanda is not around, and — as Vision highlighted last week — where are all the children? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hZSMav"&gt;It’s the recast Pietro (who, noticeably, seems to be suspiciously more aware of Wanda’s effect on the town than almost anyone else) who provides the answer. Whether consciously or not, Wanda was working to minimize her rewriting of the town’s inhabitants and the trauma it causes. The town residents’ lives still broadly resemble their own, with the children kept out of the picture until they’re needed. When Wanda and Vision aren’t around, everyone just sort of… stops. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hw0pJN"&gt;But given what we know of the Hex’s ability to rewrite reality for anyone who enters, it’s possible that Billy and Tommy aren’t just magical conjurings — they might be real children who have been recast as Wanda and Vision’s kids, similar to the reincarnated versions of the characters in the comics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CjptcL"&gt;But if Billy and Tommy are just ordinary Westview children, where does their magic and speed come from? &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IWaeio8-Q-Nn9rW1r3_fo-QpR5A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22299797/Screen_Shot_2021_02_12_at_9.39.50_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Disney / Marvel Studios&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Yc7UYy"&gt;Full spectrum&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="KUuImH"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; may have an answer to that question, though, through its hinting at the comic book destiny of Monica Rambeau. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QKPIZN"&gt;In the comics, Monica Rambeau isn’t just the daughter of Captain Marvel’s best friend; she’s a superhero in her own right, who gains energy-based superpowers as Spectrum after being exposed to extra-dimensional energy. It’s a similar origin to the lab results that Darcy reveals in this week’s episode, where Monica’s cells have begun to change on a molecular level as the only person to face repeated exposure to the Hex’s energy field. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UxOH0b"&gt;We already know that Wanda and Pietro’s powers came from exposure to the Mind Stone, and that Wanda herself has power enough to rival one of the Infinity Stones at this point. It’s not so hard to make the leap that Wanda’s own magical energy could confer superpowers of her own — powers that could be infusing Monica Rambeau &lt;em&gt;and &lt;/em&gt;Billy and Tommy, sowing the seeds for a new wave of Marvel heroes. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22279920/wandavision-episode-6-billy-tommy-wanda-vision-marvel-disney-streaming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22279920/wandavision-episode-6-billy-tommy-wanda-vision-marvel-disney-streaming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-12T10:05:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T10:05:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Switch continues its bestselling streak, but the PS5 is making more money</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZiMJ8mnO0tu-4hYeaccuOmWQ3qc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68809435/jbareham_180301_2346_nintendo_switch_0065_mario.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EKHbnw"&gt;The Nintendo Switch &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21562530/nintendo-switch-lite-sales-october-2020"&gt;continues to perform very well&lt;/a&gt;, selling the most units out of any other gaming hardware in the US in January, according to gaming analyst firm The NPD Group. But Sony’s PlayStation 5 still made more money last month, despite a more limited supply. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dib2a8"&gt;According to NPD’s January report, the Switch was the bestselling hardware platform in terms of units sold in January — the highest of any platform in that specific month since the Nintendo Wii in 2010. Despite this, Sony’s next-gen console earned the highest dollar sales total for the month of January, breaking the previous record set by the Nintendo Wii in 2009. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="bPtZS2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There are a few reasons why the Switch sold more units but made less money than the PS5&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="De9lcl"&gt;There are a few reasons why the Switch might have sold more units but made less money than the PS5. Most notably, the PS5’s starting price begins at $100 more than the Switch, with the digital-only PS5 retailing for $400 and the disc drive model retailing for $500.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="94F3UV"&gt;The PS5 has been out for nearly three months yet, just like the Xbox Series X / S, the PS5 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21451144/sony-ps5-preorder-microsoft-xbox-series-x-nvidia-rtx-3080-mess"&gt;has been &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; difficult to buy&lt;/a&gt;, with retailers mostly hosting online sales due to severe supply shortages. With no signs of retailers selling the PS5 in stores anytime soon due to the ongoing pandemic, the only way you can buy a PS5 from a retail store is to wait for another wave of PS5 restocks to appear online. But when they do, they typically sell out in minutes, and Sony’s strong numbers for the month suggest it’s going through its stock as fast as possible. NPD’s report makes no mention of Microsoft’s new Xbox consoles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DPMLOU"&gt;Nintendo’s console has been impacted by the pandemic, too, as the Switch was a bit difficult to find last spring, but supplies have remained relatively healthy since. The Switch has also seen restocks of the base console and various bundles, including limited-edition ones like the newly released &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22278494/nintendo-switch-mario-release-date-where-to-buy-amazon-best-buy-gamestop"&gt;Mario-themed bundle&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="wJJgaO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Nintendo Switch has been the US’s bestselling console for 23 straight months","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21562530/nintendo-switch-lite-sales-october-2020"},{"title":"Sony sold 4.5 million PlayStation 5 consoles last year","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/3/22263821/sony-earnings-q3-2020-ps5-launch-sales"},{"title":"The true price of a PlayStation 5 ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/6/22155611/price-ps5-xbox-series-x-nvidia-rtx-3080-3070-3090-3060-amd-rx-6800-xt-scalpers-ebay"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22279859/nintendo-switch-lite-ps5-sales-january-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/12/22279859/nintendo-switch-lite-ps5-sales-january-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-12T09:59:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T09:59:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>What’s on your desk, Sam Byford?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2pWo4F0WhuVxb7_PHHC3CqUS8aM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67665362/sbyford_201009_4236_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Two desks: one for work, one for gaming&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="6bAL14"&gt;While many of us moved to home offices when companies sought to avoid COVID-19 infection, for some people, working at home is the norm. One of those people is Sam Byford, Asia editor for &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, who works out of a home office in Tokyo, Japan.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QTK0w1"&gt;We talked to Sam to find out how he has equipped his own home office and to see whether it matters these days if your remote desk is five miles away or about 6,700 miles away from your organization’s main office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oNPFyX"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell us a bit about yourself and what you do at &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Verge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YJJM57"&gt;I’m from the UK, and I’ve been based in Japan since 2008 — first in Osaka, now in Tokyo, where I live with my wife and our dog and our bunny. I came on board &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; just as the site launched in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nd3R3G"&gt;I am now &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s Asia editor, which means two things really. I handle much of our Asia-specific coverage, of course, but I’m also an editor who happens to be in Asia, which is helpful from a time zone perspective. If critical news breaks after the US signs off and before Europe wakes up, or if someone needs an edit on a piece that we’re timing for the morning in the US, that’s often me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cprNPO"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That’s a great space you have. Was that an existing setup, or did you put it together once you knew you’d be working at home?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pLplso"&gt;I’ve been working from home for as long as I’ve been with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, but this is still quite a new setup. My wife and I moved into a bigger place at the end of last year, and it turned out to be good timing since we now both have our own offices and are both at home all day. I didn’t bring any furniture in the move and essentially started from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The “gaming” desk is on the left; the “working” desk is on the right." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DfDFcKiRZzUeDuXPzHtk98UusFo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21962383/sbyford_201009_4236_0001.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The “gaming” desk is on the left; the “working” desk is on the right.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="N2Fiis"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I didn’t expect to see two desks! It looks like one is for gaming and the other for working. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QqA09z"&gt;That is exactly what they’re for! In our last place, I had a giant integrated setup on a single L-shaped glass desk. But I found it impossible to keep things organized, and I never really felt like I was off work. With this room, I decided to abandon the idea of coherent, tasteful interior design and went for an unassuming wooden desk for my Mac with an ostentatious gaming setup on the left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4gofIQ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me about the desks themselves. Where did you get them, and how did you decide which ones to get?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A4Ni5F"&gt;They’re both from Rakuten, which often has a bunch of third-party sellers offering near-identical products of unclear origin. The wooden one is simple, but it has convenient storage and a shelf to raise the monitors. The gaming desk came from a seller called &lt;a href="https://fril.jp/shop/pandatech"&gt;PandaTech&lt;/a&gt;, and it has RGB lighting, a cup holder, cable management, a USB hub, a controller rack, a headphone hanger, and a fitted mouse mat. I’m not usually into the RGB-heavy gamer aesthetic, but I thought it’d be fun to lean into it as a way to create distinct spaces in the same room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bTHyCq"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did you choose your chair especially, or is that just something you had available?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dMxKir"&gt;It’s a &lt;a href="https://www.hermanmiller.com/products/seating/office-chairs/sayl-chairs/"&gt;Herman Miller Sayl&lt;/a&gt;, which is a common chair — Vox Media’s NYC office has hundreds of them. I bought one without arms, though, because it works a little better for my posture. I’m tall, and it’s hard to find chairs that don’t encourage me to slouch. Also, I like the red.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="pKyeVN"&gt;
&lt;div id="PkExq7"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10334604" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"brief_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="Zjwjav"&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid c-image-grid__odd c-image-grid__odd-first-wide"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Working tech" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LzfH_6H8RGJcGefbVbU41iPw1wk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21962380/sbyford_201009_4236_0003.0.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EI4qp4vOuGOkwRtEh9uES7ZZRP8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21962375/sbyford_201009_4236_0007.0.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Sam’s tech setup" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/I_N4wyvouTlMsO6YS9x6MLTCZMY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21962369/sbyford_201009_4236_0013.0.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sam’s tech setup.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QyZOCY"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is obviously going to take a while, but could you tell me about your tech setup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E7svGg"&gt;*deep breath* Okay, so my main work machine is a 2018 15-inch MacBook Pro. I basically never use it as a laptop unless I’m going to trade shows, which, for obvious reasons, I haven’t done since CES 2020, so I like this &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Brydge-Vertical-Dock-Compatible-Thunderbolt/dp/B089XXYY4L?ots=1&amp;amp;slotNum=12&amp;amp;imprToken=06bbc41e-9fc2-ae34-bd5&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;ascsubtag=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D21283231%5Bt%5Dw%5Bd%5DD" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Brydge vertical dock&lt;/a&gt; that turns it into a skinny desktop computer and saves a ton of space. I go through quite a lot of mechanical keyboards, but right now, I’m using a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Keychron-Bluetooth-Mechanical-Keyboard-Wireless-Keyboard/dp/B07QCP491R?ots=1&amp;amp;slotNum=13&amp;amp;imprToken=06bbc41e-9fc2-ae34-bd5&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;ascsubtag=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D21283231%5Bt%5Dw%5Bd%5DD" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Keychron K2&lt;/a&gt;, which is working out great. It’s comfortable to type on, looks good, and works seamlessly with macOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="0vfQXN"&gt;
&lt;div id="zBVltj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10334147" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"brief_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="mxoxQm"&gt;
&lt;p id="Y0Qmy8"&gt;The MacBook is hooked up to two &lt;a href="https://www.lg.com/us/ultrafine-monitors"&gt;LG UltraFine 4K&lt;/a&gt; monitors, the discontinued 21-inch model and the current 24 inch. Below them, there’s an &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-homepod%2Fhomepod&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21519190%2Fhome-remote-work-desk-setup-tech-monitors-lg-nikon-apple-nintendo#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple HomePod&lt;/a&gt; for music and Mac audio, and next to that is one of three &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/12/6/13843536/google-wifi-review-mesh-router-system-vs-eero"&gt;original Google Wifi routers&lt;/a&gt; we have around the apartment. The camera is a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nikon-FX-Format-Digital-Camera-Silver/dp/B00GD1KASM/?ots=1&amp;amp;slotNum=14&amp;amp;imprToken=e4bbc8a8-e67c-133e-d73&amp;amp;ascsubtag=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D21283231%5Bt%5Dw%5Bd%5DD&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nikon Df&lt;/a&gt;, which I use for most of my personal photography, and I also keep my &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1732031547999991806" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/a&gt; charging on this desk. There are a bunch of dongles, power cables, and wireless chargers in easy reach, plus my two current personal phones: an &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0875L51VV/?ots=1&amp;amp;slotNum=15&amp;amp;imprToken=e4bbc8a8-e67c-133e-d73&amp;amp;ascsubtag=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D21283231%5Bt%5Dw%5Bd%5DD&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;iPhone SE&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1732031699818461964" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Pixel 4A&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NAuzux"&gt;My gaming PC lives under the other desk, and it’s a custom build from 2016. The monitor is an &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/PG279Q-DisplayPort-Adjustable-Ergonomic-EyeCare/dp/B017EVR2VM?ots=1&amp;amp;slotNum=17&amp;amp;imprToken=e4bbc8a8-e67c-133e-d73&amp;amp;ascsubtag=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D21283231%5Bt%5Dw%5Bd%5DD&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Asus PG279Q&lt;/a&gt;, and the speakers are &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1557198-REG%2Fjbl_hksoundstick4whtam_harman_kardon_soundsticks_wireless.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21519190%2Fhome-remote-work-desk-setup-tech-monitors-lg-nikon-apple-nintendo#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Harman Kardon Soundsticks&lt;/a&gt;, which are also hooked up to my Sony record player across the room over Bluetooth. (I’m not an analog purist.) There’s an &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=43993&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oculus.com%2Fquest-2%2F&amp;amp;u1=vergewhatsonyourdesksambyfordrepub02112021" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Oculus Quest VR&lt;/a&gt; headset, a &lt;a href="https://www.thrustmaster.com/en_US/products/tca-sidestick-airbus-edition"&gt;Thrustmaster Airbus flight stick&lt;/a&gt;, and a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Neogeo-Arcade-Stick-Pro-Neo-Pocket/dp/B07XR9V88V?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Neo Geo Arcade Pro&lt;/a&gt; fight stick. There is a dedicated button on my gaming desk to cycle through the colored lighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="yk6ijX"&gt;
&lt;div id="pFhrnN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10318379" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"brief_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="OX4qvC"&gt;
&lt;p id="YZ3QPL"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And the Google Nest Hub?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4H5w5D"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://store.google.com/us/product/google_nest_hub_max"&gt;Google Nest Hub&lt;/a&gt; is a recent addition that I got for two specific reasons: to control my Hue smart lights and to keep an eye on Pascal, our unhinged Shiba puppy who spends most of the day upstairs and occasionally tries to destroy our living room. I have a cheap &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Security-TP-Link-KC120-Assistant-Chromecast/dp/B074WJPPCZ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;TP-Link Kasa&lt;/a&gt; camera hooked up, which does the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fkH4li"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That’s a great toy collection. Do you have any favorites?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PILspR"&gt;I would say the cacti, which come from an amazing &lt;a href="https://izushaboten.com/lang/"&gt;cactus-themed zoo&lt;/a&gt; (yes) near Mt. Fuji that my wife and I went to this summer. You can pick the cacti yourself and choose the pots to plant them in, and I like bears and dinosaurs, so.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Cacti, bears and dinosaurs" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4gUzFEfZJlXEhs1_BHEvIDZqz_4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21962370/sbyford_201009_4236_0012.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cacti, bears, and dinosaurs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="gX8Ql5"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Okay, I need to know about those polar bear basketball players hanging around your computer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7DX8wR"&gt;The bear is, for reasons I’m not sure I understand, the mascot character of a Japanese cosmetics brand called Smelly. There’s a store in Harajuku with a gacha machine featuring it in various poses, and I liked the basketball one, so I gave it a shot. Thankfully, it came out quickly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cJaKnN"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you do game playing on both desks? (I see controllers on the right-hand desk.)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yIVUtR"&gt;Not unless it’s work-related. The Switch just lives there on its charging dock, and those little handheld consoles are Game Gear Micros that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21519010/sega-game-gear-micro-review"&gt;I was in the process of reviewing&lt;/a&gt;. There aren’t really any situations where I’d play a game on a Mac when there’s a PC right next to it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NrQq4I"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you keep the world out while you’re working — or do you need to?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e91GMx"&gt;I get locked in pretty easily. The outside light is super bright in the mornings here, even on cloudy days, so I just close the curtains for a few hours and settle in. We live in a mostly quiet neighborhood, so the biggest distraction is our dog, really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="etA1nw"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I see you like basketball. (That may be putting it mildly.) Is there anything special about that poster?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sAajQl"&gt;My Torontonian wife got me into the Toronto Raptors soon after we met, and now I’m a big fan. This is a print of Kawhi Leonard scoring his &lt;a href="https://www.raptorshq.com/2019/5/12/18617092/2019-nba-playoffs-toronto-raptors-philadelphia-76ers-game-7-final-score-recap"&gt;iconic Game 7 buzzer-beater over the Sixers&lt;/a&gt; to send the Raptors to last year’s Eastern Conference finals on their way to the NBA championship. It’s a great, inspiring image that has taken on new meaning after Kawhi bounced to LA only to see his Clippers collapse embarrassingly in the playoffs this year. I should maybe get it framed or something, but honestly, I kind of like just having sports posters on my wall.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Toronto Raptors and an OK Computer CD cover" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T7uOzxXQuL4jaxz7Rpu7Azc_ZEI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21962372/sbyford_201009_4236_0010.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Toronto Raptors and an OK Computer CD cover.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="3UqKPe"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How about the small print on your wall?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OXuyAc"&gt;That’s an OK Computer CD cover signed by Thom Yorke from Radiohead. My dad used to be an obsessive autograph hunter, and back when I lived in the UK, we’d often go to gigs together, and he’d wait around for hours afterward to get things signed. Radiohead was one of my favorite bands as a kid, so it’s a neat thing to have that reminds me of home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cD5Nyh"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything you’d like to change about or add to the current setup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pDjLHP"&gt;I’m mostly good, but I don’t think my gaming PC is going to last very long once next-generation consoles with much better CPUs are on the market. So I’ll probably be looking to rebuild in a year or so. I would also love for Apple to make a version of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/2/21161487/apple-mac-pro-display-xdr-review-6k-lcd-screen-price-features"&gt;6K pro monitor&lt;/a&gt; that doesn’t cost $6,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FHeoqa"&gt;Also, I recently bought Belkin’s ridiculously named &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22265910/belkin-magsafe-3-in-1-wireless-charger-hands-on-iphone-12-watch"&gt;Boost↑Charge Pro 3-in-1 Wireless Charger with MagSafe&lt;/a&gt;. Charging Apple devices has gotten more complicated recently, at least for me. Now that the Apple Watch tracks sleep, I’ve been charging it with a messy cable at my desk for an hour or so when I start the day instead of overnight. And the iPhone 12 mini turns out to be too small for most stands — the charging coil isn’t high enough on the back of the phone. Belkin’s new charger solves both of those problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="xV3sGP"&gt;
&lt;div id="9cbGwe"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10338662" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"brief_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="KSoQ8l"&gt;
&lt;p id="O5FEUy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 11th, 2021, 5:15PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article was originally published on October 21st, 2020. Several links and prices have been updated, and the Belkin Wireless Charger has been added.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WSiBuq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21519190/home-remote-work-desk-setup-tech-monitors-lg-nikon-apple-nintendo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21519190/home-remote-work-desk-setup-tech-monitors-lg-nikon-apple-nintendo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-12T09:51:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T09:51:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best AirPods deals you can get right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Xuyyq2uKdLAhw_sX1Ij4bBYJxio=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67012056/cwelch_191031_3763_0003.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Apple’s AirPods Pro wireless earbuds | Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="V9cZCU"&gt;Apple AirPods are among the most popular headphones on the market. They’re compact, easy to pair with your devices, and offer reliable connectivity, which can sometimes be a problem with truly wireless earphones. So there’s a chance that you might be looking for a deal on them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OR97R2"&gt;Surprisingly, they’re no stranger to the occasional price cut. There are often discounts on even the more expensive AirPods Pro, which offers noise cancellation and better sound than the standard second-generation model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eJ0Ffb"&gt;We’ll run through all three of the current models below, including the standard AirPods, the more expensive AirPods that include a wireless charging case, and finally, the AirPods Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZuVjFm"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Apple AirPods 2 review: even more wireless|63428" data-volume-uuid="c798b260f" data-volume-id="63428" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-125" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="VFDHZw"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AirPods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="R1mQdI"&gt;These are Apple’s entry-level wireless earbuds. They are a reliable pair of wireless earbuds with a one-size-fits-most design. The AirPods usually retail for $160, which is not a bad price, but this model frequently gets discounted.  You can currently find Apple’s most affordable AirPods for $110 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Charging-Latest-Model/dp/B07PXGQC1Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. You can also get them for $120 at &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Charging-Case-Latest-Model%2F604342441&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, or $130 at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1731722633239801630" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-airpods-with-charging-case%2F-%2FA-54191097%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Evae3q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yHjw-MSSOE9krvMa6cC9qYmHU9s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15993019/akrales_190327_3315_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="PK1JRu"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AirPods (with wireless charging case)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ImEUfP"&gt;The AirPods with wireless charging case are identical in every way to the standard AirPods, save for one: their charging case can be charged on a Qi wireless pad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rYNUWv"&gt;You’ll need to provide your own wireless charging pad to take advantage of this feature (if you have no use for it, just get the more affordable option above), but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/this-is-my-next/2017/10/27/16554680/best-wireless-charger-qi-ravpower-samsung-anker-mophie"&gt;even the best ones are fairly inexpensive&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="glqkTs"&gt;Most of the time you can find this version for less than Apple’s sticker price of $199, but keep a lookout for deals that bring the price down to $160 or below. You can get them for $160 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Wireless-Charging-Latest/dp/B07PYLT6DN/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=4781ccd9dac6fb8bf9e60c657cd3fbba&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/979838/2092?sharedid=verge&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-airpods-with-wireless-charging-case%2F-%2FA-54191099"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OGXtAu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9507432"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="Uv43TD"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="AirPods Pro review: the perfect earbuds for the iPhone|73652" data-volume-uuid="c840e1e11" data-volume-id="73652" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-842" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="eG2fnz"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="s9Ofwq"&gt;Apple’s high-end truly wireless earbuds, the AirPods Pro, have better sound quality than the other models described above, include noise cancellation, and now support Apple’s new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/2/21498931/apple-spatial-audio-airpods-pro-surround-sound-quick-auto-switching"&gt;spatial audio feature&lt;/a&gt;. We think &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds"&gt;they’re the best wireless earbuds that iPhone owners&lt;/a&gt; can buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yaMGwU"&gt;The AirPods Pro are frequently available for less than their $249 retail price, and in fact, sometimes drop down to $200 and lower. Right now, if you don’t mind buying refurbished, they are &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1730154636955201273" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$190 at Best Buy (Geek Squad Certified)&lt;/a&gt;. If you want a new pair, the lowest price you can get them for currently is $200 at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1731722683585155103" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1513304-REG%2Fapple_airpods_pro_with_wireless.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;. if those deals run out, the next best price is $220 at &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-airpods-pro%2F-%2FA-54191101&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YdTSzD"&gt;If you want to get an Apple Care Plus protection plan for your wireless earbuds, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1570785-REG%2Fapple_airpods_pro_with_wireless.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21302051%2Fbest-apple-airpods-deals#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H is selling a bundle that includes both for $278&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TuBiVT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FDsE87"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c9yAKy"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-12T09:40:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T09:40:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>Can anyone moderate podcasts?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8GNBKxPzyfWnRSux98ffiUcF70A=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68809253/VRG_4403_002.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Apple, Spotify, and the impossible problem of moderating shows&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="Pr108d"&gt;When former White House adviser-turned-podcaster Steve Bannon called for the beheading of Dr. Anthony Fauci and FBI director Christopher Wray, the tech platforms reacted. Twitter, YouTube, and Spotify all banned him and his podcast relatively quickly, cutting off access to their millions of users. Apple Podcasts, however, took a different stance. The most popular podcast app let his show stay live in its directory so that, months later, when Bannon encouraged his listeners to converge on the Capitol to protest election results, people still had an easy way to access his thoughts. His show, even this week, ranks among Apple Podcast’s top 20 news podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="70vBDw"&gt;A story from &lt;a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/twitter-and-youtube-banned-steve-bannon-apple-still-gives-him-millions-of-listeners"&gt;&lt;em&gt;ProPublica&lt;/em&gt; in January&lt;/a&gt; pointed out the dangers of not moderating someone like Bannon. It’s reasonable to want Apple to not benefit from clearly harmful voices, but the incident speaks to how unprepared the podcast industry is to moderate: companies face huge challenges in even finding infringing content, and there’s little to no transparency from the big players in how they monitor the listings in their apps. Plus, people in the space have real, philosophical concerns about the extent to which podcasting’s open ecosystem should be policed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JYVFZ1"&gt;A disparate network of companies makes up the podcasting world, including apps, hosting services, sales teams, and networks. Moderation will need to happen across these companies to be effective, and in this current moment, that effort doesn’t work the way it does at tech monoliths like Facebook, Twitter, or YouTube, which can remove someone with a push of a button. Put simply, podcasting isn’t ready for full-scale, widespread moderation — if that’s even what the industry wants. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FwweYa"&gt;“There’s no podcasting company that has the scale, or the reach, or the resources, to be able to do anything like [that],” says Owen Grover, the former CEO of Pocket Casts, when asked whether he thinks the podcasting ecosystem could monitor shows like Facebook does the posts, images, and videos on its platform. “If the podcasting industry cares about this stuff ... it’s going to require multiple organizations that exist across the industry value chain.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="fCRH34"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The fractured nature of podcasting makes it hard to moderate&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Z8NYq4"&gt;Moderation isn’t a simple task, and even platforms like Facebook and Twitter routinely get it wrong. Audio presents an even tougher challenge. For one, new content rapidly streams into the space. A report published this month from podcast marketing company &lt;a href="https://chartable.com/blog/2020-year-in-review"&gt;Chartable says&lt;/a&gt; 17,000 shows launch weekly, and to moderate them would mean scanning audio, whether that be with actual human ears, transcripts, or software, and then discerning whether they cross the line. This assumes the companies in the space even care to moderate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0G6si4"&gt;“It’s quite hard to do it at scale,” says Mike Kadin, founder and CEO of the podcast hosting platform RedCircle. “We would have to transcribe everything, maybe, and apply some automated filters to look at everything. A: that’s expensive, and B: even if we could get everything in text, I don’t think a computer can understand the nuance of some of these issues, so it’s super challenging, and we do the best we can.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8RXGqg"&gt;Even in high-profile moments, the industry has been slow and inconsistent about moderation. It should have been easy to ban shows from the notorious conspiracy theorist Alex Jones in 2018, for example, but it took weeks to build out even an incomplete blockade across the industry. Spotify started out by removing specific episodes, with Apple Podcasts removing his shows a week later. After that point, a constellation of smaller podcast apps made their own decisions on whether Jones deserved a ban.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VoVjgh"&gt;These efforts didn’t even remove the podcasts entirely. &lt;em&gt;The Alex Jones Show&lt;/em&gt; is still available today on Google Podcasts and smaller apps like Castbox, and the open nature of RSS means you can still listen to his shows inside of Apple Podcasts and other apps where it’s banned if you seek it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="f8bVR2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;You can still add the RSS feed for ‘The Alex Jones Show’ to Apple Podcasts&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BihxEh"&gt;All of which is to say, one of the most high-profile podcast deplatforming incidents wasn’t even wholly effective, which doesn’t bode well for a future of podcast moderation in which people want apps to take a heavier hand. Now, QAnon podcasts &lt;a href="https://www.mediamatters.org/qanon-conspiracy-theory/qanon-flourishes-podcast-hosting-platform-podbean"&gt;are flourishing&lt;/a&gt; on at least one hosting platform, Podbean, which also hosts Bannon’s podcast, and outright fraud &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/29/18097381/apple-podcast-charts-click-farm-advertiser-revenue"&gt;has occurred&lt;/a&gt; on Apple’s podcast charts. Copycat podcasts have also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/14/21436713/anchor-copycat-podcasts-mike-mignano-spotify-upload"&gt;sprung up on Anchor&lt;/a&gt;, Spotify’s podcast creation software. The industry isn’t catching every show that passes through its systems, meaning the problematic programming lives on until someone points it out, forcing the companies to respond. In other cases, the apps and hosting providers either struggle to find these programs or don’t care enough to bother with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bC6eI4"&gt;This speaks to the core of podcasting’s moderation issues, and the industry’s selling point for many: its open nature. Podcasts are distributed through RSS feeds, which are essentially a link to a list of episodes. Most apps (apart from Spotify, Audible, and Amazon Music) effectively serve as search engines for these feeds. As long as a show is hosted online somewhere, it can generally show up in these apps when someone searches for it. Apple, in particular, plays an integral role in the space because it gives smaller podcast apps the ability to incorporate its catalog, meaning Apple’s moderation decisions ripple throughout the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tlq0ky"&gt;But because the ecosystem is diffuse and multiple podcast indexes exist, most companies end up having to make moderation decisions themselves. The teams’ jobs become easier if a particular program gains the mainstream media’s attention — as Jones’ did — because the team then knows what they’re looking for. But doing their own, preemptive moderation work is tough, if not nearly impossible because day-to-day operations often involve small groups with limited resources. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="x3BZq5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;If the big platforms can’t find every problematic show, how can smaller teams?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sqPoUe"&gt;One podcast app creator, Xavier Guillemane, who made the popular Android podcast player Podcast Addict, says he fills his catalog with shows both from Apple Podcasts and The Podcast Index, a podcast search engine. He relies on user reports for moderation, and if he receives a report, he first checks Apple Podcasts and Google Podcasts to see if the show is listed there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sjWHj4"&gt;“If it is then it means that the content does not violate their content policies,” he says over email. “If not, then I make sure that this podcast isn’t visible in any popular / suggested lists. That’s all I can do for moderation as I’m developing this app alone. With more than 2 million podcasts available, and with podcasts available in every language, there’s nothing more I can do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q9BFVP"&gt;Grover echoed this idea, saying user reports were mainly how Pocket Casts policed its catalog. Those reports weren’t always reliable, however. “Signals from listeners are not always a good way to go because I will tell you that the whole notion of libertarian, do not censor — these things are powerful currents inside of podcasting,” he says, adding that many users saw the Jones removal as censorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T7uMvp"&gt;Apple and Spotify, the two largest podcast players, each have their own set of community guidelines. Both platforms don’t allow content that encourages violence, for example, or shows that infringe on copyright. Spotify &lt;a href="https://www.spotify.com/us/legal/spotify-for-podcasters-platform-terms/"&gt;even specifically prohibits&lt;/a&gt; programs that promote pyramid schemes, while Apple &lt;a href="https://itunespartner.apple.com/podcasts/articles/podcast-requirements-3058"&gt;doesn’t allow&lt;/a&gt; Nazi propaganda “as restricted by local law.” Like most terms, though, it’s hard to grasp how moderation would work in practice, and both companies are cagey about how exactly they moderate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EXw9wt"&gt;Spotify, which also owns one of the biggest podcast hosting platforms, Megaphone, issued a statement for this story saying Spotify uses a “variety of algorithmic and human detection measures to ensure that content on our platform is in keeping with our long-standing policies.” Apple Podcasts spokesperson Zach Kahn declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="7oUjWe"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Every podcast app has its own content guidelines&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5sVQWv"&gt;Beyond the listening apps, podcast hosting platforms, like Podbean, also play a key role in moderation. While they don’t necessarily care about distribution, they’re the ones keeping podcasts live and available. In the past, hosting services haven’t been at the center of the moderation debate, but when Amazon Web Services &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/9/22222637/amazon-workers-aws-stop-hosting-services-parler-capitol-violence"&gt;booted Parler&lt;/a&gt;, a chat app known for far-right material, off its servers, it emphasized the critical role these hosts play. Podcast hosting platforms have a particular incentive to moderate when they help shows make money, or sell ads for them, because brands generally don’t want to advertise on a controversial show. Otherwise, the hosting platforms don’t have much reason to rein in their own customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WGSQm8"&gt;At RedCircle, the team needs to moderate because it monetizes its users’ shows, but because the company only employs 11 people, Kadin says they can’t listen to or check out every program that joins the hosting service. Instead, the team reviews the shows that are the most popular each week to make sure they’re within the company’s content guidelines, including copyright, and also to ensure they’re receiving proper account support from RedCircle. Meanwhile, Spreaker, a company that’s now owned by iHeartMedia, uses algorithms and a 10-person team to review shows, says Andrea De Marsi, the company’s COO. They mostly focus on the shows that Spreaker monetizes through its advertiser marketplace and try to avoid taking sides on political rhetoric, so long as a podcaster doesn’t say or do anything illegal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Du8OLl"&gt;RedCircle says it’s caught some issues itself, like a neo-Nazi podcast that employed obvious imagery while Spreaker has removed dangerous propaganda creators, like ISIS, because of reports they received from law enforcement agencies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K48cLK"&gt;Even Podiant, a podcast hosting platform that &lt;a href="https://podiant.co/us/"&gt;prominently advertises itself&lt;/a&gt; as a team of “compassionate liberals,” doesn’t have the bandwidth to screen new customers and mostly monitors shows based on user reports. “It’s a really tricky task, especially at the hosting level,” says Podiant founder Mark Steadman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2Rg52a"&gt;Acast, another major hosting provider, says it’ll soon be publishing community guidelines for its service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lP5Xog"&gt;“This topic is something Acast takes very seriously, and we know we have a responsibility to constantly learn and work on new ways to support podcasters, listeners and advertisers alike,” says Susie Warhurst, SVP of content at Acast in an email statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="wWVwNn"&gt;Ultimately, It’s the bigger companies that will have the most say in how moderation happens in podcasting. But because of the system’s open nature, there’s only so far the biggest company, Apple, can go in policing its platform. Asking it to remove a show from its directory is like asking it to make a specific webpage inaccessible in Safari — is that something people want? Podcasting has, so far, avoided crowning one platform as king, meaning anyone, both on the creator and business side, can enter the space and possibly find success in it. That’s what makes podcasting great, even if it requires unclear answers on moderation.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22273071/podcast-moderation-apple-spotify-podbean-steve-bannon"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22273071/podcast-moderation-apple-spotify-podbean-steve-bannon</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-12T09:35:13-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T09:35:13-05:00</updated>
    <title>Snag a set of Beats Flex at Amazon for $40, the lowest price yet</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Apple’s new Beats Flex earbuds, pictured in yellow." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2ThVRReB02YwRCh4hDzqt5mDMNQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68809232/BF904AC7_A371_4D8E_B0A9_0CA38299CBD9.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZBJT59"&gt;The Beats Flex wireless earbuds &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08L6ZYW21?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;are $10 off at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; in the black or neon green colorways. This might not sound like a big price cut, but this is a fifth off the total cost since they’re normally $50. You can read up on everything that makes them a solid purchase with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21522700/beats-flex-wireless-earbuds-review"&gt;Chris Welch’s review&lt;/a&gt;, but the notable highlight is that they’re just as good to use with Android phones as they are with iPhones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="faCdH3"&gt;This is the first set of Beats headphones with a USB-C charging port, and the Android app makes for easy configuration. If you have an iPhone, these have Apple’s W1 wireless chip to make them easy to pair to your phone, Apple Watch, or iPad. For the low cost, the sound quality is better than I expected, and they ship with a few different-sized silicone tips to help you find a better fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9mCCVD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9591203"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BPPEDF"&gt;Apple’s fourth-generation iPad Air was released last year, and despite a higher price tag compared to its predecessor, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s Dieter Bohn thinks this Apple tablet is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21525780/apple-ipad-air-2020-review"&gt;the best for most people&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re looking to pick up this midrange iPad, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08J6FD94H?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon is currently selling the 64GB model with Wi-Fi only for $540&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1EnrYz"&gt;This is the lowest price we have seen on this iPad Air model to date. If you want a bit more storage, the 256GB storage configuration with Wi-Fi is back down to its best-ever price of $699 at Amazon if you buy this model in &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08J63W44Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;green&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08J6FTH75?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;rose gold&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08J6FVJMX?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;sky blue&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9WCN93"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9546269"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5dc_cEVQG8ReG9H8ktIPmMo-H7M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19897857/mchin_200413_3971_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Vu6iY1"&gt;Dell’s eBay store is selling a new, high-end, rose gold-colored configuration of the 2020 XPS 13 at a steep discount (via &lt;a href="https://slickdeals.net/f/14831167-dell-xps-13-i7-16gb-uhd-2020-model-999-99?attrsrc=Test%3AjfyProvider%3AControl%7CFeature%3AisPersonalized%3Atrue&amp;amp;src=jfy%7Crecombee%7C92e99d9e76e0b64ef1a24d2ab1993e0a"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slickdeals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Normally $1,700, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Frover.ebay.com%2Frover%2F1%2F711-53200-19255-0%2F1%3Fmpre%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fwww.ebay.com%252Fitm%252F224289851806%253FViewItem%253D%2526item%253D224289851806%26campid%3D5338421468%26toolid%3D20008&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F2%2F12%2F22279812%2Fapple-beats-flex-earbuds-ipad-air-dell-xps-13-deal-sale-ebay-amazon#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;it costs $1,000&lt;/a&gt; to get the model with a 4K touchscreen, Intel’s Core i7-10710U processor, a fast 512GB NVMe SSD, and 16GB of RAM. It also has two Thunderbolt 3 ports. Check out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/15/21221003/dell-xps-13-2020-review-core-i7-specs-features-price"&gt;my colleague Monica Chin’s review here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="59jGE2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10339606"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3uUswGTfXDjBo1d2bi7tRD5stoY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21920561/502515ee2c7e0520348.13650686_13S_Announce_2.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7N9zS1"&gt;Sony is hosting &lt;a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/category/b81cc589-d207-44dd-81ad-a63e15e05790/1"&gt;several “Big in Japan”-themed discounts&lt;/a&gt; on digital game downloads on the PlayStation Store, but the deal that sticks out is on &lt;a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP0177-CUSA19610_00-BSTUBCUSA1961000"&gt;&lt;em&gt;13 Sentinels: Aegis Rim&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from Vanillaware. It’s only $30, down from its usual $60 price. It’s a PS4-exclusive title (compatible on PS5, of course), and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21493208/13-sentinels-aegis-rim-ps4-review-vanillaware"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s games editor Andrew Webster says&lt;/a&gt; playing it is like binge-watching an amazing, ambitious sci-fi drama. I guess I’m picking this one up today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="qY9zxB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="DuToWA"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DhJ1Jc"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ec8hU4"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/2/12/22279812/apple-beats-flex-earbuds-ipad-air-dell-xps-13-deal-sale-ebay-amazon"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/2/12/22279812/apple-beats-flex-earbuds-ipad-air-dell-xps-13-deal-sale-ebay-amazon</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-12T09:24:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T09:24:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to score a COVID-19 vaccine appointment </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_u2r1v0qpkmDCofvfzLEcU6WDG4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68809161/acastro_201217_1777_vaccine_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DzZXIa"&gt;One of the most frustrating tasks for many of us these days is finding how and where to get an appointment for a COVID-19 vaccination. It can be a real exercise in exasperation: the websites are often difficult to navigate and prone to frequent crashes; in addition, after finding an open appointment slot and filling out multiple pages of questions, you are often told that the opening has disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Vp4Bt"&gt;In view of all this, we’ve tried to gather as much helpful information as we can about ways to research and snag vaccination appointments for yourself and others. We’ll update this as more information presents itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="JYv8ZW"&gt;Research the vaccination qualifications in your state&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="jJJ2mU"&gt;To begin with, it’s a good idea to try to pin down if you or the person you are assisting is currently qualified for the COVID-19 vaccine. Find the vaccine information site (or sites) that is being run by your state and / or city. This will also help you figure out when you might be qualified if you aren’t already. If you can’t find it via a quick search, &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/specials/plan-your-vaccine/"&gt;NBC News has created a simple website&lt;/a&gt; that lets you find out what the current situation is in your specific state. &lt;a href="https://www.goodrx.com/covid-19/where-to-get-covid-19-vaccine"&gt;Prescription company GoodRx&lt;/a&gt; offers similar information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="N5dWHX"&gt;Find all the places that might offer appointments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="XK1Cc0"&gt;There are, fortunately or unfortunately, many different sites where you can go to find out if you can get an appointment to be vaccinated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dgvDmn"&gt;For example, here in New York City, we’ve had to navigate separate sites run by the city and the state. Various hospital systems also have their own sites, as do pharmacies such as Walgreens and CVS, which have recently begun offering appointments for vaccinations. It’s a lot to check — and it can be enormously confusing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="usTdFX"&gt;As a result, your first step is probably to check your state’s government health website (searching your state name and “COVID vaccine” will probably do it). If you’re an urban dweller, check for your city’s information site as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H8ot2F"&gt;While most personal physicians do not have access to vaccines, your doctor may be able to tell you some of the places to check. Other resources include your local hospital system, your union (especially if your employment qualifies you for a vaccination), and, of course, friends and colleagues, many of whom have probably been doing their own searches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WZ6Bfn"&gt;As you find resources and sites, make sure to bookmark them. I keep a folder on my bookmarks bar called “COVID” — you may want to name yours something more cheerful.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Looking for an available vaccine appointment can be frustrating, but persistence can pay off." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8lP4_R3np2CX9crqTcg9Mq6I2Js=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13963741/IMG_1653.1419968302.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Looking for an available vaccine appointment can be frustrating, but persistence can pay off.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="6uguNM"&gt;Have all your information ready&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="1Dt0LZ"&gt;Many of us who have tried to register for vaccination appointments have gone through the experience of filling out several screens of information only to find that, by the time we got to the end, the appointment was gone. So it’s a good idea to have all your data — such as your name, age, address, insurance info, and the registration ID / password for the site — immediately at hand. The faster you can go through the registration process, the more likely you are to actually get an appointment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tRD8jU"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; colleague Cory Zapatka says that he highly recommends using a password manager if you have one. He created accounts with all the vaccination sites in his area, even if they didn’t have appointments available at the time, so that if / when the time came, he could just auto-fill and get in right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q9bBlc"&gt;And if you do get an appointment, make sure you have the appropriate paperwork already handy — especially since available appointments can be last minute. Necessary paperwork could include proof of employment, proof of age, or proof of a qualifying condition. Since the last one may require a doctor’s note or other record, it’s a good idea to call your doctor now — or if you’ve got access to a doctor’s or hospital website, that may offer you access to the proof you need. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5dqUcf"&gt;One more thing: check to see if you’ve gotten all the email that has been sent to you by your vaccine supplier. At least one staff member of &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; found a necessary consent form hiding in her spam folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="wCK4vB"&gt;Watch for news of upcoming vaccination sites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="bDlWg4"&gt;Keep an eye on the news. More and more sites and hubs are being added as the US gears up for a stronger push. If you see a news item saying that a hub is about to open, find the site for the hub and keep checking — once it does open, the available slots will probably go quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rz172X"&gt;One thing that sometimes helps is to look for patterns in the appearance of new appointments. For example, when I heard that the pharmacy chain Walgreens was going to begin giving out vaccines in my area, I spent a couple of days going onto the site, and suddenly realized that there was a pattern: the company was only scheduling appointments two to four days in advance and was adding new appointments each day just after midnight. Once I understood the pattern, I was able to get appointments for a couple of friends, and let others know about it as well. (Note: since vaccine supplies and scheduling methods can change on a dime, this particular strategy may no longer work by the time you read this.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Sites like the NYC Vaccine List can help by gathering together available resources in one place." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FsRia6ki1VqiuNodQvjKHdK9-ek=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22299690/Screen_Shot_2021_02_12_at_8.47.56_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sites like the NYC Vaccine List can help by gathering together available resources in one place.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gz26d4"&gt;Look for help online&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="PgrwN8"&gt;There are a number of online resources popping up headed by developers and other technology-savvy folks who have taken the time and effort to try to make sense of this confusion. (Thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/02/10/covid-vaccine-appointment-websites/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/09/nyregion/vaccine-website-appointment-nyc.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for some of these listings.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Vhk2GI"&gt;A NYC site called &lt;a href="https://www.turbovax.info/"&gt;TurboVax&lt;/a&gt; pulls “the latest appointments from 43 city and state-run vaccine sites in the NYC area” and puts them on Twitter. Followers who set their Twitter notifications for &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/turbovax"&gt;@turbovax&lt;/a&gt; can quickly find out about newly opened appointment slots. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="c0AX5B"&gt;Another called &lt;a href="https://nycvaccinelist.com/"&gt;NYC Vaccine List&lt;/a&gt; uses a combination of scripts and checks by volunteers to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/31/22256167/covid-vaccine-website-nyc-appointment"&gt;scour various sites for openings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="111Dwk"&gt;In California, &lt;a href="https://www.vaccinateca.com/"&gt;VaccinateCA&lt;/a&gt; checks pharmacies and hospitals for information about open appointments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZYJAS8"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://vaccinatenj.com/"&gt;Vaccinate NJ&lt;/a&gt; also uses volunteers to try to help state residents find vaccine opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZJic26"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.covid19vaccinetx.com/"&gt;Covid 19 Vaccine TX&lt;/a&gt; is a crowdsourced resource for registering with local counties and finding locations where vaccines may be available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WLYqtL"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.macovidvaccines.com/"&gt;MA Covid Vaccine Appointments site&lt;/a&gt; offers lists of and links to sites with available appointments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="nhHjOx"&gt;By the way, if you’re a developer and / or coder who wants to help, check out &lt;a href="https://www.usdigitalresponse.org/"&gt;US Digital Response&lt;/a&gt;, an independent organization which, according to its website, “connects experienced, pro-bono technologists with local government and non-profit organizations responding to crisis.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Reservation Of The Anticovid Vaccine For Over Eighty In Apulian Pharmacies" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4leCSmB_jTd6jhw7V_SvQQsfQ8Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22299704/1231117569.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Davide Pischettola / NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are able, it’s a good idea to reach out and help those who may not be able to get appointments on their own.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="8mSy40"&gt;If you can, help others&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Kz9AlN"&gt;One of the worst things about the distribution of the COVID-19 vaccines is that those who need it the most are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22227531/covid-vaccine-website-appointments-accessible-seniors"&gt;often the least likely to be able to navigate the technology required to get an appointment&lt;/a&gt;: older people, differently abled people, or those who don’t have or can’t afford computers and / or internet connections. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W2VOR9"&gt;If you have the time and talent, reach out to anyone you know who may not be able to get an appointment on their own. This could be as simple as finding phone numbers they can call to try to schedule an appointment, going online and getting an appointment for them, or helping them get to and from the vaccination site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Evm4o5"&gt;You could also see if there are any groups that are organizing help. &lt;a href="https://www.westsiderag.com/2021/01/19/need-help-signing-up-for-a-vaccine-a-young-tech-savvy-person-can-help-you"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The West Side Rag&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, for example, reports that a group of New Yorkers created the &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScO11RAr7tqHU6LJp_ZNMl5mRbxdg-zc1lO1SuVHBBDLTyJrg/closedform"&gt;Vaccine Appointment Assistance Team (VAAT)&lt;/a&gt; to help their non-technically-savvy neighbors navigate the process. (At the time this was written, because of low supplies of vaccine, VAAT had temporarily suspended their services.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="rm5plO"&gt;Look for leftover vaccine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="M5v0nn"&gt;While the vaccines can last for six months while they’re kept frozen, once thawed and refrigerated, the Pfizer vaccine will last five days while the Moderna vaccine will last for 30 days. As a result, when people don’t show up for their appointments, some centers will &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/22229169/leftover-vaccines-random-people-grocery-stores-pharmacies"&gt;offer vaccinations to those who may not immediately qualify&lt;/a&gt; rather than waste vaccines that would otherwise be rendered unusable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EI3933"&gt;However, running to a nearby pharmacy or vaccine hub in the hit-and-miss hopes that there will be some shots waiting at the end of the day isn’t the most effective way to be vaccinated. (Besides, getting hypothermia while waiting in the cold isn’t going to help.) At least one group is trying to ameliorate the situation: a pilot project called &lt;a href="https://vaxstandby.com/"&gt;Vaccination Standby&lt;/a&gt; says that it will monitor providers around the US for word of extra doses and text notifications to those whose zip codes are near the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nAc3tM"&gt;There are also local organizations that are offering standby lists. For example, Buncombe County in North Carolina has a &lt;a href="https://www.buncombecounty.org/countycenter/news-detail.aspx?id=19137"&gt;vaccination waitlist and standby list&lt;/a&gt;, as does the &lt;a href="https://www.co.monroe.in.us/egov/documents/1611179705_09719.pdf"&gt;Monroe County Health Department&lt;/a&gt; in Indiana. Check your local government site to see if there’s one in your area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Fg3eNk"&gt;Be persistent!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="JTTPvK"&gt;Yes, it’s frustrating as hell, but keep at it. If a website crashes, try again. If you’re dropped from a phone call, call again (and have a game, video, or book ready to keep yourself occupied while you’re on hold). If you can’t find anything during working hours, try late at night or very early in the morning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cBXxUO"&gt;Persistence may be one of the most important aspects to getting an appointment for a COVID-19 vaccination. You may be tempted to give up, especially after hitting the “no appointments available” wall time and time again. But until vaccine production is ramped up enough to cover more of our population, and until distribution becomes more organized and easier to manage, simple stubbornness may be your best tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lwiVs8"&gt;And hopefully this article, and all the advice it contains, will soon be unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZwQk0g"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c0F1RM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22279023/covid-19-vaccine-appointment-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22279023/covid-19-vaccine-appointment-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
