<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2020-12-29T05:55:09-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-29T05:55:09-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-29T05:55:09-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple Watch leak offers rare glimpse inside Apple’s ‘Ultra security program’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hJ6xDvcK8RnWY2LKRoPbUs4a1jQ=/23x0:1177x769/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68591953/EqXuTU0XMAE7gPC.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/AppleDemoYT" target="_blank"&gt;Apple Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dgl2PV"&gt;New images and video purporting to show an Apple Watch prototype, concealed by a security case that resembles a tiny iPod, offer a rare look behind the product-development curtain of the notoriously secretive company built by Steve Jobs. First &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/9/4/20975197/apple-watch-prototype-tiny-ipod-security-case-rumor"&gt;teased a few months ago&lt;/a&gt; by Twitter user &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AppleDemoYT"&gt;Apple Demo&lt;/a&gt;, this is our first look at the device turned on and running Apple’s own internal development apps on a pre-watchOS 1.0 software build. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4d5lGV"&gt;The video starts by showing what appears to be the original cardboard packaging used to deliver the prototype hardware to testers. “This product is classified as Apple Confidential and is designated an ‘Ultra’ security program,” reads the label. “This prototype MUST be returned when recalled or when your,” says the labelling before being obscured to hide the origins of the device. A sticker on the back of the prototype device itself shows it’s a “PVTe” configuration, which presumably means Prototype Validation Testing (engineering) in line with language seen on previous Apple development hardware, like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/19/18263844/apple-iphone-prototype-m68-original-development-board-red"&gt;leaked EVT board for the original iPhone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_UgFiIdYthbyTUri0Q3neG8-EMg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22202075/CONFIDENTIAL.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/AppleDemoYT" target="_blank"&gt;Apple Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The original cardboard packaging used to ship the prototype hardware to testers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="mDsr6Y"&gt;When the touchscreen device is turned on, we can see that it’s configured to show Apple’s own internal apps. One is the “Lisa tester,” identified with an icon of Lisa Simpson but likely a tribute to Jobs’ daughter and namesake of Apple’s Lisa computer — one of the first computers to feature a GUI interface. The app lets testers tweak the UI elements of the prototype Watch. The “Springboard zoom” app found inside the Lisa Tester is very similar to the original watchOS home screen that shipped on the first Apple Watch in 2015. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="owrfCR"&gt;There’s no Digital Crown for navigation. Instead buttons along the right side of the case can be used for home and power. The Home button on the front and what appear to be volume up/down buttons on the left are never shown being used and might not be functional. When clicking into settings, the device reports that it hasn’t received FCC approval for sales, adding additional confirmation of its prototype status. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XDtg6TUcRZrFFGaioEH528X3sdE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22202077/EqNaCxJXUAIB_DN.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/AppleDemoYT" target="_blank"&gt;Apple Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The “Lisa tester” is accessible via the Lisa Simpson icon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fIT3EZ"&gt;Assuming the prototype is real — and it definitely seems that way — then it’s a remarkable example of a pre-production Apple device we were never meant to see.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/29/22204270/apple-watch-pvt-ultra-security-program-prototype"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/29/22204270/apple-watch-pvt-ultra-security-program-prototype</id>
    <author>
      <name>Thomas Ricker</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-28T22:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-28T22:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>LG’s new ‘QNED’ TVs will have up to nearly 30,000 tiny LEDs behind the screen</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TCVKEeqJNBCtuKInA9OdnPpvRWA=/88x0:1882x1196/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68591325/LG_QNED_grab.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;LG’s new QNED TV uses Mini LEDs as the light source.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: LG&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XGvhhb"&gt;LG might be the company that’s most synonymous with OLED TVs, but tonight it’s announcing what to expect from its LCD-based sets in 2021. Like other manufacturers including TCL have already done (and &lt;a href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/excited-first-samsung-mini-led-tvs-are-just-around-the-corner/"&gt;Samsung is expected to soon join in on&lt;/a&gt;), LG is adopting Mini LED technology for its premium LCD 8K and 4K TVs coming next year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4maltP"&gt;LG says Mini LED allows for “a giant leap forward in LCD TV picture quality.” The best LCD TVs today have what’s called “full-array local dimming,” where LEDs — in some cases hundreds of them — serve as the backlighting behind the screen. These can be controlled in zones, and each zone can be dimmed as appropriate for dark scenes, which helps improve black levels and contrast. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HmtF53"&gt;Mini LED changes up the strategy a bit by using much smaller LEDs (but way more of them) for greater contrast than TVs that might top out at a couple hundred dimming zones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TLh67F"&gt;In LG’s case, the company says its new backlight “comprises up to almost 30,000 tiny LEDs that produce incredible peak brightness and a contrast ratio of 1,000,000:1 when paired with up to 2,500 dimming zones and advanced local dimming zones.” The end result is better contrast, more dynamic HDR, and improved color accuracy over the company’s prior LCD sets. Like all of LG’s 2020 flagships, refresh rates of up to 120Hz are supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y6RNTN"&gt;LG has branded these upper-end LCD TVs as “QNED,” with the Q referring to quantum dot color and the N presumably standing for LG’s “NanoCell” branding. It comes off a little awkward — especially since TV shoppers will have to contend with a mix of OLED, QLED, and QNED TVs when at their local Best Buy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vaUQE7"&gt;The closest comparison for LG’s QNED TVs would be &lt;a href="https://www.tcl.com/us/en/products/home-theater/8-series"&gt;something like TCL’s 8 Series&lt;/a&gt;, which contains 25,000 LEDs in around 1,000 control zones. (LG says the QNED will come in sizes up to 86 inches, which is the one I’m guessing those earlier numbers come from.) TCL’s 6 Series also uses Mini LED, though the total number is much lower than the pricey 8 Series.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eKQT1XArFgVCa3K1JEqmthTKZDQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22201617/Screen_Shot_2020_12_28_at_9.02.59_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: TCL&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Shrinking the LEDs allows TV makers to use many more of them for greater contrast and better blacks.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="uyyZJ8"&gt;But as the leading OLED TV brand, LG is being careful to underline that OLED is still where the absolute best picture can be had — even with all these advancements on the LCD side. 2020 saw Vizio enter the OLED TV field and try to undercut LG on price, but LG isn’t about to easily give up its position at the top. (Sony also makes high-end OLEDs; all three companies use panels from LG Display.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KXiZoZ"&gt;Last, don’t make the mistake of mixing up Mini LED with MicroLED. Think of Mini LED as another evolution of LCD TVs, whereas &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22166062/samsung-110-inch-microled-4k-tv-announced-features"&gt;MicroLED is a more radical upgrade&lt;/a&gt; that removes the backlight from the equation altogether (just like OLED) and combines millions of self-emissive LEDs that only light up when they’re needed. MicroLED TVs are still outrageously expensive, and while we won’t know pricing for LG’s QNED TVs for a few more months, it should be much less eye-popping.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203910/lg-qned-mini-led-4k-8k-lcd-tv-announced-ces-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203910/lg-qned-mini-led-4k-8k-lcd-tv-announced-ces-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-28T20:44:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-28T20:44:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>Coinbase halts trading of XRP following SEC suit against Ripple</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Cryptocurrency 2018" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VD2hgCexv4DyaQhcuJCFJSJoGDk=/3005x0:5000x1330/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68591099/1035974108.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Yu Chun Christopher Wong/S3studio/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5JQuZf"&gt;Coinbase announced today that it is halting all trades of XRP on its cryptocurrency exchange, according to &lt;a href="https://blog.coinbase.com/coinbase-will-suspend-trading-in-xrp-on-january-19-2e09652dbf57"&gt;an official blog post&lt;/a&gt; (via &lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/coinbase-suspends-xrp-trading"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Coindesk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Certain kind of trades became restricted today, and the full suspension will go into place January 19th, 2021 at 10:00AM PT. Coinbase is the largest cryptocurrency exchange, and suspending a currency like XRP naturally casts doubt on the currency’s future, even before the SEC lawsuit over it is settled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qDQK9S"&gt;Coinbase says it made the decision to suspend XRP “in light” of the suit the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) filed against XRP’s original creator, Ripple. With the suspension in place, people will no longer be able to trade XRP on Coinbase, though they will still be able to deposit and withdraw from their XRP wallets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ACHqmx"&gt;In the suit that started it all, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22196064/ripple-sec-cryptocurrency-security-currency-xrp"&gt;the SEC’s main concern is what an XRP actually is&lt;/a&gt;. The SEC claims XRP is a security and should be treated as such. That means Ripple’s former CEO and current CEO should have been responsible for disclosing a variety of additional information necessary to access the risks of XRP before anyone invested. Ripple, of course, believes the opposite. In Ripple’s opinion, XRP is a currency, and so it doesn’t fall under the jurisdiction of the SEC. For more on why it matters what XRP is called, check out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22196064/ripple-sec-cryptocurrency-security-currency-xrp"&gt;my colleague Liz Lopatto’s piece&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8FwZLw"&gt;Coinbase is the highest profile exchange to suspend XRP, but other exchanges like &lt;a href="https://www.bitstamp.net/article/xrp-trading-and-deposits-be-halted-us-customers/"&gt;Bitstamp&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://blog.okcoin.com/2020/12/28/suspension-of-xrp-trading-and-deposits-on-okcoin/"&gt;OK Coin&lt;/a&gt; have made similar decisions following the SEC’s legal action. With the simple announcement of a lawsuit, the SEC has already impacted the short-term future of XRP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="VfGbN6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Congratulations, the US got you cryptocurrency regulation for Christmas ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22195834/cryptocurrency-fincen-regulations-private-wallets"},{"title":"‘I was told I don’t have the right brain’: Read the NYT’s damning report on Coinbase ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21722972/coinbase-black-racial-discrimination-new-york-times"},{"title":"Coinbase says it halted more than $280,000 in bitcoin transactions during Twitter hack ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/20/21331499/coinbase-twitter-hack-elon-musk-bill-gates-joe-biden-bitcoin-scam"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203761/coinbase-halts-trading-xrp-ripple-sec-suit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203761/coinbase-halts-trading-xrp-ripple-sec-suit</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-28T20:35:02-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-28T20:35:02-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google inexplicably takes away wide-angle astrophotography from Pixel phones</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The regular and ultrawide cameras" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PJxqta9Egd54-qSYt-TzfF1WArQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68591078/akrales_201013_4137_0225.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ILFVCu"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21514312/google-pixel-5-review-camera-speed-processor-fingerprint"&gt;Pixel 5&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21514296/google-pixel-4a-5g-review-camera-speed-video"&gt;4a 5G&lt;/a&gt; users can no longer use their ultra-wide cameras to take pictures of the stars: Google apparently removed the lens’s astrophotography capabilities with the Google Camera 8.1 update. The feature was a selling point of the Pixel 4, and was available on the regular and telephoto cameras. When the 4a 5G and 5 were announced with new wide-angle lenses, the feature was added to those as well. Now it’s been taken away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vAOoxZ"&gt;The astrophotography feature lets users capture the night sky by pointing their phone up and keeping it still, either by balancing it on a nearby object or putting it on a tripod. The feature is still available on the phones’ other cameras, but if you go to Night Sight mode and switch to the ultra-wide angle camera you’ll now get a warning saying “Zoom to 1x for astrophotography.” Before the update it would say “Astrophotography on.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kQhXLN"&gt;Google didn’t respond to our request for comment asking why it had made the change, but it did update its &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/googlecamera/answer/9708795"&gt;low-light photography support document&lt;/a&gt; to add the following caveat: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="iUEaWQ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important&lt;/strong&gt;: On Pixel 4a (5G) and Pixel 5, astrophotography only works on zoom settings equal to or greater than 1x.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="FuOwKU"&gt;Taking a look &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://support.google.com/googlecamera/answer/9708795?hl=en"&gt;at the Wayback Machine&lt;/a&gt;, we can see that this change occurred some time between November 1st and November 7th. It’s slightly odd timing given that the update wasn’t released until &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2020/11/12/google-camera-8-1-redesign-older-pixel/"&gt;a couple of days later&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A screenshot of a forum post comparing the two camera’s results in astrophotography mode." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Wfb47QYI6FZzfUdkNLdLBexrYEQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22201553/Screen_Shot_2020_12_28_at_5.18.58_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google Pixel Phone forum user’s posted comparisons of the ultra-wide (top) and standard angle lenses shooting in astrophotography mode.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="GkZWAI"&gt;For an explanation as to why the feature may have been cut, you can check out &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/thread/83061074?hl=en"&gt;this thread on Google’s Pixel Phone Help forum&lt;/a&gt;. It has examples from two users, showing the results astrophotography mode produced on the Pixel 5’s regular camera, compared to what the ultra-wide lens put out. I’ll let you judge the pictures for yourself. The forum post, however, is another bit of timing weirdness — it was made days after the update removing the feature had already started rolling out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HT4rtz"&gt;Given that the update was out for a month and a half before most people really started noticing that the feature had been removed, it may be obvious why Google thought it could get away without mentioning it in the changelog. Even if it’s a feature that won’t be missed by many, it still stands as a reminder that software features used to advertise a phone may be subject to change (just like the Pixel’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21562908/google-future-pixel-phone-no-unlimited-photos-storage-confirmed"&gt;unlimited original quality storage in Google Photos&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203782/google-removes-wide-angle-astrophotography-pixel-4a-5g-5"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203782/google-removes-wide-angle-astrophotography-pixel-4a-5g-5</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-28T17:52:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-28T17:52:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>Your car may be recording more data than you know</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OtxG6atqyJobMoGrfUbU_73N17Q=/0x0:3120x2080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68590524/DSCF1984_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6j1vbE"&gt;When we think about privacy and who can access our location data, we’re often &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/19/21029992/smartphone-location-tracking-legal-technology-privacy-new-york-times"&gt;focusing on our phones&lt;/a&gt;, and not on the machine that actually takes us places: our car. A &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/snitches-wheels-police-turn-car-data-destroy-suspects-alibis-n1251939"&gt;recent report from NBC News&lt;/a&gt; goes into just how much data is collected by our vehicles, and how it can be used by police and criminals alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N5Urso"&gt;Your car, depending on how new it is and what capabilities it has, could be collecting all sorts of data without your knowledge — including location data, when its doors were opened, and even recordings of your voice. The NBC article uses the example of Joshua Wessel, a man who’s been charged with murder because the victim’s truck has a recording of his voice at the time of the killing. The report also looks at a company called Berla Corp., which has built a business out of extracting that data on behalf of police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kRxXKD"&gt;In broad strokes, it’s hard to guarantee any kind of data protection, simply because cars collect so much sensitive data. Berla’s software boasts the ability to read the unique IDs of Bluetooth and Wi-Fi devices that had connected to a car’s infotainment system, as well as call logs, contacts, and text messages. But infotainment data isn’t all it can read — it can also look at the logs kept by the car’s internal computer, revealing when specific doors were opened, as well as providing a location log from its built-in GPS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VKZeNP"&gt;It’s not just police that are able to get at this information. NBC mentions an Australian man &lt;a href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/2019-11-06/ract-employee-pleads-guilty-to-using-app-to-stalk-ex-girlfriend/11678980"&gt;who used an app to access live data from his ex-girlfriend’s Land Rover&lt;/a&gt;. Not only was he able to access live information about the car, he was also able to control it, remotely turning it on and off and opening windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7j5MSu"&gt;I’ve seen firsthand how people don’t think about all the information their car keeps. I recently bought a used one, and it turned out that the dealership hadn’t wiped any of the previous owner’s information. I could’ve easily seen their phone number and home address if I wanted (and I had to see what they had named their phone in order to delete it from the system). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wpm5WK"&gt;The heart of the problem is that we’re sharing our private data with more and more devices, and the systems we rely on to keep that data safe keep getting more complex. If we really want to deal with the issue, we may have to take a hard look at our cars, and start thinking about how much data they really need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="S3oW6v"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Former VW owner discovered digital access to her car months after it was sold","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/4/17303644/volkswagen-car-net-security-location-access"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203587/car-recorded-data-investigation-stalking-privacy-concerns"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203587/car-recorded-data-investigation-stalking-privacy-concerns</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-28T16:45:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-28T16:45:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>In 2023, you won’t be able to fly most drones in the US without broadcasting your location</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Mhqij0APxyjLbj5N5qjzss8HxNc=/0x0:2200x1467/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68590221/DJI_Phantom_3_Skyscraper.0.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Sean O’Kane / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GggEW5"&gt;If you intend to fly a drone in the US, you’re going to want to pay attention: &lt;a href="https://www.faa.gov/news/press_releases/news_story.cfm?newsId=25541"&gt;the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) just issued&lt;/a&gt; the single biggest set of changes to US drone law since the agency first took an interest in the technology. With the proper license, you’ll soon be able to fly at night and over people. But the biggest change is this: in 2023, it may be illegal for you to fly some drones &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt; unless you retrofit them with their own broadcasting equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tw76Yi"&gt;In 2022, the US government will require every new mass-produced drone weighing over 0.55 pounds (0.25kg) to broadcast your location — and I do mean your location, not just the location of your drone. You’ll also be broadcasting an identification number that law enforcement can cross-reference with your registration number, as well as your drone’s speed and altitude. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="UmERIS"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The FAA is casting it as a digital license plate&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HZIrov"&gt;It’s all part of a new “Remote ID” standard designed to give the FAA and law enforcement a handle on what’s actually flying around in the skies, and it makes sense we might want something like that, considering &lt;a href="https://www.faa.gov/uas/getting_started/register_drone/"&gt;the current system&lt;/a&gt; only requires you to slap a sticker on your drone that nobody’s going to be able to see while it’s flying through the air. This way, law enforcement can theoretically figure out who’s flying any given drone dangerously and shut them down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PO5vaL"&gt;But the Remote ID rule doesn’t just apply to brand-new drones: in 2023; it’ll be illegal to fly your existing drones without that same broadcast. There’s no grandfathering clause for older drones, no exemption for home-built racing drones, and it doesn’t matter whether you’re flying it for fun or even just flying it indoors. You’ll either need to retrofit it with a new broadcast module or only fly it in a specially designated drone flying zone called an “FAA-Recognized Identification Area,” according to the new rules. No such areas yet exist — the FAA will be accepting applications for the new zones in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iPGfcc"&gt;It’s also noteworthy the FAA isn’t saying &lt;em&gt;precisely how &lt;/em&gt;or &lt;em&gt;how far&lt;/em&gt; these drones need to broadcast their identity, largely leaving it up to manufacturers to figure out the best way to do so over the next 18-20 months, which is when new drones sold in the US will have to comply. “At this time, no means of compliance have been FAA-approved,” writes a spokesperson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RETcYc"&gt;For a DJI-style drone that already packs plenty of technology and already connects to your smartphone, it might theoretically be as easy as sending an additional signal every so often, but it depends on what the FAA decides to approve in the end. DJI declined to comment for this story, which makes me wonder if there’s some wrinkle I’m missing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="220vtP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;What does “broadcast” mean? TBD&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aDCkam"&gt;It is worth noting that while &lt;a href="https://content.dji.com/we-strongly-support-drone-remote-id-but-not-like-this/"&gt;DJI railed against the FAA’s original proposal&lt;/a&gt; that might have required every drone to broadcast their Remote ID over the internet, the final rules explicitly don’t require an internet connection, and suggest that manufacturers might simply use short-range Bluetooth or Wi-Fi. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Aw6Zs"&gt;Here’s self-flying drone maker Skydio’s statement: “We are reviewing the FAA’s new rule on remote identification, which comes into effect in roughly 30 months. There is no immediate impact on Skydio customers. We are working closely with the FAA and taking steps to ensure that our current and future products will be in compliance with the new framework.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EP709d"&gt;If it does prove difficult to add these broadcasts. or if people become worried about revealing their location, it could change the way drones are made and sold. Companies like DJI already try to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/4/21550181/dji-mavic-mini-2-drone-4k-price-release-date-battery-life"&gt;keep some drones under the 0.55-pound weight limit&lt;/a&gt; so buyers don’t have to legally register them with the FAA. Now, more drones are likely to follow suit, and manufacturers of cheaper flying toys might think twice about crossing that weight limit as well. Even racing drones designed to shed as much weight as possible may now need to factor a possible Remote ID transmitter into their build. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yxZM3q"&gt;And just because you’ve got a Remote ID transmitter doesn’t mean you can take an eye off  your drone, by the way. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/6/21505064/faa-visual-line-of-sight-skydio-2-waiver-ncdot-chula-vista"&gt;The Visual Line of Sight rule&lt;/a&gt; still applies. “Persons operating a drone with a remote ID broadcast module must be able to see their drone at all times during flight,” writes an FAA spokesperson, who also confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that there’s no exemption for home-built drones. “[FAA-Recognized Identification Areas] are the only locations unmanned aircraft (drones and radio-controlled model airplanes) may operate without broadcasting remote ID message elements without other authorization from the FAA,” they wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f9ibgH"&gt;If you’re a professional, licensed drone operator, there is some very intriguing and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/15/18183830/faa-drone-regulations-usa-crowds-night"&gt;long-awaited&lt;/a&gt; news today alongside the Remote ID rule, though: the FAA has decided to finally allow you to fly drones over people, at night, and in some cases even over moving vehicles without applying for a special exemption. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IsfOWb"&gt;Flying at night requires additional training and anti-collision lights “that can be seen for 3 statute miles and have a flash rate sufficient to avoid a collision.” Flying over people depends on how dangerous your drone is in terms of weight and sharp propeller blades. There are four categories of drone:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="srK1x7"&gt;Category 1 eligible small unmanned aircraft must weigh less than 0.55, including everything on board or otherwise attached, and contain no exposed rotating parts that would lacerate human skin. No FAA-accepted Means of Compliance (MOC) or Declaration of Compliance (DOC) required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lm0rpG"&gt;Category 2 eligible small unmanned aircraft must not cause injury to a human being that is equivalent to or greater than the severity of injury caused by a transfer of 11 foot-pounds of kinetic energy upon impact from a rigid object, does not contain any exposed rotating parts that could lacerate human skin upon impact with a human being, and does not contain any safety defects. Requires FAA-accepted means of compliance and FAA-accepted declaration of compliance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KsBjo7"&gt;Category 3 eligible small unmanned aircraft must not cause injury to a human being that is equivalent to or greater than the severity of injury caused by a transfer of 25 foot-pounds of kinetic energy upon impact from a rigid object, does not contain any exposed rotating parts that could lacerate human skin upon impact with a human being, and does not contain any safety defects. Requires FAA-accepted means of compliance and FAA-accepted declaration of compliance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iPxRI5"&gt;Category 4 eligible small unmanned aircraft must have an airworthiness certificate issued under Part 21 of FAA regulations. Must be operated in accordance with the operating limitations specified in the approved Flight Manual or as otherwise specified by the Administrator. The operating limitations must not prohibit operations over human beings. Must have maintenance, preventive maintenance, alterations, or inspections performed in accordance with specific requirements in the final rule. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="SbT4RN"&gt;You can’t fly a small Category 1 or Category 2 drone over people unless it’s got a Remote ID transmitter, while Category 3 can’t be flown over “open-air assemblies of human beings,” only private areas where people are either under covered structures or have been warned that a drone will be flying over. Regardless, you’ll need a Part 107 permit to fly at night or over people at all, which means taking a test and getting licensed. These specific rules should go into effect in about two months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0hkpKq"&gt;Here’s &lt;a href="https://www.faa.gov/news/media/attachments/OOP_Executive_Summary.pdf"&gt;the FAA’s executive summary (PDF) on flying over people&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href="https://www.faa.gov/news/media/attachments/RemoteID_Final_Rule.pdf"&gt;full text of the Remote ID rule (PDF)&lt;/a&gt; so you can read for yourself. The FAA has addressed loads of public comments and suggestions in there, so it’s worth a read if you’re wondering why they chose to go this way.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203398/faa-remote-id-rules-location-night-over-people"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203398/faa-remote-id-rules-location-night-over-people</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-28T16:39:13-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-28T16:39:13-05:00</updated>
    <title>TikTok’s one-night Ratatouille musical will star some of Broadway’s biggest names</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lDIAuKEWkY38ZWqyV-COS0kHjoU=/44x0:607x375/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68590199/Seaview_Work_Featured_Images_Ratatouille_650x375.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HMOKY8"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ratatouille: The TikTok Musical&lt;/em&gt; has some big Broadway talent on board for its January 1st streaming performance. Adam Lambert, Wayne Brady, Kevin Chamberlin, Mary Testa, and Priscilla Lopez will play key roles, with Tituss Burgess starring as Remy, the sophisticated rat who loves fine food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qgye8m"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;COULDN’T GET ANY BETTER! &lt;a href="https://t.co/UeJdEqR70z"&gt;https://t.co/UeJdEqR70z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Emily Jacobsen (@anEmilyJacobsen) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/anEmilyJacobsen/status/1343618164018589698?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 28, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TSEsFR"&gt;The one-time only performance will benefit the Actors Fund. Based on the 2007 Disney-Pixar movie &lt;em&gt;Ratatouille&lt;/em&gt;, the musical came together on TikTok, with creators composing songs based on the original film, building the “show” piece by piece. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/anEmilyJacobsen/status/1336789469018681344"&gt;Emily Jacobsen&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@e_jaccs/video/6859521038418447622?referer_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.playbill.com%2F&amp;amp;referer_video_id=6859521038418447622"&gt;@e_jaccs&lt;/a&gt;) made the original “&lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@e_jaccs/video/6859521038418447622?referer_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.playbill.com%2F&amp;amp;referer_video_id=6859521038418447622"&gt;Remy the Ratatouille&lt;/a&gt;” song for TikTok, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/danieljmertz/status/1336765015911768069"&gt;composer Daniel Mertzlufft&lt;/a&gt;, created the very Broadway-esque &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@danieljmertzlufft/video/6885475193410620678"&gt;arrangement of Jacobsen’s song&lt;/a&gt; that really started the ball rolling for a full-blown show. Honestly it’s so good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="imvBEv"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="tiktok-embed" cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@danieljmertzlufft/video/6885475193410620678" data-video-id="6885475193410620678" style="max-width: 605px;min-width: 325px;"&gt; &lt;section&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" title="@danieljmertzlufft" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@danieljmertzlufft"&gt;@danieljmertzlufft&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p&gt;Remy: The Musical OG Song @e_jaccs add. Vocals @cjaskier &lt;a title="remy" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/remy"&gt;#remy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="ratatouille" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/ratatouille"&gt;#ratatouille&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="musicaltheatre" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/musicaltheatre"&gt;#musicaltheatre&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="broadway" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/broadway"&gt;#broadway&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="singer" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/singer"&gt;#singer&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="musical" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/musical"&gt;#musical&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="disney" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/disney"&gt;#disney&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="fyp" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/fyp"&gt;#fyp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="disneymusicals" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/disneymusicals"&gt;#disneymusicals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" title="♬ original sound - danieljmertzlufft" href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/original-sound-6885475237366926086"&gt;♬ original sound - danieljmertzlufft&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/section&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async="" src="https://www.tiktok.com/embed.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="n0tckV"&gt;“&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VjU_p3uvlkU"&gt;The Rat’s Way of Life&lt;/a&gt;” and “&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MvI0Lg8JmPQ"&gt;Ratatouille Tango&lt;/a&gt;” created by TikToker &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@blakeyrouse?lang=en"&gt;Blake Rouse&lt;/a&gt; will be featured in the musical, and the Playbill program created by TikToker &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tinymallet/status/1327652187980312579"&gt;Jess Siswick&lt;/a&gt; is the musical’s &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com/?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https://www.todaytix.com/x/nyc/shows/22803-Ratatouille%E2%80%94The-TikTok-Musical&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22166215/ratatouille-the-tiktok-musical-broadway-show-todaytix-streaming-one-night-date-viral-disney&amp;amp;xcust=___vg__e_21930256__r_google.com__t_w__d_D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;promotional artwork&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nSe5JE"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="tiktok-embed" cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@blakeyrouse/video/6897702582710521093" data-video-id="6897702582710521093" style="max-width: 605px;min-width: 325px;"&gt; &lt;section&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" title="@blakeyrouse" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@blakeyrouse"&gt;@blakeyrouse&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p&gt;Reply to @blakeyrouse y’all wanted it, here it is !! &lt;a title="theatrekids" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/theatrekids"&gt;#TheatreKids&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="ratatouille" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/ratatouille"&gt;#ratatouille&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="RatatouilleMusical" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/RatatouilleMusical"&gt;#ratatouillemusical&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="musical" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/musical"&gt;#musical&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="theatre" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/theatre"&gt;#theatre&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="musicaltheatre" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/musicaltheatre"&gt;#musicaltheatre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" title="♬ original sound - Yay Blake Rouse!!" href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/original-sound-6897702665153678086"&gt;♬ original sound - Yay Blake Rouse!!&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/section&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async="" src="https://www.tiktok.com/embed.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PL06SG"&gt;TodayTix, which is the ticket vendor for the show, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TodayTix/status/1336762601150312448?s=20"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; that “creators are, indeed, being compensated and credited! Our teams are collaborating with them to make this the show of all your dreams.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OMRsDI"&gt;Disney isn’t directly involved with development but has apparently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22166215/ratatouille-the-tiktok-musical-broadway-show-todaytix-streaming-one-night-date-viral-disney"&gt;given its blessing&lt;/a&gt; to the project. As has actor Patton Oswalt, the original voice of Remy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XYWWWX"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;OH MY GOD IT’S HAPPENING. What an amazing way to start out 2021! And the proceeds benefit &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TheActorsFund?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@TheActorsFund&lt;/a&gt;!!!! You gonna be there?!? I will! &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ratatouillethemusical?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#ratatouillethemusical&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/a0h7dMq16A"&gt;https://t.co/a0h7dMq16A&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Patton Oswalt (@pattonoswalt) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/pattonoswalt/status/1336777336084041728?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 9, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MB5nby"&gt;The show will stream via &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com/?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https://www.todaytix.com/x/nyc/shows/22803-Ratatouille%E2%80%94The-TikTok-Musical&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22166215/ratatouille-the-tiktok-musical-broadway-show-todaytix-streaming-one-night-date-viral-disney&amp;amp;xcust=___vg__e_21930256__r_google.com__t_w__d_D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;TodayTix&lt;/a&gt; on January 1st at 7PM ET, with ticket prices ranging from $5 to $50. &lt;em&gt;Ratatouille: The TikTok Musical&lt;/em&gt; will be available on demand for 72 hours after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XTV2CZ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203490/ratatouille-tiktok-musical-tituss-burgess-adam-lambert-wayne-brady-pixar-disney"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203490/ratatouille-tiktok-musical-tituss-burgess-adam-lambert-wayne-brady-pixar-disney</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-28T16:24:05-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-28T16:24:05-05:00</updated>
    <title>New York Post’s Hunter Biden laptop source sues Twitter for defamation</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zWMXWqiSQlaGWUTzPKEZ6OHg7xk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68590133/acastro_180827_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Sgz1TR"&gt;A computer repair shop owner cited in a controversial &lt;em&gt;New York Post&lt;/em&gt; story is &lt;a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.flsd.583882/gov.uscourts.flsd.583882.1.0.pdf"&gt;suing Twitter for defamation&lt;/a&gt;, claiming its content moderation choices falsely tarred him as a hacker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qntc35"&gt;John Paul Mac Isaac was the owner of The Mac Shop, a Delaware computer repair business. In October, the &lt;a href="https://nypost.com/2020/10/14/email-reveals-how-hunter-biden-introduced-ukrainian-biz-man-to-dad/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;New York Post&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; that The Mac Shop had been &lt;a href="https://nypost.com/2020/12/11/repair-shop-owner-at-center-of-hunter-biden-saga-defends-himself/"&gt;paid to recover&lt;/a&gt; data from a laptop belonging to Joe Biden’s son Hunter, and it published emails and pictures allegedly from a copy of the hard drive. After the &lt;em&gt;Post’s&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.politifact.com/article/2020/oct/15/look-behind-ny-post-headline-about-joe-biden-and-u/"&gt;sourcing and conclusions&lt;/a&gt; were disputed, Facebook and Twitter both &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/14/21515972/facebook-new-york-post-hunter-biden-story-fact-checking-reduced-distribution-election-misinformation?scrolla=5eb6d68b7fedc32c19ef33b4%5C"&gt;restricted the article’s reach&lt;/a&gt;, and Twitter pointed to its ban on posting “hacked materials” as an explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y2AVir"&gt;Mac Isaac claims Twitter specifically made this decision to “communicate to the world that [Mac Isaac] is a hacker.” He says that his business began to receive threats and negative reviews after Twitter’s moderation decision, and that he is “now widely considered a hacker” because of Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UDpBtX"&gt;Unlike &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/27/21272066/social-media-bias-laura-loomer-larry-klayman-twitter-google-facebook-loss"&gt;many suits&lt;/a&gt; against social media companies, Mac Isaac isn’t specifically complaining that Twitter removed content — a choice that would be likely protected by the First Amendment. Nor is he claiming other people defamed him &lt;em&gt;through&lt;/em&gt; Twitter, a strategy &lt;a href="https://www.abajournal.com/news/article/twitter-dismissed-from-devin-nunes-defamation-suit-over-parody-accounts"&gt;unsuccessfully pursued&lt;/a&gt; by Rep. Devin Nunes of California. His suit loosely mirrors that of conservative activist Laura Loomer, who &lt;a href="https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20200416/15055144320/facebook-tells-court-laura-loomers-defamation-allegations-all-target-protected-opinions.shtml"&gt;sued Facebook&lt;/a&gt; for banning her under a “dangerous individuals” policy. (Loomer’s case was &lt;a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/docket/17143914/loomer-v-facebook-inc/"&gt;dismissed voluntarily&lt;/a&gt; in August.) Basically, his argument rests on the fact that Twitter said the &lt;em&gt;New York Post&lt;/em&gt; report was based on hacked materials, and by extension, it maliciously implied he was a hacker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PPDuJV"&gt;Twitter defines “hacking” loosely to include obtaining documents without authorization, and it didn’t name a specific individual as a “hacker.” The &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; said it indirectly obtained its files via Trump lawyer Rudy Giuliani’s attorney, who in turn obtained them from Mac Isaac. Some critics of the &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; speculated that Russian disinformation operatives had &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/national-security/feds-examining-if-alleged-hunter-biden-emails-are-linked-foreign-n1243620"&gt;planted the emails&lt;/a&gt;, which wouldn’t place the blame on Mac Isaac. (These critiques have not been corroborated.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iJHfe2"&gt;The complaint cites several negative business reviews that criticize Mac Isaac based on the facts of the &lt;em&gt;Post &lt;/em&gt;story — but it’s unclear why Twitter should be held liable for those reviews. Twitter also declared a day later that the &lt;em&gt;Post’s&lt;/em&gt; reporting &lt;em&gt;didn’t&lt;/em&gt; violate its “hacked materials” policy, part of a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/30/21542801/twitter-lifts-ny-post-ban-policy-changes"&gt;rapid series of policy shifts&lt;/a&gt; around the saga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="prZxyK"&gt;Mac Isaac is nonetheless demanding $500 million and a public retraction from Twitter. Twitter did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203412/john-paul-mac-isaac-hunter-biden-laptop-new-york-post-twitter-moderation-hacked-materials-lawsuit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203412/john-paul-mac-isaac-hunter-biden-laptop-new-york-post-twitter-moderation-hacked-materials-lawsuit</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-28T15:21:43-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-28T15:21:43-05:00</updated>
    <title>Trump administration appeals yet another TikTok ruling </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iNjLQwiwFE7vqnX-TVHpEs7Wbb0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68589682/acastro_200713_1777_tikTok_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XTW5RK"&gt;The Trump administration has gained some &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/donald-trump-losing-election-lawsuits-36d113484ac0946fa5f0614deb7de15e"&gt;experience losing in court&lt;/a&gt; recently, and has suffered setback after setback in its stance that TikTok should be banned in the US. Still, its pursuit of the video sharing app continues. On Monday, the Department of Justice filed an appeal of a judge’s order that blocked restrictions on TikTok in the US from taking effect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cFXAWp"&gt;US District Judge Carl Nichols issued an order December 7th that blocked the Commerce Department’s restrictions on TikTok, which would have prevented new downloads of the app from US app stores. Nichols’ order followed an October order from US District Judge Wendy Beetlestone in Pennsylvania, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/30/21542641/tiktok-ban-commerce-department-blocked-november-12-influencers"&gt;who issued an injunction&lt;/a&gt; against the ban. In that case, three content creators had argued that a TikTok ban would have a negative effect on their income. And on Monday, the &lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22200922/6896727_0__30750.pdf"&gt;DOJ appealed Nichols’ decision&lt;/a&gt; to the US Court of Appeals for the DC Circuit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="lbbp1N"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A US ban on TikTok seems less and less likely&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="S9Nait"&gt;The TikTok-Trump saga began back in August, when &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/10/21358505/trump-tiktok-wechat-tencent-bytedance-china-ban-executive-order-legal-sanctions-rules"&gt;President Trump issued an order&lt;/a&gt; saying the security concerns about TikTok and WeChat, both China-based apps, constituted a national emergency. He invoked the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (IEEPA), which allows the president to ban transactions between US and foreign entities. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/14/21369753/bytedance-tiktok-trump-china-app-privacy-90-days"&gt;President Trump then issued an order&lt;/a&gt; August 14th giving parent company ByteDance 90 days to either sell or spin off its TikTok business in the US. That order was set to go into effect on November 12th and would have halted the app’s US operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mH6eMI"&gt;On September 18th, the US Commerce Department &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/18/21445060/trump-tiktok-wechat-ban-us-apple-app-store-google-play-commerce-department"&gt;issued an order&lt;/a&gt; to block downloads of the app in the US. But a day later, the president said he &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/19/21437850/president-trump-approves-oracle-tiktok-partnership-bytedance-china-ban"&gt;had approved “in concept”&lt;/a&gt; a bid from cloud computing giant Oracle to become TikTok’s “trusted tech partner.” That deal called for creating a new entity, TikTok Global, which would be based in the US and take over processing and storage for all US-based TikTok users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cjbfqS"&gt;But then the Trump administration... kind of forgot about the whole thing, it seemed. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/10/21559677/tiktok-cfius-court-petition-ban-deadline"&gt;TikTok filed a petition November 10th&lt;/a&gt; seeking a 30-day extension of the November 12th deadline, and the company said it had received “no substantive feedback” from the Trump administration for some time. The administration gave an extension until November 27th, and again until December 4th. Then the government &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/4/22154801/us-government-tiktok-ban-deadline-bytedance-trump-administration-cfius"&gt;said it would not enforce&lt;/a&gt; its own deadline.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JMgXpU"&gt;What shape the appeal will take in the waning days of a lame duck administration is still to be determined, but a US ban on the app seeks less and less likely to happen. TikTok did not immediately reply to a request for comment Monday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ikGDzY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203284/trump-administration-appeal-tiktok-china-bytedance"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203284/trump-administration-appeal-tiktok-china-bytedance</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-28T14:51:02-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-28T14:51:02-05:00</updated>
    <title>You can get a OnePlus 7T for $300 at B&amp;H</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/biDnx6girr9OFiVWYJgbRaaeAFM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68589443/vpavic_190924_3684_0096.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DBH7mo"&gt;The T-Mobile variant of the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1600544-REG%2Foneplus_610214661821_7t_t_mobile_smartphone_frosted.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2020%2F12%2F28%2F22203289%2Foneplus-7t-sale-deal-b-and-h-price#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;OnePlus 7T is on sale at B&amp;amp;H&lt;/a&gt; for $300, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oneplus.com%2Foneplus-7t-tmo%3Ffrom%3D7t&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2020%2F12%2F28%2F22203289%2Foneplus-7t-sale-deal-b-and-h-price#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;undercutting OnePlus’s own sale&lt;/a&gt; at $350. This matches the lowest price the phone has ever been, so if you’ve been looking for a flagship-specced phone at a budget price, this deal may be worth checking out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WnqpQD"&gt;This being the T-Mobile variant, there are some caveats that B&amp;amp;H lists on its site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="WStSqS"&gt;The OnePlus 7T is an unlocked T-Mobile variant. It may be used in other parts of the world; however, LTE access may be limited or unsupported, depending on the network. Please choose your country/carrier above to confirm the network compatibility of this phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RGLcV6"&gt;This phone may also be T-Mobile branded and come pre-loaded with T-Mobile firmware and applications. The phone was originally manufactured and locked for T-Mobile, but T-Mobile has since unlocked it for resale. The phone is new and not pre-owned, though the box has been opened in order to unlock the phone. The phone may be used on any compatible carrier; however, certain features like Wi-Fi tethering may not work on other carriers. The phone is also dependent on T-Mobile for software updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Vqxk6w"&gt;If you &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/29/21540535/amazon-motorola-razr-fingerprint-folding-phones-screen-protection"&gt;don’t like the idea of the phone having previously been opened&lt;/a&gt;, you can also get a fully unlocked version for $350 from B&amp;amp;H, or the T-Mobile locked variant for $350 from OnePlus themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GUJkAP"&gt;The 7T &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/26/20881638/oneplus-7t-review-specs-features-price-availability"&gt;was a good deal when it launched&lt;/a&gt; at $599, and has &lt;a href="https://www.androidauthority.com/oneplus-7t-long-term-review-1164176/"&gt;only improved after a year of updates&lt;/a&gt; (though it’s worth remembering that you’ll be reliant on T-Mobile for those with this version). When compared to the market now, it does lack some features: it doesn’t have 5G, and it’s screen is slower at 90Hz &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21514174/oneplus-8t-review"&gt;than its successor’s&lt;/a&gt;, which runs at 120Hz. But if you value savings more than those features, you may want to hop on the deal — it expires this Wednesday, December 31 at 11:59PM ET.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2020/12/28/22203289/oneplus-7t-sale-deal-b-and-h-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2020/12/28/22203289/oneplus-7t-sale-deal-b-and-h-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
