<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2022-01-19T15:56:41-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T15:56:41-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T15:56:41-05:00</updated>
    <title>Halo Infinite gets a hotfix to address Big Team Battle problems, but it hasn’t helped</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Halo Infinite multiplayer" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7RkfmNGt4VGQYSe3rM6rme-pw7Q=/182x0:2342x1440/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70409454/Halo_Infinite_Multiplayer_4_4K_3840x2160_scaled.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite multiplayer&lt;/em&gt; | Image: 343 Industries&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yghErv"&gt;Microsoft’s latest Halo game has finally arrived, and as we’ve seen, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/6/22820011/halo-infinite-campaign-review-xbox-series-x"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Infinite&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;campaign mode delivers. But for players already missing features like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22791487/halo-infinite-campaign-co-op-season-2-may-2022-forge"&gt;campaign co-op&lt;/a&gt; and Forge customizations, ongoing issues with the &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; Big Team Battle matchmaking have been another source of disappointment. A little over a week ago, the developers at 343 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/10/22877515/microsoft-halo-infinite-big-team-battle-matchmaking-fix-343"&gt;said a hotfix was on the way&lt;/a&gt;, and now it has arrived. But there’s bad news — it doesn’t seem to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Irczw0"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://support.halowaypoint.com/hc/en-us/articles/4412306622356"&gt;size of the update varies by platform&lt;/a&gt;, but players report it comes in at about a gigabyte on Xboxes and 110MB for PC players via Steam. If you’ve been online the whole time, you may need to restart your game to download it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="adyKQH"&gt;&lt;a href="https://forums.halowaypoint.com/t/halo-infinite-update-btb-and-more-updated-jan-19/490385"&gt;Here’s 343 on what’s happening:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="PeaBPj"&gt;Hey everyone - The Hotfix was deployed at 10AM PT today for Xbox and PC and included a fix for an issue with Oddball but also was hoped to address the ongoing matchmaking issues affecting Big Team Battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e3oN7p"&gt;Unfortunately it looks like today’s patch did not fully resolve the BTB matchmaking problems. The team is continuing to investigate and while we believe there may be some minor improvements, matchmaking is still not working as expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="28hevD"&gt;Many people worked hard to get this fix out the door and it’s naturally very disappointing we’re not seeing the desired and expected results. We know this is an ongoing source of frustration and the team will continue to work towards a resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YXe8Qt"&gt;We’ll continue to provide updates as we have them. In the meantime, we greatly appreciate your patience and understanding as we navigate this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CxHMSg"&gt;The aforementioned grants of 5 XP boosts and Challenge Swaps also went live at 10AM today. Log in any time between now and 10AM PT on Feb. 16 and they’ll be automatically added to your inventory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vmS3Ct"&gt;Thank you and our sincere apologies that today’s update did not go as we’d hoped. More to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="L7NH6s"&gt;Their data is showing the same thing &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/halo/comments/s7wjqt/halo_infinite_patch_january_19th_2022_discussion/"&gt;commenters on Reddit report&lt;/a&gt; — Big Team Battle is still a bit of a mess, with games that too frequently fail to start or drop many of the players before they get going. Now that accelerating these fixes from a planned mid-February patch has failed to fix things, it’s unclear what’s next for one of our favorite Halo modes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ItKOd7"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/HaloInfinite?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#HaloInfinite&lt;/a&gt; hotfix is now live with updates to Oddball and minor matchmaking improvements for BTB. If you're currently playing, close and relaunch Halo Infinite to install (1GB or less). More info in the January 19 update section of our release notes.&lt;a href="https://t.co/EFJ0w03eXM"&gt;https://t.co/EFJ0w03eXM&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/bmYhv78idr"&gt;pic.twitter.com/bmYhv78idr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Halo Support (@HaloSupport) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HaloSupport/status/1483876581873385475?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 19, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891256/halo-infinite-multiplayer-big-team-battle-patch-update-problems"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891256/halo-infinite-multiplayer-big-team-battle-patch-update-problems</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T15:53:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T15:53:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>Half of internet-connected devices in hospitals are vulnerable to hacks, report finds</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An IV medication drip." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4JAPJsccg6j6G2yrqhpdkJecxc4=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70409446/HH_IV_3.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PFgK4h"&gt;Over half of internet-connected devices used in hospitals have a vulnerability that could put patient safety, confidential data, or the usability of a device at risk, according to a &lt;a href="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5d2ad783e06f4c19469d363a/61e70fd9286e1d6d68a86ba8_A%20Cynerio%20Report%20-%20The%20State%20of%20IoMT%20Device%20Security%202022.pdf?__hstc=40021757.4448268d52e298f28d5bc2dbbc585809.1642605620912.1642605620912.1642605620912.1&amp;amp;__hssc=40021757.1.1642605620913&amp;amp;__hsfp=2234910243"&gt;new report&lt;/a&gt; from the healthcare cybersecurity company Cynerio. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ADAtQ"&gt;The report analyzed data from over 10 million devices at over 300 hospitals and health care facilities globally, which the company collected through connectors attached to the devices as part of its security platform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZnclJb"&gt;The most common type of internet-connected device in hospitals was an infusion pump. These devices can remotely connect to electronic medical records, pull the correct dosage of a medication or other fluid, and dispense it to the patient. Infusion pumps were also the devices most likely to have vulnerabilities that could be exploited by hackers, the report found — 73 percent had a vulnerability. Experts worry that hacks into devices like these, which are directly connected to patients, could be used to hurt or threaten to hurt people directly. Someone could theoretically access those systems and change the dosage of a medication, for example. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="46yKEn"&gt;Other common internet-connected devices are patient monitors, which can track things like heart rate and breathing rate, and ultrasounds. Both of those types of devices were in the top 10 list in terms of numbers of vulnerabilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6whdG0"&gt;Health care organizations are now a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/4/18293817/cybersecurity-hospitals-health-care-scan-simulation"&gt;major target for hackers&lt;/a&gt;, and while a direct attack on internet-connected medical devices doesn’t seem to have happened yet, experts think it’s a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686000/medical-device-cybersecurity-hack-minnesota"&gt;possibility&lt;/a&gt;. The more active threat is from groups that break into hospital systems through a vulnerable device and lock up the hospital’s digital networks — leaving doctors and nurses unable to access medical records, devices, and other digital tools — and demand a ransom to unlock them. These attacks have escalated over the past few years, and they slow down hospital functions to the extent that it can &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632378/pandemic-ransomware-health-risks"&gt;hurt patients&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YJtQni"&gt;Cynerio’s report notes that most of the vulnerabilities in medical devices are easily fixable: they’re due to weak or default passwords or a recall notice that the organization hasn’t acted on. Many healthcare organizations just don’t have the resources or personnel to keep systems up to date and might not know if there’s an update or alert concerning one of their devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jgR3vz"&gt;But reports like this one, combined with the growing frequency of ransomware attacks, is pushing more health care organizations to invest in cybersecurity, experts say. “I think this is reaching a level of criticality that is getting the attention of CEOs and board rooms,” Ed Gaudet, CEO and founder at cybersecurity company Censinet, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696097/hospital-ransomware-cyberattack-death-rates-patients"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; this fall.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GcFEkY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mKn1J2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891440/internet-connected-medical-devices-vulnerable"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891440/internet-connected-medical-devices-vulnerable</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T15:47:44-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T15:47:44-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to file for a tax extension</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="irs (ray tsang flickr)" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a2ynZbODfdQPeDxbr_PmeP8MlI8=/0x3:1100x736/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70409425/irs.1419979791.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;irs (ray tsang flickr)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="NDMozI"&gt;When, in 2020, the IRS pushed the due date for federal income taxes from April 15th to July 15th because of the upheaval brought about by COVID-19, a lot of taxpayers must have breathed a sigh of relief. Depending on where we lived, many of us were dealing with product shortages, layoffs, sudden isolation, and trying to figure out how to cope with the new normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vj3xwD"&gt;Time marches on, however, and two years later, the tax deadline is back to mid-April (April 18th for most states, April 19th in Maine and Massachusetts). So if you won’t be able to file your taxes by then, what do you do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="6XZzpl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to file and pay your 2021 taxes online ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22889295/taxes-irs-file-pay-online-2021-how-to"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="6Wly7i"&gt;One thing you don’t do is panic. You can still file for an extension — and it won’t take long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AavhkF"&gt;If you’re an individual (and let’s assume you are), you can file for an extension easily online by &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-pdf/f4868.pdf"&gt;filling out Form 4868&lt;/a&gt; using the &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/forms-pubs/extension-of-time-to-file-your-tax-return"&gt;IRS’s Free File program&lt;/a&gt;. (Filing an extension is free no matter what your income level is.)  Some things to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="ZQPI3A"&gt;When you go to the page on the IRS site offering the Free File extensions, you’ll be faced with several possible choices of services. It might be worth it to take a glance at all of them since they handle forms differently, and you might feel more comfortable with one specific service. Whichever you choose, it will be free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nVgDj0"&gt;You may also need to file a state extension form. Some of the services in the IRS Free File program should handle that as well; if not, you can check with your state tax authority to find out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="e21nh8"&gt;Once you file an extension, you will have until October 17th to file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="aEYQuh"&gt;You will still have to approximate how much you owe the government and pay the amount due.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RIC0SG"&gt;If you know you will owe taxes and decide to pay them all or in part through &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/payments/direct-pay"&gt;Direct Pay&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/payments/eftps-the-electronic-federal-tax-payment-system"&gt;Electronic Federal Tax Payment System (EFTPS)&lt;/a&gt;, or a &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/payments/pay-taxes-by-credit-or-debit-card"&gt;credit or debit card&lt;/a&gt;, you can indicate that the payment is for an extension and you won’t even have to file a separate form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qQ9y00"&gt;If you’d rather mail a hard copy form, you can find a PDF to print out &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-pdf/f4868.pdf"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. You’re on time as long as it is postmarked by April 18th (April 19th if you’re from Maine or Massachusetts).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="stTUjQ"&gt;Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nMAXPg"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 19th, 2022, 3:20PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article was originally published on July 14th, 2020, and has been updated to change dates and other information for tax year 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HGxaAN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22891931/taxes-file-extension-deadline-irs-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22891931/taxes-file-extension-deadline-irs-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T15:14:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T15:14:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google will make free ‘legacy’ G Suite accounts pay for its office apps starting in July</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MdztgNtxkdnN7bqzWzgll7xoTqg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70409289/acastro_180508_1777_google_IO_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oKuC5o"&gt;If you’re part of a business or school that is a G Suite legacy free edition user, your organization will &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/a/answer/60217#faq"&gt;soon have to sign up for a paid subscription&lt;/a&gt; to continue using Google Workspace (via &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2022/01/19/g-suite-legacy-free-edition/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Google will automatically upgrade free plans to a Google Workspace subscription “based on the features you currently use” if your organization doesn’t sign up for a paid plan by May 1st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LecFM7"&gt;The free edition was initially available in &lt;a href="http://googlepress.blogspot.com/2006/08/google-launches-hosted-communications_28.html"&gt;Google’s first iteration of Workspace&lt;/a&gt;, called Google Apps, which launched in 2006. &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/29/google-rebrands-its-business-apps-as-g-suite-launches-team-drive-upgrades-apps/"&gt;Google Apps rebranded as G Suite&lt;/a&gt; in 2016, before &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/6/21503649/google-workspace-g-suite-gmail-chat-meet-docs"&gt;becoming the Google Workspace we know today in 2020&lt;/a&gt; by bundling Gmail, Docs, Meet, Sheets, and Calendar along with some extra perks. Google &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/a/answer/2855120"&gt;stopped offering the legacy free edition&lt;/a&gt; as of December 2012 but still allowed existing users to access its services for free as a courtesy. Unfortunately, it looks like this grace period has finally come to an end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="q2Fyj0"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Legacy free edition users won’t be charged for a subscription until July 1st&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AdbxT0"&gt;According to Google, the company is giving legacy free edition users until May 1st to sign up for a subscription, &lt;a href="https://workspace.google.com/pricing.html"&gt;which consists of four tiers&lt;/a&gt;; otherwise, Google will choose a plan that suits users’ needs based on the features they use. There’s no option for a free plan, with only some &lt;a href="https://edu.google.com/intl/ALL_us/products/workspace-for-education/"&gt;educational institutions&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/nonprofits/answer/3367223?hl=en"&gt;non-profit organizations&lt;/a&gt; eligible for a plan at no cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B0JxaC"&gt;Administrators will have until July 1st to enter payment information into Google (if they haven’t already), and Google won’t start charging a subscription fee until July 1st. If no payment information is entered, Google will suspend the account for 60 days, after which users won’t be able to access Workspace’s “core services,” like Gmail, Calendar, and Meet. You can find out more about how to upgrade to a paid plan or export your organization’s data &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/a/answer/60217#faq"&gt;on Google’s support page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8uC6Vf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891509/g-suite-legacy-free-google-apps-workspace-upgrade"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891509/g-suite-legacy-free-google-apps-workspace-upgrade</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T15:08:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T15:08:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>The FAA says some 777s are cleared to fly to airports with 5G C-band</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Cell Tower" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ax_faz-fwHHNCiwSmYTuhaA2Td8=/104x0:3967x2575/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70409265/1234861974.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Bill Clark/CQ-Roll Call, Inc via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dD3Tcr"&gt;The Federal Aviation Administration &lt;a href="https://www.faa.gov/newsroom/faa-statements-5g"&gt;has announced&lt;/a&gt; that more planes will be able to land in low-visibility conditions despite the rollout of 5G C-band, including some models of the Boeing 777 aircraft that’s used by many international airlines. According to a statement from the regulatory agency, it’s cleared three more models of radar altimeters as safe and reliable, even in areas where the upgraded cellular technology has been rolled out. This change comes after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22890080/5g-flight-cancel-att-verizon-c-band-emirates-air-india-ana-japan"&gt;several international airlines announced on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt; that they were suspending flights to some US airports due to the 5G C-band rollout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GaDJzM"&gt;According to the FAA’s statement, which you can read in full below, it cleared three additional altimeters on Wednesday morning, after clearing two on January 16th. The FAA has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22867221/att-verizon-5g-midband-spectrum-faa-air-safety-delay-cband"&gt;been in a back-and-forth with AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon&lt;/a&gt;, claiming that the companies’ cell towers could interfere with equipment needed to safely land planes in low-visibility conditions. Earlier this month the carriers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22866098/faa-dot-verizon-fcc-att-5g-c-band-delay-airplane-safety"&gt;delayed their rollouts&lt;/a&gt; to give the FAA more time to test and clear altimeters, and have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889664/att-5g-limits-c-band-expansion-airports-further-carrier-airline"&gt;said they’ll limit C-band expansion around certain airports&lt;/a&gt; that frequently have low visibility conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="imFEfj"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The new approvals clear an estimated 62 percent of US commercial airplanes for low-visibility landings at airports with C-band&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vNvq3y"&gt;With the additional safety buffer that AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon announced on Tuesday, this should clear some models of Boeing 717, 737, 747, 757, 767, 777, MD-10/-11 and Airbus A300, A310, A319, A320, A330, A340, A350, and A380. The FAA says that these new approvals should “allow an estimated 62 percent of the U.S. commercial fleet to perform low-visibility landings at airports where wireless companies deployed 5G C-band.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MmJlHK"&gt;While 62 percent of airplanes seems low, it’s higher than the FAA’s previous estimates; when the agency announced its new list of approvals on January 16th, it said they covered around “45 percent of the U.S. commercial fleet.” The administration has also said that, despite Wednesday’s clearances, “flights at some airports may still be affected.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3KCQjG"&gt;There were hints that this change would be coming — earlier on Wednesday, ANA and Japan Airlines &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22890080/5g-flight-cancel-att-verizon-c-band-emirates-air-india-ana-japan"&gt;announced that they would be resuming normal operations&lt;/a&gt; thanks to an FAA notification that cleared the 777 (the FAA’s announcement wasn’t public at the time). In a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, US-based Southwest Airlines said that it “expects minimal disruptions today after the telecomm companies announced their delay in 5G expansion near U.S. airports.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bPLOSE"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The FAA’s full statement: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="uC5tjQ"&gt;The FAA issued new approvals Wednesday that allow an estimated 62 percent of the U.S. commercial fleet to perform low-visibility landings at airports where wireless companies deployed 5G C-band. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pvmJDo"&gt;The new safety buffer announced Tuesday around airports in the 5G deployment further expanded the number of airports available to planes with previously cleared altimeters to perform low-visibility landings. The FAA early Wednesday cleared another three altimeters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8CfYzH"&gt;Even with these approvals, flights at some airports may still be affected. The FAA also continues to work with manufacturers to understand how radar altimeter data is used in other flight control systems. Passengers should check with their airlines for latest flight schedules. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="boHBij"&gt;Airplane models with one of the five cleared altimeters include some Boeing 717, 737, 747, 757, 767, 777, MD-10/-11 and Airbus A300, A310, A319, A320, A330, A340, A350 and A380 models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RpYmUx"&gt;For additional 5G information, including the airport list, please visit &lt;a href="https://www.faa.gov/5g"&gt;www.faa.gov/5g&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891725/faa-radar-new-altimeter-clearance-5g-c-band-rollout-airlines-boeing-777"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891725/faa-radar-new-altimeter-clearance-5g-c-band-rollout-airlines-boeing-777</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T15:08:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T15:08:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>Moon Knight’s Gaspard Ulliel has died following skiing accident in the French Alps</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Alternative Views At “Cesar - Revelations 2020” At Petit Palais In Paris" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ujLQZ5CCZR08-X5fC2fNEgXTMgQ=/146x0:5624x3652/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70409261/1199337652.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Francois Durand/Getty Images for the Cesar&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PbRTmG"&gt;Gaspard Ulliel, the French actor known for his portrayal of Yves Saint Laurent in director Bertrand Bonello’s &lt;em&gt;Saint Laurent &lt;/em&gt;and his upcoming role in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22889548/marvel-moon-knight-trailer-english-accent-villains"&gt;Marvel’s &lt;em&gt;Moon Knight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;series, has died at the age of 37 following a skiing accident in the Alps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t7uO5i"&gt;&lt;a href="https://variety.com/2022/film/news/gaspard-ulliel-dead-moon-knight-marvel-1235157242/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Variety reports&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;that Ulliel was initially rushed by helicopter to a hospital in Grenoble after a collision with another skier in the Alps’ Savoie region that left the actor with traumatic brain injuries. A burgeoning fixture in the French cinema scene, Ulliel’s roles in projects like &lt;em&gt;A Very Long Engagement&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;La Princesse de Montpensier &lt;/em&gt;made him one of the most recognizable faces at Cannes over the years during which he also became an in-demand model for brands like Vogue and Chanel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EGUycx"&gt;Ulliel first made waves Stateside with his performance as a younger Hannibal Lecter in Peter Webber’s &lt;em&gt;Hannibal Rising&lt;/em&gt; and is likely to feature largely in Disney Plus’ &lt;em&gt;Moon Knight, &lt;/em&gt;where he’s set to play a version of Midnight Man, a frequent foe of the show’s titular hero. Following news of Ulliel’s passing, Cannes Film Festival director Thierry Fremaux spoke fondly of the actor, remembering him as part of “this new generation of actors who were making tomorrow’s French cinema.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uTaYFR"&gt;“He knew how to select his roles and shaped his career, which filled every promise,” Fremaux said. “Each appearance on the red carpet, from &lt;em&gt;La Princesse de Montpensier&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;It’s Only The End of the World,&lt;/em&gt; illustrated his presence, both discreet and full of kindness. He was equally brilliant and talented. He gave a lot, and we’ll always remember him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YKCORM"&gt;Ulliel is survived by his wife Gaëlle Piétri and their son.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oA8k9X"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891235/moon-knights-gaspard-ulliel-has-died-following-skiing-accident-in-the-alps"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891235/moon-knights-gaspard-ulliel-has-died-following-skiing-accident-in-the-alps</id>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Pulliam-Moore</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T15:04:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T15:04:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>Strava can help you avoid the runs on those long runs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EJDv95beNRvYM2hkVgFBU8e3ZvE=/505x0:3022x1678/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70409243/Screen_Shot_2022_01_19_at_12.13.16_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Points of Interest is Strava’s latest feature&lt;/em&gt; | Screenshot: Victoria Song / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rDy5zv"&gt;There’s nothing like being 45 minutes into a run on a new route, far from civilization, and feeling the tell-tale gurgle in your intestines signaling the dreaded &lt;a href="https://www.health.com/condition/digestive-health/runners-trots"&gt;runner’s trots&lt;/a&gt;. Sometimes, Google can come to your aid, but searching for a public restroom while trying not to publically poop your pants is, needless to say, incredibly stressful. So, it’s nice to see that Strava’s quietly added a new feature called Points of Interest that will help users find helpful locations on a given route. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x24qLh"&gt;According to a &lt;a href="https://support.strava.com/hc/en-us/articles/4420443741453-Points-of-Interest"&gt;Strava support post&lt;/a&gt;, Points of Interest is a feature that adds “community-powered local hotspots” to make outdoor activities like running, cycling, and hiking more enjoyable. These hot spots can include the obvious, like public restrooms and water fountains, as well as cafes, bike shops, photo spots, and other landmarks. The company says that the points are created from areas that are popular with Strava athletes from OpenStreetMap. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MQRleW"&gt;“Most maps have been optimized for cars, so we wanted to build a map oriented around athletes rather than vehicles,” Will Meyer, senior product manager for Strava’s Places team, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Dp-Lf16yI2uNkQTM-rnLJ7c7lQE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23179508/IMG_2486.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot: Victoria Song / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can also see Points of Interest in the mobile app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="L6iRWJ"&gt;The idea is to help athletes figure out the best part of an area to start an activity, as well as see where helpful areas might be located. Depending on whether you need a snack, bathroom break, or a place to refill a water bottle, you can now reroute yourself to a relevant area. While all Strava users will be able to see the Points of Interest map layer, subscribers can also create their own routes based around hotspots using the Routebuilder tool on the website or via the Maps tab in the app. There are also suggested Start Points, or popular areas where Strava users begin activities from. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D6Yt6r"&gt;Using Points of Interest is pretty straightforward — though, personally, it was most useful when planning out a route beforehand. (I try not to look at my phone while running, lest I run headfirst into a lamp post.) We’ll have to see how useful it ends up being when in a pinch. That said, it’s good to see fitness services adding handy navigational and safety tools for users. Aside from a case of runner’s trots, dehydration and “hitting the wall” are also major concerns that can leave runners, cyclists, or hikers in a lurch. This is particularly true for beginners, who may not have invested in a fitness watch with preloaded maps and primarily rely on smartphones. Aside from Strava, Garmin also recently announced its new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22883556/garmin-fenix-7-epix-gps-smartwatches-outdoors-fitness"&gt;Fenix 7 smartwatches&lt;/a&gt; would also include a similar feature dubbed Up Ahead that highlights aid stations, water, and elevation climbs on a given route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="INywSh"&gt;“Points of Interest has been in development for over five months, and more ways to interact with dynamic POI will be coming later this year, along with a suite of features that complement POI,” Meyer added. “We’re just getting started with how athletes can engage with points of interest and trailheads on Strava and working to build the best athlete-centric map.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891366/strava-routes-maps-points-of-interest-running"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891366/strava-routes-maps-points-of-interest-running</id>
    <author>
      <name>Victoria Song</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T14:45:08-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T14:45:08-05:00</updated>
    <title>Instagram is testing paid subscriptions with a small group of creators</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-kW_L_SKtAt_I9Q_JnQHOoKXBXc=/0x43:1024x726/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70409099/FJfCrvxVQAQkLQv.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Instagram&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FYPODQ"&gt;US Instagram users will soon be able to subscribe to a small number of creators and influencers to access exclusive content and features. In a blog post, the company says it’s launching &lt;a href="https://business.instagram.com/blog/subscriptions-creators-instagram-recurring-monthly-income/"&gt;a test of subscriptions&lt;/a&gt; today, with more creators being added in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="14uOl3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;10 creators are part of the early test, including basketball player Sedona Prince, Olympian Jordan Chiles, and astrologer Aliza Kelly&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rwQepO"&gt;Fans will pay a monthly fee to access subscriber-only content from creators they follow, like exclusive Lives and Stories. Subscribers will also get a purple badge by their username that signals their status to the creator. Price tiers will range from $0.99 to $99.99 per month, and creators can select the price point for their subscriptions. Co-head of product Ashley Yuki &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/instagram-launches-early-test-of-creator-subscriptions-in-the-u-s"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;that Instagram will not take a cut of creators’ subscription revenues “until at least 2023.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nq6ksp"&gt;Ten creators are part of the early test, including basketball player Sedona Prince, Olympian Jordan Chiles, and astrologer Aliza Kelly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mkNDEg"&gt;“I’m excited to keep building tools for creators to make a living doing creative work and to put these tools in more creators’ hands soon,” Mark Zuckerberg, CEO of Meta, which owns Instagram, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10114247293526361"&gt;wrote in a Facebook post&lt;/a&gt;. Facebook also has its own version of a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/creators/earn-money-with-subscriptions"&gt;subscription&lt;/a&gt; program for creators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JVA4lM"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mosseri/status/1483867380878958593"&gt;In a video today&lt;/a&gt;, Instagram head Adam Mosseri says subscriptions are “one of the best ways” for influencers and creators to have a predictable income. Some creators have already been monetizing Instagram features like Close Friends by &lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2019/09/close-friends-instagram-subscription-charge-influencers/598171/"&gt;charging fans a fee&lt;/a&gt; off-platform for access to Stories. Instagram and Facebook aren’t the only companies to roll out subscription models to compete with platforms like TikTok; in 2021, Twitter &lt;a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/product/2021/introducing-super-follows"&gt;introduced&lt;/a&gt; Super Follows, and some creators offer additional subscriber content off-platform on Patreon or Substack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nSHBKE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891722/instagram-paid-subscriptions-test"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891722/instagram-paid-subscriptions-test</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mia Sato</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T14:16:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T14:16:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>Belkin’s Boost Charge Pro is a $60 MagSafe puck with a kickstand and braided cable</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1ymzF4VRYu34a_agF_PV6_giTyo=/0x123:1000x790/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70408973/webdam.web.1000.1000.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The cable is also a meter longer than Apple’s version.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Belkin&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mbMu6O"&gt;Belkin’s new Boost Charge Pro wireless charging pad takes Apple’s MagSafe puck and ... well, makes it “pro” with a 2-meter-long braided cable and a kickstand for propping your phone up to make it easier to see while it’s charging (&lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2022/01/18/belkin-launches-magsafe-charger-with-kickstand/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). It also comes in black, a must for any accessory sporting the pro moniker. There is a bit of a catch, though — like many accessories with official MagSafe certification, it doesn’t come cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5BZjfn"&gt;At $60, which it’s listed at in both the &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/HPT72ZM/A/belkin-boost%E2%86%91charge%E2%84%A2-pro-portable-wireless-charger-pad-with-magsafe-special-edition"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.belkin.com%2Fus%2Fmagsafe-magnetic-accessories%2Fmagsafe%2Fboost-charge-pro-portable-wireless-charger-pad-with-magsafe-15w%2Fp%2Fp-wia004%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2022%2F1%2F19%2F22890567%2Fbelkin-boost-charge-pro-magsafe-puck-kickstand-braided-cable-expensive-chargers" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Belkin&lt;/a&gt; stores, the Boost Charge Pro costs significantly more than &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MHXH3AM/A/magsafe-charger?fnode=d76192b5c56e1c17af16d3c4b14699bc630d952cc4a5270eb57358c107d1627abb5684e394d566146208b03ae324c2aaaa5c81a50cc7b3e2458e016fb69760a3460ed0958f075e9ce2c4d0b285230d910e243d7c13efecd8d63a2f62b679a8140b7cb0349a986f62055ef44ac3ff3196"&gt;Apple’s $40 MagSafe charger&lt;/a&gt;, which was already seen as a bit on the pricy side. Yes, you do get that kickstand, and having a longer cable is definitely a plus. But is it really worth an extra $20, especially considering that you may need to budget for a USB-C charging brick, as it’s not included with either option?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ScN-V7xljU_DRjkbjNT6mJtOjDM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23178248/HPUC2_AV4.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Belkin&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ll admit it does look good in black.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="C0BeEF"&gt;This is a familiar story with MagSafe; despite the technology launching with the iPhone 12, MagSafe certified charging accessories aren’t particularly common. Amazon is full of MagSafe &lt;em&gt;compatible &lt;/em&gt;wireless chargers that’ll magnetically attach to your phone (some of them even have a kickstand!), but they’re almost certainly going to max out at 7.5W of charging instead of the 15W that MagSafe affords on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22691602/iphone-13-mini-slower-magsafe-charging-speeds-12w"&gt;non-Mini iPhones&lt;/a&gt;. (It’s also worth noting that some Amazon vendors still advertise their charging pucks as being capable of putting out 15W, but the listings usually&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;admit that number is only achievable on Samsung phones.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="jZ55d3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The handful of MagSafe accessories that are out have eye-popping prices&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JekqBu"&gt;When manufacturers do come out with MagSafe accessories, the prices are often eye-popping. Perhaps one of the most infamous instances is Belkin’s $40 Car Vent Mount Pro with MagSafe, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22387722/apple-magsafe-belkin-car-vent-mount-pro-review-no-charger"&gt;&lt;em&gt;is not capable of charging your phone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. But Belkin is far from the only company putting out pricy MagSafe accessories — &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2022/01/18/mophie-magsafe-travel-charger/"&gt;Mophie just announced&lt;/a&gt; a $150 three-in-one travel charging mat that has a MagSafe phone charger, an Apple Watch charging puck, and a (presumably Qi) charger for AirPods. Apple’s own MagSafe Duo Charger, which doesn’t include that extra AirPod pad, will set you back $130. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B0fdA8"&gt;Compared to those products, &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/HPP82ZM/A/mophie-3-in-1-stand-for-magsafe-charger?fnode=4e74707df6f53e9bea4a2730e6b91cc8e624a572af1b687dea4d8ba0f88f9a40a92e8c22b7be656ee1ca763cca646e95d9e1d17ce95265d37db2ba9c5e3b330a9dc2ef381460f0e183da6eae69971d7d1867d2eb196a2b5a5488fb315e9486761d4932a636f839dd87b6803cbb5dda19"&gt;Mophie’s $90 three-in-one stand&lt;/a&gt; that’s meant to stay at home almost seems reasonable — except for the fact that you have to bring your own MagSafe puck, putting its price in line with &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/HPU82ZM/A/belkin-boost%E2%86%91charge%E2%84%A2pro-3-in-1-wireless-charging-pad-with-magsafe?fnode=4e74707df6f53e9bea4a2730e6b91cc8e624a572af1b687dea4d8ba0f88f9a40a92e8c22b7be656ee1ca763cca646e95d9e1d17ce95265d37db2ba9c5e3b330a9dc2ef381460f0e183da6eae69971d7d1867d2eb196a2b5a5488fb315e9486761d4932a636f839dd87b6803cbb5dda19"&gt;Belkin’s similar $150 home charging mat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="SuTcSh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"A year later, Apple’s MagSafe continues to underwhelm","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728967/apple-magsafe-duo-wallet-cases-charging"},{"title":"Apple’s been playing it too MagSafe","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22629703/apple-magsafe-charging-mfi-standard-accessory"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="sVKV2e"&gt;This isn’t to say that MagSafe is bad or that these manufacturers should feel bad. It’s just that over a year since they were first introduced, MagSafe accessories are still quite expensive. And while Belkin’s latest puck doesn’t buck that trend, it is at least nice to have a MagSafe charger with a longer, braided cable that you won’t have to buy a separate stand for. It’s still &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22265910/belkin-magsafe-3-in-1-wireless-charger-hands-on-iphone-12-watch"&gt;not as cute as Belkin’s charging tree&lt;/a&gt;, though.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22890567/belkin-boost-charge-pro-magsafe-puck-kickstand-braided-cable-expensive-chargers"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22890567/belkin-boost-charge-pro-magsafe-puck-kickstand-braided-cable-expensive-chargers</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T14:15:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T14:15:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to file and pay your 2021 taxes online </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="irs (ray tsang flickr)" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2q0opZZPof55VL_p6_kem5Om2QQ=/0x3:1100x736/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70408963/irs.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QSUmXj"&gt;In 2020, the COVID-19 pandemic took everyone, including the IRS, by surprise, and the filing deadline for federal tax payments was moved from the usual mid-April date to July 15th. In 2021, the due date was pushed back to May 17th, 2021. Right now, however, it looks like we’ll be back to the traditional mid-April due dates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pThjvo"&gt;Actually, because the tax deadline can’t be the same day as an official holiday, most of us have until April 18th (April 15th is Emancipation Day in DC). If you live in Maine or Massachusetts, you actually have until April 19th because of Patriots’ Day. Need an extension? After you’ve &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22891931/taxes-file-extension-deadline-irs-how-to"&gt;applied for that extension&lt;/a&gt;, you have until October 17th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T1IHJ6"&gt;However, the IRS has also made it known that the &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/newsroom/irs-operations-during-covid-19-mission-critical-functions-continue"&gt;pandemic is still slowing down some operations&lt;/a&gt;, such as processing returns filed on paper. As a result, it might not be a bad idea to start working on those taxes as soon as possible — and to submit them online. In fact, whether you’re a full-time worker dealing with a single 1040 or a freelancer / gig worker getting a series of 1099s, the fastest way to pay the piper these days is to do it online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="7RmRXX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10286635"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DtewJZ"&gt;The IRS offers a series of directions &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/"&gt;on its website&lt;/a&gt; to help US citizens figure out their taxes, report those taxes, and send in payments (or ask for refunds) using its e-file online method. Here’s a rundown of what’s available and where you can find it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Your first stop: IRS.gov" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bropDdmR6TVbcwzKTPMNEQt_4Js=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23179136/Screen_Shot_2022_01_19_at_10.40.37_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your first stop: IRS.gov&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="MrTZxI"&gt;How do I file online?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Wfouu8"&gt;There are several ways to file online, depending on your income and your comfort level in dealing with the whole income tax process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IAGjYo"&gt;If your &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/e-file-providers/definition-of-adjusted-gross-income"&gt;adjusted gross income&lt;/a&gt; was $73,000 or under, you can use the &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/filing/free-file-do-your-federal-taxes-for-free"&gt;IRS Free File option&lt;/a&gt;. The site offers a number of third-party services that can help you put together and file your taxes free of charge. Of course, that is assuming the third party doesn’t try to scam you into paying more than you have to; back in April of 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/turbotax-deliberately-hides-its-free-file-page-from-search-engines"&gt;&lt;em&gt;ProPublica&lt;/em&gt; revealed&lt;/a&gt; that TurboTax and other suppliers were deliberately hiding the pages for their free services in order to convince taxpayers to purchase additional features. As a result, in early 2020, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/1/21045779/irs-turbotax-free-file-h-r-block-tax-preparation-new-rules"&gt;IRS published rules&lt;/a&gt; prohibiting these practices. Still, it pays to be careful.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Free File is available for those whose income is $73,000 or less." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w7fFoMfWnTL-co_lcFIqLOtGLtQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23179142/Screen_Shot_2022_01_19_at_10.43.17_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Free File is available for those whose income is $73,000 or less.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fC7FEJ"&gt;If your income is above $73,000, you can still use fillable forms provided by IRS Free File, but you don’t get the support of the free software, and you can’t do your state taxes through this method. The forms will be available starting on January 24th. (If you’re really into doing your own taxes, you may want to check out the &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/newsroom/irs-tax-tips"&gt;IRS page on tax tips&lt;/a&gt;, which includes how to handle things like &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/newsroom/taxpayers-must-report-gig-economy-earnings-when-filing-taxes"&gt;gig economy earnings&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dlnklN"&gt;If you’re not a pro at filling out taxes, you’re going to either have to use e-file with one of the available software solutions or find a tax preparer who can do it for you. For those whose income is $58,000 or less, the IRS has a program called the Volunteer Income Tax Assistance (VITA) to help with tax preparation; there is also Tax Counseling for the Elderly (TCE) for people who are 60 or older. The &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/individuals/free-tax-return-preparation-for-qualifying-taxpayers"&gt;page describing these programs&lt;/a&gt; has a locator tool so you can find one of these sites near you; considering the current pandemic, it’s likely that much of the help will happen over the phone or via videoconferencing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yHhDuA"&gt;If you use a tax preparer, the person or company who does your taxes needs to be authorized to use e-file; if you don’t already have a tax professional, you can find one at &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/e-file-providers/authorized-irs-e-file-provider-locator-service-for-tax-professionals"&gt;the IRS site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="5JFGLd"&gt;How do I pay online?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="qQd1r5"&gt;The IRS lists a variety of ways you can &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/payments"&gt;pay your taxes online&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EmMzlE"&gt;If you use tax preparation software or have your taxes prepared by a tax professional, you can have the IRS pull the funds directly from your bank account via the &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/payments/eftps-the-electronic-federal-tax-payment-system"&gt;Electronic Federal Tax Payment System (EFTPS)&lt;/a&gt; at the same time you file. Be aware that, according to the IRS, it can take up to five business days to process a new enrollment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JwT6HE"&gt;You can also use &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/payments/direct-pay"&gt;IRS Direct Pay&lt;/a&gt; to pull funds from a savings or checking account. Finally, you can &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/payments/pay-your-taxes-by-debit-or-credit-card"&gt;use a credit or debit card&lt;/a&gt;; however, there is a fee involved (since the IRS isn’t going to absorb what your credit card company is charging for the service). In fact, if you use a credit card, you may have to add as much as 1.98 percent of your payment amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ugxyPN"&gt;How do I get my refund?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="o8jn9l"&gt;One of the ways the IRS tries to convince you to file online is to assure you that you will get your refund faster — &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/refunds/tax-season-refund-frequently-asked-questions"&gt;in less than 21 days&lt;/a&gt;, in most cases, although there are exceptions. Once you’ve filed, you can &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/refunds"&gt;check the status&lt;/a&gt; of your refund online. You can also &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/newsroom/irs2goapp"&gt;download the official IRS2Go&lt;/a&gt; mobile app, which allows you to check the status of your refund, pay your taxes, and get other information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l9GmZM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22889295/taxes-irs-file-pay-online-2021-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22889295/taxes-irs-file-pay-online-2021-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
