<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-23T07:00:36-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-23T07:00:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-23T07:00:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple lawsuit over ‘buy’ and ‘rent’ labels for digital content can continue, rules federal judge</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fq0LmCW3roSsZeMH42Rdq4LXNcA=/42x0:1590x1032/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69174133/apple_previews_macos_catalina_apple_music_screen_06032019.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZAqtTC"&gt;A federal judge has rejected a motion by Apple to dismiss a putative class action lawsuit over the company’s use of the labels “buy” and “rent” when selling digital content. As first covered by &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/thr-esq/apple-must-face-lawsuit-for-telling-consumers-they-can-buy-movies-tv-shows"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hollywood Reporter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the suit can now continue, though could yet be settled before ever reaching trial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xnmeP6"&gt;The lead plaintiff in the case, David Andino, argues that Apple is misleading consumers when it tells them it can “buy” digital versions of albums, TV shows, and films from its stores. Why? Because the iPhone-maker retains the power to terminate customers’ access to this content whenever it likes. This can happen, for example, when the company loses distribution rights to content that users haven’t secured by downloading to their device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="HAO8ke"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Just like Best Buy cannot come into a person’s home to repossess [your] DVD”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="M0ptNB"&gt;“Just like Best Buy cannot come into a person’s home to repossess the movie DVD that such person purchased from it, defendant should not be able to remove, or permit the removal by others of, digital content from its customers,” says Andino’s &lt;a href="http://casefilingsalert.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Apple-Video-Content.pdf"&gt;lawsuit&lt;/a&gt;. “Though some consumers may get lucky and never lose access to any of their paid for media, others may one day find that their digital content is now gone forever.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i7Oc68"&gt;Apple attempted to have the case dismissed, but a ruling this week by US District Court Judge John Mendez shows that the company’s arguments weren’t entirely convincing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WA5YOC"&gt;“Apple contends that ‘[n]o reasonable consumer would believe’ that purchased content would remain on the iTunes platform indefinitely,” wrote Mendez in an &lt;a href="https://cases.justia.com/federal/district-courts/california/caedce/2:2020cv01628/377618/22/0.pdf?ts=1618990542"&gt;order&lt;/a&gt; filed with the Eastern District of California. “But in common usage, the term ‘buy’ means to acquire possession over something. It seems plausible, at least at the motion to dismiss stage, that reasonable consumers would expect their access couldn’t be revoked.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="XIvBgO"&gt;&lt;q&gt;To quote Webster’s definition of “buy”...&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="O69b21"&gt;To emphasize his point, Mendez pointed to the definition of the word “buy” in the &lt;a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/buy"&gt;Mirriam-Webster dictionary&lt;/a&gt; (meaning “to acquire possession, ownership, or rights to the use or services of by payment especially of money”) — a timeless move that is, apparently, as welcome in federal legal proceedings as in hastily-written wedding speeches. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="27Kz4t"&gt;Apple tried to argue that Andino’s “injury” was purely speculative, as he has not actually lost access to any content. But, as Mendez summarizes, the injury being presented is not the threat of losing future access, but the deception involved in Apple’s use of the word “buy.” This misleads consumers about the exact nature of ownership, meaning Andino “paid either too much for the product or spent money he would not have but for the misrepresentation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EwygkI"&gt;Apple did have some success, though, and one element of the lawsuit was dismissed: Andino’s claims to “unjust enrichment,” which would affect how any potential damages would be calculated. Mendez did, though, leave open the possibility of future “injunctive relief” — that is, material changes to how Apple sells content in future. All these questions, though, will have to be settled in future proceedings. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22399008/apple-lawsuit-over-buy-and-rent-labels-for-digital-content-can-continue-rules-federal-judge"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22399008/apple-lawsuit-over-buy-and-rent-labels-for-digital-content-can-continue-rules-federal-judge</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-23T07:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-23T07:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Keychron K3 wireless keyboard review: compact with compromises</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;The K3 is remarkably thin, but at the cost of versatility&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="gvBxVo"&gt;Keychron’s keyboards are an appealing option for anyone looking for a relatively affordable wireless mechanical keyboard. Its latest model is the Keychron K3, which starts at $74. The K3 combines the low-profile design of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/13/18223192/mechanical-wireless-keyboard-mac-keychron-k1-review-specs-features"&gt;K1&lt;/a&gt; with the compact 75 percent layout of the K2. The result is a keyboard with a slim and compact form factor, with a height that sits somewhere between a typical mechanical keyboard and a keyboard with laptop-style switches. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UobozL"&gt;It’s a tempting prospect if you’re after a compact, portable board that won’t take up too much space in a laptop bag. The K3 also features several other useful features like hot-swappable switch options that let you completely change the feel of your keyboard without having to do any soldering and cross-compatibility with Windows and Mac. But unless you really want or need a thin keyboard, the K3’s low-profile design comes with compromises that hold the keyboard back from being the perfect choice for everybody. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8hk6j6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10460080"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bStDKq"&gt;The Keychron K3 is available with either a white backlight for $74 or an RGB backlight for $84. In terms of switches, you have the choice of a set of low-profile switches made by Gateron or a set of Keychron’s hot-swappable optical switches. Keychron claims these optical switches are &lt;a href="https://www.keychron.com/blogs/news/the-difference-between-optical-switches-and-mechanical-switches#:~:text=Optical%20switches%20can%20have%20the,soldering%20switches%20to%20a%20PCB."&gt;more responsive and durable&lt;/a&gt;, but more important is that, unlike the Gaterons, they’re hot-swappable, meaning you can remove and replace them without having to do any soldering. Varieties of these optical switches include linear (white, red, or black), tactile (brown), or clicky (blue or orange) switches. That’s a good amount of options, and &lt;a href="https://www.keychron.com/products/low-profile-keychron-optical-switch-set-87-pcs?variant=32264204451929"&gt;Keychron is currently selling sets&lt;/a&gt; of these for $19 (regular price $25). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PQkgql"&gt;My model came with a US ANSI layout with RGB backlighting. I primarily used Keychron’s brown optical switches during my time with the K3, but I switched to its stiff clicky orange switches for a few days to see what they were like. Keychron tells me a version of the keyboard with a UK ISO layout will release in July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iQLlju"&gt;If you’re familiar with the keyboard layout used by most laptops, then you’ll immediately feel at home with the Keychron K3’s so-called “75 percent” keyboard layout. It’s a lot more compact than a full-size keyboard layout (one that has a number pad on the side) or even a tenkeyless (same thing, minus the number pad), but it still includes arrow keys and a function row, as well as five out of the six keys normally placed above the arrow key cluster. (There’s no dedicated “Insert” key, but the built-in shortcut is Fn + Delete.) The function row also offers Mac- and Windows-compatible media keys, like brightness and volume control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f8qDVuIU51uSrX7wXb35aJM6U_c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22462173/jporter_20210420_4539_0007.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Its 75 percent layout includes arrow keys.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YifzZCDGrmb18G_OGg6hNPFhEdM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22462171/jporter_20210420_4539_0005.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The compact layout finds room for the most commonly used keys.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="q2wVHf"&gt;For many people, especially those accustomed to a laptop, I suspect this will be all the keys they’ll require, and I never found myself needing a key that’s not present on the keyboard. I also don’t think there are any keys that are wildly misplaced, like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/13/18223192/mechanical-wireless-keyboard-mac-keychron-k1-review-specs-features"&gt;original K1&lt;/a&gt;’s annoyingly easy-to-hit backlighting key. That’s helpful because the Keychron K3 doesn’t let you natively remap its keys, meaning you can’t reconfigure the keyboard to change key locations or add others that might be more important for your needs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vpBEgh"&gt;Keychron advertises that you can technically remap your keyboard’s keys at the OS level using programs like &lt;a href="https://karabiner-elements.pqrs.org/"&gt;Karabiner on the Mac&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.randyrants.com/category/sharpkeys/"&gt;SharpKeys on Windows&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s a bit hacky and means your keyboard’s layout will change if you ever need to connect it to another device. I don’t think most people will have major problems with Keychron’s 75 percent layout, but beware if you’ve got muscle memory built up from using another compact board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iKzirf"&gt;There is one layout customization option built into the keyboard, and that’s a small switch on the top-left of the keyboard to swap it between Mac / iOS and Windows / Android layouts. The keyboard also comes with Mac-specific Command and Option keycaps out of the box, but if you’re a Windows user like me, there are Alt and Windows keys included for you to install on the board during setup. Just use the included keycap puller to whip off the Mac keys and press the Windows keys firmly onto the switches in their place. (Here’s a &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/s_cTrV7QLbA?t=84"&gt;quick video guide&lt;/a&gt; in case you’ve never done this before.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Bxbg-EYYHCrB8aF5DHmHv0qVwoY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22462176/jporter_20210420_4539_0012.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Swapping the keyboard’s switches is relatively simple.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HhGMQV"&gt;The other switch on the top left of the K3 is a slider to swap it between its wired and wireless modes. Wired mode works as expected over the K3’s included USB-C cable, while wireless mode lets you pair with up to three devices over Bluetooth 5.1. I paired the K3 with a Surface laptop, iPhone, and iPad, and the keyboard switched between them with no issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R6niiK"&gt;Wireless users should note that battery life has taken a dip compared to the K2. With the backlight off, Keychron says the K3 should last around 99 hours, down from 240 hours with the K2. With the backlight on, battery life drops as low as 34 hours (down from between 68 and 72 hours). That’s likely because the K3’s slim form factor means Keychron can only fit in a 1,550mAh battery rather than a 4,000mAh one like the K2. I was switching between wired and wireless modes throughout the review period, which meant I never saw the keyboard’s battery life run down to zero. But these numbers mean you’ll likely have to recharge the K3 on a weekly basis if you want to keep the lights on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aChbj7"&gt;On the underside of my review sample, there is a pair of flip-out feet to adjust the angle of the keyboard. I’m told these were added as a revision compared to the first boards, which came with two sets of feet for you to swap between if you wanted to change its angle. I can’t speak for how annoying a system this might have been, but the new feet support two different angles, and they’re easy to use. Keychron tells me it still has stock of the model without flipping feet and that this new model should be in circulation by late May. Build quality is otherwise solid, with little flex in the keyboard’s casing on my model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dbA8sjE2tFyDLNcX7M332BBb4uI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22462175/jporter_20210420_4539_0010.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The flip-out feet can be set at two different heights.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Xwiqq6WD4D5H7WUHCJgoMSRynhg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22462169/jporter_20210420_4539_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;I mean, just look at how thin this thing is.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BzMCYX"&gt;One of the nicest things about buying a mechanical keyboard with traditional Cherry MX-style switches is the customization options you get. If you want a more colorful or interesting set of keycaps or if the keycaps on your board wear out over time, then it’s normally easy to swap them out for a new set. Swapping out actual switches after the fact is generally a little harder because it often requires soldering, so it’s not popular in quite the same way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jrc02h"&gt;In some ways, the Keychron K3 flips this dynamic on its head. Its hot-swappable keyswitches are easy to swap out without needing to pick up a soldering iron, but while its keycaps are just as easy to remove, there’s not much reason to. That’s because there are no third-party keycaps on the market that are fully compatible with Keychron’s low-profile design at the moment. The Cherry MX-style cross design suggests they should be, but when I tried some I had lying around, the stabilizer alignment on keys like the spacebar didn’t line up. Keychron tells me it plans to release new keycap sets later in the year for the board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6qZG9F"&gt;It’s a shame because it would be nice to have the option of replacing Keychron’s stock keycaps. They are made of thin ABS plastic rather than the more premium PBT or thicker ABS, and their gray-and-orange color scheme is plain dull. At least their legends are crisp, they’re nicely curved to let your fingers find their placement, and their double-shot construction allows the keyboard’s backlighting to shine through and illuminate each key label.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1lHXQS"&gt;Swapping out the switches themselves was much easier than pulling out a soldering iron, though it still took a little bit of elbow grease to remove some of the more stubborn ones using the included tool. It works by clipping the metal hook around each switch and wiggling until it comes free. Swapping out all the switches took me around half an hour while watching TV in the background, plus an extra 15 minutes on either end to deal with the keycaps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OVDfrQ22uFgsItys2ntRkqwhKGc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22462172/jporter_20210420_4539_0006.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;With limited keycap compatibility, you better get used to the K3’s stock caps.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="z7kdKe"&gt;As well as being hot-swappable, the benefit of these low-profile switches is how thin they allow the board itself to be. At its thickest point, it’s a little over 22mm off the surface of your desk, and Keychron boasts that its low-profile optical switches are just 10.77mm tall, compared to 17.9mm for a conventional switch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AwGqTV"&gt;But being so low-profile makes these optical switches a bit of an acquired taste. Whether I used the brown optical switches that originally came installed in the board, or the stiff and clicky optical orange switches, I never loved the typing experience of the Keychron K3. It’s not awful. This isn’t a mushy rubber dome or MacBook butterfly keyboard. But the limited key travel of the K3’s low-profile switches feels unsatisfying if you’re used to, and like, regular Cherry MX-style switches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div id="pAUQrp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10460594"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="lBhcGj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10460601"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8p6tnL"&gt;Of the two switches I tried, I preferred the stiff and clicky orange switches over the tactile browns. The stiffness of the orange switches combined with the more tactile click went some way to making up for their low travel, while I ended up making more typos while typing on the browns. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X2C7lz"&gt;At the end of the day, I just plain like the height of a standard MX switch. That extra distance gives your fingers space to make mistakes and pull back before pressing the wrong key. In contrast, there’s something jarring about having a key bottom out so quickly. If you’re used to typing on slim keyboards like Apple Magic Keyboard, then the K3’s low key travel might feel more pleasant and familiar. But as someone who likes regular MX-style switches, I wasn’t a fan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Cd7B1sJD_SkX5y1KqQey7_HXbYQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22462174/jporter_20210420_4539_0008.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are Windows- and Mac-specific keys in the box.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nY-YaH2zj_sUM93tKUHfKy3zFY0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22462170/jporter_20210420_4539_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;RGB lighting shining through the keycaps.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Uivn6B"&gt;The Keychron K3 is a feature-packed mechanical keyboard at a reasonable price. It works great over USB-C or wirelessly, and it has a 75 percent layout that covers the keys most people need, as well as a useful selection of function keys on top of that. The hot-swapping process is easy, and Keychron has a suitable selection of switches that work with its hot-swap system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PiBGrr"&gt;But Keychron has had to make a series of compromises to make a keyboard this slim, and you have to want a low-profile keyboard to put up with them. Battery life has taken a dip compared to the K2, and the K3’s low-profile switches can be an acquired taste. The lack of support for third-party keycaps is also unfortunate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="QCQVx6"&gt;If you’ve got a strong preference for a low-profile keyboard and you’re not interested in trying out third-party keycaps, then the K3 is a nice package. But it can’t match the versatility of Keychron’s other boards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tdmcro"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Jon Porter / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22397467/kechron-k3-wireless-keyboard-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22397467/kechron-k3-wireless-keyboard-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-23T06:01:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-23T06:01:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>SpaceX launches its third astronaut crew, the first on a used Crew Dragon capsule</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ho0SqHZ6TuWiKi4n_zoy4iR4-68=/218x0:1691x982/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69173973/Screen_Shot_2021_04_23_at_5.50.59_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;SpaceX’s Falcon 9 rocket launches four astronauts to space | NASA&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xH1Tbv"&gt;SpaceX launched its third crew of astronauts to the International Space Station early Friday morning, reusing a Crew Dragon space capsule to fly humans for the first time. The mission, dubbed Crew-2, is the latest flight under NASA’s Commercial Crew Program, and will add four more astronauts to the orbital space station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6RxaPU"&gt;A used Falcon 9 rocket, last flown for SpaceX’s Crew-1 mission last year, lifted off at 5:49AM ET from Cape Canaveral, Florida carrying Endeavor, the same Crew Dragon capsule that first launched SpaceX’s debut astronaut mission nearly one year ago. For this flight, the Endeavor capsule carried four astronauts from three different countries — SpaceX’s most diverse NASA-managed crew yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EEHnA1"&gt;“Off the Earth, for the Earth, Endeavor is ready to go,” NASA astronaut Shane Kimbrough, the mission’s spacecraft commander, told SpaceX mission control in Hawthorne, California minutes before lifting off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="LfyifY"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;3.. 2.. 1.. and liftoff! Endeavour launches once again. Four astronauts from three countries on Crew-2, now making their way to the one and only &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Space_Station?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Space_Station&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href="https://t.co/WDAl8g7bUK"&gt;pic.twitter.com/WDAl8g7bUK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— NASA (@NASA) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NASA/status/1385531690458783744?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 23, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="11skq9"&gt;Kimbrough and fellow NASA astronaut Megan McArthur, serving as the pilot, accompanied mission specialists Akihiko Hoshide of the Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency (JAXA) and Thomas Pesquet, a French aerospace engineer from the European Space Agency (ESA). The crew will spend roughly 23 hours in transit as Endeavor autonomously raises its orbit toward the ISS ahead of a 5:10AM ET docking tomorrow, April 24th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x1888i"&gt;Sunlight beamed into the windows of Crew Dragon Endeavor as it separated from its Falcon 9 second stage booster roughly 12 minutes after the pre-dawn liftoff, prompting cheers and applause from engineers on a live video feed in SpaceX’s mission control. “Thanks for flying our first flight-proven, crewed Falcon 9,” mission control said to Endeavor, confirming a successful arrival in orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2YOdHo"&gt;“We’re great, glad to be back in space for all of us, and we’ll send our regards to Crew-1 when we get there,” Kimbrough, seen on live camera feeds from inside Crew Dragon, replied from Endeavor. A stuffed penguin toy, serving as a microgravity indicator, rose from under the astronauts’ seats once they reached orbit. The capsule’s separation occurred just as Falcon 9’s first stage booster returned back to Earth for landing on SpaceX’s “Of Course I Still Love You” drone-ship in the Atlantic Ocean. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nbjZ3T"&gt;Kimbrough, McArthur, Hoshide and Pesquet will spend six months in space and join seven astronauts already aboard the space station, an orbital science laboratory flying more than 17,000 miles per hour in orbit roughly 250 miles above Earth. Two days after the crew’s arrival, four other astronauts from SpaceX’s Crew-1 mission, which launched to the ISS November 15 last year, will board a separate Crew Dragon capsule and return to Earth to cap their own six-month stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VDVKxF"&gt;Crew-2 marks SpaceX’s third astronaut mission under NASA’s Commercial Crew Program, the agency’s public-private initiative to revive its human spaceflight capabilities after a nearly 10-year dependence on Russian rockets. It’s the second of six operational missions SpaceX is contracted to fly under that program, which awarded the company $2.6 billion in 2014 to develop and fly Crew Dragon. SpaceX’s first crewed mission in May 2020, carrying Bob Behnken and Doug Hurley, counted as a test flight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ST0hMw"&gt;Accompanied by two Russian cosmonauts and NASA’s Mark Vande Hei, who all launched on a Russian Soyuz rocket on April 9th, Crew-2’s stay aboard the ISS will make for an 7-person crew in space for the next several months. During their stay, the crew will conduct an array of microgravity science experiments. The Crew-2 astronauts’ science efforts will center on a cassette-sized device containing human cells to &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/tissue-chips"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; how those cells respond to various drugs and health conditions in microgravity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dEShcT"&gt;The increased crew size means other science experiments, including a few projects tracking how plants grow and behave in space, will also see some progress. “It’s like a party up there,” said Annmarie Eldering, a project scientist at NASA’s Jet Propulsion Laboratory working on Orbiting Carbon Observatory-3, a device astronauts will use to measure carbon dioxide in Earth’s atmosphere. “When you get all those measurements from space, in the same time, same place, it’s really powerful for science,” Eldering said Friday morning in a live NASA broadcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YA2JDa"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XpvpHU"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w5NGf2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LURYAs"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e6iodC"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MdOH2t"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k5CSeq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q5etw1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22398981/spacex-launches-third-nasa-astronaut-crew-used-crew-dragon-capsule"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22398981/spacex-launches-third-nasa-astronaut-crew-used-crew-dragon-capsule</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-23T05:45:40-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-23T05:45:40-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google is developing a price tracking feature for Chrome on Android</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AQLyadSDT6S-JYNM9stJOv2b1Do=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69173916/acastro_180416_1777_chrome_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kCYdpC"&gt;The latest version of Chrome on Android has started rolling out a new price tracking feature to alert you about price drops. &lt;a href="https://www.smartdroid.de/chrome-preisnachlaesse-tabs-alarm/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;SmartDroid &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; receiving the new feature in Chrome version 90, though it doesn’t seem to be live for everyone. Once activated, Chrome monitors your open tabs for any price drops, and sends you a notification if any happen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GYHQfe"&gt;It could be a useful bit of functionality for the Android app, which isn’t compatible with price tracking extensions like &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/keepa-amazon-price-tracke/neebplgakaahbhdphmkckjjcegoiijjo?hl=en"&gt;Keepa&lt;/a&gt; that are available for Chrome’s desktop client. But the requirement that you keep a tab open in order to track its prices seems clunky. Hopefully Google finds a sleeker solution before the feature gets a widespread rollout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dabfaeYdhh8r_dgFMPVdREzNiEU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22464288/Screenshot_20210421_101455.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2021/04/21/chrome-price-tracking-android/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Once enabled, the feature is accessible from the settings menu in the tab selection screen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e7FNR7vvteJrLWxHXssg_7f0lgw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22464289/Screenshot_20210421_101458.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2021/04/21/chrome-price-tracking-android/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The tool promises to let you “See price drops on your tabs.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cNTdmY"&gt;If your version of Chrome has been updated with the feature, you can turn it on via the three dot settings menu in the top right of the tab select screen where it’s listed as “Track prices.” If it’s not appearing, &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/04/21/heres-how-to-enable-chromes-nifty-new-price-tracking-feature/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/04/21/chrome-price-tracking-android/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt; report&lt;/a&gt; that you may be able to manually enable it by going to “chrome://flags/#enable-tab-grid-layout” in the address bar, tapping into the drop down menu, and selecting “Enabled Price notifications.” Your browser may need to be restarted again before the feature appears. The technique doesn’t work for everyone however, since we weren’t able to enable the feature using this method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8JJyW2"&gt;News of Chrome’s price tracking feature comes just months after Microsoft’s Edge browser &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/8/21507374/microsoft-edge-price-comparisons-screenshot-tool-features"&gt;added a price comparison tool&lt;/a&gt;, which was shortly followed by built-in support for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/19/21575038/microsoft-edge-coupons-promo-codes-feature-pdf-annotation-screenshot-inking"&gt;coupon and promo codes&lt;/a&gt;. Firefox also trialed a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/12/18087772/firefox-price-wise-test-pilot-mozilla"&gt;price tracking feature back in 2018&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/firefox/price-wise/"&gt;Price Wise&lt;/a&gt;; though it doesn’t appear to have ever received an official release since.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22399007/google-chrome-android-price-tracker-drop-notification"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22399007/google-chrome-android-price-tracker-drop-notification</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-23T04:56:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-23T04:56:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Live: Watch SpaceX’s third crewed mission to the ISS</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tIviU0RLZsBKAKAFw9yl-Ndvhg8=/0x0:2048x1365/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69171211/51130235765_cc815b0c41_k.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;(NASA/Joel Kowsky)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HXRZ6P"&gt;SpaceX is slated to launch its third crew to the International Space Station early Friday morning, ferrying two astronauts from NASA, one from the Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency, and the first European Space Agency astronaut to fly a private US spacecraft to orbit. The four-person crew will launch atop SpaceX’s Falcon 9 rocket at 5:49AM ET on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NuHIpk"&gt;The mission, dubbed Crew-2, marks the second operational mission under the Commercial Crew Program, NASA’s public-private initiative to revive its human spaceflight capabilities after a 10-year dependence on Russian rockets. It will mark the first time NASA astronauts fly a reused crew capsule — Crew-2’s ride first flew in May 2020 as SpaceX’s first astronaut mission, carrying Bob Behnken and Doug Hurley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BW7ogz"&gt;The crew includes NASA astronauts Shane Kimbrough, the mission’s spacecraft commander, and Megan McArthur, serving as the pilot. JAXA astronaut Akihiko Hoshide and ESA astronaut Thomas Pesquet, a French aerospace engineer, will serve as mission specialists. All the astronauts are in Florida ahead of the launch, and they’ll wake up at 11:09PM ET Thursday to prepare for flight. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Imq9V"&gt;NASA’s live coverage of the mission will begin hours before liftoff, at 1:30AM ET Friday. Liftoff is at 5:49AM ET. The trek to the International Space Station will take a little less than a day — the crew is scheduled to dock with the space station at around 5:10AM ET Saturday, April 24th. They’ll spend six months on the station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="BFPCCc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHAT TIME IS SPACEX’S CREW-2 LAUNCH?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="czmgig"&gt;SpaceX’s Falcon 9 rocket will take off on Friday, April 23rd, from NASA’s Kennedy Space Center in Cape Canaveral, Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZWQqcV"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scheduled launch time:&lt;/strong&gt; New York: 5:49AM / San Francisco: 2:49AM / London: 10:49AM / Berlin: 11:49AM / Moscow: 12:49PM / New Delhi: 3:19 PM / Beijing: 5:49PM / Tokyo: 6:49PM / Melbourne: 7:49PM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="QcT0EO"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOW TO WATCH SPACEX’S CREW DRAGON LAUNCH LIVE:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="NLS82h"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Live stream:&lt;/strong&gt; NASA’s live stream coverage can be found &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=21X5lGlDOfg"&gt;on YouTube&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/nasalive"&gt;on the agency’s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2TWn6N"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oTdJ86"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ys4RyX"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cYJj59"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xRYNgz"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zKHnC5"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4jJzLe"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22395543/spacex-liftoff-how-to-watch-nasa-iss-third-crewed-mission"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22395543/spacex-liftoff-how-to-watch-nasa-iss-third-crewed-mission</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-23T04:20:15-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-23T04:20:15-04:00</updated>
    <title>New Siri Remote waves goodbye to Apple TV games that require motion control</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EVlOdKQnByZasU0uBk2tT9_NSXs=/121x0:1414x862/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69173835/WcGeQVXeT3.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SFX6wg"&gt;Apple’s new Siri Remote doesn’t come equipped with an accelerometer or gyroscope, which means it won’t work as a motion controller in certain Apple TV games. The omission was initially &lt;a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/new-siri-remote-59-dollars/"&gt;spotted by &lt;em&gt;Digital Trends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and can be seen on the remotes’ product pages. The &lt;a href="https://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:ir5H-fryxNwJ:https://www.apple.com/uk/shop/product/MQGD2ZM/A/siri-remote+&amp;amp;cd=1&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ct=clnk&amp;amp;gl=uk"&gt;old&lt;/a&gt; Siri Remote lists an “Accelerometer” and “Three-axis gyro” in the tech specs, but they’re missing from the &lt;a href="https://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:n66JH8vbfHYJ:https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MJFM3LL/A/siri-remote+&amp;amp;cd=1&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ct=clnk&amp;amp;gl=uk"&gt;new listing&lt;/a&gt; (we’ve linked to a Google Cache because as of this writing Apple’s store is down ahead of AirTags pre-orders going live).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H7asiI"&gt;The change means that the new Siri Remote won’t work with certain Apple TV games that rely on motion controls. According to code in tvOS 14.5 &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/04/22/new-siri-remote-lacks-accelerometer-gyroscope/?utm_source=feedly&amp;amp;utm_medium=webfeeds"&gt;seen by &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, trying to play an incompatible game will lead to the following error message: “To play this game on your Apple TV, you need to connect the Apple TV Remote (1st generation) or a compatible PlayStation, Xbox or MFi controller.” If you’ve got one, you might want to keep an old Siri Remote around for occasions like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KQhZTH"&gt;The lack of motion controls might sound surprising given the new Apple TV box was expected to have a bigger gaming focus, and arrives as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22370217/apple-arcade-fantasian-nba2k-wonderbox-classics-netflix"&gt;Apple Arcade is maturing&lt;/a&gt; into a pretty compelling games subscription service. But in recent years Apple has shifted its attention towards more traditional gaming controllers, away from motion controls. It dropped its requirement for games to support the Siri Remote’s motion controls &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2016/6/14/11930760/apple-tv-games-controller-remote-requirement"&gt;in June 2016&lt;/a&gt; just months after the remote launched alongside the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/10/28/9630952/new-apple-tv-4-review"&gt;2015 Apple TV&lt;/a&gt;. Then, in June 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/3/18650683/apple-tv-xbox-one-ps4-controller-support-wwdc-2019"&gt;it announced&lt;/a&gt; Apple TV support for Xbox One and PS4 controllers. Support for PS5 and Xbox Series X and S controllers is &lt;a href="https://www.flatpanelshd.com/news.php?subaction=showfull&amp;amp;id=1612241720"&gt;expected to arrive with tvOS 14.5&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dTdow6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WJqfkY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22398974/apple-tv-siri-remote-motion-controls-accelerometer-three-axis-gyro"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22398974/apple-tv-siri-remote-motion-controls-accelerometer-three-axis-gyro</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-23T00:13:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-23T00:13:16-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple extends reprieve, won’t take a cut of online classes and events until next year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/q9YV-Fg0lbSGN7QOfXK9oShZhfg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69173462/acastro_190322_1777_apple_streaming_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Vl0knn"&gt;Apple announced on Wednesday that it’s &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=6qfoid1d&amp;amp;1619114022"&gt;once again extending the deadline&lt;/a&gt; for requiring in-app purchases for iOS apps that sell access to online classes and group events until December 31st, 2021, effectively meaning it won’t impose its 30 percent cut on businesses providing those services until next year. Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/23/21595040/apple-developer-in-app-purchase-deadline-online-classes-events"&gt;extended the deadline initially to June 30th, 2021&lt;/a&gt;, but now developers have another six months. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2TeBrI"&gt;Apple cites the ongoing pandemic as its main justification for the change, but we have to wonder if it might also have something to do with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22396544/apple-app-store-google-play-monopoly-antitrust-bill-hearings"&gt;the Congressional antitrust hearings that have zeroed in on whether Apple and Google’s app stores are monopolies&lt;/a&gt;. Helping out small businesses by not taking its traditional 30 percent cut is an example Apple can now use to demonstrate how it encourages small businesses to flourish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DGWxmt"&gt;Wednesday’s &lt;a href="https://www.judiciary.senate.gov/meetings/antitrust-applied-examining-competition-in-app-stores"&gt;“Antitrust Applied: Examining Competition in App Stores”&lt;/a&gt; hearing featured complaints from lost item tracker company Tile, who Apple is now in direct competition with thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22396693/apple-airtag-location-tracker-hands-on-find-my-privacy-safety"&gt;Apple’s new AirTags&lt;/a&gt;, and Match Group, whose Tinder dating app uses Apple’s in-app purchases for subscriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4oDlVz"&gt;Not every company pays 30 percent. Apple doesn’t apply the same in-app purchases requirement to one-on-one classes like tutoring, so individuals can take other forms of payments and bypass Apple’s cut entirely. Apple’s also been criticized for quietly creating special deals for big companies like Amazon, where subscriptions sold on its Prime Video app &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/30/21348108/apple-amazon-prime-video-app-store-special-treatment-fee-subscriptions"&gt;are only subject to a 15 percent fee&lt;/a&gt;. (Generally, Apple doesn’t reduce its cut of subscription fees to 15 percent until users have been subscribed for a full year.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bGfuN5"&gt;After Amazon’s seeming sweetheart deal came to light, Apple launched a new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/18/21572302/apple-app-store-small-business-program-commission-cut-15-percent-reduction"&gt;App Store Small Business Program&lt;/a&gt; in January 2021 where developers who earn less than $1 million in sales every year can apply to lower Apple’s commission to 15 percent on purchases — but only with Apple’s approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NVIcV8"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22381980/apple-podcasts-app-subscriptions-new-design"&gt;Apple is now launching podcast subscriptions too&lt;/a&gt;, ones where podcasters can join by paying $19.99 a year plus 30 percent of each subscriber’s first year of revenue, then 15 percent after for subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="enJjh1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Can Apple get you to pay for podcasts?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22396042/apple-podcast-subscriptions-launch-price"},{"title":"Apple’s $64 billion-a-year App Store isn’t catching the most egregious scams","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22385859/apple-app-store-scams-fraud-review-enforcement-top-grossing-kosta-eleftheriou"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22398338/apple-iap-classes-events-deadline-december-2021-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22398338/apple-iap-classes-events-deadline-december-2021-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-22T19:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-22T19:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Mortal Kombat movie is at its best when it mimics the games</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/D-XoNto9QrBLmqi_NZvmTt9TX84=/356x0:1565x806/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69172465/rev_1_MK_FP_0004_High_Res_JPEG.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Warner Bros. Pictures.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yEqSRe"&gt;For a series about people getting their spines ripped out, &lt;em&gt;Mortal Kombat&lt;/em&gt; has a surprising amount of story. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/23/18512337/mortal-kombat-11-ps4-xbox-switch-ed-boon-interview"&gt;Over three decades&lt;/a&gt; the fighting franchise has amassed a large mythos, filled with histories, lore, and motivations for its many combatants, which are mostly used to answer the question of &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; somebody is having their spine and / or arms removed. You wouldn’t really know that from watching the new movie, though. The film features plenty of callouts to the games — gruesome fatalities, goofy one-liners, and lots of familiar faces — but it never stops long enough to tell you why you should care about anything. It’s also not particularly fun, despite all of the aforementioned ripped-off arms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l85XAv"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mortal Kombat &lt;/em&gt;largely follows the same basic premise as the games, where champions from Earth face off against creatures from a place called the Netherrealm in a fighting tournament, with the fate of the world hanging in the balance. In the movie, there’s a slight twist as Earth’s champions are chosen for this task — and they know they’re chosen because they all have matching &lt;em&gt;Mortal Kombat&lt;/em&gt; dragon logo birthmarks. Unfortunately, their Netherrealm counterparts have decided not to play fair and are hunting down Earth fighters ahead of the tournament, so that they can win by default.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FDG2z7FnJDPBY4tvY3xgnlg-tI0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22462926/rev_1_MKM_T1_0061_High_Res_JPEG.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Warner Bros. Pictures&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ngiWwP"&gt;Of course, that premise is mostly just a way to explain the action, and, for the most part, the film does deliver on that front. In the early stages, you get to see exactly why Sub-Zero is so feared; he uses his ice powers to terrorize an entire city block and, yes, rip off someone’s arms. (Sorry Jax.) Later, when the two realms face off, it’s an incredible spectacle. There’s a sequence where an invisible Reptile is stabbed with a flare so he can be tracked in the dark, as well as an absolutely brutal battle with a very CG-looking Goro — &lt;em&gt;Mortal Kombat&lt;/em&gt;’s iconic four-armed warrior — who doesn’t have four arms by the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="vRvl25"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10460665"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="elVyls"&gt;But the story gets in the way of all that. The setup is a bit like a big superhero epic, with a bunch of superpowered folks banding together to fight a common foe. But unlike, say, &lt;em&gt;The Avengers&lt;/em&gt; or even &lt;em&gt;Justice League&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Mortal Kombat&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t spend nearly enough time introducing its huge cast. The first half of the almost two-hour-long movie is a blur, racing from one character to the next, while also trying to set up the rules of this unique fantasy world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UASYlw"&gt;It’s both too much and not enough: there’s an overwhelming amount of information, but the movie doesn’t give you a reason to care about any of it. I couldn’t tell you much about the main cast aside from basic details like “washed-up MMA fighter” or “really serious army guy.” There are plenty of dramatic moments and twists where it’s clear the movie &lt;em&gt;wants&lt;/em&gt; you to be emotionally invested, but they never hit as intended. It’s also seriously lacking a sense of humor. The closest thing to a joke you’ll find is when someone points out that “kombat” is spelled wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qOJEwLRi7DagjxgiLfWuvJeTbII=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22462930/rev_1_MK_FP_0010_High_Res_JPEG.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Warner Bros. Pictures.&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="C0cDbJ"&gt;The movie is actually at its best when it mimics the games. In a sequence toward the end, fighters are warped around the world for one-on-one battles complete with gruesome fatalities. There are &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of deaths in &lt;em&gt;Mortal Kombat&lt;/em&gt;, and, just like in the games, they’re gleefully sadistic. Heads get sawed in half, limbs are lopped off, and blood flows freely. Someone even says “flawless victory” after a particularly bloody kill. The fighting is a great mixture of almost balletic martial arts and vicious violence. It looks cool and it hits hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EhO88S"&gt;There just isn’t enough of it. If &lt;em&gt;Mortal Kombat &lt;/em&gt;was nothing more than a steady stream of carefully choreographed fights and inventive deaths, I’d be all for it. That’s kind of the franchise’s whole deal. But instead it spends far too much energy on the how and why, without actually delving deep enough to make either compelling. It wants to be both a ridiculous action movie &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; a serious one, and those two sides never fully gel. Even worse, it’s barely a complete story; instead of a true ending, &lt;em&gt;Mortal Kombat&lt;/em&gt; finishes with a giant tease for another movie. It’s like a two-hour-long prologue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S6B0zb"&gt;Playing &lt;em&gt;Mortal Kombat&lt;/em&gt; is brutal and bloody, but it’s also a lot of fun — the movie is missing out on much of the latter.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22398015/mortal-kombat-2021-movie-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22398015/mortal-kombat-2021-movie-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-22T17:48:40-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-22T17:48:40-04:00</updated>
    <title>Call of Duty: Warzone pulls a Fortnite with the launch of its new map</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1vV57SPrM9w8C8qSw95r54o2-cw=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69172111/cod_warzone.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZhFLey"&gt;After launching a little over a year ago, &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Warzone&lt;/em&gt; is one of the most popular free-to-play titles right now, with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22396481/call-of-duty-warzone-100-million-players-apex-legends"&gt;100 million people&lt;/a&gt; playing the battle royale shooter. Following a &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/call-of-duty/22396153/call-of-duty-warzone-destruction-of-verdansk-part-1-nuke-servers-event-playlist-bug-crash"&gt;nuclear missile that destroyed the game’s map&lt;/a&gt;, the in-game city of Verdansk is back with a new map set in the year 1984, as seen in the announcement trailer above. This mirrors a similar move made by its competitor &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/15/20905428/fortnite-chapter-2-season-1-release-date-battle-pass-black-hole"&gt;destroyed its original map&lt;/a&gt; and replaced it with a new one in 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5m1762"&gt;Despite the shape and layout remaining the same as its predecessor, players will notice changes to most locations along with a 1980s vibe that fits the game’s new time period. Verdansk ’84, the name of the new map, has some alterations to make it a new location and not a direct reskin, while also becoming more closely integrated with &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Black Ops Cold War&lt;/em&gt;, which is set in the same decade. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/6/21552437/call-of-duty-warzone-player-progression-weapons-cosmetics-shared-unified-black-ops-cold-war"&gt;Both games share content across one another&lt;/a&gt;, meaning weapons, cosmetics, and other in-game unlockables like killstreaks can be shared across both titles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lPvdIk"&gt;The debut of Verdansk ’84 serves as an official start to the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RavenSoftware/status/1385065877754716166?s=20"&gt;third season of &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Warzone &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Black Ops Cold War&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s available now with plenty of new weapons added and a few old ones nerfed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AHHzxp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22398157/call-of-duty-warzone-season-3-new-map-verdansk-84"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22398157/call-of-duty-warzone-season-3-new-map-verdansk-84</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-22T17:40:12-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-22T17:40:12-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook pivots from politics to ‘inspiration’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The word facebook in white against a blue background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/O-izgVZPVUuVj_JebfaqMsm62EI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69172064/acastro_180522_facebook_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uHz4r3"&gt;Facebook wants to inspire, apparently. The company announced changes to its News Feed today that are supposed to fill feeds with things users like, rather than the content that annoys them. At the end of March, Facebook began introducing filters &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/31/22359782/facebook-news-feed-turn-off-algorithmic-ranking-favorites-most-recent-filter-bar"&gt;to allow users to customize their feed&lt;/a&gt;, and now, the company is hoping to learn more about what users like and dislike, with what seems like a special focus on &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/04/incorporating-more-feedback-into-news-feed-ranking/"&gt;moving away from political content and toward “inspirational posts.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6vi9f5"&gt;The company has been under intense scrutiny for helping &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/11/16449976/facebook-political-ads-trump-russia-election-news-feed"&gt;fan the flames of political division&lt;/a&gt; in the US and even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/7/21055348/facebook-trump-election-2020-leaked-memo-bosworth"&gt;playing an outsized role in elections&lt;/a&gt;. Facebook’s influence on both issues has largely stemmed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/17/21183341/facebook-misinformation-report-nathalie-marechal"&gt;from the misinformation&lt;/a&gt; that’s been spread on the platform. It’s an issue that seems directly connected to Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg taking an aggressive stance in support of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/29/21537040/facebook-mark-zuckerberg-section-230-hearing-reform-pact-act-big-tech"&gt;replacing Section 230&lt;/a&gt; of the Communications Decency Act in 2020. Facebook hasn’t named a specific alternative it supports, but it generally favors the government having more control (and receiving more blame) for moderating inflammatory speech online.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nyDfh8WfyOxf3ONCto3JJm25FlQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22462834/NRP_NF_Ranking_Product_01.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Facebook&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook’s new survey questions will include gauging whether a post is inspiring.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Ng51P7"&gt;I’m not sure inspiring posts are the News Feed cure the company should be hoping for, though. Facebook is planning to survey users on what posts they find inspiring to adjust how News Feed ranks content. According to Facebook, users want inspirational content because it “motivates them and can be useful to them outside of Facebook.” It’s certainly a nice idea, but who or what people find inspiring could vary wildly. Per a statement Facebook provided &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="H3kfIu"&gt;For the purposes of our surveys, we’ll ask people how inspiring they find a given post on their News Feeds, so we’re leaving it up to them as to what they find inspirational. According to feedback sessions we’ve conducted, though, people have told us they find content to be “inspiring” if:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V9oPKM"&gt;It gives them positive, new ideas to do something different&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XBo6l2"&gt;It’s information that changes their thinking or perceptions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tOOd6Y"&gt;It provokes uplifting and creative thinking&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="eaOciD"&gt;As Facebook suggests in its original blog post, “a photo of a national park can inspire someone to spend more time in nature,” but it’s not hard to imagine other photos and posts that are much more controversial earning a similar rating of “inspiring” from some users.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8kHbk2GQH7y0UHWVL-XbiLBINgE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22462821/NRP_NF_Ranking_Product_02.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Facebook&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook is testing a new method for hiding psots in the News Feed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="J57vnh"&gt;Facebook also says it will ask users what topics they are not interested in, like cooking, sports, or politics (the three types of people) so that it can show them other posts that are relevant to their interests. The company says it’s also testing an easier way to prune posts you might not want to see in your feed via a small “X” in the top-right corner of a post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rd2Y1N"&gt;Neither of these changes sounds like they would actually help with Facebook’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/26/21270659/facebook-division-news-feed-algorithms"&gt;habit of radicalizing users&lt;/a&gt;. If anything,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;depending on how heavily News Feed weighs those answers, it could lead people further down whatever potentially dangerous rabbit holes they’re already exploring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FsVFQd"&gt;While the plan seems vague, engaging with users over their News Feed likes and dislikes is broadly good. Facebook has long seemed focused on maintaining and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22325355/facebook-growth-ai-go-read-this-ethics-misinformation-bias"&gt;increasing engagement&lt;/a&gt;, at the cost of providing people a healthy environment to talk to family and friends. This survey approach is a small step in the right direction, but it is dependent on people actually participating in the first place, which isn’t guaranteed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UzDS8i"&gt;Despite this measure of progress, Facebook still seems slow and reluctant to make big positive changes on its platforms. The company made a drastic change to the News Feed after the US election, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/24/21612728/facebook-news-feed-us-election-change-mainstream-news-misinformation"&gt;boosting authoritative news sources&lt;/a&gt; but only temporarily. Relying on surveys and hiding its division problem rather than directly addressing it feel like steps back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="47R2TD"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tF3lQ1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22397583/facebook-news-feed-customer-survey-inspirational-relevant-interests-posts"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22397583/facebook-news-feed-customer-survey-inspirational-relevant-interests-posts</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
