<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-28T17:39:47-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-28T17:39:47-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-28T17:39:47-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amid the fluff, Meta showed an impressive demo of its Codec Avatars</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3zg_6gUA42IKcFk_sncD9d_x_Pw=/240x0:2640x1600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70059609/Screen_Shot_2021_10_28_at_12.12.29.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6wyJE3"&gt;Meta, the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22745234/facebook-new-name-meta-metaverse-zuckerberg-rebrand"&gt;formerly known as Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, held a presentation today where it announced its rebranding and showed off what it imagines the future of computing will look like — but amid all the fluff, it actually had some interesting tech demos. The first showed off its life-like Codex avatars and an environment for them to exist in, which the company says was rendered in real-time and reacted to real-world objects. Mark Zuckerberg also talked about the company’s work with neural interfaces that let you control a computer just by moving your fingers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ln7TUX"&gt;We’ll discuss the demos in just a moment, but it’s really worth seeing them for yourself. You can check them out &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/facebookrealitylabs/videos/561535698440683/?t=10291"&gt;on the Facebook keynote archive&lt;/a&gt; or on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/XOn2CZWnxxY?t=3684"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;’ YouTube stream&lt;/a&gt; if you prefer that interface.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i93fk9rsraSFKk5yWTgUBD0DPqI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22964553/avatar_demo.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Gif: Meta&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;According to Meta, this is both a virtual avatar and a virtual environment.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="eyT9zo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10833239"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="z5O2K2"&gt;During the presentation, Meta showed off the work it’s been doing on &lt;a href="https://tech.fb.com/codec-avatars-facebook-reality-labs/"&gt;its Codec Avatars&lt;/a&gt; to give users better control over their eyes, facial expressions, hairstyles, and appearance. The company also showed off the ability to simulate how the avatar’s hair and skin could react to different lighting conditions and environments and even how it was working on interactive clothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1D0SUW"&gt;The presenter made it very clear that this tech is “still very definitely research,” and it’s no wonder — there’s an immense amount of hardware required to make one of the avatars, and Meta’s likely using very high-powered computers to render it. But it’s at least exciting to see that Meta’s goal is to let us render ourselves with graphics equivalent to what &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/13/21256079/epic-unreal-engine-5-playstation-5-demo-next-gen-graphics-release-date"&gt;cutting-edge video game engines are capable of&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ddjL2y-9jkZz9OIWykJA53yPxRk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22964185/fb_real_time_environment.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Gif: Meta&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;According to Meta, this was rendered in real-time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="KDb1Bq"&gt;The company also showed off its real-time environment rendering, which it said would eventually be a place for you to use your avatar to interact with others. The system also lets people interact with real-life objects, with the changes being reflected in the virtual world. While realistic environments are nothing new, being able to make changes to them in the real world and see those changes happen in a virtual one makes for a really cool demo (even if the tracking points added to the real-life objects are a bit distracting in how much they stand out). &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-ot9NUuyY7HXl8d6zyjYvERxbjo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22964246/FB_Marketing_EMG.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Gif: Meta&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meta’s “illustration” of what the neural interface might do in the future.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="wpi9St"&gt;As for the neural interface, Meta’s relying on something called electromyography, or EMG, to turn the signals your brain is sending to your hand into computer commands. It showed off the wristband it uses to do this &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22338008/facebook-reality-labs-emg-wristbands-ctrl-labs-ar-interface-demo"&gt;earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;, and the demo Meta gave today didn’t really show off &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/6/17433516/ctrl-labs-brain-computer-interface-armband-hands-on-preview"&gt;anything that wasn’t around&lt;/a&gt; in 2019 when it bought a company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/23/20881032/facebook-ctrl-labs-acquisition-neural-interface-armband-ar-vr-deal"&gt;called CTRL-Labs&lt;/a&gt; and acquired its tech, but it’s still good to see that it’s being worked on. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/itkAbEFFcrmHvNSVkGFbPc0shgk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22964236/FB_Research_EMG.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Gif: Meta&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The actual prototype Meta researchers are using.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="cfARZQ"&gt;Meta has said that it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22577095/facebook-bci-ucsf-chang-lab-brain-typing-research-update-project-steno-ar-vr"&gt;pursuing EMG input instead of brain-reading devices&lt;/a&gt;, so it may have been showing off the way you interact with its future devices. Compared to visions of people playing VR ping-pong for an audience of avatars, this felt like the most realistic thing Meta showed off Thursday. That doesn’t mean the Oculus (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751220/facebook-portal-oculus-quest-meta-horizon-renaming"&gt;er, Meta, apparently&lt;/a&gt;) Quest 3 will come with an EMG wristband, but in a sea of hype without much substance, its demo and the other actual research Meta showed off was a sight for sore eyes. &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/XOn2CZWnxxY?t=3684"&gt;Check them out&lt;/a&gt; if you’re looking for a break from the rest of the Facebook / Meta news.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751177/facebook-meta-codec-avatar-real-time-environment-rendering-neural-interface"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751177/facebook-meta-codec-avatar-real-time-environment-rendering-neural-interface</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-28T17:08:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-28T17:08:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple lost $6 billion to chip shortage and manufacturing delays in Q4, Tim Cook says</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rva65arZ-PiIObusakoSD4ivn0Y=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70059433/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bP2687"&gt;Apple today posted strong earnings for its &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/10/apple-reports-fourth-quarter-results/"&gt;fourth fiscal 2021 quarter&lt;/a&gt;, reporting all-time highs for its services and Mac divisions. The company says it took in revenue of $83.4 billion, a year-over-year increase of 29 percent, and earnings per share of $1.24. That earnings number came in below Wall Street expectations of $84.85 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CbzuCz"&gt;CEO Tim Cook &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/10/28/apple-aapl-q4-2021-earnings.html"&gt;told CNBC&lt;/a&gt; that supply chain constraints had a clear impact on financial results this quarter. “We had a very strong performance despite larger than expected supply constraints, which we estimate to be around $6 billion,” Cook said, attributing the supply issues to “the industry-wide chip shortages that have been talked about a lot and COVID-related manufacturing disruptions in Southeast Asia.” Apple expects an even greater loss from supply chain issues in the December quarter, it said during Thursday’s earnings call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PKp8XU"&gt;The company is fresh off the launch of several new products, including the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22684421/apple-iphone-13-mini-review"&gt;iPhone 13&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22684033/apple-iphone-13-pro-max-review"&gt;13 Pro&lt;/a&gt;, a new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22696652/ipad-mini-2021-6th-gen-review"&gt;iPad mini&lt;/a&gt;, ninth-gen iPad, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22722533/apple-watch-series-7-review-screen-watchos-features"&gt;Apple Watch Series 7&lt;/a&gt;, third-generation &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22744686/apple-airpods-third-gen-review"&gt;AirPods&lt;/a&gt;, and most recently, the eagerly anticipated MacBook Pro powered by Apple silicon. The latest iPhones weren’t released until late in the quarter, but the iPhone business as a whole continued to show strong momentum and was up 47 percent over a year ago. The iPad was also up 21 percent over the year-ago quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NQpqjy"&gt;Like other large tech companies, and as Cook made clear, Apple is dealing with major supply chain challenges: the high-end iPhones remain difficult to find in stock at Apple retail locations, and its 14-inch and 16-inch MacBook Pros are already severely backordered. If you don’t want to deal with long shipping delays, the best option is routinely checking stock at local Apple stores. But even that’s not a guaranteed strategy, and the reality is that buying Apple’s latest gadgets is more difficult than in years past.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751418/apple-q4-2021-earnings-supply-constraints-chip-shortage"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751418/apple-q4-2021-earnings-supply-constraints-chip-shortage</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-28T16:44:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-28T16:44:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon will spend ‘several billion dollars’ to avoid holiday shipping delays</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HZirqdNAJqgGhcK5BdVqB8LM4n8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70059292/acastro_190920_1777_amazon_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RLrVw2"&gt;Amazon wants to avoid holiday shipping delays as much as you do. The company said today that it plans to spend “several billion dollars” to avoid problems during the holidays, which might extend from product delivery issues to keeping items in stock. The money will be spent on increased pay for workers, heightened shipping costs, and mitigating supply chain issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c0c78q"&gt;“It’ll be expensive for us in the short term, but it’s the right prioritization for our customers and partners,” Amazon CEO Andy Jassy said today in &lt;a href="https://ir.aboutamazon.com/news-release/news-release-details/2021/Amazon.com-Announces-Third-Quarter-Results/default.aspx"&gt;the company’s third-quarter earnings release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="47njQg"&gt;The big spending comes as both a promise and a warning. Amazon’s earnings disappointed investors with a significant dip in quarterly profits from last year. That’s largely due to increased spending across the board — the company spent $3.8 billion more on fulfillment, $3.3 billion more on tech costs, and $2.6 billion more on marketing, to name just a few expenses — which ate into the quarter’s $110.8 billion in revenue, which was up 15 percent from last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RZuS5f"&gt;Jassy, who was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/5/22563671/andy-jassy-amazon-ceo-jeff-bezos"&gt;only installed as CEO on July 5th&lt;/a&gt;, said that these expenses were necessary to deliver good service to customers. “We’ve always said that when confronted with the choice between optimizing for short-term profits versus what’s best for customers over the long term, we will choose the latter,” he said. Jassy called the expenses, “extraordinary investments across our businesses to satisfy customer needs.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751331/amazon-spending-billions-holiday-shipping-delays-q3-2021-earnings"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751331/amazon-spending-billions-holiday-shipping-delays-q3-2021-earnings</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-28T16:38:45-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-28T16:38:45-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook Connect: all the news about ‘Meta’ and Mark Zuckerberg’s VR dream</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7ThF0I2iExmwWX6ywgrznTY31JU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70059231/DSCF7685.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Vjeran Pavic/The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The company unveiled a new name and vision for the future in its keynote&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="IWw8JJ"&gt;Facebook held its virtual reality labs Connect event on Thursday, where CEO Mark Zuckerberg &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22745234/facebook-new-name-meta-metaverse-zuckerberg-rebrand"&gt;announced that the company would be rebranding as Meta&lt;/a&gt; and showed off his vision of a metaverse that inspired the name change. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FNJ6yX"&gt;During the prerecorded livestream, we saw the company’s plans for Oculus VR, which included a tease for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22749008/facebook-oculus-project-cambria-pro-vr-ar-headset"&gt;a new high-end headset&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22750569/facebook-oculus-horizon-home-social-vr-space-connect"&gt;addition of a more customizable home space&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22749648/active-pack-oculus-quest-2-fitness-workouts-sweat-hygiene"&gt;fitness-focused accessories&lt;/a&gt;, as well as a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751009/grand-theft-auto-san-andreas-oculus-quest-2"&gt;VR remake of &lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. We also got to see a lot of videos that involved virtual avatars going to concerts, playing ping-pong, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BYvik1"&gt;Since the stream ended, more details have come out about the company’s rebranding, including that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751220/facebook-portal-oculus-quest-meta-horizon-renaming"&gt;the Oculus name would be replaced&lt;/a&gt; and that the company had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751143/facebook-thumbs-up-like-meta-sign-global-headquarters-replaced"&gt;changed its office’s iconic sign&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; reporter Alex Heath &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22749919/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-meta-company-rebrand"&gt;interviewed Zuckerberg to talk about the motivation behind the name change&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OrS0BR"&gt;There’s sure to be more information coming about Facebook’s rebranding and its potential ramifications, so stay tuned here for all the latest news about Meta. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rjk122"&gt;Oh, and if you’re still confused about what the heck a metaverse is, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22701104/metaverse-explained-fortnite-roblox-facebook-horizon"&gt;check out our excellent explainer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22751328/facebook-meta-rebrand-metaverse-vr-ar-oculus-gta-horizion"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22751328/facebook-meta-rebrand-metaverse-vr-ar-oculus-gta-horizion</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
      <name>Alex Heath</name>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
      <name>Umar Shakir</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-28T16:27:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-28T16:27:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>New Biden plan would give e-bike buyers up to $1,500 in tax credits</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="E-Bikes Increasing In Popularity" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8-fLvv0zzlMj6-ui9B29teBXEu4=/0x9:3500x2342/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70059128/1236048159.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Erin Clark/The Boston Globe via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8dXIK5"&gt;There’s good news in the latest version of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751099/white-house-budget-climate-electric-vehicles-ev-tax-credit-deal-manchin-sinema"&gt;White House budget deal&lt;/a&gt;: the proposed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/24/22590792/ebike-act-senate-brian-schatz-tax-credit-infrastructure"&gt;federal tax credit for new electric bike purchases&lt;/a&gt; has survived the most recent round of Congressional bloodletting. Not only that, but it’s been restored to its former glory of 30 percent, after the &lt;a href="https://www.bicycleretailer.com/industry-news/2021/09/16/e-bike-tax-credit-bill-cut-half-half-ways-and-means-committee#.YXsGy9bMJAc"&gt;House of Representatives slashed it to 15 percent&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LEv4Ht"&gt;Still, it’s a hugely important proposal for a product that is still struggling to reach mass adoption. If the deal passes in its current form, e-bikes would become significantly cheaper for most Americans. In turn, that could mean a significant change in the transportation options for millions of people around the country. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qdfCWs"&gt;The legislation would offer Americans a refundable tax credit worth 30 percent of a new e-bike’s purchase price, capped at $1,500. All three e-bike classes would be eligible for the tax credit, but bikes with motors more powerful than 750W would not. The credit would be fully refundable, which would allow lower-income individuals to claim it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="QaIuAA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There are some caveats&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5Olv3l"&gt;Bikes that cost more than $5,000 would not be eligible. The program is also means-tested, meaning the credit would begin phasing out $200 for every $1,000 spent on the purchase for individuals who earn $75,000, heads of household earning $112,500, and married couples who file jointly earning $150,000. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YhdjJb"&gt;E-bikes are significantly more expensive than normal bikes, typically costing anywhere from $1,000 to $8,000. But they also have the potential to replace car trips for a lot of people, which could help make real progress in the fight against climate change. A recent study found that if 15 percent of car trips were made by e-bike, &lt;a href="https://www.bicycling.com/news/a33798099/e-bikes-can-reduce-carbon-emissions-study/#:~:text=Take%20an%20E%2DBike%20to,emissions%20would%20drop%2012%20percent.&amp;amp;text=Research%20from%20a%20recent%20study,reducing%20carbon%20emissions%20in%20cities."&gt;carbon emissions would drop by 12 percent&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iZDPfY"&gt;There are other benefits for cyclists tucked away in the massive 1,600-page bill. People who ride bikes to work or use bike-share would be eligible for pre-tax commuter benefits similar to those who drive and park or take public transportation to work. Under the proposal, employees would be allowed to receive a bicycle benefit of up to 30 percent of the parking benefit — currently equivalent to $81 a month, less than $1,000 a year, for bicycling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f9t5ob"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751273/ebike-tax-credit-build-back-better-biden"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751273/ebike-tax-credit-build-back-better-biden</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-28T16:07:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-28T16:07:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>With Facebook’s change to Meta, what’s the new Big Tech acronym?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9m23TA9Rjqnnfnn8HXJMjsuHS1E=/168x0:1992x1216/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70059041/248542531_922091671726906_154548412751156736_n.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A collage of Meta logos.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Meta&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ARsuiR"&gt;The company formerly known as Facebook just revealed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22745234/facebook-new-name-meta-metaverse-zuckerberg-rebrand"&gt;its new name, Meta&lt;/a&gt;. And while that change brings &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22749919/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-meta-company-rebrand"&gt;a whole lot of questions&lt;/a&gt;, there’s one that many of us at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; have been pondering for about 30 minutes: how does the Meta name change the acronym used to refer to the biggest tech companies in one fell swoop?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="muOa6m"&gt;Before Thursday, FAANG — Facebook, Apple, Amazon, Netflix, and Google — was perhaps the most commonly used one. But that acronym already doesn’t quite work. Google is technically a part of Alphabet now, so there should be a third A. (FAAAN?) It’s missing Microsoft, which is just as mind-bogglingly huge as some of the other companies. And you could argue that Tesla should be part of the acronym conversation, especially now that its market cap has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22744504/hertz-tesla-order-100000-vehicles-electrify-fleet"&gt;surpassed $1 trillion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ds1En2"&gt;Now that we all have to start saying Meta, we’ve put together a list of some potential Big Tech acronyms we could use instead. And before we dive in, here are the letters we’re playing with: &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;pple, &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;mazon, &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;lphabet or &lt;strong&gt;G&lt;/strong&gt;oogle, &lt;strong&gt;M&lt;/strong&gt;eta, &lt;strong&gt;M&lt;/strong&gt;icrosoft, &lt;strong&gt;N&lt;/strong&gt;etflix, and &lt;strong&gt;T&lt;/strong&gt;esla. In short: A, A, A / G, M, M, N, T.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="AV6xym"&gt;GAMMA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="QGUJcw"&gt;MAGMA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="zxg15f"&gt;MAMAA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LRkQkc"&gt;MAAAN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2yad3e"&gt;MMAAGT (pronounced “maggot”)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="TV7ff2"&gt;GAMAT (Used in a sentence: “We’re running the GAMAT of options here.”)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wc7IgD"&gt;MATMAN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="MdcABL"&gt;MGMT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="An7eWR"&gt;MANAGMT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="U3t99B"&gt;MANTA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yae9FB"&gt;A MANTA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="U94cZU"&gt;ANTMAN (Apple, Netflix, Tesla, Meta, Amazon, Nicrosoft [it works, okay, don’t question it])&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="YQXBGV"&gt;Or perhaps we’ll just keep saying Facebook and Google, swap in Microsoft for Netflix, and say FAAMG&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="iP4zdV"&gt;What are your ideas? Post them in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/10/28/22751274/facebook-meta-name-change-new-big-tech-acronym-faang"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/10/28/22751274/facebook-meta-name-change-new-big-tech-acronym-faang</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-28T15:48:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-28T15:48:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>Dropbox clarifies that a native Apple Silicon app is coming in 2022 after forum outrage</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5FJSImoVKSscJ0gK7033q8W0Nkk=/125x0:1475x900/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70058892/dropbox_logo_2x.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9Pdh3z"&gt;Dropbox will finally be updating its Mac app to natively support Apple Silicon sometime in the first half of 2022, the company confirmed today. A previous forum thread saw Dropbox staffers claim that a native app would require “a bit more support before we share your suggestion with our team.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9MAXIF"&gt;The months-old thread was resurfaced in a post by developer &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mitchellh/status/1453394500848537605?s=20"&gt;Mitchell Hashimoto&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter (&lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/10/28/dropbox-no-plans-to-support-apple-silicon/"&gt;spotted by &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), sparking complaints from Dropbox users who were disappointed by the impression that the company would only develop the app if enough customers asked for it. While Dropbox technically does work with Apple Silicon hardware thanks to Apple’s Rosetta 2 software translation layer, it’s not as power or memory efficient as it could be if it ran natively. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="27WhBd"&gt;In response to the confusion, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/drewhouston/status/1453762478479843332"&gt;Dropbox’s CEO Drew Houston&lt;/a&gt; clarified that the service is “certainly supporting Apple Silicon” and that it’s been “working for a while on a native M1 build which we aim to release in H1 2022.” Houston also apologized for the support thread responses, which he called “not ideal.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="1zbF00"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We're certainly supporting Apple Silicon, sorry for the confusion. We've been working for a while on a native M1 build which we aim to release in H1 2022. (And agree the responses in the support thread were not ideal)&lt;/p&gt;— Drew Houston (@drewhouston) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/drewhouston/status/1453762478479843332?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 28, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bodyDisplay_9"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.dropboxforum.com/t5/Dropbox-ideas/Apple-Silicon-M1-Desktop-Sync-Compatibility/idc-p/553669/highlight/true#M64135"&gt;support thread&lt;/a&gt; has also since been resolved with a similar update clarifying the current development of a native M1 app and apologizing for the confusion. “While we regularly ask for customer feedback and input on new products or features, this should not have been one of those instances.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751178/dropbox-native-apple-silicon-app-m1-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751178/dropbox-native-apple-silicon-app-m1-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-28T15:47:09-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-28T15:47:09-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook’s Oculus Quest will soon be called the Meta Quest</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/apFUuZwvQg2jWZIAIOX2ioS5pK8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70058886/akrales_200904_4160_0010.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="45y3Cv"&gt;Meta, formerly known as Facebook, is rebranding its hardware to match its new name. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/boz/posts/10114026973983491"&gt;Meta CTO Andrew Bosworth announced&lt;/a&gt; that the company is phasing out its Oculus branding, including on the Oculus Quest virtual reality headset. Starting in 2022, the Oculus Quest product line will be known as the Meta Quest, while the Oculus App will become the Meta Quest App. The Facebook Portal video device is also getting rebranded to “Meta Portal” sometime in the next few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AjViRH"&gt;“When people buy our products, we want them to clearly understand that all of these devices come from Meta and ladder up to our metaverse vision,” Bosworth’s post reads. That means retiring the name Facebook took on when it acquired Oculus in 2014. “We all have a strong attachment to the Oculus brand, and this was a very difficult decision to make. While we’re retiring the name, I can assure you that the original Oculus vision remains deeply embedded in how Meta will continue to drive mass adoption for VR today.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="RDnhtp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“This was a very difficult decision”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7APFVW"&gt;Some Oculus products will also be given Horizon branding that reflects the company’s VR “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22701104/metaverse-explained-fortnite-roblox-facebook-horizon"&gt;metaverse&lt;/a&gt;” platform. “We’ll also expand Meta Horizon as the brand that will encompass all of our first-party immersive social experiences,” Bosworth notes. “You’ve seen this already with Horizon Workrooms and Horizon Worlds. Soon you’ll see us shift from Oculus to Horizon Home, Horizon Venues, Horizon Friends, and Horizon Profile.” Facebook Reality Labs, the VR / AR division Bosworth heads, will be renamed to Reality Labs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tmolpW"&gt;Company CEO Mark Zuckerberg announced the Meta name earlier today during the annual Facebook Connect (formerly known as Oculus Connect, possibly henceforth known as Meta Connect) keynote. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22749919/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-meta-company-rebrand"&gt;Zuckerberg explained the change&lt;/a&gt; as a solution to “confusion and awkwardness” around the company’s name also being the brand of a specific social app. Zuckerberg singled out the issue of Oculus users being required to log in via Facebook, a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/19/21375118/oculus-facebook-account-login-data-privacy-controversy-developers-competition"&gt;sore point for some VR enthusiasts&lt;/a&gt;. “I think that there was a confusion about, ‘Am I signing into this with my Facebook corporate account or is this going to be tied to my social media account?’” he noted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wNkRv3"&gt;Bosworth brought up the same issue in his post. “As we’ve heard feedback from the VR community more broadly, we’re working on new ways to log into Quest that won’t require a Facebook account, landing sometime next year. This is one of our highest priority areas of work internally,” Bosworth’s post notes. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22748969/facebook-oculus-quest-vr-progressive-web-apps-slack-dropbox-instagram"&gt;The company announced today&lt;/a&gt; that Meta’s Quest for Business program will let users log in with &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/news/introducing-products-for-the-next-era-of-personalized-experiences"&gt;Work Accounts&lt;/a&gt; rather than personal Facebook accounts — but based on Bosworth’s statement, as well as a similar comment from Zuckerberg during the Connect keynote, it’s possible we’ll see a greater shift during the months to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="cZ8AcF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"What is the metaverse, and do I have to care?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22701104/metaverse-explained-fortnite-roblox-facebook-horizon"},{"title":" Facebook’s new name is Meta","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22745234/facebook-new-name-meta-metaverse-zuckerberg-rebrand"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751220/facebook-portal-oculus-quest-meta-horizon-renaming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751220/facebook-portal-oculus-quest-meta-horizon-renaming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-28T14:59:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-28T14:59:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook’s famous thumbs-up HQ sign has been replaced with Meta</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FTTb6HsYmHcBYsNwrPvu83sZaCM=/0x1:6056x4038/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70058608/verge_vjeran_pavic_meta_3_20211028.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vNBlit"&gt;Facebook just announced that it will &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22745234/facebook-new-name-meta-metaverse-zuckerberg-rebrand"&gt;change its company name to Meta&lt;/a&gt;. The new name comes with a new logo, a blue M that looks kind of like a pretzel, and now that logo has replaced the iconic thumbs-up Like icon at the company’s global headquarters in Menlo Park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DvsXmD"&gt;Here are two more images of it, taken by &lt;em&gt;The Verge’s&lt;/em&gt; own Vjeran Pavic:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZFF5ES9hO1ap8dBKNocWPGK0nDE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22964006/verge_vjeran_pavic_meta_20211028_2_3000.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It did not take long before people began to pose for photos.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8DnDL_zJMt7LL0sCC5Rs6uZeYXY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22964003/verge_vjeran_pavic_meta_20211028.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A larger group.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="M62EAM"&gt;For comparison, here’s what the old sign looked like:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Facebook is located at 1 Hacker Way, in Menlo Park, Calif., on Thursday, February 28, 2019." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Tu5ob7vjXdFIzWzAt860oya7jNk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22964052/1298876066.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Yalonda M James/San Francisco Chronicle via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dzLdEt"&gt;The new sign had been teased ahead of its official reveal. At one point, it was covered in a canvas &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/edludlow/status/1453751573260083205?s=21"&gt;with the Like icon&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CyOJ0O"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Hmm. The "Facebook   Sign" at 1 Hacker Way is covered in a temporary canvas/cover which also shows  . Earlier a small security team was putting up a barrier/cordon around it and guards are patrolling   ‍♂️ (Note: did not see the cover go up) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24FB&amp;amp;src=ctag&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;$FB&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Facebook?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Facebook&lt;/a&gt; story &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TheTerminal?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@TheTerminal&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/NPUyBoH4v2"&gt;pic.twitter.com/NPUyBoH4v2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ed Ludlow (@EdLudlow) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/EdLudlow/status/1453751573260083205?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 28, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PURQSi"&gt;And a tweet Wednesday evening captured artists &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ro_olvera/status/1453528203549544452"&gt;painting the new logo&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OKObWc"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Facebook?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Facebook&lt;/a&gt; new name! &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SneakPeek?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#SneakPeek&lt;/a&gt;   &lt;a href="https://t.co/z28kEx7MMQ"&gt;pic.twitter.com/z28kEx7MMQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— RO (@ro_olvera) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ro_olvera/status/1453528203549544452?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 28, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="xrUnJd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10833239"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hBppdm"&gt;The new sign represents just how big of a shift the company is trying to make with the change to Meta. “I used to study Classics, and the word ‘meta’ comes from the Greek word meaning ‘beyond,’” Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/10/founders-letter/"&gt;said in a blog post&lt;/a&gt;. “For me, it symbolizes that there is always more to build, and there is always a next chapter to the story.” The company also went into great detail about the new brand &lt;a href="https://design.facebook.com/stories/designing-our-new-company-brand-meta/"&gt;on a dedicated website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KicXq7"&gt;Facebook’s campus used to be owned by Sun Microsystems, and the company flipped the old Sun sign around when it moved in. Even though the company has switched from the Like icon to the Meta one, that old Sun sign is still there. “The old sign remains as a reminder of what happens when you take your eye off the ball,” &lt;a href="https://time.com/facebook-world-plan/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Time&lt;/em&gt; wrote in a Facebook profile&lt;/a&gt; from 2014. It seems Meta wants that reminder to stay in place.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3sU48zy4pfyy__3h1S5WD_zaecY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22964081/DSCF7697__1_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Sun Microsystems sign is still on the back.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751143/facebook-thumbs-up-like-meta-sign-global-headquarters-replaced"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751143/facebook-thumbs-up-like-meta-sign-global-headquarters-replaced</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-28T14:32:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-28T14:32:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>White House unveils $1.75 trillion budget package with billions for climate</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="President Biden Speaks In The White East Room Before Departing For Europe" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1hdC2zN8uHRkgkT7tsD6J3DHoOk=/0x0:4296x2864/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70058471/1349773970.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="b8409c"&gt;After months of negotiations, President Joe Biden released the latest version of his &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/build-back-better/"&gt;Build Back Better framework&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday, advancing the landmark proposal into what will likely be its final phase before approval. The plan’s original $3.5 trillion budget resolution now sits at $1.75 trillion, unveiling scaled-back initiatives to tackle climate change and other social services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f9U3qT"&gt;In its latest budget proposal, the White House’s total investment in fighting climate change remains relatively the same, sitting at $550 billion. What’s changed the most is how those funds will be used: focusing on manufacturing, electric power, and transportation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="YAzyUU"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The White House’s total investment in fighting climate change remains relatively the same, sitting at $550 billion.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SXYzti"&gt;The new framework includes $320 billion of expanded tax breaks over the next ten years to support clean energy and electric vehicle adoption. The framework specifically focuses on “clean passenger” and commercial vehicles, but it’s unclear if the credit applies to e-bikes as well. An additional $105 billion has been set aside to address climate resiliency in communities affected by natural disasters and to reduce pollution in low-income areas. The White House also outlined $110 billion in incentives to create new supply chains and technologies, “like solar batteries, and advanced materials.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Kb5vjk"&gt;Outside of climate, the framework includes &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/build-back-better/"&gt;hundreds of billions for social programs&lt;/a&gt; and healthcare subsidy expansion, including $400 billion for child care and universal preschool, $200 billion for expanded child and earned income tax credits, and $150 billion for affordable housing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QTdvSA"&gt;While still transformative, the new Build Back Better framework no longer includes key programs like the Clean Electricity Payment Program, an important measure to create a 100 percent clean energy grid. The program would have paid utility providers if they achieved certain clean energy standards and enforce these rules through fines if they didn’t. The program was tossed out after negotiations with Sen. Joe Manchin (D-WV) who opposed the bill. Democrats need Manchin to support the budget resolution in order to pass it in the Senate and overcome a razor-thin majority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ADfZsO"&gt;The climate plan no longer includes a fee on methane use as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="llFvhn"&gt;Thursday’s framework was announced in an effort to win over House progressives who have vowed to tank a separate vote on the Biden administration’s bipartisan infrastructure package if the budget resolution did not receive a floor vote at the same time. Progressive Rep. Ilhan Omar (D-MN) told reporters Thursday, “As a caucus, the progressive caucus is happy with this framework and eager to push it through,” however, she said that they &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/biden-framework-before-europe-departure-44601d00-fe9b-474f-9b6b-85e597f5ff1f.html"&gt;could not vote on the infrastructure package&lt;/a&gt; until a formal legislative text is released and scheduled for a vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SfCmmE"&gt;Progressive organizations, like the climate change-focused Sunrise Movement, echoed Omar’s remarks in statements on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A3xAR1"&gt;“This framework is exactly that – it’s just a framework. A deal is not a deal until progressives agree to it,” said Varshini Prakash, Sunrise Movement executive director. “It’s promising to see a substantial investment in climate action, but it’s appalling and frankly cruel that drug pricing, paid leave, Medicare expansion on dental and vision, are all cut from the framework, and Biden seems willing to leave a pathway to citizenship for millions up to an un-elected Parliamentarian.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751099/white-house-budget-climate-electric-vehicles-ev-tax-credit-deal-manchin-sinema"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22751099/white-house-budget-climate-electric-vehicles-ev-tax-credit-deal-manchin-sinema</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
