<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-11-03T12:55:53-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T12:55:53-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T12:55:53-04:00</updated>
    <title>A one-ton tungsten cube was just bought by a crypto cabal for $250,000</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3zFh5b52HyzlbAhcICpTOpIAK3o=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70086774/acastro_211103_1777_tugnstenCube_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hhKaTE"&gt;What’s 14.545 inches across, weighs one ton (around 907kg or 2,000lbs), and just sold to a group of anonymous crypto investors for roughly $250,000? Why, it’s the biggest tungsten cube ever to be manufactured by Midwest Tungsten Service of Willowbrook, Illinois. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JT9TAV"&gt;Confused? Yes, that’s understandable. But consider this: tungsten cubes are one of the most popular memes in the world of cryptocurrency right now, a realm where value is defined as much by attention as anything tangible. (Call it the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22744728/money-fandom-cryptocurrency-retail-trades-stocks"&gt;stonk market&lt;/a&gt; if you like.) Tungsten, if you’re not familiar, is a metal 1.7 times as dense as lead, and since 2015, &lt;a href="http://6https://twitter.com/tweetsauce/status/726125711220563968"&gt;nerdy types&lt;/a&gt; have been able to buy small cubes of tungsten manufactured by outfits like the Midwest Tungsten Service. Owning one has been a &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/copypasta/comments/eyqwn9/tungsten_cube_amazon_review/"&gt;joke on Reddit&lt;/a&gt; for years, but in recent months, the cubes have become &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/tungsten-cubes-bitcoin-gamestop-crypto-investors-11635431036"&gt;fashionable among crypto aficionados&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="16MmHv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Some say the density of tungsten contrasts with the immateriality of crypto&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="I9mwfB"&gt;Why exactly this happened isn’t all that important. Some claim that the density of the cubes makes for a pleasing contrast with the immaterial nature of cryptocurrency and NFTs. Others say that the experience of holding these objects is its own reward. (I can vouch for that myself. I once had the pleasure of holding a kilogram made of an iridium alloy, which is denser than tungsten, and it was a genuinely cool experience.) The simplest and most convincing answer, though, is that buying tungsten cubes is just a good, solid meme. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rzEQBl"&gt;The recent interest in tungsten cubes led the folks at Midwest Tungsten Service to ask themselves an important question: what’s the biggest tungsten cube they can build? From this query, their 14.545-inch cube was born, with access to the cube sold via an NFT. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wEsiag"&gt;As the company explained in a &lt;a href="https://midwesttungsten.com/blog/midwest-tungsten-service-cube-nft/"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; announcing the project last month:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="4lDOon"&gt;We will make the 14.545” cube, it will weight approximately 2,000 pounds. This NFT represents a real-world physical cube that will be stored at Midwest Tungsten Service headquarters and owned by the NFT owner. One visit to see/photograph/touch the cube per calendar year will be allowed and scheduled with a Midwest Tungsten Service representative. Unlockable content required for scheduling and proof of ownership required for entry. The cube will be stored in a room of its own that will be locked and only accessible by the NFT owner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T6FASF"&gt;Subsequent owners of the NFT cannot visit the cube in a year in which the cube has already been visited. The cube will not be available to view until 12 weeks after the first sale. Burning the NFT will result in shipment to the most recent owner via freight truck, owner will be responsible for alerting Midwest Tungsten Service of the intention to burn and transport after freight drop-off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="L5hWED"&gt;Now that NFT has sold to a group calling themselves TungstenDAO, with the sale — which you can &lt;a href="https://opensea.io/assets/0x495f947276749ce646f68ac8c248420045cb7b5e/36033305814565393839012117540795495898903988734891995320738861183142759235585/"&gt;see here on OpenSea&lt;/a&gt; and which we &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/v7dgnm/crypto-investors-spend-dollar250k-to-touch-2000-lb-tungsten-cube-once-a-year"&gt;spotted via &lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — going through on Monday for 56.9 ETH or roughly $250,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3b18oa"&gt;Exactly what TungstenDAO plans to do with their purchase isn’t clear (we’ve reached out to the group for comment and will update this story if we hear back). But, fittingly, it seems they bought the NFT simply to bring more attention to the group itself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="wghqti"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The cube’s buyers call themselves an “experimental meme incubation studio”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="raozBQ"&gt;If you’re not aware, a “DAO” or “decentralized autonomous organization” is a type of co-operative organization whose rules are supposedly enshrined in the blockchain. DAOs are typically investment vehicles of one sort or another, and for TungstenDAO, their preferred asset is memes. The group describes itself as an “experimental meme incubation studio” and &lt;a href="https://foundation.app/@TungstenDAO/~/104253"&gt;says its aim&lt;/a&gt; is to “amass a collection of assets that are highly memeable, then create content that reinforces their social significance and strengthens memetic desires for these assets.” Really, it’s a logical evolution for the world of cryptocurrency and NFTs. If attention assigns value and memes drive attention, then why not cut out the middleman and buy memes? In this case (and just to reinforce this point), that meme is a 14-inch tungsten cube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SMeBjq"&gt;Will the cube hold onto its value? Will TungstenDAO become the first trillion-dollar meme studio? Honestly, who knows. But some whispers in the crypto world suggest cubes may have already had their day, and the hot new property is the tungsten &lt;em&gt;sphere&lt;/em&gt;. Still confused? Just roll with it.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761305/tungsten-cube-meme-nft-crypto-midwest"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761305/tungsten-cube-meme-nft-crypto-midwest</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T12:32:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T12:32:16-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nokia G50 review: affordable but awfully average</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Why suffer for a $300 budget 5G phone?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="AaZTJg"&gt;Finding a good budget 5G phone seems as elusive as finding a unicorn these days. Not only do manufacturers have to keep the price as low as possible, but the device also has to pull off some advanced 5G-compatible technologies. No wonder phone makers tend to compromise on other components, and the overall experience takes a hit as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IiJZLo"&gt;This is where I find the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22687760/nokia-g50-phone-battery-android-upgrades"&gt;Nokia G50&lt;/a&gt;, the $300 phone that Nokia pitches as an affordable 5G-phone alternative. While the Nokia G50 is a solidly built phone with a minimalist, no-nonsense Scandinavian aesthetic, it has many flaws that I haven’t experienced in a modern smartphone in a long time. Its entry-level 5G processor lags, its low-resolution touchscreen requires more effort to use than others, and I even had some connection issues with my 4G T-Mobile service on this phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8hVCPW"&gt;These are significant trade-offs for a device that is not the only $300 5G phone in town, assuming you need 5G connectivity at all. There is the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22214280/oneplus-nord-n10-5g-review"&gt;$300 OnePlus Nord N10 5G&lt;/a&gt; that is a T-Mobile exclusive, the newer and cheaper &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22547482/oneplus-nord-n200-5g-review-screen-price-specs"&gt;$239.99 OnePlus Nord N200 5G&lt;/a&gt;, as well as the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22529760/samsung-galaxy-a32-5g-review-price-screen-specs"&gt;$279 Samsung Galaxy A32 5G&lt;/a&gt;. It’s hard to see how the Nokia G50 could possibly stand out from this increasingly crowded, budget 5G space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="fTlwZX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10843493"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="G4pAdw"&gt;Heavy. That’s the first word that comes to mind when holding this 6.84 x 3.06 x 0.35-inch phone that weighs 7.76oz (220g), which is heavier and taller than the Pixel 6 Pro (7.4 oz; 210g). While I appreciate that its stainless steel-framed body is a rarity in smartphones these days (other than the much more expensive Pro-model iPhones), this phone is too heavy to hold with just one hand for long. Its sharp edges dig into my palms due to its heft and make me eager to put the device down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R37XDV"&gt;As classy as that Ocean Blue matte ombre looks, the G50’s smooth polycarbonate coating is a sucker for finger smudges and makes the phone way too slippery to use without a case. I can’t tell you how many times the phone has slipped off a table or countertop, thanks to a combination of its slippery back and the vibrate mode. My review unit only survived the falls because it’s built like an indestructible tank. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/c6ATy29iSPGiUEvElKGocVnKQ2Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22940472/akrales_211015_4805_0011.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;On its right side, the Nokia G50 has a handy fingerprint sensor embedded into its power button.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tpVyMH"&gt;Its durability is definitely a plus since Nokia (and parent company HMD) expects you to keep this Android 11-running phone for longer and is committed to providing two years of OS updates and three years of security updates. This is not as impressive as it sounds: the $279 Samsung Galaxy A32 5G provides four years of security updates, which is the longest out of this class. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1TtDBy"&gt;Like other Nokia Android phones, the G50 has a non-customizable Google Assistant button and a combination SIM and microSDXC tray on its left side, a volume rocker, as well as a power button embedded with a fingerprint sensor on the right. It has a 3.5mm audio jack on top for your wired headphones or mic, as well as a USB-C port and a mono speaker at the bottom. Because the speaker is located on the bottom right corner, it’s easy for your hand to cover the sound. When listening to the &lt;em&gt;Succession&lt;/em&gt; theme song from the HBO series, the opening percussion track sounds more muffled and buzzy on the Nokia, whereas each beat sounds clear and distinct on the OnePlus 9 Pro. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="EdLwsX"&gt;One of the ways Nokia cut corners with the G50 is by using a 720p low-resolution display.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W6i4pg2LMUX2M-BzIsf-IFPoZiw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22940475/akrales_211015_4805_0051.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nokia G50 comes with a pre-applied screen protector, which you can feel around the edge of the display.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MYVXcF"&gt;The G50’s 6.82-inch, 720 x 1560 LCD display is simply too big for so few pixels to produce sharp, high-resolution content. Although its IPS LCD panel does offer good viewing angles with vibrant colors, it doesn’t make up for its low-resolution or 252ppi pixel density. It’s a fine screen for reading emails and social media posts, but there is a noticeable difference when looking at multimedia content. &lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gAOcTfVX5IHtCBRNm73e2-VGr8M=/0x0:2040x1360/1075x1075/filters:focal(857x517:1183x843):format(webp)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70073384/Verge10yearEditorsnote_homepage_2.0.jpg"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge’s&lt;/em&gt; 10th Anniversary image with the stacked motherboards&lt;/a&gt;, for example, looks pixelated and has blurred edges at maximum zoom on the Nokia phone, but lines still look sharp on the OnePlus 9 Pro, even when completely zoomed in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a3NiUi"&gt;Not only does the G50 have a low-resolution screen, but it’s also not as touch-sensitive as other modern phones, where you only need to lightly brush the display to navigate the interface. When I was playing &lt;em&gt;Pokemon Unite&lt;/em&gt;, for example, I had to exert more force with each of my swipes to move my character along the battlefield. It’s not a deal-breaker, but it makes this phone a little less enjoyable to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oxZqd0"&gt;The G50 comes pre-installed with a screen protector, which explains the weird horizontal streaks that run across the screen when the phone is off, as well as the slightly raised edge around the display. The screen protector looks invisible when the phone is on, but if you’re looking at a video with a significant black frame around it, random sightings of this layer can be distracting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dmRuqRm8RX12tnBgeoQBkahDR1M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22940476/akrales_211015_4805_0062.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nokia G50 has a stainless steel framed body and a polycarbonate coating in a matte, ombre finish.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="69kQoI"&gt;The Qualcomm Snapdragon 480 5G processor may be responsible for making the Nokia G50 one of the few $300 5G phones around, but it might just be too underpowered for its ambitions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PhgUC5"&gt;Despite the fact the processor is supported with 4GB RAM and 128 GB of internal storage, the G50 sometimes struggles with very basic tasks. It can take an extra second longer to open a link or an app, or a web page would crash, and I’d have to reload it. The G50 also seems to have trouble multitasking when using a resource-intensive app like &lt;em&gt;Pokemon Unite&lt;/em&gt;. After I downloaded the game, I could not even open it until every single app I had running in the background was closed, and there were only three apps in the background. The game is playable on the G50, but the combination of its slower performance and less sensitive touchscreen can make it feel like you’re moving your character through molasses against faster opponents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="JmyqV2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The $300 Nokia G50 is neither the cheapest nor the best budget 5G phone out there&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hAKozV"&gt;For a phone that is supposed to be future-proofed for 5G connectivity — at least on sub-6Hz 5G networks on T-Mobile and AT&amp;amp;T and not Verizon’s mmWave network — the Nokia G50 I was testing had some trouble connecting to 4G LTE cellular service. My T-Mobile SIM card worked fine until the one day I needed cellular access, and no amount of restarting the phone would fix it. After speaking with Nokia’s PR representative, I realized I was missing an important system update but had trouble installing it until it just installed itself on another day. My G50 has had no problem accessing my T-Mobile 4G service since then. It’s unclear whether my connection issue is a known problem with the hardware, or I just got unlucky with an update or just this particular unit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="LpiaR1"&gt;One place Nokia did not skimp on is the 5,000mAh battery in the G50. It is a nice luxury to have a large capacity battery in your phone, even for a $300 device. To test its battery life, I used only Wi-Fi to actively post on Twitter and Hangouts, read online articles, take photos, and check my two email accounts. All in, I was able to get about 28 hours of active use out of the G50 over two days, which tracks with other phones with 5,000mAh batteries like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22717002/tcl-20s-and-20se-review-budget-affordable-unlocked-smartphone"&gt;TCL 20S&lt;/a&gt;. The included 18W charging brick is definitely not a fast charger, though, because it took almost three hours to recharge this gigantic battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-BlXYnsiKNbUO7Oa7sw5etS0DVA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22940473/akrales_211015_4805_0019.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can tell this is a Nokia phone by its iconic circular array of three rear cameras on the back of the phone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="4dY15x"&gt;You can tell this is a Nokia phone by its iconic circular array of three rear cameras on the back of the phone. This may be a budget phone, but Nokia did not compromise on photography — at least not on the main 48-megapixel wide camera. It also has a 5-megapixel ultrawide camera, 2-megapixel depth camera, as well as a front 8-megapixel wide camera embedded into the bezel of the display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wNs4Za"&gt;The main camera, with its wide lens, f/1.8 aperture, and auto phase detection autofocus, can capture some detailed shots during the day, as well as on clear nights. You can still see the bubbles in my boiling-hot Korean stew and the distinct lamination layers in the pastry. I was particularly surprised by the night photo of colorful graffiti against the backdrop of an office tower. Using the 5-megapixel ultrawide camera, I was able to capture One World Trade and the Oculus in one shot, though, of course, the lights from the towers are all blown out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="EF4zyf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10843175"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Z20ECC"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sample photos from the Nokia G50.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XtSog2"&gt;The biggest downside to the ultrawide camera is that its photos’ colors are not always accurate. For example, the pastries look significantly more yellow in the ultrawide photo compared to the photo of the mini cakes from the main camera. The photo with the two colorful doors is another example of how the ultrawide camera skews yellow in misleading ways. While the two doors look like they’re yellow and blue in the photo, in real life, the doors are actually orange and teal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dlP9Jl"&gt;If you need to capture anything that’s far away on a dim day, I wouldn’t bother using the cameras on this phone with digital zoom. I took some waterfront photos on a cloudy evening, and all the photos were either blurry messes or way too saturated with yellow lighting.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MN6C-xtnxBIrxlkSMIVSn0TvRzU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22940474/akrales_211015_4805_0039.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nokia G50 is a $300 budget 5G phone that works on the sub-6GHz 5G network.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="sK98bD"&gt;The $300 Nokia G50 is neither the cheapest nor the best budget 5G phone out there, and you may be better served by its competitors. For example, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22547482/oneplus-nord-n200-5g-review-screen-price-specs"&gt;$239.99 OnePlus Nord N200 5G&lt;/a&gt; uses the same Snapdragon 480 5G processor as the G50 but has a 1080p display with 90Hz refresh rate for less money. Or, if you’re already a T-Mobile customer, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22214280/oneplus-nord-n10-5g-review"&gt;$300 OnePlus Nord N10 5G&lt;/a&gt; might be the better choice, as it uses the faster Snapdragon 690 5G processor and has the same HD display as its sibling. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22214280/oneplus-nord-n10-5g-review"&gt;Samsung Galaxy A32 5G&lt;/a&gt; is another popular choice at $279. It uses a faster MediaTek Dimensity 720 5G processor, has four years of security updates, and is compatible with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299903/fcc-cband-auction-results-verizon-att-tmobile"&gt;newer 5G C-band&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WJkgcM"&gt;Yet all these budget 5G phones suffer from the same problem: they all had to compromise in some way to make room for its more expensive 5G components. Since 5G isn’t ubiquitous yet and is hardly essential to our lives in 2021, I’m not sure it’s necessary to limit yourself to 5G phones when there is a world of 4G phones that already offers better value and user experience. For around $300, you can get a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21351770/google-pixel-4a-review-camera-specs-price"&gt;Pixel 4a&lt;/a&gt; with a camera that will blow any budget 5G phone’s camera out of the water. Or you can get the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22717002/tcl-20s-and-20se-review-budget-affordable-unlocked-smartphone"&gt;TCL 20S&lt;/a&gt; with premium looks and specs for just $250 and save some money toward your future 5G phone —  when the technology matures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8nHkiJ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Amelia Holowaty Krales&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="V24prX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10843665"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22760873/nokia-g50-review-mobile-5g-sub6hz-android-smartphone"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22760873/nokia-g50-review-mobile-5g-sub6hz-android-smartphone</id>
    <author>
      <name>Gloria Sin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T12:22:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T12:22:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>Biden admin’s bug fix mandate aims to prevent the next major cybersecurity attack</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZKUMZBWMs5AhvCyOjaF5w4vB2l0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70086595/acastro_170621_1777_0008.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7nBrFg"&gt;The Biden administration &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/news/2021/11/03/cisa-releases-directive-reducing-significant-risk-known-exploited-vulnerabilities"&gt;is requiring civilian federal agencies&lt;/a&gt; to fix hundreds of cybersecurity flaws, as reported earlier by &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/biden-administration-to-order-federal-agencies-to-fix-hundreds-of-cyber-flaws-11635937200"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. As the&lt;em&gt; WSJ&lt;/em&gt; states, the &lt;a href="https://cyber.dhs.gov/bod/22-01/"&gt;BOD 22-01&lt;/a&gt; directive from the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) covers around 200 known threats that cybersecurity experts discovered between 2017 and 2020, as well as 90 more flaws that were found in 2021. Federal agencies have six months to patch older threats and just two weeks to fix the ones that were discovered within the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tn5jlp"&gt;The&lt;em&gt; WSJ&lt;/em&gt; report points out that federal agencies are usually left to their own devices when it comes to security, sometimes resulting in poor security management. The goal is to force federal agencies to fix all potential threats, whether they’re major or not, and establish a basic list for other private and public organizations to follow. While zero-day vulnerabilities that exploit previously unknown openings get major headlines, addressing “the subset of vulnerabilities that are causing harm now” can get ahead of many incidents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="FbuEDV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Federal agencies have six months to patch older threats&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wuIbDZ"&gt;Previously, &lt;a href="https://cyber.dhs.gov/bod/15-01/"&gt;a 2015 order&lt;/a&gt; gave federal agencies one month to fix threats deemed “critical risk.” This was changed &lt;a href="https://cyber.dhs.gov/bod/19-02/"&gt;in 2019&lt;/a&gt; to include threats categorized as “high risk,” as pointed out by the&lt;em&gt; WSJ&lt;/em&gt;. The new mandate distances itself from prioritizing specific threat levels and instead acknowledges that small holes can quickly cause larger problems if hackers can find a way to take advantage of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4kIN9R"&gt;“The Directive lays out clear requirements for federal civilian agencies to take immediate action to improve their vulnerability management practices and dramatically reduce their exposure to cyber attacks,” says CISA director Jen Easterly. “While this Directive applies to federal civilian agencies, we know that organizations across the country, including critical infrastructure entities, are targeted using these same vulnerabilities. It is therefore critical that every organization adopt this Directive and prioritize mitigation of vulnerabilities listed in CISA’s public catalog.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PfcIsV"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/known-exploited-vulnerabilities-catalog"&gt;CISA’s newly released list of known vulnerabilities&lt;/a&gt; notably includes the Microsoft Exchange Server flaw. In March, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/5/22316189/microsoft-exchange-server-security-exploit-china-attack-30000-organizations"&gt;emails from over 30,000 US governmental and commercial organizations were hacked&lt;/a&gt; by a Chinese group, thanks to four known security holes that, had they been patched, would’ve prevented the attacks. CISA’s list requires patching the “Microsoft Exchange Remote Code Execution Vulnerability” and is calling on federal agencies to install available SolarWinds patches by May 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IoaZLx"&gt;The Solarwinds Orion Platform is also on the list, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/13/22173035/hackers-russia-breached-us-government-agencies-email-cozy-bear"&gt;was the victim of a major hack in late 2020 that compromised US government agencies&lt;/a&gt;. The CISA notes that the “SolarWinds Orion API is vulnerable to an authentication bypass that could allow a remote attacker to execute API commands.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OpLHTB"&gt;Cybersecurity has been a priority for President Biden since he entered office. In May, he &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/12/22433266/biden-executive-order-cybersecurity-government-infrastructure-colonial-pipeline-solarwinds-hafnium"&gt;signed an executive order to help prevent future cybersecurity disasters&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/12/fact-sheet-president-signs-executive-order-charting-new-course-to-improve-the-nations-cybersecurity-and-protect-federal-government-networks/"&gt;The order mandates&lt;/a&gt; two-factor authentication across the federal government, establishes a protocol for responding to cyberattacks, and forms a Cybersecurity Safety Review Board, among other safety measures.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761208/biden-administration-security-vulnerabilities-patch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761208/biden-administration-security-vulnerabilities-patch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T12:19:27-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T12:19:27-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft’s GitHub CEO steps down</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MZuqgK9KD2eeg3qXPgeOrRSIDls=/0x0:1320x880/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70086575/microsoftgithub.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Cat8ik"&gt;GitHub CEO Nat Friedman is stepping down after three years at the company. Friedman originally joined Microsoft after the company acquired Xamarin, which Friedman helped found. He then took over as the head of GitHub when &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/4/17422788/microsoft-github-acquisition-official-deal"&gt;Microsoft acquired GitHub&lt;/a&gt; three years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hsRHt2"&gt;Friedman is now returning to his startup roots. “With all that we’ve accomplished in mind, and more than five great years at Microsoft under my belt, I’ve decided it’s time for me to go back to my startup roots,” &lt;a href="https://github.blog/2021-11-03-thank-you-github/"&gt;says Friedman in a GitHub blog post&lt;/a&gt; today. “I’m moving on to my next adventure: to support, advise, and invest in the founders and developers who are creating the future with technology and tackling some of the biggest opportunities of our day.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="4BL2Sa"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Microsoft’s new GitHub CEO takes over on November 15th&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WMxL3B"&gt;Thomas Dohmke, GitHub’s chief product officer, will now take over as GitHub CEO on November 15th, and GitHub will continue to operate as an independent Microsoft-owned business. Dohmke will report to Julia Liuson, who is being promoted to president of Microsoft’s developer division.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zwONeJ"&gt;That’s a change in the GitHub structure at Microsoft, as Friedman used to report to Scott Guthrie, Microsoft’s Cloud and AI chief. Julia Liuson was at the center of a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/22/22740701/microsoft-dotnet-hot-reload-removal-decision-open-source"&gt;recent controversial .NET change&lt;/a&gt; that triggered an open source community backlash and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/23/22742282/microsoft-dotnet-hot-reload-u-turn-response"&gt;forced the company to quickly U-turn on its decision&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mEwosX"&gt;While there were some &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/18/17474284/microsoft-github-acquisition-developer-reaction"&gt;initial fears&lt;/a&gt; around Microsoft acquiring GitHub, the company has kept the business running separately without seeking to make major changes. Friedman was quick to respond to the firing of a Jewish employee at GitHub earlier this year, admitting that “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/17/22235913/github-significant-mistakes-were-made-firing-jewish-employee-nazis"&gt;significant mistakes were made&lt;/a&gt;.” Microsoft also revealed recently that GitHub is now home to 73 million developers, up 2x since the company acquired GitHub in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761493/microsoft-github-ceo-leaving"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761493/microsoft-github-ceo-leaving</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T12:12:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T12:12:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>The 2022 Volkswagen ID 5 is a sporty electric SUV with over 300 miles of range</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kMWXmz4Wl3YMh1M5BbN2KX44quA=/0x0:4096x2731/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70086532/DB2021AU00964_large.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dlhcwx"&gt;Volkswagen revealed the ID 5, a smaller, sportier version of its landmark ID 4 electric SUV that will only be available in Europe. It’s the latest vehicle to join VW’s growing “ID family” of electric vehicles as the company gets closer to its 2035 deadline &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/26/22551956/volkswagen-stop-selling-combustion-engine-vehicles-europe-2035"&gt;to stop selling gas-powered vehicles&lt;/a&gt; in its home continent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Kpxxw7"&gt;VW is releasing two versions of its new EV: the entry level ID 5, and the more premium ID 5 GTX, with dual electric motors on both the front and rear axel. (GTX is for VW’s ID models what GTI, or Grand Tourer Injection, means for the Golf.) The entry-level ID 5 will be equipped with a single rear-wheel-drive motor with an output of 174 horsepower and a 77kWh battery pack — theoretically enabling over 320 miles of range. (VW has yet to release range estimates for the ID 5.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p3eXyT"&gt;On the surface, the ID 5 looks indistinguishable from the ID 4, but a closer look reveals some key differences. It’s slightly shorter than the ID 4, with 12 millimeters less headroom in the back, and the bumper, painted door paneling, and new roof line are distinctive. Other than that, the ID 5 is basically just a coupe version of the ID 4. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/22291294/vw-id5-ev-electric-suv-coupe-production-volkswagen-2021"&gt;Earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;, a VW spokesperson said there were “no plans” to sell the ID 5 in North America. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Epwd5o"&gt;&lt;q&gt;VW says the ID 5 in-car features will be improved over the ID 4&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="68Q2JI"&gt;VW says the ID 5 in-car features will be improved over the ID 4, including an updated voice assistant that is now “learning-enabled” with “online access to information from the cloud.” The vehicle will also be equipped with VW’s “Car2X communication” to improve safety and data collection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="1vPtZJ"&gt;Data from compatible vehicles in the Volkswagen fleet and signals from infrastructure within a radius of up to 800 metres can be locally interpreted in a fraction of a second, enabling driver alerts about dangerous areas, accidents and stationary traffic. The ID. Light in the cockpit helps by providing visual warnings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="svI4M2"&gt;The ID 4 is the first vehicle built on VW’s modular MEB electric architecture to be available in North America. Its predecessor, the hatchback ID 3, is only being sold in Europe. The company sold over 6,000 in the first three quarters of 2021, which is fewer than the number of Mustang Mach-E SUVs sold by Ford but still a solid start for a brand-new EV in the US. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="swoIJf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10843783"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lJ7pH0"&gt;VW’s ID electric lineup also includes concept versions of a large SUV (&lt;a href="https://jalopnik.com/the-volkswagen-i-d-roomzz-concept-has-room-for-days-an-1834048772"&gt;ID Roomzz&lt;/a&gt;), a dune buggy (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/7/18254329/volkswagen-id-buggy-electric-concept-car-geneva-motor-show-2019"&gt;ID Buggy&lt;/a&gt;), and a revamped version of its iconic microbus (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/8/19/16173938/volkswagen-microbus-i-d-buzz-concept-production-nostalgia"&gt;ID Buzz&lt;/a&gt;), for which VW has also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/20/17882400/vw-volkswagen-id-buzz-cargo-van-concept-electric"&gt;promised a delivery variant&lt;/a&gt;. All are being built on Volkswagen’s modular electric vehicle platform known as MEB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bo5mmt"&gt;The ID family of vehicles won’t be VW’s first foray into battery-powered drivetrains. The e-Golf was first launched in 2012 but was discontinued in 2020 as the automaker shifts focus to its MEB-built vehicles. VW subsidiary &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/27/20983836/porsche-taycan-turbo-electric-car-first-drive-hands-on-photos-video-range"&gt;Porsche’s first all-electric sports car, the Taycan&lt;/a&gt;, went on sale in 2019. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/18/17876012/dieselgate-volkswagen-vw-diesel-emissions-test-epa-german-auto-industry-mercedes-benz-bmw"&gt;The E-Tron&lt;/a&gt;, the first battery-electric SUV from Volkswagen Group-owned Audi, debuted in 2018, followed by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274376/audi-etron-gt-rs-electric-car-specs-price"&gt;the E-Tron GT&lt;/a&gt;. Together, these vehicles represent the tip of the spear in VW’s effort to dominate the emerging EV market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ipYYGi"&gt;They’re also crucial in helping VW turn the page on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/18/17876012/dieselgate-volkswagen-vw-diesel-emissions-test-epa-german-auto-industry-mercedes-benz-bmw"&gt;now six-year-old Dieselgate scandal&lt;/a&gt;, in which VW was accused of installing illegal software in 11 million diesel cars in order to trick emissions tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0ujqmG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761441/vw-id5-electric-suv-coupe-specs-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761441/vw-id5-electric-suv-coupe-specs-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Brydge’s 11-inch Max Plus iPad keyboard is now available</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wbnJyj0hA9CRKotgVWZESUMN71c=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70086425/dseifert_4858_brydge_11_max_plus_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Brydge 11 Max Plus keyboard with an 11-inch iPad Pro in it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PWj0BD"&gt;Following the launch of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22553643/brydge-12-9-max-plus-review-price-shipping"&gt;12.9-inch Max Plus keyboard for the iPad&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year, Brydge is now releasing an 11-inch version. The new, smaller keyboard has all of the same features as its bigger sibling, including Brydge’s new magnetic mounting system and Instant-On Bluetooth tech, but is sized to fit all generations of the 11-inch iPad Pro and the fourth-generation of the 10.5-inch iPad Air. It’s available starting today, November 3rd, from both &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.brydge.com%2Fproducts%2Fbrydge-max-plus-for-ipad-pro%3Fvariant%3D39674056966249&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22759698%2Fbrydges-11-inch-max-plus-ipad-keyboard-now-available-review-price-specs-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Brydge’s online store&lt;/a&gt; and Amazon for $199.99. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OR0P3l"&gt;Despite its smaller size, the 11-inch Max Plus’ pitch is exactly the same as the 12.9-inch model’s: it’s meant to provide a MacBook-like experience with an iPad. That includes a full keyboard layout with a function row, plus a large trackpad that supports multitouch gestures and navigation. The aluminum chassis can be purchased in either a dark gray or a silver finish to match your iPad’s color, and it has a very MacBook-like appearance when the iPad is installed in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AxoD1EnoshadMbeA7wjhr95UBKA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22980077/dseifert_4858_brydge_11_max_plus_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The back panel of the 11 Max Plus is plastic and has tabs to easily pop the iPad off of it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sq5nntfMZ3aBYNgydxlj_THVy00=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22980078/dseifert_4858_brydge_11_max_plus_7.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 11 Max Plus connects to the iPad’s built-in magnets to hold it in place.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="P7ayvW"&gt;The big new innovation with the Max Plus line is the magnetic attachment system, which eschews the clamps Brydge used in older designs for a full backplate that connects to the magnets inside the iPad to hold it in place. The advantage here is that it allows you to quickly remove the iPad from the keyboard and use it handheld and just as easily snap it back into place when you want to use the keyboard again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p84uXJ"&gt;The Max Plus does not use the iPad’s Smart Connector, relying instead on a Bluetooth connection with the tablet. To overcome the usual delays that happen when using a Bluetooth keyboard with an iPad, Brydge developed its Instant-On technology, which allows the keyboard to stay connected to the iPad for up to four hours, even if it isn’t being used, without detrimental battery drain on either the case or the iPad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7G61ky"&gt;This makes waking up the iPad feel much the same as a directly connected keyboard and mitigates one of the major complaints with Bluetooth. Brydge claims up to three months of battery life between charges, but that varies greatly on how much you utilize the three-level backlight. In the week or so I’ve been testing the product, I’ve not had to charge it back up once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ax7BVZ"&gt;Brydge CEO Nick Smith tells me that the company’s inspiration for the keyboard feel was the vaunted 2015 MacBook Pro. As a result, the Max Plus keys have a bit more travel than either &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/20/21227345/magic-keyboard-ipad-pro-tablet-laptop-review-price-specs-features"&gt;Apple’s Magic Keyboard case&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22547938/logitech-combo-touch-ipad-air-fourth-generation"&gt;Logitech’s Combo Touch&lt;/a&gt;, the two main competitors in this space. The keycaps themselves are also a little smaller and have a little bit more space between them, but I had no trouble getting comfortable with the layout after a few minutes of use.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/n88GEQqlJgIPgnFRtSS2HfnuTE0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22980079/dseifert_4858_brydge_11_max_plus_5.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 11 Max Plus has a full keyboard with function row and a large multitouch trackpad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="NzwXx3"&gt;Brydge is also very proud of the size of the trackpad it was able to include with the Max Plus; the 11-inch model has a larger trackpad than either Apple or Logitech’s keyboard. It supports multitouch gestures and has good tracking, if not quite as precise as Apple has in the Magic Keyboard. Due to the smaller size of the 11-inch’s deck, I did have a few instances of palm rejection, which caused my cursor to jump across the screen when I didn’t expect it to. But otherwise, the trackpad experience on the Max Plus is quite nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nxdnmp"&gt;Using the Max Plus keyboard is a different experience than the Magic Keyboard or the Combo Touch, by design. It’s a chunkier, heftier product, adding nearly two pounds of weight to the iPad itself, but it’s more stable on a lap, like you’d expect a laptop to be. It’s also more comfortable to type on for longer periods because the deck provides more room to rest your hands. And the full function row is a boon compared to the Magic Keyboard, which requires reaching up to use the iPad’s buttons or touch the screen anytime you want to adjust brightness or volume. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zPwJcz"&gt;Lastly, because the Max Plus uses a Bluetooth connection, you can remove the iPad from the case and still use the keyboard and trackpad with it. I particularly liked putting the iPad in a portrait orientation when working on a long document, which you can’t do with the Magic Keyboard or the Combo Touch.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1eZo1MBkMOokkxIqaaoS6YU9rVM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22980081/dseifert_4858_brydge_11_max_plus_3.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;When closed, the 11 Max Pro is chunkier than other keyboards, but preserves the MacBook-like aesthetic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="qrsgNm"&gt;The Max Plus is also not designed to provide much in the way of protection. Unlike Logitech’s Combo Touch, when you remove it from the keyboard, you’re holding a bare iPad, and it doesn’t provide any corner protection from drops. If you are looking for a more protective design that has similar traits as the Max Plus, Brydge offers the plastic &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.brydge.com%2Fproducts%2Fbrydge-air-max-plus%3Fvariant%3D39421148594281&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22759698%2Fbrydges-11-inch-max-plus-ipad-keyboard-now-available-review-price-specs-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Air Max Plus&lt;/a&gt;, which provides four feet of drop protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EoEeWd"&gt;At $200, the Max Plus undercuts Apple by about $100 and is priced similarly to the Combo Touch. It’s not a budget product by any means; that’s reflected in the copious amount of aluminum used and the long feature list. But if you’re looking for a way to get more out of your 11-inch iPad Pro or iPad Air and want a more traditional experience than Apple’s keyboard provides, there’s a lot to like here.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22759698/brydges-11-inch-max-plus-ipad-keyboard-now-available-review-price-specs-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22759698/brydges-11-inch-max-plus-ipad-keyboard-now-available-review-price-specs-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Asus’ VivoBook 13 Slate is a detachable laptop with an OLED screen</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A user watches a movie on the Asus Vivobook 13 Slate, stood horizontally on its kickstand without the keyboard or stylus attached, on a red table." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mMbBaE2_xBNGoChaOhhfmSFTv40=/580x428:2920x1988/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70086427/Vivobook_13_Slate_OLED_T3300_Entertainment.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Asus Vivobook 13 Slate OLED has a keyboard and kickstand.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Asus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KLDKTo"&gt;Asus is known for delving into unconventional form factors, and its latest experiment is no exception. The &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.asus.com%2FLaptops%2FFor-Home%2FVivobook%2FVivobook-13-Slate-OLED-T3300%2F%3Futm_source%3Dmedia%26utm_medium%3Dpr%26utm_campaign%3D21q4_wowtheworld_hq&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F11%2F3%2F22761276%2Fasus-vivobook-13-slate-oled-price-release-date-features-screen-stylus" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;VivoBook 13 Slate OLED&lt;/a&gt; is a 13.3-inch Windows tablet with an OLED screen and a detachable keyboard which starts at $599.99.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bAIh2U"&gt;OLED screens are unusual, though not unheard of, in the detachable form factor. Asus claims that this one is capable of displaying 1.07 billion colors, covers 100 percent of the DCI-P3 color gamut, and has a 0.2-millisecond response time. It’s said to have blue-light levels “up to 70 percent lower than an LCD display” (although many modern LCD PCs also have technology to &lt;a href="https://voxmedia.stories.usechorus.com/compose/4aa6d3d3-f12e-46e7-87b9-313bd31ed89a"&gt;reduce blue light&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tWODUT"&gt;Rather than framing the Slate as purely a tablet for artists, though, Asus seems to be pushing it as an entertainment device. The company emphasizes that the tablet’s 16:9 aspect ratio “provides a full-screen viewing experience” (which is basically the only thing 16:9 screens are good for). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qoHgYt"&gt;The Slate OLED also ships with a stylus, the Asus Pen 2.0, which attaches magnetically to the chassis.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Vivobook 13 Slate OLED stood horizontally on a red desk beside a small stack of books with the keyboard attached. The screen displays the Asus Vivobook OLED logo on a multicolored background." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DRrVj0h8fS9cW_eEn0PVsBMuuCk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22982581/Vivobook_13_Slate_OLED_T3300_Laptop_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Asus&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here it is with the keyboard.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="R1OJKh"&gt;Certainly, $599.99 is an affordable price as OLED products go. It’s also a refreshing one for detachable Windows laptops. A decent model of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22709876/microsoft-surface-pro-8-review"&gt;Surface Pro 8&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22442084/ipad-pro-2021-review-features-screen-mini-led-m1-processor"&gt;iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt; would be close &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1023026/7613?subId1=VergeVivoBook110321&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-ipad%2Fipad-pro" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;to twice&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=VergeVivoBook110321&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fstore%2Fconfigure%2FSurface-Pro-8%2F8QWCRTQ8V8XG%3Fcrosssellid%3Dfbt-f2c%26selectedColor%3D86888a%26preview%3D%26previewModes%3D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;that price&lt;/a&gt;, and that’s not including a keyboard and stylus (which are bundled in the VivoBook 13 Slate OLED’s price). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T3g4au"&gt;OLED screens are becoming more common on 13-inch and 14-inch laptops across the board. Samsung announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/21/22242005/samsung-display-oled-laptop-production-90hz-14-inch"&gt;in January&lt;/a&gt; that it would soon begin mass-producing laptop-sized OLED panels and actually started that production &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/15/22676223/samsung-display-90hz-oled-laptop-screens-lenovo-asus"&gt;in September&lt;/a&gt;. The new Samsung panels are featured on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22652549/asus-proart-studiobook-16-pro-oled-vivobook-expertbook"&gt;a number of 2021 Asus releases.&lt;/a&gt; Shoppers can now find smaller and more affordable OLED devices from other manufacturers as well, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/8/22660761/lenovo-chromebook-duet-detachable-release-oled"&gt;Lenovo’s Duet 5 detachable Chromebook&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yNXyuZ"&gt;The VivoBook 13 Slate OLED will be available in December. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761276/asus-vivobook-13-slate-oled-price-release-date-features-screen-stylus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761276/asus-vivobook-13-slate-oled-price-release-date-features-screen-stylus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T11:33:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T11:33:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon confirms its support for Matter</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Tazw7vyyKLB0CuI7zOhKtnzMXAY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70086250/dseifert_210219_4433_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Amazon Echo Show 10&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YjlYFo"&gt;Amazon has affirmed its support for the smart home connectivity standard Matter, announcing in a &lt;a href="https://developer.amazon.com/en-US/blogs/alexa/device-makers/2021/11/support-for-matter-over-thread-coming-to-echo-and-eero-devices"&gt;blog post today&lt;/a&gt; that it will support Matter over Thread in its Echo devices and Eero Wi-Fi routers. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22741839/eero-ceo-confirms-matter-support-thread"&gt;Eero had previously confirmed its support of the standard&lt;/a&gt;. Amazon says the announcement is about “further expanding Amazon’s commitment to Matter and reinforcing its smart home philosophy of flexibility, privacy, collaboration, and interoperability.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6OLSFc"&gt;Additionally, Amazon has joined Apple, Google, and Samsung on the Thread Group Board of Directors — it has been a member for five years. Alongside Wi-Fi, Thread is a primary protocol for Matter. It provides a low-power, low-bandwidth, and low-latency mesh network for smart home devices to connect to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ufs62n"&gt;The company confirmed that the Echo 4th gen will gain Matter over Thread support, with support for additional Echo devices coming later. Earlier this summer, Amazon said &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586377/amazon-echo-matter-standard-dot-show-studio-flex-plus-upgrade"&gt;it would upgrade most of its Echo smart speakers&lt;/a&gt; to support Matter, including most Echo and Echo Dot speakers and every Echo Studio, Echo Show, Echo Plus, and Echo Flex. All Eero Pro, Eero Beacon, Eero Pro 6, and Eero 6 devices have Thread radios in and already act as Thread border routers for Thread devices to connect to. They will gain Matter support next year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="15Q1PJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The 4th Gen Echo will be the first one to get Matter support&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="f9iWN0"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/11/22430666/matter-project-chip-smart-home-partnership-apple-amazon-google-zigbee"&gt;Matter&lt;/a&gt; is an IP-based application protocol that will establish a common language and common interaction model across smart home devices and ecosystems. With support for Matter over Thread and Wi-Fi in Echo devices, Alexa users should be able to connect any Matter-enabled smart home devices to their Echo smart speakers and control them within the Alexa app and with Alexa voice control. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CcHycT"&gt;For example, Amazon name-checked Eve in a list of companies it is working with around Matter. Eve, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/4/22310378/eve-smart-home-thread-plug-home-kit-weather-station-price-specs-features"&gt;makes smart home devices&lt;/a&gt; such as sensors, plugs, switches, and lighting, has previously only worked with Apple’s HomeKit, but with Matter, its products will be able to connect to Alexa and other smart home ecosystems. Amazon also mentioned Yale, Wemo, Schlage, Sengled, Netatmo, Nanoleaf, Tuya, eWeLink, and Leedarson as brands that are creating Matter over Thread devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aum2WY"&gt;One of Matter’s main promises is multi-admin control. This means you should be able to control any Amazon smart home device that supports Matter using any other Matter controller. SmartThings, Google, and Apple have all committed to Matter, so in theory, you will be able to use those companies' apps and voice assistants to control your Amazon smart home devices, should you want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7QOWPM"&gt;There are no Matter devices available to buy yet, as the standard is still being finalized. But according to the Connectivity Standards Alliance, which oversees Matter, we should start seeing Matter-enabled smart home products later in 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RE0VSw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VL579P"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aVADbM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761340/amazon-matter-smart-home-standard"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761340/amazon-matter-smart-home-standard</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T11:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T11:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Stack Overflow’s copy / paste keyboard is no joke</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Hear me out&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="wRd2Pw"&gt;A Stack Overflow-branded keyboard with just three buttons (Ctrl, C, and V) is a &lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.blog/2021/03/31/the-key-copy-paste/"&gt;great April Fools’ gag&lt;/a&gt; that has no business being as neat and useful as it is. And yet Stack Overflow and manufacturer Drop have managed to turn The Key into a surprisingly competent little $29 accessory. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mq8uQG"&gt;On its surface, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdrop.com%2Fbuy%2Fstack-overflow-the-key-macropad&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22761188%2Fstack-overflow-the-key-copy-paste-review-price-release-date-keyboard" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The Key&lt;/a&gt; looks like it’s only capable of doing two things: copying and pasting. You shamelessly copy your code from Stack Overflow’s thousands (millions?) of helpful contributors and paste it into your own work. Simple. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g6kzsh"&gt;But The Key is a lot more powerful than that. It draws upon QMK open-source keyboard firmware so that it can be fully reprogrammed to do so much more than just copy and paste. It’s not the most user-friendly process, but it’s enough to turn The Key from a goofy novelty into a great little accessory. And it might actually be worth tracking one down when Drop has more in stock next year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="FlsmLW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10843447"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fJr7fl"&gt;Right off the bat, I should say that in functional terms The Key isn’t doing anything particularly new or original. Head over to eBay and search for “Macro Keypad” and you’ll find dozens of inexpensive keyboard add-ons with anywhere from a single blank key to nine or more. The &lt;a href="https://keeb.io/products/bdn9-rev-2-3x3-9-key-macropad-rotary-encoder-and-rgb"&gt;BDN9 from Keebio&lt;/a&gt; is another option I’ve seen recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ftk3vY"&gt;But The Key ends up succeeding where another diminutive keyboard I bought a couple of months back did not. And it’s also available preassembled, unlike other boards that are aimed much more firmly at hobbyists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pjr2iU"&gt;For starters, The Key is straight up nicely made. Its case is made out of aluminum, and underneath each key is a linear Kailh Box Black switch that’s just a hair stiffer than regular Cherry MX Reds. Press one, and it has a nice thunk to it, like you’d expect from a mechanical switch. It even has a modern USB-C port on its back for connecting to your PC. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YgTAiw4v-rzOFfAiBNgyUi8gfJk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22938115/jporter_211018_4805_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kailh Box Black switches sit under each key.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6dgcrF"&gt;More importantly, it’s also got relatively &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdrop.com%2Ftalk%2F93641%2Fhow-to-configure-stack-overflow-the-key-macropad%3Fsort%3Dvotes&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22761188%2Fstack-overflow-the-key-copy-paste-review-price-release-date-keyboard" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;easy-to-follow instructions available on Drop&lt;/a&gt; to help you reprogram it. In contrast, the last macro board I bought arrived without any documentation in a plain cardboard box, and its eBay listing directed me toward a chaotic Discord server filled with confused customers and (admittedly) helpful support staff. For all I know, there are much better documented cheap macro boards available, but my experience so far wasn’t ideal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8hFDpV"&gt;Before I get into reprogramming The Key, I should clarify that, yes, it’s capable of copying and pasting out of the box… for most Windows users. The key with the Stack Overflow logo acts as your “Ctrl” key, and the C and V keys act as you’d expect. You know the drill, you don’t need me to explain how copying and pasting works. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Idxc9w"&gt;Obviously this is a problem for Mac users, where the default copying and pasting shortcuts rely on the Cmd key rather than Ctrl, and any Mac users who want to use The Key will have to reprogram their device accordingly. The Key’s layout was also a problem for me specifically because I use the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/17/18223384/dvorak-qwerty-keyboard-layout-10-years-speed-ergonomics"&gt;Dvorak keyboard layout rather than QWERTY&lt;/a&gt;, which confused The Key’s default layout and caused the C key to register as a “J,” and the “V” to register as a “K.” What I needed was for the “C” switch to be rebound to “I” and for the “V” to be rebound to the “.” (compare &lt;a href="https://thekindle3books.com/qwerty-vs-dvorak-the-two-great-keyboards-the-time-were-born/"&gt;QWERTY’s layout side by side with Dvorak&lt;/a&gt; and this will make a little more sense). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AcWrIg"&gt;Fixing these problems forced me to get acquainted with programming The Key, and I’m glad I did. It opened up the full possibilities of this macro pad, which can do so much more than just copy and paste. The amount of commands QMK supports &lt;a href="https://docs.qmk.fm/#/keycodes?id=keycodes-overview"&gt;is a little mind boggling&lt;/a&gt;, and you can even have one key perform multiple tasks using a modifier key. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BYp_6ASI0WX9csMcNQ4yaaNnThY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22938119/jporter_211018_4805_0006.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4eRjM4"&gt;So maybe you want to use The Key as a small trio of media playback controls (play / pause, skip forward, skip back) or for volume (volume up, volume down, mute). Or maybe you want to go even further and program each key to a macro, where each key can handle a series of button presses automatically. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="99Rn3X"&gt;That’s where I ended up after I decided to turn The Key into a Zoom shortcut macro pad, inspired in part by the &lt;a href="https://github.com/lanewinfield/zoomout"&gt;many DIY projects&lt;/a&gt; that emerged last year. Two of its buttons could handle turning my camera and microphone on and off respectively, and a third would quit the Zoom call entirely. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="o02fR4"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Yes, the copying and pasting works&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="V3B15l"&gt;What’s nice is that as well as programming simple key combinations (Alt+V for the camera and Alt+A for the microphone), QMK also lets you program multiple stages. So as well as programming a button to hit the Alt+Q command to &lt;em&gt;start&lt;/em&gt; the process of exiting a Zoom meeting, I could also program it to follow up with a tap of the “Enter” key. So now my colleagues won’t have to see me stare awkwardly into the middle distance the next time I forget about Zoom’s confirmation dialog box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lLBnBI"&gt;There are a lot of keyboards out there that already offer macro keys like this. Companies like Corsair and Logitech have long offered models with extra programmable buttons, and there are much fancier devices like Elgato’s $149.99 Stream Deck which include small displays on each key to let you customize their appearance as well as their function. But The Key costs just $29. It’s an affordable, and yet surprisingly flexible, alternative. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AUjUaF"&gt;There are some downsides to using The Key like this, but not many. First, as I alluded to above, there’s obviously no way to change the keycaps’ legends when you reprogram their commands. They’re nicely made PBT keycaps with legends printed on using dye sublimation, but whatever fancy functions you program them to perform, they’re going to look the same way. So your options are to commit their functions to memory, buy some more appropriate keycaps, or maybe stick on some ugly Post-it notes to keep track of what each key is doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="2T72g1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It can’t compete with a Stream Deck, but at $29 it doesn’t have to&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GrTGaM"&gt;The second problem is that although &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdrop.com%2Ftalk%2F93641%2Fhow-to-configure-stack-overflow-the-key-macropad%3Fsort%3Dvotes&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22761188%2Fstack-overflow-the-key-copy-paste-review-price-release-date-keyboard" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Drop’s instructions&lt;/a&gt; are straightforward, actually flashing the custom firmware to The Key is a little cumbersome. You have to unscrew the four screws on the underside of the board to expose the PCB inside, where you’ll find a physical button to press and put the keyboard into flashing mode. It’s fine if you’re planning on just setting up The Key once and then forgetting about it, but a little annoying if you want to experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d8Hojm"&gt;Finally, although I found &lt;a href="https://kbfirmware.com/"&gt;KBFirmware.com&lt;/a&gt; an intuitive way to remap The Key, I’d be remiss if I didn’t point out that it’s technically end-of-life and hence there’s a risk of it being shut down. I tried using a different QMK configurator, &lt;a href="http://config.qmk.fm"&gt;Config.QMK.fm&lt;/a&gt;, to design a layout and got an error message saying it’s not compatible with the configuration files Drop has provided for The Key. When I asked Drop about this, it said it was actively working to fix the issue, and pointed me toward a complicated-looking &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdrop.com%2Ftalk%2F93641%2Fhow-to-configure-stack-overflow-the-key-macropad%2F2848184%3Futm_source%3Dlinkshare%26referer%3DBQTJ2K&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22761188%2Fstack-overflow-the-key-copy-paste-review-price-release-date-keyboard" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;community-made fix&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-roieiqbfjWvMJVlSTH-vklnXlc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22938117/jporter_211018_4805_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A USB-C port handles connectivity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JkPIz0"&gt;Out of the box The Key is a silly novelty. Copying and pasting is a task so common I imagine every computer user has committed it to muscle memory, and your keyboard’s existing Ctrl, C, and V keys are sitting right there underneath your left hand. Training yourself to reach for a separate keyboard is a pointless waste of time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V19S3S"&gt;Which is why it’s great that Stack Overflow and Drop haven’t half-assed The Key, despite its silly novelty status. It’s not doing anything particularly new or original, but it’s well made, well documented, and incredibly flexible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="74WAY1"&gt;The biggest problem with The Key at the moment is that it’s incredibly difficult to get hold of. Drop tells me it’s already sold out of an additional production run that’s due to ship in December, and although it’s got another run planned for next year, it declined to share more details than that. You can sign up to be notified when Drop has more available, but who knows when that’ll be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="Qqb5wc"&gt;The Key isn’t going to be giving Elgato’s Stream Deck a run for its money, but if you’re craving a couple of extra media keys or macros after downsizing to a super compact &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/1/6/21048109/fujitsu-happy-hacking-keyboard-professional-3-classic-hybrid-type-s-mechanical-ces-2020"&gt;Happy Hacking keyboard&lt;/a&gt;, it’s a pretty neat option. It just might be a while before Drop’s supply catches up with demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yW2uyC"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FfkJv0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22761188/stack-overflow-the-key-copy-paste-review-price-release-date-keyboard"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22761188/stack-overflow-the-key-copy-paste-review-price-release-date-keyboard</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-03T11:09:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-03T11:09:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Eero’s Pro 6 highlights the latest early Black Friday sales</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kb_cnUXMS81_lTRnW7wrWdytE0U=/284x0:1820x1024/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70086066/dseifert_201213_4337_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eero’s Pro 6 offers mesh Wi-Fi options as a standalone unit or in two and three-pack options.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WyjO75"&gt;November has come roaring out of the gates with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22759214/black-friday-early-deals-best-headphones-laptops-gaming-tvs-tech-sale"&gt;some strong deals&lt;/a&gt; and early &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/black-friday"&gt;Black Friday&lt;/a&gt; sales. It’s not every year that you can start buying holiday gifts and know you’re getting the best deals possible, even before we push the clocks back, but that’s what we’re looking at here with these discounts on Eero mesh routers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MQeaUN"&gt;You can pick up a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B085VNCZHL?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;one-pack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0866V73R6?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;two-pack&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B085VNCZHZ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;three-pack&lt;/a&gt; of Eero Pro 6 tri-band mesh Wi-Fi 6 routers at Amazon and Best Buy for all-time low prices. Eero mesh routers are popular for good reason. They offer one of the simplest and streamlined ways to bring a solid Wi-Fi connection to all corners of your house, regardless of its size or tricky layout. And, you can add more routers to your mesh Wi-Fi system later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J1cFIn"&gt;When we &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22193059/eero-pro-6-review-mesh-router-wifi-6-test-speeds-network"&gt;reviewed the Eero Pro 6 line&lt;/a&gt;, we had mixed feelings about how “Pro” these models were at their high-end gigabit performance. Though, our primary complaint was how expensive they originally sell for, and these deals go a long way to rectify that. Plus, this is the model to get if you need to connect several devices, including wired ethernet devices, since each router has two ethernet ports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MG51pH"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9599966"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YuKimY"&gt;For larger homes (up to 6,000 square feet, according to Eero’s spec sheet), a three-pack of the Pro 6 is just $449 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B085VNCZHZ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfVkBgAVUXS" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. That’s a full $150 off the usual price of $600. While it might sound like overkill to go for a three-pack if you don’t own a small mansion, keep in mind the layout of your house. The multiple nodes can help if your home has a bit more of an oblong-shaped floor plan, like a ranch-style that is longer in one direction, or if the routers’ signal needs to pass through several walls or a floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="isICaI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9624413"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="My5p7A"&gt;Don’t own a giant house, or you’re rocking the apartment life? Don’t worry — we did not forget about you. You can also pick up a single Eero Pro 6 on sale right now. It’s just $171 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B085VNCZHL?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfVkP9fBn9w" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, compared to its usual $229. It’s not a bad idea to start out with just one since you can always add more routers to the system later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vdghbt"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10843446"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JpaonM"&gt;Amazon is also having an &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/b?node=23602414011&amp;amp;ref=dx_early_gd_dcl_tlt_2_3e381fc9_dt_sl5_b3" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;early Black Friday sale on Philips Hue smart lighting&lt;/a&gt;. The sale is just for today, and it offers some exceptional pricing on both color and white E26 bulbs. You can get a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Philips-Hue-Bluetooth-Compatible-Assistant/dp/B08D9N7RJ4/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;three-pack of color bulbs for $80&lt;/a&gt;, a big discount off its full price of $135. This is a great price for Hue bulbs, and they can adjust to nearly any color you desire, rendering them great for accent lighting in lamps or even as the main bulbs for any room. They don’t come with a Hue Bridge to connect them via your local network, but they are controllable via Bluetooth with the Philips Hue app. The Hue ecosystem is expansive, too, so you can always add more to it. This is a great pack to get started or to further build out your repertoire of smart bulbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="562gLm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10649409"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fvTQp2"&gt;If you prefer more fine-tuned control through the Hue smartphone app or even via a wall-mount switch, the Philips Hue white LED smart button kit is another option to consider. These bulbs cannot take on every color of the rainbow, but they can be adjusted from a relaxing warm white to an energizing bright white. This kit comes with the bridge hub, so you can expand the system and use more smart functionality through the app. The included smart button can also mount to a wall, without any wiring, to control the lights smartphone-free. This is a lot of functionality and convenience for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Philips-Hue-Starter-HomeKit-Assistant/dp/B07XC2CXKK?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$80, on sale just for today at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DSPZXd"&gt;There is one more Hue deal at Amazon to consider, pairing this &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Philips-Hue-Button-Bluetooth-Lightstrip/dp/B09783J3Q4?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;smart button kit with a Bluetooth smart light strip for $144&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OOibm5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10843381"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wjuiBA"&gt;Brydge iPad keyboard cases that feature a trackpad are on sale this week, offering some nice alternatives to the pricier iPad smart keyboards from Apple while doubling as protective cases when they’re folded shut. Some notable discounts include: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="ngpQTc"&gt;The Air Max Plus for the popular iPad Air released last year is now discounted to &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Brydge-Multi-Touch-Generation-Detachable-MIL-STD-810G/dp/B0988BQH1R?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$130 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; (was $150).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JVzIpG"&gt;The 12.9 Max Plus for 12.9-inch iPad Pro models, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfVlv4oe4EV" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$50 off a Best Buy for a sale price of $200&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22553643/brydge-12-9-max-plus-review-price-shipping" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BGrgkb"&gt;Brydge’s 10.2 Max Plus for the base iPads (including the recent ninth-gen model), on sale for &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfVlycbuN34" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$110 at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="5RGPOi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Brydge’s Pro Plus iPad keyboard gets much better trackpad support with new firmware","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287000/brydge-pro-plus-ipad-keyboard-new-firmware-native-multitouch"},{"title":"Brydge’s new keyboard for the M1 iPad makes it more MacBook-like than ever","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22396039/brydge-keyboard-magnetic-tablet-laptop-m1-ipad-max"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="ioZ8Jy"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10843491"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="1xaQ9G"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10843508"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="QTFXyh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10685165"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="wYwmWS"&gt;Other deals you shouldn’t miss&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="6ExQYu"&gt;Beats Solo Pro noise-canceling wireless headphones with Apple’s H1 chip are &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07YW2HJZ6?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;50 percent off at Amazon, for just $149&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/25/20931329/beats-solo-pro-review-noise-canceling-on-ear-wireless-headphones-features-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ppwSaN"&gt;Sennheiser Momentum 3 noise-canceling wireless headphones are &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08B3MJBW8/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$160 off at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, bringing them down to $240. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/5/20843395/sennheiser-momentum-wireless-3-review-release-date-news-specs-features-noise-cancelling-headphones" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yWm50l"&gt;November &lt;a href="https://gaming.amazon.com/home" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Prime Gaming&lt;/a&gt; promotions include free PC digital copies of &lt;a href="https://gaming.amazon.com/loot/dragonageinquisition" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dragon Age: Inquisition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on EA’s Origin, &lt;a href="https://gaming.amazon.com/loot/control" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Control: Ultimate Edition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on GOG, and &lt;a href="https://gaming.amazon.com/loot/riseofthetombraider" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rise of the Tomb Raider&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on Epic Games Store. If you’re an Amazon Prime member, these Prime Gaming offers are included with your subscription.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="PIR5An"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/11/3/22761102/eero-pro-6-philips-hue-black-friday-brydge-apple-ipad-keyboard-amazon-gaming-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/11/3/22761102/eero-pro-6-philips-hue-black-friday-brydge-apple-ipad-keyboard-amazon-gaming-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
