<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-30T09:16:02-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-30T09:16:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-30T09:16:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to use your Oculus Quest 2 to play any PC VR game wirelessly</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Virtual Desktop" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/q8Sb_6aZYKAVgUN-Mu726FoGJrQ=/0x0:1440x960/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68643020/hero.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oh hey, it’s all of my PC games available to play on the Quest 2, wire-free, from within a virtual room. This is getting weird.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vDDDh3"&gt;One of the best features of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21437674/oculus-quest-2-review-features-photos"&gt;Oculus Quest and Quest 2&lt;/a&gt; is that they can be manually linked via USB to your gaming PC so you can play more demanding VR games that couldn’t otherwise be run natively on the headsets. That’s great if you want a way to play games like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/23/21188291/half-life-alyx-review-valve-index-oculus-quest-vr-shooter"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Half-Life: Alyx&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; but the obvious downside is that you’re now physically tethered to a PC — so much for the wireless freedom that the Quest platform advertises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WTupji"&gt;Since then, the developers at Virtual Desktop — and, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22400197/oculus-quest-2-air-link-pc-streaming-v28-launch"&gt;more recently, Oculus itself&lt;/a&gt; — have both figured out how to stream the visual feed from your PC to your VR headset while quickly syncing all of your movements over Wi-Fi. Either option will give you the best of both worlds: letting you play the games you want without being attached by a cable to your computer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f3KFeB"&gt;Oculus’ method, which is called Air Link, now comes as a complimentary feature with the headset (if you’re running v28 software), while using Virtual Desktop requires a $20 app. There are benefits to both options, so we’re going to walk you through setting up each of them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XfdGX2"&gt;Up first is Oculus Air Link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="uPJ4bd"&gt;Installing and enabling Oculus Air Link&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="GkS9lu"&gt;In late April 2021, Oculus released the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382805/oculus-quest-2-facebook-wireless-pc-streaming-120hz-infinite-office"&gt;v28 software&lt;/a&gt; containing Air Link, a feature that enables wireless PC streaming. To check if your Quest is running the right software: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="GNuRoA"&gt;Click the gear icon along the bottom section of the headset’s screen to access the system settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="UyttUw"&gt;Scroll all the way down to bottom to find the “About” section and click that. Once you’re there, make sure that the version number is 28 or above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="2wToEf"&gt;Now, you need to enable the feature within the Oculus app on your PC. First off, make sure that app is updated to v28, like the headset. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="PqDQhD"&gt;Click “Settings” on the left-side navigation panel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dFlpcd"&gt;Go to the “General” tab and scroll all the way down to see the version number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Nw3zq8q1b7fRUlOdIMzZANx9kmI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21885654/Oculus_Quest_2.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="oI4cmb"&gt;Within the settings menu on the Oculus PC app, click the “Beta” tab. That’s where you should find Air Link, at least until it exits beta. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="T9iDm0"&gt;Toggle the switch to turn on Air Link. This &lt;a href="https://support.oculus.com/airlink/"&gt;FAQ on the Oculus site&lt;/a&gt; should show the most up-to-date info for these steps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/air5GeBy-l2KfmNLsZms6nUyNmk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22478856/oculusairlinkPCsetting.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Open settings, go to the beta tab, then toggle Air Link on.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="o9Tdgp"&gt;Switch Air Link on within your Quest headset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="oOUwex"&gt;Now that your software is updated and the feature has been turned on at your host PC, you can enable it within the headset. To do this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="EGHAl6"&gt;Put the headset back on and reopen the system settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yIJSAf"&gt;Find “Experimental Features.” Air Link will be nestled within that menu (at least for as long as Oculus considers it to be an experiment). Tap the toggle switch to activate it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="79aueL"&gt;Activate Air Link to play a game&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="QHTUBN"&gt;The Oculus app for PC must remain open for your headset to connect to it over Wi-Fi. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="nwS0oH"&gt;Physically position yourself within line of sight (or as close as possible) of your Wi-Fi router to get the best possible experience. Then put your headset back on and click once more into its system settings. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="aWUzzc"&gt;The first option on the left-hand side of the menu will say “Quick Actions.” Click that. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7V7LS2"&gt;You should see a large button for Air Link on the right side of this menu pane. Click on it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wG4T1k"&gt;After you click on Air Link, the next prompt will ask you to pick from a list of devices to connect to. Find your computer, and once you’ve successfully connected, you’ll be pushed into Oculus’ desktop interface, which looks a bit different than the Quest interface. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="jEv77u"&gt;If you need to make quick adjustments to Air Link’s bit rate to optimize performance (or if you want to quit using Air Link and return to the Quest interface), the left-most option at the bottom of your field of view will pull up a menu (shown below) that lets you do either.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Oculus Air Link" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ahqf6_Nm35VneWc5jxc0JfCj-8w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22478813/oculusairlink.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s what the Air Link menu looks like within the Oculus Home interface for PC.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="E0oS4h"&gt;Alternatively, buy the Virtual Desktop app for Quest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="qYkSF8"&gt;The Virtual Desktop app also lets you access your PC through the lens of a Quest VR headset. You can use it for games, like we’ll be doing here, but you can also watch movies you have stored on your PC in a variety of different virtual environments, or just browse the internet. &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=43993&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oculus.com%2Fexperiences%2Fquest%2F2017050365004772%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;There’s a Quest-specific version of the app that you can purchase here for $20&lt;/a&gt;. (Make sure it says that it’s compatible with Quest underneath the purchase button.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ViT64X"&gt;Compared to using Air Link, Virtual Desktop doesn’t take you completely out of the Quest interface. You can still hit the Oculus button on the right Touch controller to see the Quest universal menu. Yet, it allows for far more fine-tuning than Air Link currently does. You can adjust myriad settings to find the perfect performance for your setup, and it even has some extra tweaks, like letting you choose the kind of virtual environment the app will boot into. There’s an apartment, a computer room, an auditorium, and the vast expanse of deep space, to name a few examples. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2SQ7Hi"&gt;Get Virtual Desktop if you really want to have a custom experience, or as an alternative if Air Link doesn’t work all that well for you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Virtual Desktop" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iVvcJViGCifzUvXoqbandzJ1-6Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22220864/vd.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Virtual Desktop running on the Quest 2.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="7F3xXK"&gt;Download Virtual Desktop Streamer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="zwiEFT"&gt;There’s yet one more application to download for your PC: &lt;a href="https://www.vrdesktop.net/"&gt;Virtual Desktop Streamer&lt;/a&gt;. It’s free, and made by the same folks who made the Virtual Desktop app you purchased on the Quest or Quest 2. This app is necessary for streaming PC content to your headset via Wi-Fi. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="LRXQqT"&gt;Once this app is downloaded and installed, you’ll need to input your Oculus username in the Streamer window &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Ovpydi"&gt;If you don’t know it off the top of your head, you can find it by opening the Oculus app on mobile, navigating to “Settings,” and then tapping on the area that shows your name and email address. The name that will display next to your avatar is your username.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Oculus app" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R-J0UPjJSbyMOlAcOy2iyZNZhBk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22220804/oculusname.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Having a hard time finding your Oculus username? Tap on your full name in the Settings menu to see this view pictured above.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="dCc3Bu"&gt;After that’s entered, hit “Save”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RXWg5x"&gt;That’s the last step! But remember that it’s crucial to have the Virtual Desktop Streamer app open in order for your headset to communicate with your PC. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Virtual Desktop Streamer" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uFCk8sazQ5CJ39c4U4ARWJVRwXA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22220811/streamer.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s what the Virtual Desktop Streamer app looks like. It’s very simple.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="FylPqj"&gt;Open Virtual Desktop on your Quest headset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="tFxMTY"&gt;You should see your PC pop up in the list of available devices to connect to from within the Virtual Desktop app on your Quest or Quest 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oWDSZP"&gt;Once you’ve connected, the Options button (the left Touch controller’s equivalent of the Oculus button) is mapped to open up the top-level menu for Virtual Desktop, as shown in the image below. From there, clicking “Games” will reveal every game that’s installed on your PC. You can simply boot each one from there, and your PC will handle all of the hard work of opening the necessary apps. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Virtual Desktop" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RetcNAlbbLJZGLVlASVqciHC1_U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22220812/virtudaldesktopgames.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;All of the VR-ready games installed on your PC will show up within Virtual Desktop.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="E4ucp4"&gt;If you aren’t happy with the visual fidelity within each game, you’re free to customize some settings that affect latency, refresh rate, and more. Note that you’ll likely get a clearer, more fluid image if your PC is powerful. Your wireless router plays a huge role in delivering a smooth experience, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PNzjSC"&gt;Streaming VR over Wi-Fi certainly isn’t a perfect solution. I play just a few feet away from a Wi-Fi 6-ready router that’s wired directly to my PC via an ethernet switch, yet I still experience the occasional spot of lag and slightly fuzzy image. Though with enough tweaking on the Virtual Desktop app (turning Wi-Fi off on seldom-used tech items never hurts), I think you’ll have a good time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="zU1OZb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Facebook is turning VR into a platform — but some indie devs fear its power","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21455665/facebook-oculus-vr-indie-developers-power-monopoly-concerns"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="L6crr9"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update April 30th, 9:16AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated this post with the steps involved for setting up Air Link for Oculus Quest and Quest 2.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ot7NCR"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; The original article erroneously suggested that internet speed played a role in your ability to use this wireless solution to play your VR games. It’s all handled locally. Also, due to a malfunctioning USB-C port on the author’s PC, they erroneously stated that the USB-C cable included with each Quest 2 couldn’t be used to complete this how-to. A reader pointed out that it will work, and the author confirmed it by using the cable with an OTG adapter. We regret these errors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22218827/oculus-quest-2-wireless-pc-vr-games-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22218827/oculus-quest-2-wireless-pc-vr-games-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-30T09:00:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-30T09:00:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>Roku removes YouTube TV from channel store as dispute with Google escalates</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aq1tMjfCzmPCYzzYmNYMRKoe0rw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69211454/cwelch_20210428_4565_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Fhxoz3"&gt;Roku has pulled YouTube TV from its channel store. The distribution agreement between Roku and Google for YouTube TV has expired as of today — and the two sides haven’t been able to reach a new deal. However, Roku says it is “taking the extra step to continue to offer existing subscribers access to YouTube TV on the Roku platform unless Google takes actions that require the full removal of the channel.” New subscriptions from the YouTube TV app have also been switched off “until an agreement is reached.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Oijh6b"&gt;In an email to customers, Roku warned “it is also important that you do not delete the YouTube TV app as it will not be available for download to Roku devices.” The regular YouTube app is unaffected by this situation and remains freely available on Roku devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="68iHaA"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/26/22403740/roku-youtube-tv-google-standoff-competition-negotiations-contract"&gt;Roku has accused Google&lt;/a&gt; of seeking unfair terms that would adversely affect streaming competitors and benefit the YouTube suite of apps. Google has also asked for deeper access to Roku customer data than other services, Roku claims, and is pushing Roku to adopt new hardware requirements; presumably the company is aiming to get VP9 supported in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qipS6m"&gt;“We have only asked Google for four simple commitments,” Roku said in a new statement today. “First, not to manipulate consumer search results. Second, not to require access to data not available to anyone else. Third, not to leverage their YouTube monopoly to force Roku to accept hardware requirements that would increase consumer costs. Fourth, not to act in a discriminatory and anticompetitive manner against Roku.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dXilMH"&gt;Earlier this week, Google accused Roku of abusing its strong position in the streaming hardware market. “Roku often engages in these types of tactics in their negotiations. We’re disappointed that they chose to make baseless claims while we continue our ongoing negotiations,” a Google spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; on Monday. “All of our work with them has been focused on ensuring a high quality and consistent experience for our viewers. We have made no requests to access user data or interfere with search results. We hope we can resolve this for the sake of our mutual users.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YE6l2r"&gt;The takeaway is that we’re witnessing a more online, digital version of the carriage disputes that are so common between cable providers and content providers. Both companies are choosing their words extremely carefully. Roku has insisted it’s not demanding more money from Google, and its email to customers — sent out at 8AM ET this morning — says “we cannot accept Google’s unfair and anticompetitive requirements that would allow for the manipulation of your search results, impact the usage of your data, and ultimately cost you more.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22411711/roku-removes-youtube-tv-channel-store"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22411711/roku-removes-youtube-tv-channel-store</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-30T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-30T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Solar flare: why Tesla’s price hike has customers seeing spots</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9eTt3NtZIV57WxuKJjLItbY19Ek=/0x73:1040x766/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69211368/3558a860_8c1c_425b_8760_8766d441ae27.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Elon Musk says ‘significant mistakes’ were made in how Tesla calculates solar roof costs. Customers are irate&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="hVuaWG"&gt;Gene Frakes, an electrician and skydiving instructor who lives outside of Rockford, IL, became a Tesla Energy customer after watching &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f_GHVSL35-k&amp;amp;t=251s"&gt;a video of snow effortlessly sliding off one of the company’s new solar roofs&lt;/a&gt;. It was just the proof he was looking for that Tesla’s innovative glass roof tiles with embedded solar cells would work just as well in snowy climates as they do in sunnier parts of the country like California. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XAybtQ"&gt;“That was impressive,” Frakes, 50, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Upop4"&gt;But his excitement quickly faded after he received an email from Tesla informing him that the original estimate for the 10.58kW project would be increasing to $53,649 from $34,743 — a 54 percent jump. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BNTrjL3q8IBRiF46jokPvCIp4bQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22478663/iMarkup_20210412_174014.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gene Frakes could hardly believe it when Tesla told him it was raising the price of his solar roof by 54 percent.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LuLZNi"&gt;“It seems so incorrect that I could hardly believe it,” Frakes said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D2CXri"&gt;Frakes wasn’t the only one left sun-kissed by Tesla’s massive price increase. In early April, notices started going out to customers awaiting installation of their Tesla solar roofs that their prices would be going up, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/12/22380057/tesla-solar-roof-price-increase-contract-amount"&gt;sometimes by as much as 100 percent&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; spoke to 11 Tesla solar roof customers around the country who have canceled or are considering canceling their orders. They are commiserating with each other in chat groups, airing their grievances online, and launching petitions to raise awareness about the issue. Some are even considering filing a class action lawsuit against Musk’s company.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ghXkFu"&gt;Tesla offers two solar products: conventional solar panels, which are installed over a customer’s existing roof; and the solar roof, which replaces the current roof slats with ones capable of soaking up the sun’s rays and transforming it into energy. The solar roof is designed to look like asphalt, slate, and Spanish barrel tiles to fit the style of each home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eyeHH1"&gt;It would later be revealed that the company had underestimated the complexity of some of the roofs. Tesla CEO Elon Musk admitted as much in an earnings call on April 26th, saying that the company had made “significant mistakes” in how it calculates the installation costs. Tesla tried to soften the blow by offering some aggrieved customers free Powerwall home batteries if they renewed their orders. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zKCCAT"&gt;But it may not work. Even before the price increases, solar roof customers were filing lawsuits claiming Tesla had destroyed their credit rating by reporting loans they never requested. The price increases are the latest self-inflicted wound that has caused Tesla’s once vaunted solar business, which it originally acquired in 2015, to lose market share as more companies get involved and the price of solar drops nationwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M-Iy2T-lIPXjMkjdqRTIYjGHt64=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22478645/0x0_Solar_Roof_17.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Tesla&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="j0F2eH"&gt;In early March, everything was going well for Amr Kader, an OB-GYN from East Greenwich, RI, and his solar roof project. He’d taken out two loans and started paying down the premium. And he had received the necessary permits from his utility company and the local township. Kader, who also owns a Tesla Model Y, was excited about adding another Tesla product to his lifestyle.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6ZzFbt"&gt;But days before the project was set to begin, he received word from Tesla that it would be rescheduled for late April. After that, he was told his project would be delayed indefinitely due to the company’s inability to secure an installation crew in Rhode Island. After some back-and-forth, Tesla informed Kader that it would also be raising his price by $3,000, or 30 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="kjjT5y"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“abandonment of contract, extortion and deliberate misguidance and misinformation”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="N8lZ6O"&gt;Kader was incensed. He filed a complaint with the state attorney general’s consumer division, accusing Tesla of “abandonment of contract, extortion and deliberate misguidance and misinformation.” He also has been talking to a lawyer about filing a lawsuit against the company, and hopes to see Tesla’s license suspended or revoked in his state. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fZnKAU"&gt;As for his own order, Kader’s initial reaction was to dig in his heels. “I did not cancel my signed contract and made it clear I am not canceling,” he said. But ultimately he decided it wasn’t worth the effort and informed Tesla he wouldn’t be moving forward with the project. And he began shopping around for other, cheaper solar roof products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PY18Mp"&gt;“Honestly, I wouldn’t trust them installing my roof even if they would honor the original contract,” he said. But the Model Y in his driveway serves as a constant reminder of the whole debacle.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="30V3S0"&gt;“It definitely made me feel not proud any more of riding my Tesla car,” Kader admitted, “[and] advertising for them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Tesla’s Patient Superfans Are Willing To Pay Up For Solar Roofs" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nJlVaJxHqKJVRxU_71StHRvGo5U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22478650/1201885701.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Getty&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;On paper, Tesla’s energy division seems to be booming. But the division has never been profitable.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="DZTw8I"&gt;On paper, Tesla’s energy division seems to be booming. The company said it installed 92 mega-watts (MW) of solar energy in the first quarter of 2021, more than twice as much as the first quarter of 2020 — its strongest quarter in two-and-a-half years. Tesla generated $494 million in sales on its solar roofs, including storage products like the Powerwall battery. For all of 2020, Tesla installed 205 MW of solar energy, an 18 percent increase compared to 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="apN9rg"&gt;In the earnings call, Musk claimed that demand for Tesla’s solar roofs “remains strong.” But overall, the division is unprofitable and the company has gone from the biggest rooftop solar installer in the US to a distant second in recent years, falling behind San Francisco-based Sunrun. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UF487d"&gt;Tesla’s solar ambitions date back to 2015, when it acquired SolarCity, a company owned by Musk’s cousin. A year later, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/10/28/13463236/tesla-solar-roof-battery-new-elon-musk"&gt;Musk unveiled the solar roof&lt;/a&gt; on the former &lt;a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2019/08/how-elon-musk-gambled-tesla-to-save-solarcity"&gt;set of &lt;em&gt;Desperate Housewives&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, claiming that the roofs would look “as good or better” than conventional roofs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="njtnvs"&gt;&lt;q&gt;almost from the beginning, the deal proved to be a thorn in Musk’s side&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Atp3xV"&gt;But almost from the beginning, the deal proved to be a thorn in Musk’s side. Critics called it a “bailout” of the struggling SolarCity, which had piled up massive amounts of debt over the years. A number of Tesla shareholders sued Musk over the deal, alleging he overvalued SolarCity and did not properly recuse himself from the deal. &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-tesla-solarcity-lawsuit/tesla-directors-settle-isolating-musk-as-solarcity-trial-looms-idUSKBN1ZT2HF"&gt;Tesla’s board of directors settled the suit&lt;/a&gt; last year without Musk, leaving the CEO the lone defendant in the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xBkwYL"&gt;It’s also seen its share of the market slip. Tesla has fallen far behind Sunrun, which is the largest installer of solar panels in the US. It’s so far behind, Wall Street analysts barely pay attention to the company’s reports on its energy division, Wedbush’s Dan Ives said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ahL0it"&gt;“The Street doesn’t really assign a value to Tesla’s solar business,” Ives said, “because it’s relatively unproven thus far.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AVrHvd"&gt;“It’s been choppy to say the least,” Ives added, “since Tesla has really focused on solar the last few years. It’s between competition, pricing, and execution issues. I think they’ve gotten some upward momentum over the last nine to 12 months, but it’s definitely been more of a black eye on the overall Tesla story.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wUfLQj"&gt;Tesla’s decision to jack up prices on its solar roof customers also flies in the face of the trend of falling prices for solar installations overall, said Seth Blumsack, professor of energy and environmental economics at Penn State. The price of conventional solar panels that are installed on top of a customer’s roof — which are different from Tesla’s solar roof — have gone down 90 percent over the last decade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BiuUg9"&gt;“The pace of these cost declines has been just even beyond what even a lot of experts had predicted,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="EB8Nu5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The pace of these cost declines has been just even beyond what even a lot of experts had predicted”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YtJ8Ok"&gt;And the pace of installations have been growing, to the point where they are about 13 times greater than they were a decade ago, according to the Solar Energy Industries Association. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8Ypwkt"&gt;That said, it’s not unheard of for energy companies trying to introduce a new technology to the market to underestimate the initial costs, Blumstack said. If enough customers “bite the bullet” and decide to absorb the cost increases, that could send a signal to Tesla’s competitors on the direction this technology is going. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zx9kA7"&gt;“It’ll be interesting to see if they’re able to start driving the costs of solar roofs down the same way that we have seen the cost of traditional solar panels decline,” Blumsack said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ks0AqD"&gt;A spokesperson for Tesla did not respond to a request for comment, which isn’t surprising considering the company has eliminated its public relations department and hasn’t responded to a request for comment in over a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Solarglass Roof" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OTGXOVDFBa6NlkXW4if5a679ASc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22478660/1199455787.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Smith Collection / Gado / Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Close-up of Solarglass Roof, a roof shingle with integrated solar panels, from Tesla Energy, a division of Tesla Motors, on Santana Row in the Silicon Valley, San Jose, California, January 3rd, 2020.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="H5IClV"&gt;Texas resident Wissam Mehio is not one of those customers willing to “bite the bullet.” He promptly canceled his order after Tesla informed him that it would be increasing his price to $104,000 from the previous estimate of $69,000. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hZ3Sjt"&gt;“Tesla was so happy to see me go, my $100 [deposit] was refunded to my credit card less than 24 hours later,” he laughed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SiOUOg"&gt;It was particularly disappointing given how Mehio had started telling friends how proud he was about his new “beautiful solar roof.” He even expected a little price increase, and had budgeted an extra $5,000-10,000 for it, given that Tesla had said that the price it gave him was an estimate and would likely change once an onsite assessment is done. But slamming him with a 50 percent increase before coming out for the onsite assessment made canceling a “no-brainer,” Mehio said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="xT99ka"&gt;“With such a move, I feel Tesla Energy wants to transition back from ‘solar for everyone’ to ‘solar for those who don’t count their money,’” he added. “No hard feelings, but I’m out.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22410075/tesla-solar-roof-price-increase-customer-reactions"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22410075/tesla-solar-roof-price-increase-customer-reactions</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-30T08:43:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-30T08:43:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to buy the new iPad Pro with the M1 processor</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="iPad Pro 2021" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q9GZIA0Gfi4WQPK-l2mCpNu-xOw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69159356/ipadpro2021lede.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new iPad Pro&lt;/em&gt; | Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GUYWLh"&gt;Apple announced a 2021 refresh to its iPad Pro lineup, which now includes the same powerful and efficient M1 processor that’s in its MacBook Air, Pro, and Mac mini computers. Both the new 11-inch and 12.9-inch models will feature the chip, as well as a Thunderbolt port and optional 5G support. The display on the larger tablet has received a particularly big boost, jumping to a Liquid Retina XDR Mini LED screen. My colleague Monica Chin has gone deeper on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22385675/apple-ipad-pro-m1-chip-specs-features-price"&gt;more of this year’s big improvements&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iB5ppe"&gt;If you have your eye on the new iPad Pro, preorders begin today, April 30th, with shipping beginning the week of May 21st. Preorders are available at several retailers, including Apple’s direct website and Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="IcpI9v"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The colorful M1 iMac, Mini LED iPad Pro, and refreshed Apple TV 4K are available to preorder now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22409463/apple-m1-imac-ipad-pro-apple-tv-4k-preorders-price-release-date"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="24HsU8"&gt;Where to buy the 11-inch M1 iPad Pro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="euCrDs"&gt;The 11-inch iPad Pro starts at $799 for 128GB of storage and Wi-Fi connectivity. The model with LTE and 5G support costs $200 more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FRO1s7"&gt;If you are looking for this specific model, you can buy it at &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/435031/7613?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-ipad%2Fipad-pro&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Apple’s direct website&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-11-inch-Wi-Fi-128GB/dp/B08637NV8M?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1636248-REG%2Fapple_mhqr3ll_a_11_ipad_pro_wi_fi.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1739232056163661547#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-ipad-pro-11-inch-wi-fi-only%2F-%2FA-82866372%3Fpreselect%3D77616907%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;subid1=WhereToOrderM1iPadPro04302021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iArXoZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10456970"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="27UT4W"&gt;Where to buy the 12.9-inch M1 iPad Pro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="rHZnHK"&gt;If you want the big 12.9-inch iPad Pro, that model starts at $1,099 and comes with 128GB of storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w4b5Km"&gt;The high-end M1 iPad Pro is available for preorder at &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/435031/7613?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-ipad%2Fipad-pro&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-12-9-inch-Wi-Fi-128GB/dp/B0863D15R6?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1636228-REG%2Fapple_mhnf3ll_a_12_9_ipad_pro_wifi.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1739232031086405668#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-ipad-pro-12-9-inch-wi-fi-only%2F-%2FA-82866370%3Fpreselect%3D80601874%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;subid1=WhereToOrderM1iPadPro04302021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="UWdJ8G"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10456977"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="qGFHmp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple announces thinner iMac with M1 chip and bright colors","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394034/apple-new-imac-m1-chip-colors-design-specs-price-release-date"},{"title":"Apple debuts $29 AirTag, a new Tile-like item tracker","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/20844326/apple-airtags-bluetooth-tracker-keys-tile-features-price"},{"title":"Apple announces new Apple TV 4K","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22386298/apple-tv-4k-a12-bionic-price-features-release-date"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="bPQbD3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394227/apple-ipad-pro-2021-how-where-to-buy-preorder-link"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394227/apple-ipad-pro-2021-how-where-to-buy-preorder-link</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-30T08:30:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-30T08:30:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>The colorful M1 iMac, Mini LED iPad Pro, and refreshed Apple TV 4K are available to preorder now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An image showing all seven colors of the new iMac: green, yellow, orange, pink, purple, blue, and silver." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0rtwDK7ce854Oqg-tIjyJow3Ic4=/168x0:1977x1206/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69211243/apple_new_imac_spring21_hero_04202021_Full_Bleed_Image.jpg.medium_2x.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zVUzXt"&gt;Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394034/apple-new-imac-m1-chip-colors-design-specs-price-release-date"&gt;colorful new M1-powered iMacs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22385675/apple-ipad-pro-m1-chip-specs-features-price"&gt;refreshed iPad Pros&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22386298/apple-tv-4k-a12-bionic-price-features-release-date"&gt;updated Apple TV 4K&lt;/a&gt; (with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/18277449/apple-tv-remote-new-design-4k-features-price-release-date"&gt;not-terrible-looking remote&lt;/a&gt;) are now &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1043467/7613?subId1=VergeColorfulMacs043021&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-ipad%2Fipad-pro"&gt;all available to preorder today&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1043467/7613?subId1=VergeColorfulMacs043021&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-tv%2Fapple-tv-4k"&gt;Apple’s website. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZKghJ5"&gt;The company says that the new products will be delivered starting on May 21st —at least for the first wave of orders, although that timing will certainly slip as stock sells out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bn5giu"&gt;Customers interested in &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1043467/7613?subId1=VergeColorfulMacs043021&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-mac%2Fimac"&gt;buying the new iMac&lt;/a&gt; should take note that only some of the color schemes will be available in stores: green, pink, blue, and silver models will be sold in-person at Apple Store locations, but the full seven-color spectrum will only be offered through Apple’s website, at least for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="pG1SBW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10474574"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RIuuCz"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1043467/7613?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-ipad%2Fipad-pro%2F12.9-inch-display-128gb-space-gray-wifi"&gt;new iPad Pro &lt;/a&gt;also features Apple’s new M1 processor (the same as the iMac and last falls updated MacBooks), in addition to an upgraded ultra-wide angle camera for better video calls. Additionally, the larger 12.9-inch model will feature a new Mini LED display, which promises a far brighter and more accurate screen experience — at the cost of a $100 price increase over the 2020 model. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CpLbLU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10456970"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="7VWyXn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10456977"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BGx6Iy9UvD77g1r7uSQJtT6KIzo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22479128/Screen_Shot_2021_04_29_at_4.31.13_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ICQOxQ"&gt;Also of particular note: in addition to the preorders for the updated Apple TV 4K, preorders have also opened for &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/1043467/7613?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FMJFM3LL%2FA%2Fsiri-remote"&gt;the standalone $59 Siri Remote&lt;/a&gt; for existing Apple TV HD and Apple TV 4K (first-gen) owners looking to replace the infamous first-generation Siri Remote with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/18277449/apple-tv-remote-new-design-4k-features-price-release-date"&gt;(hopefully) better new design&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iujnaU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10474579"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="W4Vwzt"&gt;Alongside the preorders for the new Apple products, the first wave of last week’s AirTag and purple iPhone 12 and 12 mini devices should be arriving to both customers and in Apple Stores starting today. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22409463/apple-m1-imac-ipad-pro-apple-tv-4k-preorders-price-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22409463/apple-m1-imac-ipad-pro-apple-tv-4k-preorders-price-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-30T07:41:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-30T07:41:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s answer to the problems of open plan offices? Inflatable walls</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="U.S. DOJ File Antitrust Lawsuit Against Google" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mkzAcIeSBOj12vlXcjBQXZXFtcQ=/0x2:3500x2335/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69210992/1281728505.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Eduardo MunozAlvarez/VIEWpress&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HC2pcJ"&gt;Google is redesigning its offices for the post-pandemic world, and &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; has &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/30/technology/google-back-to-office-workers.html"&gt;a big report full of pictures and videos&lt;/a&gt; outlining the company’s plans. But if I had to sum up the tech giant’s approach in two words I would choose “over” and “engineered.” Google has ambitious plans to shake up its offices, but some of them seem needlessly complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cFdFxl"&gt;As the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; notes, the standard for Silicon Valley offices has long been open plan, with designers and developers working by cheek by jowl in the name of “spontaneous collaboration.” (Though this is often a pretext to cut costs by cramming as many workers into pricey real estate as possible.) But, in a cautious COVID-conscious culture neither cramming nor cubicles can cut it: people want space, man. At least six feet of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g0ahdO"&gt;Here’s the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;, paraphrasing concerns from Google’s VP for real estate and workplace services, David Radcliffe:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="qeE1Ct"&gt;&lt;em&gt;In its current office configurations, Google said it would be able to use only one out of every three desks in order to keep people six feet apart. Mr. Radcliffe said six feet would remain an important threshold in case of the next pandemic or even the annual flu.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fAHRJh"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Psychologically, he said, employees will not want to sit in a long row of desks, and also Google may need to “de-densify” offices with white space such as furniture or plants. The company is essentially unwinding years of open-office plan theory popularized by Silicon Valley — that cramming more workers into smaller spaces and taking away their privacy leads to better collaboration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="OFAOwb"&gt;This makes sense! But Google’s approach to implementing these changes in its Mountain View offices are a mixed bag. Here are some of the methods mentioned:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="YRxhNN"&gt;Instead of rows of desks and meeting rooms, Google will use “Team Pods” containing “[c]hairs, desks, whiteboards and storage units on casters” that can be “wheeled into various arrangements, and in some cases rearranged in a matter of hours”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="IxOUM8"&gt;To create temporary divides between open plan desks, the company is testing inflatable robot walls that can be wheeled around and blown up like a bounce house.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9WowNm"&gt;“[A] fabric-based overhead air duct system that attaches with zippers and can be moved over a weekend for different seating arrangements.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="MDBLpQ"&gt;To accommodate remote workers in meetings, a new semi-circular “campfire” meeting room alternates seats for those physically present with screens for those calling in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="A7i8gZ"&gt;More outdoor work and meeting spaces, with tables and chairs in open-air tents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="QXMAXY"&gt;To make hot-desking easier, Google is testing a workstation that remembers users’ settings, adjusting the local temperature and height and tilt of the monitor based on a worker’s card swipe. It even “brings up family photos on a display” for that cubicle feeling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kjMVKD"&gt;Optional “leaf-shaped partitions” called “petals” can be attached to desks to “to eliminate glare” and office chairs with built-in speakers in the headrest will play white noise “to muffle nearby audio.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dL83HMLH5DgJaonQ8EBOIvUtIuQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22480829/inflatable_robot_wall_small.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/30/technology/google-back-to-office-workers.html" target="_blank"&gt;Cayce Clifford for &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The inflatable robot wall in action&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dAS1e6"&gt;Again, some of these sound great. Who wouldn’t want more outdoor space in their office or meeting rooms that are more welcoming for remote workers? But the focus on &lt;em&gt;modularity&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;adaptiveness&lt;/em&gt; seems like a recipe for disaster. The mix of inflatable privacy shields, fabric air ducts, dynamic hot-desks, clip-on desk partitions, and rearrangeable desks and storage make it sound like employees will have to build their office from scratch each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vxElEQ"&gt;Indeed, some of these solutions are trying to solve problems that only exist in the first place &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; of open plan offices. You don’t need speakers blasting white noise at your head or removable partitions to reduce glare if you’ve got a room of your own to work in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DRts16"&gt;I’m sure the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; is playing up some of these more bizarre elements, and it’s not like Google employees are known for the hardships they face. (Play a tune on an appropriately-sized violin for the closure of the company’s complimentary massage rooms.) But it does baffle me somewhat that such complicated solutions need to be created in the first place. Maybe old-fashioned offices (with appropriate ventilation) could be the answer? Specially if you don’t have to fit in as many employees because more are working from home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fBVIT6"&gt;I may be alone in this, but I’ve always quite fancied a genuine, honest-to-goodness, walls-and-a-door office of my own. That was true pre-pandemic and it’ll be true post-pandemic, too. Ironically, it’s only being forced to work remotely that’s meant I’ve created a decent working space in my own home for the first time. If only I could get the same at the office.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/4/30/22411593/google-post-pandemic-office-plans-inflatable-robot-walls"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/4/30/22411593/google-post-pandemic-office-plans-inflatable-robot-walls</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-30T06:44:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-30T06:44:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google is cracking down on scammy Play Store app listings</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mAV1xOaeinCYnUeOYCWP2UVvNuc=/0x0:801x534/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69210776/BadExample_Emoticons.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An example of the kind of listing that will be prohibited under the new policy.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pEyPiC"&gt;&lt;a href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2021/04/updated-guidance-to-improve-your-app.html"&gt;Google has announced&lt;/a&gt; new Play Store policies and guidelines designed to make app listings more succinct, accurate, and less of an eyesore. New guidelines affecting the screenshots and videos meant to demonstrate an app’s features and functionality will come into force in the second half of 2021, while specific details about the enforcement of new policies for app titles, icons, and descriptions are coming “later this year.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aK3ByR"&gt;The new app metadata policies will ban a variety of tricks that app developers use to make their app listings excessively eye-catching. Writing words in all-caps will no longer be allowed unless it’s the name of a brand, and neither will including emoji in app names. App titles will be limited to 30 characters, and they can’t “incentivize installs” by including a phrase like “download now.” Trying to promote deals by including a “Sale” banner in an app icon is also being banned.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P1ILMy6pCoxQxUsWNTbgLEZTE-w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22480745/BadExample_PlayPrograms_Categories.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Incentivizing installs via an app’s title is being banned.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nnjBA5jdkby30rP7EeVuCcXQXPM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22480744/BadExample_StorePerformance.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;As is implying an app is top-ranked.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="JHlU2b"&gt;Google calls this week’s blog post a “pre-announcement” designed to help developers plan for the upcoming changes. However, when the policies governing app title, icon, and developer name come into effect, Google says that apps that violate the policies “will not be allowed on Google Play.” It says that more details on the changes will arrive later in the year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EK77KL"&gt;Separately, the new guidelines about app preview assets will come into effect in the second half of the year. These guidelines ask that graphics, videos, and short descriptions “accurately represent” apps and games, “provide enough information” to users, don’t use buzzwords like “free” or “best,” and are localized correctly. “Assets that don’t meet our guidelines may be ineligible for promotion and recommendation on major Google Play surfaces like Apps and Games home,” Google says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JAKPPF"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wnSBV7"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22411560/google-play-store-listings-scammy-emoji-deals-misleading-assets-guidelines-policy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22411560/google-play-store-listings-scammy-emoji-deals-misleading-assets-guidelines-policy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-30T06:22:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-30T06:22:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>EU accuses Apple of App Store antitrust violations after Spotify complaint</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VqtFOuFebY1LbsCuVX4Zn5glh60=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69210747/acastro_20200818_1777_epicApple_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="l4xjY4"&gt;The European Commission is issuing antitrust charges against Apple over concerns about the company’s App Store practices. The Commission &lt;a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/ip_21_2061"&gt;has found&lt;/a&gt; that Apple has broken EU competition rules with its App Store policies, following an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/13/18263453/spotify-apple-app-store-antitrust-complaint-ec-30-percent-cut-unfair"&gt;initial complaint from Spotify&lt;/a&gt; back in 2019. Specifically, the Commission believes Apple has a “dominant position in the market for the distribution of music streaming apps through its App Store.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O2aX30"&gt;The EU has focused on two rules that Apple imposes on developers: the mandatory use of Apple’s in-app purchase system (for which Apple charges a 30 percent cut), and a rule forbidding app developers to inform users of other purchasing options outside of apps. The Commission has found that the 30 percent commission fee, or “Apple tax” as it’s often referred to, has resulted in higher prices for consumers. “Most streaming providers passed this fee on to end users by raising prices,” according to the European Commission. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="hFR5pP"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Our preliminary conclusion: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Apple?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Apple&lt;/a&gt; is in breach of EU competition law. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AppleMusic?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@AppleMusic&lt;/a&gt; compete with other music streaming services. But &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Apple?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Apple&lt;/a&gt; charges high commission fees on rivals in the App store &amp;amp; forbids them to inform of alternative subscription options. Consumers losing out.&lt;/p&gt;— Margrethe Vestager (@vestager) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/vestager/status/1388071379094982659?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 30, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2VYy8v"&gt;“Apple’s rules distort competition in the market for music streaming services by raising the costs of competing music streaming app developers,” says a statement from the Commission. “This in turn leads to higher prices for consumers for their in-app music subscriptions on iOS devices.” The EU has also sent Apple a statement of objections, which is essentially a list of how the Commission believes Apple has violated competition rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uOdCJp"&gt;This is the initial, formal stage of antitrust proceedings against Apple, and the company will have the chance to respond to the Commission’s list of objections within the next 12 weeks. This specific case is limited to Apple’s App Store practices for music streaming, and the EU is investigating additional separate cases on ebooks and the App Store in general. “This is not the last case we will have when it comes to the App Store,” said European commissioner Margrethe Vestager in a press conference this morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yvwu7E"&gt;Vestager also revealed the Commission is taking an interest in Apple’s policies around games on the App Store. “We also take an interest in the gaming app market,” said Vestager, responding to a question about the money involved in gaming apps on the App Store. “That’s really early days when it comes to that.” Microsoft &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/19/21296657/microsoft-apple-app-store-antitrust-comments"&gt;called on regulators to investigate the App Store last year&lt;/a&gt;, just a couple of months before a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/6/21357771/apple-cloud-gaming-microsoft-xcloud-google-stadia-ios-app-store-guidelines-violations"&gt;public spat with Apple&lt;/a&gt; over its xCloud game streaming service.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9Uu-KLuKdNnlK8sa1T0vd91UANM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16334298/microsoft_xcloud_e3_2019_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Nick Statt / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The EU may look into gaming apps on the App Store, too.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="WN6Lnc"&gt;Apple now faces a fine of up to 10 percent of its annual revenue if it’s found guilty of breaking EU rules, which could be as high as $27 billion based on Apple’s annual revenue of $274.5 billion last year. Apple could also be forced to change its business model, which has more damaging and lasting effects than a fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fGyeEf"&gt;Spotify has welcomed the initial charges. “Ensuring the iOS platform operates fairly is an urgent task with far-reaching implications,” says Horacio Gutierrez, Spotify’s chief legal officer. “The European Commission’s statement of objections is a critical step toward holding Apple accountable for its anticompetitive behavior, ensuring meaningful choice for all consumers and a level playing field for app developers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jlGqEp"&gt;Apple has also responded to the EU’s findings in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="jMHOy5"&gt;“Spotify has become the largest music subscription service in the world, and we’re proud for the role we played in that. Spotify does not pay Apple any commission on over 99% of their subscribers, and only pays a 15% commission on those remaining subscribers that they acquired through the App Store. At the core of this case is Spotify’s demand they should be able to advertise alternative deals on their iOS app, a practice that no store in the world allows. Once again, they want all the benefits of the App Store but don’t think they should have to pay anything for that. The Commission’s argument on Spotify’s behalf is the opposite of fair competition.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="7ren1R"&gt;Central to this entire case is the 30 percent cut that Apple takes on subscriptions. Companies like Netflix and Spotify have long opposed this so-called Apple tax, but Apple has argued that the revenue contributes toward the costs of maintaining the App Store and enforcing its various content, privacy, and security policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BPZH40"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/6/18530894/apple-music-monopoly-spotify-app-store-europe"&gt;Spotify previously claimed&lt;/a&gt; that Apple uses its App Store to stifle innovation and limit consumer choice in favor of its own Apple Music service. That complaint was followed up with a similar one &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/16/21292625/apple-rakuten-kobo-app-store-antitrust-complaint-europe"&gt;by Rakuten&lt;/a&gt;, alleging that it’s anti-competitive for Apple to take a 30 percent commission on ebooks sold through the App Store while promoting its own Apple Books service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lVGfEE"&gt;Epic Games also joined many developers and companies opposing Apple’s App Store policies, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22286998/epic-games-apple-european-comission-antitrust-complaint-app-store-fortnite"&gt;filed an antitrust complaint&lt;/a&gt; with the EU earlier this year. It’s part of an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21367923/fortnite-apple-app-store-epic-games-need-to-know/archives"&gt;ongoing dispute with Apple&lt;/a&gt;, after the &lt;em&gt;Fortnite &lt;/em&gt;developer publicly criticized Apple’s App Store policies around distribution and payments. This resulted in Epic &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21366259/epic-fortnite-vbucks-mega-drop-discount-iphone-android"&gt;attempting to circumvent&lt;/a&gt; Apple’s 30 percent cut on in-app purchases in &lt;em&gt;Fortnite, and &lt;/em&gt;Apple quickly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21366438/apple-fortnite-ios-app-store-violations-epic-payments"&gt;removing the game from its App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pp0rbg"&gt;Apple has eased some of its policies over the past year, as the pushback against the App Store grows louder. Apple now lets some video streaming apps &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/1/21203630/apple-amazon-prime-video-ios-app-store-cut-exempt-program-deal"&gt;bypass the App Store cut&lt;/a&gt;, and it has reduced its App Store &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/18/21572302/apple-app-store-small-business-program-commission-cut-15-percent-reduction"&gt;commission rate to 15 percent&lt;/a&gt; for any developer that earns less than $1 million in annual revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IplmjP"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, April 30th 6:30AM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Article updated with statements from Apple and Spotify.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2cPwZy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, April 30th 7:40AM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Article updated with additional comments from European commissioner Margrethe Vestager.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22407376/apple-european-union-antitrust-charges-app-store-music-competition-commission-margrethe-vestager"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22407376/apple-european-union-antitrust-charges-app-store-music-competition-commission-margrethe-vestager</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-30T04:09:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-30T04:09:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>Coinbase now lets you buy cryptocurrency with your PayPal account</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/doS28LXxd_NoRPDZ5n9Nmmw61zk=/87x0:614x351/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69210554/1_EDmBagfVu5kYfH95xOCLDA.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;PayPal is now available as a payment method for US Coinbase users.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Coinbase&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rdZnoW"&gt;Coinbase has added the option for users to buy cryptocurrency using their PayPal accounts in the US, the &lt;a href="https://blog.coinbase.com/a-new-way-to-buy-crypto-on-coinbase-using-paypal-e9162f735dcb"&gt;company has announced&lt;/a&gt;. It says the feature offers a “familiar and trusted” experience for users buying any of the &lt;a href="https://help.coinbase.com/en/coinbase/getting-started/getting-started-with-coinbase/supported-cryptocurrencies"&gt;numerous cryptocurrencies&lt;/a&gt; that the exchange currently supports, and using PayPal as an intermediary means you don’t have to give your bank account or debit card information directly to the cryptocurrency exchange. The feature will expand to other countries in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VRIDJt"&gt;To use the new option, Coinbase says you can add your PayPal account via the “Add a payment method” option, which links to the PayPal login screen. Purchases made via PayPal are capped at $25,000 a day, or 0.46 Bitcoin as of this writing. Debit cards and bank accounts linked to a PayPal account can be used to buy cryptocurrencies, but a &lt;a href="https://help.coinbase.com/en/coinbase/getting-started/add-a-payment-method/paypal-faq#:~:text=prepaid%20cards%2C%20business%20cards%2C%20and%20credit%20cards%20linked%20to%20your%20paypal%20account%20are%20not%20currently%20supported%20by%20coinbase."&gt;Coinbase FAQ notes&lt;/a&gt; the feature doesn’t support payment methods like prepaid cards or credit cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oL5Yg3SkxufAj78uQNT-3yxirjs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22480708/1_hD2y9sfhbtm6uey_UjcXaQ.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Coinbase&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A PayPal account can be added from the “Add a payment method” screen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JwCoex"&gt;The news is part of PayPal’s broader trend towards embracing cryptocurrency. In November last year, the company started letting US users buy, sell, and hold cryptocurrencies &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21562771/paypal-cryptocurrency-buy-sell-bitcoin-ethereum-litecoin-us-users"&gt;directly from their PayPal accounts&lt;/a&gt;, and this year it rolled out the option for users to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22357246/paypal-buy-with-bitcoin-litecoin-ethereum-crypto-checkout"&gt;pay with cryptocurrency held in their PayPal account&lt;/a&gt; (though this is converted to local currency before a merchant is paid). PayPal currently only supports four cryptocurrencies natively — Bitcoin, Ethereum, Litecoin, and Bitcoin Cash — compared to the dozens available on Coinbase.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22411545/coinbase-paypal-support-cryptocurrency-trading"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22411545/coinbase-paypal-support-cryptocurrency-trading</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-29T21:02:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-29T21:02:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple adds a way to speed up searches on the App Store by suggesting words</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/I84pK6Ff1OVJoG3QqhzZ_U6t_s4=/266x0:1129x575/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69208989/Image_21.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qFFjoR"&gt;Apple has added &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AppStore/status/1387865090007908357?s=20"&gt;a new App Store search suggestions feature&lt;/a&gt; in the US, Canada, Australia, and the UK, that might make it easier to find apps. Now, after typing in a search term, the App Store will attempt to predict what you’re looking for and offer suggested words that, when tapped, will further narrow down your search results and speed up your hunt for specific kinds of apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OlpL1h"&gt;Search suggestions actually appeared on some iPhones earlier in April as part of a test, &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/04/08/app-store-search-tags/"&gt;according to MacRumors&lt;/a&gt;, but now the feature should be rolling out to all iPhones in the supported regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vzex1Z"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;  Introducing search suggestions on the App Store!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Select (or deselect) multiple suggestions to refine your search so you can find even more amazing apps and games.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Search suggestions roll out today starting with the USA, Canada, the UK, and Australia. &lt;a href="https://t.co/viaZHlCZMb"&gt;pic.twitter.com/viaZHlCZMb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— App Store (@AppStore) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AppStore/status/1387865090007908357?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 29, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ahMf2E"&gt;Using search suggestions is pretty simple. Let’s say I’m looking for an app to help me make some pizza from scratch: I can type “pizza” in the App Store’s search field and see additional words pop up like “maker,” “game,” “call,” “calculator,” or “order.” Selecting one of those suggestions filters the results further, so choosing calculator will pull up apps for calculating the correct ratio ingredients for pizza dough (surprisingly there’s a lot of those). &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HCpMupZchS3unTOR5WbablRSkHA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22479656/Image_20.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hunting for “pizza calculators” using the new App Store search suggestions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="bTN0i6"&gt;Currently, not every search allows you to select multiple suggestions. I was able to refine Apple’s example of “food” with “delivery” and “Indian,” but my other sample searches only gave me one filter each. Not every search brings up a suggested filter, either. We’ve reached out to Apple for clarification on when suggestions appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p3J5PB"&gt;What does consistently show up in search are ads, which Apple originally &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/10/6/13184346/apple-app-store-ads"&gt;added to App Store search in 2016&lt;/a&gt;. It’s easy to see how my plan to make pizza from scratch could get derailed by a big Uber Eats or Papa John’s ad above my helpful dough calculator app. Ordering delivery is so much easier than doing math.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="45Z4KY"&gt;Those ads are likely to inflame Apple’s App Store critics further — they’ll no doubt argue that an indie developer trying to make it easier to figure out the ratios of water to flour in pizza shouldn’t have to compete with Uber’s ad budget, the same way &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1019859186224594944?s=20"&gt;they think competing apps shouldn’t be buying ads in front of one another’s products&lt;/a&gt; while Apple profits from the result. But every change to a search engine has winners and losers, and it’s not yet clear whether this one will make it easier or harder for small developers to get more exposure. They could wind up being helpful for everyone who uses the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NCWHHB"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22410708/apple-app-store-search-suggestions"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22410708/apple-app-store-search-suggestions</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
