<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-01-14T20:44:11-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-14T20:44:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T20:44:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>A Parler archive is being converted into an interactive map of the Capitol building attack</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/u_d3zYDe3sdttLN9gx1Rgma3_tE=/189x67:998x606/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68670796/Screen_Shot_2021_01_14_at_3.10.16_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Patr10tic&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6BO1zF"&gt;A developer going by the name of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/patr10tic"&gt;Patr10tic&lt;/a&gt; has created &lt;a href="https://thepatr10t.github.io/yall-Qaeda/"&gt;an interactive map&lt;/a&gt; using GPS metadata and videos from the app Parler to offer a glimpse of what was happening inside and around the Capitol building during &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/6/22217411/capitol-building-lockdown-protesters-trump-supporters"&gt;the violent protest&lt;/a&gt; on January 6th (&lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/pkdmm8/developer-makes-interactive-map-of-parler-videos-from-capitol-hill-riots"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WtCGTk"&gt;The project is an expansion on similar maps &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/parler-users-breached-deep-inside-u-s-capitol-building-1846042905?rev=1610480731991"&gt;like the one &lt;em&gt;Gizmodo &lt;/em&gt;created&lt;/a&gt; to illustrate just how many Parler users were part of the mob that occupied the Capitol building, based off an archive &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224689/parler-posts-gps-data-archived-independent-researchers-amazon-apple-google-capitol"&gt;created by a researcher known as @donk_enby&lt;/a&gt;. Patr10tic’s map (currently named “Y’all Qaeda”) uses the same archive and connects GPS coordinates with actual video, offering a map of red icons placed around the Capitol for each associated video post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o1Aidl"&gt; Viewing the videos has an unsettling quality, not just because of the intersection of conspiracy theories and white supremacist ideology on display, but also the perspective they offer on the Capitol itself. Most people haven’t seen the chambers of Congress and the halls of the Capitol outside of press photos or &lt;em&gt;C-SPAN&lt;/em&gt; live feeds. Seeing protesters milling about in Congressional offices feels strange, but it’s even stranger seeing them wander through the Capitol building, unbothered, with police looking on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EHEkKr"&gt;Whatever feelings watching the videos provoke, the map and other projects like it could prove vital to investigating just how the events of January 6th took place. Parler’s already been identified &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/content-series/fastthinking/fast-thinking-how-the-capitol-riot-was-coordinated-online/"&gt;as a site for planning last week’s protests&lt;/a&gt;, and this growing, mapped compilation of posts shows that it was one of the main ways it was documented as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fn7Q36"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231749/parler-interactive-map-video-gps-capitol-attack"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231749/parler-interactive-map-video-gps-capitol-attack</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-14T20:41:45-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T20:41:45-05:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung will gradually remove chargers and earbuds from future phones  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IdAoNgju0Ospakpat_qY_HC2yqU=/216x0:1271x703/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68670789/galaxy_s21_5g_highlights_box.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Samsung&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IOacv4"&gt;Samsung’s future phones &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22225930/samsung-galaxy-s21-no-charger-brick-headphones-price"&gt;will also&lt;/a&gt; not come with charging bricks, the company &lt;a href="http://www.samsungmobilepress.com/featurestories/answers-to-your-questions-about-the-galaxy-s21-series-from-samsung-mobile-executives"&gt;has revealed&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s leaving itself some wiggle room. In a Q&amp;amp;A about why &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/1/14/22231102/samsung-apple-kill-charging-brick-obituary-eulogy"&gt;it’s no longer including headphones and a charging brick in the box&lt;/a&gt;, Samsung says it believes &lt;em&gt;gradually&lt;/em&gt; removing the accessories from its phones could help make them more sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WvvecV"&gt;This answer implies that, while the next generations of its phones may not come with the included accessories, some may. Samsung has other lines that it brands as Galaxy, from its folding phones to its more budget options, and it’s left itself room to keep including a charger in some of them for a little while longer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gxANF4"&gt;Maybe Samsung wants to keep the charger around &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22220858/samsung-a02s-us-unlocked-verizon-att"&gt;in cheaper phones&lt;/a&gt; so people who aren’t tech enthusiasts will have a higher likelihood of buying them, or maybe it doesn’t want to upset the people who buy &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/1/21407750/samsungs-galaxy-z-fold-2-price-release-date-hinge-screen-durability"&gt;its $2,000 phones&lt;/a&gt;. It could do both, either, or neither, and it would still count as “gradually.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kbGsMY"&gt;The company doesn’t appear, however, to be following &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21514480/apple-iphone-charging-brick-charger-earbuds-box-environmental-impact-carbon-emissions"&gt;Apple’s route of pulling the plugs from its lineup of existing phones&lt;/a&gt;. The listings for the Note 20 Ultra and Note 10 still show a charger coming in the box. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A “what’s in the box” image of the Note 20 Ultra, including a charging brick." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tC2N5qlU-eL6ocGQJh-WYOFKv9Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22236779/Screen_Shot_2021_01_14_at_4.24.55_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Note 20 Ultra looks to still include a charger.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="8adKhW"&gt;While a company shipping older products with something that’s no longer included in its latest and greatest might seem odd, it means Samsung doesn’t have to re-make all the boxes for its old products, and that consumers won’t end up in the awkward situation where they watch an unboxing from a phone’s launch on YouTube and then have a decidedly different experience. Which approach is correct really depends what you’re optimizing for, but this seems to be the one Samsung has chosen: slow and steady wins the race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i5lUFA"&gt;You can read the full answer down below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="gWPCmn"&gt;We discovered that more and more Galaxy users are reusing accessories they already have and making sustainable choices in their daily lives to promote better recycling habits. To support our Galaxy community in this journey, we are transitioning to removal of the charger plug and earphones in our latest line of Galaxy smartphones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5mllep"&gt;We believe that the gradual removal of charger plugs and earphones from our in-box device packaging can help address sustainable consumption issues and remove any pressure that consumers may feel towards continually receiving unnecessary charger accessories with new phones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1V567T"&gt;We’ve also been implementing standardized USB-C type charging ports since 2017, so older chargers can still be compatible with our newest Galaxy models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231954/samsung-to-gradually-remove-chargers-earbuds-from-future-phones"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231954/samsung-to-gradually-remove-chargers-earbuds-from-future-phones</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-14T19:13:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T19:13:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>Spotify’s Car Thing shows up in FCC filings with a new design and bigger screen</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uez6rpgNlX61LAa1TslCBpw55tE=/2x0:1732x1153/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68670464/image.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A photo of Spotify’s Car Thing, taken from FCC filings.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: FCC filings&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ayzaT0"&gt;Back in May 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/5/17/18628772/spotify-car-thing-audio-experience-data-premium-assistant"&gt;Spotify announced&lt;/a&gt; that it would be publicly testing a voice-controlled smart assistant for cars that the company called “Car Thing.” But nearly two years on, we haven’t heard much from the project — though that might change soon. A Car Thing with a totally new design and a bigger screen has appeared &lt;a href="https://fccid.io/2AP3D-YX5H6679"&gt;in FCC filings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3TXMlN"&gt;This new version of the Car Thing seems like it will function similarly to the 2019 version — it’s a “voice controlled accessory for phone/Spotify App with supporting display and buttons,” according to a description found in the filings. “Bluetooth enabled for communication with the Car Head Unit. Powered from a 12V outlet,” continues the description, bluntly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9B5Qj9"&gt;The design, though, is radically different. The new Car Thing looks almost like a mini-tablet, with some kind of button and a large knob. It’s pictured at the top of this post. Compare it to this image from Spotify of the version it announced in 2019:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zus0O3A9yF07LbqHlRnu_5xVOus=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22236672/device_testdrive_1100x618.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Spotify&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spotify’s image of what the Car Thing looked like in 2019.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pEhMgJ"&gt;And if you want to get a better look at the newer version, we’ve collected some photos from the new FCC filings in this gallery, including a few of the device powered on. Disappointingly, though, it’s hard to tell anything about how the device actually works from the photos, or what the software looks like. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gwTNxP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10284862"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="g8z4AH"&gt;It’s also unclear if this is a product people will ever be able to get their hands on. A product hitting the FCC doesn’t necessarily mean that it will be released for the general public. And we never heard much about the 2019 version of the Car Thing following its initial announcement (though that one also had &lt;a href="https://www.stereonet.co.uk/news/spotifys-car-thing-to-deliver-in-car-music-streaming"&gt;a trip through the FCC&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lSwUbS"&gt;“Spotify is focused on becoming the world’s number one audio platform, and we’re continuing tests of a voice-controlled music and podcast device to help us learn more about how people listen to audio in the car,” the company said in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; after the original publication of this article. “While we don’t have any further news to share at this time, we’re always testing and seeking feedback from our users before rolling out new features or products broadly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="H2zVWq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Spotify begins testing its first hardware: a car smart assistant","url":"https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/5/17/18628772/spotify-car-thing-audio-experience-data-premium-assistant"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="WJisUl"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 14th, 8:17PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Added statement from Spotify.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231876/spotify-car-thing-fcc-design-screen-pictures-photos"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231876/spotify-car-thing-fcc-design-screen-pictures-photos</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-14T19:00:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T19:00:30-05:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung says S Pen support is coming to ‘additional device categories’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dC2DzBJIDf-ClQQwc6RWGK8-DCE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68670390/cgartenberg_210111_4369_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Fyaa1y"&gt;Samsung just revealed the new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22227772/samsung-galaxy-s21-plus-ultra-price-specs-release-date-unpacked"&gt;Galaxy S21 Ultra&lt;/a&gt; would be its first Galaxy S phone to support the S Pen stylus, but the company is already saying that S Pen support will come to other devices in the future, according to a statement first given &lt;a href="https://www.sammobile.com/news/samsung-confirmed-s-pen-more-galaxy-smartphones/"&gt;to &lt;em&gt;SamMobile&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mkUdII"&gt;“We are committed to innovating new mobile experiences that flow seamlessly and continuously to make our consumers’ lives easier and better,” Samsung president of mobile TM Roh says in the statement, which the company shared with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “We’ve made the bold decision to expand the S Pen experience to Galaxy S21 Ultra, and plan to expand the S Pen experience across additional device categories in the future.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1DlTXe"&gt;“Additional device categories” is vague on its own. But given that S Pen is already compatible with some of Samsung’s smartphones and its Tab tablets, the next logical device category that could use the S Pen, to me, would be Samsung’s foldables. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZGaw8F"&gt;&lt;q&gt;This isn’t Samsung’s first suggestion that S Pen support will come to other devices&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="V8jik2"&gt;This isn’t Samsung’s first suggestion that S Pen support will come to other devices. Back in December, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22175769/samsung-stylus-galaxy-phones-s21-foldable"&gt;Roh said that the company&lt;/a&gt; has been “paying attention to people’s favorite aspects of the Galaxy Note experience and are excited to add some of its most well-loved features to other devices in our lineup,” though didn’t specify further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BCsDOp"&gt;And Roh has even hinted toward the S Pen coming to foldables. In a Q&amp;amp;A during Samsung’s Galaxy Note 20 and Galaxy Z Fold 2 presentation from August, Roh left the door wide open to the idea that the S Pen would make its way to foldables in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ECXOIM"&gt;“The S Pen has always been a well-loved feature of the Galaxy Note. And we are happy to hear that people want it so much, they even want it on the Fold,” Roh said. (You can hear his statement in &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/CmS5rlX9cDA?t=5079"&gt;context here&lt;/a&gt;.) Later, after reiterating the features of the Galaxy Z Fold 2, he added, “and we will certainly to continue to listen to our customers’ feedback. So please stay tuned for what the future will hold.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231677/samsung-s-pen-foldable-support-additional-device-categories"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231677/samsung-s-pen-foldable-support-additional-device-categories</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-14T18:26:50-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T18:26:50-05:00</updated>
    <title>Trump administration blacklists Xiaomi as a ‘Communist Chinese military company’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="xiaomi mi8" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/n3VLx2p_6HRL9sxaoFrOWs1eaH8=/0x0:1820x1213/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68670216/mi83.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Xiaomi&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yZW5GY"&gt;With six days left in office, the Trump administration has decided to put one more Chinese electronics giant in its sights: Xiaomi, the world’s number three phone manufacturer. The US Department of Defense &lt;a href="https://www.defense.gov/Newsroom/Releases/Release/Article/2472464/dod-releases-list-of-additional-companies-in-accordance-with-section-1237-of-fy/"&gt;is now designating Xiaomi&lt;/a&gt; as a “Chinese Communist military company,” meaning it’s now vulnerable &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/executive-order-addressing-threat-securities-investments-finance-communist-chinese-military-companies/"&gt;to Trump’s executive order&lt;/a&gt; that bans the US from investing in such companies — and might force US companies and other US investors to divest in Xiaomi on November 11th, 2021, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-china-comac-military-exclusive/exclusive-trump-administration-adds-chinas-comac-xiaomi-to-chinese-military-blacklist-idUSKBN29J2HK?il=0"&gt;as reported by &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5gKs6f"&gt;While a Biden administration might overturn the order before then, it’s interesting to see an electronics company like Xiaomi on the list at all. Most of the other companies on &lt;a href="https://www.defense.gov/Newsroom/Releases/Release/Article/2472464/dod-releases-list-of-additional-companies-in-accordance-with-section-1237-of-fy/"&gt;the list&lt;/a&gt; are more industrially oriented, specializing in aviation, aerospace, shipbuilding, chemicals, telecommunications, construction, and other forms of infrastructure. Huawei, the world’s number two phonemaker, is also on the list, but Huawei builds large-scale telecommunications equipment too; US lawmakers have been specifically worried &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/4/21422939/huawei-zte-us-phone-networks-fcc-congress-reimbursement-cost"&gt;about Huawei being part of the nation’s cellular infrastructure (also see: ZTE)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TA0GJN"&gt;This list isn’t the same as the US Commerce Department’s “entity list,” by the way, which typically keeps US companies from exporting technology to companies that have been blacklisted, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22193660/us-government-dji-drone-entity-list-export-ban-effects"&gt;like dronemaker DJI&lt;/a&gt;. But some Chinese companies like Huawei (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/26/21457350/us-tightens-trade-restrictions-china-chipmaker-smic"&gt;and Chinese chipmaker SMIC&lt;/a&gt;) are on both lists now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EAXXo6"&gt;Speaking of the Commerce Department, &lt;a href="https://www.commerce.gov/news/press-releases/2021/01/commerce-department-issues-interim-rule-secure-icts-supply-chain"&gt;it’s moving ahead&lt;/a&gt; to try to block six entire countries, now designated as “foreign adversaries,” from providing communications equipment to the United States at all, including China, Russia, Iran, North Korea, Cuba, and the government of Venezuela’s Nicolás Maduro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iZ1yv6"&gt;Xiaomi didn’t immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231786/trump-administration-blacklists-xiaomi-communist-chinese-military-company"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231786/trump-administration-blacklists-xiaomi-communist-chinese-military-company</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-14T17:16:17-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T17:16:17-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to preorder the Samsung Galaxy S21, S21 Plus, and S21 Ultra</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P8A0dzHGIxoeM1CiU288TcgffH4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68667935/cgartenberg_210111_4368_0008.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yhHXHw"&gt;During Samsung’s Unpacked event, the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22227561/samsung-galaxy-s21-event-news-announcements-biggest-products-unpacked"&gt;unveiled three new phones&lt;/a&gt; as part of the Galaxy S21 lineup — the Galaxy S21, S21 Plus, and the S21 Ultra — which will be available to preorder starting January 14th and will release on January 29th. As a reminder, their prices range from $999.99 to upward of $$1,379.99.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FMchhq"&gt;We will be reviewing the S21 line soon, but if you are interested in preordering the phone, we’ve compiled a list of retailers that currently have product listings available. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T1DlkM"&gt;See below for how to preorder and any promotions currently available. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="EDtpRM"&gt;Where to buy the Samsung Galaxy S21&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="2e3Lhs"&gt;You can preorder the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1729414717821678319" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung Galaxy S21 directly through Samsung’s website&lt;/a&gt;, starting at $799.99. If you have a &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1729428936976019171" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;phone to trade-in&lt;/a&gt;, you can get up to $700 in credit towards your new Galaxy S21. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="UusUPD"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.att.com%2Fbuy%2Fphones%2Fsamsung-galaxy-s21-5g-128gb-phantom-violet.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/a&gt; has a promotion that includes up to $800 off the Samsung Galaxy S21 line; this includes the Galaxy S21, which would be free for new and existing customers. To receive this offer, customers will need to trade-in an eligible device and buy a 30-month installment plan. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="88w8nx"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fcell-phone%2Fsamsung-galaxy-s21-5g%3Fsku%3D610214667793#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;T-Mobile&lt;/a&gt; has a similar promotion to AT&amp;amp;T, where it is offering new and existing customers a free Samsung Galaxy S21 when you trade-in an eligible device. If you do not have a phone to trade-in, the carrier is offering the phone for $799.99. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7zVUiQ"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https://www.verizon.com/smartphones/samsung-galaxy-s21-plus-5g/&amp;amp;xcust=___vg__e_21989669__t_w__d_D#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Verizon&lt;/a&gt; has the Samsung Galaxy S21 Plus starting at $999.99 or $33.33 per month for 30 months or $41.66 per month for 24 months with 0% APR as part of a device payment plan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7bGEZY"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1729421894218140956" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; is offering the Samsung Galaxy S21 (Unlocked) starting at $769.99 or $33.34 per month for 24 months for Verizon and Sprint legacy customers. The retailer also has a promotion, allowing you to save up to $800 on the Galaxy S21 line with a qualified activation and trade-in, in addition to a $200 Samsung credit and a free Galaxy SmartTag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="30WvM2"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fsearch%3FNtt%3DSAMSUNG%2520GALAXY%2520S21%26N%3D0%26InitialSearch%3Dyes%26sts%3Dma#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt; has the Samsung Galaxy S21 (Unlocked) available for preorder now starting at $799.99. The retailer also has a promotion, allowing you to receive up to $200 in Samsung credit and a free Galaxy SmartTag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AWIFbn"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xfinity.com%2Fmobile%2Fshop%2Fphone%2Fgalaxy-s21-5g-samsung%3FcolorName%3DPhantom%2520Violet#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xfinity Mobile&lt;/a&gt; has the Samsung Galaxy S21 with 128GB of storage for $799.99 if you pay in full or starting at $16.67 per month for 24 months with 0% APR. Xfinity Mobile is currently running a promotion for new customers, allowing them to receive $400 off when they purchase a Samsung 5G device, this includes the Samsung Galaxy S21 line. Existing customers who upgrade their device will receive a $400 Visa prepaid card. Additionally, the phone carrier's customers can also take advantage of a limited time offer by Samsung, which provides a $100 Samsung credit that you can use towards the purchase of a Galaxy S21. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9fQUyC"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://fi.google.com/about/phones/samsung-galaxy-s21-5g"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; is offering its Fi customers a special promotion to save up to 50% off with Fi credit the purchase of a new Galaxy S21. Additionally, you pre-order the smartphone through the tech giant, you can also receive up to $200 in Samsung credit plus a free Galaxy SmartTag for a limited time. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="22vK0C"&gt;Where to buy the Samsung Galaxy S21 Plus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="AOTd7l"&gt;You can preorder the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1729414681879531534" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung Galaxy S21 Plus directly through Samsung’s website&lt;/a&gt;, starting at $999.99. If you have a &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1729428983835354785" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;phone to trade-in&lt;/a&gt;, you can get up to $700 in credit toward’s your new Galaxy S21 Plus when they trade-in an eligible device and select an Unlimited plan. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RLWqjj"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.att.com%2Fbuy%2Fphones%2Fsamsung-galaxy-s21-5g-128gb-phantom-violet.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/a&gt; has a promotion that includes up to $800 off the Samsung Galaxy S21 line; this includes the Galaxy S21 Plus, which would be $199.99 for new and existing customers. To receive this offer, customers will need to trade-in an eligible device and buy a 30-month installment plan. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ueL6Na"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fcell-phone%2Fsamsung-galaxy-s21-plus-5g%3Fsku%3D610214667823#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;T-Mobile&lt;/a&gt; has a similar promotion to AT&amp;amp;T, where it is offering new and existing customers up to $800 off the purchase of a Samsung Galaxy S21 Plus when you trade-in an eligible device. If you do not have a phone to trade-in, the carrier is offering the phone for $999.99. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jwPgoC"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.verizon.com%2Fsmartphones%2Fsamsung-galaxy-s21-plus-5g%2F#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Verizon&lt;/a&gt; has the Samsung Galaxy S21 Plus starting at $999.99 or $33.33 per month for 30 months or $41.66 per month for 24 months with 0% APR as part of a device payment plan. Customers that switch to Verizon can get a 128GB Samsung Galaxy S21 Plus when you trade-in an eligible device and with select Unlimited plans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="FOV0Bw"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1729422208318758096" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; is offering the Samsung Galaxy S21 Plus starting at $949.99 (Unlocked) or for $39.58 per month for 24 months for Verizon customers or $41.67 per month for 24 months for Sprint legacy customers. The retailer also has a promotion, allowing you to save up to $800 on the Galaxy S21 line with a qualified activation and trade-in, in addition to a $200 Samsung credit and a free Galaxy SmartTag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="aWcG2x"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fsearch%3FNtt%3DSAMSUNG%2520GALAXY%2520S21%2520Plus%26N%3D0%26InitialSearch%3Dyes%26sts%3Dma#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt; has the Samsung Galaxy S21 Plus (Unlocked) available for preorder now starting at $999.99. The retailer also has a promotion, allowing you to receive up to $200 in Samsung credit and a free Galaxy SmartTag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ftQLPu"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xfinity.com%2Fmobile%2Fshop%2Fphone%2Fgalaxy-s21ssplus-5g-samsung%3FcolorName%3DPhantom%2520Violet#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xfinity Mobile&lt;/a&gt; has the Samsung Galaxy S21 Plus with 128GB of storage available for $999.99 if you pay in full, or starting at $25 per month for 24 months with 0% APR. Xfinity Mobile is currently running a promotion for new customers, allowing them to receive $400 off when they purchase a Samsung 5G device, this includes the Samsung Galaxy S21 line. Existing customers who upgrade their device will receive a $400 Visa prepaid card. Additionally, the phone carrier's customers can also take advantage of a limited time offer by Samsung, which provides a $150 Samsung credit that you can use towards the purchase of a Galaxy S21 Plus. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uh3HQJ"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://fi.google.com/about/phones/samsung-galaxy-s21-plus-5g"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; is offering its Fi customers a special promotion to save up to 50% off with Fi credit the purchase of a new Galaxy S21 Plus. Additionally, you pre-order the smartphone through the tech giant, you can also receive up to $200 in Samsung credit plus a free Galaxy SmartTag for a limited time. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="0jlnsy"&gt;Where to buy the Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="GRtTEG"&gt;You can preorder the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1729414703290468147" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra directly through Samsung’s website&lt;/a&gt;, starting at $1,199.99. If you have a &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1729429016905004660" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;phone to trade-in&lt;/a&gt;, you can get up to $700 in credit toward’s your new Galaxy S21 Ultra. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hnfqfo"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.att.com%2Fbuy%2Fphones%2Fsamsung-galaxy-s21-5g-128gb-phantom-violet.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/a&gt; has a promotion that includes up to $800 off the Samsung Galaxy S21 line; this includes the Galaxy S21 Ultra, which would $399.99 for new and existing customers. To receive this offer, customers will need to trade-in an eligible device and buy a 30-month installment plan. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dOMqu2"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fcell-phone%2Fsamsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-5g%3Fsku%3D610214667786#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;T-Mobile&lt;/a&gt; has a similar promotion to AT&amp;amp;T, where it is offering new and existing customers up to $800 off the purchase of a Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra when you trade-in an eligible device. If you do not have a phone to trade-in, the carrier is offering the phone for $1,199.99. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="1RcybD"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.verizon.com%2Fsmartphones%2Fsamsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-5g%2F#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Verizon&lt;/a&gt; has the Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra starting at $1,199.99 or $39.99 per month for 30 months or $49.99 per month for 24 months with 0% APR as part of a device payment plan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jmUJvE"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1729422220897196518" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; is offering the Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra starting at $1,149.99 (Unlocked) or for $47.91 per month for 24 months for Verizon customers or $50 per month for 24 months for Sprint legacy customers. The retailer also has a promotion, allowing you to save up to $800 on the Galaxy S21 line with a qualified activation and trade-in, in addition to a $200 Samsung credit and a free Galaxy SmartTag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="luUm1u"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fsearch%3FNtt%3DSAMSUNG%2520GALAXY%2520S21%2520ULTRA%26N%3D0%26InitialSearch%3Dyes%26sts%3Dma#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt; has the Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra (Unlocked) available for preorder now starting at $999.99. The retailer also has a promotion, allowing you to receive up to $200 in Samsung credit and a free Galaxy SmartTag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EjVFvI"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xfinity.com%2Fmobile%2Fshop%2Fphone%2Fgalaxy-s21-ultra-5g-samsung%3FcolorName%3DPhantom%2520Black#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xfinity Mobile&lt;/a&gt; has the Samsung Galaxy S21 Ultra available starting at $1,119.99 if you pay in full or starting at $33.33 per month for 24 months with 0% APR. Xfinity Mobile is currently running a promotion for new customers, allowing them to receive $400 off when they purchase a Samsung 5G device, this includes the Samsung Galaxy S21 line. Existing customers who upgrade their device will receive a $400 Visa prepaid card. Additionally, the phone carrier's customers can also take advantage of a limited time offer by Samsung, which provides a $200 Samsung credit that you can use towards the purchase of a Galaxy S21 Ultra. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="KMH9Jl"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://fi.google.com/about/phones/samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-5g"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; is offering its Fi customers a special promotion to save up to 50% off with Fi credit the purchase of a new Galaxy S21 Ultra. Additionally, you pre-order the smartphone through the tech giant, you can also receive up to $200 in Samsung credit plus a free Galaxy SmartTag for a limited time. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22225628/samsung-galaxy-s21-plus-ultra-preorder-how-to-price-verizon-tmobile-sprint"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22225628/samsung-galaxy-s21-plus-ultra-preorder-how-to-price-verizon-tmobile-sprint</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-14T17:00:51-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T17:00:51-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Galaxy A32 5G debuts in Europe as Samsung’s cheapest 5G phone</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AOHF6diQ4OW-ysNMLO9C9TyzM2E=/0x84:2000x1417/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68669855/02_galaxya32_5g_2p_lg.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Galaxy A32 5G offers a 6.5-inch display and 5,000mAh battery.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Samsung&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kVfz2V"&gt;Echoing a theme that will be repeated a lot more this year, Samsung has announced a very inexpensive 5G phone. The Galaxy A32 5G is debuting in Europe first, starting at €279 for a 64GB version or €299 for 128GB. There’s no official word yet on whether it will come to the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ipULvU"&gt;The A32 5G offers a 6.5-inch 1600 x 900 display, a 5,000mAh battery, and a side-mounted fingerprint reader. Its rear camera array includes a 48-megapixel main camera, an 8-megapixel ultrawide, a 2-megapixel depth-sensing camera, and the obligatory 5-megapixel macro camera. Around front, it offers a 13-megapixel selfie camera. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e9Wn8B"&gt;Samsung doesn’t say what processor the phone is using, only that it’s a 2.0GHz octa-core chipset, but &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/01/14/the-galaxy-a32-launches-as-samsungs-cheapest-5g-phone-to-date"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt; suspects&lt;/a&gt; it’s a Dimensity 720. And &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22230868/samsung-galaxy-s21-storage-microsd-support-slot"&gt;unlike the flagship phones&lt;/a&gt; debuting today, the A32 5G will offer a microSD card slot for storage expansion. &lt;a href="https://news.samsung.com/de/samsung-galaxy-a32-5g-neuer-mittelklasse-star-ab-mitte-februar-verfugbar"&gt;Samsung Germany says&lt;/a&gt; the phone will be available starting on February 12th. Color options include (get ready for it) “awesome black,” “awesome white,” “awesome blue,” and “awesome violet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="oA3gbj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10284547"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Lmh8bS"&gt;2021 should see no shortage of affordable 5G phones. We’ve already reviewed the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22214280/oneplus-nord-n10-5g-review"&gt;OnePlus Nord N10 5G&lt;/a&gt;, which just came to the US for $299. The arrival of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/4/22204586/qualcomm-snapdragon-480-5g-android-smartphone-price"&gt;Qualcomm’s Snapdragon 480 5G chip&lt;/a&gt; also paves the way for even cheaper, sub-$200 devices. We’d still like to remind you that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/12/21511946/5g-iphone-12-upgrade-speed-network-mmwave-hype"&gt;5G alone isn’t a good reason&lt;/a&gt; to buy a new phone, but it’s getting more and more likely that &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; new phone you consider this year will offer 5G, regardless. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231420/samsung-galaxy-a32-5g-europe-cheapest-5g-phone"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231420/samsung-galaxy-a32-5g-europe-cheapest-5g-phone</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-14T16:49:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T16:49:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>BMW becomes the latest automaker to shut down its subscription service</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="BMW steering wheel stock" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3nELWOUEkTAKV-m8JRxYNYj1dJU=/1x0:1099x732/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68669771/bmwstock.1419971671.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ks53W6"&gt;BMW is suspending its two-year-old car subscription service, &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;has learned. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9Hv0Vo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/4/17199532/bmw-subscription-service-nashville"&gt;Access by BMW was launched in 2018&lt;/a&gt; in Nashville as a pilot project to test out whether customers would want to have access to a fleet of fancy cars but not necessarily own one. But recent requests to sign up have been met with a disclaimer that the service is in the process of shutting down. A Nashville resident who was interested in applying for the subscription service was told that it was going to be defunct by the end of January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RbekUO"&gt;“Unfortunately the Access by BMW subscription program is ending on January 31st and we are no longer taking new members,” a sales representative said in an email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="T3g9yw"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Unfortunately the Access by BMW subscription program is ending on January 31st”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zUt5H1"&gt;A BMW spokesperson confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;that BMW was winding down its pilot, though the company appears to be leaving the door open for future experiments. “The Access by BMW vehicle subscription program was launched in Nashville, TN in April of 2018 and was always intended to be a pilot program,” the spokesperson said. “As such, the pilot will conclude at the end of this month. We are in the process of developing the next iteration of Access by BMW and will share more information with you as it becomes available.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XsDZNq"&gt;The spokesperson declined to share sales numbers but acknowledged that “the program had reached its capacity limits.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dz8Wd1"&gt;Despite the imminent shutdown, the &lt;a href="https://www.accessbybmw.com/"&gt;Access by BMW&lt;/a&gt; website is still up and running, with a link on the automaker’s North American site redirecting to it. “A new way of driving BMW is coming,” the homepage promises.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oKBA3c"&gt;Access by BMW consisted of two tiers. For $2,000 a month, members could choose between models like the X5 SUV, 4 Series, and 5 Series sedans, including all plug-in hybrid versions. For the higher-tier $3,700-a-month fee, they could get M4, M5, or M6 convertibles as well as X5M and X6M SUVs. (BMW’s highest-end 7 Series was not available through the service). The fee included insurance, maintenance, and roadside assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CPMyuX"&gt;If that seems a bit pricey, you’re not wrong. The top-tier $3,700-a-month plan is almost three times the cost of leasing an M5 sedan in the Nashville area (though a lease requires a down payment of $5,724 and doesn’t include insurance and maintenance).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PkaLPE"&gt;Subscriptions have been a mixed bag for the auto industry. Ford walked away from its service last fall following low demand. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/2/18050020/cadillacs-car-subscription-service-shutting-down"&gt;Cadillac shut down its service Book in 2018&lt;/a&gt;, only to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/25/18197772/cadillac-book-2-subscription-service-dealers"&gt;resurrect it&lt;/a&gt; several months later with fewer options. Last summer, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/29/21306823/mercedes-benz-collection-subscription-service-cancel-sales"&gt;Mercedes-Benz pulled the plug&lt;/a&gt; its Collection subscription service, citing mediocre sales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R2i7XI"&gt;Other automakers have had some success. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/10/16455246/porsche-car-subscription-service-launch"&gt;Porsche&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/21/17888304/audi-subscription-service-monthly-fee-dallas"&gt;Audi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/30/16720830/volvo-suv-subscription-plan-600-la-auto-show-2017"&gt;Volvo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/19/21143852/nissan-switch-subscription-service-price-model-vehicle"&gt;Nissan&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/15/17464548/jaguar-land-rover-car-subscription-service-carpe-uk"&gt;Jaguar&lt;/a&gt; are still offering some variation of a subscription service. Even the big car rental companies, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/4/18652907/hertz-my-car-subscription-rental-terms-enterprise"&gt;Hertz&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/24/18514404/enterprise-car-subscription-service-rental"&gt;Enterprise&lt;/a&gt;, are getting in on the action. Most of these subscriptions are only available in specific cities and are still in the pilot phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DBPmbN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XPtKpN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231451/bmw-access-subscription-shut-down-nashville-cancel"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231451/bmw-access-subscription-shut-down-nashville-cancel</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-14T16:44:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T16:44:24-05:00</updated>
    <title>Intel updates its NUC lineup, including a follow-up to its Hades Canyon gaming mini-PC</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-OP-_BBVk9EPGVBF752nz1r9koc=/177x101:1322x864/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68669762/Screen_Shot_2021_01_14_at_12.02.05_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Intel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WiyJNU"&gt;Intel is updating its Next Unit of Computing (NUC) lineup of miniature computers with its 11th Gen processors, and it’s again including a gaming-focused model. The NUC 11 Enthusiast is a follow-up to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/14/17346234/intel-nuc-8-pc-gaming-amd-vega-review"&gt;the NUC 8 Hades Canyon from 2018&lt;/a&gt;, which managed to pack triple-A gaming performance (not to mention I/O that rivaled a full-size desktop) into a tiny enclosure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b1a9Xf"&gt;Included in the refresh are updates to the company’s more traditional small-cube NUC Performance Mini computers, which previously had 10th Gen processors. The upgrade brings Wi-Fi 6 and Intel Xe graphics to the i5 and i7 models. Intel has also added a NUC Pro line, some of which have vPro-enabled CPUs and all of which can drive 8K displays. There’s also a NUC 11 compute unit, which is just a board meant to be integrated into future computers. This &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/24/21234333/intel-nuc-9-extreme-mini-pc-ghost-canyon-gaming-review-price-specs-features"&gt;isn’t the first time Intel has had that idea&lt;/a&gt;, but we’ll get more into that in just a moment.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2tNrPQKpoliFytopIFkFhamCb18=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22236260/Screen_Shot_2021_01_14_at_12.58.48_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Intel&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The NUC 11 Pro computers come in many sizes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="nY16m9"&gt;NUCs, however, are notable because of their size, and while the Performance and Pro lines are indeed very small, they’re more minor updates to what we already had before. What’s more interesting is the gaming version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k9yLsiR8jSHfsrm4aFK6qNSB56E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22236040/Screen_Shot_2021_01_14_at_11.47.45_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Intel&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NkvVx1"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/products/docs/boards-kits/nuc/nuc-11-enthusiast-mini-pc-kit-brief.html"&gt;NUC 11 Enthusiast&lt;/a&gt;, codenamed “Phantom Canyon,” promises gaming performance with a 28W quad-core i7-1165G7 (the same found in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21546784/dell-xps-13-late-2020-review-design-specs-price-features"&gt;the 2020 Dell XPS 13&lt;/a&gt;) and an RTX 2060, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226546/nvidia-geforce-rtx-3060-specs-price-release-date"&gt;which was made outdated the day before Intel’s announcement of the computer&lt;/a&gt;. It also keeps the stacked I/O that made the last generation great, including two Thunderbolt 4 ports, 2.5Gb Ethernet, a whopping six USB 3.2 Type-A ports, and Wi-Fi 6. The lack of HDMI 2.1 (it only has 2.0b) can be somewhat forgiven due to the inclusion of a Mini DisplayPort 1.4 output. And again, all of this is fitting inside an enclosure that’s roughly the size of a hefty book.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1YFqgc9OFBMNBGcZH6RkHBtTQR4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22236257/Screen_Shot_2021_01_14_at_11.44.47_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Intel&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ports, beautiful ports. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Djl89X"&gt;Like the other NUC models, the Enthusiast also has Xe integrated graphics, which should be good for streamers or creative professionals that enjoy Intel’s Quick Sync video encoding technology. While it’s a shame about the almost-up-to-date graphics card, the computer should still provide a good amount of gaming performance in an absolutely diminutive package, and I’m glad to see Intel’s still working on mini gaming PCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Awgcuk"&gt;Intel has a long history of trying to make the NUC into a miniature gaming PC with full-sized performance. It even teamed up with AMD to put dedicated Vega graphics into the NUC 8, which was clearly hoping to appeal to gamers more than office workers, with a glowing skull logo emblazoned on the top. Then, at CES 2020, it showed off the NUC 9 Extreme, which aimed to be a gaming PC with an easy-to-upgrade compute unit. Except Intel, so far, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22225459/best-tech-ces-2020-where-are-they-now-what-happened-next"&gt;hasn’t released any updates for the compute units&lt;/a&gt;, so at the moment, it’s just an expensive and modular-for-no-reason gaming PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FvwCnW"&gt;Intel hasn’t released pricing and availability yet, &lt;a href="https://simplynuc.com/phantom-canyon/"&gt;but SimplyNUC.com has the Phantom Canyon starting at $1,349&lt;/a&gt;. That looks to be a better deal than the NUC 9 Extreme, which is $1,599 on the same site and also requires a separate mini graphics card. It also beats its more direct predecessor, the NUC 8 Hades Canyon, which is still $1,234 for nearly two-year-old hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bn4PZQ"&gt;Intel appears to be using the same strategy it’s used for the NUC computers in the past, where people can buy either a complete computer or a kit where they’ll be required to provide the RAM, storage drive, and OS. SimplyNUC’s $1,349 model has the drive and RAM, but you will have to pay extra for or bring your own copy of Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231244/intel-nuc-11-pc-announcement-includes-mini-gaming-computer"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22231244/intel-nuc-11-pc-announcement-includes-mini-gaming-computer</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-14T16:19:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T16:19:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>WandaVision can be weird because Marvel has already won</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lWrbDwsNbBbkVZEGOReRoU8DR_k=/260x0:3062x1868/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68669590/wcb1160_102_comp_v340_20201119_r709_c8d55508.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Marvel Studios&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gtLqPZ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; is the Marvel universe’s most comic book show yet, if not in content at least in concept. It’s a dense-looking storyline that will be released on an episodic basis, with characters and a setting that are virtually impenetrable to new viewers — so much so that Marvel Studios even went so far as to produce a clip show recapping the critical moments of the 23-odd films that precede it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lK2aoC"&gt;It may seem like &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; would be barreling toward the same issue that has hounded traditional comics for years — a high barrier to entry with complex storylines, character dynamics, and lore that span decades and serve to confuse and drive away new readers — but &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; arguably doesn’t have that same problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="g625zS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"As WandaVision arrives, Marvel Studios is about to enter a never-ending cycle ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22229076/wandavision-marvel-studios-disney-plus-streaming-loki-falcon-winter-solider-black-widow-theatrical"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="iyQbOq"&gt;Pick up a random issue of &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Iron Man&lt;/em&gt;, and you’ll likely be confused by the contents, unless you’ve found a particularly accessible entry ramp like a creative reboot (for example, Jonathan Hickman’s recent run of the X-Men books) or a self-contained crossover. Comic sales are doing just fine, but the industry itself is a drop in the bucket compared to the massive pop culture impact of the Marvel blockbusters. &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/comics/2019/7/26/8893276/best-selling-comic-book-of-all-time-x-men-1-marvel-dc"&gt;Even the bestselling books of all time&lt;/a&gt; can’t come close in popularity. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/muZoJW6xTftKTvHOPC7uDONNbec=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22236249/Screen_Shot_2021_01_14_at_3.55.25_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Marvel Studios&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="YFmGPG"&gt;The fact that &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; isn’t particularly accessible to new viewers isn’t a mark against it: it’s a spinoff of what’s arguably the single most popular film franchise ever made and a direct follow-up to &lt;em&gt;Avengers: Endgame&lt;/em&gt;, the biggest movie in history. Comic book movies and shows are no longer tiny underdogs trying to lure in new viewers who aren’t the traditional comic audience — they &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; popular culture now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EIpmT7"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t have to cater to a new audience; it’s free to get as weird as it wants for the unprecedentedly large audience it already has, an audience that Disney is hoping will sign up for monthly Disney Plus subscriptions to watch it. (The same goes for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/21591343/falcon-winter-soldier-premiere-date-disney-plus-sebastian-stan-anthony-mackie-august"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Falcon and the Winter Soldier&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22168459/loki-trailer-marvel-studios-disney-plus-tom-hiddleston-release-date"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loki&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Hawkeye&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Ms. Marvel&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167976/disney-investor-day-2020-biggest-announcements-plus-marvel-star-wars-pixar-animation"&gt;all of the other Marvel shows heading to the service&lt;/a&gt;.) After all, why sell customers a $15 movie ticket to a giant blockbuster only once when you can get them to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22229076/wandavision-marvel-studios-disney-plus-streaming-loki-falcon-winter-solider-black-widow-theatrical"&gt;subscribe to your streaming service for $8 per month forever&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uF44Wd"&gt;In fact, Disney Plus’ very existence incentivizes Disney to make &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; more obtuse to new viewers. After all, &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of the Marvel movies that you’d need to understand &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; are already on the streaming service. If someone opens up &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; on Friday and decides to shelve it while they work their way through the rest of the MCU on Disney Plus, then Disney wins just as much as it would have had they watched &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; itself. Even &lt;em&gt;Marvel Legends&lt;/em&gt; — the recap show — requires a Disney Plus subscription to view, and it ends each episode with a list of movies (also streaming on Disney Plus) people should watch to better understand &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Mandalorian" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hXqYl34ddUAuviiRRga7ntDuKrw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22162694/HUC2_FF_003556.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Lucasfilm Ltd.&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="zAm0WF"&gt;It’s a strategy that we’ve already seen Disney use to great effect with &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt;’s second season tied in heavily to past &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; shows like &lt;em&gt;The Clone Wars&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Rebels&lt;/em&gt;. For fans who were up to speed on the older shows, &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt; was delivering payoffs that were years in the making. For fans who weren’t, they suddenly had a great reason to keep those subscriptions going after the season finale to catch up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dZUSvZ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; is by all accounts one of the strangest Marvel entries yet. It’s not the show the studio was hoping to use to kick off its TV efforts. (That title goes to the delayed — and more mainstream — &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Falcon and the Winter Soldier&lt;/em&gt;, which will follow in March.) It doesn’t need to cater to new fans because of the sheer momentum of the Marvel machine, even though the first few episodes also demonstrate that it’s weird enough — and detached enough — from the main films that people can still come to it as its own thing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mgnql0"&gt;But Marvel’s entertainment juggernaut is so big and consistent that it doesn’t really matter which show kicks off Disney Plus. The company has already won over viewers. All &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; needs to do is give them a reason to subscribe.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22231578/wandavision-marvel-studios-disney-plus-streaming-characters-mcu-audience"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22231578/wandavision-marvel-studios-disney-plus-streaming-characters-mcu-audience</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
