<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-05-09T17:45:51-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-09T17:45:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-09T17:45:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>Simple bank shutdown goes awry leaving customers without account access</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="simple card" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/elZ_8JbG-WGt4DRTBaMIsyUw_0M=/1x0:640x426/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69260570/simple_card.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hWdhO3"&gt;The online bank Simple shut down on Saturday and was supposed to seamlessly transition customers’ accounts over to its parent company, BBVA. But instead, many users found themselves unable to access their bank account at all, as BBVA’s website returned an assortment of error messages, from “system error” to warnings that their account information was mismatched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9qdjsh"&gt;The transition has gone so poorly that &lt;a href="https://www.bbvausa.com/"&gt;BBVA’s US website&lt;/a&gt; now opens on a large red banner warning users of extended customer service wait times. Anyone who visits &lt;a href="https://www.bbvausa.com/go/simple.html"&gt;the Simple transition page&lt;/a&gt; will see a different red banner, apologizing for the issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="316iHI"&gt;“To Simple customers converting to BBVA: This has not been a good conversion experience for many of you,” part of the message reads. “We know this, and we sincerely apologize.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A banner on BBVA’s website reading in part, “To Simple customers converting to BBVA: This has not been a good conversion experience for many of you. We know this, and we sincerely apologize. BBVA teams are working around the clock to understand the situation and make it right. Lines have been overwhelmed at our customer service center, leading to the service center being down. Again, we apologize for this and we are working to get it back online as soon as possible.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5CTPvoZvs60gLG64HForm3tYo3Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22502565/bbva_simple_transition.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A banner on BBVA’s transition page for Simple customers.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KcRvX7"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sPwz8O"&gt;Simple opened to customers in 2012 and was supposed to offer a digital-first approach to banking. In fewer words, it was supposed to be “a bank that doesn’t suck,” to &lt;a href="https://www.al3x.net/blog/2010/05/17/something-new"&gt;quote&lt;/a&gt; one of its co-founders. The service had a website and app that broke down your spending and made it easy to categorize payments, send money, and set savings goals. It was purchased by BBVA in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hg6CzU"&gt;BBVA said in January that it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22219271/simple-bank-online-shutting-down-pnc-bbva"&gt;would be shutting down Simple&lt;/a&gt; later in 2021. The decision came from the company “reassessing its goals” as part of a planned sale to PNC Bank, which reached an agreement to acquire BBVA’s US operations in November 2020. The acquisition has not yet closed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="716HjN"&gt;Accounts were successfully transitioned from Simple to BBVA on Saturday, but technical issues prevented customers from logging in, a BBVA spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. That led to a cascading series of problems. “Due to the volume of customers attempting to enroll in mobile and online banking simultaneously, there were technical difficulties with the enrollment process, leading to high call volume in our call centers, which overwhelmed the system, and created longer than normal wait times,” the spokesperson said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1aCxzz"&gt;Debit cards, ATMs, checks, and scheduled transactions still functioned properly, according to the spokesperson. Though online and mobile account access remains unavailable for users encountering issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aBauVJ"&gt;“We know this conversion process was not smooth for our incoming Simple customers and we sincerely apologize to them,” the spokesperson said. “We are working to make it right, including extending hours in our call center and adding staff to handle the incoming calls.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pBGyBG"&gt;It seems that some people have been able to gain access to their accounts after waiting or working with BBVA’s customer service. Judging by reactions on Twitter from Simple’s very online user base, plenty of people still don’t have access though and have been unable to get help from BBVA’s customer service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6crEus"&gt;BBVA hasn’t provided a timeline for when it expects to restore account access for all Simple users. In its banner message, BBVA wrote that the company is “working to get it back online as soon as possible.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22427811/simple-bbva-transition-errors-bank-shutdown"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22427811/simple-bbva-transition-errors-bank-shutdown</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-09T13:35:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-09T13:35:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Elon Musk’s SpaceX is literally launching a Dogecoin-funded satellite to the Moon</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TLYlFbESwmLdGUJJLD3N1kS7uxw=/0x56:2000x1389/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69259963/50908787221_9cf383a2b4_o.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;SpaceX launches a Falcon 9 rocket in February 2021. | Photo: SpaceX&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="u2Fwxj"&gt;SpaceX is now accepting Dogecoin, and it’ll be paid exclusively in the cryptocurrency to launch an upcoming satellite named DOGE-1 to — yes — the Moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F9iQll"&gt;The DOGE-1 is a cubesat meant to acquire “lunar-spatial intelligence” using onboard cameras and sensors. It’s being &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/spacex-to-launch-doge-1-to-the-moon-301287016.html"&gt;sent and paid for&lt;/a&gt; by a company named Geometric Energy Corporation, and it’ll be flown up on a Falcon 9 rocket in the first quarter of 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SDtmTX"&gt;Dogecoin, a cryptocurrency that started out as a goofy meme and is now a somewhat more valuable goofy meme, has been on the rise lately, with enough trading around spikes in the currency to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419159/robinhood-dogecoin-outage-crypto-trading-crash"&gt;cause&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388447/robinhood-app-dogecoin-rally-failed-trades"&gt;crashes&lt;/a&gt; of the trading app Robinhood. Elon Musk is the coin’s highest profile supporter, tweeting Dogecoin memes, referring to himself as the “Dogefather,” and hyping it up (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22427006/dogecoin-crashing-elon-musk-snl-host"&gt;sort of&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;em&gt;Saturday Night Live&lt;/em&gt;. Investors like to talk about sending Dogecoin’s value “to the Moon,” thus, we’re getting this silly stunt about sending a satellite named DOGE-1 paid to Musk’s company in Dogecoin to the Moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zbffjs"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;SpaceX is going to put a literal Dogecoin on the literal moon&lt;/p&gt;— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1377567762919292938?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 1, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zw0kRt"&gt;Given all that, SpaceX includes in the announcement the exact quote one might assume Musk mandated the company include: “We’re excited to launch DOGE-1 to the Moon!” said SpaceX vice president of commercial sales Tom Ochinero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p3tFuR"&gt;It’s a spot of good news for Dogecoin, which has had a tough week. After spiking in price, falling around a Robinhood crash, and spiking again in anticipation of Musk’s &lt;em&gt;SNL &lt;/em&gt;appearance, the cryptocurrency &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22427006/dogecoin-crashing-elon-musk-snl-host"&gt;crashed overnight&lt;/a&gt; following a segment in which Musk joked about Dogecoin being a “hustle.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jMqP1O"&gt;The announcement seems to be designed to fight back against that narrative. Ochinero says the partnership sets “the foundation for interplanetary commerce.” And Geometric Energy Corporation’s CEO says the transaction “solidified DOGE as a unit of account for lunar business in the space sector.” The press release goes on to say that Dogecoin is “sophisticated enough to finance a commercial Moon mission in full” and that it’ll be used for all lunar business between the two companies. (Musk’s other company, Tesla, recently started accepting car purchases &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/24/22347905/tesla-bitcoin-payment-us-cryptocurrency-elon-musk"&gt;in Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1fDLNQ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;has reached out to SpaceX and Geometric Energy Corporation for more information on the planned launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kn6tg1"&gt;So assuming all goes according to plan, Dogecoin will help send DOGE-1 to the Moon next year. Will that also send Dogecoin to the Moon? It probably depends on how much the parties involved continue to hype it. As Musk’s &lt;em&gt;SNL &lt;/em&gt;character admits, “Yeah, it’s a hustle.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="14Rjk1"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/x5RCfQyTDFI?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22427588/spacex-dogecoin-satellite-doge-1-to-the-moon"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22427588/spacex-dogecoin-satellite-doge-1-to-the-moon</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-09T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-09T13:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Call of Duty League’s champions are being honored at Verdansk Stadium in Warzone</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/S1e0ndGEjTFTdOQS4tY2K0Yg41E=/103x0:1074x647/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69259847/0.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PEFPVh"&gt;The champions of the first season of the &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt; League are being honored in a unique way: with their faces plastered at the stadium in &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Warzone&lt;/em&gt;. Today, Activision revealed that the front entrance to Verdansk Stadium in &lt;em&gt;Warzone&lt;/em&gt; will soon display a giant rendition of the CDL trophy, along with pennants featuring all five members of the Dallas Empire who were crowned champions for the 2020 season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="QkmXow"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Call of Duty League will look very different in its second season","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22276595/call-of-duty-league-cdl-2021-season-preview-johanna-faries-interview"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="o5eQTQ"&gt;It’s a unique kind of crossover and an example of how game developers and publishers are able to leverage popular games to promote esports. In the past, games like &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; have introduced unique skins to celebrate championship teams or players. But this move by the CDL is more akin to traditional sports, where championship banners are raised in local stadiums. It also makes a lot of sense for Activision to leverage &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt;’s incredibly popular battle royale spinoff: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22396481/call-of-duty-warzone-100-million-players-apex-legends"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warzone&lt;/em&gt; currently boasts more than 100 million players&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CODa78"&gt;This isn’t the first time the CDL has come up with a surprising way to celebrate its best team. In addition to a trophy and ring, the Dallas Empire also received &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/27/21401584/call-of-duty-league-cdl-championship-throne"&gt;a ridiculous championship throne&lt;/a&gt;. The changes in Verdansk will be featured in-game starting on May 10th.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yxWJX4mYAbk-1sDyQU4sbWX3cfg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22498717/CDL_Warzone_2.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22424868/call-of-duty-league-cdl-warzone-verdansk-statue-champions"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22424868/call-of-duty-league-cdl-warzone-verdansk-statue-champions</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-09T12:15:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-09T12:15:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Clubhouse comes to Android after more than a year of iOS exclusivity</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d6QSI7-YKiAP8XzQWSnz1_sbY0g=/548x0:3548x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69259742/clubhouse_graphic.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Clubhouse&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vlxOzQ"&gt;After more than a year of iOS exclusivity, social audio platform Clubhouse is releasing its Android app. It will be available in beta on Google’s mobile OS today in the US, allowing users to sign up and participate in its audio-only chat rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P8nZgT"&gt;“Our plan over the next few weeks is to collect feedback from the community, fix any issues we see and work to add a few final features like payments and club creation before rolling it out more broadly,” the company said in a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F572IM"&gt;The Android app, which the company says has been the top request from its community by far, will roll out to other English-speaking markets and the rest of the world in the days and weeks ahead, the company said. Users outside the US will be able to pre-register for access via the Clubhouse page in the Google Play store, to be notified when the Android app is available in their area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X6mBuO"&gt;However, Clubhouse says the platform will remain invite-only for now, meaning it’s still not open to just anyone, “as part of the effort to keep the growth measured,” the company said in a statement. Over the summer, the company plans to begin migrating what it says are millions of iOS users who have been waitlisted while the company built the app’s infrastructure. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IZ9BEaAvPNlDZAN7E0M4eZ48awk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22501952/welcome_android_social_image.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Clubhouse&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Lpc4Ow"&gt;Despite limited access Clubhouse has generated significant buzz, thanks in part to its early popularity with the venture-capital crowd dotted around Silicon Valley. The company was recently &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theinformation.com%2Farticles%2Fandreessen-horowitz-values-clubhouse-at-4-billionwith-dst-tiger%3Firclickid%3D30y0-83Z5xyLRMDwUx0Mo3EtUkBxIu02cSPvSM0%26irgwc%3D1%26utm_source%3Daffiliate%26utm_medium%3Dcpa%26utm_campaign%3D10078-Skimbit%2BLtd.%26utm_term%3Dtheverge.com&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F5%2F9%2F22424399%2Fclubhouse-android-app-release-date-news-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;valued at $4 billion&lt;/a&gt; after a new funding round. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vyZ8YH"&gt;However, this early excitement has meant multiple big tech firms are interested in launching similar audio features of their own. Twitter has already rolled out its own &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22413033/twitter-spaces-android-ios-ticket-schedule-clubhouse-captions"&gt;Spaces feature&lt;/a&gt;, Discord has added &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/31/22356682/discord-stage-channels-clubhouse-like-feature-voice"&gt;Stage Channels&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22391551/facebook-audio-podcasts-clubhouse-competitor-spotify-live-rooms"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22356993/spotify-locker-room-clubhouse-launch-acquisition"&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/03/26/slack-wants-to-be-more-than-a-text-based-messaging-platform/"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22359332/linkedin-clubhouse-clone-social-audio-networking-room"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/19/reddit-unveils-its-clubhouse-clone-reddit-talk/"&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt; are all at varying stages of adding similar audio-only features to their services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UWIewF"&gt;The company acknowledged in its post announcing the Android app that the platform had grown faster than expected. “This had its downsides, as the load stressed our systems—causing widespread server outages and notification failures, and surpassing the limits of our early discovery algorithms,” the post stated. “It made us shift our focus to hiring, fixing, and company building, rather than the community meetups and product features that we normally like to focus on.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="myXiXw"&gt;With more than a year under its belt, Clubhouse has turned its attention to attracting creators to its platform, and recently announced the results of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22420644/clubhouse-creator-first-pilot-program-season-audio-social"&gt;an accelerator program&lt;/a&gt; which will see it fund 50 audio shows on the platform. Now, with its release on Android, Clubhouse is finally letting US users with an invite on the biggest smartphone OS in the world get involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WXDQAo"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="105Kgg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22424399/clubhouse-android-app-release-date-news-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22424399/clubhouse-android-app-release-date-news-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-09T10:10:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-09T10:10:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Watch Elon Musk play Wario, parody SpaceX, and hype dogecoin on Saturday Night Live</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZXzucObhMhm9Vx273t46puseMoI=/158x0:2108x1300/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69259405/elon_wario.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Elon Musk dressed as Wario. | Image: SNL&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CPuENB"&gt;As you’ve surely heard, last night’s guest host on &lt;em&gt;Saturday Night &lt;/em&gt;Live was not a charismatic movie actor promoting a new project but instead an endlessly hyped CEO named Elon Musk. Over the course of an hour and a half, &lt;em&gt;SNL &lt;/em&gt;had Musk dress up as a misunderstood Wario, mock some of his more questionable ideas during a cowboy sketch, and play a version of himself set some years into a future where SpaceX has made it to Mars. Musk’s partner, Grimes, also made a cameo appearance as Princess Peach. I’ll let you guess which sketch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AasKs5"&gt;While the show was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/8/22426596/saturday-night-live-elon-musk-live-stream-international-nbc-miley-cyrus"&gt;streamed internationally on YouTube&lt;/a&gt; last night, those of us in the United States who don’t pay for cable were stuck waiting for clips to appear the following morning. As of press time, it is now the following morning. And as expected, the clips have appeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X3WLI6"&gt;Here’s a roundup of Musk’s appearances ranked from best to “I haven’t watched them yet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="RtM5Sj"&gt;Elon plays Wario (ft. Grimes)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id="g1U54W"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jrTXBFcvoMQ?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id="10TUY2"&gt;Elon plays Elon (ft. SpaceX, sort of)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id="jGe5YN"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FuaDWyCnJxs?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id="m6ADBH"&gt;Elon plays a cowboy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id="mMbhlI"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mOctrS7j8dg?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id="pGtd3z"&gt;Elon plays a dogecoin hypebeast (not himself)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id="MGwiMr"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/x5RCfQyTDFI?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id="pfdLrm"&gt;Elon plays an awkward guy at a party&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id="2C4sf6"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lesTkxvcSFw?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id="OymiSH"&gt;Elon plays a creepy priest&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id="UTE8ia"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qaKZi6p6sxg?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id="c7PiAT"&gt;Elon delivers a monologue&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id="sGKUyM"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fCF8I_X1qKI?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id="dP3IeL"&gt;Elon plays a doctor&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id="Rn2MdC"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JF2Mf6HxIi0?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id="I8KXd3"&gt;Elon plays an Icelandic TV producer&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id="hCDjZ3"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/f7oOmwc1c8o?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22427429/elon-musk-snl-clips-wario-dogecoin-monologue-saturday-night-live"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22427429/elon-musk-snl-clips-wario-dogecoin-monologue-saturday-night-live</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-09T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-09T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>New trailers:  A Quiet Place 2, Stranger Things 4, Loki, and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BgzSpByt-h7rH_HOHvNuqbSHtBE=/176x0:1694x1012/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69259343/a_quiet_place_part_ii_trailer.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image; Paramount&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="efdeQT"&gt;I’m sticking with &lt;em&gt;The Handmaid’s Tale&lt;/em&gt; for now; in the latest episode we see a lot of very improbable situations that need to happen in order to move the plot along but at last, finally, the main story moves away from Gilead. Does that mean things are going well for June? I don’t think it’s a major spoiler to say “nope, not really.” But we get to see some backstory for Janine, who asks June some uncomfortable questions in the present. More of that, please. The back half of the season looks promising. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9f8Rxw"&gt;Our trailers this week have a theme of sorts: Sequels. Trailers for the sequels to &lt;em&gt;A Quiet Place&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/em&gt;, and third trailers for &lt;em&gt;Loki&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;In the Heights. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="83Ofdg"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BpdDN9d9Jio?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="GxqIdt"&gt;A Quiet Place Part 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="NxKlX9"&gt;As my colleague Alex Cranz noted, this movie &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22422708/quiet-place-part-2-trailer-theater"&gt;had its theatrical premiere&lt;/a&gt; last March but was abruptly pulled from wide release shortly after because of the pandemic. So Paramount is going to try again, because they really want to give it a run in theaters, apparently. The latest trailer shows some flashbacks  (hi John Krasinski!) to the attack by the sound-sensitive aliens that wiped out most of civilization, but most of what we see is the time period immediately after the first movie’s ending. Emily Blunt and Millicent Simmonds reprise their roles from the first movie, trying to be quiet and connect with other human survivors. &lt;em&gt;A Quiet Place Part 2&lt;/em&gt; also stars Cillian Murphy, Noah Jupe, and Djimon Hounsou, and was directed by Krasinski. It hits theaters March 28th, and will be on the Paramount Plus streaming channel 45 days later. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ib3I1I"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ILwLN6hV-X8?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=1&amp;amp;start=1" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="VsZwf6"&gt;Stranger Things 4&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="W9Xe3w"&gt;This is an unsettling preview of what Eleven’s life was like before she escaped from the facility where she had experiments performed on her— OK look. I liked the first season of this show because I am a child of the 1980s and a fan of Winona forever, and, because Millie Bobby Brown gave a spectacular performance as the abused Eleven. But I don’t know if I can sit through another season where she endures misery after misery (although, I am currently midway through the latest season of &lt;em&gt;The Handmaid’s Tale &lt;/em&gt;so...). Please bring back Hopper for reals, show? No release date yet for Season 4, but as my colleague Andrew Webster pointed out the other day, if they don’t get on with it, the lovable kids from Hawkins, Indiana are going to be in their mid-20s before this drops. Let’s go, Netflix!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nHB0Lv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="A0awXG"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EVvK10eFmo8?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Y2JULZ"&gt;Loki Trailer 3: “Doing Great”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="9hO3b3"&gt;The god of mischief (played by Tom Hiddleston) &lt;em&gt;jumps out of a plane&lt;/em&gt; in this latest trailer for &lt;em&gt;Loki&lt;/em&gt;. We don’t get a whole lot of new details about what’s coming from Marvel’s latest TV series in trailer No. 3 but can this show hurry up and drop already please? &lt;em&gt;Loki&lt;/em&gt; premieres on Disney Plus June 9th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WXN9RL"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="P3p234"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yCgdWHwEnrg?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="2JfAqN"&gt;Halston&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="sjDaIW"&gt;Ewan McGregor stars as larger-than-life fashion designer Halston who built a fashion empire amid all the excesses of the 1970s and 1980s.  The miniseries also stars Bill Pullman, Vera Farmiga, Rory Culkin, and Krysta Rodriguez (as Liza Minnelli!). Halston debuts on Netflix Mary 14th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lNoiib"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/etqN4QSXUyQ?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="jLSOG0"&gt;In the Heights: 96,000 &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="lyXovI"&gt;The latest trailer for the movie version of  Lin-Manuel Miranda’s Broadway play &lt;em&gt;In the Heights &lt;/em&gt;focuses on a major plot point: Someone bought a lottery ticket worth $96,000 from the bodega where main character Usnavi (played by Anthony Ramos) works.&lt;em&gt; In the Heights &lt;/em&gt;comes to theaters and HBO Max on June 11th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xoTPZG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22426500/new-trailers-stranger-things-loki-quiet-place-netflix-disney-marvel-hbo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22426500/new-trailers-stranger-things-loki-quiet-place-netflix-disney-marvel-hbo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-09T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-09T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple Shortcuts is great, but it needs a notification toggle</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DsBqG0T7o0mFVbpBHW1uyjVKZ4o=/80x0:2480x1600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69259235/shortcuts.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vTZsNM"&gt;Apple’s Shortcuts app is a fantastic piece of iOS, a nearly limitless corner of the operating system that lets users automate almost anything they can think of, limited only by imagination and ability to use Apple’s coding system (Federico Viticci’s comprehensive collection &lt;a href="https://www.macstories.net/shortcuts/"&gt;on &lt;em&gt;MacStories&lt;/em&gt; is a great place to start&lt;/a&gt;.) But Shortcuts has an issue so awful it renders it one of the most annoying parts of my phone, instead of one of the most useful: Apple insists on always showing notifications when I do something, and it’s virtually impossible to turn it off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rp7Ah2"&gt;Yes, I am aware that there is an extremely janky hack for disabling notifications on Shortcuts on a global level. The trick, &lt;a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/722717/how-to-disable-notifications-for-the-shortcuts-app-on-iphone/"&gt;as detailed by &lt;em&gt;HowToGeek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, involves going to the Screen Time part of settings and toggling back and forth between weeks to trick the software into giving you access to the standard notifications menu for the Shortcuts app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d2fZIr"&gt;There are a few issues with this, including the fact that it’s annoying to do, requires mucking around with what is almost certainly a glitch, and it’s extremely difficult to reenable notifications if you do disable them (since you’ll have to flip back to the last week you had notifications enabled in Screen Time to glitch back into the same menu). It’s also a global setting: you’re either all in on Shortcuts banners or completely disabling them. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KONg7e3oMSfXUaALOweoq92I0YM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22499393/Untitled.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7SqjDg"&gt;Apple, I assume, mandates notifications because Shortcuts &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; extremely powerful tools for automating things on your iPhone, and it’s easy to imagine unscrupulous use of them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0hjOtK"&gt;But the thing is, the power of Shortcuts is to &lt;em&gt;automate&lt;/em&gt; things in the background that I don’t want to have to deal with, whether that’s automatically disabling rotation lock when I open or close an app, open an app with a custom icon, or &lt;a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90632845/this-clever-iphone-wallpaper-ensures-your-battery-will-never-die-again"&gt;change the wallpaper when the battery life is low&lt;/a&gt;. A big glaring notification every time I do something detracts from that idea. I want my phone to be quietly helpful, not shouting in my face every time it does what I asked it to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="oAKrMW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to customize your iPhone’s home screen with widgets and app icons","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21448712/customize-iphone-home-screen-app-icons-widget-ios14"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="GtZ3BL"&gt;My new favorite use of Shortcuts is the recently added ability in iOS 14.5 to automatically turn on and off rotation lock &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; when I’m in video playing apps like Apple TV Plus or YouTube. The Shortcut works amazingly, but it's marred by the fact that every time I open or close YouTube (or the other apps I have it configured in), I lose the top chunk of my screen to a notification alerting me that, yes, the phone is doing the exact thing I programmed it to do. (It’s a &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt; notification, too, often taking a few seconds before it goes away.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="38QmjA"&gt;All I’m asking for is some middle ground. Apple doesn’t need to fully nuke notifications for Shortcuts. But the company could easily allow for specific automations to have the option to run silently in the background on a case-by-case basis — giving users the best of both worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o0GOba"&gt;The ball’s in your court, Apple. And WWDC (with the presumed reveal of iOS 15) is just a few weeks away. Fingers crossed. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22424463/apple-shortcuts-notifications-toggle-user-settings"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22424463/apple-shortcuts-notifications-toggle-user-settings</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-09T00:52:07-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-09T00:52:07-04:00</updated>
    <title>Dogecoin is crashing while Elon Musk is on Saturday Night Live </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GVyZc7eYy_P-w651XdTNgorkjZc=/151x0:1558x938/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69258720/Screen_Shot_2021_05_08_at_9.24.43_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="V8EjB4"&gt;While Elon Musk hosted &lt;em&gt;Saturday Night Live&lt;/em&gt;, Dogecoin investors sold. When &lt;em&gt;SNL &lt;/em&gt;first went live, the cryptocurrency hovered around 69 cents (nice). But as the show wore on, the price dropped. As of this writing, it is &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.coinbase.com%2Fprice%2Fdogecoin%3Futm_source%3Dgoogle_search_nb%26utm_medium%3Dcpc%26utm_campaign%3D10039201167%26utm_content%3D99760198023%26utm_term%3D%252Bdoge%2520%252Bcoin%26utm_creative%3D435822229415%26cb_device%3Dc%26cb_placement%3D%26cb_country%3Dus%26cb_city%3Dopen%26cb_language%3Den_us%26gclid%3DCjwKCAjw7diEBhB-EiwAskVi1-lc6zXKCfdEJfP1Ol5MYfCcq6SQdmQ0eCg0lqnfcts1XQdDsZasxhoCHI4QAvD_BwE&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F5%2F9%2F22427006%2Fdogecoin-crashing-elon-musk-snl-host" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;worth 56 cents&lt;/a&gt;, an 18 percent plunge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="h3DKSb"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Me watching SNL crack cringe jokes while my portfolio plummets &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DogeSNL?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#DogeSNL&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/OBiA1d3Pe1"&gt;pic.twitter.com/OBiA1d3Pe1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;—         (@N3KO1030) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/N3KO1030/status/1391243750089924615?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Y11pWj"&gt;There was a slight recovery when Musk — on “Weekend Update,” &lt;em&gt;SNL&lt;/em&gt;’s parody news program — explained to a bewildered Michael Che and Colin Jost what Dogecoin was. (“A hustle,” Che finally said, knowingly.) He also called himself the “Dogefather.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tweet-text"&gt;As if to celebrate, trading platform Robinhood promptly crashed for cryptocurrency users. Earlier this week, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RobinhoodApp/status/1391117310862118916"&gt;Robinhood tweeted&lt;/a&gt;, “We’re all paws on deck, all weekend. [rocket emoji]” (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22373990/robinhood-ipo-form-regulators-finance"&gt;I &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; the S-1&lt;/a&gt;.) A month ago, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388447/robinhood-app-dogecoin-rally-failed-trades"&gt;the trading platform crashed&lt;/a&gt; during a Dogecoin rally. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bVU8WV"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Update: We’re currently experiencing issues with crypto trading. We're working to resolve this as soon as possible. For the latest updates, check &lt;a href="https://t.co/ZS733G6N1J"&gt;https://t.co/ZS733G6N1J&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Robinhood Help (@AskRobinhood) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AskRobinhood/status/1391247108078915588?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fBt7hy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article initially flubbed the percentage change math — saying what was really was an 18 percent dive was just a 12 percent drop. We apologize for the late-night math error.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22427006/dogecoin-crashing-elon-musk-snl-host"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22427006/dogecoin-crashing-elon-musk-snl-host</id>
    <author>
      <name>Elizabeth Lopatto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-09T00:32:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-09T00:32:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>Elon Musk’s SNL monologue poked fun at his public persona</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VB4_jXkn-O-E__8jFesTkXrfk8g=/127x0:1534x938/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69258685/Screen_Shot_2021_05_08_at_8.59.18_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Elon Musk on Saturday Night Live | NBC&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9eLZTc"&gt;Elon Musk opened his hosting gig on &lt;em&gt;Saturday Night Live&lt;/em&gt; by acknowledging his public comments get him in trouble. “Sometimes after I say something I have to say ‘I mean that,’” he said. He pointed to his “69 days after 4/20 again haha” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1277359833721655302?lang=en"&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt;, but didn’t mention the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/27/17911428/sec-lawsuit-elon-musk-tesla-funding-tweet"&gt;2018 tweet&lt;/a&gt; that got him in hot water with the Securities and Exchange Commission. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8UTdrz"&gt;Musk said he was the first person with Asperger’s to host &lt;em&gt;SNL&lt;/em&gt; — something he hasn’t said publicly before. It did not appear he was joking, but it was a bit difficult to be sure how sincere Musk was being, given his history as both an internet troll and someone who doesn’t always know how to deliver a joke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vXY4lC"&gt;The Tesla and SpaceX CEO joked that people sometimes don’t know what to expect from him. “I reinvented electric cars and I’m sending people to Mars on a rocket ship,” Musk said. “Did you think I was going to be a chill, normal dude?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="NInDpU"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fCF8I_X1qKI?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YYP9Mx"&gt;Musk said his famous appearance on Joe Rogan’s podcast where he smoked weed wasn’t his usual habit. And he appeared to relish the live audience: “I could say something truly shocking like ‘I drive a Prius.’” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZpnzQB"&gt;He also said the name of his youngest child, spelled X Æ A-12 is “pronounced ‘cat running across keyboard.’” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hnMkmH"&gt;Musk’s mother Maye also made an appearance during the monologue. “I’m excited for my Mother’s Day gift, I just hope it’s not Dogecoin,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wc4PYn"&gt;To which Elon replied “it is.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22426973/elon-musk-snl-monologue-saturday-night-live"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22426973/elon-musk-snl-monologue-saturday-night-live</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-09T00:22:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-09T00:22:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>Every other EV brand showed up to Elon Musk’s SNL</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W56DOwvwpRzccVnxOh5B23UOv3I=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69258657/E0zpPE0XoAECxyP.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="sfPNsz"&gt;At least five of Tesla’s competitors bought ad time during &lt;em&gt;Saturday Night Live&lt;/em&gt; hosted by Elon Musk, using the billionaire’s appearance to sell their own. non-Tesla EVs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zmgu7I"&gt;Commercials for the Audi E-tron, Ford Mustang Mach-E, Volkswagen ID 4, and Lucid Air all aired within the first 30 minutes of &lt;em&gt;SNL&lt;/em&gt;. Lucid Motors, a company founded by Peter Rawlinson, the former head engineer of the Tesla Model S who &lt;a href="https://insideevs.com/news/505126/elon-musk-tweet-rawlinson-not-chief-engineer/"&gt;frequently clashes with Musk&lt;/a&gt;, teased its commercial earlier in the week. It was its debut commercial for the Lucid Air, a claimed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/11/21358613/lucid-motor-air-electric-vehicle-ev-range-517-miles"&gt;500-mile EV&lt;/a&gt; due later this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PDfG6j"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Guess who is making an appearance during &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SNL?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#SNL&lt;/a&gt; tomorrow? &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/LucidAir?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#LucidAir&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Firstto500?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Firstto500&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/aXquKSEND6"&gt;pic.twitter.com/aXquKSEND6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Lucid Motors (@LucidMotors) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LucidMotors/status/1390742832751779847?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8kgEr8"&gt;In his opening monologue, Musk noted he’s the guy who made electric vehicles popular. The commercials were intended to remind the audience that Tesla isn’t the only name in the game anymore. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H1qYLP"&gt;It wasn’t just EV companies either. &lt;a href="https://www.adweek.com/programmatic/how-sierra-space-a-rival-of-elon-musks-spacex-built-an-ad-strategy-around-his-snl-debut/"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Adweek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Sierra Space, a rival of Musk’s SpaceX, purchased several spots that will run on YouTube clips of Musk’s appearance on SNL. The company is also targeting non-SNL Musk clips on the platform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Uikc0r"&gt;We’ll update this post if more related commercials air. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22426978/elon-musk-snl-electric-vehicle-commercials-tesla-saturday-night-live"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/9/22426978/elon-musk-snl-electric-vehicle-commercials-tesla-saturday-night-live</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
