<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-07-19T06:32:28-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-19T06:32:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-19T06:32:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>Huawei’s P50 flagship will launch on July 29th  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Huawei P50" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eP926GkIn4de4_9Pg1xUMqK_oWY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69599671/huaweip50.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Huawei has previously teased the design of the flagship’s rear cameras.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Huawei&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5ggIou"&gt;Huawei’s next flagship phone, the P50, is set for launch on July 29th, &lt;a href="https://weibo.com/1839167003/KpqpgD10d"&gt;the company has announced&lt;/a&gt;. Writing on his own Weibo page, Huawei consumer group CEO &lt;a href="https://weibo.com/1100856704/KpqvOEtsk?from=page_1003061100856704_profile&amp;amp;wvr=6&amp;amp;mod=weibotime&amp;amp;type=comment"&gt;Richard Yu&lt;/a&gt; said (via Google translate) that the phone would mark the beginning of “a new era of mobile imaging,” suggesting that Huawei may once again make cameras the focus of its upcoming flagship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4awyiP"&gt;The launch comes a little over a year since Huawei &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/26/21194248/huawei-p40-pro-plus-release-date-specs-price-features-camera-google"&gt;announced its P40 series&lt;/a&gt;, but the launch  of the P50 has been far from certain. US sanctions placed on the company over national security concerns have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/9/21360598/huawei-chips-us-sanctions-trump-china-privacy-smartphone"&gt;seriously impacted&lt;/a&gt; Huawei’s ability to produce its own Kirin chipsets, creating doubts about its ability to release new flagship devices. “For reasons you are all aware of, a launch date has not been set,” Yu said when he teased the design of the P50 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22464776/huawei-p50-phone-camera-periscope-telephoto-leica-harmonyos"&gt;during a launch event last month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8FML29"&gt;These chip challenges, combined with sanctions that mean Huawei can no longer preinstall Google’s apps and services on its devices, have eroded Huawei’s market share. Globally it failed to rank in the top five smartphone vendors &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22579771/worldwide-smartphone-market-share-ranking-q2-2022-canalys-xiaomi-apple-samsung"&gt;in the second quarter of this year&lt;/a&gt; (after being the biggest in the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/30/21347685/worlds-biggest-smartphone-company-huawei-overtakes-samsung-canalys"&gt;same quarter the previous year&lt;/a&gt;), and even domestically in China &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22318941/china-smartphone-market-share-oppo-huawei-vivo-apple-xiaomi-january-2021"&gt;Oppo overtook it&lt;/a&gt; to become the country’s most popular smartphone brand in January.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583225/huawei-p50-launch-july-29th-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583225/huawei-p50-launch-july-29th-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-19T05:34:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-19T05:34:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung’s colossal 1,000-inch MicroLED display has improved colors and a thinner design</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cuAYsCh8HPPdC3UT5shBdV1vFBo=/0x0:2500x1667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69599594/The_Wall_R5_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall as a massive in-store display.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Samsung&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="05dFAz"&gt;Samsung is releasing &lt;a href="https://news.samsung.com/global/samsungs-2021-the-wall-is-now-available-worldwide"&gt;a new version of The Wall&lt;/a&gt;, its massive modular MicroLED display. Measuring in at over 1,000 inches in size, the new “IWA Series” display is aimed at businesses and commercial applications rather than homes, and Samsung’s promotional images showcase it being used as a huge display in a retail environment. The display is available in “select markets” from today, but Samsung’s press release doesn’t publicly list a price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aQ80Xu"&gt;Improvements for this year’s display include LEDs that are up to 40 percent smaller than last year, which Samsung says should lead to higher contrast and better color uniformity. The purity of The Wall’s colors has also been improved over the 2020 model, and Samsung boasts that it’s got a new AI processor that further improves picture quality and contrast, and removes noise. Docking connections have an improved, wireless design, and the display’s depth has been cut in half.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zBH5vU7R-nvMxH9R7619vHeL2IM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22725701/The_Wall_R5_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall, now with smaller pixel and a thinner design.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ClbxlG"&gt;The display has an 8K resolution with a 120Hz refresh rate, and because it’s made up of modular panels, it can be arranged in a number of different configurations, including an ultrawide 15,360 x 2,160 16K resolution. Samsung says the new 2021 model can be arranged to be concave, convex, or installed in other positions like being hung, mounted to a ceiling, or installed in the shape of an “L.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="94xZV7"&gt;The new IWA Series of The Wall is Samsung’s latest display to use its MicroLED technology, which relies an array of self-emissive LEDs to create its image, rather than an LCD layer like most traditional TVs. It means that the panels can create better black levels by turning off pixels entirely, similar to the effect you’ll see from an OLED TV but without OLED’s traditional limitations like the risk of burn-in and lower peak brightness than LCD panels. Samsung says its latest version of The Wall has a peak brightness of 1,600 nits, while the best of LG’s OLEDs still peak at under 1,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dpYBsz"&gt;While The Wall is an attempt to sell massive MicroLED displays to commercial customers, Samsung has also started including the technology in traditionally-sized TVs for the rest of us. At this year’s CES it announced a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22166062/samsung-110-inch-microled-4k-tv-announced-features"&gt;110-inch MicroLED TV&lt;/a&gt;, and it later expanded this range &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/samsung-micro-led-tv-first-look"&gt;to include 76 to 99-inch models&lt;/a&gt;. These are still massive TVs, to be sure, but at least they should fit on a wall in your house, unlike Samsung’s colossal 1000-inch monster.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583204/samsung-the-wall-micro-led-display-business-commercial"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583204/samsung-the-wall-micro-led-display-business-commercial</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-19T04:35:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-19T04:35:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>Tencent is buying British game studio Sumo for $1.27 billion</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="ANT FINANCIAL SERVICES GROUP Blockchain CUP Alipay GOAL" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qf5237zlJGtWey4tSrrWeuRzKF4=/0x0:5472x3648/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69599544/1233863534.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Costfoto/Barcroft Media via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ccCh6s"&gt;Tencent has announced plans to buy British video game company Sumo Group for $1.27 billion. The Chinese tech giant already has an 8.75-percent stake in the developer, as &lt;a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/articles/2021-07-19-tencent-to-buy-crackdown-and-sackboy-developer-sumo-in-usd1-3bn-deal"&gt;Gamesindustry.biz reports&lt;/a&gt;, and the offer represents a 43-percent premium on Sumo’s current valuation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dkUogs"&gt;Based in Sheffield, England, Sumo’s well-regarded core studio Sumo Digital has carried out contract work for many of the biggest names in gaming. It developed Sony’s PlayStation 5 launch title &lt;em&gt;Sackboy: A Big Adventure&lt;/em&gt; and was the primary studio behind &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/14/18224550/crackdown-3-review-xbox-one-pc"&gt;Microsoft’s &lt;em&gt;Crackdown 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for Xbox consoles and PC. In 2017 Sumo &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/4/13/15283820/snake-pass-review-nintendo-switch"&gt;released &lt;em&gt;Snake Pass&lt;/em&gt; for multiple platforms&lt;/a&gt;, its first foray into original IP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="AuiyWc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Crackdown 3 review: the Netflix Original of games","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/14/18224550/crackdown-3-review-xbox-one-pc"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="sqbVAV"&gt;“The three founders of Sumo, who work in the business, Paul Porter, Darren Mills and I are passionate about what we do and are fully committed to continuing in our roles,” says Sumo CEO Carl Cavers in a statement. “The opportunity to work with Tencent is one we just couldn’t miss. It would bring another dimension to Sumo, presenting opportunities for us to truly stamp our mark on this amazing industry, in ways which have previously been out-of-reach.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="esP0b3"&gt;Cavers says Tencent has “demonstrated its commitment to backing” Sumo’s client work, as well as its own original IP, so things are unlikely to change too quickly. The buyout does, however, give Tencent &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/7/21358252/tencent-wechat-ban-trump-executive-order-consequences"&gt;yet another foothold&lt;/a&gt; in the international gaming industry, following prominent investments in companies like Epic, Riot, Activision, and Ubisoft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4uTWBD"&gt;“Tencent intends to bring its expertise and resources to accelerate the growth of Sumo both in the UK and abroad, supporting Sumo in the market for top-notch creative talent, and the UK as a hub for game innovation,” says Tencent’s chief strategy officer James Mitchell. “We believe the proposed transaction benefits all stakeholders, delivers compelling value for Sumo shareholders, while enhancing the Sumo business for the future.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GY4Mbr"&gt;This would be the second billion-dollar deal involving a British game developer this year — EA completed its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/14/22173732/ea-codemasters-buyout-agreed-price-need-for-speed-dirt"&gt;acquisition of racing game specialists Codemasters&lt;/a&gt; for a similar price in February.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583186/tencent-sumo-digital-buyout-announced-price-acquisition"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583186/tencent-sumo-digital-buyout-announced-price-acquisition</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-19T02:36:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-19T02:36:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nintendo denies report that OLED Switch will have higher profit margin</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5njCRdzwYqRyblwZn_taRJpaOUE=/0x0:2160x1440/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69599370/switch_oled.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="t67PNS"&gt;Nintendo has issued an unusual statement denying a report that said the upcoming OLED version of the Switch would have higher profit margins than the regular model. The report in question was published &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-07-14/nintendo-switch-s-big-price-hike-takes-gamers-into-new-territory"&gt;by Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt; last week and speculated that the higher-end components in the OLED Switch could total around an extra $10 per unit, based on analyst estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iQ9Ocl"&gt;“A news report on July 15, 2021(JST) claimed that the profit margin of the Nintendo Switch (OLED Model) would increase compared to the Nintendo Switch,” Nintendo’s &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoCoLtd/status/1416986986464776196"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; reads. “To ensure correct understanding among our investors and customers, we want to make clear that the claim is incorrect.” Nintendo didn’t provide any information about the profit margins of either Switch console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="vgkPkr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Nintendo’s OLED Switch: all of the news about the console upgrade","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/6/22565307/nintendo-oled-switch-screen-news-updates"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="TD3N2r"&gt;The OLED Switch costs $349.99, $50 more than the standard model. Aside from the 7-inch 720p OLED screen, it also doubles the internal storage to 64GB, adds an ethernet port to the dock, and includes a more flexible kickstand. If the estimates cited by Bloomberg were accurate, it’d mean that Nintendo could be making up to $40 more on each model sold, but the company now says this isn’t the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y7lyLN"&gt;Nintendo also said in its statement that it has “no plans for launching any other model at this time.” Bloomberg had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/23/22346041/oled-nintendo-switch-dlss-nvidia-chip-report"&gt;previously reported&lt;/a&gt; that a new version of the Switch would come not only with an OLED screen, but more powerful internals and the ability to output 4K resolution by making use of Nvidia’s DLSS technology.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583141/nintendo-switch-oled-profit-margin-report-denial"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583141/nintendo-switch-oled-profit-margin-report-denial</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-18T18:13:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-18T18:13:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>New Trailers: Sweet Girl, Reservation Dogs, Flee, What We Do in the Shadows, and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8hPXq1tTLlxktjatTyXBgTzNGgM=/128x0:1126x665/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69598601/jason_momoa1.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Jason Momoa stars in Sweet Girl | &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NiFuJV2GLkY&amp;amp;ab_channel=Netflix" target="_blank"&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="sUneiG"&gt;Season one of &lt;em&gt;Loki&lt;/em&gt; is a wrap and while I know not everyone loved the finale, the show is my favorite of the Marvel/Disney streaming series so far. That’s due mostly to Tom Hiddleston’s fascinating performance as the title character, once a villain who’s evolved into... someone else, not quite sure who yet. Plenty of storylines to pick up in &lt;em&gt;Loki&lt;/em&gt; season two (yay). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jjw27a"&gt;And a reminder it’s &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt; week; season two arrives on Apple TV Plus July 23rd. In the media buzz leading up to the new season, there has been some evidence that Ted and creator Jason Sudeikis are kinda the same person: At the show’s world premiere, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/brfootball/status/1415887128588869633"&gt;Sudeikis wore a shirt&lt;/a&gt; with the names of three England footballers who were subjected to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/12/22574082/black-players-england-italy-football-soccer-racist-instagram-twitter-telegram"&gt;racist vitriol on social media&lt;/a&gt;, to show his support. And &lt;em&gt;Uproxx &lt;/em&gt;entertainment writer &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mikeryan/status/1415730436798619655"&gt;Mike Ryan shared a story about Sudeikis&lt;/a&gt; from a few years ago that gives further credence to the Ted/Sudeikis theory.  Love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4Jfw9l"&gt;This week’s trailers include a couple of comedies, and a Jason Momoa Netflix movie filmed in Pittsburgh whose title confuses me somewhat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="IjRS8m"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NiFuJV2GLkY?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="EOFtlI"&gt;Sweet Girl &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="vdrUG3"&gt;Jason Momoa stars as Ray Cooper, whose cancer-stricken wife dies after she’s unable to get a drug she needs. Why? Because the pharmaceutical company took it off the market to drive up its price. Ray’s out for revenge/justice, and his daughter Rachel (played by Isabel Merced, presumably the sweet girl of the title), is along for the quest. &lt;em&gt;Sweet Girl’&lt;/em&gt;s trailer makes excellent use of Pittsburgh’s Golden Triangle area, many bridges, and even our light rail line as dramatic backdrops for punching, stabbing, and throwing bad guys through windows. &lt;em&gt;Sweet Girl&lt;/em&gt; comes to Netflix August 20th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WumlU9"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RoHewFAkrWU?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="VPv9RS"&gt;Reservation Dogs &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="m8VlRN"&gt;This new half-hour comedy series from Taika Waititi and Sterlin Harjo is about a gang of Indigenous teenagers in Oklahoma whose criminal activities (they steal a chip delivery truck in the trailer), are part of their larger plan to raise money to get to California. &lt;em&gt;Reservation Dogs &lt;/em&gt;has strong Indigenous representation at every level of production and if the trailer is any indication, it’s a wickedly funny show that pokes holes in stereotypes of Indigenous people. D’Pharaoh Woon-A-Tai, Devery Jacobs, Paulina Alexis, and Lane Factor star in &lt;em&gt;Reservation Dogs&lt;/em&gt;, which comes to FX on Hulu August 9th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="FVMO1t"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LjKiM-Hz4Qs?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="TU0z9I"&gt;What We Do in the Shadows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="On6664"&gt;Season three of this ridiculously funny show about goofy vampires is finally almost here, and we have this teaser that shows Nandor walking around ... in the sunlight!? He’s not going to burst into flames, don’t worry; he’s just wearing a VR headset. This is a good binge show and everyone has been telling you how funny it is, so try to find time to catch up before season three hits FX on September 2nd (and Hulu a day later). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4WGMs0"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6ttU1iKSpdA?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="QlUePc"&gt;TItans&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="zKrrpn"&gt;We got a short teaser for season three of &lt;em&gt;Titans&lt;/em&gt; last month, but we get a lot more in this first official trailer, including a look at Red Hood, Vincent Kartheiser’s Scarecrow, and Gotham, the setting for this season. &lt;em&gt;Titans&lt;/em&gt; comes to HBO Max for its third season August 12th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="pVtKvv"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2aRfHsMgfdg?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="M9tW50"&gt;Flee&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="1QsqKY"&gt;This animated documentary film doesn’t have a release date, but won the Sundance Jury Prize and is already generating Oscar buzz, says Zack Sharf &lt;a href="https://www.indiewire.com/2021/07/flee-trailer-animated-doc-best-films-2021-1234651173/"&gt;at &lt;em&gt;Indiewire&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;It tells the story of a man, Amin Nawabi, who was a child refugee from Afghanistan, and fled to Moscow with his family. The trailer is just fascinating, using pieces of an audio interview with Nawabi as the voiceover. Riz Ahmed and Nikolaj Coster-Waldau are executive producers on&lt;em&gt; Flee&lt;/em&gt;, directed by Jonas Poher Rasmussen. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/18/22582379/new-trailers-reservation-dogs-sweet-girl-flee-what-we-do-in-the-shadows-netflix-hulu-hbo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/18/22582379/new-trailers-reservation-dogs-sweet-girl-flee-what-we-do-in-the-shadows-netflix-hulu-hbo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-18T16:25:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-18T16:25:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>New Steam Deck reservations now showing ‘expected order availability’ in Q2 and Q3 2022</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_u78r5KshOHYYbkxAsIQ7sTXiCI=/0x116:3684x2572/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69598360/Steam_Deck_case.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Steam Deck will start shipping in December 2021 | Image: Valve&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qSCCqs"&gt;If you’re looking to reserve a Steam Deck and haven’t managed to secure a reservation yet, it looks like you’ll be waiting a while to actually get your device. According to Steam’s store site on Sunday, the $399 64GB Steam Deck and the $529 256GB version both have “expected order availability” dates of of Q2 2022, meaning sometime next spring. The 512GB $649 model is even later; it’s showing expected availability in Q3 of next year, which is sometime between July and September 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="igPMbC"&gt;According to Steam’s website, it plans to &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/steamdeck"&gt;send order invitations&lt;/a&gt; by December of this year. Steam will then convert reservations to orders. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BtVdRbSINDGXBsplHcufyMnF4y4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22724907/choose_your_steam_deck.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;As of July 18th, the wait time for the top-of-the-line Steam Deck is Q3 of 2022. &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="8mYqZN"&gt;Steam’s official Twitter account &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Steam/status/1416811315985666051?s=20"&gt;posted Sunday&lt;/a&gt; that reservations for Steam Deck were open to new Steam accounts as well as existing accounts. Valve &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578783/valve-steam-deck-gaming-handheld-pc"&gt;only revealed&lt;/a&gt; its handheld PC gaming device on Thursday, but when it opened up to reservations on Friday afternoon, many people got repeated error messages. &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2021/07/html-holes-provide-a-glimpse-of-steam-decks-initial-preorder-numbers/"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Valve got more than 110,000 reservations for the 256GB and 512GB devices in the first 90 minutes after orders opened. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KYLJDs"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/18/22582617/new-steam-deck-reservations-q2-q3-valve-hand-held"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/18/22582617/new-steam-deck-reservations-q2-q3-valve-hand-held</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-18T14:08:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-18T14:08:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>Latest leaks indicate new iPhones may have always-on displays like Apple’s Watch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mf_L1zV7IAzv_m4dcuHJ_uI_jM0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69598039/jbareham_170916_2000_0057.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="R1XMX5"&gt;A new report from &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;’s Mark Gurman says the 2021 iPhone may have an always-on display &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/18/20869098/apple-watch-series-5-always-on-screen-features-price-best-smartwatch"&gt;similar to Apple’s Watch&lt;/a&gt;, and which Android phones have had for some time. Gurman wrote in his &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/account/newsletters/power-on"&gt;Power On newsletter&lt;/a&gt; that the phones will have improved battery life, a smaller notch on the screen, better video recording, a 120Hz refresh rate, and a faster A15 chip. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m7WmVs"&gt;It isn’t the first time a leak has suggested Apple is working on always-on screens for upcoming iPhones. Leaker Max Weinbach hinted &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FqOujNnuHBg&amp;amp;ab_channel=EverythingAppleProEAP"&gt;earlier this year&lt;/a&gt; that Apple may use the same kind of low temperature polycrystalline oxide (LTPO) panels that its Watches have on future iPhones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AYvGYi"&gt;That’s in keeping with &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;’s previous reporting that “at least one” of the four new iPhones will include an LTPO display. The technology dynamically adjusts Watches’ screen refresh rates to conserve battery life. Analyst &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/1/22307312/iphone-13-smaller-notch-high-refresh-rate-screen-hole-punch-foldable-se-5g"&gt;Ming-Chi Kuo&lt;/a&gt; also said earlier this year that the Pro iPhones coming this year would have LTPO displays and 120Hz refresh rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EIFGFl"&gt;In addition to the possibility of always-on iPhone screens, Gurman reported that Apple will likely announce new MacBook Pros this fall, “between September and November at the latest.” The computers will begin production in the third quarter, he adds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="jK75jI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"iPhone 13 rumors grow more certain ahead of September launch","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22576703/iphone-13-rumors-sizes-notch-camera-processor"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/18/22582569/leaks-apple-iphone-screen-always-on-watch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/18/22582569/leaks-apple-iphone-screen-always-on-watch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-18T13:42:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-18T13:42:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>Pegasus spyware used to target phones of journalists and activists, investigation finds</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mnXcqYLtop5iYJ5X4w-_uNJHloE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69597977/acastro_180109_1777_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="W5P0OF"&gt;A sweeping investigation by 17 media outlets found that NSO Group’s Pegasus software was used in hacking attempts on 37 smartphones belonging to human rights activists and journalists, &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/interactive/2021/nso-spyware-pegasus-cellphones/?itid=hp_alert"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; reported.&lt;/a&gt; The phones were on a leaked list of numbers discovered by Paris journalism nonprofit Hidden Stories and human rights group Amnesty International, according to the Post. The numbers on the list were singled out for possible surveillance by countries who are clients of NSO, the report states, which markets its spyware to governments to track potential terrorists and criminals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mVnXwL"&gt;Pegasus can extract all of a mobile device’s data, and activate the device’s microphone to listen in on conversations surreptitiously, as &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/18/ft-editor-roula-khalaf-among-180-journalists-targeted-nso-spywarer"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;notes. The list of journalists dates back to 2016, the &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; reports, and includes reporters from the &lt;em&gt;Post, CNN&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Associated Press&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Voice of America,&lt;/em&gt; the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg News&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Le Monde&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Al Jazeera&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jUl5zO"&gt;In a statement emailed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; on Sunday, an NSO spokesperson denied the claims in the report, saying it was “full of wrong assumptions and uncorroborated theories that raise serious doubts about the reliability and interests of the sources,” and questioned the sources that supplied the information. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0cfhet"&gt;“After checking their claims, we firmly deny the false allegations made in their report,” the statement continues. The company is considering a defamation lawsuit according to its statement, because it says “these allegations are so outrageous and far from reality.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TBdhTP"&gt;It’s not the first time NSO’s Pegasus spyware has been accused of being part of a larger surveillance campaign. Between July and August 2020, research organization &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/21/22192922/al-jazeera-journalists-hack-nso-group-hack-ios-imessage-zero-click-day"&gt;Citizen Lab found that 36 phones belonging to Al Jazeera journalists&lt;/a&gt; had been hacked using Pegasus technology, possibly by hackers working for governments in the Middle East. In 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/29/20938676/whatsapp-nso-group-spyware-hack-encrypted-chat-lawsuit"&gt;WhatsApp sued NSO&lt;/a&gt;, claiming Pegasus was used to hack users of WhatsApp’s encrypted chat service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qEv2bB"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/18/22582532/pegasus-nso-spyware-target-phones-journalists-activists-investigation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/18/22582532/pegasus-nso-spyware-target-phones-journalists-activists-investigation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-18T11:59:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-18T11:59:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook pushes back against Biden remarks on COVID-19 misinformation</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="facebook stock art" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hnOzlsd01mnbvPa0prbsSyyJNj0=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69596112/acastro_180928_1777_facebook_hack_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fI3bse"&gt;Facebook continued its pushback Saturday against President Biden’s comment that social media &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580620/biden-facebook-vaccine-misinformation-platforms"&gt;platforms were “killing people”&lt;/a&gt; with COVID-19 misinformation, in a &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/07/support-for-covid-19-vaccines-is-high-on-facebook-and-growing/"&gt;blog post from its vice president of integrity Guy Rosen&lt;/a&gt;. The post states that the “facts tell a very different story to the one promoted by the administration in recent days.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gWrarp"&gt;“At a time when COVID-19 cases are rising in America, the Biden administration has chosen to blame a handful of American social media companies,” Rosen wrote. “While social media plays an important role in society, it is clear that we need a whole of society approach to end this pandemic. And facts — not allegations — should help inform that effort.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eyDP8V"&gt;(The post was titled “Moving Past the Finger Pointing: Support for COVID-19 vaccines is high on Facebook and growing.”) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fZPEeB"&gt;On Friday, &lt;em&gt;NBC News&lt;/em&gt; reporter Peter Alexander asked Biden what his message was “to platforms like Facebook.” The president replied: “they’re killing people ...  the only pandemic we have is among the unvaccinated, and they’re killing people.” See the exchange below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bDOvKq"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;NBC's &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PeterAlexander?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@PeterAlexander&lt;/a&gt;: "What's your message to platforms like Facebook [regarding COVID misinformation]?"&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;President Biden: "They're killing people." &lt;a href="https://t.co/TIaoeESMdk"&gt;pic.twitter.com/TIaoeESMdk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— The Recount (@therecount) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/therecount/status/1416118730904510467?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rZOqO7"&gt;According to Rosen’s post, Facebook has worked with Carnegie Mellon University in Pittsburgh and the University of Maryland on a &lt;a href="https://delphi.cmu.edu/covidcast/surveys/"&gt;global survey &lt;/a&gt;on COVID-19 symptoms, testing, and vaccination rates. The results, Rosen writes, show 85 percent of Facebook users in the US have or want to be vaccinated against the coronavirus. “President Biden’s goal was for 70% of Americans to be vaccinated by July 4. Facebook is not the reason this goal was missed,” Rosen added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lKLSi9"&gt;Biden’s comment came amid growing pressure from the White House toward Facebook and other social platforms to better stem the flow of coronavirus vaccine misinformation on their sites. A Thursday report &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578431/white-house-surgeon-general-facebook-youtube-twitter-covid-19-misinformation-vaccines"&gt;from Surgeon General Vivek Murthy&lt;/a&gt; on “confronting health information,” included recommendations for different stakeholders, including tech platforms, individuals, educators, health professionals, funders, researchers, journalists, and governments. The recommendations for the platforms included suggestions to “strengthen the monitoring of misinformation,” and “amplify communications from trusted messengers and subject matter experts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DNR5Af"&gt;In Saturday’s post, Rosen argued that Facebook had already taken action on &lt;a href="https://www.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/surgeon-general-misinformation-advisory.pdf"&gt;Murthy’s recommendations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="42FxY6"&gt;A Facebook spokesperson said Friday that the “accusations” weren’t supported by the facts. Several Republicans also expressed concern about the White House’s efforts; Congressman Ken Buck (R-CO) said the White House was “colluding with Facebook to censor Americans.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sf8S1q"&gt;In response to a request for comment, a White House spokesperson pointed to Murthy’s &lt;a href="https://video.foxnews.com/v/6264177467001#sp=show-clips"&gt;comments on &lt;em&gt;Fox News Sunday&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;This isn’t about me or about a specific social media company, this is about the health of Americans. And the reality is that misinformation is still spreading like wildfire in our country, aided and abetted by technology platforms,” Murthy said, acknowledging that some technology companies have “taken positive steps,” but it’s not enough. “Despite some of the actions they have taken, we’re still seeing significant spreading of misinformation,” on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iTtP0o"&gt;“I’m asking these companies to step up and take responsibility for what’s happening on their sites,” Murthy added. “I’m asking them to look out for the people all across this country whose lives depend on having access to accurate information. And that’s what I’m going to continue to do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hO8mmW"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update July 18th 11:59AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Adds Sunday comments from Vivek Murthy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/17/22581683/facebook-biden-remarks-covid-19-vaccine-misinformation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/17/22581683/facebook-biden-remarks-covid-19-vaccine-misinformation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-18T11:30:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-18T11:30:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>Robot collision at Ocado warehouse near London sparks fire, delaying customer orders</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IrTYWaH8Mhc57aexSbPmQDT1hO0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69597620/jvincent_180501_2547_0012.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by James Vincent / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Exm3I3"&gt;Online-only British supermarket Ocado has had to cancel some customers’ delivery orders after a Friday robot collision at one of its warehouses caused a fire, &lt;a href="https://www.ocadogroup.com/response-to-fire-at-erith"&gt;the company said&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lFYc48"&gt;The fire at the company’s Erith warehouse east of London “appears to have been caused by the collision of three bots on the grid,” the company said in a statement on Sunday. No one was injured, and the damage was limited to less than 1 percent of its grid, according to Ocado.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H77UFb"&gt;The grocer’s warehouses are populated with washing machine-sized robots that move products around on a grid system. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s James Vincent wrote about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/8/17331250/automated-warehouses-jobs-ocado-andover-amazon"&gt;Ocado’s plans in a 2018 feature&lt;/a&gt; story. He described the process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="o6LiSQ"&gt;Deliveries are unpacked into crates; crates are placed onto conveyors; and conveyors carry the crates to shelves, where human “pickers” take what they need to fill customers’ orders. The new paradigm, though, is all about using space as efficiently as possible. Items are still placed in crates, but those crates are now stored in huge stacks, up to 17 boxes high. Their position in this stack seems to be at random — a box of razors next to cod fillets, for example — but it’s algorithmically decided; with frequently accessed items placed on the top and rarer purchases near the bottom. On top of this hoard, the robots do their work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div id="ZCU2Vm"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="This is an automated warehouse for groceries|38290" data-volume-uuid="cd275e54f" data-volume-id="38290" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-829" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="caption"&gt;Robots at Ocado’s warehouses operate on grids. Three of the robots collided at its Erith warehouse on July 16th, causing a fire that has disrupted operations.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="T7UDc0"&gt;The company said Sunday that the Erith plant, which processes some 150,000 orders a week &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/aaddf4b1-a78b-4289-b42f-fd3f5cd7f176"&gt;according to the &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, should restart operations in the next few days. “While we expect some disruption to operations, we are working to restore normal service as soon as possible,” the company said. “We expect the facility to begin operating within the coming week and thank customers whose orders are affected for their patience.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/18/22582454/robot-collision-ocado-warehouse-england-fire-delayed-orders"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/18/22582454/robot-collision-ocado-warehouse-england-fire-delayed-orders</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
