<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2022-01-17T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-17T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-17T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Verge’s favorite tools to stay organized</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The overflow pile includes review devices, sensors, and an Echo Show 8." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PkaaKd3aW8ozCd3TwpPug41zjMg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70399675/dseifert_20210415_4535_0017.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="J6gNu7"&gt;Life these days can be very complicated, and many of us — I’d guess that most of us — are constantly looking for the best method to keep our lives in order. What do you need on your grocery list? When is that work project due, and who is working on it with you? A friend wants to do a movie-watching session, but is that the same day you promised your parents to help clean the garage? Which bills are due, and can you afford to pay them all? Where is that article about which masks to wear? And on and on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wlJzbE"&gt;So we decided to start off 2022 by asking the staff of &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; what they use to keep track of all their appointments / tasks / projects / workflows. And it turned out that they use a variety of different apps or some fairly old-fashioned paper-and-pen solutions — or both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IpXCGN"&gt;If you’re finding that this year is turning out to be a confusing one, and you need a way to try to keep your life and your sanity in order, here are some methods that we use. We hope they are helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="S8hqYA"&gt;A notebook&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Leuchtturm 1917 notebooks" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tDcCdoEi0zQFbeSmKBRjfg67w7A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23169716/notebook_classic.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Leuchtturm&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leuchtturm1917 notebooks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="0yN1tn"&gt;Get a notebook. You do not need tech for this. In fact, keeping track of yourself is much easier if you aren’t using tech designed for someone else. You know why? Only you operate your brain. You are much more likely to design a system you will use than someone else is. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uYELgk"&gt;You will need a pencil or a pen. You can get wild and buy markers and a ruler. Personally, I like markers because I like &lt;em&gt;color&lt;/em&gt;, but this is your notebook, so you should follow your heart. Now you are going to experiment. Are you a monster who operates her life through jerry-rigged to-do lists? Great. Make some to-do lists. Do you want to track stuff using Bullet Journal layouts? Great. Do that. Do you just want to write down your feelings before you talk to someone about them? Brainstorm on a task? Whatever? Great news! There is a blank piece of paper, &lt;em&gt;and it can be whatever you want it to be.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I8QA4T"&gt;You do not need to buy an expensive notebook, though I like them because they make me feel fancy, and &lt;a href="https://www.leuchtturm1917.us/notebooks/?filters%5B17847%5D%5B%5D=9901&amp;amp;filters%5B17846%5D%5B%5D=19294"&gt;the paper is nice to touch&lt;/a&gt;. Still, my oldest notebooks are cheapo, nasty spiral-bound ruled paper I bought at the drugstore for under a dollar. The point is not the tools you are using. The point is that you are using something &lt;em&gt;that works for your own brain.&lt;/em&gt; Glad we had this talk. — &lt;em&gt;Elizabeth Lopatto, deputy editor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vrdtKh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10978638" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"description_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="uRT3DH"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.notion.so/personal"&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Notion" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fd--oCjbxaXC1MAZozBXIRdN4bE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23167344/Screen_Shot_2022_01_13_at_5.26.52_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Notion Labs&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="mG3jvW"&gt;I’ve always had a not-so-great memory, and as a result, throughout most of my career, I’ve gone through I-don’t-know how many different apps for keeping track of what I have to do. I need something I can consult to track projects, remind myself of who owes me an article, which articles I promised to write or edit, what how-tos I swore I would take on next, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VVSyHp"&gt;As a result, while I appreciate (and sometimes use) simple note-taking apps such as &lt;a href="https://keep.google.com/"&gt;Google Keep&lt;/a&gt; or reminders such as &lt;a href="https://ticktick.com/"&gt;TickTick&lt;/a&gt;, I love experimenting with more complex task managers. (Remind me sometime to rant about &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ecco_Pro"&gt;Ecco Pro&lt;/a&gt;, a wonderfully flexible outliner / database back in the ’90s that was eventually acquired by another company and immediately abandoned, dammit.) Currently, my go-to for trying to maintain all my various projects is Notion. I’m sure I haven’t learned 50 percent of the various ways one can use it. But it lets me nest pages inside pages inside pages; create outlines and to-do lists and on-the-fly notes; and, most importantly, add reminders and links so that I don’t let important things drop under my radar.&lt;em&gt; — Barbara Krasnoff, reviews editor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gPHPgn"&gt;&lt;a href="https://todoist.com/app"&gt;Todoist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Todoist" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TUTQltDCaa4p2vPPKEKRya_8hec=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23167233/chrome_extension_2x.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Doist&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Todoist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="sWaNTH"&gt;Todoist — namely, the Chrome plug-in — has been my ride-or-die daily organizational app for years now. The free version that I use is very basic but does exactly what I need it to: allow me to add items to my daily checklist and cross them off as I get things done. The “crossing things off when I’m done” is essential because I am an elder millennial, and I require affirmation that I’m doing things right. Favorite features in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="eM9VqT"&gt;Drag and drop tasks from one day to another&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WssLA6"&gt;The ability to add a website as a task for stuff I want to read later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="GYqY1M"&gt;Priority flags that you can add to tasks and then ignore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="377PQ3"&gt;Move a task to tomorrow’s list with one click&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="L6nJ0k"&gt;It doesn’t do everything — I need a separate tool for long-term planning — but it is a lifesaver for daily priorities. And I swear it used to display a pleasant little sunset graphic when you emptied your checklist for the day, which was very gratifying. It doesn’t do that anymore, and I miss it. &lt;em&gt;— Allison Johnson, reviewer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="aPIHvY"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/reminders/id1108187841"&gt;Apple’s Reminders&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://ticktick.com/"&gt;TickTick&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Reminders" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/adV1uKOmELLlYelzCzeEtDy4dhA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23167239/Screen_Shot_2022_01_13_at_4.46.21_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reminders&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="VovlY4"&gt;I use two apps to keep track of my to-dos: Apple’s Reminders app for personal tasks and TickTick for work tasks. I like Reminders because it integrates well across Apple’s device ecosystem (which I am in), and it allows my wife and I to easily make shared reminders if needed. I like TickTick for work because it’s easy to add tasks and because it sits unobtrusively in my menu bar. Keeping tasks across two different apps isn’t the most efficient process, but it helps me keep a better separation between personal and work stuff. &lt;em&gt;— Jay Peters, news writer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gkdXQl"&gt;Fountain pens&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Lamy Safari fountain pen" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5wKGsrp6XBqrmoiM_R5wq-lTg1E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23167246/LamySafariPen.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Lamy&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lamy Safari fountain pen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="vqcOe8"&gt;I have to piggyback off Liz a little because I’ve tried digital solutions to organize myself, yet I often come back to pen and paper. I’m more focused when taking a moment to jot something down, whether it’s making a to-do list and outline in my notebook or creating a down-to-the-minute morning routine on an index card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZTFB71"&gt;I channel my obsessively geeky tendencies into my choice of writing instrument. I got into fountain pens years ago, and I’ve picked up a bunch that I love using. They motivate me to take personal notes, get organized, and plan out my day — because I just like writing with these pens, even when it’s only a few words and a checkbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xg6UNy"&gt;Find yourself something you like to write with, whether it be a fancy (or affordable) fountain pen, a quirky gel pen bought off AliExpress that &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.aliexpress.com%2Fitem%2F4000325642482.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22882328%2Forganization-tools-todo-notes-journals" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;looks like a cute bear&lt;/a&gt; (I have this, too), or a cheap ballpoint that just feels right to you. Fountain pens can be finicky, but they make everything very purposeful. Check out the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Lamy-Safari-White-Fountain-Pen/dp/B0002XT27W?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Lamy Safari&lt;/a&gt; for a tried-and-true pen that is fairly inexpensive but undeniably good, or the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/TWSBI-ECO-Clear-Fountain-Pen/dp/B07JK2Z9H3?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;TWSBI Eco&lt;/a&gt; for a bit more money and get a cool &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Pilot-Iroshizuku-Bottled-Fountain-69226/dp/B003MVMB7E?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;bottle of colorful ink&lt;/a&gt; you can see slosh around in the translucent piston-filled barrel. You’ll feel like the coolest nerd around. — &lt;em&gt;Antonio G. Di Benedetto, commerce writer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kwn7Vb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10977851" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"description_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="BZAMJ4"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="TlkzPw"&gt;&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.stuff.todo"&gt;Stuff - To Do List Widget for Android&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Stuff widget" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4AGe53q5C7QTytA_8kwoXmnV-pc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23167305/Screenshot_20220113_171106.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stuff widget&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Adding a task" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/X0K1R1AmsjZCwmSn_SKFXSrx4l4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23167308/Screenshot_20220113_171221.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Adding a task&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LyBshh"&gt;I’m usually not as organized as I would like to be. But outside of jotting essential to-do’s and must-buy groceries on sticky notes, my other line of defense from getting overwhelmed by the flailing tentacles of life is an Android widget called Stuff. It’s a free to-do list app that lets you denote tasks for today, tomorrow, or sometime down the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="knyH3A"&gt;I like it more than other to-do list apps that I’ve tried because it’s actually a widget, so it can live front-and-center on your screen if you want it to. Also, it doesn’t require an account, nor does it have ads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M1atWC"&gt;Stuff is fairly limited in terms of customization, but you can pay $2 as an in-app purchase for more features, like the ability to rename the categories (I happen to like the default ones) or change the color of the bullet points that appear next to each line item, as well as more under-the-hood details of the widget itself. You can round its corners, change its background color, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O7y939"&gt;I still find myself bouncing off using it (more of a “me” problem than this widget), but when I’m trying to get focused, I turn to Stuff. &lt;em&gt;— Cameron Faulkner, reviewer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="suODdg"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Ffive-star-3-subject-college-ruled-spiral-notebook-colors-may-vary%2F-%2FA-14045827%3Fclkid%3Dba953179N6e3e11ec9756a3c600bed8d5%26lnm%3D1237061%26afid%3DVox%2520Media%26ref%3Dtgt_adv_xasd0002&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Five Star notebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Five Star 3 notebook" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i_IYvHmU4lviLB4qWg6IkpquTGk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23167320/Screen_Shot_2022_01_13_at_5.16.28_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Five Star&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Five Star 3 notebook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="iIpi16"&gt;I use a combination of things, but like a few other people on this list, this simple &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/1237061/2092?subId1=TheVergeFavoriteTools11222&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Ffive-star-3-subject-college-ruled-spiral-notebook-colors-may-vary%2F-%2FA-14045827"&gt;$4.79 Five Star notebook&lt;/a&gt; is my favorite tool. Although I don’t adhere to it religiously, I like the bullet journal approach, so I manually number each page and add a separate index sheet in one of the notebook’s folders to easily find what I need by categories I’m constantly creating. I like color, so I use a few markers and pens, but nothing too fancy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S3urSa"&gt;For me, the simpler and cheaper the notebook, the better, because I find I feel less guilty about using it not just to write out my to-do list but also to plan, brainstorm, quickly jot down notes, journal, add my grocery shopping lists, and more. I find I just can’t do all of that when I have a high-end or exceptionally beautiful notebook. Don’t get me wrong — I have a collection of stunning journals that look like art, but I rarely use them because I know it’ll be expensive to buy another. When I do actually use them, I almost feel this kind of pressure to make my entries as organized, attractive, and as Pinterest-worthy possible — while never actually getting anything done (true story). &lt;em&gt;— Sheena Vasani, commerce writer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JvUd4R"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10977855" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"description_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="hg1yEZ"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="TICEZM"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.omnigroup.com/omnifocus/"&gt;OmniFocus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="OmniFocus" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-UKX52qCe83-eCAOGpvSq5MgiYo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23167326/Screen_Shot_2022_01_13_at_5.20.25_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: The Omni Group&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;OmniFocus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="lVxaGT"&gt;I basically run my life out of OmniFocus. Work tasks, home tasks, they all go into the same app, laden with tags and metadata like a defer (read: “don’t bug me about this until”) date, due date, and project. The app lets me change views if I only want to see personal tasks or work tasks, or it’ll let me get the big-picture view of everything I’ve got coming up and everything I’ve been putting off from the Forecast view. It can be a bit fiddly with managing projects and folders, but now that I’ve got a system set up, it feels like I can do almost anything when it comes to organizing and displaying my tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bGwYEa"&gt;I mean, I don’t. I pretty much explained everything I do in the first two sentences. But the point is that I could — and yes, I realize that my use of OmniFocus is like someone insisting they need an F-650 box truck to move a plastic table made for children. (Seriously, I’m getting jealous of my co-workers who are happy with $5 notebooks or free apps, especially since I’ll probably be dropping anywhere from $50 to $100 to upgrade to OmniFocus 4 when it comes out.) But none of the other apps I’ve tried have mapped so perfectly onto how my brain categorizes tasks, and I love using it so much that it (and Overcast) are basically what made me switch from Android to iOS. I’ve got no plans to change task management systems anytime soon. &lt;em&gt;— Mitchell Clark, news writer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1Wk8Qh"&gt;Apps and notebooks&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Tsuki ‘Winter Wishes’ bullet journal" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W6DwPvGH6ncfGG0t79US89aoSVo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23167331/Screen_Shot_2022_01_13_at_5.22.26_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Notebook Therapy&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tsuki ‘Winter Wishes’ bullet journal &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="1hehIk"&gt;Like many of my colleagues, I use a hybrid of apps and notebooks. However, there’s a clear line between work and personal tasks. Work tasks get apps, personal tasks are analog. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4QMkuo"&gt;For personal stuff, I’ve been a &lt;a href="https://www.leuchtturm1917.us/notebooks/?filters%5B17847%5D%5B%5D=9901&amp;amp;filters%5B17846%5D%5B%5D=19294"&gt;Leuchtturm1917&lt;/a&gt; fan for many years, but recently, I’m trying out this &lt;a href="https://notebooktherapy.com/collections/bullet-journal/products/tsuki-winter-wishes-limited-edition-bullet-journal?variant=39545906004083"&gt;cute bullet journal&lt;/a&gt; from NotebookTherapy. Don’t get me started on how much I’ve spent on Japanese and Korean pens, markers, and highlighters. Basically, if it’s at &lt;a href="https://www.jetpens.com/"&gt;JetPens&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://shop.mochithings.com/"&gt;MochiThings&lt;/a&gt;, I have probably spent too much of my money on it. (Can you tell I was the dork with color-coded notes in school?) It’s just a soothing way to process all the big picture things going on in my life and break them down into more digestible pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m8x31v"&gt;But as a tech reviewer, my entire working life is digital, and I need to be able to switch between my phone and laptop. That’s why I also like Todoist — it’s got a mobile app, Chrome extension, integrates with my email client, the works. I also use &lt;a href="https://dayoneapp.com/"&gt;Day One&lt;/a&gt; as a scratchpad for drafts I’m struggling with and 3AM shower thoughts alike. Otter.ai is essential for recording briefings. On days I really can’t focus, I like to use &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/be-focused-focus-timer/id973134470?mt=12"&gt;Be Focused&lt;/a&gt;, which is basically a Pomodoro timer. &lt;em&gt;— Victoria Song, reviewer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ukOWjE"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10977860" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"brief_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="LscLuU"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="44KlpR"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/guide/stickies/welcome/mac"&gt;Stickies&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Stickies" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ik9vuhUYgki3TSEW3QMHqR_WW9c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23167339/Screen_Shot_2022_01_13_at_5.25.02_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stickies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="OEEu4a"&gt;I have been using Apple’s macOS Stickies app on my work computers for as long as I can remember. This is the primary way I organize my thoughts throughout the workday, and I use the app for just about everything. I make lists of assignments and ongoing stories, ordered by deadline or urgency; I transcribe specific times at which I want to revisit a quote during interviews and live events; I write myself reminders for things that I know I’ll later forget; and I keep tabs on specific threads I want to follow up on when time allows. This very blurb was drafted in Stickies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vgNix1"&gt;To be clear, this isn’t the only way I organize my life. I use Asana for long-term projects, physical notebooks and a day planner for note-taking and personal planning, as well as tools like the Slack reminders feature (which I use &lt;em&gt;exhaustively&lt;/em&gt;). But Stickies are tremendously useful for day-to-day list-making and scrawling down stray thoughts. And the Notes app simply won’t do — that’s for things like groceries and errands!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jFzFEo"&gt;I’m sure there’s a better way to hack your productivity, but this one’s worked for me for years. If you don’t mind your desktop image being obscured by a rainbow of translucent windows packed with lists and blocks of text, I recommend this (admittedly chaotic) method of workflow management. &lt;em&gt;—  Catie Keck, reporter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="XzVOMV"&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/guide/notes/welcome/mac"&gt;Apple Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Apple Notes" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4ZptaNk5Iozky077H1zp9IX7eb0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23168646/applenotes1.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="JRRTy9"&gt;Don’t @ me. It’s just so easy! Right there at my fingertips on my laptop and my phone! Apple’s built-in Notes app has delightfully few features. Really the only one that I use is the checklist feature that allows you to make lists with empty bubbles next to them, and nothing is more satisfying than clicking to check off one of those bad boys once you’ve finished your task. Notes allows you to bold and italicize, too, which I do every once in a while if I’m feeling wild. Plus, you can search your Notes. You can’t command+F an analog notebook! Notes syncs across all of your iOS devices if you want it to, but I don’t. Mine are kept separate. My laptop notes are for work, my phone notes are for personal tasks, and my iPad notes are for random musings and journaling in times when my analog diary is out of reach. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T5Q6PM"&gt;Taylor Swift uses the Notes app to jot down lyrics whenever inspiration strikes, and since she’s one of the most prolific humans on this earth, that should be all the convincing you need. &lt;em&gt;— Jackie McDermott, associate producer, Decoder&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22882328/organization-tools-todo-notes-journals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22882328/organization-tools-todo-notes-journals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-17T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-17T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Roomba j7 Plus vs. Jet Bot AI Plus: can these robot vacuums pass the poop test?</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Home robots are getting smarter&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="2VHGgf"&gt;Robot vacuums have come a long way since the days I used to babysit my original Roomba (circa 2006), following it around to make sure it didn’t thrash around on a threshold or ignore the miniature lighthouses and trundle unseeingly into a no-go zone. Back then, my biggest issue was coming home to a robot vacuum that had gone about 10 minutes into its cleanup route and been derailed by a shoe, sock, or dress-up wig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3XmbBw"&gt;Fast forward a decade or so, and robot vacuum manufacturers claim they’ve cracked it. Using improved sensors combined with artificial intelligence, the latest crop of bots can now see and recognize everyday household objects and nimbly navigate around them to carry on their merry way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ibEpsN"&gt;But is this feature worth splashing out on a top-of-the-line bot for? I put two of the newest to the test — &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/iRobot-Roomba-Self-Emptying-Robot-Vacuum/dp/B094NYHTMF?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;iRobot’s Roomba j7&lt;/a&gt; ($650 for the vacuum, $850 for the j7 Plus version with the auto-empty base) and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Recognition-Intelligent-Touchless-Navigation/dp/B0912TLG7T?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung’s Jet Bot AI Plus&lt;/a&gt; ($1,300 for the bot and base, you can’t buy it separately) — to see if they lived up to their lofty promises. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div id="106DTr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10974596"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="XKCU06"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10974616"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WfRxPu"&gt;The main advantage of this flagship feature is you don’t have to tidy up before the robot runs. I’m not convinced this is as big a selling point as some other advances, like self-emptying or smart mapping. Floors can’t really be cleaned if they’re still littered with clutter. But if it means the bot won’t get tripped up by that stray cable you didn’t know was sitting under the couch or the pair of shoes your significant other carelessly discarded in its path, then there’s some benefit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Shy0Kh"&gt;The other perk for pet owners is that one of those common household objects the bots will avoid is poop. Yep, if you have a pup who often poops in the living room, iRobot promises its newest vacuum won’t smear the crap all over the place thanks to iRobot’s PrecisionVision Navigation technology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="c6CQRw"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The only robot that actually went over the fake poop was the Roomba&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YJIfMJ"&gt;If it fails, then the iRobot Pet Owner Official Promise (P.O.O.P for short) kicks in, and they’ll send you a new one (only in the first year, though, and no word on who will come and clean up the catastrophe). It will also avoid phone cords, power cables, shoes, and socks, with more objects on their way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AKcUTk"&gt;Samsung’s Jet Bot AI Plus doesn’t come with the same promise, but its AI-powered 3D Object Recognition technology is backed by an Intel processor and is programmed to discern turds and other common clutter. Plus, you can have it check in on your dog throughout the day using the vacuum’s built-in HD camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yPFa5hih-0y97RJOZjKnS3gUyF0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23163834/vtuohy_220110_4963_0018.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Roomba j7 Plus and Samsung JetBot AI Plus both come with charging docks that can auto-empty the robot’s dustbin. These can hold two to three months of debris before being replaced, depending on use. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id="3TW8Mr"&gt;All the features&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="J8gpMS"&gt;As high-end robot vacuums, both models have all the features you’d expect: smart mapping to ensure every nook and cranny is reached, voice assistant compatibility so you can imperiously command your robot army of one (even say which room to head to), scheduling and location-based automations, strong cleaning performance, the ability to add virtual no-go zones (and physical ones if you prefer), and a self-emptying dock, so you rarely have to get your hands dirty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ErdoY0"&gt;Both robots have an upgrade to intelligent mapping that includes furniture and appliances. This is handy as it means you can tell the robot to go “clean in front of the fridge.” (The Roomba works with the Alexa and Google voice assistants and the Samsung with both of those plus Bixby). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VXhc4f"&gt;The Jet Bot AI Plus can automatically identify appliances, adding them to the map in the app (which is the SmartThings app). You can edit and add if it gets it wrong (oddly, it never spotted my giant Samsung refrigerator). The Roomba lets you add Clean Zones into the map in its iRobot app and label them as “counter,” “dining room table,” or “couch” (the AI should suggest them over time, iRobot tells us, but that hadn’t happened in my six weeks of testing). The Roomba also lets you create multiple maps for other floors, the Jet Bot only has one map. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="iyhiRX"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Samsung Jet Bot AI Plus was clearly inspired by a galaxy far, far away&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Q90Y2N"&gt;The Roomba has smart connections that can tell the robot to run when you leave, including the options to link it to the closing of your MyQ smart garage door controller or locking of your August lock. You can also use IFTTT or Alexa Routines to set up location-based prompts for the robot to get busy while you’re gone. Samsung offers this feature through SmartThings’ Automations. The app is a little challenging to navigate as it’s an entire smart home ecosystem, not just an app to run your robot, but it does include a wide variety of automation options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jcjW4E"&gt;Neither bot doubles as a mop, but Roomba has a mopping robot that can share maps with the vacuum and which you can program to pop out and mop after the vacuum is done. Samsung also has a robot mop, but there are no linked features yet. In my experience, stand-alone mop bots are better. Most robot vacs that also mop put most of their power into vacuuming, and the mopping portion is more about ineffectually dragging a wet towel over your floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3PWqOd9yUZMyhZjQ-57XYGeaQ0o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23168877/Samsung_JetBot_App.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Jet Bot is controlled through the SmartThings app. The map shows the layout of the test space, including furniture and appliances it thinks are there. It also pops up an image of any obstacle in the cleaning report. You can also view the robot’s camera feed here. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XqkjJW"&gt;Samsung does have another trick up its sleeve to justify that eye-wateringly high price tag (it’s one of the most expensive robot vacuums you can buy). It doubles as a mobile security camera — think &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22692048/ring-always-home-cam-drone-amazon-price-release-date-specs"&gt;Ring’s Always Home Cam &lt;/a&gt;without the hazard of flying and with the bonus that you can actually buy it (we’re still waiting on that Ring drone). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AI7adm"&gt;Both robots have cameras built-in for navigation purposes, but with the Jet Bot AI Plus, you can use its onboard lens as a home monitoring device. Which is actually really fun, although of minimal use beyond tracking your pet (which it can also do — although only dogs, no kitties) or monitoring someone sneaking around your house. Because of its height, it’s limited in what it can see (so you can’t use it to check the stove is on), and there’s no zoom, plus it can’t do stairs. But you can schedule it to patrol on the hour (using the SmartThings app) and look for motion, as well as choose up to five “spots” on the robot’s map to go surveil. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="Bl0GZ6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;You can rebuild your Roomba, if needed, making it an investment that should last&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YEC01U"&gt;A pet monitoring feature is a separate option using the free SmartThings Pet add-on in the app. This lets you set a schedule for the Jet Bot AI Plus to patrol around and look specifically for your pet. It will report back if it doesn’t find him or her. If it does see them, it pops up a notification and records a quick video. In my testing, this was pretty spotty. It only ever went into two rooms, stubbornly refusing to check out the living room, where the pet was sitting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iLmQIe"&gt;You can manually control the robot through the app to go find your furry bundle, all the while muttering the phrase, “I am not a helicopter pet parent. I am not a helicopter pet parent.” Live streaming and 10-second video clips are free, and you can upgrade to 60-second clips for $8 a month or $80 a year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Sp6BFzgxLQaUQdhcS9gzrM0YzHw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23163829/vtuohy_211029_4963_0013.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Roomba j7 has a polished look, and its Clean Base has a more contemporary design, with a ribbed, matte black plastic, and a faux leather pull tab for accessing the bin.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id="E933Di"&gt;Design decisions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="DUX5Tw"&gt;Both robots boast unique designs. The Samsung Jet Bot AI Plus was clearly inspired by a galaxy far, far away, and if you’ve always wanted a sleek-looking storm-trooper-like robot (vacuum) in your home, here it is. It’s also a beast — weighing about 10 pounds and measuring 5.5 inches at its tallest point (which is when the little LiDAR sensor pops up). This means it won’t get under that mid-century mod couch easily. However, its tank-like wheels will surmount nearly any obstacle (except perhaps rug tassels). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2w3qiO"&gt;The Roomba is much more compact. At just 3.5 inches tall, it got under all my furniture with no issues. While the Jet Bot has a squared-off front end that tapers down as low as 2 inches, allowing it to get into places like along kitchen cabinets, the Roomba still has it beat on versatility. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ytr2AE"&gt;The Roomba’s bin/dock is also much shorter and squatter than most (including the Samsung’s, which is taller and narrower). Not short enough to live under a couch or bed, but certainly less obtrusive (it also now holds an extra bag, which is helpful). Speaking of bags, you’ll need to replace them every two to three months and Roomba’s cost $20 for three, with Samsung’s being more expensive at $40 for a five-pack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8JUaWgJgNumkWkdo3yIdrRR_HhM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23163824/vtuohy_210921_4963_0009.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Samsung Jet Bot AI Plus is a sleek, all-white affair with a robot-like LED eye that glows, indicating what state the vacuum is in.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MKIyDw"&gt;On-device controls vary, too — with the Samsung offering two buttons, one to start, stop and pause a run, and one to send it home. Plus, a glowing LED strip at the front gives you an indication of what it’s doing (it glows blue if it’s in patrol mode) and adds to that Star Wars vibe. The Samsung will also chatter away to you about its daily life almost incessantly. “Thank you for helping me” is one of its cutesiest phrases, but if it gets stuck or runs into a problem, it will keep talking until you rescue it. Not ideal if you like to run it at night. Thankfully, this feature can be turned off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GnTE8u"&gt;The Roomba has been stripped down to just one button that will start, stop and pause a clean with a tap or long-press to send it home. A spinning LED ring around the button also informs you what it’s doing — white for cleaning, red for low battery, and blue when it’s thinking about stuff. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CRZDyg"&gt;Unfortunately, the powers-that-be have done away with the spot clean button. So you can’t just plop it down and press one button when your kid knocks the Cheerios box over. Neither robot has this feature, found on most other robot vacuums. Instead, you have to use the app to “spot clean” — which is fiddly at best. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;
&lt;div id="qzcoqR"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Samsung JetBot AI meets dog poop_audio|105543" data-volume-uuid="47b822307" data-volume-id="105543" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="true" id="volume-placement-990" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="caption"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Testing the Samsung Jet Bot AI Plus with fake dog poop.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="SiV0EO"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Roomba J7 VS dog poop_audio|105542" data-volume-uuid="52d4be874" data-volume-id="105542" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="true" id="volume-placement-642" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="caption"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Testing the Roomba j7 with fake dog poop.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id="IoLrQF"&gt;How about that poop?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="cm50ge"&gt;But back to that signature feature. How well do these robots avoid the everyday detritus of life? Overall, excellently. Both navigated most obstacles I put in their path — from shoes to cables to socks and other cruft. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uOqku9"&gt;The main difference in my testing was how it avoided an object. Both bots reacted reliably about 90 percent of the time to things that could derail them. But the Samsung always got up close and personal with the item before moving on; the Roomba would get closer to some than others — seemingly having a better idea of exactly what it was approaching. (The Roomba also has a small, white LED light that turns on when it’s navigating to help it see objects. You can’t turn this light off.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NXsMab"&gt;This was particularly true with dog poop. If poop was spotted it would do a rather dramatic about-turn or swift reversal and give the said excrement a decently wide berth. On the other hand, the Samsung would maneuver around it, trying to clean everywhere but the spot it sits on. This meant it got way too close and would probably take a small souvenir with it as it brushed up against it. (Our test poop was made from play putty, much less squishy than the real thing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7fgCqD7jHhpNKPHnpHmkTyS8Bg4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23168886/Roomba_J7_app.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The iRobot app controls the Roomba. It maps the space, and then you manually add clean zones (such as the kitchen counter). When it encounters an obstacle, it takes a photo for you to review. Or it will cancel the run if it thinks it can’t get around it safely.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cd3X8f"&gt;The Roomba also impressed me over Samsung in terms of how it used its intelligence. They both take pictures of the objects it finds (yes, including poop) and but the Roomba gives you the option to automatically create a keep-out zone in the app, so it doesn’t go there again (which worked excellently for a lounge chair whose skinny legs repeatedly trip up every floor bot I’ve tested). Or, if it’s just a temporary problem, you can mark it as so. It will even go back after and clean just the places it missed — once you’ve tidied up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HBJn5n"&gt;The Samsung robot flags objects on the map, shows an image, and offers up a guess as to what it was (there are three recurring options — sock / towel, cup / plate, and electrical cord). But beyond that, it doesn’t do anything about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div id="89yCxR"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Roomba j7 vs dog poop doesn_t end well|105541" data-volume-uuid="74b281d47" data-volume-id="105541" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="true" id="volume-placement-638" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="caption"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The one time in our testing that the Roomba failed the ultimate test.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NCxFdr"&gt;However, when it came to the ultimate test — poop — in the repeated trials I put them through, the only robot that actually went over the fake poop was the Roomba. Granted, it only failed once out of about a dozen tests, but once is all it takes.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="OoF4yX"&gt;Peak performance &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="cy6ofC"&gt;Both these bots delivered in terms of seamless, methodical navigation that covered the majority of the space while sucking up most of the debris from my hardwood floors. The Roomba edged the Samsung as its side brush meant it reached the dirt along the edges better (the Jet Bot doesn’t have a side brush, but its square shape lets it get closer to edges), and it is the more powerful, picking up some smaller debris the Samsung missed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AKJp3x"&gt;But the Roomba is a bruiser. Even with a new feature, “Sight Touch,” that supposedly more gently navigates and encounters obstacles than previous generation Roombas, the j7 took out a piece of (styrofoam) quarter-round trim from my baseboard. On the other hand, the Jet Bot is almost too cautious, not getting close enough to some objects to clean properly around them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oQcJuo"&gt;Each robot can suck harder when it goes over non-plush carpet (neither cope well with high-pile, a common issue with robot vacs). In testing, both performed well, with the Roomba edging the Samsung on dog hair, likely thanks to its two rubber brushes that oscillate in opposite directions, whereas the Samsung has just one large bristle brush. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KAon7O_SAR71poIu0uz8o9C44P8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23163822/vtuohy_210921_4963_0005.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Samsung vac ditches wheels for tank-like treads that are impressive at getting over things (but not so good for going under).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JyMalS"&gt;The Roomba was also more reliable at navigating thresholds, just barreling over them immediately, whereas the Jet Bot AI Plus had to check them out for a minute or two, approaching and backing away before deciding it was safe to proceed. With its tank-like treads instead of wheels, however, it sailed right over.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HDpXYw"&gt;Speaking of suction — this isn’t iRobot’s most powerful sucker; that award goes to the more expensive top dog in the lineup, the $1,099 &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/iRobot-Automatic-Disposal-Connected-Anti-Allergen/dp/B07QXM2V6X?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Roomba s9 Plus&lt;/a&gt; (including the dock/bin). iRobot does not release suction power stats but says that the j7 is 10 times stronger than its entry-level Roomba 600, whereas the s9 is 40 times stronger. The j7 is just fine for regular dirt and debris, and even if you have more challenging tasks (copious kitty litter, for example), it’s hard to recommend the $250 upgrade to the s9, as you don’t get the obstacle navigation features. In my testing of the s9, it routinely fell prey to socks and charging cables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1QJfuG8VegQiacijNdeUiIMt5Mg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23163827/vtuohy_211029_4963_0011.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Roomba has smaller wheels than the JetBot, but it still managed high thresholds. It uses a side brush and two rubber brushes for sucking up dirt.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8LO59O"&gt;Both vacuums are reasonably loud, and Roomba only has one setting (you can choose from three different “cleaning behaviors,” but they apparently all suck the same). Samsung has two suction levels, max and low — at the max level, both hit 73 decibels in my testing. And both sound like jet engines taking off when they empty their bins. The Jet Bot was the more reliable at emptying its bin, never once getting clogged, whereas I had to pull some clogs consisting of long fibers and hair out of the Roomba once or twice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="faxXLs"&gt;Where things diverge significantly is battery life — the Roomba can go an impressive 1 hour and 45 minutes on one charge, whereas the Jet Bot tops out at an hour on full power. Both will go back to the base, recharge, and resume, but the Jet Bot took almost twice as long to clean our entire downstairs living area as the Roomba because it had to recharge in the middle while the Roomba could do the whole space in one go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VK2auE"&gt;My other gripe with the Samsung is that it gets easily confused. If you pick it up while it’s running a job, it resets and forgets what it’s doing. It also occasionally would just stop mid-job and say there was a problem with its LiDAR sensor and to turn it off and on again. That would fix it, but it did this often enough for it to be really irritating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/B802tAJW7pILwPy0hrjqxhqlP3U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23163823/vtuohy_210921_4963_0007.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Samsung Jet Bot’s LiDAR and camera pop out of a tall cylinder at the back of the robot when it’s moving.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ATlZSjHsJumKucq5ieGtDSsoFXs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23163828/vtuohy_211029_4963_0012.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Roomba j7 has a camera right up front with an LED light that illuminates while it’s working.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id="dsVnqJ"&gt;Are they worth it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="aIYloL"&gt;Ultimately, the object navigation alone is probably not worth the price premium here. It’s not going to kill you to just tidy up a bit, is it? If you care about the home / pet monitoring feature, the Samsung gets more attractive, but its cleaning prowess just isn’t as good as the Roomba’s. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kqZKGr"&gt;There are other robots that offer home monitoring cameras (&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Objection-Recognition-Advanced-Programming-Efficiency/dp/B086214HTZ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ecovacs Deebot T8 AIVI&lt;/a&gt; has a built-in camera and costs almost $1,000 &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Auto-Empty-Automatically-Hands-Free-Cleaning-Accessory/dp/B08GHV4YFS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;with a self-emptying dock&lt;/a&gt;), but the Samsung SmartThings smart home ecosystem gives the Jet Bot the edge. And it has more advanced pet monitoring features (it will even play music to your pet to keep them calm).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qLFufN"&gt;If you are looking for the best clean for your buck and really want to avoid the possibility that the robot won’t finish its run because of a stray piece of clutter, the Roomba j7 is the one to go with here. I also like how repairable Roombas are. While parts are expensive, they are available, and you can basically rebuild your bot if needed, making this investment one that should last a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="qUftrj"&gt;Personally, I’m looking forward to the day that robot vacs sprout arms and actually remove the crap before they clean. And it may not be that far off. Samsung already has &lt;a href="https://news.samsung.com/global/get-a-glimpse-of-the-next-generation-innovations-on-display-at-samsungs-technology-showcase"&gt;arm-wielding bots&lt;/a&gt; for the kitchen, and Colin Angle, CEO of iRobot, tells me, “The home understanding and object recognition that today helps a Roomba do its job better will be the foundation for the next class of home robots that may, one day, have arms.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2xwmk6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22880352/irobot-roomba-j7-plus-samsung-jet-bot-ai-plus-robot-vacuum-review-comparison-test"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22880352/irobot-roomba-j7-plus-samsung-jet-bot-ai-plus-robot-vacuum-review-comparison-test</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-17T08:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-17T08:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to pick a new monitor for working from home</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3Gig4NRsEPFeWiWELbj3BOLWlyY=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70380094/VRG_ILL_4947_How_to_pick_a_new_monitor.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Samar Haddad / Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;You now interact with coworkers through a flat rectangle — let’s get you a larger, better one&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="wGPX49"&gt;The shift to remote work has sent millions scrambling to improve their home office. There are many ways to do this, but the most important upgrade is the most obvious: the monitor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CSkgqT"&gt;A monitor is key. You’ll use it hour after hour, day after day, year after year. Monitors even have the audacity to resist obsolescence, so the monitor you buy today might be the one you’re still using in a decade. (My editor and I both have decade-old Dell U2412 monitors that are still going strong.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="90T38A"&gt;It’s an important decision, but not a difficult one, as there are dozens of great monitors to choose from. This guide will help you pick the best for your home office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="lAypjJ"&gt;The sweet spot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="UAHB2f"&gt;I’ve reviewed monitors and laptop displays for over a decade. While different monitors suit different owners, I believe the &lt;em&gt;ideal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;home office monitor has a 27-inch screen and 4K resolution. It uses an IPS panel, reaches a brightness of at least 250 nits, and can display 99 percent of the sRGB color gamut. Around back you’ll find a USB-C port that can deliver enough power to charge a laptop, along with HDMI and DisplayPort, plus an ergonomic stand that can adjust for height and attaches to a VESA mount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EEg3lHG7XgzIvGr8zuzCeOUU9No=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161216/lg_ultrafine_27_inch.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: LG&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;For $550, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lg.com%2Fus%2Fmonitors%2Flg-27up850-w-uhd-monitor%23&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22877788%2Fbest-monitor-work-from-home-screen-choice-4k-qhd-refresh-rate-ultrawide" target="_blank" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener"&gt;&lt;em&gt;LG’s 27UP850-W&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; is a 27-inch 4K IPS monitor that can also provide 96W of power to a USB-C connected laptop. &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gDDTkS"&gt;Finding a monitor that ticks most of these boxes won’t be too difficult. &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lg.com%2Fus%2Fmonitors%2Flg-27up850-w-uhd-monitor&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22877788%2Fbest-monitor-work-from-home-screen-choice-4k-qhd-refresh-rate-ultrawide" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;LG’s UltraFine line&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100009682-12839518?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dell.com%2Fen-us%2Fshop%2Fmonitors%2Far%2F8141%2F25-27%3FappliedRefinements%3D24271%2C43205%2C40619%2C19973" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Dell’s USB-C hub monitors&lt;/a&gt;, BenQ’s &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/BenQ-PD2720U-Thunderbolt-Reproduction-Professionals/dp/B07N4M92P1?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;PD2720U&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/BenQ-PD2725U-Thunderbolt-Mac-Ready-Accurate/dp/B0918QXTGN?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;PD2725U&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=7168&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=Verge&amp;amp;ued=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hp.com%2Fus-en%2Fshop%2Fpdp%2Fhp-u28-4k-hdr-monitor" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;HP’s U28&lt;/a&gt; can check them all. Only the price may be higher than you hope; snagging any of the above will cost at least $450. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JwQwzH"&gt;But like I said, different monitors suit different owners. These monitors are ideal for work, but they’re expensive. They also lack features you’ll crave when it’s time to clock out and fire up a round of &lt;em&gt;Valorant&lt;/em&gt;. This guide will help you navigate the monitor world’s many caveats and find one that’s a fit for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vI4kHK"&gt;Size: 27-inch is best for most&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="iiJpVl"&gt;A monitor’s most important trait is its most basic: the size. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UcjDKI"&gt;Most standard-width monitors come in one of three sizes: 24-inch, 27-inch, and 32-inch. Bigger is not necessarily better. A large display may look more impressive, but I find it uncomfortable when placed close to my eyes. There are also practical considerations like perceived pixel density. A big monitor will look fuzzier than a smaller monitor of the same resolution unless you move it further away — which isn’t always an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fYLzYk"&gt;That’s why a 27-inch monitor is my go-to recommendation. It’s large enough to look impressive on a typical home office desk but isn’t excessive. In my experience, 32-inch monitors should be reserved for unusually large and deep desks, or corner setups where it’s possible to position the display around four feet away from your face. This is especially true for 32-inch monitors with a resolution below 4K, which look grainy to me at a distance of three feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/t9XBWjLFFLhrg0E8lTn-K88eV6w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161224/e1be7ffa_52fb_4a42_9454_64f151c20698.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: HP&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08BF4CZSV/?tag=theverge02-20" target="_blank" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The HP 24mh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; is a decent entry-level 24-inch 1080p monitor for $175. &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="P9Fuwg"&gt;For the same reasons, 24-inch monitors work better if you have a small, slim desk (say, around 24 inches deep or less) or otherwise bring the monitor closer to your face. A 24-inch monitor may sound small, but it’ll look reasonably large because it’s so close. They’re also a great way to save money. You can buy a decent all-around monitor &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08BF4CZSV/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;like the HP 24mh&lt;/a&gt; for less than $200. It won’t wow you, but it works in a pinch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qT8Q1a"&gt;You can be creative with size if you mount a VESA-compatible monitor to an arm, as this will let you move it to your preference (including the proper ergonomic height). If you’re just doing it to move a large monitor farther away, though, give it a second thought. Why spend more for a larger monitor, and a monitor arm to position it farther away, instead of buying a smaller display to start? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B7XdTt"&gt;If you’re looking to stretch more screen across your field of view for multitasking, you might consider an ultrawide monitor instead. There, I think the choice is clear: go for a 34-incher. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nAwLT4"&gt;Smaller models lack vertical space. A 29-inch ultrawide &lt;a href="http://www.displaywars.com/29-inch-21x9-vs-24-inch-16x9"&gt;has less vertical display space than a 24-inch widescreen&lt;/a&gt;. Larger models generally have the opposite problem. Many are too big for a typical home office desk, not only because of their screen size, but because of the large stands used to stabilize them (some are several feet wide). You might need to rearrange your desk around a 38-inch or 43-inch monitor or add a top-tier monitor arm to make it work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JnfeQk"&gt;What about super-ultrawides, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21590961/samsung-odyssey-g9-review-ultrawide-monitor-price-specs"&gt;like the 49-inch Samsung Odyssey G9 series&lt;/a&gt;? These monitors can offer a commanding view and are a good alternative to a double or triple monitor setup but, like big ultrawides, you’ll need to build your setup around it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SnGk8XSIJDiK16hoGSTwflnPp4k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22026746/shollister_201030_42850003.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;You might need to rearrange your entire desk around a super-ultrawide like the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.theverge.com/21590961/samsung-odyssey-g9-review-ultrawide-monitor-price-specs" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung Odyssey G9.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="eXO4Nl"&gt;Resolution: 4K is great, 1440p is practical&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="7heyE7"&gt;Resolution is key. A higher resolution means more pixels, and more pixels means a sharper, crisper image. More pixels also adds flexibility. You can use scaling features in Windows and MacOS to increase content size for readability, or crank it down to show more content at once. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1LPxN1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4K resolution&lt;/strong&gt; (3,840 x 2,160) looks fantastic and is widely available on 27-inch and 32-inch displays. It’s not that expensive, either. Budget 4K 27-inch monitors like &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-8836598-12839518?sid=Verge&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dell.com%2Fen-us%2Fshop%2Fdell-27-4k-uhd-monitor-s2721qs%2Fapd%2F210-axlg%2Fmonitors-monitor-accessories" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the Dell S2721QS&lt;/a&gt; can get you 4K for $350 or less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8AJmp_FpuoWrmUpNum1lOFE7lWk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161240/dell_s2721qs.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Dell&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.dell.com/en-us/shop/dell-27-4k-uhd-monitor-s2721qs/apd/210-axlg/monitors-monitor-accessories" target="_blank" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dell S2721QS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; is a solid budget pick for a 27-inch 4K IPS monitor at under $350. A USB-C version costs a good bit more.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5lrhOK"&gt;With that said, settling for &lt;strong&gt;1440p (2,560 x 1,440)&lt;/strong&gt; can save money. It’s a bit disappointing on a 32-inch display, unless you move it far away, but it’s workable. A 27-inch 1440p display can look reasonably sharp and is a good choice if you personally don’t care about having the sharpest picture possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D7eFOt"&gt;You should probably avoid &lt;strong&gt;1080p (1,920 x 1,080)&lt;/strong&gt; in a 27-inch or 32-inch monitor, however. It will look grainy and pixelated. Small fonts and interface elements (such as buttons) can become difficult to see. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9Vqort"&gt;Twenty-four-inch monitors are a different story; 4K is rare, and 1440p is often the premium option. In fact, most monitors of this size are 1080p. It’s not ideal but it’s acceptable, as decreasing size increases pixel density. A 24-inch 1080p monitor is noticeably sharper than a 27-inch 1080p monitor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sU3Oi5"&gt;Want a 34-inch ultrawide? Look for 3,440 x 1,440 resolution. This leads to a pixel density nearly identical to a 27-inch 1440p monitor (about 109 pixels per inch). A handful of super-budget ultrawides use 2,560 x 1,080 resolution which, like 1080p on a large monitor, isn’t pleasant. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2017/12/21/16804850/lg-hdr-5k-ultrawide-monitor-ces-specs"&gt;LG’s 5K Ultrawide line&lt;/a&gt; is the sole option if you want 4K-equivalent pixel density in a 34-inch ultrawide, but you’ll typically pay $1,500 or more. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0892MHG9H?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;LG’s well-reviewed 38-inch with 3,840 x 1,600 resolution&lt;/a&gt; costs even more at $1,600 and, though it might offer more screen, is equal in pixel density to a 3,440 x 1,440 ultrawide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eTbpHk"&gt;Super-ultrawides also don’t offer much choice. All 49-inch super-ultrawides I’m aware of use the same 5,120 x 1,440 resolution which, again, roughly equals the pixel density of a 1440p 27-inch display. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="4iOM4R"&gt;Connectivity: USB-C is excellent but expensive &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="BgYTLi"&gt;Most monitors have HDMI and DisplayPort. There’s no great reason to prefer one over the other for remote work. The huge majority of monitors sold today offer both, so the port you use will likely come down to what’s available on your PC. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yXUJwca70nDbgIfTLAQ98BHSdg4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161266/lg_monitor_connections.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: LG&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This LG monitor has four video inputs, from top left to bottom left: Thunderbolt / USB-C, DisplayPort, and a pair of HDMIs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lIL7K9"&gt;What about HDMI 2.1? It’s not necessary for remote work, and productivity monitors with HDMI 2.1 aren’t yet a thing. Be warned that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/13/22833233/hdmi-2-1-fake-marketing-brand-frl-vrr-allm-bandwidth"&gt;HDMI 2.1 could get messy in 2022 due to the standard’s lax certification&lt;/a&gt;. It’s key only if you want to connect a PlayStation 5 or Xbox Series X game console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vUIXtw"&gt;If you’ve got extra cash to spend, the galaxy-brain move is to ignore HDMI and DisplayPort entirely and leap to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/usb-c"&gt;USB-C&lt;/a&gt; and/or Thunderbolt. USB-C and Thunderbolt are great because they allow a single-cable solution for modern laptops that support the standard. You can plug in the laptop and charge it from the monitor while sending video to the monitor simultaneously. The best USB-C monitors even act as a hub with multiple extra ports like USB-A, USB-C, and ethernet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q8ScKeVeijxOihxafdrXZjLz7iI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161289/dell_hub_monitor_27_inch.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Dell&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The underside of this 27-inch Dell USB-C Hub Monitor is bristling with connectivity, much of it accessible via a single USB-C cable that also provides 90W of charging.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="c8MGb1"&gt;Just make sure you check the fine print. Look for USB-C with DisplayPort Alternate Mode and Power Delivery, or Thunderbolt with Power Delivery (the standard has DisplayPort baked in). Those sorts of USB-C ports aren’t exactly uncommon on laptops: even the modest ThinkPad E545 I bought a few years back includes them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bFZlY2"&gt;But you’ll also need to make sure the monitor you buy provides enough electricity. Power Delivery currently maxes out at 100 watts, so even the most powerful monitors can’t fully power laptops like a top-spec Razer Blade or high-end MacBook Pro 16, but a monitor that delivers 60 watts or even 45 watts might be enough if you have a thin-and-light laptop like a Dell XPS 13 or MacBook Air. The higher the better, but if the USB-C monitor doesn’t deliver as much power as your laptop’s power brick, your battery might only charge when it’s idle or even powered off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C5youF"&gt;USB-C monitors are also expensive. The benefits often add several hundred dollars to the price when compared to an otherwise similar monitor that lacks USB-C. It’s worth the money, though: in 2019, I purchased a Viewsonic VG2455-2K for a sweet one-cable connection to USB-C capable laptops, and find it ideal for swiftly connecting my laptop to a larger screen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="0U3Lel"&gt;Ergonomics: The height has it &lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ox8h7l"&gt;Any monitor worth your attention will have a stand that at least adjusts for height, usually along a range from 100 to 150 millimeters. Sure, you can stack it on books or buy a plastic riser, but that’s added hassle and clutter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CC5Gs6"&gt;Many monitors also adjust for tilt and swivel, and some pivot 90 degrees into portrait orientation. That can be particularly handy when a monitor is used as a second display. For example, you could swivel a monitor to directly face you while doing detailed work, like editing a photo, and swing it away when it’s just displaying Slack or Discord. Tilt is similar but on the vertical axis, and especially handy if you have a standing desk, as you may need to tilt the monitor up while the desk is standing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Cao8nRaGJLy_0rHQwAXJSPJI-L0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161307/fully_jarvis_monitor_arm.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Fully&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.fully.com%2Fjarvis-monitor-arm.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22877788%2Fbest-monitor-work-from-home-screen-choice-4k-qhd-refresh-rate-ultrawide" target="_blank" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener"&gt;&lt;em&gt;$129 Fully Jarvis Monitor Arm&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; is a well-reviewed arm with a 15-year warranty.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Yrkdaa"&gt;But if your monitor doesn’t have enough range of motion, or you want to free up space on your desk, you could instead add a VESA-compatible monitor arm to get it off the ground. Look for monitors with a 100mm x 100mm VESA spacing pattern. This is an extremely common feature found in all but the most affordable monitors, and you only need to worry about the 100mm spacing pattern. Others exist, but are relevant to other types of displays (like televisions). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mabdrf"&gt;A monitor arm is rarely a necessity, but it’s great for multi-monitor setups that place secondary displays around and above your main monitor, or for positioning an especially large and bulky monitor. Unfortunately, monitor arms can also be a bit expensive. A basic monitor arm off Amazon can run $30 to $50, but I’ve been burnt on their quality in the past. A good arm like those from Jarvis or Ergotron will start around $130. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3bJ6Ic"&gt;Larger, heavier monitors will need a beefier, more expensive arm: &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ergotron.com%2Fen-us%2Fproducts%2Fproduct-details%2F45-647%23%3Fcolor%3Dwhite&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22877788%2Fbest-monitor-work-from-home-screen-choice-4k-qhd-refresh-rate-ultrawide" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the model Ergotron recommends&lt;/a&gt; for the 49-inch Samsung Odyssey Neo G9 is currently $379 (and, at the time I wrote this, sold out!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="N4eOu0"&gt;Color accuracy and gamut&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="6vzW0r"&gt;Color accuracy is critical to image quality. An inaccurate monitor will look unnatural, flat, and dull, with strange swings in quality depending on what you’re viewing and the precise colors that are inaccurate (it’s common for monitors to be less accurate in blue or cyan than other colors, for example). A monitor with terrible color will disappoint you every time you sit down to use it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0v7qBg"&gt;The good news? Accuracy is low-key the greatest advancement in monitors over the last decade. Noticeably inaccurate displays were common when I began testing monitors well over a decade ago. Today, most midrange monitors have reasonable accuracy straight out of the box. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Aq61gYhXRcpliCv8GgXSKn5VR7I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161335/Datacolor_SpyderX_5_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Datacolor&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;If color is key for work, you probably already know you can buy a calibration tool like &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Datacolor-SpyderX-Pro-Calibration-Photographers/dp/B07M6KPJ9K?tag=theverge02-20" target="_blank" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener"&gt;&lt;em&gt;this $160 Spyder&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6qnFAV"&gt;Still, there is a difference between midrange and premium monitors. Those who want great color accuracy should look for a “factory calibrated” monitor, which typically includes a calibration report in the box. This doesn’t guarantee color accuracy is perfect, but it at least shows the company put the monitor through an extra layer of quality assurance. Also check reviewers to see if the monitor lives up to its claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gkYFhz"&gt;Color gamut, which describes the spectrum of colors a monitor can display, is also good enough on most monitors. The majority of content on a computer targets a color gamut called sRGB. Modern monitors display at least 95 percent of this gamut, and many display it all. Other gamuts also exist. DCI-P3 is the most advertised, though you may see Rec.709 or Adobe RGB as well. These gamuts are important if your work requires them, though if that’s the case, I’m guessing you know that. As with color accuracy, buyers concerned about gamut should read reviews to verify a monitor lives up to its claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="OZjl76"&gt;Brightness and HDR: 250 nits or bust&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="kdrkF0"&gt;Odds are your home office has some form of light control, whether it’s shades or simply a room that’s naturally a bit dim. The ideal brightness will vary based on the lighting in your home office, but a monitor’s brightness rarely needs to exceed 200 nits. In fact, most monitor calibration tools (like a SpyderX Elite I use) have a built-in luminance sensor used to recommend a brightness based on ambient light. I’ve never seen it recommend more than 200 nits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FJbR8D"&gt;That’s not a big ask, but budget monitors can’t always manage it, so be careful if you’re shopping on a tight budget. Manufacturers also tend to choose a best-case scenario when quoting brightness, so the listed brightness may not always be available. Buy a monitor that promises a maximum brightness of at least 250 nits (aka cd/m2). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TRd08W"&gt;Why would you want a brighter monitor? Well, if you’re viewing SDR content, there’s no particular reason (aside from using a monitor in a very, very bright room which, though rare, does happen). Viewing SDR content at a high brightness (say, 300 nits or more) might look nice at a glance, but can cause image quality issues like disappointing dark levels and reduced overall contrast. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Wy9en"&gt;High Dynamic Range, aka HDR, is a different story. This standard supports a way higher range of luminosity than SDR. HDR10, the most common standard, technically allows for a peak brightness up to 10,000 nits. Brightness does matter for HDR because the content includes additional luminance data that only HDR-compatible displays can show. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-8J1DXnEoyBKjQj7zI4HAhBeZco=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23161359/display_hdr.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are looking for an HDR monitor, DisplayHDR certification labels could help, but know that “peak luminance” means “a tiny region on screen can get that bright,” and DisplayHDR 400 is barely HDR at all. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="i6nGwE"&gt;However, HDR is a bit of a minefield on the PC and can be counterproductive for work. Turning on HDR in Windows will often block a number of monitor controls you may need, including brightness, color gamut, and color temperature settings. The resulting image can appear eye-searingly bright and you’ll have less leeway to adjust it to your preferences. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tHzZxH"&gt;Also, most content viewed in Windows or MacOS is not designed for HDR. You can still view it, but the result will be less accurate than if you stuck with SDR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6wA1sJ"&gt;Entertainment and gaming is where HDR redeems itself. Most streaming platforms now offer a method for viewing HDR content on a PC and many new 3D games include HDR support. Windows 11 even has an auto-HDR feature that can add HDR to games that don’t officially support it. This makes HDR a nice addition to a monitor that you’ll use for work and play — though I’d recommend leaving HDR off until you clock out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ViS8Xv"&gt;Panel type: IPS rules the office&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="LdNhyo"&gt;Nearly all monitors sold today use an LCD panel based on one of three technologies: twisted nematic (TN), in-plane switching (IPS), and vertical alignment (VA). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZfnpKQ"&gt;The least expensive monitors often use a TN panel. Avoid them. TN panel monitors will display an image, but that’s about it. They look achingly dull next to IPS and have astoundingly bad viewing angles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vfYHTG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10972881"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5P315m"&gt;A majority of monitors use IPS. Monitors based on IPS have very accurate color and can support a wide color gamut at a reasonable price. IPS struggles with dark scenes, however, because it can’t achieve a convincing shade of black. This is the dreaded “IPS glow” you may have heard of, which can look unappealing when watching movies or playing games. However, gamers still enjoy IPS monitors because some IPS panels have low response times and very high refresh rates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lgp0Oc"&gt;What about VA? This panel type has the best contrast ratio and dark scene performance of the three, which makes VA a great go-to choice for entertainment and gaming. This is especially true of high-quality, modern VA panels, which have mostly solved the color accuracy and motion smearing issues of some past VA monitors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k8cy3S"&gt;The choice between IPS and VA has no clear answer, as both have their perks. When it comes to work, though, you may find the choice is made for you. A huge majority of productivity monitors use an IPS panel. VA is an option, but you’ll want to lean your search toward gaming monitors if you crave the high contrast a quality VA panel can provide. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="fTKjWK"&gt;Refresh rate: Higher is better, but there’s a compromise&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="a8tZWb"&gt;AMD and Nvidia have successfully convinced gamers that a 360Hz monitor is ideal. But what if your day includes more Excel than &lt;em&gt;Counter-Strike&lt;/em&gt;? You might still see some benefits from a refresh rate higher than the traditional 60Hz. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dvLvLB"&gt;Gaming is often &lt;em&gt;the &lt;/em&gt;reason to buy a monitor with an enhanced refresh rate. Higher refresh rates lead to smoother, more fluid motion and reduces input lag. That said, the benefits of refresh rate are not restricted to games. Higher rates make motion feel more fluid on the desktop as well, which is why Apple’s newest MacBook Pro 14 and 16, and many Windows laptops, now offer a refresh rate of 120Hz or more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WKoTfK"&gt;I feel it’s nice to have, but far down on the list of features you need to consider. Also, you probably shouldn’t pay extra for a 75Hz monitor — it’s not much gain over 60Hz. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BGvD6q"&gt;High-refresh gaming displays aren’t especially expensive, with 24-inch, 144Hz models sold for as little as $200. But you’ll typically trade something away for refresh rate: that $200 monitor might use an iffy TN panel (rather than IPS or VA) or feature a low resolution. It’s possible to snag a 4K display for a reasonable sum, or one with a high refresh rate, but going for 4K at 144Hz means looking at monitors that cost as much as big televisions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kFBvhd"&gt;Also, USB-C with Power Delivery is rarely found in gaming monitors, and I haven’t seen a USB-C gaming monitor that doubles as a USB-C hub. That could be an issue if your work setup involves a lot of wired peripherals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="x9XJnN"&gt;Mini LED and OLED&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="gPsTP7"&gt;Nearly all monitors sold today use an LCD panel with an LED backlight behind it, a tried-and-true setup that has existed for decades. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jMwskl"&gt;Mini LED adds a twist. The fundamentals remain similar, but the backlight is divided into hundreds of zones that can turn on and off independently. This allows extra brightness but also convincing contrast in shadowy scenes. Mini LED is also outstanding for HDR movies and games, where its class-leading brightness provides an edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ko6WMo"&gt;OLED? It flips the table, using an array of organic elements that create their own light. This provides pixel-level lighting control for truly unparalleled contrast you have to see to believe. OLED is also susceptible to burn-in, though there are ways to mitigate it from affecting a display prematurely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TVNZUbmRtKaTOijhZ2dVAn4zaUU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23040339/shollister_211124_4893_0008.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;We tried a 48-inch OLED TV as a monitor this past year &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22815110/lg-c1-48-oled-samsung-odyssey-neo-g9-review-monitor-tv" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;with mixed results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ho3Efk"&gt;Neither of these are necessary for working from home, and you’ll likely have to spend thousands to snag a monitor with either tech. Alternatively, you could buy a television with Mini LED or OLED technology, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22815110/lg-c1-48-oled-samsung-odyssey-neo-g9-review-monitor-tv"&gt;but televisions still have their downsides as monitors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZspQlB"&gt;If you demand the very best from a monitor, however, I recommend Mini LED. OLED’s burn-in worries are legitimate on the PC which, compared to a television, will display static images more frequently. Mini LED can’t match OLED’s contrast, but it’s still a major upgrade over a backlit LCD screen. There’s also the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22865220/sony-a95k-qd-oled-qdoled-4k-tv-announced-features-explainer"&gt;emerging&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22855531/alienware-curved-34-inch-qd-oled-samsung-gaming-monitor-specs"&gt;category&lt;/a&gt; of quantum dot OLED (QD-OLED) screens, but manufacturers haven’t announced prices for those yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="WGugUM"&gt;What about monitors with built-in webcams?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="0qMFfY"&gt;Do not buy a monitor with a built-in webcam. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H1YHiM"&gt;Webcams are small, easy to move, and can be used with multiple devices. Attaching a webcam to a monitor removes these perks. It also means you can’t upgrade your webcam in the future; you’ll have to replace the entire monitor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="BH1Uyy"&gt;Our webcam guide has several recommendations. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22652783/best-webcam-camera"&gt;Most are less than $100&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22877788/best-monitor-work-from-home-screen-choice-4k-qhd-refresh-rate-ultrawide"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22877788/best-monitor-work-from-home-screen-choice-4k-qhd-refresh-rate-ultrawide</id>
    <author>
      <name>Matt Smith</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-17T06:33:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-17T06:33:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon reverses decision to ban Visa credit cards in the UK over fees</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="VISA" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0E7Swrfg_tE0QVJf3fYtnldIb60=/38x0:4963x3283/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70399286/1237281038.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Silas Stein/picture alliance via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5vY4gi"&gt;Amazon says it will continue to accept payment in the UK from Visa credit cards, reversing a decision to ban the cards that was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22786966/amazon-visa-credit-card-ban-alternatives-fees"&gt;announced last November&lt;/a&gt; and due to kick in this week on Wednesday, January 19th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fjWQn1"&gt;In an email to customers, Amazon said it was “working closely on a potential solution that will enable customers to continue using their Visa credit cards on Amazon.co.uk.” The company did not say what the solution was or how long it might be in place, but added that “should we make any changes related to Visa credit cards, we will give you advance notice.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="5P5yYf"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Visa raised interchange fees five-fold after the UK left the EU&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pl1lPT"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22786966/amazon-visa-credit-card-ban-alternatives-fees"&gt;original decision&lt;/a&gt; to ban Visa credit cards on Amazon.co.uk arose from a dispute over payment fees levied by card issuers. The European Union sets limits on these particular fees, but when the UK left the EU it gave issuers free rein to increase them. Visa &lt;a href="https://thepaypers.com/online-payments/visa-raises-interchange-fees-for-uk-based-cardholders--1247923"&gt;raised its interchange fees&lt;/a&gt; from 0.3 percent to 1.5 percent, which evidently annoyed Amazon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OmEBRL"&gt;Although it’s not clear what deal has been brokered between Amazon and Visa and who it favors, it was Visa’s &lt;a href="https://www.investors.com/news/visa-stock-tumbles-amazon-plans-stop-accepting-its-u-k-issued-credit-cards/"&gt;stock that dropped&lt;/a&gt; after the ban was initially announced. As &lt;a href="https://news.sky.com/story/amazon-drops-date-to-stop-accepting-visa-credit-cards-for-uk-payments-12518264"&gt;per &lt;em&gt;Sky News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Visa said in a statement: “Amazon customers can continue to use Visa cards on Amazon.co.uk after 19 January while we work closely together to reach an agreement.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/17/22887637/amazon-uk-visa-credit-card-ban-reversed-deal"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/17/22887637/amazon-uk-visa-credit-card-ban-reversed-deal</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-17T05:49:59-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-17T05:49:59-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft lets you follow YouTube creators in Edge browser test</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Fn78VxzmVwXFqnwZtUPpDWLxsF4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70399206/acastro_200207_3900_Edge_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DAfS61"&gt;Microsoft has started testing some deeper YouTube integration in its Edge browser. The latest Canary developer builds of Edge include a new “followable web” feature that lets you easily follow your favorite content creators on YouTube. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EiL86G"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MicrosoftEdge/comments/rz71jh/edge_canary_now_lets_you_follow_some_of_your/"&gt;Reddit user Leopeva64 spotted&lt;/a&gt; a new YouTube follow button that appears in the address bar of YouTube pages. Following creators will add them to a feed that’s part of the Collections feature in Edge. The feature is clearly in the early preview stages, and it doesn’t support all YouTube content creators just yet. The feed that’s created in Collections lets you see recent posts from creators that you follow.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PoVZ9FMhXwl0bYfS5SmQUDUnK_A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23174192/edgefollowing.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MicrosoftEdge/comments/rz71jh/edge_canary_now_lets_you_follow_some_of_your/" target="_blank"&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt; (Leopeva64)&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new web following feature in Edge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="NrwDMG"&gt;This deeper integration with YouTube will likely extend to other parts of the web, too. Microsoft’s Edge followable web feature looks similar to Google’s &lt;a href="https://blog.chromium.org/2021/05/an-experiment-in-helping-users-and-web.html?m=1"&gt;experimental feature in Chrome&lt;/a&gt; that lets people follow blogs and creators to get the latest content when it’s published. This is essentially an extension of RSS inside Chrome, and it includes a follow button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="olz5SS"&gt;Microsoft is only trialing this new Edge feature with a limited number of Edge Canary testers, as part of what the company calls “controlled rollouts.” The software giant hasn’t officially detailed its plans for the followable web feature in Edge, but we’re expecting to hear more about this modern RSS feed in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/17/22887626/microsoft-edge-youtube-intergration-following-feature-canary-test"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/17/22887626/microsoft-edge-youtube-intergration-following-feature-canary-test</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-17T05:00:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-17T05:00:38-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple digital keys reportedly coming to some Hyundai cars this summer</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Launch Of Hyundai Motor Company’s All-New Genesis In Seoul" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SfdEivnIMZV3kc1Edqsn1Bhzhyg=/95x0:2906x1874/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70399186/452075859.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hyundai’s Genesis cars could soon get access to the feature.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Chung Sung-Jun/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WTe4XF"&gt;Hyundai and its Genesis brand are reportedly close to adding support for Apple’s digital car key feature, which lets you unlock and start compatible vehicles using the iPhone’s Wallet app, according to &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2022-01-16/what-will-apple-aapl-call-its-new-ar-vr-headset-apple-vision-apple-reality-kyhmibia"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg’s&lt;/em&gt; Mark Gurman&lt;/a&gt;. According to Gurman, the so-called “CarKey” feature is set to come to Hyundai’s Genesis lineup this summer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bOF2SK"&gt;Hyundai already offers proprietary iOS apps, including &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/myhyundai-with-bluelink/id893514610"&gt;MyHyundai with Bluelink&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/genesis-intelligent-assistant/id867941329"&gt;Genesis Intelligent Assistant&lt;/a&gt;, which include the ability to remotely start, or unlock the doors of compatible vehicles. But adding support for Apple’s implementation of the digital key feature should make the functionality more seamless, and benefit from system-level Apple Wallet shortcuts. &lt;a href="https://owners.hyundaiusa.com/us/en/resources/technology-and-navigation/frequently-asked-questions-about-hyundai-digital-key.html"&gt;Hyundai’s site&lt;/a&gt; notes that its NFC-based digital key feature is currently only available on Android phones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="JdaKwA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;References to Hyundai have previously been discovered in iOS code&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MnE6MA"&gt;Apple first announced its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/22/21299182/apple-carkey-ios-14-13-digital-key-unlock-car-iphone-wwdc-2020"&gt;digital car key feature in 2020&lt;/a&gt;, but so far it’s only available on select BMW models. Reports that it would be coming to Hyundai’s cars date back to at least January 2021 when &lt;a href="http://www.businesskorea.co.kr/news/articleView.html?idxno=58446"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Business Korea&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; on the plans, and reference’s to Hyundai’s Genesis cars &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/09/21/genesis-digital-car-keys-code/"&gt;have also been discovered in iOS 15 code&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jbuKMs"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;’s report doesn’t specify whether Hyundai plans to make use of recent iPhones’ ultra wideband (UWB) technology, which could allow owners to unlock their car without having to take their phone out of their pocket, or whether it will just use NFC. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22230569/bmw-digital-key-plus-iphone-unlock-u1-chip-ultra-wideband"&gt;BMW previously announced&lt;/a&gt; the feature for its all-electric iX, relying on the U1 chip found in the iPhone 11 and later. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5dGDqG"&gt;Apple and Hyundai were previously rumored to be in discussions to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22261893/apple-electric-car-hyundai-ming-chi-kuo-rumor-report"&gt;produce an electric car together&lt;/a&gt;. Hyundai later &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/7/22271748/hyundai-apple-car-talks-stopped-report"&gt;downplayed these rumors&lt;/a&gt;, and said it was no longer in talks with the iPhone manufacturer. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/17/22887601/apple-digital-carkey-support-hyundai-and-genesis-cars-report"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/17/22887601/apple-digital-carkey-support-hyundai-and-genesis-cars-report</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-17T04:11:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-17T04:11:26-05:00</updated>
    <title>Oppo’s next flagship leaks with OnePlus-esque Hasselblad branding</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7_ICSM7Op5l5KT4vHKed6DGZn9o=/0x0:2000x1333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70399142/1eaf989963bd7d4e0ee82817325daf47.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uI1jRl"&gt;Details on Oppo’s upcoming flagship phone are starting to come together. Multiple leaks are suggesting it’ll be called the Find X5 Pro, with a similar design to last year’s Find X3 Pro and specs broadly in line with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/6/22865569/oneplus-10-pro-camera-specs"&gt;the new OnePlus 10 Pro&lt;/a&gt;, which is already available in China. (OnePlus, of course, is now treated as a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/21/22543184/oppo-oneplus-merger-brand-pete-lau-bbk-memo"&gt;sub-brand of Oppo&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hjJTG2"&gt;The Find X3 Pro wasn’t sold in the US, but it did make its way to Europe and was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22411538/oppo-find-x3-pro-review"&gt;one of the best phones of 2021&lt;/a&gt;. Renders recently &lt;a href="https://prepp.in/news/e-509-oppo-find-x5-2022-launch-exclusive-5k-renders-expected-dates-specifications-and-more"&gt;released by OnLeaks&lt;/a&gt; show a device with a camera bump that flows into the rest of the back panel in a similar fashion to the Find X3 Pro, although the camera configuration has changed and doesn’t appear to include the previous phone’s unique ring light-equipped “microscope” camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="33Hpar"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/OPPO?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#OPPO&lt;/a&gt; Find X5 Pro&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- Snapdragon 8 Gen1&lt;br&gt;- 2K 120HZ refresh rate LTPO 2.0 display&lt;br&gt;- 50MP IMX766 OIS + 50MP IMX766 + 13MP S5K3M5&lt;br&gt;- 5000mAh battery&lt;br&gt;80 watt wired charging&lt;br&gt;50 watt wireless charging&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Actual Source:&lt;a href="https://t.co/IGsScfYEsN"&gt;https://t.co/IGsScfYEsN&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/TTCaVuVbWZ"&gt;pic.twitter.com/TTCaVuVbWZ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Abhishek Yadav (@yabhishekhd) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/yabhishekhd/status/1482910986768031744?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 17, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SyCJBJ"&gt;Alleged real-world photos that corroborate the &lt;em&gt;OnLeaks&lt;/em&gt; renders have also now appeared online, showing a white model of the phone with Hasselblad branding, just like OnePlus’ latest flagships. There’s also a shot of the device’s settings menu that says it has a Qualcomm Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 processor, like the OnePlus 10 Pro, as well as Oppo’s own new chip, the MariSilicon X. This is an NPU used for image processing; it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22833796/oppo-air-glass-ar-glasses-announced-china-release-date"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; late last year alongside Oppo’s Air Glass AR device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vJnymw"&gt;There are other specs that have been floating around Chinese social media channels that can’t be verified but don’t sound very surprising, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22855743/oneplus-10-pro-android-specs"&gt;as with the OnePlus 10 Pro&lt;/a&gt;. Oppo’s previous two Find X flagships were announced in March, so we should get official details fairly soon.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/17/22887588/oppo-find-x5-leak-specs-photos-renders"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/17/22887588/oppo-find-x5-leak-specs-photos-renders</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-16T18:07:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-16T18:07:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>Walmart is getting serious about the metaverse</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6H65h2a75hlvo0cLGBbiKy2EOLI=/0x0:4603x3069/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70397592/1183648613.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Walmart’s recent trademark applications suggest that it wants to break into the metaverse. | Photo by Yichuan Cao / NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ilWdNY"&gt;Walmart appears to be getting ready for a leap into the metaverse. Recent trademark applications indicate the company is looking to establish its own NFTs and cryptocurrency, according to a report from &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2022/01/16/walmart-is-quietly-preparing-to-enter-the-metaverse.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KBOyr3"&gt;The retail giant filed for several trademarks on December 30th, suggesting plans to start selling virtual goods, including electronics, toys, appliances, sporting equipment, apparel, home decor, and more, as noted by &lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt;. There’s mention of offering customers a digital currency, as well as the opportunity to buy and sell NFTs. Meanwhile, another application details possible “physical fitness training services” and “classes in the field of health and nutrition” that could take place in augmented reality (AR) and virtual reality environments (VR) — the company made a separate filing for the use of its name and logo in VR and AR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Sd1bGV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Walmart also filed trademarks for “Verse to Home,” “Verse to Curb,” and “Verse to Store”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TaaFs4"&gt;As pointed out by &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-01-16/walmart-plans-to-create-cryptocurrency-and-nfts-cnbc-reports"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Walmart also filed trademarks for the names “Verse to Home,” “Verse to Curb,” and “Verse to Store,” a hint that Walmart may be preparing a virtual shopping experience (that hopefully doesn’t look like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2022/1/5/22868323/walmart-metaverse-shopping-video-viral-old"&gt;the one created for the company in 2017&lt;/a&gt;). The filings are publicly available on the US Patent and Trademark Office’s site, some of which are listed under the name “Walmart Connect,” the retailer’s digital advertising endeavor. You can access the filings by searching for “Walmart” or “Walmart Connect” on the &lt;a href="https://www.uspto.gov/trademarks/search"&gt;Trademark Electronic Search System&lt;/a&gt; (TESS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jI9uGl"&gt;“Walmart is continuously exploring how emerging technologies may shape future shopping experiences,” Walmart spokesperson Carrie McKnight told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “We don’t have anything further to share today, but it’s worth noting we routinely file trademark applications as part of the innovation process.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bPpCbc"&gt;Last August, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22627111/walmart-cryptocurrency-payments-hire-amazon"&gt;Walmart posted a job listing for a cryptocurrency product specialist&lt;/a&gt;, one of the first signs of Walmart’s growing interest in the metaverse. Other retailers are taking part in the metaverse movement as well, with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22833369/nike-rtfkt-nft-sneaker-shoe-metaverse-company"&gt;Nike looking to cash in on NFTs and virtual sneakers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/17/22843104/adidas-nfts-metaverse-sold-bored-ape"&gt;Adidas selling out of its &lt;em&gt;Into the Metaverse&lt;/em&gt; NFT collection&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.gapinc.com/en-us/articles/2022-1/01/gap-launches-gamified-collectible-nft-experience-t"&gt;Gap offering NFTs of its hoodies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/16/22887011/walmart-metaverse-nft-cryptocurrency"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/16/22887011/walmart-metaverse-nft-cryptocurrency</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-16T15:05:29-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-16T15:05:29-05:00</updated>
    <title>Safari 15 bug can leak your recent browsing activity and personal identifiers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q-QZjSU3L78a6LZ3zw-_6BJ96aI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70397170/acastro_200207_3900_Safari_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XYwPrx"&gt;A bug in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686070/apple-macos-safari-tab-groups-redesign-change-back"&gt;Safari 15&lt;/a&gt; can leak your browsing activity, and can also reveal some of the personal information attached to your Google account, according to &lt;a href="https://fingerprintjs.com/blog/indexeddb-api-browser-vulnerability-safari-15/"&gt;findings from FingerprintJS&lt;/a&gt;, a browser fingerprinting and fraud detection service (via &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2022/01/16/safari-bug-leak-browsing-history-info/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The vulnerability stems from an issue with Apple’s implementation of &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/IndexedDB_API"&gt;IndexedDB&lt;/a&gt;, an application programming interface (API) that stores data on your browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QQC8Ia"&gt;As explained by FingerprintJS, IndexedDB abides by the &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Security/Same-origin_policy"&gt;same-origin policy&lt;/a&gt;, which restricts one origin from interacting with data that was collected on other origins — essentially, only the website that generates data can access it. For example, if you open your email account in one tab and then open a malicious webpage in another, the same-origin policy prevents the malicious page from viewing and meddling with your email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Ixhif6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There’s not much you can do to get around the issue&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IhMBJI"&gt;FingerprintJS found that Apple’s application of the IndexedDB API in Safari 15 actually violates the same-origin policy. When a website interacts with a database in Safari, FingerprintJS says that “a new (empty) database with the same name is created in all other active frames, tabs, and windows within the same browser session.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kHR6w5"&gt;This means other websites can see the name of other databases created on other sites, which could contain details specific to your identity. FingerprintJS notes sites that use your Google account, like YouTube, Google Calendar, and Google Keep, all generate databases with your unique Google User ID in its name. Your Google User ID allows Google to access your publicly-available information, such as your profile picture, which the Safari bug can expose to other websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="1FgUpg"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This is a huge bug. On OSX, Safari users can (temporarily) switch to another browser to avoid their data leaking across origins. iOS users have no such choice, because Apple imposes a ban on other browser engines. &lt;a href="https://t.co/aXdhDVIjTT"&gt;https://t.co/aXdhDVIjTT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Jake Archibald (@jaffathecake) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jaffathecake/status/1482627132903858176?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 16, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9bYMxQ"&gt;FingerprintJS created &lt;a href="https://safarileaks.com/"&gt;a proof-of-concept demo&lt;/a&gt; you can try out if you have Safari 15 and above on your Mac, iPhone, or iPad. The demo uses the browser’s IndexedDB vulnerability to identify the sites you have open (or opened recently), and shows how sites that exploit the bug can scrape information from your Google User ID. It currently only detects 30 popular sites that are affected by the bug, such as include Instagram, Netflix, Twitter, Xbox, but it likely affects far more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="St7eCX"&gt;Unfortunately, there’s not much you can do to get around the issue, as FingerprintJS says the bug also affects Private Browsing mode on Safari. You can use a different browser on macOS, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22421912/iphone-web-app-pwa-cloud-gaming-epic-v-apple-safari"&gt;Apple’s third-party browser engine ban on iOS&lt;/a&gt; means all browsers are affected. FingerprintJS reported the leak to the WebKit Bug Tracker on November 28th, but there hasn’t been an update to Safari yet. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; reached out to Apple with a request for comment but didn’t immediately hear back.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/16/22886809/safari-15-bug-leak-browsing-history-personal-information"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/16/22886809/safari-15-bug-leak-browsing-history-personal-information</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-16T12:04:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-16T12:04:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung’s next tablet lineup could include a 14.6-inch ‘Ultra’ model with a notch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qJwOIsI9IXEFPr5hF0yw-01sgv0=/53x0:2048x1330/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70396772/samsung_galaxy_s8_ultra_tab.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The Samsung Galaxy Tab S8 Ultra may have a 14.6-inch display with a notch. | Image by &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://winfuture.de/news,127516.html" target="_blank"&gt;WinFuture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="sAqDQj"&gt;Samsung might be adding its first-ever “Ultra” model to its upcoming Galaxy Tab S8 lineup, which will also include a Tab S8 and S8 Plus, as rumored by &lt;a href="https://winfuture.de/news,127516.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WinFuture&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bH7WWr"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;WinFuture&lt;/em&gt;, the flagship Ultra model could sport a 14.6-inch Super AMOLED display with a 2960 x 1848px resolution, a refresh rate of up to 120Hz, as well as a notch with two 12-megapixel (MP) cameras. It may also come with the option of up to 16GB of RAM and 512GB of storage, along with a 11200mAh battery. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/30F2KvIVz7ydyYWgg42-oKNdhPU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23172714/galaxy_tab_s8_plus.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image by &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://winfuture.de/news,127516.html" target="_blank"&gt;WinFuture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The Galaxy Tab S8 Plus is rumored to have a 12.7-inch display with no notch.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="yUmooi"&gt;When compared to the Tab S8 Ultra, the Super AMOLED display on the Tab S8 Plus is a bit smaller, potentially measuring at 12.7 inches with a resolution of 2800 x 1752px. &lt;em&gt;WinFuture&lt;/em&gt; says the midgrade model may not have a notch and could come with a 10090mAh battery. The base Tab S8 model will obviously be the smallest of the bunch and is rumored to have an 11-inch LTPS TFT display with a resolution of 2560 x 1600px, a notch-less design, and an 8000mAh battery. Both the Tab S8 and S8 Plus have smaller memory and storage options, offering up to 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mpzpVj"&gt;As for what’s powering the devices, &lt;em&gt;WinFuture&lt;/em&gt; notes that each tablet in Samsung’s new lineup may come with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809687/qualcomm-snapdragon-8-gen-1-chip-smartphone-processor-specs-details"&gt;Qualcomm Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 chip&lt;/a&gt; and the Adreno 730 GPU. All models will also have a 13MP dual camera and 6MP ultra wide-angle lens on the back, a 12MP camera in the front (except for the Ultra, which has two), S-Pen compatibility, under-display fingerprint scanners, optional 5G connectivity, as well as quad speakers that support Dolby Atmos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tJPzVP"&gt;There’s no confirmed pricing information for any S8 Tabs just yet, but a leak from &lt;a href="https://appuals.com/samsung-tab-s8-prices-leaked/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Appuals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; might provide a hint at what to expect. &lt;em&gt;Appuals&lt;/em&gt; claims pricing for the Wi-Fi-only Tab S8 Ultra begins at 1,040€ to 1,060€ (~$1,187 to $1,210), with additional storage and 5G connectivity adding to that price. The Wi-Fi-only Tab S8 Plus could start at 880€ to 900€ (~$1,004 to $1,027), with the base Tab S8 potentially starting at 680€ to 700€ (~$776 to $799).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8GiRAC"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WinFuture&lt;/em&gt; predicts that Samsung will either introduce its Galaxy Tab S8 lineup at its February 8th Samsung Unpacked event (potentially alongside the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/30/22860479/samsung-galaxy-s22-ultra-leak-official-image-note-design"&gt;Samsung Galaxy S22&lt;/a&gt;), or at the Mobile World Conference (MWC), which begins on February 28th. Samsung last released its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21444688/samsung-galaxy-tab-s7-plus-review"&gt;Galaxy Tab S7 lineup&lt;/a&gt; in 2020, which only consists of two tablets: the Tab S7 and Tab S7 Plus. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/16/22886595/samsung-tablet-lineup-ultra-notch-rumor"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/16/22886595/samsung-tablet-lineup-ultra-notch-rumor</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
