<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-06-29T08:25:28-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-29T08:25:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-29T08:25:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sony acquires Returnal developer Housemarque, hints Bluepoint is next</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AJdqfSWyHBXnI_APN54LNuUKy4o=/85x0:1003x612/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69517791/Welcome_Housemarque_210628_scaled.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4SQN47"&gt;Sony has acquired Housemarque, the Finnish studio behind recent PS5 exclusive &lt;em&gt;Returnal&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/06/29/welcoming-housemarque-to-the-playstation-studios-family/"&gt;the company announced today&lt;/a&gt;. It was announced &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nibellion/status/1409822833631502338?s=21"&gt;with a tweet&lt;/a&gt; which suggests Sony might also be about to acquire Bluepoint Games, the studio behind the recent &lt;em&gt;Demon’s Souls&lt;/em&gt; remaster. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o40aks"&gt;In a blog post announcing the acquisition, PlayStation Studios head Hermen Hulst said that the studio “is one with incredible vision, capable of creating memorable new games that resonate with our community.” Although Housemarque has produced games across multiple platforms including PC, iOS, and the Xbox 360, the majority of its recent titles have been exclusive to Sony’s platforms. Prior to &lt;em&gt;Returnal &lt;/em&gt;it was best known for the &lt;em&gt;Super Stardust &lt;/em&gt;games, which have appeared on the PS3, PS4, and PSP. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="E59MNw"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Thrilled to announce &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Housemarque?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Housemarque&lt;/a&gt; has officially joined PlayStation Studios! The extremely talented studio with a proven track record and best-in-class gameplay has a bright future and we couldn’t be more excited to be part of it! &lt;a href="https://t.co/B47YlfmgCs"&gt;pic.twitter.com/B47YlfmgCs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Hermen Hulst (@hermenhulst) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hermenhulst/status/1409818077349306374?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 29, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CJKty3"&gt;In a statement, Housemarque’s co-founder and managing director Ilari Kuittinen welcomed the acquisition, saying that it “gives our studio a clear future and a stable opportunity to continue delivering on gameplay centric approaches, while still experimenting with new methods of narrative delivery and pushing the boundaries of this modern artform.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Uqbhcw"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;..so apparently PlayStation Japan uploaded the wrong image with their first tweet on Housemarque's acquisition, and it actually mentions a Bluepoint acquisition &lt;a href="https://t.co/yQBHtLbG5c"&gt;pic.twitter.com/yQBHtLbG5c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Nibel (@Nibellion) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Nibellion/status/1409822833631502338?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 29, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CHKdhl"&gt;News of the Housemarque acquisition arrived alongside a tweeted image that suggests Sony is about to acquire another studio. It appears that when Sony’s PlayStation Japan Twitter account tried to tweet about the Housemarque acquisition, it accidentally used a promotional image announcing an acquisition of Bluepoint Games instead. The high quality of the image suggests it’s official but premature. The original tweet and image have since been pulled, but &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Nibellion/status/1409822833631502338"&gt;Twitter user Nibel&lt;/a&gt; has verified via TweetDeck that the image came from the official PlayStation Japan account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fSq44d"&gt;Bluepoint Games is another studio with a long history of collaborations with Sony. As well as the recent &lt;em&gt;Demon’s Souls&lt;/em&gt; remaster, it’s also remastered other PlayStation titles like &lt;em&gt;Shadow of the Colossus&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Uncharted&lt;/em&gt; trilogy, and &lt;em&gt;Flower&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x739OV"&gt;Sony’s acquisition(s) comes as its main console rival, Microsoft, has been on a spending spree of its own. In recent years the Xbox manufacturer has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/9/22319124/microsoft-bethesda-acquisition-complete-finalized"&gt;acquired Bethesda&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/10/17446914/microsoft-studios-the-initiative-undead-labs-playground-games-ninja-theory-compulsion-games-xbox-e3"&gt;Ninja Theory, Playground Games&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/9/18658920/microsoft-acquires-double-fine-psychonauts-e3-2019"&gt;Double Fine&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/10/18082922/microsoft-xbox-inxile-obsidian-entertainment-studio-acquisition"&gt;Obsidian Entertainment&lt;/a&gt;. Acquisitions like these are important for filling Microsoft’s and Sony’s consoles with exclusive games to entice would-be buyers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FySpK2"&gt;However, in an &lt;a href="https://www.gq-magazine.co.uk/culture/article/housemarque-sony-playstation-acquisition"&gt;interview with &lt;em&gt;GQ&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Hulst denied that Sony is in an “arms race” with Microsoft. “I’m always looking for people that have a similar set of values, similar creative ambitions and work very well with our team that we can further invest in and help grow as creators,” Hulst said, “It’s not like we’re going around and just making random acquisitions.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22555358/sony-housemarque-returnal-developer-acquisition-bluepoint"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22555358/sony-housemarque-returnal-developer-acquisition-bluepoint</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-29T08:14:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-29T08:14:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>Dell’s versatile UltraSharp 4K webcam uses AI to keep you in the frame</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oQG3mCMs6JjEWjaENsSJ3h-o_IM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69517763/dellultrasharphero.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The UltraSharp shown on its two included mounts.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Dell&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qsr9Lw"&gt;Dell has launched the high-end UltraSharp webcam that costs $199.99 and is available now worldwide. Its cylindrical design is reminiscent of Apple’s old but iconic iSight external webcam, but its features are aimed to compete with Logitech’s Brio and other modern 4K-ready webcams. In addition, it aims to serve as a more affordable and easier-to-set up alternative to mounting a DSLR camera behind your monitor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mzfRRQ"&gt;The UltraSharp is a USB-C webcam that houses a Sony STARVIS CMOS 8.3-megapixel sensor. It’s capable of recording or streaming in 4K at 30 or 24 frames per second and in 1080p or 720p at 24, 30, or 60 frames per second. You can tweak the field of view (FOV) between 65 degrees for a close crop, 78 degrees, or 90 degrees for the widest crop available. The webcam has a bevy of auto-light correction features that aim to make your picture look good regardless of your lighting. It supports up to 5x digital zoom and has autofocus. Dell claims the UltraSharp offers the best image quality in its class. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Dell UltraSharp webcam" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jXSJjkk5gQQamRK8CVNjVcjzn10=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22686315/dellwebcam.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Dell&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The USB-C cable can be routed through the monitor mount for easy cable management. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="tVCN06"&gt;This webcam can work without drivers on Windows 10 or macOS computers, but many of its features are accessible only in Dell’s Peripheral Manager software. One of the most appealing features that the software unlocks is the AI auto-framing mode that lets it follow your movements to keep you centered in the frame. The webcam doesn’t actually move, but the video feed appeared to pan and deliver smooth, seamless motion tracking during a live demo shown to &lt;em&gt;The Verge.&lt;/em&gt; (The GIF below is an accurate portrayal.) A similar feature has appeared recently in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/12/22429549/amazon-echo-show-8-5-camera-update-price-kids-edition"&gt;Amazon’s new Echo Show smart displays&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22442084/ipad-pro-2021-review-features-screen-mini-led-m1-processor"&gt;the latest iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s a perk that currently sets Dell’s webcam apart from the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Dell UltraSharp webcam" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ffL0E1_lkOlQpExUrZUtjgvU6n4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22686368/dellultrasharpAI.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZFdZZ4"&gt;Other noteworthy features include its infrared sensor that can log you in to your PC via Windows Hello facial recognition. It also has a proximity sensor that, on Dell PCs, can take advantage of the company’s Express Sign-In feature that can log you in and out automatically depending on whether you’re sitting at your PC or not. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GxQWA6"&gt;The UltraSharp includes a standard monitor mount as well as a tripod mount. It can connect magnetically to either one. (There’s also a magnetic lens cap included.) The monitor mount seems like it’ll be a solid option for most — even for people who own monitors with the slimmest of bezels. And for streamers or people who are looking for a specific angle, it’s great to have the option to easily put it on a tripod.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XPpHYO"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/t2WVqBHV10I?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3ajYXn"&gt;But $199.99 isn’t cheap for a webcam, and I haven’t even gotten to its biggest omission: it doesn’t have an internal microphone. Dell said it was focused primarily on optics for this model, so you’ll need to source your own microphone — whether that’s a standalone USB or XLR mic or a headset. That might be a deal-breaker for some, but mic aside, this one’s stacked with enough thoughtful features that might make it worth the price still. We’ll be testing this one, so check back for more in-depth impressions soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="iHbYJv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data="{&amp;quot;stories&amp;quot;:[{&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Razer’s Kiyo Pro doesn't deliver all the goods a $200 webcam should&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.theverge.com/22295235/razer-kiyo-pro-webcam-review-adjustable-field-of-view-streaming-zoom-video-calls-price-features&amp;quot;}]}"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22553857/dell-ultrasharp-4k-webcam-features-price-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22553857/dell-ultrasharp-4k-webcam-features-price-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-29T07:14:07-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-29T07:14:07-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nothing’s debut wireless earbuds will be announced on July 27</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Gvv9DZU-lRuRSurGMinVg49rpEo=/151x0:1771x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69517591/Global_Landscape.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Nothing&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4IDnYd"&gt;Tech startup Nothing will announce its debut pair of true wireless earbuds, the Nothing Ear (1), at 9AM ET on July 27th, the company’s founder &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/getpeid/status/1409829386308624388"&gt;Carl Pei announced today&lt;/a&gt;. The launch comes around a month later than the June launch window &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/11/22428397/nothing-ear-1-true-wireless-earbuds-launch-carl-pei"&gt;Nothing previously announced&lt;/a&gt;, after Pei &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/getpeid/status/1405911656929054730"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; that the company was delaying the launch because it had “a few things left to finalize.” Carl Pei is best known as one of the co-founders of OnePlus, a company he &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/16/21519785/oneplus-carl-pei-departure"&gt;parted ways with last year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3KhkhK"&gt;Details about the Nothing Ear (1) are thin, but the company has teased several details about them over the past few months. We know they’ll have a “stripped-down aesthetic” featuring &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/9/22320915/nothing-true-wireless-earbuds-teenage-engineering-concept-1"&gt;transparent materials&lt;/a&gt; in their construction, and that they’ve been designed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22298802/nothing-teenage-engineering-swedish-design-founding-partner-audio-headphones"&gt;in collaboration with Teenage Engineering&lt;/a&gt;. But Nothing has been far less forthcoming about the earbuds’ tech specs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="inZCMs"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Are you ready for the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SoundOfChange?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#SoundOfChange&lt;/a&gt;? The &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nothing?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Nothing&lt;/a&gt; ear (1) Launch Event is on 27 July! &lt;a href="https://t.co/1qZaJaKQvD"&gt;https://t.co/1qZaJaKQvD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Carl Pei (@getpeid) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/getpeid/status/1409829386308624388?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 29, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xD70jF"&gt;Wireless earbuds are the first product category that Nothing is planning to tackle, but Carl Pei has talked about moving into more areas over time. In an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22250653/nothing-brand-oneplus-carl-pei-announcement-consumer-technology-smart-devices"&gt;interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in January, Pei said the company eventually hopes to build up an entire ecosystem of interconnected devices. “The ultimate vision of having everything connected in a seamless way, that can only happen when you have multiple categories of products,” Pei said. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22555247/nothing-ear-1-true-wireless-earbuds-july-27th-launch-oneplus-carl-pei"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22555247/nothing-ear-1-true-wireless-earbuds-july-27th-launch-oneplus-carl-pei</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-29T06:51:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-29T06:51:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google Messages will auto-delete OTPs and sort like Gmail, but only in India</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/onctS4v3GwU4qQE6IDRPcAeu6Zg=/0x0:2100x1400/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69517507/messages_otp.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;OTPs can be set to delete automatically after 24 hours.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YeUvXY"&gt;Google is updating its Messages app in India to allow it to delete one-time passwords (OTPs) automatically, to stop the single-use codes from clogging up your inbox, &lt;a href="https://india.googleblog.com/2021/06/messages-makes-it-easier-to-help-you.html"&gt;the company has announced&lt;/a&gt;. Alongside it, Google also says the app will be able to sort messages into categories, keeping your personal correspondence away from notifications about bank transactions and special offers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YLi3vj"&gt;As someone that &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; exclusively uses WhatsApp for personal communication, my phone’s default texting app is typically a graveyard of six-digit codes, which by design become useless mere minutes after they’re received. Having the ability to automatically delete them after 24 hours should make Messages less cluttered and more usable.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rZNhyjUvXV4mlQQqMp6f5TOsLqA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22688245/msedge_wB2FkrvQhQ.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Source: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new Gmail-style categories.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pFLB42"&gt;It’s a similar story when it comes to categorizing messages. Google says it’s using a machine learning model to sort messages into categories like personal, transactions, OTPs, and offers, which sounds very similar to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/5/29/4374306/gmail-declares-war-on-inbox-clutter-with-new-tabbed-design-for"&gt;what it already offers for emails in Gmail&lt;/a&gt;. The sorting process happens on-device, Google says, so it should still work while offline. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FZsUAu"&gt;Google says the new features will roll out “over the coming weeks” in India, on Android phones running version 8 and above. A spokesperson for the company declined to comment on whether the feature could see a release outside of the country.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22555333/google-messages-one-time-passwords-otp-delete-categories-gmail"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22555333/google-messages-one-time-passwords-otp-delete-categories-gmail</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-29T06:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-29T06:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google launches new search tool to help combat food insecurity</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TeA5Lpc6KfhyHYRykevgGBjiIoE=/226x0:1645x946/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69517398/google_food_support.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google is working with non-profits to aggregate 90,000 locations with free food support across all 50 states .&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bUA5vq"&gt;Google announced a new website designed to be a “one-stop shop” for people with food insecurity. The &lt;a href="http://g.co/findfoodsupport"&gt;“Find Food Support” site&lt;/a&gt; includes a food locator tool powered by Google Maps which people can use to search for their nearest food bank, food pantry, or school lunch program pickup site in their community. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9rGbnt"&gt;Google is working with non-profit groups like No Kid Hungry and FoodFinder, as well as the US Department of Agriculture, to aggregate 90,000 locations with free food support across all 50 states — with more locations to come. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cCLMyV41Dh9-ItVHK31NVqJTyu4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22687633/oNi6GDgn4Vdz5B4W3X383J0AxEvKEnQuLEzgqP1rAR5j7qs818cPe916aCTj7vR_ID_kEXl_x1aZtTyqRB6qi8HHdfncLu07S6BjHTm3637efWRTnpf2Cc_YATCr9JTumsuh3EYiKlFqaqGm5UrcsmvxQQOD_mmo2IZaSCD9KPEUwuc5.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CIJGK1"&gt;The new site is a product of Google’s newly formed &lt;a href="https://blog.x.company/a-new-home-for-project-delta-a39f8286b6d7"&gt;Food for Good team&lt;/a&gt;, formerly known as Project Delta when it was headquartered at Alphabet’s X moonshot division. Project Delta’s mission is to “create a smarter food system,” which includes standardizing data to improve communication between food distributors to curb food waste. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="fz5nLx"&gt;&lt;q&gt;90,000 locations with free food support&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UfeKgx"&gt;Food insecurity is defined by the US Department of Agriculture as &lt;a href="https://www.ers.usda.gov/topics/food-nutrition-assistance/food-security-in-the-us/definitions-of-food-security.aspx"&gt;a lack of consistent access to enough food for an active, healthy life&lt;/a&gt;. The number of people experiencing food insecurity spiked during the COVID-19 pandemic, affecting an estimated 45 million people or &lt;a href="https://www.feedingamerica.org/sites/default/files/2021-03/National%20Projections%20Brief_3.9.2021_0.pdf"&gt;1 in 7 Americans&lt;/a&gt;, including 15 million children. Google says that searches for &lt;a href="https://trends.google.com/trends/explore?date=all&amp;amp;geo=US&amp;amp;q=food%20bank%20near%20me"&gt;”food bank near me”&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://trends.google.com/trends/explore?date=all&amp;amp;geo=US&amp;amp;q=%2Fm%2F030gj7"&gt;”Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP)”&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://trends.google.com/trends/explore?date=all&amp;amp;geo=US&amp;amp;q=food%20stamps%20application"&gt;”food stamps application,”&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://trends.google.com/trends/explore?date=all&amp;amp;geo=US&amp;amp;q=school%20lunch%20pickup"&gt;”school lunch pick up”&lt;/a&gt; reached record highs during 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8gIwZQ"&gt;In addition to the new food location site, Google is publishing five new videos on YouTube aimed at de-stigmatizing food insecurity. The site will also include links to food support hotlines, state-by-state benefit guides, and information for specific communities, such as seniors, families and children, and military families. Visitors can also find information about how you can donate food, time and money to support those in need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MBp5IG"&gt;“We want people to know they’re not alone,” Emily Ma, head of Food for Good, &lt;a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/public-policy/connecting-people-to-food-support/"&gt;says in a blog post&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cwDTqr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ArltOW"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22554819/google-find-food-support-food-insecurity-seach-tool"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22554819/google-find-food-support-food-insecurity-seach-tool</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-29T05:45:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-29T05:45:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>Windows 11 includes new Dynamic Refresh Rate feature to save laptop battery life</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9xHlDGHI5iDWeXov8lB6NJgCM9g=/116x0:1370x836/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69517393/Windows_11_Generic_Laptop_Device_Render.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="e9wRVy"&gt;Microsoft is introducing a new Dynamic Refresh Rate (DRR) feature in Windows 11 that’s designed to save laptop battery life and boost refresh rates when they’re really needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j3j9An"&gt;A number of laptops now ship with 120Hz and beyond displays, which make Windows feel a lot smoother across scrolling, animations, and inking. While the added smoothness feels great, running at higher refresh rates takes its toll on battery life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4XSRSk"&gt;In Windows 10 you have to decide between 60Hz and 120Hz on a laptop, and it’s a static choice. Microsoft is now building DRR into Windows 11, which will allow a laptop to dynamically adjust its refresh rate. “This means that Windows 11 will seamlessly switch between a lower refresh rate and a higher refresh rate based on what you’re doing on your PC,” &lt;a href="https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/dynamic-refresh-rate/"&gt;explains Ana Marta&lt;/a&gt;, a program manager on the graphics team at Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kXDHX6"&gt;You’ll need a laptop that supports DRR and 120Hz or above refresh rates, and the feature will mean that regular tasks like writing emails or documents will run at 60Hz, and then DRR will kick in and boost the screen to 120Hz for inking and scrolling. Apps will need to support DRR, and during the Windows 11 preview DRR is limited to just Office for the scrolling boost. Office, Microsoft Edge, Microsoft Whiteboard, Microsoft Photos, Snip &amp;amp; Sketch, Drawboard PDF, Microsoft Sticky Notes, Adobe Acrobat, Adobe Illustrator, Microsoft To Do, and Inkodo will all support DRR for inking, too.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/puq8WTCCBXnv0WuhVADuGXL_vfo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22688228/DRR_UI_6.22.2021.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new DRR option in Windows 11.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="8tEULH"&gt;DRR shouldn’t be confused with VRR (variable refresh rate), particularly because DRR doesn’t apply to games and is focused purely on Windows apps. Windows 11 will be a requirement for DRR, alongside a laptop that supports a variable refresh rate of at least 120Hz. You’ll also need a new graphics driver (WDDM 3.0), and Microsoft says it’s working with its graphics display partners to enable DRR on a variety of devices running the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/28/22553639/microsoft-windows-11-download-available-preview-features"&gt;Windows 11 preview&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6IuvYr"&gt;Where DRR looks like a natural fit is with Microsoft’s Surface line of hardware, particularly thanks to Microsoft’s focus on enabling DRR in inking scenarios. No Surface devices currently ship with a 120Hz display, but this could be an early sign that Microsoft may finally deliver a Surface tablet display that can compete with Apple’s ProMotion displays on the iPad.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22555295/microsoft-windows-11-dynamic-refresh-rate-laptops"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22555295/microsoft-windows-11-dynamic-refresh-rate-laptops</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-29T05:07:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-29T05:07:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google beefs up Play Store developer verification in response to scams</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vMy11f4h-yYq1mFelvh0OfUcesA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69517335/acastro_180508_1777_google_IO_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5MaO2a"&gt;Google is working to enhance the integrity of the Play Store by adding new restrictions and safeguards to developer accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RLVzyr"&gt;Google Play Store developers will soon have to verify their email address and phone number and provide extra details like a physical address in an attempt to increase security and ensure that accounts are being created by ‘real people,’ &lt;a href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2021/06/play-dev-id-requirements-2-step.html"&gt;the company has announced&lt;/a&gt;. Developers will also be required to use two-step verification. The search giant says it’s making the changes “to keep Google Play safe and secure and to better serve our developer community,” and to “make sure that every account is created by a real person with real contact details.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rrGIDd"&gt;&lt;a href="https://therecord.media/google-to-require-2fa-and-a-physical-address-from-android-app-devs/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Record&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that the announcement coincides with the emergence of a cottage industry of sellers who’ll create large amounts of developer accounts for others to use to upload malware and other scammy apps to the Play Store. A screenshot of a cybercrime forum post published by &lt;em&gt;The Record&lt;/em&gt; shows these accounts being sold for $89 each. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="fR6qGZ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“To keep Google Play safe and secure and to better serve our developer community”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dxGH8M"&gt;Meanwhile, the two-step verification requirement should make it harder for scammers to break into and steal legitimate developers accounts. It mirrors a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22422778/google-accounts-enabling-two-step-verification-default"&gt;similar change the search giant announced&lt;/a&gt; for regular Google accounts earlier this year, where it will now enable two-factor authentication by default. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FyhMSH"&gt;The changes are significant compared to Google’s current developer account policies that only require new signups to provide an email address and phone number. Details like a physical address “will not be public-facing,” the company says, and are solely to “to help us confirm your identity and communicate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JFKlqY"&gt;Google is introducing the new requirements in stages. It says that, from today, account owners will have the option of setting their account type as personal or business and verifying their contact details. Then, in August, all new signups will be required to follow these same steps when they create their accounts, and to use two-step verification. “Later this year” the changes will be fully implemented for all existing accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c8BllN"&gt;The changes come amidst a wider crackdown on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22411560/google-play-store-listings-scammy-emoji-deals-misleading-assets-guidelines-policy"&gt;scammy apps on the Play Store&lt;/a&gt;, which will prohibit developers from using cheap tactics in their listings to incentivize installs. App listings will no longer be able to use eye-catching features like all-caps or emoji in their titles, or include phrases like “download now.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CrdxmN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LYuFJF"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22555281/google-play-developer-information-verification-two-factor-authentication-2fa-scams"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22555281/google-play-developer-information-verification-two-factor-authentication-2fa-scams</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-29T00:01:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-29T00:01:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nikon’s Z FC is a film camera revival in mirrorless form</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2gUF5w0d2VNqtK1-vbm6_hfPqyU=/0x0:2000x1333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69517035/Zfc_USDD_TO_6573.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YRJpV4"&gt;Nikon is going all-in on the retro aesthetic with its latest Z-series mirrorless camera. The company says the new Z FC, officially styled “Z fc,” is designed specifically to evoke its FM2 film SLR from the ‘80s, with dedicated dials for settings like shutter speed, exposure compensation, and ISO. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2PNUbN"&gt;The approach is similar to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/11/4/5066118/nikon-df-full-frame-modern-camera-in-a-stunning-old-school-body"&gt;the Nikon DF&lt;/a&gt;, a retro-style full-frame DSLR that Nikon released in 2013. But the DF was much larger than the film cameras it was inspired by. The Z FC has a 20.9-megapixel APS-C sensor (and of course no SLR mirror and prism), which means the resulting camera is far more compact and looks a lot closer to something like an FM2.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5lO7JdRdm2y6a5c7WyqTK4KS-to=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22688024/Zfc_16_50DX_3.5_6.3_top.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6e6zGf"&gt;Beyond the exterior, the Z FC is a modern camera with broadly similar specs to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/10/20906990/nikon-z50-camera-announced-mirrorless-z-mount-instagram"&gt;the Z50&lt;/a&gt;. There’s a vari-angle touchscreen, an OLED electronic viewfinder, USB-C charging, SnapBridge wireless connectivity, and of course the now-requisite ability to use it as a webcam. While the camera can be shot in fully manual mode with the dials, there’s also a switch for PASM operation, and you can check aperture settings with a tiny LCD on the top plate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5KtyhE"&gt;The native ISO range is 100-51,200 and there’s a hybrid AF system with 209 points across 87 percent of the frame. Video isn’t really a focus with the Z FC, unsurprisingly, but it can shoot at up to 4K/30fps.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IUUb9N4Yh5WSWl8wWq4rSxFOKSc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22688022/Cool_PBS_C.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ThVUsw"&gt;As a Z-mount camera, the Z FC will be able to use any of the full-frame lenses that are native to cameras like the Z6 and Z7, but Nikon’s lineup of DX/APS-C lenses that can make the most of the Z FC’s small size is still lacking. Nikon is announcing one new prime lens today, however — a 28mm (42mm equivalent) f/2.8 that’ll be available in a special edition with styling that makes it look like an older Nikkor D lens. Nikon will also release a silver version of its 16-50mm pancake zoom alongside the Z FC, and says a DX 18-140mm travel zoom will be available at some point this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kKpgWB"&gt;The ZFC will cost $959.95 body-only, $1,099.95 with the silver 16-50mm lens, and $1,199.95 with the 28mm lens. All three options will be released in black and silver late July. Nikon is also releasing six extra color options that’ll be sold solely through its own site.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ykPx3ueDbkJ8yoPl_dRPYl-kgYs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22688021/Q1985_Color_Cams.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22555091/nikon-z-fc-announced-price-specs-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/29/22555091/nikon-z-fc-announced-price-specs-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-28T21:05:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-28T21:05:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>LG’s C1 and G1 OLEDs get even better at gaming with 120Hz Dolby Vision</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YLK4LBuGcWwQxp8qwUre5aomD9Y=/22x0:1030x672/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69516674/LG_Dolby_Vision_Gaming_02a.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Drqel1"&gt;With Dolby Vision gaming HDR technology &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/14/22435864/microsoft-dolby-vision-xbox-series-x-s-test"&gt;available on Xbox Series X and Series S consoles&lt;/a&gt;, some TV owners have noticed that suddenly there’s a new setting to worry over. While some HDMI 2.1-equipped 4K displays could handle 120Hz, and some can support Dolby Vision for gaming, at first there weren’t any that could do both things at once. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HalHt3"&gt;Now LG has &lt;a href="https://www.lgnewsroom.com/2021/06/gaming-on-lg-premium-tvs-reach-new-heights-with-latest-dolby-vision-update/"&gt;confirmed&lt;/a&gt; it’s the first manufacturer with Dolby Vision HDR at 4K 120Hz support on some of its TVs, just a couple of weeks after owners noticed it arriving in updates. The 03.15.27 firmware enables the feature on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224271/lg-2021-tvs-oled-qned-g1-c1-a1-announced-specs-ces"&gt;C1 and G1 2021 OLED TVs&lt;/a&gt;, and today LG says support is on the way for other premium TVs in its 2021 lineup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="ElcdBW"&gt;Additional premium models in LG’s 2021 TV lineup such as OLED Z1 series, QNED Mini LED QNED99 series and NanoCell NANO99 series TVs will also receive the update in July. Additional 2021 and 2020 TV models are also being tested for Dolby Vision gaming in either 60Hz or 120Hz.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="7Cm7Kv"&gt;The press release wasn’t specific about support for previous years, but the company has said to &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnarcher/2021/06/21/lg-reveals-more-on-its-new-dolby-vision-gaming-oled-tv-updateincluding-wider-model-support/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forbes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that beta software with 4K/120Hz support is coming to other 4K TVs including last year’s CX and BX models. There’s no word yet on any update for 2019 OLED TVs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XgRBsd"&gt;All of this is happening before the first Dolby Vision HDR-enabled games are available, which we believe should help gamers automatically configure their brightness and image settings to match the TV’s capabilities. As the company behind the technology &lt;a href="https://www.dolby.com/gaming/"&gt;explains&lt;/a&gt;, “Dolby Vision games automatically map to your Dolby Vision display as you play, so you’re always seeing the full picture.” Microsoft has said it means you’ll see “brighter highlights, sharper contrast, and more vibrant colors,” although how that applies to other HDR games is harder to tell. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oaewRAS4wI5X2uxclq86vwjQeHk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22687780/LG_Dolby_Vision_Gaming_03a.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="TP8C2y"&gt;The new firmware also adds Game Dashboard, a floating menu that should help LG owners configure their TVs and see which settings are enabled. It works on any 2021 LG TV with Game Optimizer, and can show the status of the TV’s black stabilizer, low latency and variable refresh rate (VRR), or flip between settings tuned for specific genres. Samsung was first &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/6/22215172/samsung-neo-qled-4k-8k-tv-announced-specs-ces-2021"&gt;with a game bar feature on its 2021 TVs&lt;/a&gt;, but with something this useful we hope more manufacturers pick up the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/games/2021/6/28/22554939/lg-dolby-vision-hdr-xbox-c1-g1-4k"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/games/2021/6/28/22554939/lg-dolby-vision-hdr-xbox-c1-g1-4k</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-28T20:43:13-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-28T20:43:13-04:00</updated>
    <title>Parler reportedly refused to ban Trump’s critics as part of discussions to bring him onboard</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Parler’s logo" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/N-GBIF930tf6N5o4IiBD58dPoE4=/0x0:5000x3333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69516611/1230591653.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Thiago Prudêncio/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yRJCDl"&gt;The alternative social network Parler and representatives of former president Donald Trump were reportedly considering an idea to make Trump an active member of the platform after he left office, but Parler apparently pushed back on one key part of the proposed arrangement: the platform did not want to ban Trump’s detractors, according to an excerpt of Michael Wolff’s upcoming book about the last days of Trump’s presidency &lt;a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/michael-wolff-landslide-final-days-trump-presidency-excerpt.html"&gt;published in &lt;em&gt;New York Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0YuR1w"&gt;Here’s what was going on, according to Wolff: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="JZio80"&gt;One curious point of consideration for the [Trump] family [the morning of January 6th] — prescient of the events that would shortly unfold — was a follow-up to a discussion initiated some months before by aides and family. Trump representatives, working with Trump-family members, had approached Parler, the social network backed by Bob Mercer and his daughter Rebekah, far-right exponents and large Trump contributors. They had floated a proposition that Trump, after he left office, become an active member of Parler, moving much of his social-media activity there from Twitter. In return, Trump would receive 40 percent of Parler’s gross revenues and the service would ban anyone who spoke negatively about him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zLj9SB"&gt;Parler was balking only at this last condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="4eqrLO"&gt;Parler, which has been popular with conservative users, has long promoted itself as a social network that isn’t moderated as tightly as other platforms, so it’s not entirely surprising that it didn’t want to lay down a red line on content, even at the request of its most famous potential user. The company has not replied to a request for comment about the reported discussions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gINUrP"&gt;In February, &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/trump-parler-ownership"&gt;&lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/em&gt; also reported on the conversations&lt;/a&gt; about Trump’s potential increased involvement with Parler, but shared different proposed terms — “Parler offered the Trump Organization a 40% stake in the company,” according to &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/em&gt; — and did not report on Parler’s apparent refusal to ban Trump critics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iiG8on"&gt;Shortly after the January 6th attack on the US Capitol, Parler was banned by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/9/22221730/apple-removes-suspends-bans-parler-app-store"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22221648/google-suspends-bans-parler-play-store"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; from their respective app stores and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22223335/parler-amazon-terminates-web-hosting-aws-google-apple-capitol"&gt;Amazon terminated Parler’s hosting&lt;/a&gt;. The app returned to Apple’s App Store in May, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22440005/parler-apple-app-store-return-amazon-google-capitol"&gt;though it had some content excluded&lt;/a&gt;. It still isn’t available on Google Play.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/28/22554880/parler-ban-trump-criticize-book-excerpt"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/28/22554880/parler-ban-trump-criticize-book-excerpt</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
