<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-01-13T16:51:59-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T16:51:59-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T16:51:59-05:00</updated>
    <title>Asus’ latte dispenses movies instead of coffee and milk</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GAumssSlrzC898ri8cmHglCFsX4=/0x0:696x464/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68663967/feature.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fDb20X"&gt;Asus announced its &lt;a href="https://edgeup.asus.com/2021/asus-zenbeam-latte-l1-portable-projector-ces-2021/"&gt;new ZenBeam Latte&lt;/a&gt; at CES 2021 today, and it’s kind of cute. It’s a mobile movie projector that looks like a one-eyed, fabric-covered mini-robot of sorts. Importantly, it fires out its 720p image using up to 300 lumens of LED light, making it brighter &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/6/20683533/nebula-capsule-ii-mini-projector-review-tv-netflix"&gt;than capsule projectors we’ve seen from the likes of Anker&lt;/a&gt;, and it has an integrated 10W Harman Kardon-tuned speaker system to boot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LWelhD"&gt;Weirdly, Asus insists that its projector looks like a coffee cup. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y85sH-NlzadMV-iofKj8xVHowAc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22233590/feature.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Asus&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The ZenBeam Latte projector.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="BS2lle"&gt;It does not. It’s not the right shape (just watch the video!), and why would a “homey” coffee cup (Asus’ word) be gray instead of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227941/samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-plus-brown-zune-unpacked-2021"&gt;a glorious brown&lt;/a&gt;? Asus also claims it is “the first projector to offer a fabric exterior,” &lt;a href="https://www.mi.com/us/mi-smart-compact-projector"&gt;which is demonstrably false&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KH8EgE"&gt;Of course, you cannot drink Asus’ latte because it only dispenses light and sound. It can wirelessly project your phone or an HDMI device, though. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uHTEfF"&gt;So consider this an opportunity, gadget makers: build the coffee cup that Asus didn’t. Just make sure it lasts longer than a movie — Asus quotes three hours from a 6,000mAh battery — and gets bright enough to create a decent-sized screen. Asus says this one can produce a 40-inch picture when placed one meter from the wall, 80 inches at two meters, and a maximum of 120 inches (presumably at three meters). Don’t expect a 300-lumen projector to be very bright at nine feet away, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jfWMQz"&gt;Asus says it’s coming to the US in the second quarter of the year, but there’s no word on pricing.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/1/13/22229575/asus-latte-movie-projector-mobile"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/1/13/22229575/asus-latte-movie-projector-mobile</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T16:39:27-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T16:39:27-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Samsung Galaxy S21: all of the rumors and news as it happens</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Samsung reservation page" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Tb1K5arqACZZowqEDnQbI9ipG8c=/0x0:614x409/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68663893/galaxys21reservation.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Samsung&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;All of the things we’re expecting to unpack on January 14th&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="rUvTfn"&gt;Samsung will be holding its Unpacked event on January 14th at 10AM ET, and we’ve already got a pretty clear picture of what it’ll be releasing. Obviously, the Galaxy S21 will be shown off in its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21570706/samsung-galaxy-s21-phones-leaks-rumors"&gt;regular, Plus, and Ultra varieties&lt;/a&gt;, and it seems like we’ll be seeing a new pair of wireless earbuds and tracking tags alongside the phones. This post has all of the rumors we’ve gathered up until now, and we’ll be adding all of the news from the event as it happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="roxUjy"&gt;Samsung hasn’t been shy about the fact that it’s releasing a new phone — you can even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22202683/samsung-galaxy-s21-ultra-plus-s-pen-preorder-reserve"&gt;already reserve a preorder for it&lt;/a&gt;. The company has also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22175769/samsung-stylus-galaxy-phones-s21-foldable"&gt;more or less confirmed&lt;/a&gt; that the S Pen stylus, previously limited to the Note line of phones, will be coming to the Galaxy S line. Rumors also indicate that the phones will include a wide variety of cameras but not a charger in the box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y88PdC"&gt;It’s also expected that Samsung will launch &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/24/22198622/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-price-specs-active-noise-cancelation"&gt;a $199 set of wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt;, dubbed the Galaxy Buds Pro, which are rumored to have active noise cancellation. We may also see &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22221020/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-smarttags-s21-ultra-pre-order-january-14th"&gt;a tracking tag&lt;/a&gt; meant to compete with the likes of Tile, possibly called the Galaxy SmartTag. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DInwvC"&gt;The hours are short until the event, but if you’d like to see a list of all the things we expect to see, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22220913/samsung-unpacked-event-date-time-galaxy-s21-phones-earbuds"&gt;you can check out our full roundup&lt;/a&gt;. Otherwise, we’ll see you back here when everything kicks off so you’ll have all your Unpacked news in one place.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22229537/samsung-unpacked-galaxy-s21-event-buds-pro-announcements"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22229537/samsung-unpacked-galaxy-s21-event-buds-pro-announcements</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
      <name>Thomas Ricker</name>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T16:28:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T16:28:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>Qualcomm just bought a two-year-old startup founded by former Apple engineers for $1.4 billion</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ByI-VZRgXa3MpWsXI_iXNs_238k=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68663783/acastro_180529_1777_qualcomm_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iMaorN"&gt;Qualcomm has just made a &lt;a href="https://www.qualcomm.com/news/releases/2021/01/13/qualcomm-acquire-nuvia?mkt_tok=eyJpIjoiWm1RMk1qazFOV0ZqT1dWaCIsInQiOiJpdWM0WjJIUitvMlgxOHNvS1Y2WWY3VXBBQ2xZY0lSd1I1eXNRdVpIRVJNcXlEd2d1QlZKcUljMHl4WnhDYmgrRWhcL3Irc3VFTEo3M3lLUDVQUHQzZUdaS3BtTUZlTitXMTB5bEFhdXZoRWlieGZ4d3QwM2lVS1FoNDVyYWVSOU8ifQ%3D%3D"&gt;splashy acquisition&lt;/a&gt; in the chip market that’s sure to shake up the semiconductor industry in a substantial fashion. The company Qualcomm is purchasing, Nuvia, was formed in 2019 by three former engineers and chip specialists, all of whom &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/15/three-of-apple-and-googles-former-star-chip-designers-launch-nuvia-with-53m-in-series-a-funding/"&gt;worked at Apple on the A-series chip line that powers the iPhone and iPad&lt;/a&gt;. And now, Qualcomm is paying an eye-popping $1.4 billion for the firm, placing a huge bet on the team’s talent and its focus on building next-generation CPUs for use in data centers, mobile, and other devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AdD4RT"&gt;Qualcomm is specifically calling out the growth of 5G as one of the reasons it’s paying such a handsome sum for a company of just a couple hundred employees founded just two years ago. “5G is further accelerating the convergence of mobility and computing. The acquisition of Nuvia builds on Qualcomm Technologies’ Snapdragon technology leadership, delivering step-function improvements in CPU performance and power efficiency to meet the demands of next-generation 5G computing,” Qualcomm said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IMpB2x"&gt;All three of the company’s co-founders — Gerard Williams, Manu Gulati, and John Bruno — will be joining Qualcomm, which expects to integrate the company’s chips “across Qualcomm Technologies’ broad portfolio of products,” including the modems and chips that make their way into data centers, smartphones, laptops, vehicles, and other devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="p7npXr"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Nuvia is just two years old, but Qualcomm is paying $1.4 billion to acquire its technology&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="M5vI10"&gt;“CPU performance leadership will be critical in defining and delivering on the next era of computing innovation,” Nuvia CEO Gerard Williams, formerly chief CPU architect at Apple, said in a statement. “The combination of Nuvia and Qualcomm will bring the industry’s best engineering talent, technology and resources together to create a new class of high-performance computing platforms that set the bar for our industry.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="twDKSg"&gt;Qualcomm is collecting tech and talent and taking aim at the data center industry at a time of significant change in the chip market. Many companies that once used to rely on big-name chipmakers like AMD, Intel, and Qualcomm have spent much of the last decade building out their own internal chip design teams to lessen their reliance on third-party companies and to better integrate their hardware and software. This is true not just of Apple, at which Nuvia’s co-founders gained their expertise, but also Amazon, Google, Facebook, and others, too. (Nuvia’s other two co-founders worked on chip design at Google, too.) All of these companies are building their own chips for use in everything from data centers to smart speakers and everything in between, often licensing the Arm architecture to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VZcE2Q"&gt;That’s put Qualcomm at odds with companies it used to consider core partners. Apple and Qualcomm, in fact, engaged in a bitter multiyear patent infringement legal battle the two companies &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/16/18410985/apple-qualcomm-settle-royalty-dispute-patent-licensing-terms-high-fees"&gt;settled in 2019,&lt;/a&gt; but the message was clear: Apple was tired of paying other companies to license their tech and would rather go it alone using Arm-based designs. That was only further cemented by Apple’s landmark decision to drop Intel in the CPU field for Apple’s own custom-designed line of M1 processors, which arrived on the scene last fall powering the first of many new Apple computers to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21569603/apple-macbook-air-m1-review-price-specs-features-arm-silicon"&gt;critical acclaim thanks to their huge performance gains&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lWPZV7"&gt;While Apple and Qualcomm cut a deal for the iPhone maker to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/1/18525962/qualcomm-apple-settlement-4-5-billion-dollars-patent"&gt;continue using Qualcomm’s modems&lt;/a&gt;, including its 5G ones that enable the network capabilities on the latest iPhones, Apple is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22168779/apple-leak-cellular-modem-johny-srouji-town-hall"&gt;reportedly hard at work on building its own cellular modems&lt;/a&gt; to further extricate itself from Qualcomm in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="auSOKt"&gt;And that’s where a company like Nuvia comes in. While many companies are building their own Arm-based CPUs to compete with AMD and Intel in the data center — like &lt;a href="https://www.anandtech.com/show/15578/cloud-clash-amazon-graviton2-arm-against-intel-and-amd"&gt;Amazon’s Graviton chip&lt;/a&gt; — Nuvia is &lt;a href="https://venturebeat.com/2020/09/24/nuvia-raises-240-million-to-design-arm-based-cpus-for-datacenters/"&gt;reportedly building a more flexible custom chip core&lt;/a&gt; (also based on Arm) called Phoenix. That chip core could result in a variety of different CPUs down the line, not just those designed to act as data center processors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AWkUEz"&gt;“We’re designing our own core from the ground up,” Williams &lt;a href="https://venturebeat.com/2020/09/24/nuvia-raises-240-million-to-design-arm-based-cpus-for-datacenters/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;VentureBeat &lt;/em&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt;, when the company raised $240 million in a Series B funding round. “Our secret sauce is really physical design capabilities and microarchitecture. And that’s where you see the differentiation coming into play for almost anybody that builds a processor.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xAsNbS"&gt;Williams said at the time that the speed and efficiency of its chip core was “very much like a mobile core in terms of size and power,” but with with “substantially higher” performance, a prescient statement to make considering Qualcomm’s plans to use Nuvia technology in its mobile Snapdragon system-on-a-chip line. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22229497/qualcomm-apple-nuvia-acquisition-cpu-chip-design-data-center"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22229497/qualcomm-apple-nuvia-acquisition-cpu-chip-design-data-center</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T16:24:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T16:24:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best Apple Watch deals right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zLjcArAq4sGebo8JT2J9VP6QFsQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66976955/vpavic_200930_4216_0258.6.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Mf4umG"&gt;Thinking about picking up a new Apple Watch? It’s never a bad idea to wait until there’s a good deal, and thankfully, those happen with some regularity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FtR5HF"&gt;There are currently three models to choose from, all of which support &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/22/21294434/apple-watchos-7-features-sleep-tracking-face-sharing-fitness-apps-2020"&gt;watchOS 7&lt;/a&gt;. The latest model, and the highest end, is the Apple Watch Series 6 with GPS and Wi-Fi connectivity, which starts at $399. If that’s a little too expensive, you can drop about $120 off the price by buying an Apple Watch SE, which also launched this fall. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Im58vs"&gt;Finally, the three-year-old &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/21/16680206/apple-watch-series-3-non-lte-smartwatch-review"&gt;Series 3&lt;/a&gt; is the most affordable Apple Watch model to date. It has a starting retail price of $199, but it frequently goes on sale. If you’re looking for something to last a few years, though, it’s probably worth looking at one of the other two watches, as it’s not clear how much longer Apple will deliver software updates to the Series 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X6WKu4"&gt;While deals are a fairly regular occurrence, there will be times where there are no price drops on new models. For those times, we also include some deals on refurbished models.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="support watchOS 7" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-2TkUJkurmgX8ZHUE8HnJGYxv-s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/9693867/akrales_171113_2119_0045.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple Watch Series 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="OlUIlK"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/21/16680206/apple-watch-series-3-non-lte-smartwatch-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple Watch Series 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="c2iEiy"&gt;The regular price for the 38mm Series 3 is $199 ($229 for the 42mm), which is a decent deal. It’s a great entry-level Apple Watch if you are looking for a smartwatch with reliable battery life and don’t want to burn a massive hole in your wallet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ns6w5t"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple Watch Series 3 (non-LTE) review: third time’s the charm","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/21/16680206/apple-watch-series-3-non-lte-smartwatch-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="q5eI6X"&gt;Currently, the 38mm Series 3 is $169 at &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-Series-3-GPS-38mm-Sport-Band-Aluminum-Case%2F499753351%3Fwmlspartner%3Dwlpa%26selectedSellerId%3D0%26wl13%3D2435%26%26adid%3D22222222227257067173%26wl0%3D%26wl1%3Dg%26wl2%3Dc%26wl3%3D304471618288%26wl4%3Dpla-546497580682%26wl5%3D9008008%26wl6%3D%26wl7%3D%26wl8%3D%26wl9%3Dpla%26wl10%3D8175035%26wl11%3Dlocal%26wl12%3D499753351%26veh%3Dsem%26gclid%3DCjwKCAiAoOz-BRBdEiwAyuvA664EIRAtCz_lz7elMSJ9eUHfN0gX3036s_ONGfk5-66T-g5QFKrPNRoCoA0QAvD_BwE%26irgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_ywp0i3SwExyOT35wUx0Mo38vUkEUlN3vWQ-N3A0%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_482924%26clickid%3Dywp0i3SwExyOT35wUx0Mo38vUkEUlN3vWQ-N3A0%26sharedid%3Dverge%26affiliates_ad_id%3D565706%26campaign_id%3D9383&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; (spacey gray only). Or for $189 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07K37HKT8/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=vergegooddeals-20&amp;amp;linkId=0d1a72f49279f5c3ff832b7b9721e419&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1725327349047065530" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, which is $10 off its usual price of $199. If you are looking for the Series 3 in 42mm, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Watch-GPS-38mm-Space-Aluminium/dp/B07K387Y7K?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-Series-3-GPS-42mm-Sport-Band-Aluminum-Case%2F185638711&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, have knocked $30 off its price, bringing it down to $199. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="LW3abi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9514914"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E_QxMIj0p0peveuBy3iswJodr-A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21926110/dseifert_200930_4218_0009.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple Watch SE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="kKDn2C"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496928/apple-watch-se-review-smartwatch-wearos-price-specs-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple Watch SE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="GaARPa"&gt;Starting at $279 for a 40mm version or $309 for the 44mm, the Apple Watch SE is a good midrange wearable and shares some features also found on the flagship Series 6 model, such as a built-in accelerometer and hand-washing detection. But it doesn’t have the always-on display found on the Series 5 and Series 6. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="0eLZZK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple Watch SE review: pay a lot less to give up only a little","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21496928/apple-watch-se-review-smartwatch-wearos-price-specs-features"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="6p1Qub"&gt;The best deal right now on the Apple Watch SE 40mm with GPS is at Amazon, which has knocked $9 off its normal price in gold or space gray, bringing the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-Apple-Watch-SE-40mm/dp/B08J5W9QWZ/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;th=1&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=f487a960520964ac860d89f77404bb1b&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;price down to $270&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NYyAAC"&gt;The 44mm with GPS is also on sale at several retailers. The lowest you can currently get this model for at Amazon is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-Apple-Watch-SE-40mm/dp/B08J5XTRZD/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=b1bbcc98b9b514babd7b0198463cd917&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;th=1" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$270 in space gray&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-Apple-Watch-SE-40mm/dp/B08J5QB5QT/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;th=1&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=f16e9235da90ab510af5e23d08d74daf&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$280 for silver with a white band&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-Apple-Watch-SE-40mm/dp/B08J5V7H7H/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=b1bbcc98b9b514babd7b0198463cd917&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;th=1" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$294 for gold&lt;/a&gt;. Walmart also has this model on sale for &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-SE-GPS-44mm-Space-Gray-Aluminum-Case-with-Black-Sport-Band-Regular%2F460386378%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$270 in space gray with a black sport band&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-SE-GPS-44mm-Silver-Aluminum-Case-with-White-Sport-Band-Regular%2F168696232%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$280 in silver&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-SE-GPS-44mm-Gold-Aluminum-Case-with-Pink-Sand-Sport-Band-Regular%2F804932402%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$294 in gold&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="NRwn2Q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9514947"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="3BP7mi"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Apple Watch Series 6 review: a minute update|95764" data-volume-uuid="447f29cb2" data-volume-id="95764" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-405" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="xtEsXh"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496141/apple-watch-series-6-review-blood-oxygen-monitor-watchos-7"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple Watch Series 6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="oTrUCf"&gt;The flagship Apple Watch comes in two sizes, 40mm and 44mm, with respective starting costs of $399 and $429. The Apple Watch Series 6 features more sensors than previous models, including a sensor that allows the device to detect your body's blood oxygen levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="QdFhyi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple Watch Series 6 review: minute improvements","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21496141/apple-watch-series-6-review-blood-oxygen-monitor-watchos-7"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="jwogLj"&gt;If you are looking for the 40mm with GPS, Amazon has the lowest price right now for this model for as low as &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-Apple-Watch-GPS-40mm-Aluminum/dp/B08J5RBMRN/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;th=1&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=6439a0460fc67d733f45fd0ffdf01e6a&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$339 if you buy the watch in red&lt;/a&gt; or $379 in &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-Apple-Watch-GPS-40mm-Aluminum/dp/B08J5QC43Q/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=186125dd4ed9ccbf40a9c028391fe1db&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;other colors&lt;/a&gt;. Walmart is price matching this product if you &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-Series-6-GPS-40mm-Space-Gray-Aluminum-Case-with-Black-Sport-Band-Regular%2F896460500%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;buy this configuration in spacey gray&lt;/a&gt;. Best Buy has also discounted this model, knocking &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1726819561729688298" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$20 off its usual $399 price&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xMKKL1"&gt;If you are looking for the 44mm size with GPS, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08J5MK16F/ref=as_li_ss_tl?th=1&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=30541eb55d80dc34c4bb5ff46d3f21e0&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1725901169577600920" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; have this model on sale for $409. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="stLULs"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9432291"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21289209/best-apple-watch-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21289209/best-apple-watch-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T16:16:27-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T16:16:27-05:00</updated>
    <title>Cyberpunk 2077’s first major update coming in the next 10 days</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Cyberpunk 2077" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/O7e5ixRQfKMapn8dkQeMDuErC50=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68663685/Cyberpunk_2077_screen_5.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: CD Projekt Red&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Noiy2M"&gt;Following the disastrous launch of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22157995/cyberpunk-2077-cd-projekt-red-review-xbox-ps4-ps5-pc-stadia"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;/a&gt; CD Projekt Red says it will release the first update within the next 10 days, with “a larger, more significant update, in the weeks after.” In a video released today, co-founder Marcin Iwinski issued a mea culpa to players, adding that he and the board members are “the final decision makers” for the game’s faulty release. “Please, don’t fault any of our teams for what happened,” Iwinski said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Etczl1"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077 l&lt;/em&gt;aunched December 10th, 2020, with immediate problems. While the game’s PC release was mostly praised by critics, console players — particularly those playing on the older generations — ran into widespread bugs, frame-rate issues, and more. A week after the game’s release, Sony &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22188007/sony-cyberpunk-2077-removed-playstation-store-full-refunds-policy"&gt;pulled &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;from the PlayStation Store and began offering refunds. An investor is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/25/22199768/cdprojekt-cyberpunk-2077-lawsuit-launch"&gt;suing CD Projekt Red&lt;/a&gt; over the disastrous launch. Today, you can buy the PC version of the game for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/1/13/22228682/cyberpunk-2077-pc-sale-deal-gog-sony-headphones"&gt;nearly half-off.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qYB3ER"&gt;In the five-minute video posted today, Iwinksi said that “despite good reviews on PC, the console version of &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; did not meet the quality standard we wanted it to meet. I and the entire leadership team are deeply sorry for this.” Iwinksi went on to point to the massive scope of the game and the developer’s grave underestimations of how much work it would take to match vision to reality, as well as the difficulties of working from home due to Covid. “We really believed we would deliver in the final days,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CFC3kO"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O3V4UBZmC9o?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gnEufC"&gt;On its site, CD Projekt Red outlined concerns in an FAQ. In response to the quality gap between the PC version of the game and older generation consoles, the developer said it made the work “more difficult for ourselves by first wanting to make the game look epic on PCs and then adjusting it to consoles — especially old-gens. That was our core assumption. And things did not look super difficult at first, while we knew the hardware gap, ultimately, time has proven that we’ve underestimated the task.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="igKnU7"&gt;Moving forward, CD Projekt Red says it is “committed to fixing bugs and crashes and will continue to work and improve the game via future updates to make sure you are enjoying the game regardless of the platform.” That work will apparently impact the game’s free DLC, planned for release this year, as well. “We have decided that our priority is working on the most important fixes and updates. We will be releasing free DLC afterwards — we’ll have more to say about that in the coming months.” The developer added that it intends to do so without “obligatory” overtime, despite the &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2020/12/4/21575914/cyberpunk-2077-release-crunch-labor-delays-cd-projekt-red"&gt;months of crunch&lt;/a&gt; leading up to the game’s release. “Avoiding crunch on all of our future projects is one of our top priorities.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hpkvlz"&gt;As for the game’s return to digital storefronts, the developer says it is “working on fixes and updates, and are working with Sony to bring &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; back to PlayStation Store as soon as possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IFMc19"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22229627/cyberpunk-2077-first-update-launch-cd-projekt-red-playstation-store"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22229627/cyberpunk-2077-first-update-launch-cd-projekt-red-playstation-store</id>
    <author>
      <name>Megan Farokhmanesh</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T15:34:18-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T15:34:18-05:00</updated>
    <title>Period tracking app settles charges it lied to users about privacy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2jDuuIR-ZoUEP0FSiiuznE-6q5Y=/0x0:6720x4480/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68663380/Main_Screen_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="R5x65L"&gt;A popular period and fertility tracking app has &lt;a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/press-releases/2021/01/developer-popular-womens-fertility-tracking-app-settles-ftc"&gt;settled with the Federal Trade Commission&lt;/a&gt; over allegations that it lied to users about sharing private health information with third-party firms, including Facebook and Google. Flo, a period and ovulation tracking app, has more than 100 million users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tnSKKJ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ftc.gov/system/files/documents/cases/flo_health_complaint.pdf"&gt;In the complaint&lt;/a&gt;, the FTC alleges Flo told users their information would be kept private. Then it shared their sensitive health data, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/20/18508382/apps-mental-health-smoking-cessation-data-sharing-privacy-facebook-google-advertising"&gt;including the dates of their periods and their pregnancy plans&lt;/a&gt;, with outside companies that provided marketing and analytics services to the app. It also failed to limit how this data would be used. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZQdHTY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The move could have allowed Facebook to match sensitive health information with users’ profiles&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Ak0GGY"&gt;The move could have allowed Facebook to match sensitive health information with users’ profiles and target ads at them more effectively. As some users are more willing to share private information with an app like Flo than a major social network, the disclosures can feel invasive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hIv6WZ"&gt;“Apps that collect, use, and share sensitive health information can provide valuable services, but consumers need to be able to trust these apps,” said Andrew Smith, director of the FTC’s Bureau of Consumer Protection. “We are looking closely at whether developers of health apps are keeping their promises and handling sensitive health information responsibly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ufIW8K"&gt;News of the settlement follows a &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/you-give-apps-sensitive-personal-information-then-they-tell-facebook-11550851636?mod=e2tw"&gt;2019 report from &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;which revealed that Flo was secretly sharing sensitive user data with Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qp7MdY"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/20/18508382/apps-mental-health-smoking-cessation-data-sharing-privacy-facebook-google-advertising"&gt;A 2019 study published in &lt;em&gt;JAMA Network Open&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; also showed that apps marketed to people with depression or who wanted to quit smoking were sharing health data with Facebook and Google as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MZzx93"&gt;As part of the settlement, Flo has to notify users about how their personal information was shared and ask for their permission before sharing more information in the future. The company also has to receive an independent audit of its privacy practices. It did not admit any wrongdoing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Va1UZG"&gt;In a statement emailed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, a spokesperson for Flo said: “We are glad to have reached an agreement with the FTC and resolved the matter. We will be conducting a compliance review into our policies and procedures as requested as part of the Consent Agreement and providing the FTC with regular updates. We are committed to ensuring that the privacy of our users’ personal health data is absolutely paramount.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ADGTDr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 13th, 4:35PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article has been updated with a statement from Flo. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8xj6Uc"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="20fV8a"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n5kmVc"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oN8TS5"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22229303/flo-period-tracking-app-privacy-health-data-facebook-google"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22229303/flo-period-tracking-app-privacy-health-data-facebook-google</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T15:31:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T15:31:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>Valve’s Steam Year in Review shows PC gaming on the rise — and VR, too</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/scfReSYwtQBxRsX7HiwfD1d5FF0=/0x0:1820x1213/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68663334/acastro_180509_1777_steam_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pBFmV0"&gt;Valve is doing its part to illustrate gaming’s growth last year with &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/group/4145017/view/2961646623386540826"&gt;its Steam 2020 Year in Review&lt;/a&gt; report. It includes some rather impressive numbers, like the fact that PC gamers increased their playtime by over 50 percent last year, and that &lt;em&gt;each month&lt;/em&gt;, 2.6 million people bought a game on Steam for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Tg4vd"&gt;2020 was a rough year, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21536084/video-games-ps4-ps5-xbox-series-x-among-us-animal-crossing"&gt;many of us used gaming as a way to escape&lt;/a&gt; from the awfulness of everything going on in the world — an aim helped by the fact that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22158504/best-games-2020-ps5-xbox-nintendo-tlou2-animal-crossing-miles-morales"&gt;so many good games&lt;/a&gt; were released last year. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/6/22215786/video-games-covid-19-animal-crossing-among-us"&gt;Over half of Americans played video games in 2020&lt;/a&gt;, and while Steam’s numbers only represent the PC (and doesn’t count games like &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; that appear on rival PC stores), it still speaks to the fact that PC gaming is not just surviving, but thriving. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-bzE4az-Wzhwgc1Ac74UyTSkefI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22233454/ca3ca74e50490d1db3dfdd3823bc73f7514e9606.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Valve&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The statistics bear out what we all felt: 2020 was a year for gaming.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="e6wAaF"&gt;In addition to the extra time spent playing and the newcomers to the platform, Steam’s data also shows that the number of games sold grew by 21.4 percent, and the platform had as many as 24.8 million people playing at once, setting a new record for concurrent players &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/16/21181272/steam-concurrent-user-record-set-cs-go"&gt;for the second time that year&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vle4Ao"&gt;2020 was also the year that Valve’s own &lt;em&gt;Half-Life: Alyx&lt;/em&gt; came out, which we hoped &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/22/20977938/half-life-alyx-vr-reactions-opinions-verge-staff"&gt;might finally be a killer app for VR&lt;/a&gt;, a game that would finally entice people to give VR a go. Do Steam’s numbers bear that out? Well, VR certainly grew, with 1.7 million people using Steam’s VR interface for the first time, potentially due to new headsets coming out to rave reviews, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21437674/oculus-quest-2-review-features-photos"&gt;like the Oculus Quest 2&lt;/a&gt;. Valve also reports that there was a 71 percent increase in VR sales, with &lt;em&gt;Alyx&lt;/em&gt; alone making up 39 percent of them. People were playing more in VR as well, with playtime going up by 30 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KjzdzxpXMJdo9DooiKWkGQWqUyA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22233451/f82d7d992ee4f90f6b3a4d54670692e4b9367e21.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Valve&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steam’s VR stats are looking up.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="0H2aUd"&gt;Speaking of PC games being played outside the traditional “mouse and keyboard connected to a Windows machine” model, Valve also notes a 66.6 percent increase in game sessions that were played with a controller. Steam also notes its work on bringing games to Linux with its Proton runtime and calls out &lt;em&gt;Death Stranding&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; as games that were available on the OS soon after they were released on Windows. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1vnJgC"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22229234/valve-steam-2020-review-pc-gaming-vr-expanding"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22229234/valve-steam-2020-review-pc-gaming-vr-expanding</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T15:10:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T15:10:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>Streamer CriticalBard talks being the temporary face of PogChamp</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MQmFbUdIkEluAuX2RhN_612SmJY=/0x121:904x724/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68663162/Screen_Shot_2021_01_13_at_1.57.38_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="p54sBG"&gt;Last week, Twitch &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22220874/twitch-pogchamp-face-change-ryan-gootecks-gutierrez"&gt;deleted the face of its extremely popular PogChamp emote&lt;/a&gt;, Ryan “Gootecks” Gutierrez, after he called for further violence at the Capitol just after a mob sacked the building. In the aftermath, Twitch responded to a suggestion from the community for the emote — why not have a different face represent hype on Twitch every day? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Ki6a6q"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Yo &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Twitch?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Twitch&lt;/a&gt; suggestion for PogChamp: create a database of streamer and/or general faces.  Whenever someone types PogChamp, display one of those faces at random.  Would give a really nice crowd feel to a chat spamming PogChamp and allow the meaning to be tied to all of us instead.&lt;/p&gt;— Sean Plott (@day9tv) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/day9tv/status/1347021857359163393?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XZ8ngi"&gt;So that’s what the company did. Three days after the experiment began, &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/criticalbard"&gt;Omega “CriticalBard” Jones&lt;/a&gt;, a partnered Black streamer who writes music for &lt;em&gt;Critical Role&lt;/em&gt;, took his turn as the face of the global emote. The racist harassment came almost immediately. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ieFIeH"&gt;“At the beginning it was fine. I was nervous. I’ll say beforehand I prepped my mods on Twitch,” Jones says. “And they were like, ‘Well, the person who’s a PogChamp today seems like they’re doing fine. So I think you’ll be fine.’ I said ‘Ha but I’m Black.’” Jones started receiving comments on Twitter from people saying that he didn’t look like PogChamp, that Twitch should bring back the old emote instead, and then “a crap ton of people, you know, saying racist things.” After he went live on Twitch, however, the trouble really began. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F9jiSv"&gt;Jones was playing &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; with friends — “not playing it well, which is why I don’t do competitive,” he says — when Twitch users stormed his chat saying that he didn’t deserve to be PogChamp. “But it got to the subject of Black lives not mattering and other stuff,” Jones says. “And then someone mentioned white Lives Matter, whatever. And I said ‘No, white lives don’t matter because a white life isn’t a thing.’” Someone clipped it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nwQFxX"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Last thing before I actually lay down.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Some dudebros decided to clip a small part of my stream making it seem like I was "being racist towards white folk."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Allow me to post the FULL clip &amp;amp; take from it what you will.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;xoxo.&lt;br&gt;GossipPogChamp. &lt;a href="https://t.co/jNZq6iDvSk"&gt;pic.twitter.com/jNZq6iDvSk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— CRITICAL BARD! ✊  (@CriticalBard) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CriticalBard/status/1348743164459421705?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NkuopX"&gt;The clip went viral in places like the Twitch drama subreddit &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/LivestreamFail/comments/kv9urp/new_face_of_pogchamp_responds_to_racist_tweets/"&gt;/r/LivestreamFail&lt;/a&gt; and across the live stream-watching internet. It was, however, pulled out of its context. “I said you can be proud of being Italian, you can be proud of being Scottish — because those are nationalities,” says Jones, echoing what he said in the full version of the clip. “That’s your heritage.” He continued: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="WoTcqj"&gt;You cannot be proud of being white. Because whiteness is a concept that was only created because blackness became a thing. And the only reason blackness is a thing because we as a Black people were taken away from Africa without our consent, enslaved, and left for dust. Our literal heritage and identity was taken away from us. All we have to hold on to in America — for the most part, most Black people — is our blackness. So, there is a Black culture, there is not a white culture. There was never a white culture. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="XlIOJb"&gt;It’s an elegant way to put a pretty complicated concept, one that people across the internet seem intent on misunderstanding. To discuss race in America is to discuss power dynamics and history, which is something that’s hard to understand if it behooves you to not understand it. Jones says he was trying to explain that to people. “But you know racists gotta be racist,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lOj6ME"&gt;Jones says he wanted to be the face of PogChamp because it was going to mean a lot to other people who want to see marginalized people on Twitch. “I can deal with a little bit of bull if that means someone else gets to see something that’s, you know, them. Their color. Or somebody they can identify with,” he says. He was also into the idea of a community-based rotating emote. “The funny thing is people don’t even care about PogChamp as a person. They just care about keeping what they consider to be tradition,” says Jones. “But if PogChamp is about that excitement, it shouldn’t matter who the face of that is.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iZUEcc"&gt;Jones’ harassment points to a larger problem on Twitch: the site doesn’t seem to know how to protect its creators from marginalized backgrounds from the toxic elements of its community. Jones told me that the Twitch representative who initially reached out to him about being the face of PogChamp did say the company planned on giving future PogChamp faces additional moderation support in their channels. But Jones says that’s not enough. “What annoys me about that is instead of doing what y’all can do, which is ban these people from your platform — if we want to get into it, you need to start banning IP addresses,” says Jones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eKR6Mo"&gt;Furthermore, Jones says, it’s not as though the Black Twitch community hasn’t spoken up to the company about the issue in the past. “Like, it wasn’t just yesterday where someone said, ‘Twitch, you need to fix this.’ Racism has been very wild on Twitch for a long time. And they’ve yet to do anything about it,” says Jones. “So it makes us go like, ‘Okay, so what’s the point?’” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Spzy4i"&gt;Twitch obliquely referenced Jones’ harassment in a Twitter thread yesterday, where the company wrote that it believes in celebrating diversity. A Twitch spokesperson sent me the following statement when I asked for more details:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="wnwfz9"&gt;Highlighting a new PogChamp every day was an idea that came directly from our community and was created in the spirit of celebrating the diversity of creators on Twitch. While we’ve seen an overwhelmingly positive response from both the community and those highlighted, we are also in close contact with the new faces of PogChamp to offer support as needed. We do not tolerate harassment on Twitch, and will take action on any behaviors on our service that violate our rules.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div id="VvvJIa"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Hateful conduct and harassment stand in the way of that ideal, and they have no place on Twitch, social media, or anywhere else. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We’ll continue to take action against those who violate our community guidelines and seek to harm our community and creators.&lt;/p&gt;— Twitch (@Twitch) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Twitch/status/1349188693337141258?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 13, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3GgSYQ"&gt;But in Jones’ view, that isn’t enough. “They didn’t even say ‘we were sorry.’ They said, we’re working to make this place more diverse and all this stuff,” he says. “They didn’t condemn anything. They need to start condemning this stuff,” Jones continues. “They need to start saying, ‘This is not what we want as a platform. This is not what we promote as a platform. And people are going to start seeing the repercussions of their actions. Start seeing the consequences of the things that they do.’” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cghcil"&gt;Jones also took pains to clarify that it wasn’t just random Twitch users who came to his stream to harass him. He says it was directed by some affiliates and Twitch partners. “If Twitch is a company that’s saying, ‘We don’t agree with that,’ then you need to show that you don’t agree with that. AKA, terminating them accounts, getting rid of them partner badges. Getting rid of that affiliate status. Because I’m pretty sure in the partner and affiliate rules and all that stuff, you can’t really be, you know, doing hate speech and all that. But I guess, when Twitch is making money, it’s fine?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DTzmWF"&gt;The harassment hasn’t fazed Jones, though. Some members of the community rallied to his defense, like &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/hasanabi"&gt;Hasan “hasanabi” Piker&lt;/a&gt;, a prominent political streamer, who defended Jones on his own stream. “I loved watching the clip of Hasan,” says Jones. “One of the best things that can just give you all the light, the nutrients that your life needs, is watching these folk look up to somebody and expect them to like be on their side, and they’re not.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="X1a9so"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://clips.twitch.tv/embed?clip=HappyAgreeableArmadilloHeyGuys&amp;amp;autoplay=false&amp;amp;parent=www.theverge.com&amp;amp;parent=iframe.ly&amp;amp;parent=iframely.com&amp;amp;parent=cdn.iframe.ly&amp;amp;parent=if-cdn.com" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="t6oc6u"&gt;He also told me that he saw a large influx of new subscribers — “But I’m not gonna be like, ‘Thank you for being racist,’” jokes Jones — and that he’s still here. “Black folk have had to walk through this world on high alert, since we were practically born,” he says. “So there is literally nothing they can do. I got doxxed. I got death threats. You can say all that behind your keyboard that you barely can afford, with your two viewership. You can say all that, but understand that you’re only fueling me.”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mwCr3q"&gt;February is Black History Month, and Jones tells me that Twitch has already started reaching out to prominent Black creators about activations. It’s an open question whether Twitch’s overhauled Hateful Conduct policy — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22165342/twitch-hateful-conduct-harassment-policy-update"&gt;which was announced in December and goes into effect at the end of this month&lt;/a&gt; — will have an impact on the droves of people who swarm marginalized creators when Twitch gives them the spotlight. As with everything else, the devil is in the enforcement. Will Twitch protect its marginalized creators? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jVunLY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22229209/criticalbard-pogchamp-gootecks-hasanabi-twitch-emote-harassment"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22229209/criticalbard-pogchamp-gootecks-hasanabi-twitch-emote-harassment</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bijan Stephen</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T14:46:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T14:46:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>Belkin wireless charger sold by Apple is being recalled for fire hazards</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/auIZmerAseUZlB7ENAjX5ZRmgHI=/9x0:674x443/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68663023/Screen_Shot_2021_01_13_at_11.10.15_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Belkin&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="m7NpHH"&gt;Belkin is voluntarily recalling its &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.belkin.com%2Fus%2Fsupport-article%3FarticleNum%3D317696&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F1%2F13%2F22229147%2Fapple-belkin-recall-wireless-charging-stand-fire-shock-hazard#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Portable Wireless Charger + Stand Special Edition&lt;/a&gt; that was sold in Apple retail stores and online on Apple and Belkin’s sites because of fire and shock safety hazards. No incidents or injuries have been connected to the charger, according to &lt;a href="https://www.cpsc.gov/Recalls/2021/Belkin-Recalls-Portable-Wireless-Chargers-Stand-Special-Edition-Due-to-Fire-and-Shock-Hazards"&gt;the Consumer Product Safety Commission&lt;/a&gt;, and the malfunction should only affect chargers sold between July 2020 and October 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1xiCAu"&gt;The wireless charging stand has a 10,000mAh power capacity and can charge at 10W speed for phones that support it, but an issue with the “power supply unit” could cause the device to overheat and leave it vulnerable to catching fire or shocking people. Belkin is advising anyone who’s purchased the device to stop using it and unplug it from power. The company will also issue refunds to anyone who owns an affected charger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0AnByf"&gt;In the grand scheme of Apple’s iPhones, wireless charging has only been available since the 2017 launch of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/19/16323570/apple-new-iphone-8-review-plus-2017"&gt;iPhone 8&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/31/16579748/apple-iphone-x-review"&gt;iPhone X&lt;/a&gt;. Apple announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/12/16278310/apple-iphone-8-wireless-charging"&gt;AirPower&lt;/a&gt; at the same event, a wireless charging mat that was supposed to charge multiple devices at once, but it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/3/29/18287383/apple-airpower-wireless-charger-cancelled"&gt;ultimately canceled&lt;/a&gt; because it didn’t meet Apple’s “high standards.” Rumors later pointed to issues with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/17/17869072/apple-airpower-overheating-issues"&gt;the device’s charging coils overheating&lt;/a&gt; as part of the motivation for Apple canceling. All of this to say, wireless charging is harder than it looks, and Belkin’s recall is yet another example of issues that can arise in a deceptively simple product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qJEUoA"&gt;If you own a charger affected by the recall, you can submit a form to request a refund on &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.belkin.com%2Fus%2Fsupport%2Fwiz003recallform%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F1%2F13%2F22229147%2Fapple-belkin-recall-wireless-charging-stand-fire-shock-hazard#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Belkin’s support site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22229147/apple-belkin-recall-wireless-charging-stand-fire-shock-hazard"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22229147/apple-belkin-recall-wireless-charging-stand-fire-shock-hazard</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-13T14:45:17-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T14:45:17-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google says a fix for Android coronavirus tracking delays is on the way</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CbM1vlpQu56y_n4WVClH9U3uLCc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68660442/acastro_180427_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XXhsVI"&gt;Google says it’s working to investigate issues with Android apps that use the Android Exposure Notifications System to track the spread of COVID-19. An issue began causing delays for apps using the system, resulting in longer load times and delays in notifications for regular exposure checks. The NHS COVID-19 app that’s used across England and Wales is &lt;a href="https://github.com/nhsx/covid-19-app-android-ag-public/issues/39"&gt;affected by this Android issue&lt;/a&gt;, with a loading notification stuck in the notifications area for many users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ShOlj5"&gt;“We are aware of an issue affecting Android apps developed using the Android Exposure Notifications System,” a Google spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;in a statement earlier on Wednesday. “Our engineers are investigating the issue.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vGTXJ4"&gt;As of Wednesday afternoon, Google tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;it’s issued a fix, but it may take some time for issues to subside, though Google says it’ll work with any affected app developers directly to remedy the issue if it persists. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wqu882"&gt;“Late in the evening on January 12, an issue with the Exposure Notifications System on Android began causing delays in the checking of potential exposures for those with apps installed,” a Google spokesperson said in a statement. “We have issued a fix. It may take a few hours for devices to catch up, and in some cases we will work directly with developers to help with recovery. The issue did not cause the loss of any data or potential exposures.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QxyH51"&gt;Google also provided some clarity on the issue. The company tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;the issue was with the signature key configuration, which meant exposure notification apps ran into issues downloading diagnosis keys from their key servers. This resulted in notification delays, a serious issue given the important of timely contact tracing efforts in stemming the spread of any positive COVID-19 cases. Google advises users not clear their storage in the app while the fix is going out. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CANl41hv0gjAEgvFoXtqeg-yS-k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22232458/104391472_d3359b00_5537_11eb_96a2_002ba81410c6.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The NHS COVID-19 notification issue.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="W9M3fA"&gt;These issues have been affecting all apps worldwide that use the Android Exposure Notifications System. The CoronaMelder app in the Netherlands is also &lt;a href="https://nos.nl/liveblog/2364163-sneltest-verplicht-voor-reizigers-uit-vk-en-zuid-afrika-d66-wil-nu-geen-avondklok.html"&gt;experiencing issues&lt;/a&gt;. More than 10 million people in England and Wales downloaded the NHS COVID-19 app &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/nhs-covid-19-app-has-been-downloaded-over-10-million-times"&gt;in September&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s not clear how many total downloads have been made to date or the split between iOS and Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xXKmiC"&gt;Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/10/21216484/google-apple-coronavirus-contract-tracing-bluetooth-location-tracking-data-app"&gt;first introduced its coronavirus tracking system&lt;/a&gt; for Android in April 2020. The app uses Bluetooth to anonymously broadcast data and help enable tracking and tracing programs worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6CxwQs"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 13th 10:18AM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Article updated with details on the CoronaMelder app also experiencing issues.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZlHYK4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 13th, 2:45PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added a new statement from Google saying the company has pushed out a fix to solve the delays. The headline has also been updated to reflect this fact. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228594/google-coronavirus-tracking-app-exposure-notifications-issues-problems"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228594/google-coronavirus-tracking-app-exposure-notifications-issues-problems</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
