<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-05-31T15:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-31T15:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-31T15:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>EA’s new multiplayer dodgeball game is now free to play until you reach level 25</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ogvQ2vUmTrzN72-lzV4SFUyiuis=/80x0:943x575/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69367998/koc_screenshot_16x9_1.jpg.adapt.crop16x9.575p.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A screenshot from &lt;/em&gt;Knockout City&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: EA&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tTvtnp"&gt;EA just released its chaotic and fun new multiplayer dodgeball game, &lt;em&gt;Knockout City&lt;/em&gt;, on May 21st, and for the launch, had put together a special promotion: the full game would be free to play until May 30th, after which you could pay $19.99 on the platform of your choice if you wanted to keep playing. (It’s also included with an EA Play or Xbox Game Pass Ultimate subscription.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ms0z9a"&gt;But on Sunday, EA and developer Velan Studios announced that even if you missed that window to try &lt;em&gt;Knockout City&lt;/em&gt; without paying for it, you can still check it out without dropping a dime: the game is now free to try up until you level up your “Street Rank” (&lt;em&gt;Knockout City’s&lt;/em&gt; take on a &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;-like battle pass) to 25. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Saa7ly"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Block Party is over, but new players to Knockout City can still start brawlin' for free! &lt;br&gt;If your friends are just joining us, they'll be able to play for free and level up to Street Rank 25 before purchasing the game. That’s also enough game time to teach them to pass the ball. &lt;a href="https://t.co/aWjPjKS0ES"&gt;pic.twitter.com/aWjPjKS0ES&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Knockout City (@knockoutcity) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/knockoutcity/status/1398972535727955972?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 30, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DPv0z6"&gt;That level cap should give you few hours of playtime to try &lt;em&gt;Knockout City&lt;/em&gt; for yourself and decide if you want to pay full price for it. And I recommend you give the game a whirl — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453234/knockout-city-dodgeball-ea-velan-studios"&gt;I was impressed&lt;/a&gt; with just how well it captures the feeling of actually playing dodgeball. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OASw83"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Knockout City&lt;/em&gt; is available on PC, PS4, PS5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X / S, and Nintendo Switch, and it offers crossplay multiplayer, meaning you can play with your friends no matter what platform they’re on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="f9gEgI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Knockout City’s virtual dodgeball is even more chaotic than the real thing","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453234/knockout-city-dodgeball-ea-velan-studios"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/31/22462044/knockout-city-free-to-play-level-25-ea-velan-studios-dodgeball"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/31/22462044/knockout-city-free-to-play-level-25-ea-velan-studios-dodgeball</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-31T14:27:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-31T14:27:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>How bad is Google Photos’ compression anyway?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EjfUx8UkkENNwUi08FxdJa38kfM=/0x168:4032x2856/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69367842/newlede.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;My cat, Pretzel. The original photo is on the left, the compressed version is on the right.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GtCtkV"&gt;Google Photos has long offered one of the best deals in all of photo storage: it’ll back up your entire library for free, so long as it can compress the images a bit. But as of tomorrow, June 1st, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/11/21560810/google-photos-unlimited-cap-free-uploads-15gb-ending"&gt;that deal goes away&lt;/a&gt;, and you’re now eating through Google storage (which you may have to pay for) whether your images are compressed or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7a4M8H"&gt;With the change looming, I’ve been wondering how bad Google’s compression actually is. Does the compression leave my photos in “High Quality,” as Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/24/22451607/google-photos-high-quality-storage-saver-tool-free-space-blurry-screenshots"&gt;has claimed for years&lt;/a&gt;? Or does the compression degrade my photos enough to make it worth using more storage by switching over to “Original Quality” backups?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fCjfty"&gt;I ran some quick tests this morning to find out. I took some photos and videos from my Pixel 5 (one of a few phones that will &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/photos/answer/6220791?co=GENIE.Platform%3DAndroid&amp;amp;oco=1#storage"&gt;continue to get&lt;/a&gt; free compressed storage) and a photo from my Fuji X-T30 and uploaded them to two separate Google Photos accounts, one with compression turned on and one that maintained original quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OYnVlK"&gt;The results were mixed. For photos, the compressed versions were often indistinguishable from their uncompressed counterparts. But once you’re losing resolution, the compression really starts to show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AU06eR"&gt;Here’s what I found across a handful of tests. You can click the images to view them at a larger size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="hsh1pD"&gt;I can’t find a difference in this photo of my cat&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2omYkz9Fte7JrdwCUnf6b-kCO3U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22550722/PXL_20210407_172630922.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The original quality photo.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qAJmHv2HmBaHKjagXmp5yerxeSU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22550723/PXL_20210407_172630922.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The compressed photo.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="u9rZSV"&gt;Here’s a photo I took recently of my cat, Pretzel. I zoomed in on his hair, his eyes, and the books in the background, and I can’t find a difference. The photo, taken on a Pixel 5, was originally 3.4MB but was compressed down to 1.5MB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="G0XrCc"&gt;This ultrawide photo looks basically the same&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LrbPoVscD5iuKyTtntd4X5IXWQs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22550724/PXL_20210524_175950510.MP.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The original quality photo.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WSXMduO6_vChyMVXETqk_xt2b5U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22550725/compressedPXL_20210524_175950510.MP.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The compressed photo.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lSnKcP"&gt;I took this picture on Yale’s campus last weekend with the Pixel 5’s ultrawide camera. Both versions look great while in full screen on my computer. You could probably make an argument about whether there’s some more noises around the edges of the leaves in the compressed version, but I’m generally of the mindset that if you have to search for image issues, they don’t really matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uzPAq8"&gt;The space saving isn’t very substantial here: Google’s compression takes the file size from 7.3MB to 5.7MB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="37j10y"&gt;The image size shrinks dramatically from my mirrorless camera&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Gp-Ehhf-YyhM9ZmqoPObttgEX4o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22550726/DSCF0267.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The original quality photo.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7jeQqTrHRg2nz8Bs56g6agoCF4U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22550727/DSCF0267.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The compressed photo.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2yqKIV"&gt;Here’s a photo I took this morning of Pretzel on my Fuji X-T30. I zoomed in on his face, and couldn’t find a difference even when both were blown up as large as Google Photos could make them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GyjHPs"&gt;At first, it seemed like this was a situation where Google Photos’ compression won out: the file size shrank from 12MB to just 662KB, and the images look practically identical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rg9amn"&gt;But there’s one very notable difference. Google caps photo resolution at 16 megapixels, which shrank the photo significantly from the original 26 megapixel file my camera saved. Here’s a zoomed-in crop showing how the detail starts to disappear as blocky noise comes in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="1yRQYn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10527132"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vJYQRg"&gt;Now look, I don’t know that I need all 26 megapixels of this image at this point in time. But if I ever wanted to print this photo in a larger format, crop it down the road, or otherwise make changes to it, those extra pixels would be a huge advantage to have retained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="K4THyC"&gt;Video compression is just bad&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id="OY9DYw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10527143"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Goz5gv"&gt;There’s nothing inherently wrong with 1080p video, but there is something wrong with the way Google processes it. And unfortunately, if you use Google’s compression, all your videos will be compressed at 1080p.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ANKYZc"&gt;When that happens, everything becomes smudgy, details just vanish, and some colors even lose their pop. It’s a really significant downgrade in terms of quality. I’m not able to embed a Google Photos video here, so I included a screenshot comparison above. I think you can see most of the differences, although it’s much clearer how blurry text becomes at larger sizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9lyDsE"&gt;I originally recorded this video in 4K back on my Pixel 5 back in February. It looks nice enough on my not-4K computer screen. Street signs, faces, and the falling snow all look sharp. But the compressed version is kind of a mess — it looks like I recorded it with a layer of grease on my camera lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m6qq7z"&gt;The loss (or savings) of data is a big one here: it falls from 55MB for this 10 second clip to just 6MB. No wonder it looks so much worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="0yYteb"&gt;The compression makes a difference... sometimes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="MfcLEW"&gt;I still came away &lt;em&gt;mostly&lt;/em&gt; impressed by the quality maintained after Google’s compression. For photos, the result can be nearly indistinguishable so long as the original file is under 16 megapixels. But for videos, there’s no question that uncompressed is the way to go. It’s too bad that Google doesn’t let you set different options for photos and videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X7LtdD"&gt;The real drawback is that compressing your photos doesn’t always save a ton of space. That extra space definitely adds up as you push thousands of new photos into the cloud each year. But if you’re going to have to pay anyway, it might be worth maintaining your photos — and especially your videos — at their full quality, especially if you’re uploading them in higher resolutions.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/31/22461871/google-photos-compression-comparison-storage"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/31/22461871/google-photos-compression-comparison-storage</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-31T12:55:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-31T12:55:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>Climate change responsible for about a third of heat deaths, study says</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="PORTUGAL-WEATHER-HEAT-FEATURE" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-Xxcw_htjnYddENANRAwmYL2HnM=/0x0:3901x2601/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69367253/1010354674.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;People try to keep cool in Lisbon, Portugal during a heatwave in 2018. | Photo credit should read PATRICIA DE MELO MOREIRA/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ei0ahA"&gt;Heat is a killer — and climate change is driving up its body count. On average, about 37 percent of heat deaths can be tied back to human-caused climate change, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41558-021-01058-x"&gt;new study in &lt;em&gt;Nature Climate Change&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UlflGE"&gt;The study looked at data from 732 places in 43 countries over a period of about three decades, from 1991-2018. They used information including heat deaths and temperature readings from those places to build computer models that calculated how many deaths could be attributed to climate change. The numbers varied depending on location, with a larger percentage of climate-change related deaths occuring in warmer countries than cooler ones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="56rsXL"&gt;Overall, about 166,000 people died of heat-related deaths between 1998 and 2017, according to the &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/health-topics/heatwaves#tab=tab_1"&gt;World Health Organization&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to climate change, more people are being exposed to heatwaves than ever before. “Between 2000 and 2016, the number of people exposed to heatwaves increased by around 125 million,” the WHO estimates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ozPakz"&gt;There is one notable limitation to this new study — while hundreds of locations were included, many areas of Africa and Southeast Asia were not, due to a lack of data. Gathering that information in the future will be vitally important for new efforts to create a global accounting of heat-related deaths and illnesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="35ehJh"&gt;“The countries where we do not have the necessary health data are often among the poorest and most susceptible to climate change, and, concerningly, are also the projected major hotspots of future population growth,” climate change researcher Dann Mitchell &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41558-021-01049-y"&gt;wrote in an article accompanying the paper&lt;/a&gt;. “Obtaining these data will be key for science to provide the information needed to help these countries adapt.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1AfCqv"&gt;“We are thinking about these problems of climate change as something that the next generation will face,” said Ana Maria Vicedo-Cabrera, the lead author of the paper in an interview &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/31/climate/heat-deaths-climate-change.html"&gt;with &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “It’s something we are facing already. We are throwing stones at ourselves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="THKCNi"&gt;That’s in line with other research, which has found that climate change is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22007541/climate-change-health-disaster-doctors-lancet-report"&gt;already a disaster for human health&lt;/a&gt;. Older people, in particular, are particularly vulnerable, with heat-related deaths for this age group increasing by about &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.telegraph.co.uk%2Fglobal-health%2Fclimate-and-people%2Fheat-related-deaths-uk-elderly-double-20-years-climate-change%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F5%2F31%2F22461924%2Fclimate-change-heat-deaths-study" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;54 percent between 2000 and 2018&lt;/a&gt;. Some areas of the planet are getting hit worse than others, with extreme conditions happening &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21252174/heat-humidity-human-survival-climate-change-science-advances"&gt;even more frequently than predicted&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1K8w8E"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/31/22461924/climate-change-heat-deaths-study"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/31/22461924/climate-change-heat-deaths-study</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mary Beth Griggs</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-31T10:18:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-31T10:18:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Bacteria get a fresh gig as art restorers in Italy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A marble sculpture of a nude bearded man reclining" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AccmjXAHR-hEsOqMUJSpCp864js=/0x75:3541x2436/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69366107/146325207.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;An image of Michalangelo’s The Day, part of the tomb of Giuliano de’ Medici. This image was taken in 2002, long before bacteria got a chance to feast on its grime.  | Photo by DeAgostini/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zX0NuZ"&gt;Michelangelo’s marbles in the Medici Chapel were looking dingy, so a team of art restorers decided to smear some bacteria on the situation. The specialized microbes cleaned up centuries of grime, leaving the marble statues with a fresh new look, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/30/arts/bacteria-cleaning-michelangelo-medici-restoration.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nDfxFh"&gt;The team selected specialized strains of bacteria to target different stains on the marble. Some types of bacteria can thrive in harsh environments and are adapted to eating things that can cause humans problems. These bacteria can break down things like pollutants into relatively harmless components. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tlL9P8"&gt;In this case, the team looked for bacterial strains that would eat away at the stains and other gunk, without harming the marble itself, and tested their top choices on an unobtrusive patch of marble behind an altar in the chapel. They found a few types that would work, and used gel to spread them across the statues. The different strains of bacteria ate away at residues, glue, and even the stains from an improperly disposed-of corpse that was dumped in one of the tombs in 1537. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KAKmFj"&gt;The results of the project will be released in June, but you can get a tiny preview by looking through the images in &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/30/arts/bacteria-cleaning-michelangelo-medici-restoration.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times &lt;/em&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SkWaW5"&gt;This is far from the first time that bacteria have been pressed into art-cleaning service. Italy, in particular, is known for putting microbes to work in conservation efforts. A sulfur-chomping bacteria was used to &lt;a href="https://aem.asm.org/content/73/17/5671.abstract"&gt;remove “black crusts”&lt;/a&gt; from parts of the Milan Cathedral, and performed way better than a comparable chemical treatment. In Pisa, a bacterial strain that eats pollutants helped clean up damaged frescos &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/evaamsen/2019/04/12/bacteria-cleaned-paintings-in-pisa-cathedral/?sh=5524c4731099"&gt;on a cathedral dome&lt;/a&gt; and at a &lt;a href="https://www.abc.net.au/science/articles/2003/06/23/886276.htm"&gt;cemetery near the Leaning Tower&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OdDwpB"&gt;Other researchers are mapping out the bacteria and other tiny beings that &lt;a href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/science/2018-12-06/art-conservation-painting-microbes-bacteria-fungi/10584390"&gt;&lt;em&gt;already&lt;/em&gt; live on paintings&lt;/a&gt;. They found that some microbes that made their home on the pigments might actually help keep &lt;a href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/science/2018-12-06/art-conservation-painting-microbes-bacteria-fungi/10584390"&gt;the artwork from deteriorating in the first place&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/31/22461712/bacteria-art-restoration-michelangelo-marble-medici"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/31/22461712/bacteria-art-restoration-michelangelo-marble-medici</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mary Beth Griggs</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-30T23:53:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-30T23:53:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>Xiaomi says it can now fully charge a phone in eight minutes at 200W</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NTEREz7crVo5fh-ISkhh1It2pKM=/0x0:2100x1400/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69365040/xiaomi.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vZKE5y"&gt;Xiaomi has shown off its latest fast charging tech demo, and consequently is claiming the new world records for both wired and wireless charging speeds. Using a modified Mi 11 Pro with a 4,000mAh battery, Xiaomi says it’s able to fully charge the phone in 8 minutes over a 200W wired “HyperCharge” system, or in 15 minutes with 120W wireless charging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YeV6et"&gt;Charging speeds are a frequent battleground for Chinese smartphone companies, who often release demonstrations of breakthroughs that may or may not show up in final products. Two years ago, for example, Xiaomi &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/3/26/18282069/xiaomi-100w-super-charge-turbo-fast-charger"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; a 100W system that could charge a 4,000mAh battery in 17 minutes, while &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/11/21363317/xiaomi-mi-10-ultra-announcement-twitter-fast-charging"&gt;last year’s Mi 10 Ultra&lt;/a&gt; filled up in 23 minutes at 120W — though it did have a bigger 4,500mAh battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="14Pfmq"&gt;Oppo is another leader in this field, with its VOOC technology forming the basis of OnePlus’ Dash and Warp fast charging systems. Last year it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/15/21325289/oppo-125w-fast-charging-65w-airvooc-wireless-charger"&gt;demonstrated&lt;/a&gt; a 4,000mAh-in-20-minutes 125W system, though that was more than a year after Xiaomi’s supposedly faster 100W announcement, and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22411538/oppo-find-x3-pro-review"&gt;excellent current flagship Find X3 Pro&lt;/a&gt; charges at “only” 65W.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O1oLy7"&gt;You can see Xiaomi’s latest effort here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9ysK0k"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Charge up to 100% in just 8 minutes using wired charging and 15 minutes wirelessly! &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/XiaomiHyperCharge?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#XiaomiHyperCharge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Too good to be true? Check out the timer yourself! &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/InnovationForEveryone?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#InnovationForEveryone&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/muBTPkRchl"&gt;pic.twitter.com/muBTPkRchl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Xiaomi (@Xiaomi) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Xiaomi/status/1399186017421127680?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 31, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ktDnpG"&gt;Progress is always welcome, and the thought of being able to fully charge a phone in eight minutes is certainly appealing. It’s worth noting, though, that these fast-charge systems always require proprietary chargers and cables, so they’ll mostly be used at home rather than in the emergency situations where they might be most useful. Ultimately, any given phone’s ability to make it through the day on its own juice will continue to be the more important factor for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/30/22461435/xiaomi-fast-charging-world-record-200w-wired-120w-wireless"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/30/22461435/xiaomi-fast-charging-world-record-200w-wired-120w-wireless</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-30T22:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-30T22:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Intel’s latest 11th Gen processor brings 5.0GHz speeds to thin and light laptops</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_1yJS7TmWuo1Cc0MXZtu2OI9JTE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69364881/acastro_210120_1777_intel_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7WOe68"&gt;Intel made a splash earlier in May with the launch of its first &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/11/22423545/intel-tiger-lake-h-mobile-processors-11th-gen-laptops"&gt;11th Gen Tiger Lake H-series&lt;/a&gt; processors for more powerful laptops, but at Computex 2021, the company is also announcing a pair of new U-series chips — one of which marks the first 5.0GHz clock speed for the company’s U-series lineup of lower voltage chips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0df8VH"&gt;Specifically, Intel is announcing the Core i7-1195G7 — its new top of the line chip in the U-series range — and the Core i5-1155G7, which takes the crown of Intel’s most powerful Core i5-level chip, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="WnkU6O"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Intel announces its new 11th Gen Tiger Lake CPUs, available on laptops this fall","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/2/21408718/intel-11th-gen-tiger-lake-cpu-processor-announcement-laptops-fall"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="5pSqBq"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/2/21408718/intel-11th-gen-tiger-lake-cpu-processor-announcement-laptops-fall"&gt;Like the original 11th Gen U-series chips&lt;/a&gt;, the new chips operate in the 12W to 28W range. Both new chips are four core / eight thread configurations, and feature Intel’s Iris Xe integrated graphics (the Core i7-1195G7 comes with 96 EUs, while the Core i5-1155G7 has 80 EUs.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LmgxVm"&gt;The Core i7-1195G7 features a base clock speed of 2.9GHz, but cranks up to a 5.0GHz maximum single core speed using Intel’s Turbo Boost Max 3.0 technology. The Core i5-1155G7, on the other hand, has a base clock speed of 2.5GHz and a boosted speed of 4.5GHz. Getting to 5GHz out of the box is a fairly recent development for laptop CPUs, period: Intel’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/23/18512501/intel-9th-gen-laptop-desktop-processors-5ghz-update-specs-speed-features"&gt;first laptop processor to cross the 5GHz mark&lt;/a&gt; arrived in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ykakbu"&gt;Along with the new processors, Intel has also announced its latest 5G modem solution for laptops — a new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/4/18250061/intel-qualcomm-m-2-5g-modules-computer-pc-laptop"&gt;M.2 card&lt;/a&gt; that device makers will be able to incorporate into their designs, called the Intel 5G Solution 5000. (While Intel famously sold off its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/25/8909671/apple-intel-5g-smartphone-modems-acquisition"&gt;smartphone 5G division to Apple&lt;/a&gt;, Intel has continued its efforts in other areas of the next-generation connectivity standard.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T2NmZP"&gt;The new modem is a collaboration between Intel, Mediatek (which is handling the modem firmware) and Fibocom (which is actually manufacturing the modules), and will offer sub-6GHz 5G support and integrated eSIM technology. Intel says that Acer, Asus, and HP will all be offering laptops combing Intel’s Tiger Lake chips and new 5G Solution 5000 cards later this year. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/30/22459025/intel-11th-gen-tiger-lake-processor-5g-modem-computex"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/30/22459025/intel-11th-gen-tiger-lake-processor-5g-modem-computex</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-30T15:39:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-30T15:39:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>Instagram making changes to its algorithm after it was accused of censoring pro-Palestinian content</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/H6dhYmT0EeXs7x29WAbtHENgZxE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69364062/acastro_190919_1777_instagram_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2UzTvW"&gt;Facebook-owned Instagram has made changes to its algorithm after a &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/facebook-employees-bias-arabs-muslims-palestine"&gt;group of its employees reportedly complained&lt;/a&gt; that pro-Palestinian content was not viewable for users during the conflict in Gaza. Instagram typically surfaces original content in its stories before reposted content, but will now begin to give equal weighting to both, the company confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xevjqx"&gt;As reported by &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/em&gt; and the&lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/f2b394e5-d0c5-45e5-ba96-130865b02ce7."&gt; &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the Instagram employee group had made numerous appeals about content that had been censored by Instagram’s automated moderation, such as posts about the al-Asqa mosque being mistakenly removed. The employees didn’t believe the censorship was deliberate, according to &lt;em&gt;FT&lt;/em&gt;, but one said that “moderating at scale is biased against any marginalized groups.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LHFE57"&gt;The change is not only in response to concerns over pro-Palestinian content, a Facebook spokesperson said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, but the company realized the way the app functioned— bubbling up posts that it believes its users care about most— led people to believe it was suppressing certain points of view or topics. “We want to be really clear— this isn’t the case,” the spokesperson said. “This applied to any post that’s re-shared in stories, no matter what it’s about.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i2WedV"&gt;Twitter, Facebook, and Instagram have been criticized over the past several weeks about how they have surfaced — or not surfaced—content around the conflict between Israel and Palestine. Earlier this month &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/qj8b4x/twitter-said-it-restricted-palestinian-writers-account-by-accident"&gt;Twitter restricted the account of a Palestinian writer&lt;/a&gt;, which it later said was done “in error.” And Instagram ended up apologizing after many accounts were &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2021/5/7/palestinians-criticise-social-media-censorship-over-sheikh-jarrah"&gt;unable to post Palestine-related content&lt;/a&gt; for several hours on May 6th, a move that &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mosseri/status/1390764509019607040?s=20"&gt;head of Instagram Adam Mosseri tweeted&lt;/a&gt; was due to a “technical bug.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uoby0Z"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Many people thought we were removing their content because of what they posted or what hashtag they used, but this bug wasn’t related to the content itself, but rather a widespread issue that has now been fixed.&lt;/p&gt;— Adam Mosseri   (@mosseri) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mosseri/status/1390764510378532864?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qygd3H"&gt;Instagram says it has repeatedly heard from users who say they are more interested in original stories from close friends than they are in seeing people who reshare others’ photos and posts. That’s why it prioritized original stories, the spokesperson said. “But there’s been an increase— not just now but in the past as well — in how many people are resharing posts, and we’ve seen a bigger impact than expected on the reach of these posts,” the spokesperson said. “Stories that reshare feed posts aren’t getting the reach people expect them to, and that’s not a good experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tYt87h"&gt;The spokesperson added that Instagram still believes users want to see more original stories, so is looking at how to focus stories on original content through new tools.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/30/22460946/instagram-making-changes-algorithm-censoring-pro-palestinian-content"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/30/22460946/instagram-making-changes-algorithm-censoring-pro-palestinian-content</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-30T14:57:07-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-30T14:57:07-04:00</updated>
    <title>Vilnius, Lithuania built a ‘portal’ to another city to help keep people connected</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/opmAm5lBqIKYOW6_K-Ru0lw9Cd4=/0x0:1731x1154/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69363977/vilnius_portal.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Go Vilnius&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EZIdkp"&gt;Weary of pandemic travel restrictions and aching to get out and see new people? The city of Vilnius, Lithuania has interesting solution: A real-time “portal” to another city. They really went all-in on the idea and the design; it looks quite a bit like something out of the erstwhile sci-fi movie/show &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/21/16338798/stargate-command-sg1-atlantis-universe-dedicated-streaming-service-mgm"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stargate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pdAmIi"&gt;The city installed a circular “door” for the portal near its train station that connects to a portal in Lublin, Poland, about 600 kilometers (or roughly 375 miles) away. The portals both have large screens and cameras that broadcast live images between the two cities— a kind of digital bridge, according to its creators— meant to encourage people to “rethink the meaning of unity,” Go Vilnius said in a &lt;a href="https://www.leta.lv/eng/home/press_release/8F8551B3-B997-4722-B6C5-96EB498FD60F/"&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;. Aw. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iCgP5SRdm_SAKjPiebRkK-PLTok=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22549376/portal_vilnius_group.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Go Vilnius&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Vilnius, Lithuania says hi to Lublin, Poland&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="wBXGoU"&gt;“Humanity is facing many potentially deadly challenges; be it social polarization, climate change or economic issues. However, if we look closely, it’s not a lack of brilliant scientists, activists, leaders, knowledge or technology causing these challenges. It’s tribalism, a lack of empathy and a narrow perception of the world, which is often limited to our national borders,” says Benediktas Gylys, President of the Benediktas Gylys Foundation and who Go Vilnius credits as the “initiator” of the portal idea. He says the project is “a bridge that unifies and an invitation to rise above prejudices and disagreements that belong to the past.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hPvAi3txmjzlzYPacfakiAdrt5k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22549358/portal_vilnius.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Go Vilnius&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Circular portals in Vilnius, Lithuania and Lublin, Poland allow people to view each other in real time, meant to inspire a new idea of unity.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="1zouAk"&gt;The circle design, meant to evoke the wheel of time, and a “well-known ... sci-fi symbol,” was designed by engineers at the Creativity and Innovation Centre (LinkMenu fabrikas) at Vilnius Gediminas Technical University— aka Vilnius Tech. It was five years in the making, and its unveiling at the end of a yearlong pandemic is well-timed. There are plans to add portals in other cities in the future, organizers say. The portal is a joint project with the Benediktas Gylys Foundation, the City of Vilnius, the City of Lublin, and the &lt;a href="http://rozdroza.com/en/"&gt;Crossroads Centre&lt;/a&gt; for Intercultural Creative Initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O1usOC"&gt;“From design and 3D modelling, to digital content development and logistic challenges – a project like this requires a broad and multifunctional team,”  said Adas Meskenas, director of LinkMenu fabrikas. “Meaningful projects like this one are born when diverse people succeed in working together and achieving synchronicity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6x3C4I"&gt;Is it a little corny? Perhaps. But it’s also good and charming and I am all for building more portals because it has been a long, long year and we all could use a little bit of fresh inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QBpJCk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3wCzcP"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/30/22460964/vilnius-lithuania-portal-poland-connection-pandemic"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/30/22460964/vilnius-lithuania-portal-poland-connection-pandemic</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-30T13:35:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-30T13:35:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>New Trailers: The Tomorrow War, Eternals, Infinite, Werewolves Within, and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5qm7ECqaTYQqCn56zjkpJBmoq00=/0x1:1171x782/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69363800/chris_pratt_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Chris Pratt in &lt;em&gt;The Tomorrow War&lt;/em&gt; | &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QPistcpGB8o&amp;amp;ab_channel=AmazonPrimeVideo" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Prime Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="T7hvLh"&gt;So tonight is the finale for &lt;em&gt;Mare of Easttown&lt;/em&gt; and there are so many threads that need to be tied up that I legitimately don’t know how they’ll answer all the open questions. I have a theory of who the killer is, and I &lt;em&gt;don’t&lt;/em&gt; think it’s the same person who fathered Erin’s baby. Will Mare ever find happiness? It seems unlikely, I’m afraid. But maybe she’ll find answers or closure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CKbTMj"&gt;I realized that in this week’s trailer roundup that— in addition to a time-traveling theme— we have two movies that feature Sam Richardson, who played Richard Splett, arguably the best supporting character on the late great HBO show&lt;em&gt; Veep. &lt;/em&gt;Please cast him in all the things, Hollywood, he’s hilarious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="BMCuWL"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QPistcpGB8o?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="lhDaCu"&gt;The Tomorrow War&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="aWMHRU"&gt;Chris Pratt is drafted into a war where he has to go into the future and fight aliens that sound and look (from the brief glimpse we get) like the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oSeQQlaCZgU&amp;amp;ab_channel=MovieclipsClassicTrailers"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aliens&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; aliens, because if present-day people don’t help, all human beings will be wiped/disappear “from the face of the Earth” (which we know is Very Serious because two separate characters say so in the trailer). Lots of guns, lots of Pratt wisecracks (which somehow don’t quite land here), and lots of stuff blowing up, plus an Independence Day weekend release date ensure many people will watch this movie.  And what a cast: J.K. Simmons, Betty Gilpin, Mary Lynn Rajskub, Yvonne Strahovski, and Sam Richardson all join Pratt, so hopefully they can breathe life into what seems like a movie we’ve &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B1E7h3SeMDk&amp;amp;ab_channel=20thCenturyStudiosUK"&gt;seen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vw61gCe2oqI&amp;amp;ab_channel=WarnerBros.Pictures"&gt;once &lt;/a&gt;or &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k64P4l2Wmeg&amp;amp;ab_channel=MovieclipsClassicTrailers"&gt;twice&lt;/a&gt; before. &lt;em&gt;The Tomorrow War&lt;/em&gt; comes to Amazon Prime July 2nd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="BIgBGs"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X0WzPQNIBJ4?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="CtlqpY"&gt;Werewolves Within&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="MoTszf"&gt;Based on the &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2016/3/15/11231148/werewolves-within-ubisoft-werewolf-virtual-reality"&gt;Ubisoft VR game&lt;/a&gt; of the same name, &lt;em&gt;Werewolves Within&lt;/em&gt; takes place in the small town of Beaverfield, and stars Sam Richardson as new-in-town Forest Ranger Finn, who discovers a dead body that may have been the victim of a wolf attack. But not just any wolf! A snowstorm forces a group of the very weird townspeople to hole up in an inn with Finn, and oh yeah one of them is probs a werewolf. Horror/comedy combos aren’t always easy to pull off, but the trailer shows Richardson’s comedy chops are in fine form. &lt;em&gt;Werewolves Within&lt;/em&gt; will release in theaters June 25th and on demand July 2nd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="DXFQdg"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0WVDKZJkGlY?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="xMktk8"&gt;Eternals &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="3HzM5R"&gt;As my colleague Chaim Gartenberg &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22451091/eternals-marvel-trailer-chloe-zhao"&gt;noted earlier this week&lt;/a&gt;, this trailer doesn’t really tell us much about the plot of&lt;em&gt; Eternals&lt;/em&gt;, the latest entry in the Marvel Cinematic Universe. We see how the Eternals, a band of immortal heroes, have helped humans across the centuries. But something is amiss, because as Salma Hayek says in the voiceover “We have watched and guided. We have helped them progress and seen them accomplish wonders. Throughout the years, we have never interfered — until now.” The all-star cast includes Gemma Chan, Angelina Jolie, Kumail Nanjiani, Brian Tyree Henry, Lauren Ridloff, Hayek, Lia McHugh, Don Lee, Richard Madden, and Kit Harington, and it’s directed by Chloé Zhao, whose &lt;em&gt;Nomadland&lt;/em&gt; garnered Best Picture and Best Director Oscars. &lt;em&gt;Eternals&lt;/em&gt; is set for a November release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qovQ8M"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zI2qbr99H64?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="vhXZ39"&gt;Infinite&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="130ziE"&gt;Mark Wahlberg stars as a man haunted by memories he doesn’t recognize because surprise! he’s an Infinite, a person who has had multiple past lives and is part of a secret group of warriors who are trying to save humanity from one of their own, played by Chiwetel Ejiofor. This is one of the many movies whose release date was pushed back from last summer by the pandemic, but oddly isn’t getting a theatrical release. Based on the book &lt;em&gt;The Reincarnationist Papers&lt;/em&gt; by&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;D. Eric Maikranz,&lt;em&gt; Infinite&lt;/em&gt; also stars Sophie Cookson, Jason Mantzoukas, Rupert Friend, Toby Jones, and Dylan O’Brien, and was directed by Antoine Fuqua. It hits Paramount Plus on June 10th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="rB43KS"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A4U2pMRV9_k?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7Dtf99"&gt;Old&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qis9RH"&gt;This is the first official trailer for the latest M. Night Shyamalan flick (we got a teaser during the Super Bowl — and side note, what is the difference between teasers and trailers anymore?). A family (and others) on a beach vacation begins aging rapidly, adding years in a matter of hours. Is it something in the water? We don’t know! Gael Garcia Bernal, Eliza Scanlen, Thomasin McKenzie, Aaron Pierre, Alex Wolff, Vicky Krieps, Abbey Lee, Embeth Davidtz, Rufus Sewell, and Ken Leung star in &lt;em&gt;Old&lt;/em&gt;, which comes to theaters July 23rd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="91B9nz"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hJZ82pwwJqA?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="K37Ug0"&gt;Jungle Cruise&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="Jkn1R7"&gt;A movie based on a Disneyland ride starring Dwayne Johnson and Emily Blunt. OK sure, why not, we base movies on books, video games, and board games, so this is the next logical step, right? And the second trailer for this movie gives a glimpse of Jesse Plemons, usually a sign that things are headed in the right direction. &lt;em&gt;Jungle Cruise&lt;/em&gt; comes to theaters and Disney Plus (with Premier Access) on July 30th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DLyGzn"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="nSodbO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The first trailer for Last Night in Soho shows a neon-filled time-traveling ghost story","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453132/last-night-in-soho-edgar-wright-ghosts-anya-taylor-joy"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/30/22456798/new-trailers-tomorrow-war-eternals-infinite-werewolves-within-marvel-disney"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/30/22456798/new-trailers-tomorrow-war-eternals-infinite-werewolves-within-marvel-disney</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-30T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-30T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>ZTE Axon 30 Ultra review: the right stuff for the right price</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Specs for less&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="P1dvF9"&gt;The ZTE Axon 30 Ultra is a high-end device that checks all the right hardware boxes. Snapdragon 888 processor? Check. Fast refresh rate screen? Check. A metric ton of rear-facing cameras? Check, check, check, and check. It’s also priced well, starting at $749 while many of its competitors start around the $1,000 mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IxpM46"&gt;The Axon 30 Ultra delivers on many fronts, like its high-quality screen and flagship-level performance. For some, that will be enough. However, it falls short in more subtle ways that you won’t see on a spec sheet. Its novel camera array is let down by uneven, heavy-handed processing. There’s also a stray bug here and there, which can range from harmless (a 5G on / off toggle appears twice in a quick settings menu) to more annoying (the camera shutter noise going off even in silent mode). ZTE may iron out these bugs in future updates, or they won’t, and you’ll be the obnoxious parent with the noisy smartphone camera during your child’s dance recital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="wJJMY4"&gt;&lt;q&gt;the Axon 30 Ultra offers top-notch performance with a large, lovely screen&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="D0XZjf"&gt;And even though all of the key hardware is there, a few flagship-y features have been omitted to hit the Axon 30 Ultra’s more aggressive price point. There’s no IP rating for water resistance and no wireless charging. The phone doesn’t work on Verizon either, just on T-Mobile and AT&amp;amp;T, and 5G service on T-Mobile is limited to one band.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i2drbo"&gt;If those factors aren’t dealbreakers and you’re comfortable working around the occasional quirk, then the Axon 30 Ultra offers top-notch performance with a large, lovely screen at a lower price than the competition. We don’t see too many of those high-performance / lower cost premium phones in the US to challenge the heavyweights of the Android world, and it’s nice to have an alternative. But it does lack some of the polish and a few features that distinguish the more expensive competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="RISD3i"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10523685"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9CB5vm7q1v7wttz73DMdCW-o9i8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22541699/ajohnson_20210524_4601_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 30 Ultra’s screen is curved on the edges for a more immersive feel.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="NBY3pw"&gt;ZTE Axon 30 Ultra screen, battery, and performance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="F2OVYN"&gt;At 6.7 inches, the Axon 30 Ultra’s screen is about as big as they come these days. It’s a 1080p OLED with a refresh rate up to 144Hz. You can set it manually to 60, 90, 120, or 144Hz, or let it switch automatically between those rates based on the content you’re viewing. That 144Hz rate is a little faster than the 120Hz rate you’ll find on most high-end devices, but I’m not sure I could tell the difference between them if I didn’t know which was which. The bottom line is that every swipe, scroll, and animation looks incredibly smooth on the 30 Ultra’s screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZTCogS"&gt;Generally speaking, it’s just a really nice screen. Contrast is rich, the bezels are slim, and the panel curves over the sides of the phone; marketers love to call a screen like this “immersive,” but that actually feels like a fair descriptor. It’s a little tough to see outside in bright light, but it’s still usable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JMM5vd"&gt;That big screen makes the Axon 30 Ultra a big device. It’s comfortable enough to hold, and the curved screen and back panel help, but I definitely can’t reach my thumb clear across the screen while using it one-handed. There’s Gorilla Glass 5 on the front and back panels and the frame is aluminum, giving the whole phone a solid, premium feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OBllqlbe-u4OEX7RujUiRbvUw1k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22541698/ajohnson_20210524_4601_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Axon 30 Ultra offers Gorilla Glass 5 on the front and back panel.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="l74KmZ"&gt;Phone performance also meets the “premium” bar, thanks to that Snapdragon 888 processor. It feels very snappy jumping between apps, pinching and zooming around Google Maps, and scrolling through Twitter. I’m also happy to report that the in-screen optical fingerprint sensor is quick and responsive, too — it gave me a little thrill with every unlock and password manager authentication. It’s a feature that goes the extra distance to making this feel like a highly responsive, premium device. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="52B1Z7"&gt;The Axon 30 Ultra’s 4,600mAh battery is big enough and consistently got me through a day of moderate use. However, I was conservative with some battery-draining settings like screen refresh rate, and all of my use was on Wi-Fi, so I expect you could fully drain the battery over the course of a day if you really went for it. Wireless charging is, as mentioned earlier, not an option here, but the phone supports 65W wired charging with the included charging brick, and it is plenty fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wPTv60"&gt;Android 11 comes preloaded on the Axon 30 Ultra, and ZTE says an Android 12 update will come at the end of the year or in early 2022. The company doesn’t give a firm timeline for security updates but says it generally provides them for around three years. Not the worst support policy by far, but not among the very best. ZTE’s Android interface is called MyOS, and it’s a straightforward affair that doesn’t try to get too fancy. There are a truly overwhelming number of shortcuts in the fully expanded quick settings menu accessed by swiping from the top of the screen, but you can rearrange and whittle them down to your heart’s content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZMSnp4xWK8VPPsKzNKLSuU3NKws=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22541697/ajohnson_20210524_4601_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cameras galore.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="xNBIzj"&gt;ZTE Axon 30 Ultra cameras&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="qjDNQk"&gt;Rather than one high-resolution main camera complemented by several lower-resolution sensors, ZTE has chosen to put three 64-megapixel sensors in the Axon 30 Ultra’s rear camera array. You’ll find a standard wide-angle main camera with optical stabilization, a 35mm-equivalent wide-angle for portraits, and an ultrawide. There’s also an 8-megapixel 5x telephoto camera with optical stabilization. It’s a lot of cameras, and none of them are throwaways. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KYlN8t"&gt;The Axon 30 Ultra’s cameras are impressive, but they’re also a little frustrating. First, the good: these three 64-megapixel cameras all capture a lot of detail in good light, which I’d expect from the main camera, but that isn’t always the case with ultrawides since they tend to have lower resolution chips. The telephoto module offers 5x true optical zoom — results aren’t great indoors or in dim light, but with plenty of available light, it’s much better than the digital zoom alternative. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="owRAuH"&gt;I also really like the portrait lens, which is wider than the telephoto options most other smartphone cameras use. This is a personal preference; I like getting more of the scene in portrait photos, you may not. There’s no option to digitally zoom in while using portrait mode if you don’t like the wide-angle look, and portrait mode photos (with artificially blurred backgrounds) can only be taken with the dedicated portrait lens or the selfie camera. Something to consider if wide portraits are really not your thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="LW4sU9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10523726"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="e8ARRZ"&gt;Now the bad: image processing (particularly color and saturation) is inconsistent between cameras, and two photos from the same camera can vary noticeably with slight shifts in composition or subject positioning. Images from the main camera often look oversaturated. Most of the time it’s subtle enough not to bother me much, but then I’ll take a picture of my orange cat and he’ll look like a Cheeto. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bm86wQ"&gt;Portrait mode photos suffer some misses, too: subject separation from blurred backgrounds can look a little clumsy, and the lack of OIS in the portrait camera means you’re more likely to see slight blur in dimmer conditions, even without much camera movement. The wider focal length also means you’ll need to crank up the blur if you want to obscure a distracting background, which makes the subject cut-out problems more obvious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="sDGqA5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;when the Axon 30 Ultra does get things right, images look really good&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zqwvia"&gt;Maybe these shortcomings are more frustrating because when the Axon 30 Ultra does get things right, images look really good. Exposure is well balanced, all four cameras are genuinely useful, and each of them offers an impressive level of detail retention. I’d entertain leaving my dedicated camera at home more often with this combination of focal lengths and capabilities, but image processing is too much of a wild card for me to feel comfortable with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PCWFDO"&gt;One of the Axon 30 Ultra’s most annoying bugs lives in the camera app, too: the camera shutter sound is permanently stuck on, even with every volume control set to silent. There’s no way to turn it off in the camera settings menu or the main settings menu. I hate this. Maybe some people could live with it. Maybe you can root your phone and eliminate the problem yourself. Maybe ZTE will fix the issue soon. All I know is that I cannot live a shutter-sound-on lifestyle and it’s the kind of thing I might return a phone over, no matter how good the pictures look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mH6bRMCt-aI9NDyBwx9TNIZnS1I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22541700/ajohnson_20210524_4601_0005.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Axon 30 Ultra is missing a few flagship-y features like wireless charging, but it doesn’t skimp on build quality.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="KuqBgm"&gt;The ZTE Axon 30 Ultra is exactly what it appears to be: a lower cost alternative to the big Android flagships with top-tier performance and a great screen. I wouldn’t recommend it to just anyone, and you need to be comfortable either living with a couple of quirks or navigating a way around them. You don’t quite get the same level of polish or reassurance that you would from a Samsung, OnePlus, or Google device, but in return you get excellent performance for the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g9oJVY"&gt;The Axon 30 Ultra has a healthy price advantage over the other big-screen-big-performance competition like the $1,069 OnePlus 9 Pro and the $999 Samsung Galaxy S21 Plus. If you’re willing to concede some screen real estate, then its advantage narrows compared to the OnePlus 9 ($729) and standard Galaxy S21 ($800). With either of those options, you’ll get the same excellent performance and a few other benefits, like wireless charging and more sophisticated image processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="WqvMNv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Axon 30 Ultra has a healthy price advantage over the other big-screen-big-performance competition&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QrI7E8"&gt;Of course, it’s an important caveat that the Axon 30 Ultra doesn’t work on Verizon. That will rule out a significant number of prospective customers in the US. And I wish the cameras lived up to their hardware potential more often. If that’s not much of a concern, you’re not a Verizon customer, and your priorities are set on a big screen and snappy day-to-day performance, then you have a great option in the 30 Ultra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="m4pRSn"&gt;All that said, I can’t see a reason not to buy the Axon 30 Ultra if none of the above concerns you. You’ll get excellent performance, a massive screen with a silky smooth fast refresh rate, and great camera hardware — and you can rub it in your friends’ faces when you pay several hundred dollars less for your phone than they did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8ySZnB"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="RYjqbm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10523752"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22458629/zte-axon-30-ultra-review-screen-price-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22458629/zte-axon-30-ultra-review-screen-price-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
