<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-27T14:58:45-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T14:58:45-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T14:58:45-04:00</updated>
    <title>CIA developed plans to kidnap Julian Assange, per report</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Julian Assange at the Ecuadorian embassy" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/C9if5Lop4zeAhfhGYWLErloRdNI=/0x0:2560x1707/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69916211/assange_cc.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/dgcomsoc/14933990406/" target="_blank"&gt;Cancillería del Ecuador / Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IgpqE5"&gt;The Trump administration’s CIA actively developed plans to kidnap or assassinate Wikileaks founder Julian Assange during his seclusion in London’s Ecuadorian embassy, according to &lt;a href="https://news.yahoo.com/kidnapping-assassination-and-a-london-shoot-out-inside-the-ci-as-secret-war-plans-against-wiki-leaks-090057786.html"&gt;a detailed new report from Yahoo News&lt;/a&gt;. Scenarios included abducting Assange from the embassy, intercepting a Russian effort to extract him, or an outright assassination attempt. While none of the operations were ever approved, they paint an alarming portrait of intelligence agencies’ ongoing obsession with Wikileaks and its controversial founder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cMXX1j"&gt;As sources, Yahoo cites conversations with more than 30 former US officials. Among those, eight provided details on plans to kidnap Assange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e2pTOU"&gt;The report mostly details operations developed during the Trump administration, which placed fewer restraints on the CIA and was less troubled by the implications of launching direct operations against a figure many saw as a journalist. The issue became particularly heated in March of 2017, when Wikileaks &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/23/15035988/wikileaks-cia-hacking-macbook-iphone-vault-7"&gt;published a catalog of hacking tools&lt;/a&gt; developed by the CIA. After that, “WikiLeaks was a complete obsession of Pompeo’s,” a source told Yahoo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kYjgPw"&gt;“There was a fundamental change” when Trump took office, Yahoo quotes a former senior counterintelligence official as saying. “Nobody in that crew was going to be too broken up about the First Amendment issues.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A3fyJa"&gt;The report confirms long-held suspicions about surveillance of Wikileaks activists, as well as espionage activists around Assange’s stay at the embassy. “It got to the point where every human being in a three-block radius [of the embassy] was working for one of the intelligence services,” one official told Yahoo, “whether they were street sweepers or police officers or security guards.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WsBblG"&gt;The plans were mostly blocked by lawyers associated with the White House or the Justice Department, who saw any abduction as straightforwardly illegal. The idea of an assassination was shut down even earlier, with one official describing it as “just spitballing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f1AAGd"&gt;Still, the reporting cuts a stark contrast with President Trump’s &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/trump-wikileaks-campaign-speeches-julian-assange-2017-11"&gt;statements on the campaign trail&lt;/a&gt;, where he often praised Assange and Wikileaks for their role in publishing hacked information from the Clinton campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696436/cia-kidnap-julian-assange-assassination-pompeo-trump"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696436/cia-kidnap-julian-assange-assassination-pompeo-trump</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T14:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T14:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Welcome to Hot Pod from The Verge</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Hot Pod logo" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xQA2CtNQ-hHdLgTdMq1Nnmrlcyw=/0x0:1600x1067/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69916111/3426Sg8A.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8XLUMy"&gt;The podcast world is changing. Welcome to your front-row seat on the action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b5UkiT"&gt;In case you haven’t heard, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/7/22660584/hot-pod-newsletter-the-verge-ashley-carman"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;acquired &lt;em&gt;Hot Pod&lt;/em&gt; this month&lt;/a&gt;, and former writer and editor Nicholas Quah joined &lt;em&gt;Vulture&lt;/em&gt;, our sister publication at Vox Media, as a full-time podcast critic. He’s still publishing over there — you can subscribe to his criticism newsletter &lt;a href="https://www.vulture.com/promo/sign-up-for-15-speed-podcast-newsletter.html"&gt;right here&lt;/a&gt; — but I’ll be writing &lt;em&gt;Hot Pod&lt;/em&gt; from here on out. I’m excited, and although I know Nick’s legacy and insight are unparalleled, I hope to do it justice. I appreciate you sticking with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="araHi2"&gt;I’ve been at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; for nearly six years and covering podcasting and audio for the past three. In that time, podcasting has gone from something that existed on the fringe to a full-blown cultural and business force. I started at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; as a cybersecurity reporter, then became a full-time gadget blogger, and eventually landed in the broad world of “creators.” My natural interest in podcasting (I co-hosted a show here called &lt;em&gt;Why’d You Push That Button?&lt;/em&gt;) and radio (I was a college radio kid and also still stan WXRT in Chicago) landed me in audio reporting. I’ve linked a few of my past podcasting stories at the end here to give you a better idea of what I’m into and what you can expect to read in future issues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SU8uJA"&gt;Here’s the main thing: as it has gotten bigger, the world of podcasting entered a period of flux. Big tech platforms are moving into the space; the idea of a “podcast” both in how it’s distributed and what it sounds like is evolving; Hollywood stars and literal princes are making shows; and eye-popping, massive deals are being inked. I mean, Paris Hilton is &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/digital/news/spotify-podz-acquisition-1235000159/"&gt;investing in and profiting off&lt;/a&gt; podcast technology — who could have imagined!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k8ha0k"&gt;I believe we’re seeing the beginning of a new age of audio, one in which more people than ever interact with audio content — whether that’s through a traditional podcast chat show, a live room on Clubhouse, a YouTube video, or Siri talking in their ears. Audio is going mainstream, and I plan to chronicle the bumpy road to that moment. There will be drama, infighting, tech companies feuding over show deals, and hand-wringing over the future of the industry. With your help, I plan to guide us all through these changes. Hopefully we’ll even have some fun along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B1RwvG"&gt;Among the questions I hope to answer: Who will win this audio attention war? Who will make money? Who gets to have a podcast? What happens to indie podcasters? What happens to podcasting’s open ecosystem? Are we experiencing a “pivot to audio” that ends like the disastrous “pivot to video?” Is this all a bubble?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nAXhuV"&gt;My employer, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, and all of us who work here, are well-acquainted with covering Big Tech and the ways in which it impacts our behavior, livelihoods, and world. And we all want to see &lt;em&gt;Hot Pod&lt;/em&gt; grow in various ways — maybe that means more frequent audio-adjacent product reviews from our stellar team here or lengthier features with baller art from our always-impressive creative staff. But a paid newsletter is new for us, so first, we need to learn how to do it and what you all like and need from &lt;em&gt;Hot Pod&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ucc2TD"&gt;So for now, &lt;em&gt;Hot Pod&lt;/em&gt; will consist of much of the same coverage it’s always done well. I’ll cover the stories you need to read and provide extra reporting and commentary around them. I hope you will all come to know and trust me and feel comfortable chatting about what you’re reading. I’m open to feedback, tips, and criticism. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Us7svi"&gt;Here are a few stories I’m especially proud of, which I hope provide some concrete examples of what I’m talking about somewhat abstractly in this first newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="sWb7mw"&gt;The first is about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/21/22241066/spotify-anchor-sponsorships-ad-money-spend-podcasting"&gt;Anchor’s sponsorship tool not having any sponsors&lt;/a&gt; apart from Spotify itself. I liked this story because it’s a peek inside the Spotify machine — what it’s like for podcasters who use the platform to create and how Spotify’s lofty podcast ambitions are going.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dRP9uQ"&gt;The second is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/27/18156895/npr-remote-audio-data-rad-analytics-podcast-tracking-apple-spotify"&gt;my first podcasting story&lt;/a&gt; — one about NPR’s ad-tracking technology, RAD. It was a wonky piece that hinged on the idea that NPR needed buy-in from the major podcast apps to succeed. Apple still hasn’t bought into it, and neither has Spotify. We also don’t hear NPR speak about RAD anymore. It’s one that set up the dynamics of Big Tech’s power in podcasting and hinted at the incoming battle over podcast privacy and ad tracking — another topic I hope to cover.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Udlak7"&gt;And finally, here’s a feature about the “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22526502/himalaya-histudios-notorious-llc-podcast-audio-hype-house"&gt;podcasting hype house from hell&lt;/a&gt;.” This story took months to report and was one where the business moves — Himalaya launching in the US, it spinning out HiStudios, and then HiStudios and Himalaya separating — looked obvious on the outside, but had much more happening on the inside (like drug use, podcast conferences gone wrong, and even the appearance of an ice sculpture bong). The podcast industry, like every creative industry, is made up of characters — and knowing those characters can tell you a lot about the business itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="Bw3GXx"&gt;I have many more links — feel free to check out my Twitter! — but this column is already getting long. This post is a version of last Tuesday’s free newsletter, and going forward I’ll continue to publish free newsletters every Tuesday — with associated columns here on &lt;a href="http://theverge.com"&gt;theverge.com&lt;/a&gt; — followed by premium, paid editions on Thursday and Friday. (You can subscribe to those &lt;a href="https://hotpodnews.com/subscribe/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="jvggOc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"podcasts"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="hMkg8H"&gt;Now, as I said, always feel free to reach me. I’m on Twitter at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashleyrcarman"&gt;@ashleyrcarman&lt;/a&gt; and email at ashley (at) theverge.com. I hope to get to know you all soon!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696629/hot-pod-newsletter-the-verge-new-host-ashley-carman"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696629/hot-pod-newsletter-the-verge-new-host-ashley-carman</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T14:20:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T14:20:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook is spending $50 million to ‘responsibly’ build the metaverse</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UmR80marZc3yGNU6JJS1w7V7hHM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69916069/acastro_180522_facebook_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="to5NQK"&gt;&lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/09/building-the-metaverse-responsibly/"&gt;Facebook has announced&lt;/a&gt; a $50 million fund that it says will help it develop the metaverse more responsibly. It’s officially called the XR Programs and Research Fund, and the company says it’ll be invested into “programs and external research” over the course of two years. Facebook &lt;a href="https://research.fb.com/programs/research-awards/proposals/2021-towards-trustworthy-products-in-ar-vr-and-smart-devices-request-for-proposals/"&gt;has previously funded&lt;/a&gt; academic research into the social impact of AR wearables and solicited VR hardware proposals. Facebook’s announcement blog calls the metaverse the “next computing platform” and says that the company will be working with policymakers, researchers, and industry partners while building it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zNEO6U"&gt;The announcement also gives us Facebook’s definition of the sometimes nebulous word “metaverse.” The company describes it as “virtual spaces where you can create and explore with other people” that you’re not physically with, spread out over a variety of products and services. Facebook says the fund’s goal is to make sure it builds its part of the metaverse with an eye towards compatibility with other services, as well as inclusivity, privacy, safety, and “economic opportunity.” Right now, Facebook’s metaverse biggest metaverse program is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/28/21405249/facebook-vr-space-horizon-access-public-beta"&gt;a platform called Horizon&lt;/a&gt;, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22629942/facebook-workrooms-horizon-oculus-vr"&gt;exists as a beta Oculus app&lt;/a&gt; that lets people have VR meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0jixet"&gt;&lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/09/building-the-metaverse-responsibly/"&gt;The company says&lt;/a&gt; it’ll be partnering with organizations like Women in Immersive Tech, Africa No Filter, Electric South, and the Organization of American States. It also says it’ll “facilitat[e] independent external research” with organizations like the University of Hong Kong and the National University of Singapore. When asked for comment on how the research will stay independent if Facebook is involved with it, the company said it would only be providing funds to the researchers, not data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="UV2yJc"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Facebook wants people to think it’s a responsible platform owner&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XGG0BX"&gt;Facebook VP Nick Clegg also spoke about the program, calling it “a start” to research into the metaverse, and saying that he hoped it would help provide answers when regulators start asking questions about the new tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="L2IDkq"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xje15hkOQYA?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=2412&amp;amp;start=2412" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XvxUTf"&gt;Facebook has recently been trying to paint itself as a responsible platform owner. On Monday, it announced that it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696039/facebook-instagram-kids-app-pause-development-criticism"&gt;pausing work on a pre-teen-focused Instagram&lt;/a&gt; after the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/26/22695629/facebook-says-instagram-is-not-toxic-for-teens-despite-damning-wsj-report"&gt;strongly pushed back against a report&lt;/a&gt; that claimed the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/15/22675130/facebook-instagram-teens-mental-health-damage-internal-research"&gt;knew Instagram was bad for teenage girls&lt;/a&gt;. The company has also said &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22688840/facebook-releases-content-distribution-guidelines-for-news-feed"&gt;it’s becoming more transparent&lt;/a&gt; about what types of posts its algorithms try to hide and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/joeosborne/status/1440452726433804296?s=21"&gt;issued denials&lt;/a&gt; about another report that said the company tried to promote itself using the News Feed. Despite its efforts, it’s still been mired in controversy: it had to apologize to researchers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/11/22668396/facebook-provided-inaccurate-data-misinformation-researchers"&gt;after providing them inaccurate data&lt;/a&gt;, and its oversight board has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686364/facebook-oversight-board-xcheck-moderation-exemption"&gt;called for more information&lt;/a&gt; about how the platform &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671565/facebook-xcheck-moderation-system-high-profile-exemptions"&gt;moderated its famous users differently&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YE8ZMY"&gt;While Facebook pitches this fund as metaverse-focused, it appears to have a broader focus given its name. The company already does a lot of &lt;a href="https://research.fb.com/programs/research-awards/proposals/2021-towards-trustworthy-products-in-ar-vr-and-smart-devices-request-for-proposals/"&gt;research in the AR/VR space&lt;/a&gt;, and while $50 million is a lot of money, it’s a very small portion of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22598592/facebook-second-quarter-earnings-29-billion"&gt;what Facebook makes in a single quarter&lt;/a&gt; (never mind the two years over which the fund will be invested). The amount also doesn’t seem to match the importance Facebook places on AR/VR and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22588022/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-ceo-metaverse-interview"&gt;future impact of the metaverse&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jXC1f6"&gt;Facebook says it will continue to share updates on the program’s progress, as well as future partners it adds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sb5YTT"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 27th, 2:58PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added information about research grants, and Nick Clegg’s interview.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696578/facebook-metaverse-ar-vr-fund-research-definition"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696578/facebook-metaverse-ar-vr-fund-research-definition</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T14:02:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T14:02:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>Skype is getting another redesign with new themes and features</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/svQeSQx9UKxCH7GBWWILI6skmDo=/0x8:2000x1341/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69915977/macbook_pro_mockup.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Skype’s new design and colorful layouts.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Rx189p"&gt;Skype’s had more redesigns in the past five years than I’ve had hot dinners, but Microsoft is still ready to try and tweak things once again. The software maker is &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.skype.com%2Fen%2Fblogs%2F2021-08-announcement-modern-skype%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F27%2F22696716%2Fskype-new-design-themes-calling-features-updates" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;teasing plans&lt;/a&gt; for an “improved, faster, reliable, and super modern-looking Skype.” Microsoft says it has been listening to feedback and, over the next few months, will start rolling out changes to modernize Skype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cn9KCE"&gt;The most important part of Skype, what Microsoft calls the call stage, is getting the most attention. The grid that’s displayed during calls will soon include everyone on a call, regardless of whether they have enabled video or not. This puts all participants side by side, including your own video in the main interface.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7S5Pr2atkcAEZqIc5ULjz60cbWQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22882337/light_theme_3.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new calling interface in Skype.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="lrshtV"&gt;Microsoft is also adding new themes and layouts to this view, offering some much-needed customization to the main calling interface in Skype. You’ll be able to pick between speaker view, grid view, large gallery, Together Mode, and even a content view — with options to only show people with video enabled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V9tTv1"&gt;Skype’s new colorful themes will soon be available, with button gradients, an improved side panel on mobile, and Fluent Design icons throughout the apps. Skype users without avatars will also get colorful gradients to make it easier to tell chats apart.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EnbHp29ntPh_VelyrrmmBQ3rAxM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22882346/themes.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Skype’s colorful new themes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="3mOW57"&gt;It’s not all just design changes, though. “While we love the design changes, we knew they weren’t enough,” admits the Skype team &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.skype.com%2Fen%2Fblogs%2F2021-08-announcement-modern-skype%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F27%2F22696716%2Fskype-new-design-themes-calling-features-updates" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;in a blog post detailing the changes&lt;/a&gt;. “We needed to focus on performance to make the experience delightful.” Microsoft claims it’s increasing performance on the Android version by more than 2,000 percent in “key scenarios” and 30 percent on desktop versions of Skype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EVAAKN"&gt;Microsoft is also making a commitment to support all browsers with its future Skype changes. “We believe the Skype experience should be seamless, accessible, and reliable no matter what browser or device you are using, so we are adding support for all browsers,” says the Skype team. “We would like to make sure that no matter which device, platform, or browser you’re using, Skype will always give you a great experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qi71Y82JWDjVCZd9OjCcFwnwj1M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22882342/mobile_stage.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Skype on mobile is also getting some design improvements.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="lbexUe"&gt;Some of these improvements are live now, while others will roll out in the coming months. Custom notification sounds are part of the immediate new features, while a new TwinCam feature that lets you add your phone camera to a call appears to be coming later. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c4xESL"&gt;Microsoft is certainly focusing on a wide range of improvements for Skype. This is the latest redesign of Skype since Microsoft started tweaking things &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/10/9/6951087/skype-new-design-for-windows-mac-desktop-clients"&gt;initially in 2014&lt;/a&gt;, followed by a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/6/1/15723594/microsoft-skype-redesign-features"&gt;Snapchat-like design in 2017&lt;/a&gt;, another &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/2/17811588/microsoft-skype-redesign-2018-highlights"&gt;redesign in 2018&lt;/a&gt; that killed off the radical Snapchat-like changes, and lots of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/16/17576306/skype-classic-desktop-app-design-features-call-recording"&gt;changes to the desktop&lt;/a&gt; and mobile apps ever since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NVEKFE"&gt;It’s surprising to see yet another redesign, albeit a modest one. Microsoft has signaled a shift in focus towards Microsoft Teams over the past year, with attempts to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/22/21298766/microsoft-teams-personal-launch-preview-accounts"&gt;entice consumers into Teams&lt;/a&gt;. Microsoft’s struggles with Skype &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/31/21200844/microsoft-skype-zoom-houseparty-coronavirus-pandemic-usage-growth-competition"&gt;created a Zoom moment&lt;/a&gt; at the beginning of the pandemic last year, and the company has tried to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439924/microsoft-teams-personal-version-launch-available-download"&gt;leverage Teams and its free all-day video calling&lt;/a&gt; as an answer to Zoom for consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696716/skype-new-design-themes-calling-features-updates"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696716/skype-new-design-themes-calling-features-updates</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T13:18:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T13:18:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>Congress isn’t satisfied with Facebook’s pause on Instagram Kids</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/D0DRXtiOXsJUal7ZP7sugizm6kU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69915702/acastro_190919_1777_instagram_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5Ax1zQ"&gt;Facebook announced that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696039/facebook-instagram-kids-app-pause-development-criticism"&gt;it would be “pausing” work&lt;/a&gt; on its Instagram for kids app on Monday after weeks of growing pressure from lawmakers and advocacy groups to scrap the app. But many lawmakers aren’t satisfied with the pause, calling on Facebook to stop development entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RgF3ij"&gt;In a statement issued Monday, Democrats in the House and Senate called Facebook’s decision to halt development of the Instagram product targeted to kids under 13 as “insufficient.” Four lawmakers signed onto the statement, including Sen. Ed Markey (D-MA) and Rep. Lori Trahan (D-MA),&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="3LcslX"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Facebook has completely forfeited the benefit of the doubt”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dwXwdj"&gt;“Facebook has completely forfeited the benefit of the doubt when it comes to protecting young people online and it must completely abandon this project,” the statement reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Rfb9c"&gt;Facebook’s reversal comes on the heels of new reporting from &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-facebook-files-11631713039"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;claiming that the company conducted several studies that identified the harm apps like Instagram cause when used by young people, especially teenage girls. In light of this reporting, Sens. Richard Blumenthal (D-CT) and Marsha Blackburn (R-TN) called a hearing for this week in the Senate Commerce Committee to grill company executives over their research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KFXOwv"&gt;“Facebook’s decision to pause ‘Instagram Kids’ is a step in the right direction to ensuring a safe environment, but there is still much work to be done,” Blackburn said in a statement Monday. “Big Tech’s pattern of choosing profit over the wellbeing of young users is extremely concerning &amp;amp; we must hold them accountable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NheGag"&gt;Facebook’s global head of safety, Antigone Davis, &lt;a href="https://www.commerce.senate.gov/2021/9/protecting-kids-online-facebook-instagram-and-mental-health-harms"&gt;is slated to testify&lt;/a&gt; at the hearing entitled “Protecting Kids Online: Facebook, Instagram, and Mental Health Harms” on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JvzgZZ"&gt;For now, Instagram chief Adam Mosseri said that the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/26/22695629/facebook-says-instagram-is-not-toxic-for-teens-despite-damning-wsj-report"&gt;will continue speaking&lt;/a&gt; with parents and safety groups before moving forward on Instagram for kids. But it’s unclear how long the announced “pause” on development will continue.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696698/facebook-instagram-for-kids-mosseri-markey-blumenthal-blackburn-pause"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696698/facebook-instagram-for-kids-mosseri-markey-blumenthal-blackburn-pause</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T13:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Discord will now let you set a unique avatar in each of the servers where you hang out</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1q-vM47_ZGVIqqq5cK2gT-gebws=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69915602/acastro_200318_1777_discord_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Discord will let you have unique avatars across different servers | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oWroiH"&gt;Messaging app Discord announced today that its premium Nitro tier will now allow subscribers to use a different avatar on each of their servers. The option to “change nickname” in the app has been changed to “edit server profile.” That’s where you’ll be able to change both your nickname and server avatar, so if you use multiple servers — as a lot of Discord users do — you can keep each identity separate and unique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zepfMG"&gt;Discord also announced today that they’re starting the rollout of scheduled events, which allow users to plan ahead, giving time to spread awareness and join. The company says it’s seeing more communities use stage channels to connect with members, in AMAs, open mic events, or other large-scale discussions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S2yLkm"&gt;With scheduled events in Discord, users can create an event with a topic name for a future date, allow members to RSVP — which will then send them a notification when the event starts — and create an invite link for a specific event. Members will also be able to browse a list of future events on a server. The scheduled events feature will be available on desktop, iOS, and Android, and there are no time restrictions on how far ahead of time moderators and admins can schedule events, but there will be a limit of 100 total events at a time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3ym1OC"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22694834/discord-unique-avatar-nickname-servers-gaming-events"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22694834/discord-unique-avatar-nickname-servers-gaming-events</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T12:33:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T12:33:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Ford recalls Mustang Mach-Es over risk of glass roof flying off</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FVTrD3NuyU6FkAOB3knodaGPlZY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69915483/sokane_210125_4386_0016.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Sean O’Kane / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="l80R44"&gt;Ford is recalling the Mustang Mach-E out of concern that the windshield and panoramic roof could leak or, worse, come flying off during a crash or while driving. Nearly 18,000 of the electric SUVs sold to date are at risk of the former, though Ford says only around 13,000 of them run the risk of the roof detaching. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bjAEyo"&gt;The company will start providing owners with recall instructions in late October, and it says it is not aware of any accidents or injuries related to the defect. Ford initially started recalling Mustang Mach-E SUVs last week in Canada, &lt;a href="https://electrek.co/2021/09/21/ford-recalls-mustang-mach-e-risk-of-glass-roof-falling-off-mocking-tesla-same-issue/"&gt;as &lt;em&gt;Electrek &lt;/em&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z5svfw"&gt;Ford told the &lt;a href="https://www.nhtsa.gov/vehicle/2021/FORD/MUSTANG%252520MACH-E/SUV/AWD#recalls"&gt;National Highway Traffic Safety Administration&lt;/a&gt; earlier this month that it had become aware that the windshield and panoramic roof of the Mustang Mach-E may not be properly bonded to the car. The company said it does not yet know the cause of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F4QVES"&gt;The recall is just the latest hiccup in the rollout of the Mustang Mach-E, which is the Detroit automaker’s first mass-market electric car. Ford recalled dozens of the first Mach-Es sold in March &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/5/22316055/ford-mustang-mach-e-recall-loose-bolt-delivery-delays"&gt;after discovering loose subframe bolts&lt;/a&gt;. Many of the first deliveries were delayed, too, while the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311594/ford-mustang-mach-e-delays-quality-free-charging-cash-back"&gt;tightened up its quality checks&lt;/a&gt;. Some early vehicles were also plagued by a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22373903/mustang-mach-e-deep-sleep-12v-battery-jump-start"&gt;software problem that led to the 12-volt battery dying&lt;/a&gt;, as &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;first reported in April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IiKktf"&gt;Panoramic glass roofs have become a popular feature in new electric vehicles, especially after Tesla started making them standard on its cars. Tesla is familiar with the problem Ford is running into now, too, as the company dealt with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/5/21502379/tesla-modely-roof-flies-off-convertible-quality-issue"&gt;glass roof problems&lt;/a&gt; with the Model Y SUV, including &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/second-tesla-model-y-owner-reports-roof-issue-glass-adhesion-2020-10"&gt;one that literally blew off on the highway&lt;/a&gt;. In fact, Ford’s head of electric vehicles even took an indirect shot at Tesla after this happened, &lt;a href="https://electrek.co/2021/09/21/ford-recalls-mustang-mach-e-risk-of-glass-roof-falling-off-mocking-tesla-same-issue/"&gt;as &lt;em&gt;Electrek &lt;/em&gt;points out&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZKpl6Z"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696482/ford-mustang-mach-e-glass-windshield-recall-roof"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696482/ford-mustang-mach-e-glass-windshield-recall-roof</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T12:21:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T12:21:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>TikTok says it has passed 1 billion users</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SFyWKyxAQEu4YpAXcP-ZNZdKxz8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69915415/acastro_200803_1777_tikTok_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;TikTok has passed 1 billion users | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wUsfUE"&gt;TikTok said Monday it has passed 1 billion monthly users. It’s a remarkable number for a platform launched in August 2018 that has been scrutinized by governments — including the US — that are worried about the data collection practices of its parent company, Beijing-based ByteDance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="srkr7J"&gt;TikTok’s popularity soared during the pandemic, becoming the most-downloaded app in the world in the first quarter of 2020, with some &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/abrambrown/2020/05/20/inside-the-hunt-for-tiktoks-new-ceo-and-whats-next-for-the-worlds-hottest-app"&gt;315 million downloads&lt;/a&gt; in that quarter alone according to app analytics company SensorTower. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W4IqY9"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/06/17/chinas-bytedance-tiktok-owner-saw-revenue-surge-111percent-in-2020.html"&gt;ByteDance reportedly saw its 2020 revenue&lt;/a&gt; more than double from the year prior, to $34.3 billion. From its launch to date, SensorTower says TikTok installs have reached 3.2 billion, which includes information from Douyin, the Chinese version of the app. TikTok’s monthly average users in August were up 25 percent from August 2020. In June of this year, &lt;a href="https://asia.nikkei.com/Business/36Kr-KrASIA/TikTok-creator-ByteDance-hits-425bn-valuation-on-gray-market"&gt;ByteDance was valued&lt;/a&gt; at $425 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OUNdUe"&gt;And other apps, seeking to duplicate TikTok’s enormous success, created short-form video products of their own. Facebook-owned &lt;a href="https://voxmedia.stories.usechorus.com/compose/76ed0392-a59c-4e20-adeb-2d1e87983ddd"&gt;Instagram launched Reels&lt;/a&gt; last August; Snapchat introduced its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/23/21585513/snapchat-snap-spotlight-creators-app-update-tiktok"&gt;in-app TikTok clone Spotlight&lt;/a&gt; in November, and even video behemoth YouTube got into the short-form game, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22334540/youtube-shorts-us-beta-tiktok-competition-launch"&gt;debuting its YouTube Shorts&lt;/a&gt; in the US earlier this year. But TikTok continued growing; a report earlier this month found &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/7/22660516/tiktok-average-watch-time-youtube-us-android-app-annie"&gt;TikTok users spend more&lt;/a&gt; time watching its content than YouTube users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6WHrjy"&gt;On Monday, TikTok chief operating officer Vanessa Pappas thanked users in a video on TikTok for “making TikTok a truly special place.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CmdukK"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="tiktok-embed" cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@tiktok/video/7012606652008402182" data-video-id="7012606652008402182" style="max-width: 605px;min-width: 325px;"&gt; &lt;section&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" title="@tiktok" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@tiktok"&gt;@tiktok&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p&gt;✨ 1 billion✨ people on TikTok! Thank you to our global community  &lt;/p&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" title="♬ original sound - TikTok" href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/original-sound-7012606465961757445"&gt;♬ original sound - TikTok&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/section&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async="" src="https://www.tiktok.com/embed.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lYSDN3"&gt;ByteDance reportedly postponed its plans for an initial public offering indefinitely amid a crackdown on tech firms by Chinese regulators over the &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/chinas-tech-clampdown-is-spreading-like-wildfire-11622971802?mod=article_inline"&gt;past few months&lt;/a&gt;. China is scrutinizing what it considers anti-competitive practices from its big tech firms and how the firms handle customers’ sensitive data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZO1KeK"&gt;ByteDance and TikTok were among the Chinese tech firms targeted by the Trump administration last year via &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/10/21358505/trump-tiktok-wechat-tencent-bytedance-china-ban-executive-order-legal-sanctions-rules"&gt;a series&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/5/22215961/trump-executive-order-prohibiting-transactions-eight-chinese-apps-alipay-tencent-qq-wechat-pay"&gt;executive orders&lt;/a&gt; blocking their apps from US app stores. None of the orders ever took effect, and in June, President Joe Biden signed an executive order &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/9/22525953/biden-tiktok-wechat-trump-bans-revoked-alipay"&gt;revoking the Trump-era bans&lt;/a&gt;. Biden directed the commerce secretary to investigate apps with ties to foreign adversaries like China, that may collect sensitive data from US consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fDHibO"&gt;But TikTok also saw some novel bright spots during the pandemic, not the least of which was the fan-made, crowdsourced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22166215/ratatouille-the-tiktok-musical-broadway-show-todaytix-streaming-one-night-date-viral-disney"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ratatouille&lt;/em&gt; TikTok musical&lt;/a&gt;. It started as a one-off bit based on the 2007 Disney / Pixar film that Broadway fans, composers, choreographers, and others added to, one TikTok at a time. &lt;em&gt;Ratatouille: The TikTok Musical&lt;/em&gt; debuted as a one-night-only streaming concert on January 1st, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/2/22210416/ratatouille-tiktok-musical-1-million-actors-fund-disney-pixar-broadway"&gt;raising more than $1 million&lt;/a&gt; for The Actors Fund, which supports performers and workers in the entertainment industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2s5h3C"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction September 27th 12:32PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; The first name of TikTok’s COO is Vanessa, not Veronica. We regret the error. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696281/tiktok-1-billion-users"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696281/tiktok-1-billion-users</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T12:19:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T12:19:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Roblox is negotiating with music publishers after settling a copyright lawsuit</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Lil Nas X performing ‘Old Town Road’ inside Roblox" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/O5JP4nKmdv8WxuS1qUVx2lZ7iI0=/43x0:1663x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69915389/LNX_Concert_Old_Town_Road.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Roblox&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4WHnD8"&gt;Virtual world-building platform Roblox has settled a lawsuit with the National Music Publishers’ Association (NMPA) and is negotiating potential deals with individual music publishers. Roblox announced the news this morning, saying it was “committed to partnering with the music industry.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V6B6tS"&gt;The NMPA &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22527713/roblox-nmpa-lawsuit-copyright-infringement-deadmau5-ariana-grande-imagine-dragons"&gt;sued Roblox in June&lt;/a&gt; for letting users upload copyrighted songs into its shared library of game-building assets. Roblox quickly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/6/22564922/roblox-sony-music-partnership-lil-nas-x-collaboration-licensing"&gt;signed individual deals with BMG and Sony&lt;/a&gt;, but the new agreement settles all claims involving NMPA members. According to a press release and the NMPA, Roblox and the organization have agreed to the terms of an industry-wide settlement that individual music publishers can decide whether to opt in to, and the agreement also “opens a negotiation period for members to engage individually in new go-forward licensing deals” with the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="nEKGN4"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Roblox announced new ‘listening parties’ last week&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="G9nzws"&gt;Music is a major element of Roblox. The platform has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/16/21570454/lil-nas-x-roblox-concert-33-million-views"&gt;hosted concerts&lt;/a&gt; by artists like Lil Nas X, and &lt;a href="https://corp.roblox.com/2021/09/roblox-launches-listening-parties-new-way-release-music/"&gt;last week, it launched&lt;/a&gt; “listening parties” where artists premiere an album by streaming it across a variety of individual Roblox worlds. But the NMPA accused Roblox of deliberately overlooking or obscuring the range of pirated music on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iW0XmR"&gt;Roblox has yet to sign broad-ranging deals that cover users legally adding songs to their experiences — something platforms like YouTube have done — although it offers access to some tracks through &lt;a href="https://en.help.roblox.com/hc/en-us/articles/360000927163-Using-Licensed-Music-on-Roblox"&gt;a licensing agreement&lt;/a&gt; with APM Music. While this settlement news doesn’t explicitly discuss those kinds of deals, it seemingly opens the door to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FVmpgS"&gt;“Roblox will work closely with the global music publishing industry to help them unlock new ways for music to be more meaningfully integrated into the global Roblox community of more than 48 million daily active users. The deal paves the way for innovative partnerships between Roblox and publishers that will offer songwriters new ways to monetize their songs and catalogues,” a press release says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yA70h8"&gt;This settlement follows a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22686404/twitch-national-music-publishers-association-nmpa-agreement-music"&gt;separate NMPA agreement&lt;/a&gt; with Amazon-owned broadcast platform Twitch. That deal was similarly open-ended, but it included an explicit change to how Twitch handles copyright violations, something Roblox and the NMPA’s announcement doesn’t mention.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696387/roblox-nmpa-lawsuit-settlement-music-piracy-licensing-negotiations"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696387/roblox-nmpa-lawsuit-settlement-music-piracy-licensing-negotiations</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-27T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Death Stranding Director’s Cut makes the most of the PS5</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6qUguCENQb5zcHfnfTQ5PCU_EUo=/160x0:1888x1152/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69915169/51298386042_570941bddd_k.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0UuTgs"&gt;Okay, I’ll make the obvious joke: was there really anything cut from &lt;em&gt;Death Stranding&lt;/em&gt;? For better and worse, Hideo Kojima’s deeply indulgent post-apocalyptic delivery simulator did not feel like it had been subject to heavy editing. But &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/7/12/22573731/death-stranding-directors-cut-hideo-kojima-missions-name-debate"&gt;Kojima himself has said&lt;/a&gt; that he doesn’t like the name of this new PlayStation 5 version of the game, dubbed a “director’s cut,” arguing instead that it has simply had new content produced for it. So there you have it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SQBEUp"&gt;In any case, &lt;em&gt;Death Stranding Director’s Cut&lt;/em&gt; is one of the more worthwhile PS5 upgrades out there. For $10 (if you own the PS4 release), this new edition comes with extra missions, improved visuals and performance, more tools and items, DualSense-powered haptic feedback, and 3D audio support. It all adds up to one of the better showcases of the PS5’s hardware we’ve seen so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="XDkOPv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Death Stranding is so good that it shouldn’t have a sequel","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/7/20953031/death-stranding-hideo-kojima-metal-gear-solid-sequel"},{"title":"Death Stranding is a long, bizarre journey that’s both breathtaking and boring","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20941606/death-stranding-review-ps4-hideo-kojima"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JXZwBN"&gt;Already a beautiful game on the PS4, Kojima Productions didn’t have to do a whole lot in order to make &lt;em&gt;Death Stranding&lt;/em&gt; seem at home on the PS5. The technical upgrades are largely related to resolution and performance: there’s a 4K quality mode and a slightly less sharp 60fps performance mode, though the former usually sticks to 60fps, and the latter is still fairly high resolution. I normally play games in their performance modes, but a quality mode that doesn’t limit you to 30fps is very welcome here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S3jeMm"&gt;Another notable addition is the ability to play the game in an ultrawide aspect ratio. This gives you a wider field of view at the expense of screen real estate — you have black bars on the top and the bottom of your screen, but you can see more of your character’s surroundings. It’s a great fit for &lt;em&gt;Death Stranding&lt;/em&gt;’s sweeping vistas. On my 55-inch TV, though, the picture does feel a little small at couch distance. I think the mode would work better on a bigger set — especially if it’s OLED, where the black bars will be less distracting — or for anyone using a smaller TV like the 48-inch LG CX as a monitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="H9IW6y"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EV53lnCzP1w?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="v8VBqk"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Death Stranding&lt;/em&gt; was the first game I thought of when Sony announced the PS5’s DualSense controller, which has triggers that can provide variable levels of resistance. In &lt;em&gt;Death Stranding&lt;/em&gt;, you spend a lot of time carrying heavy cargo on your back and using the trigger buttons to balance the load. With the DualSense, the weight is reflected in how difficult it is to pull the trigger, giving you a better indication of when you might end up overexerting yourself and tumbling down a mountain. The increased precision of the haptic feedback also helps convey the feeling of the ground underfoot, as well as weather conditions like rain. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549072/astros-playroom-ps5-review-dualsense-controller"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Astro’s Playroom&lt;/em&gt; is still the best DualSense demo&lt;/a&gt;, but &lt;em&gt;Death Stranding Director’s Cut&lt;/em&gt; is almost as impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9nzFP2"&gt;This release also includes one of the best implementations of 3D audio I’ve heard to date. I’ve found the feature to be a little underwhelming on most PS5 games so far, for all that Sony has touted the console’s Tempest sound engine. But in &lt;em&gt;Death Stranding Director’s Cut&lt;/em&gt;, it really adds to the immersion. Characters speaking in cutscenes sound like they’re accurately placed around you, and you can hear where ghostly enemies are trying to stalk you from. It’s definitely worth playing this one with headphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GGirKB"&gt;The extra content appears to be quite slight, though I haven’t been able to play through the entire game a second time yet. Many of the additions are typically quirky, from a full-on racing mode to a catapult that lets you launch heavy cargo across the scenery, while there are some more fundamental tweaks like new melee combat moves. I don’t think any of this will change anyone’s mind about the game, but there’s enough new here to make a replay feel fresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WrnwmM"&gt;A free 60fps patch as seen in games like &lt;em&gt;Horizon Zero Dawn&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Last of Us Part II&lt;/em&gt; would have been appreciated, but I think the $10 upgrade is worth it for any PS5 owner who enjoyed &lt;em&gt;Death Stranding&lt;/em&gt; on the PS4. At $49.99 for new players, it’s also a reasonable time to get on board with a game that is truly unlike anything else. &lt;em&gt;Death Stranding &lt;/em&gt;certainly isn’t for everyone, and that remains the case here, but with this version, you’re getting a very well-rounded package that makes the most of its platform.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696322/death-stranding-directors-cut-ps5-kojima-3d-audio-dualsense"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696322/death-stranding-directors-cut-ps5-kojima-3d-audio-dualsense</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
