<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-20T07:26:40-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-20T07:26:40-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-20T07:26:40-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon leaks new Kindle Paperwhite with larger 6.8-inch display</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UzxiHRwo7t1_vEY4SAlIz5FxpBA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69881921/akrales_181101_3056_0332.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon’s last Kindle Paperwhite, released in 2018.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hg3LVO"&gt;A new generation of Kindle devices appears to have leaked via a since-removed comparison chart on Amazon Canada, &lt;a href="https://goodereader.com/blog/electronic-readers/amazon-is-going-to-release-kindle-paperwhite-5-signature-edition-soon"&gt;&lt;em&gt;GoodEReader&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;. Two new devices are shown in the chart, a CA$149.99 (around $117) Kindle Paperwhite, and a CA$209.99 (around $164) Kindle Paperwhite Signature Edition. Both feature a larger 6.8-inch E ink display compared to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/7/18065960/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-2018-review"&gt;current 6-inch Paperwhite&lt;/a&gt;, but only the more expensive model has the new wireless charging, alongside more storage and lights that adjust based on the brightness of the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3XrPBM"&gt;The basic Kindle Paperwhite appears to include 8GB of storage, while the Signature Edition has 32GB, the same as the two storage options available for the current Paperwhite. The 300ppi resolution is also unchanged. However, the amount of LEDs for the device’s front-light has increased from five with the current Paperwhite to 17, and their color temperature should also be adjustable like the current Kindle Oasis. The screens on both devices will be flush with the bezel, and they also have an IPX8 waterproof rating, same as the current Paperwhite. Wi-Fi connectivity is included, but there’s no mention of cellular models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="IrV8QT"&gt;&lt;q&gt;With a much improved front light&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gibHbL"&gt;While the new Kindle Paperwhites have inherited some features from the Oasis, there’ll still be some exclusive features left for Amazon’s premium e-reader. These include its ergonomic design, auto-rotating page orientation, and physical page-turn buttons, according to the comparison table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vd9ZxG"&gt;Unfortunately, there’s no mention of which USB connector type the new Kindles will use, so it’s unclear if Amazon finally intends to upgrade them to USB-C after having stuck with Micro USB for an embarrassingly long time. Even Amazon’s premium &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/24/20707619/amazon-kindle-oasis-2019-e-reader-review-price-specs-features-display"&gt;Kindle Oasis&lt;/a&gt; continues to use the outdated USB connector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b1e0BU"&gt;News of the two models follows the arrival of a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671844/amazon-kindle-e-reader-interface-design-changes"&gt;new Kindle interface&lt;/a&gt; last week, which was released as an update for basically every Kindle produced since 2015. The new layout adds a navigation bar that makes it easier to jump between the device’s Home screen, library, and in-progress book. Presumably this new interface will come preloaded on the new Kindles upon release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zEqIsR"&gt;It’s unclear when Amazon might officially announce the new e-readers. It typically holds a fall hardware event at the end of September, so we might not be too far away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mAxMeo"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="soK9tF"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22683627/kindle-paperwhite-2021-signature-edition-6-8-inch-screen-wireless-charging"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22683627/kindle-paperwhite-2021-signature-edition-6-8-inch-screen-wireless-charging</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-20T07:09:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-20T07:09:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>Surface Duo 2 passes through the FCC with 5G, NFC, and wireless charging support</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/v15FBblav2V84_ph-rJRpXJ6ulc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69881905/vpavic_4176_20200905_0061.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The original Surface Duo.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VxwfzV"&gt;Microsoft is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671271/microsoft-surface-event-pro-8-surface-book-4-rumors"&gt;expected to announce&lt;/a&gt; its new Surface Duo 2 handset at a special Surface hardware event on Wednesday September 22nd. While rumors have so far pointed towards a triple-camera system, the device appears to have passed through FCC certification with 5G, NFC, and wireless charging support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8fR6fd"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/surface-duo-2-fcc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Windows Central &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; that the dual-screen Android device has been spotted in &lt;a href="https://apps.fcc.gov/oetcf/eas/reports/ViewExhibitReport.cfm?mode=Exhibits&amp;amp;RequestTimeout=500&amp;amp;calledFromFrame=N&amp;amp;application_id=ZBCqX0Z47t7zHHJi40AiWQ%3D%3D&amp;amp;fcc_id=C3K1995"&gt;FCC documents&lt;/a&gt; published last week. The documents mention “Wireless Power Transfer,” but it’s not entirely clear whether the Qi standard will be supported for wireless charging here. &lt;em&gt;Windows Central&lt;/em&gt; speculates that the Surface Duo 2 may include support for inductive charging for the Surface Pen instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8hBjRM"&gt;The FCC documents also confirm 5G and NFC support, both of which were missing from the original Surface Duo. There’s also a mention of ultra-wideband (UWB) support, which could mean the Surface Duo 2 will connect to accessories that support the standard.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/78nJzAewY4SnWAvHLnYtdij1miI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22740410/surfaceduo2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Tech Rat (&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8PQJOndIdGk" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The leaked Surface Duo 2 triple-camera system.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="QklcUP"&gt;There are no hints at the new triple-camera system that we’re expecting to see on the Surface Duo 2, though. This new camera system is expected to add a camera bump to the rear of the device, as seen in the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/26/22593992/microsoft-surface-duo-2-triple-camera-leak-photos"&gt;leaked photos earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;. The Surface Duo 2 should also ship with Qualcomm’s latest Snapdragon 888 processor, and include some other minor changes like moving the fingerprint reader into the power button and centering the USB-C port along the bottom on the right-hand side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="geQ3n6"&gt;Microsoft’s Surface event will kick off at 11AM ET / 8AM PT on September 22nd. We’re also expecting a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/19/22682271/surface-pro-8-120hz-display-thunderbolt-support-leak-rumors"&gt;Surface Pro 8 with a 120Hz display&lt;/a&gt; and Thunderbolt support, a newly designed Surface Book 4, a Surface Go 3, and an update to the Surface Pro X. We’ll be covering all the announcements live, so stay tuned to &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;for all the latest Surface news.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22683595/microsoft-surface-duo-2-fcc-5g-nfc-wireless-charging-support-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22683595/microsoft-surface-duo-2-fcc-5g-nfc-wireless-charging-support-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-20T05:18:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-20T05:18:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google reportedly has a second foldable in the works</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cxim-Tpgm0VyRYWxUi4KayOnBhc=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69881709/dseifert_4711_samsung_z_flip_3_3.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung’s recent foldable, the Z Flip 3, is more hamburger than hotdog.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dCt8oQ"&gt;Google appears to be internally testing a second foldable Pixel smartphone, according to &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/09/18/pixel-fold-jumbojack-android-12-1/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;’s sources&lt;/a&gt;. The device is said to be under development with the codename “Jumbojack,” that’s referenced in a future version of Android 12 which &lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt; identifies as “Android 12.1.” This is the latest foldable codename we’ve heard about at Google, following reports of another device called &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22525271/google-pixel-fold-folding-phone-samsung-display-theelec"&gt;“Passport.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wZ5d9v"&gt;Not much is known about what form Jumbojack could take, but &lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt; has a couple of key details. It seems to have two screens, with one that deactivates when the device is folded. That suggests we’re looking at a similar design to Samsung’s foldables, which combine a small external screen with a larger internal folding display. There’s no word on screen sizes or internal specs, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="AnrUvZ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A “hamburger style” design?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cZTjcr"&gt;Interestingly, there’s speculation that the Jumbojack codename could be a reference to Jack in the Box’s Jumbo Jack cheeseburger, an implication that the phone will fold “&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/nostalgia/comments/cgyc1v/folding_paper_hot_dog_and_hamburger_style/"&gt;hamburger style&lt;/a&gt;” like a Z Flip as opposed to “hotdog style” like a Z Fold. But, much like the foodstuffs, that speculation is best taken with a good pinch of salt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FnHDK5"&gt;Unlike Passport, which reliable leaker &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1439827216343474176"&gt;Evan Blass reported this morning&lt;/a&gt; is still scheduled to launch before the end of the year, there’s no indication about when or even if Jumbojack will see a commercial release. There’s a possibility it might just be an internal prototype, designed to help build foldable functionality like improved multitasking into Android itself. Regardless, its existence suggests Google is more serious about foldables that it initially appeared as the company gears up to produce its first true flagship competitor with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605094/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-specs-ai-ml"&gt;Pixel 6&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ywx2nC"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 20th, 7:30AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added corroboration from Blass that Google’s “Passport” foldable is still expected to launch before the end of the year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZM9BaM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G3fuYu"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XYdUUg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ix95hi"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gIxf6u"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22683566/google-jumbojack-foldable-passport-android-12-1-code-discovery"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22683566/google-jumbojack-foldable-passport-android-12-1-code-discovery</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-19T16:34:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-19T16:34:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>Ikea’s $39.99 pad adds built-in wireless charging to almost any table</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YuZqhhPUgGbhSN3zWsSAxQ0ZSlA=/53x0:548x330/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69880306/ikea_qi_table.5.gif" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ikea’s Sjömärke fits under a table to make it a charger. &lt;/em&gt; | GIF: Ikea&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7LUDsw"&gt;Ikea got in relatively early on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/3/1/8130119/ikea-wireless-power-consortium-qi-wireless-charging-furniture"&gt;selling furniture embedded with wireless charging coils&lt;/a&gt;, but what if you don’t have one of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/22/16349152/ikea-wireless-chargers-iphone-ad-campaign"&gt;powered-up desks or shelving units&lt;/a&gt;? If you want seamless Wireless Qi charging without redecorating, then next month, there will be a solution. Meet the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ikea.com%2Fus%2Fen%2Fp%2Fsjoemaerke-wireless-charger-80512718%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F19%2F22677980%2Fikea-sjomarke-wireless-qi-charging-existing-furniture" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sjömärke&lt;/a&gt;, a $39.99 wireless charging pad made to work with furniture you already own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RN2U9B"&gt;This device isn’t like most Qi charging pads, where you’d put your phone or earbuds directly on the mat. Instead, the seven-inch by three-inch aluminum and plastic charger works through plastic or wood, so you can use its double-sided tape (or screws, not included) to put it on the underside of a table or shelf.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Sjömärke" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kcJp3eCxNDKwYERn1WyUws1nZg0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22862358/sjoemaerke_wireless_charger__0987908_pe818216_s5_900.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Ikea&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Ikea Sjömärke instructions" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fRE9yS8d_oCpbfveARVJ1-lhqGQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22862348/ikea_sjoemaerke_manual.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Ikea&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Ikea Sjömärke instructions&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="GmVOOd"&gt;As long as you’re mounting the device on something wood or plastic, it should safely send an electric charge through to your gadgets on the other side. It needs a minimum distance from the phone of about 8mm, and Ikea recommends using it with a surface between three-eighths and seven-eighths of an inch thick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="01cNzS"&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ikea.com%2Fus%2Fen%2Fmanuals%2Fsjoemaerke-wireless-charger__AA-2281316-2_pub.pdf&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F19%2F22677980%2Fikea-sjomarke-wireless-qi-charging-existing-furniture" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ikea’s manual (pdf)&lt;/a&gt;, it’s “Perfect to mount on a desk, side table or bedside table when you want chargers and cables to blend into the decor to keep the room neat and tidy.” Other than the sticky tape, it comes with a six-foot power cable and stickers to mark the location of your new charging spot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PM1kIS"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/K0IvUXG-8wQ?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=3&amp;amp;start=3" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mcueYA"&gt;The LED indicates charging status, and it has temperature and power monitoring for safety. It’s compatible with the latest Qi 1.2.4 baseline power profile, so you can expect it to perform within the range of standard 5W charging — no &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/16/21519292/samsung-galaxy-fit-2-trio-wireless-charger-price"&gt;Samsung&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/10/23/18016492/google-pixel-3-fast-wireless-charging-approved-chargers-restriction-qi"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21514850/apple-iphone-12-magsafe-wireless-charging-speed"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;-specific improvements here. Still, it’s impressive enough if you’d like to charge a phone by simply putting it on the desk where it already sits and not have to move anything else around. An Ikea spokesperson confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the Sjömärke will be available in-stores and online in the US and other countries in October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="YcV2ik"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Ikea 2.0: inside the furniture giant’s big bet on the smart home","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/18/21024497/ikea-smart-home-tech-sweden-furniture-sonos-meatballs-bjorn-block"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/19/22677980/ikea-sjomarke-wireless-qi-charging-existing-furniture"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/19/22677980/ikea-sjomarke-wireless-qi-charging-existing-furniture</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-19T14:20:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-19T14:20:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>New trailers: Succession, You, Nightmare Alley, Hawkeye, and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0hS2w7hodnxRlEtNpKzX5MPAOQ4=/0x0:1406x937/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69879850/kendall_1.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Kendall Roy, smiling because he is happy Succession is returning soon (probably) | &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kevqiiYNFrc&amp;amp;t=1s&amp;amp;ab_channel=HBO" target="_blank"&gt;HBO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KzOhz2"&gt;OK so the latest &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso &lt;/em&gt;spends almost the entire episode on Coach Beard in its most unusual, dream-like episode ever. I didn’t hate it (and I know it’s one of the two episodes added to the mix after &lt;a href="https://www.latimes.com/entertainment-arts/tv/story/2021-08-13/ted-lasso-christmas-episode-apple-tv"&gt;Apple said it wanted 12 episodes&lt;/a&gt; instead of the 10 the writers had already sketched out. The Christmas episode was the other), but I wish we had actually gotten to know Beard a little better. “I listen more than I talk” seems like a line that could be his mantra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fHLlsu"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Morning Show&lt;/em&gt; is back and honestly the first episode seemed rushed to get certain characters to do specific things we as the audience know they must do in order to have a show at all. I’ll stick with it for a bit, remembering that this was a show that took a little while to find its groove in season 1, but the first offering felt a little more chaotic than usual. Billy Crudup keeps me coming back, to be honest; he makes Cory such a likeable weasel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pak65O"&gt;This week’s trailers include a dysfunctional family, a serial killer, a carnival charlatan, and a classic musical. Never let it be said that I don’t try to add some variety to these roundups. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YTLU6M"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="49czGb"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kevqiiYNFrc?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=1&amp;amp;start=1" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="mnB2Vq"&gt;Succession&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="6bZCgQ"&gt;The squirmiest show on streaming about awful rich people (yes even more awful than you, &lt;em&gt;White Lotus&lt;/em&gt;) is returning for a third season and the Roy family has never looked more dysfunctional. The fallout from the bombshell Kendall delivered in last season’s finale appears to be a central plot line as the Roys decide which side they’re on and how to keep the family business— toxic as it may be— from going under. Cousin Greg is as awkward as ever in this trailer as he informs Kendall he is the “number one trending topic ahead of tater tots.” And Logan is as angry as ever, shouting that he’s ready to go “full fucking beast.” God I missed this show. Adrien Brody, as a billionaire activist investor, and Alexander Skarsgard, as a tech founder and CEO, have joined the show for the upcoming season. Jeremy Strong, Brian Cox, Sarah Snook, Kieran Culkin, Nicholas Braun, Matthew Macfadyen, and J. Smith Cameron return in the third season of &lt;em&gt;Succession, &lt;/em&gt;coming &lt;em&gt;to &lt;/em&gt;HBO Max October 17th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="aVz2Dm"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5VYb3B1ETlk?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="E200u0"&gt;Hawkeye&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="skY9Ro"&gt;So I was not aware this would be a Christmas show but sure, let’s roll with it. &lt;em&gt;Hawkeye&lt;/em&gt; picks up after the events of the &lt;em&gt;Avengers: Endgame&lt;/em&gt; movie, with Clint Barton just trying to enjoy the holidays in New York City with his family when he discovers there’s a new bow-wielding vigilante in town. The trailer has a decidedly jocular tone, which is kind of a new thing for this character. Jeremy Renner, Hailee Steinfeld, Vera Farmiga, Fra Fee, Tony Dalton, Zahn McClarnon, Brian d’Arcy James, and Alaqua Cox star in &lt;em&gt;Hawkeye&lt;/em&gt;, which comes to Disney Plus on November 24th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="evFJSI"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xAN1ThhTWsE?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="2aNCuJ"&gt;You&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="j1A7lI"&gt;Netflix’s show about the serial killer/stalker next door who found his perfect match in season 2 returns for a third season, and Joe and Love are now parents which seems a little problematic? Joe of course has fixated on a new target for his obsession and Love is not super happy about it. Penn Badgley, Victoria Pedretti, and Saffron Burrows return for season 3, which adds Tati Gabrielle, Dylan Arnold, Shalita Grant, Travis Van Winkle, Scott Speedman, McManus, Shannon Chan-Kent, Ben Menhl, Chris O’Shea, and Christopher Sean to the cast. &lt;em&gt;You&lt;/em&gt; comes back to Netflix October 15th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="fSuU7c"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k-qVV8zyVmI?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="BHaGHG"&gt;Nightmare Alley&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="LJw9vW"&gt;Based on the 1946 novel by William Lindsay Gresham, Nightmare Alley is not a supernatural film, director Guillermo del Toro said in an &lt;a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/hollywood/2021/09/nightmare-alley-guillermo-del-toro-awards-insider"&gt;interview with &lt;em&gt;Vanity Fair&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Given his body of work, it’s not a surprise people might make that assumption. The story revolves around a con man and former carnival worker who convinces people he can read minds. The all-star cast includes Bradley Cooper, Cate Blanchett, Toni Collette, Willem Dafoe, Richard Jenkins, Rooney Mara, Ron Perlman, and David Straithairn. &lt;em&gt;Nightmare Alley&lt;/em&gt; comes to theaters December 17th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qi7mJI"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A5GJLwWiYSg?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="eEUcRK"&gt;West Side Story&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="Vu72Ar"&gt;We got a teaser for Steven Spielberg’s adaptation of &lt;em&gt;West Side Story&lt;/em&gt; in May, but this is the first official trailer and I am a little perplexed that it focuses on the plot— of perhaps one of the most famous American movies based on a Shakespeare play which is itself very famous— instead of the songs? At least we get to see snippets of the dance numbers and some words of wisdom from Rita Moreno: Anita in the original 1961 film, who has a small role in this remake and served as a consultant to Spielberg. Ansel Elgort, Rachel Zegler, Ariana DeBose, David Alvarez, Mike Faist, Josh Andres Rivera, Ana Isabelle, Corey Stoll, Brian d’Arcy James also star in &lt;em&gt;West Side Story&lt;/em&gt;, which comes to theaters December 10th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5zadoU"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gBR4e1"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tmv92GzD0pY?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="EO2iMP"&gt;Bonus: Foundation first look trailer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="sgY6Re"&gt;With less than a week to go before this massive series hits Apple TV Plus, we get a first-look trailer with commentary from stars Jared Harris, Leah Harvey, Lee Pace, and Lou Llobell, and writer David S. Goyer, who calls Foundation (the book) “the greatest science fiction work of all time.” Adapted from the Isaac Asimov books, &lt;em&gt;Foundation&lt;/em&gt; drops its first episode on September 24th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jVqpRl"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="R1NTTq"&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="PNgDXB"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/19/22679766/new-trailers-succession-you-nightmare-alley-hawkeye-marvel-disney-netflix-hbo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/19/22679766/new-trailers-succession-you-nightmare-alley-hawkeye-marvel-disney-netflix-hbo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-19T11:05:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-19T11:05:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>Emmys 2021: How to watch online, and who’s nominated</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="73rd Emmy Awards Cedric the Entertainer, executive producers Reginald Hudlin and Ian Stewart, left to right, on stage for a “Sneak Peek” behind-the scenes reveal of television’s biggest night" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2Tzs2dCUffjXNIfUiowZcq4TbPg=/0x0:4000x2667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69879266/1235302770.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The 73rd Emmy Awards will be held on September 19th. | Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oLFfcq"&gt;The 73rd annual Primetime Emmy Awards ceremony is tonight at 8PM ET (5PM PT), and streaming platforms like Apple TV Plus, Netflix and HBO Max are poised to win big. Cedric the Entertainer will host the show, which will be broadcast live from outside the Microsoft Theater in Los Angeles, to accommodate social distancing, which also means the audience will be limited to nominees and their guests. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bGoizX"&gt;Where DO I WATCH THE EMMYS?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="FjlfJF"&gt;This year, CBS will broadcast the Emmys, so you can watch on your local CBS affiliate. The show will also stream live on CBS’ Paramount Plus streaming app. You can sign up for a &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.paramountplus.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F19%2F22680938%2Femmys-2021-watch-date-time-how-to-nominations-online-streaming-cbs-paramount-plus" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;free trial of Paramount Plus&lt;/a&gt; to check it out if you’re not already a subscriber. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2LGLzj"&gt;HOW DO I WATCH THE EMMYS ONLINE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="sEU6pt"&gt;There are plenty of options for watching the Emmys if you don’t have cable TV. You can watch in your internet browser, or through a streaming device (Apple TV, Google Chromecast, Amazon Fire TV, Roku) connected to your television using Hulu with Live TV, YouTube TV, or SlingTV. These are paid services but most offer a free trial period as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3Yu2la"&gt;WHO IS NOMINATED FOR AN EMMY?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="XxGLgU"&gt;Netflix’s series about the British monarchy &lt;em&gt;The Crown&lt;/em&gt;, and Disney Plus’ &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt; each got 24 nominations, and Disney Plus’ Marvel show &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; received 23 noms. The Apple TV Plus comedy &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt; got 20 nominations, and HBO’s (unfortunately canceled) &lt;em&gt;Lovecraft Country&lt;/em&gt; received 18 nominations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rTtpZI"&gt;Some awards were handed out at last weekend’s Creative Arts Emmys. &lt;a href="https://www.vulture.com/2021/09/creative-arts-emmys-2021-night-one-winners-complete-list.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vulture&lt;/em&gt; has that list of winners here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aeIyRH"&gt;Here’s who else could take home an Emmy tonight:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ig8vZI"&gt;OUTSTANDING DRAMA SERIES&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="cVYPB0"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Bridgerton &lt;/em&gt;(Netflix)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8DpiiV"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Boys &lt;/em&gt;(Amazon Prime Video)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="CzhqCG"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Crown &lt;/em&gt;(Netflix) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rV2Uk3"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Handmaid’s Tale&lt;/em&gt; (Hulu)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uCnLV6"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Lovecraft Country &lt;/em&gt;(HBO)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="eEfwij"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian &lt;/em&gt;(Disney Plus)	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kUTxQX"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Pose &lt;/em&gt;(FX)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="5VqC8B"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This Is Us &lt;/em&gt;(NBC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="HZeW4P"&gt;LEAD ACTRESS IN A DRAMA&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="ToW6H3"&gt;Uzo Aduba, &lt;em&gt;In Treatment&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="L4ZzLC"&gt;Olivia Colman, &lt;em&gt;The Crown &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JfvUEY"&gt;Emma Corrin, &lt;em&gt;The Crown &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="CcxtEl"&gt;Elisabeth Moss, &lt;em&gt;The Handmaid’s Tale&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wcjQIM"&gt;MJ Rodriguez, &lt;em&gt;Pose&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2eVith"&gt;Jurnee Smollett,&lt;em&gt; Lovecraft Country&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="q85p7M"&gt;LEAD ACTOR IN A DRAMA&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="GsNYPn"&gt;Sterling K. Brown, &lt;em&gt;This Is Us&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6Noxdi"&gt;Jonathan Majors, &lt;em&gt;Lovecraft Country&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AMko3W"&gt;Josh O’Connor, &lt;em&gt;The Crown&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Zjk7Yo"&gt;Regé-Jean Page, &lt;em&gt;Bridgerton&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dF2USf"&gt;Billy Porter,&lt;em&gt; Pose &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="sj7o4C"&gt;Matthew Rhys,&lt;em&gt; Perry Mason&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Bp2gLo"&gt;SUPPORTING ACTRESS IN A DRAMA&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="2n5x24"&gt;Gillian Anderson, &lt;em&gt;The Crown &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xKhaCE"&gt;Helena Bonham Carter, &lt;em&gt;The Crown &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="sWnLiO"&gt;Madeline Brewer, &lt;em&gt;The Handmaid’s Tale&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="IwRoc5"&gt;Ann Dowd, &lt;em&gt;The Handmaid’s Tale&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2NPUOU"&gt;Aunjanue Ellis, &lt;em&gt;Lovecraft Country&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kq0V2E"&gt;Emerald Fennell,&lt;em&gt; The Crown &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EmsTkJ"&gt;Yvonne Strahovski, &lt;em&gt;The Handmaid’s Tale&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="a04zzo"&gt;Samira Wiley, &lt;em&gt;The Handmaid’s Tale&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vNVNmJ"&gt;SUPPORTING ACTOR IN A DRAMA&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="il6upN"&gt;Giancarlo Esposito, &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="stXMdP"&gt;O.T. Fagbenle, &lt;em&gt;The Handmaid’s Tale &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="d6Fs6C"&gt;John Lithgow,&lt;em&gt; Perry Mason&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="osa2Rd"&gt;Tobias Menzies, &lt;em&gt;The Crown &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="KnvyTN"&gt;Max Minghella, &lt;em&gt;The Handmaid’s Tale &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Lk8Fuf"&gt;Chris Sullivan,&lt;em&gt; This Is Us&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cDDtPE"&gt;Bradley Whitford, &lt;em&gt;The Handmaid’s Tale &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9CcE7q"&gt;Michael K. Williams, &lt;em&gt;Lovecraft Country &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="4tT6ZG"&gt;OUTSTANDING COMEDY Series&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="vVDhVn"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Black-ish&lt;/em&gt;  (ABC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="mZm1yb"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Cobra Kai&lt;/em&gt; (Netflix)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6VwdJi"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Emily in Paris&lt;/em&gt; (Netflix)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="GrQnqq"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Flight Attendant &lt;/em&gt;(HBO)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="5B3do3"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Hacks&lt;/em&gt; (HBO)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="df9emv"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Kominsky Method &lt;/em&gt;(Netflix)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="G3gEBu"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;PEN15&lt;/em&gt; (Hulu)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9pRczK"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt; (Apple TV Plus)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="FCiG6K"&gt;LEAD ACTRESS IN A COMEDY&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="L7CMfa"&gt;Aidy Bryant, &lt;em&gt;Shrill &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="5CvZaT"&gt;Kaley Cuoco, &lt;em&gt;The Flight Attendant&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="tr8eHk"&gt;Allison Janney, &lt;em&gt;Mom &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="tQ1DKx"&gt;Tracee Ellis Ross,&lt;em&gt; Black-ish &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="GTabhq"&gt;Jean Smart,&lt;em&gt; Hacks &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="L6x5oI"&gt;LEAD ACTOR IN A COMEDY&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="OWTroR"&gt;Anthony Anderson, &lt;em&gt;Black-ish&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="CXFH4q"&gt;Michael Douglas, &lt;em&gt;The Kominsky Method&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7PHhRg"&gt;William H. Macy, &lt;em&gt;Shameles&lt;/em&gt;s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="TKS1rt"&gt;Jason Sudeikis,&lt;em&gt; Ted Lasso &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="KztZMD"&gt;Kenan Thompson, &lt;em&gt;Kenan &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="q1O2V6"&gt;SUPPORTING ACTRESS IN A COMEDY&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="p2AGpO"&gt;Aidy Bryant, &lt;em&gt;Saturday Night Live&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="OQYJjv"&gt;Hannah Einbinder, &lt;em&gt;Hacks&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vSGwW2"&gt;Kate McKinnon, &lt;em&gt;Saturday Night Live &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fhv9IX"&gt;Rosie Perez, &lt;em&gt;The Flight Attendant&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cBN1Zr"&gt;Cecily Strong, &lt;em&gt;Saturday Night Live &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="L59Q3b"&gt;Juno Temple, &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="J8X0K1"&gt;Hannah Waddingham, &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ZMcl7E"&gt;SUPPORTING ACTOR IN A COMEDY&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="42gxHC"&gt;Carl Clemons-Hopkins, &lt;em&gt;Hacks &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NWuZwm"&gt;Brett Goldstein, &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="J5Ezyi"&gt;Brendan Hunt, &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="I3tMOE"&gt;Nick Mohammed, &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="s0vzI3"&gt;Paul Reiser, &lt;em&gt;The Kominsky Method &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yej5M5"&gt;Jeremy Swift, &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Hz50aT"&gt;Kenan Thompson, &lt;em&gt;Saturday Night Live&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="1483Ml"&gt;Bowen Yang, &lt;em&gt;Saturday Night Live&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="O2ZSDz"&gt;LIMITED or Anthology SERIES&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="HdSQ9i"&gt;&lt;em&gt;I May Destroy You&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RkJ0oW"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mare of Easttown&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="enBQYW"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Queen’s Gambit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3TJwSm"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Underground Railroad&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="phvIo7"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="QMYwOD"&gt;LEAD ACTRESS IN A LIMITED or anthology SERIES OR MOVIE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="oz9TnV"&gt;Cynthia Erivo, &lt;em&gt;Genius: Aretha&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZLJltd"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Michaela Coel, I May Destroy You&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WSCR3N"&gt;Kate Winslet,&lt;em&gt; Mare of Easttown&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BcI2O5"&gt;Anya Taylor-Joy,&lt;em&gt; The Queen’s Gambit&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="aIkOlL"&gt;Elizabeth Olsen, &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="UBHDws"&gt;LEAD ACTOR IN A LIMITED or Anthology SERIES OR MOVIE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="PvPe1g"&gt;Ewan McGregor, &lt;em&gt;Halston&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="d3fYj8"&gt;Lin-Manuel Miranda&lt;em&gt;, Hamilton&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qHusDg"&gt;Leslie Odom, Jr.&lt;em&gt;, Hamilton&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WuH2dd"&gt;Hugh Grant,&lt;em&gt; The Undoing&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BZCxTa"&gt;Paul Bettany,&lt;em&gt; WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vOMz67"&gt;SUPPORTING ACTRESS IN A LIMITED SERIES OR MOVIE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="1RLXSJ"&gt;Renee Elise Goldsberry, &lt;em&gt;Hamilton&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Ul8uL8"&gt;Phillipa Soo, &lt;em&gt;Hamilton&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="FliRVX"&gt;Julianne Nicholson, &lt;em&gt;Mare of Easttown&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="YyU4SD"&gt;Jean Smart,&lt;em&gt; Mare of Easttown&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3Ah3b3"&gt;Moses Ingram, &lt;em&gt;The Queen’s Gambit&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9XfAGz"&gt;Kathryn Hahn, &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sVYPsB"&gt;SUPPORTING ACTOR IN A LIMITED SERIES OR MOVIE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="XIIji1"&gt;Daveed Diggs, &lt;em&gt;Hamilton&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="K3xp6m"&gt;Jonathan Groff, &lt;em&gt;Hamilton&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="QnaYQS"&gt;Anthony Ramos, &lt;em&gt;Hamilton&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JLNpFw"&gt;Paapa Essiedu, &lt;em&gt;I May Destroy You&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="HBkDyG"&gt;Evan Peters,&lt;em&gt; Mare of Easttown&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yxn7JD"&gt;Thomas Brodie-Sangster, &lt;em&gt;The Queen’s Gambit&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="KFJfrQ"&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id="kMuB1M"&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/19/22680938/emmys-2021-watch-date-time-how-to-nominations-online-streaming-cbs-paramount-plus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/19/22680938/emmys-2021-watch-date-time-how-to-nominations-online-streaming-cbs-paramount-plus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-19T10:24:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-19T10:24:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>NTSB official says Tesla should address “basic safety issues” before expanding full self-driving </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b1SXHECvmWOFRPitVIyoT5lm36g=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69879164/acastro_180430_1777_tesla_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;NTSB chair says Tesla should address safety issues before expanding its so-called “full self-driving” mode. | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7KSds0"&gt;Jennifer Homendy, chair of the National Transportation Safety Board, told the &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/elon-musks-push-to-expand-teslas-driver-assistance-to-cities-rankles-a-top-safety-authority-11632043803?mod=hp_lead_pos3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;that Tesla should address “basic safety issues” before the carmaker expands its so-called “full self-driving” (FSD) mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cQFNl0"&gt;Tesla CEO Elon Musk said earlier this month that the company was&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/7/22660692/tesla-full-self-driving-software-release-date-leak"&gt; aiming for a wider release of FSD&lt;/a&gt; by the end of September, making a “public beta button” available to more Tesla customers. As the&lt;em&gt; WSJ &lt;/em&gt;reports, an upgrade to the software— which was designed primarily for driving on highways— is expected, in order to make the vehicles ready for driving on city streets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UuX7hm"&gt;Homendy had harsh words for Tesla’s use of the term “full self-driving,” which she called “misleading and irresponsible,” adding that Tesla “has clearly misled numerous people to misuse and abuse technology.” The NTSB can conduct investigations and make recommendations, but has no enforcement authority. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aO4ZtY"&gt;According to documents obtained by &lt;a href="https://www.plainsite.org/documents/28jcs0/california-dmv-tesla-robotaxi%E2%80%94fsd-notes/"&gt;legal transparency group PlainSite&lt;/a&gt; in May, Tesla’s director of Autopilot software had told the California Department of Motor Vehicles that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22424592/tesla-elon-musk-autopilot-dmv-fsd-exaggeration"&gt;Musk overstated&lt;/a&gt; the capabilities of the company’s advanced driver assist system, a precursor to FSD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8jX9hz"&gt;In February 2020, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/25/21153320/tesla-autopilot-walter-huang-death-ntsb-probable-cause"&gt;NTSB found Tesla’s Autopilot driver assistance system&lt;/a&gt; was one of the possible causes in a fatal 2018 crash, stating that the driver, who was playing a mobile game while using Autopilot, was overly confident in Autopilot’s capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wr7D10"&gt;The NTSB has said &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/25/21152984/tesla-autopilot-safety-recommendations-ignored-ntsb-crash-hearing"&gt;Tesla ignored its 2017 safety recommendations about Autopilot&lt;/a&gt;. The agency told Tesla and five other automakers they should add safeguards to advanced driver assistance systems so that it’s more difficult to misuse them. It also recommended the automakers limit where and when such driver assistance systems can be used. Tesla was the only carmaker that did not officially respond to the NTSB recommendations, although it did increase the frequency of alerts if a driver takes their hands off the steering wheel when using Autopilot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uSXlu7"&gt;Tesla did not respond to an email seeking comment on Sunday; the company dissolved its press office and typically doesn’t respond to media inquiries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3B2jj5"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S1ZsK3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/19/22682272/ntsb-official-tesla-safety-elon-musk-full-self-driving"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/19/22682272/ntsb-official-tesla-safety-elon-musk-full-self-driving</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-19T09:55:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-19T09:55:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Chevy Bolt recall is burning up what’s left of GM’s EV good will</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sI7HGxUE7lnVIjo3zGpULdMiu6w=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69879060/akrales_170313_1481_A_0019.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2df0OL"&gt;General Motors plans to launch &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22536601/gm-ev-investment-increase-amount-electric-autonomous-vehicles"&gt;30 new electric vehicles around the world by 2025&lt;/a&gt;, and aspires to sell &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/28/22254116/general-motors-carbon-neutral-vow-2040-tailpipe-emissions-ev"&gt;only zero-emissions vehicles by 2035&lt;/a&gt;. But over the last few years, the United States’ biggest automaker has once again squandered the advantages it held in the still-burgeoning field of electric vehicles through bad politics, bad investments, and now most notably, a massive recall of the Bolt — currently its only all-electric vehicle — thanks to around a dozen reported fires. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sxVzPj"&gt;On Thursday, GM announced that it is extending the Bolt’s production shutdown until mid-October, as it apparently hasn’t been able to get supplier LG to produce replacement batteries that are up to snuff. It will need a lot of them, too, as GM has recalled all Bolts made to date — nearly 150,000. (The company says some vehicles will only need certain modules replaced, while others will get the whole battery pack swapped.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sy4adJ"&gt;In the meantime, GM gave Bolt owners something else to worry about this week, as it advised them to park at least 50 feet away from other vehicles. That’s in addition to the previous guidance owners have received, including parking away from their homes, not charging overnight, not charging above 90 percent, or letting their vehicle’s battery drain below around 70 miles of range. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="kQVCEe"&gt;&lt;q&gt;GM’s early push into electric vehicles is looking more like a false start&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="s4PNBN"&gt;All of this has made owning a Bolt a stressful and confusing affair, despite the apparently low odds of a fire. Some owners have tried to get GM to buy back their Bolts — which the company &lt;a href="https://www.thedrive.com/news/40825/gm-is-buying-back-dozens-of-chevy-bolt-evs-that-pose-fire-risk-due-to-rare-manufacturing-defect"&gt;has done in some cases&lt;/a&gt; — only &lt;a href="https://www.freep.com/story/money/cars/general-motors/2021/09/11/chevy-bolt-recall-battery-fire-risk/5683333001/"&gt;to be rejected&lt;/a&gt;. Updates from the company have been intermittent since the initial recall in November 2020. It took until May 2021 for the automaker to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22417634/chevy-bolt-recall-fire-fix-software-update"&gt;announce its first attempted fix&lt;/a&gt; for the problem (which wound up not working), and it wasn’t until July of that year that GM finally admitted what the problem &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/23/22590210/chevy-bolt-new-recall-battery-defect-fire-risk-fix"&gt;was in the first place&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rvR6gz"&gt;“This has been a very complex recall, but we’ve been moving as quickly as possible to provide our customers with information as we learned new developments alongside our supplier, LG,” Kevin Kelly, who leads Chevy’s PR team, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; in an email. “We understand and can certainly appreciate the frustration that our Bolt EV owners have experienced over the past few months, but we’re committed to doing the right thing for our customers and we know we have to get the recall repair right.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4Fi4Oo"&gt;“We continue to make progress and will work as quickly possible and inform owners when we have new information to share,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="tndxGJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Bolt has been one of the most competent, capable, and affordable EVs&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SEC1w0"&gt;The Bolt, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/9/13/12899752/chevy-bolt-driving-impressions-review"&gt;launched in 2016&lt;/a&gt;, was supposed to help GM accomplish two things: set up GM as the first automaker to match Tesla with a mass-market, long-range electric vehicle, and also help everyone forget GM had once briefly led in this category with the EV1 — before it so thoroughly gave up on its fledgling electric car that it literally crushed most of the &lt;a href="https://www.greencarreports.com/news/1131994_report-with-ev1-gm-sparked-the-era-of-the-electric-car-but-didn-t-follow-through"&gt;remaining units to pieces&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AVQoKl"&gt;For a while, it worked. The Bolt never did gangbusters but has been one of the most competent, capable, and affordable electric cars on the market across the last half-decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f7ixWs"&gt;But while GM was making modest progress on the road, it started working against that progress in Washington. When Donald Trump became president, GM was first in line with its Detroit peers when the White House opened for business. Just days after his inauguration, they &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/03/05/business/detroit-automakers-emissions-standards.html"&gt;reportedly lobbied the president to loosen&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;the Obama-era clean car standards&lt;/a&gt; so it would be easier to sell more profitable (but more harmful) SUVs and pickup trucks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GBO2BW"&gt;Trump took that inch and stretched it a country mile. His administration spent the next few years slapping together a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/31/21201036/trump-epa-obama-fuel-economy-rule-rollback-emissions-consumer-cost"&gt;spiteful but shoddy attempt&lt;/a&gt; at a far more drastic rollback of one of his predecessor’s crowning climate achievements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="fxiXFz"&gt;&lt;q&gt;GM then spent time and money encouraging Trump’s deregulatory tendencies&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZmSCPJ"&gt;Some of those automakers, like Ford, eventually wised up and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/25/20727261/trump-emissions-rollback-ford-volkswagon-honda-bmw-california-deal"&gt;struck a compromise deal with California regulators&lt;/a&gt;, as the legal objections mounted to Trump’s decision. But GM doubled down by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/4/21026865/general-motors-ev-day-trump-emissions-rollback-climate-crisis"&gt;joining the Trump administration’s defense&lt;/a&gt;, and only &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/23/21611607/gm-trump-california-car-emission-pollution-biden-fuel-efficiency-standards"&gt;abandoned that position after Trump lost reelection&lt;/a&gt;. The company maintains it only sided with the Trump administration because it shared the belief that the federal government should have the sole right to set national standards for emissions or fuel economy, though California had a waiver to the Clean Air Act that said otherwise (which Trump fought to to revoke). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PVgxwA"&gt;While GM was risking its reputation for the sake of constitutional posturing, it started making similarly questionable moves with its checkbook. First, it &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/04/24/gm-wanted-too-much-from-ev-start-up-rivian-opening-door-for-ford.html"&gt;threw its weight around&lt;/a&gt; with buzzy EV startup Rivian. GM wanted exclusive rights to the technology that would power Rivian’s electric pickup truck and SUV in exchange for a sizable investment. Rivian politely declined and then immediately went on to raise &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/23/22590848/rivian-raise-amazon-ford-new-factory-ipo-electric-pickup"&gt;more than $10 billion&lt;/a&gt; from the likes of Ford and Amazon on its way to an IPO that could see its value skyrocket to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/27/22644601/rivian-ipo-november-december-filing-amazon-ford"&gt;nearly $100 billion&lt;/a&gt; — all without an exclusive deal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wUYosf"&gt;Then, under intense public pressure from the Trump administration, GM sold a recently-closed plant in Lordstown, Ohio to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/8/18537225/gm-factory-workhorse-ev-electric-vehicle-startup-sale-trump-tweet"&gt;a brand new electric pickup truck startup&lt;/a&gt; called Lordstown Motors run by a guy who had recently left his post in charge of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/8/18537225/gm-factory-workhorse-ev-electric-vehicle-startup-sale-trump-tweet"&gt;another unproven EV startup&lt;/a&gt; called Workhorse. GM also took a small stake in Lordstown Motors and participated in the investment portion of the startup’s merger with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/3/21352433/gm-lordstown-motors-electric-truck-startup-public-merger-spac"&gt;a special purpose acquisition company&lt;/a&gt;. GM even had the right to name a board member as part of that deal, but ultimately declined. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="PsawDU"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Spurned by Rivian, GM turned its attention to two far shakier startups&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dF3zyP"&gt;Shortly after that, GM announced a deal with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/8/21427009/gm-nikola-acquisition-electric-hydrogen-truck"&gt;hydrogen electric trucking startup Nikola&lt;/a&gt;, which had a pickup truck project of its own. But that soured quickly after Nikola’s founder and now former CEO was accused of (and later &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/07/29/us-prosecutors-charge-trevor-milton-founder-of-electric-carmaker-nikola-with-three-counts-of-fraud.html"&gt;indicted for&lt;/a&gt;) allegedly lying about a lot of what Nikola was capable of in late 2020. GM abruptly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/30/21726594/gm-nikola-deal-equity-badger-truck-hydrogen"&gt;backed out&lt;/a&gt;. This year, the Lordstown Motors founder faced similar allegations and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/14/22532976/lordstown-motors-ceo-steve-burns-resign-short-seller-investigation"&gt;was eventually pushed out&lt;/a&gt;. GM still holds a small stake in Lordstown Motors, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mgiBBC"&gt;GM is already back in the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22610501/biden-2030-ev-goal-trump-emissions-rollback"&gt;good graces of the Biden administration&lt;/a&gt;. And in a few years, with electric &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/3/22362072/hummer-suv-electric-price-specs-release-date"&gt;Hummers&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/6/22370058/gm-chevy-electric-silverado-pickup-truck"&gt;Silverados&lt;/a&gt; cruising the roads powered by the company’s next-generation battery pack, few will remember the company‘s involvement in two sketchy startups, or recall the automaker’s failed attempt at corralling one of the hottest electric vehicle companies to come to market of our time. After all, these were the kinds of metaphorical fires that tend to be easier to extinguish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="6QFN1n"&gt;The problems with the Bolt, however, could cast a lasting pall — because this time the flames are real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K2NmkT"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EFSfE6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/19/22677539/chevy-bolt-recall-gm-electric-vehicles-fire-tesla-competition"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/19/22677539/chevy-bolt-recall-gm-electric-vehicles-fire-tesla-competition</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-19T09:33:15-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-19T09:33:15-04:00</updated>
    <title>Surface Pro 8 leaks with 120Hz display and Thunderbolt support</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rYKK1ThfPq19mcYBiJZixfbIyUw=/1x0:952x634/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69879036/surfacepro8.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A leaked image of the Surface Pro 8.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Shadow_Leak (&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/Shadow_Leak/status/1439546343190638597" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8pvjpq"&gt;Microsoft is preparing to launch a new Surface Pro 8 model next week, and a leak appears to have revealed exactly what to expect. Twitter account &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Shadow_Leak/status/1439546343190638597"&gt;Shadow_Leak&lt;/a&gt; has published a photo of the Surface Pro 8 from what appears to be a retail listing. The account claims the Surface Pro 8 will ship with a new 13-inch 120Hz display with narrow bezels and two Thunderbolt ports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VxwJCH"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671271/microsoft-surface-event-pro-8-surface-book-4-rumors"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; reported last week&lt;/a&gt; that the Surface Pro 8 would ship without USB-A ports, in favor of USB-C and Thunderbolt. We also reported that Microsoft has been testing 120Hz displays for the Surface Pro lineup. The leaked image and specs line up with what we’ve heard from sources familiar with Microsoft’s plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Qfgd9i"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Microsoft Surface Pro 8 Exposure ✅&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- Intel's 11th-generation Core processor&lt;br&gt;- 13" 120Hz High Refresh Rate Narrow Border Screen&lt;br&gt;- Windows 11&lt;br&gt;- Dual Thunderbolt Interfaces&lt;br&gt;- Replaceable SSD Hard Drives&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Microsoft?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Surface?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Surface&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SurfacePro8?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#SurfacePro8&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/ITFftYG4dg"&gt;pic.twitter.com/ITFftYG4dg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Sam (@Shadow_Leak) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Shadow_Leak/status/1439546343190638597?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 19, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qv43RR"&gt;The leak also reveals Microsoft is moving to removable SSDs on the Surface Pro 8. That matches the Surface Laptop 4, Surface Pro X, and the business-only Surface Pro 7 plus and will make it easier for businesses to swap out drives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BxB7pV"&gt;Microsoft is holding a Surface hardware event on September 22nd, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671271/microsoft-surface-event-pro-8-surface-book-4-rumors"&gt;where we’re expecting&lt;/a&gt; the company to announce the Surface Pro 8, a Surface Go 3, a newly designed Surface Book 4, an updated Surface Pro X, and the successor to the Android-powered Surface Duo. Stay tuned to &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;for all the Surface news on September 22nd, from 11AM ET / 8AM PT onwards.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/19/22682271/surface-pro-8-120hz-display-thunderbolt-support-leak-rumors"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/19/22682271/surface-pro-8-120hz-display-thunderbolt-support-leak-rumors</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-19T09:00:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-19T09:00:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>TikTok parent ByteDance adds time limit for kids under 14 on its video app in China</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="ByteDance Ltd.’s Douyin App As TikTok Owner Challenges Alibaba in E-Commerce Ahead of IPO" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eSDRXJHH_PtyDeh2Q4wGTeQG_vQ=/0x2:5000x3335/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69878967/1232774217.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;TikTok is branded under the name Douyin in China | Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="95SQfz"&gt;The Chinese version of the popular short video app TikTok, known as Douyin, will limit users in China who are under 14 years old to 40 minutes a day, parent company ByteDance &lt;a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/zp43DhzwanDApoPCIgCvJQ"&gt;said in a blog post&lt;/a&gt; Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OgAF2a"&gt;The app’s youth mode keeps it in line with the Chinese government’s new restrictions on access to video games for younger children. Teens under 14 will be able to access Douyin between 6AM and 10PM, but won’t be able to use the app outside of that window, the company said. The rules will apply to “real-name authenticated users” under 14, and the company encouraged parents to help their children complete the real-name authentication process, or activate youth mode when prompted by the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PwtNuw"&gt;The Chinese government has been focused on reducing the amount of time Chinese teenagers spend online, which it views as harmful. Last month, its National Press and Publication Administration &lt;a href="http://www.nppa.gov.cn/nppa/contents/279/98792.shtml"&gt;unveiled new rules&lt;/a&gt;, which restrict Chinese citizens under 18 to playing online games only on Fridays, weekends, and holidays, between 8PM and 9PM. Authorities have directed game companies and platforms like Douyin to use real-name identification for all its users; the process requires users to provide a phone number and other identification to access online games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4EAY9b"&gt;ByteDance said the content available to users in youth mode will now include educational material like “interesting popular science experiments, exhibitions in museums and galleries, beautiful scenery across the country, explanations of historical knowledge, and so on.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KK2aau"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ytkzMP"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LDIlj9"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/19/22682219/tiktok-parent-bytedance-limits-kids-douyin-app-china"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/19/22682219/tiktok-parent-bytedance-limits-kids-douyin-app-china</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
