<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2020-12-02T11:09:46-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-02T11:09:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-02T11:09:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>Discovery, home of Shark Week, HGTV, and Food Network, enters the streaming wars with Discovery Plus </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XXaEou9eiet7gwzilq9jTWBlnTA=/2x0:785x522/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68366150/Screen_Shot_2020_12_02_at_10.50.33_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9YBmOu"&gt;Discovery, home to HGTV, Food Network, and Discovery Channel’s annual Shark Week, is entering the streaming space with Discovery Plus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sLXTfv"&gt;Details about the streamer will be revealed at a special event this afternoon, but &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/12/02/discovery-to-launch-streaming-service-in-january-for-4point99-per-month.html?__source=twitter%7Cmain"&gt;CNBC&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; that Discovery Plus will start at $4.99 with an ad-supported tier, along with a $6.99 ad-free option. The streaming service will launch in January 2021, but it’s unclear if that’s just in the United States or also internationally. CNBC&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;also reports that Discovery is partnering with Verizon to give the telecom company’s 55 million customers a free year of ad-free Discovery Plus. It’s the same move that Disney did with Verizon when the company launched Disney Plus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NTKx8c"&gt;The company’s collection of notable brands is likely what executives are banking on. CEO David Zaslav spoke about the company’s approach at a recent conference, as &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/discovery-to-unveil-global-streaming-service-strategy-on-dec-2"&gt;reported by The Hollywood Reporter&lt;/a&gt;, noting that “super fans” will want a place to watch their favorite personalities from their favorite shows on networks like HGTV (&lt;em&gt;Property Brothers&lt;/em&gt;, Joanna and Chip Gaines) or the Food Network (Guy Fieri, Ina Garten) — and then some. There are also plans for original content that would be exclusively available on Discovery Plus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YOzvvE"&gt;“We have been aggressively driving additional original content ... we think you need a substantial amount of original content,” Zaslav said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H03zNP"&gt;Discovery isn’t a mammoth conglomerate in the same way that many of its streaming competitors are (Disney, WarnerMedia, ViacomCBS, NBCUniversal), but niche streamers have found their places before. Crunchyroll, which caters to anime fans, has more than &lt;a href="https://www.crunchyroll.com/anime-news/2020/07/28/crunchyroll-crosses-three-million-subscribers"&gt;3 million subscribers&lt;/a&gt;. Shudder, a streamer dedicated to horror content, passed the &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2020/09/shudder-hits-1m-subscribers-as-key-part-of-amc-networks-targeted-streaming-approach-1234582104/"&gt;1 million paid subscribers mark&lt;/a&gt; this year. The WWE Network has &lt;a href="https://corporate.wwe.com/investors/sec-and-other-documents/financials"&gt;more than 1.6 million subscribers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y9LbPK"&gt;Still, there’s no question that competition is tough, even for the biggest players. While Disney Plus may pass 100 million subscribers by the end of the year, and Netflix is likely past 200 million subscribers, new entrants like HBO Max and Peacock are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/22/21528234/hbo-max-subscribers-activations-att-directv-warner"&gt;seeing slower growth&lt;/a&gt;. Part of that has to do with newfound difficulties creating content this year because of the pandemic, but there are also concerns from analysts and experts that the space, especially within the United States, &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/22011750-83a7-11e9-9935-ad75bb96c849"&gt;is oversaturated&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9n6V7j"&gt;In the year that every company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21536842/streaming-disney-hbo-max-peacock-cbs-all-access-warnermedia-viacom-nbcuniversal"&gt;pivoted to streaming&lt;/a&gt;, however, it’s no surprise that corporations like Discovery are trying to find new ways to pull in subscribers and develop recurring revenue. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; will update this story with more details once they’re announced at the event. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/22018581/discovery-streaming-service-launch-date-price-shark-week-hgtv-food-network"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/22018581/discovery-streaming-service-launch-date-price-shark-week-hgtv-food-network</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-02T11:05:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-02T11:05:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Mandalorian is the perfect Fortnite character</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e0uaMnxb0Ruzy4bVw-ltaqJ6qEo=/384x0:3180x1864/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68364890/Fortnite_20201202100316.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="my8bgx"&gt;Anyone who buys the battle pass for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/21831926/fortnite-chapter-2-season-5-battle-pass-trailer-mandalorian-baby-yoda"&gt;the new season of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; gets a nice initial bonus: a playable version of none other than the Mandalorian himself. He unlocks right away, and in many ways, he’s in keeping with the game’s recent strategy of focusing on branded tie-ins. Recent characters have included everyone from Wolverine to Travis Scott, Harley Quinn, and Kathleen “Loserfruit” Belsten. But Mando also differs from those others in one key way: he’s just about the perfect character for the battle royale game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MW7wb4"&gt;At this point, it’s not a new idea to point out that &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/star-wars/2019/11/25/20978320/the-mandalorian-video-game-comparison-disney-plus-fetch-quest-armor-upgrade"&gt;often structured like a video game&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a story about a bounty hunter going out on a series of fetch quests; every time he asks for help, he’s tasked with going somewhere else to either collect an item or kill a monster. He’s basically an armored version of the Witcher. And often, he’ll be rewarded for his efforts with new gear, either in the form of stronger armor or maybe a fancy new spear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wPTTY7"&gt;It turns out, this is a perfect fit for &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;’s new bounty hunter-focused season. In the game’s continuously evolving fiction, the island is now overrun with the greatest hunters from various realities, all doing... something to stop the pull of a time-bending event that resulted from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21747893/fortnite-galactus-event-chapter-2-season-5-release-date"&gt;an attack by Marvel supervillain Galactus&lt;/a&gt;. It’s confusing, but it works well with &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;’s quest structure, where you’re constantly tasked with new things in order to unlock more gear. There are even new bounties, where you can talk to NPCs or grab jobs from a bulletin board, asking you to kill a specific player.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Bq-euB_41WE6RcSYznVMmWNRpMM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22137155/Fortnite_20201202100942.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="H2RN8q"&gt;Initially, Mando looks a bit rough. He isn’t the slick, shiny hunter he is in season 2 of the show. In order to get him to that point, you have to complete quests and slowly unlock new pieces of Beskar armor. It’s going to take a while. There are nine pieces to unlock, and one appears to only be available once you hit level 100. The same goes for Mando’s most important accessory: Grogu, better known as The Child or Baby Yoda, is available once you max out this season’s battle pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="72JcT2"&gt;It’s a bit annoying that I’m going to have to wait so long to watch Grogu sip bone broth while I’m in the middle of a shootout. But I love that this version of the Mandalorian feels so true to the character: he has a lot of cool gear, but it requires plenty of effort to get it.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/22028767/the-mandalorian-fortnite-perfect-character-season-5"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/22028767/the-mandalorian-fortnite-perfect-character-season-5</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-02T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-02T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The original Fire Emblem is great on the Switch, but Nintendo’s retro strategy continues to confuse</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZKLn7Di9l748cAgJiPBUtRiym1s=/80x0:944x576/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68362999/Switch_FireEmblemShadowDragonBladeofLight_Screenshot__1__2.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VLsUZA"&gt;Like many longtime &lt;em&gt;Fire Emblem&lt;/em&gt; fans, I’ve never actually played the first game in the series. 1990’s &lt;em&gt;Fire Emblem: Shadow Dragon and the Blade of Light&lt;/em&gt; kicked off what has slowly turned into one of Nintendo’s most important franchises, a series that blends tense tactical battles with character-driven storytelling. It’s not my fault, though: the original game never actually launched outside of Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1YsyYR"&gt;Three decades later, that’s finally changing with the release of &lt;em&gt;Shadow Dragon and the Blade of Light&lt;/em&gt; on the Nintendo Switch. It’s a solid, no-frills port that’s only $5.99, making it an enticing option for fans looking for a history lesson. But it also points to Nintendo’s increasingly confusing strategy for its large library of classic games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f3odeR"&gt;First, the game itself. If you’re coming to &lt;em&gt;Shadow Dragon and the Blade of Light&lt;/em&gt; after playing a more recent entry in the series — like, say, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/25/20726336/fire-emblem-three-houses-review-nintendo-switch"&gt;2019’s &lt;em&gt;Three Houses&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — you’ll probably be shocked by how straightforward the original game is. It doesn’t have any of the relationship-building that eventually became a staple of the franchise. Instead, the focus is almost entirely on turn-based, strategic combat. You control Marth and a small army of soldiers, traveling to different kingdoms to ward off enemies. This almost always means defeating every soldier and capturing the castle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Up586y"&gt;There are some nice twists in terms of your goals and the map’s geography, and the game neatly interweaves story with combat. I actually found it surprising how well &lt;em&gt;Shadow Dragon and the Blade of Light &lt;/em&gt;holds up. It’s particularly great as a Switch game, where I can knock out a battle, or even just a few turns, whenever I have free time. While it’s mostly a straight port, there are some nice modern touches, including a rewind feature, the ability to bookmark mid-battle, and an option to fast-forward through the incredibly slow enemy turns.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4lJu5bdDrzoH2goV9Vv2VAF4ots=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22134242/Switch_FireEmblemShadowDragonBladeofLight_Screenshot__2__2.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="23fDWr"&gt;As much as I’m enjoying the game, I do wonder why it’s not part of Switch Online. Selling classic games individually is how Nintendo used to operate, of course, with its Virtual Console on platforms like the Wii and Wii U. But that changed with the Switch. In order to lure players to its fledgling online subscription service, Nintendo added a Netflix-like feature, featuring a growing library of NES and SNES titles to play through. It’s turned into one of my favorite things about the Switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pKYRT7"&gt;In the past, Nintendo has even added unreleased games, most notably &lt;em&gt;Star Fox 2&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/29/16383958/star-fox-2-snes-classic-nintendo-review"&gt;a canceled SNES game that first debuted as part of the SNES Classic mini-console&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/15/21439181/donkey-kong-country-2-nintendo-switch-online-september-games"&gt;as well as &lt;em&gt;Mario Picross&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which didn’t originally launch in North America. These kinds of surprise releases are important to drum up excitement for any streaming service. It’s why Netflix spends so much on original series and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21449178/microsoft-xbox-bethesda-zenimax-media-acquisition-xbox-game-pass"&gt;Microsoft dropped $7.5 billion on Bethesda to beef up Xbox Game Pass&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HLkAZQ"&gt;Switch Online isn’t quite the same as those, but it still needs a steady stream of new (retro) releases to keep people subscribing. And it’s in the unique position where most of the games it announces as coming soon, whether it’s &lt;em&gt;Donkey Kong Country&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Super Metroid&lt;/em&gt;, are ones that fans are already familiar with. A release like &lt;em&gt;Shadow Dragon and the Blade of Light&lt;/em&gt; changes this. It’s a rare surprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="GRX7vR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Nintendo’s remake of Fire Emblem Gaiden is a love letter to a 25-year-old strategy game","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2017/5/18/15658120/fire-emblem-echoes-nintendo-3ds-remake-interview"},{"title":"An unprecedented Nintendo leak turns into a moral dilemma for archivists","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/30/21347074/nintendo-gigaleak-controversy-history-preservation-archives"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ng3Pa3"&gt;I fully understand that rereleasing the original &lt;em&gt;Fire Emblem&lt;/em&gt; is more involved than most Switch Online titles. Not only does it have some new quality-of-life features, but it’s also a text-heavy game that had to be localized. So in some ways, it makes sense as a standalone release. But it would also be a boon for the subscription service, one that would help simplify Nintendo’s often frustrating approach to its own history that’s scattered across platforms and devices. (To make matters even stranger, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21438499/super-mario-3d-all-stars-review-nintendo-switch"&gt;much like &lt;em&gt;Super Mario 3D All-Stars&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the game will only be on sale until March 31st, 2021.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u2lpwU"&gt;Nintendo Switch Online solved some of this, with a steadily growing library that was easily accessible for subscribers, all on an incredibly popular piece of hardware. It’s also not hard to envision a future where that subscription follows you to future Nintendo devices, whatever they may be. Maybe one day I won’t have to repurchase &lt;em&gt;Super Metroid&lt;/em&gt; for every new Nintendo console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2EBUs7"&gt;I highly recommend &lt;em&gt;Shadow Dragon and the Blade of Light&lt;/em&gt; for fans looking to dig into how the series evolved. Playing the original &lt;em&gt;Fire Emblem&lt;/em&gt; in 2020 is a fascinating experience that’s long overdue. I just wish the process of playing it, and the rest of Nintendo’s enviable lineup of classic games, was a little more straightforward. Now where is &lt;em&gt;Mother 3&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4Rfx9o"&gt;&lt;small&gt;Fire Emblem: Shadow Dragon and the Blade of Light&lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt; launches on December 4th on the Nintendo Switch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/21778351/fire-emblem-shadow-dragon-and-the-blade-of-light-nintendo-switch-online-retro-games"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/21778351/fire-emblem-shadow-dragon-and-the-blade-of-light-nintendo-switch-online-retro-games</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-02T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-02T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Alphabet’s Loon hands the reins of its internet air balloons to self-learning AI</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3L5QfgHf6vbTxM9Z6XCR0Z14X_4=/176x0:1864x1125/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68363009/1_Xfj6pEzUM5Gw3UKUaEw2qQ.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Loon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mlNi09"&gt;Alphabet’s Loon, the team responsible for beaming internet down to Earth from stratospheric helium balloons, has achieved a new milestone: its navigation system is no longer run by human-designed software. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LURoKH"&gt;Instead, the company’s internet balloons are steered around the globe by an artificial intelligence — in particular, a set of algorithms both written and executed by a deep reinforcement learning-based flight control system that is more efficient and adept than the older, human-made one. The system is now managing Loon’s fleet of balloons over Kenya, where Loon &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/7/21315961/alphabet-loon-balloons-internet-kenya-telkom-4g-remote-areas"&gt;launched its first commercial internet service in July&lt;/a&gt; after testing its fleet in a series of disaster relief initiatives and other test environments for much of the last decade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ahSxwf"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Loon’s internet balloons are now piloted by an AI flight control system&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="F5Nsks"&gt;Similar to how researchers have achieved breakthrough AI advances in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/13/18309459/openai-five-dota-2-finals-ai-bot-competition-og-e-sports-the-international-champion"&gt;teaching computers to play sophisticated video games&lt;/a&gt; and helping software &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/15/20914575/openai-dactyl-robotic-hand-rubiks-cube-one-handed-solve-dexterity-ai"&gt;learn how to manipulate robotic hands in lifelike ways&lt;/a&gt;, reinforcement learning is a technique that allows software to teach itself skills through trial and error. Obviously, such repetition is not possible in the real world when dealing with high-altitude balloons that are costly to operate and even more costly to repair in the event they crash. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6dYQwE"&gt;So Loon, like many other AI labs that have turned to reinforcement learning to develop sophisticated AI programs, taught its flight control system how to pilot the balloons using computer simulation, with help from Google’s AI team out of Montreal. That way, the system could improve over time before being deployed on a real-world balloon fleet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pwpsbo"&gt;“While the promise of RL (reinforcement learning) for Loon was always large, when we first began exploring this technology it was not always clear that deep RL was practical or viable for high altitude platforms drifting through the stratosphere autonomously for long durations,” writes Sal Candido, Loon’s chief technology officer, in a blog post. “It turns out that RL is practical for a fleet of stratospheric balloons. These days, Loon’s navigation system’s most complex task is solved by an algorithm that is learned by a computer experimenting with balloon navigation in simulation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xDRUjr"&gt;Loon says its system qualifies as the world’s first deployment of this variety of AI in a commercial aerospace system. And not only that, but it actually outperforms the system designed by humans. “To be frank, we wanted to confirm that by using RL a machine could build a navigation system equal to what we ourselves had built,” Candido explains. “The learned deep neural network that specifies the flight controls is wrapped with an appropriate safety assurance layer to ensure the agent is always driving safely. Across our simulation benchmark we were able to not only replicate but dramatically improve our navigation system by utilizing RL.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S2wN8n"&gt;In its first real-world test over Peru in July 2019, the AI-controlled flight system went head-to-head with a traditional one, controlled by a human-built algorithm called StationSeeker, that was designed by the Loon engineers themselves. “In some sense it was the machine — which spent a few weeks building its controller — against me — who, along with many others, had spent many years carefully fine-tuning our conventional controller based on a decade of experience working with Loon balloons. We were nervous... and hoping to lose,” Candido says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="utorro"&gt;&lt;q&gt; “Even if it’s not the beginning of an Asimov novel, it’s a good story and maybe something worth calling AI.” &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KWvzxs"&gt;The AI-controlled system handily outperformed the human one by consistently staying closer to a device the team uses to measure LTE signals in the field, and that test paved the way for more experiments to prove the efficacy of the system before it formally replaced the one the team had spent years building by hand. Loon now thinks its system can “serve as a proof point that RL can be useful to control complicated, real world systems for fundamentally continual and dynamic activity.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XpuLcc"&gt;In his closing remarks, Candido touches on the concept of whether this type of AI is worthy of the name, because of how specialized it is and how closely it resembles a traditional but not self-learning, automated system like the ones that operate heavy machinery or control elements of mass transit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hc2plo"&gt;“While there is no chance that a super-pressure balloon drifting efficiently through the stratosphere will become sentient, we have transitioned from designing its navigation system ourselves to having computers construct it in a data-driven manner,” he says. “Even if it’s not the beginning of an Asimov novel, it’s a good story and maybe something worth calling AI.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XMh1vn"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P36Kbp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/21811123/alphabet-loon-internet-balloons-ai-machine-learning-pilot"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/21811123/alphabet-loon-internet-balloons-ai-machine-learning-pilot</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-02T10:56:48-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-02T10:56:48-05:00</updated>
    <title>Trump calls for last-minute 230 repeal as part of defense spending bill</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="President Trump Participates In Thanksgiving Video Teleconference With Military Members" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wgEBEsdg66OQR3BY2CK6b76e-Xk=/0x0:4179x2786/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68361947/1287973485.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Erin Schaff - Pool/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iwxIC8"&gt;On Tuesday, President Donald Trump threatened to veto an annual defense bill authorizing billions of dollars in military spending unless Congress agreed to strip away a pivotal internet law that provides Facebook, Google, and Twitter with legal immunity over content posted by their users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pu5gVh"&gt;The result is a standoff holding up one of Congress’ most vital pieces of legislation and placing Section 230 under an unusually imminent threat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="BTVSv7"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:8777491"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MYfZRy"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21273768/section-230-explained-internet-speech-law-definition-guide-free-moderation"&gt;A foundational legal protection for online speech platforms&lt;/a&gt;, Section 230 has become controversial in recent years, and there is growing desire across the ideological spectrum to reform the law. During the primary campaign, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/29/21274812/joe-biden-donald-trump-twitter-facebook-section-230-moderation-revoke"&gt;President-elect Joe Biden said Section 230&lt;/a&gt; “should be revoked, immediately,” responding to concerns that Facebook was shirking its responsibility to moderate the platform. Republicans have taken issue with 230 for the opposite reason, seeing it as granting platforms an inappropriately broad license to censor speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UCuOTi"&gt;The issue became particularly urgent for President Trump in the days after the election, when he used Twitter to spread &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/5/21550991/twitter-trump-stop-the-vote-tweet-restricted-election-interference"&gt;baseless accusations of election fraud&lt;/a&gt;. The platform responded by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/6/21552471/trump-twitter-restricted-false-election-claims-moderation"&gt;labeling the tweets as misinformation&lt;/a&gt; about a civic process (a specifically protected category on Twitter) and restricting their reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rAsbza"&gt;Now, the outgoing president has tied 230 repeal to defense funding, one of the few pieces of legislation that is seen as a “must-pass” by members of Congress. The National Defense Authorization Act primarily authorizes spending by the military and other national security agencies, so a failure to pass some version of the bill could have severe consequences for the nation as a whole. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aXnHMp"&gt;The “must-pass” nature of the bill makes it the perfect target for lawmakers looking to sneak their own partisan priorities (known as riders) into a bill that will surely pass by the end of the fiscal year. It’s a long-standing process for lawmakers, but rarely attempted for an issue as delicate as 230 reform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nN2ThR"&gt;In &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1333965375193624578?s=20"&gt;a series of tweets&lt;/a&gt; last night, the president was unequivocal in his desire to attach a repeal of Section 230 to the bill. “Section 230, which is a liability shielding gift from the U.S. to ‘Big Tech’ (the only companies in America that have it — corporate welfare!), is a serious threat to our National Security and Election Integrity,” Trump said. He continued, saying that if the “very dangerous &amp;amp; unfair Section 230 is not completely terminated as part of the [NDAA], I will be forced to unequivocally VETO the Bill when sent to the very beautiful Resolute desk.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ofucSS"&gt;As of publication, the first tweet in Trump’s Tuesday night thread was pinned to the top of his Twitter profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="QifOvG"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I’d like to start for the Blazers, but it’s not going to happen either,” said Sen. Wyden&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RIpWoN"&gt;This year’s NDAA includes a provision to rename 10 military installations that currently honor Confederate military officers, a policy President Trump has &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/politics-news/trump-set-veto-defense-bill-over-renaming-bases-honoring-confederates-n1248467"&gt;strenuously opposed&lt;/a&gt;. In November, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/19/us/white-house-hints-at-deal-that-would-drop-confederate-leaders-names-from-military-bases.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;reported that the White House chief of staff, Mark Meadows, told NDAA negotiators in Congress that Trump could be open to signing a version of the bill that renamed Confederate-named military bases if Democrats agreed to repeal Section 230.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7B5Dst"&gt;As of Tuesday, Republicans were also working to include bills like Sen. Roger Wicker’s (R-MS) Online Freedom and Viewpoint Diversity Act, &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/senators-offer-slip-section-230-changes-defense-bill-a09f3428-ce5f-468c-8127-5fc413c996a7.html"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Axios&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;But Wicker’s bill doesn’t amount to a full repeal of the tech industry’s liability shield, and it’s unclear whether the White House would support a version of the NDAA with Wicker’s bill as a rider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o5avoh"&gt;The NDAA is typically approved by veto-proof majorities. So even if Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell (R-KY) would agree to placing this year’s NDAA on the floor, Congress could easily overrule Trump’s veto. But according to reporting from &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post &lt;/em&gt;last month, McConnell has a policy against taking bills to the Senate floor for a vote when they’ve &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/12/01/trump-repeal-section-230-ndaa/"&gt;received a veto threat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ayvaGO"&gt;Still, some lawmakers, including Sen. Ron Wyden (D-OR), one of the original architects of Section 230, seem to think that Trump’s 230 threat holds little weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PADjWG"&gt;“I’d like to start for the Blazers, but it’s not going to happen either,” Wyden said in a statement Wednesday. “It is pathetic that Trump refuses to help unemployed workers, while he spends his time tweeting unhinged election conspiracies and demanding Congress repeal the foundation of free speech online.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/22037118/trump-section-230-repeal-ndaa-rider-facebook-twitter-moderation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/22037118/trump-section-230-repeal-ndaa-rider-facebook-twitter-moderation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-02T10:55:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-02T10:55:37-05:00</updated>
    <title>Walmart Plus drops $35 free shipping minimum to better compete with Amazon Prime</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4iOOcRMsxo9UlDT6vdUBq6qv69w=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68361486/acastro_180802_1777_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QQSxtn"&gt;Walmart is removing the $35 free shipping minimum on its annual subscription service, Walmart Plus, the company announced on Wednesday. The new policy will take effect on Friday, December 4th, and it means all Walmart Plus members will receive free next-day and two-day shipping on items ordered from Walmart’s website, regardless of the size of their order. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qUoWjz"&gt;The change is a clear attempt to better compete with Amazon Prime, the subscription service on which Walmart Plus is based. One of the biggest benefits of Prime since its introduction more than 15 years ago has been free (and often two-day and now one-day) shipping on all eligible orders. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="9zAEWh"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Amazon and Walmart are competing to offer the most convenient delivery service&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="emGzTa"&gt;That made Walmart’s $35 order minimum for its Prime competitor a significant setback for the big-box retailer when it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/1/21409944/walmart-free-delivery-subscription-service-walmart-compete-amazon-prime"&gt;launched its service back in September&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s a telling sign that Walmart is removing the restriction so early in the lifespan of its service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iG9CL2"&gt;Amazon and Walmart have long had a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/3/17630604/amazon-walmart-competition-tech-partnerships-grocery-delivery"&gt;fierce rivalry in the retail space,&lt;/a&gt; Amazon having dominated US e-commerce and now moving onward to physical retail and groceries while Walmart has attempted the reverse. Both companies are now the US’s largest employers, and both want to be the one place you buy almost everything. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0pFl3Q"&gt;At the intersection of these colossal corporations’ core businesses is ever-faster and free delivery. The more reliable, fast, and low-cost your ability to deliver products to a customer’s front door — especially amid the coronavirus pandemic — the more likely that customer will order from you again in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RecerK"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/22024753/walmart-plus-35-dollar-free-shipping-minimum-removed-amazon-prime-competition"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/22024753/walmart-plus-35-dollar-free-shipping-minimum-removed-amazon-prime-competition</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-02T10:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-02T10:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Acer Aspire 5 review: a $549 laptop that doesn’t completely suck</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;But try to find an AMD model&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="mHOZTi"&gt;The Acer Aspire 5 is a very functional laptop. I used it as my primary work driver for over a week, including the whirlwind that was Black Friday weekend. It loads the pages I need it to. It handles a heavy share of tabs and apps without burning itself up. It’s not seven pounds. Basically, it’s a $549 laptop that doesn’t completely suck. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AHgPAE"&gt;There was a time when that would’ve made this the best budget laptop you can buy. But that time has come to an end, and the reason rhymes with “bay-MD.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wkoci6"&gt;This Aspire 5 model has a four-core Intel Core i5-1035G1, the same budget- and midrange-oriented processor that powers Microsoft’s Surface Laptop Go. Performance-wise, it gets the job done — but its battery life is disastrous, and its integrated graphics are behind the times at this point. My advice: if you can get your hands on one, buy the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.acer.com%2Fac%2Fen%2FUS%2Fcontent%2Fmodel%2FNX.HW4AA.003&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21815008%2Facer-aspire-5-review-2020-15-inch-laptop-specs-features-price#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AMD model&lt;/a&gt; with a six-core AMD Ryzen 5 4500U for the same price instead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uawlMr"&gt;
&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:9839498"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The hinge of the Acer Aspire 5, with the word Aspire printed." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/c_fzHk_vgeQ9Fmpp5D9_IVrDSpc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22029469/akrales_201110_4271_0087.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Acer says the Aspire 5 is for “a range of customers who want to get the most bang for their buck.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Acer Aspire 5 fingerprint reader." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/14NbiY3kb4O_7eGWy75gBTWNB0A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22029467/akrales_201110_4271_0104.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can use the fingerprint reader to sign in without a password.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="epuXt4"&gt;Starting with the design, which is the same across both models. I’d say the Aspire 5 looks fine — it’s no Dell XPS, but it’s still respectable from all angles. It comes in a few colors including silver and black. (I have the silver one, though I think the &lt;a href="https://www.microcenter.com/product/625686/acer-aspire-5-a515-55-57a6-156-laptop-computer---black_Hatchfeed"&gt;black&lt;/a&gt; looks a bit fancier myself.) Most of it is plastic, but the top cover (the part people are most likely to see) is aluminum. There’s some flex in the keyboard and the screen, but not so much that I worried about snapping the thing in half. It’s neither ultraportable nor overly clunky, weighing 3.7 pounds (1.8 kg) and measuring 14.3 x 9.9 x 0.7 inches. Students should note that while the Aspire isn’t terribly heavy, its breadth makes it a bit of a chore to fit in a standard-sized backpack alongside a load of books and binders.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vd8ehs"&gt;A few other touches you might notice: Like the higher-priced Swift line, the Aspire 5 has a lustrous center hinge with “Aspire” printed across it, which is a nice bit of flair. The bezels, though, are quite large and very plastic-looking. The top one is particularly hefty. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qamxOb"&gt;All fair enough. At $549, I’ll take it. But it is worth noting that you don’t need to spend all that much more to get significantly higher build quality if you’re willing to compromise on screen size. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21377208/acer-swift-3-review-2020-14-inch-laptop-specs-features-price"&gt;Acer Swift 3&lt;/a&gt; (if you’ll take a 14-incher) is a nicer-looking, slimmer, and sturdier-feeling machine. Its &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.acer.com%2Fen-us%2Fswift-3-laptop-sf314-42-r7lh&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21815008%2Facer-aspire-5-review-2020-15-inch-laptop-specs-features-price#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ryzen 5 4500U model&lt;/a&gt; is only $80 more expensive than this Aspire 5 on Acer’s website (and is even cheaper when it’s &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bjs.com%2Fproduct%2Facer-swift-3-sf314-42-r7lh-laptop-amd-ryzen-5-4500u-hexa-core-mobile-processor-8gb-memory-256gb-ssd%2F3000000000002395259&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21815008%2Facer-aspire-5-review-2020-15-inch-laptop-specs-features-price#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on sale&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Acer Aspire 5 from the back, half open." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jt6BaJYMNENlnkn0gaMFRYlQnMM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22029473/akrales_201110_4271_0041.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The top cover is “sandblasted aluminum.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="7sLAQl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9842835"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qVIFJF"&gt;The strength of such a large chassis, though, is that there’s room for a useful port selection. In total, we have one USB 3.1 Type-C Gen 1, two USB 3.1 Gen 1, one USB 2.0, one HDMI 2.0, and one Ethernet, as well as a power port. That’s comprehensive, though you’ll need to look elsewhere if you’re seeking Thunderbolt support, a typical omission in this price range. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3twJ28"&gt;The display is a bit of a dud on paper. I measured it as covering just 66 percent of the sRGB gamut and 50 percent of AdobeRGB. It also maxes out at 220 nits of brightness. Those are both mediocre as laptop screens go, though they’re not terrible for the category; color-wise, the Aspire actually scored slightly better than the IPS panel on the Swift 3, as well as the &lt;a href="https://www.laptopmag.com/reviews/asus-vivobook-15-2020"&gt;Asus VivoBook 15&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Acer Aspire 5 half open from the right side." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4vQWpDe4u7P0xfiAIwUik_aXSW0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22029472/akrales_201110_4271_0056.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;3.97 pounds, 0.71 inches thick&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="ZgGzGz"&gt;The viewing experience wasn’t as bad as those metrics might indicate. The matte panel did a good job of reducing glare; even around 90 percent brightness, I could use the machine outdoors without a hassle. And while Netflix and YouTube looked drab next to more expensive screens, media consumption is still very doable. (Especially because the audio is quite good. It has a nice surround quality and can easily fill a room — I’d put it on par with a decent external speaker. I could actually hear the bass and percussion in my music.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1oxu5N"&gt;The Aspire has a nice keyboard. It’s backlit and quiet with decent travel. (It’s mushier than it is clicky, if you have strong feelings about that.) There’s a numpad on the right side, which is a nice feature, but it does push the touchpad to the left. This was irksome for me as someone with small hands. The area that was natural for me to touch with my right hand was the right-click area. I had to intentionally stretch over to left-click, and I never really got used to it — even after a week and a half, I was still accidentally right-clicking all the time. There’s also an embedded fingerprint reader in the top-left corner of the touchpad, but its location wasn’t super convenient for me as a righty and I never ended up using it much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="dmWAwd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9844998"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="APDpTy"&gt;Of course, performance is what really makes or breaks a budget laptop. The base Aspire 5 configuration, listed at &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.acer.com%2Fac%2Fen%2FUS%2Fcontent%2Fmodel%2FNX.HSMAA.001&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21815008%2Facer-aspire-5-review-2020-15-inch-laptop-specs-features-price#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$399.99&lt;/a&gt; on Acer’s website, can come with a Core i3-1005G1 or an &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.acer.com%2Fac%2Fen%2FUS%2Fcontent%2Fmodel%2FNX.A6KAA.001&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21815008%2Facer-aspire-5-review-2020-15-inch-laptop-specs-features-price#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AMD Ryzen 3 4300U&lt;/a&gt; (both with 4GB of RAM and a 128GB SSD). There are &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.acer.com%2Fac%2Fen%2FUS%2Fcontent%2Fmodels%2Flaptops%2Faspire5&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21815008%2Facer-aspire-5-review-2020-15-inch-laptop-specs-features-price#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a number of models&lt;/a&gt; at different price points, including some with &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fcharcoal-black-acer-a515-55t-5887%2Fp%2FN82E16834316934%3Fnm_mc%3Dotc-hatch%26cm_mmc%3Dotc-hatch-_-notebooks-_-acer%2Bamerica-_-34316934&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21815008%2Facer-aspire-5-review-2020-15-inch-laptop-specs-features-price#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;touchscreens&lt;/a&gt;. The system we’re looking at is listed at $549.99 on &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Acer-A515-55-56VK-i5-1035G1-Fingerprint-Keyboard/dp/B087RTV311?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and has Intel’s four-core Core i5-1035G1, 8GB of RAM, and 256GB of SSD storage. A system with the same specs and a six-core Ryzen 5 4500U is currently listed on &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.acer.com%2Fac%2Fen%2FUS%2Fcontent%2Fmodel%2FNX.HW4AA.003&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21815008%2Facer-aspire-5-review-2020-15-inch-laptop-specs-features-price#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Acer’s website&lt;/a&gt; for the same price (though it’s hard to find and looks to be sold out on &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Acer-A515-44-R41B-Hexa-Core-Processor-Graphics/dp/B087N4ZRXV?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; as of this writing). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Acer Aspire 5 half open from above." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GGWqRKvtJtawLW5MJxh_40C8xoQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22029474/akrales_201110_4271_0033.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The touchpad supports Microsoft Precision gestures.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7tOImo"&gt;It’s important to caveat here that I haven’t tried the AMD system yet — but the six-core 4500U is an impressive chip. In the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21319378/hp-envy-x360-2020-amd-review-price-specs-features"&gt;$799 HP Envy x360 13&lt;/a&gt; (which also has 8GB of RAM), it easily delivered the fantastic performance I’d expect from a Core i7, and it could even run &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; on its High settings at over 60fps. Make no mistake: the Intel Aspire 5 didn’t give me any problems during my various office work, social media, emailing, and the like. But performance wasn’t quite as zippy as it was on the AMD Envy. And I got the sense that the thing was chugging — I could almost always hear the fans spinning, even when I was just running a few Chrome tabs. I wouldn’t have wanted to try anything more intense (and unlike Intel’s new Iris Plus graphics, its UHD graphics aren’t a good choice for anything but the lightest gaming). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7j17Vb"&gt;That’s before we even talk about the battery life. This Aspire 5 averaged four hours and 49 minutes of my daily workload (12-15 Chrome tabs, Slack, Spotify streaming, and occasional Zoom calls on the Battery Saver profile at 200 nits of brightness). That’s not good, and it’s especially not enough for students who are out and about all day. AMD processors, by contrast, have been killing it on battery: the 4500U-powered Envy could churn out eight hours of my typical workload while the Swift 3 with a Ryzen 7 4700U got up to seven hours, and the 4800U-powered &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21423498/lenovo-ideapad-slim-7-2020-amd-review"&gt;IdeaPad Slim 7&lt;/a&gt; achieved a monstrous 13 and a half hours. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2XcFBL"&gt;Final note: there’s some bloatware. I got some annoying Norton pop-ups and occasional notifications from various other programs that came loaded onto the Aspire. These aren’t the end of the world at this price point, but note that you may have to take some time to uninstall if the alerts are bothering you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Acer Aspire 5 open from the front." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pO4D8o8uOcrjYm9Gei-840mU10o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22029470/akrales_201110_4271_0078.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Aspire 5 comes with an installation kit that you can use to add a hard-disk drive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="hPTsd7"&gt;So, look, the Aspire 5 gets the job done. It works. It does what you need it to (at least until the battery runs out). There are even a couple areas where it’s punching above its weight class — the audio is great, and it’s nice to have a fingerprint reader. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="HKsiCs"&gt;But if you can get all those benefits plus a six-core AMD processor for the same (or a comparable) price, I see no reason not to go that route instead if you’re wed to the 15-inch system. AMD systems are hard to find, but I recommend digging around or waiting until one becomes available. And if you’re willing to spend a bit more for the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Acer-Hexa-Core-Processor-Fingerprint-SF314-42-R7LH/dp/B087772M7L?tag=52402_iceleadscom-20&amp;amp;ascsubtag=s1606861034141l7d4a52402" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ryzen-powered Swift 3&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll see a noticeable difference in build quality and portability as well as multiple extra hours of battery life. For students and on-the-go workers, I think that’s more than worth the cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Acer Aspire 5, closed, from the left side." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9aXvrub5T-VfsHM0S7Gm76UCwXU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22029471/akrales_201110_4271_0065.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You get what you pay for (but other models can give you more).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mdpmLq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aPXNo6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21815008/acer-aspire-5-review-2020-15-inch-laptop-specs-features-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21815008/acer-aspire-5-review-2020-15-inch-laptop-specs-features-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-02T10:13:48-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-02T10:13:48-05:00</updated>
    <title>Go read this report about EPA failures in air quality monitoring</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A distant landscape photo of an oil refinery along a river on a cloudy day." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M88MCQeGrwWoYamFVLZI7AWAYew=/0x1:5771x3848/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68348962/1151690283.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The Philadelphia Energy Solutions refinery after a massive fire in 2019. | Image: Xinhua/Liu Jie via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kk5Rvq"&gt;Key pieces of environmental monitoring equipment in the US often fail to provide accurate air quality measurements, even when toxic clouds are spewing out of an exploded oil refinery, according to &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/usa-pollution-airmonitors-specialreport/u-s-air-monitors-routinely-miss-pollution-even-refinery-explosions-idUSKBN28B4RT"&gt;a jaw-dropping new report from &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IBbPHQ"&gt;“The government network of 3,900 monitoring devices nationwide has routinely missed major toxic releases and day-to-day pollution dangers,” the report says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jDwD8E"&gt;Air monitors are essential tools for determining the air quality of a particular area. An accurate air quality index (AQI) is important: hazardous particulates in the air can cause or worsen serious heart and lung problems. The article highlights myriad problems with the Environmental Protection Agency’s air quality monitoring system, using data from both the EPA and independent monitoring organizations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3zku8d"&gt;One of the most egregious examples happened in 2019, when a refinery explosion released nearly 700,000 pounds of hazardous chemicals into the air in south Philadelphia. The monitors for the area reported that day’s air quality as one of the cleanest of the year. This discrepancy is due to the fact that the nearest air monitor was programmed to only run once every six days, meaning it completely missed the explosion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NXdRSX"&gt;Even air monitors that are operating every day of the week can be inaccurate for other reasons, &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; found, including caps on the levels they’ll record. A monitor for Imperial County, California recorded nothing above a certain number of particulates, when in reality the levels in the air were more than twice that amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hCk5eg"&gt;There also just aren’t that many EPA monitors in the country, meaning it’s impossible to get a truly accurate picture of the quality of the air around us.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;AQI can be drastically different &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/25/21303326/data-air-pollution-mapped-google-street-view-aclima"&gt;from one block to the next&lt;/a&gt;, granular changes that are often overlooked in the big picture. The EPA has even redrawn maps of specific areas, essentially gerrymandering the air to ensure industrial sites can be built in areas that already have high levels of pollution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UgpVQa"&gt;Where the official EPA monitors have fallen short,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;community-led air monitoring programs have stepped up. Citizen scientists are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21440343/air-quality-sensors-wildfire-smoke-pollution-climate-change"&gt;using their own monitors&lt;/a&gt; to track AQI and put pressure on local governments to regulate air quality. In Imperial County, environmental officials adjusted the cap on their air monitors after community monitors showed the severity of the true pollution levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="haG3kv"&gt;To fully grasp the troubling inconsistencies in AQI recording, read &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/usa-pollution-airmonitors-specialreport/u-s-air-monitors-routinely-miss-pollution-even-refinery-explosions-idUSKBN28B4RT"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;’ full report here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/21833693/air-quality-index-monitoring-epa-pollution-health-reuters"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/21833693/air-quality-index-monitoring-epa-pollution-health-reuters</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kait Sanchez</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-02T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-02T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Qualcomm’s new Snapdragon 888 promises faster speeds, better cameras, and more powerful AI</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6a14hgx76gzOvv3hgM8fBuQEU0o=/0x0:9504x6336/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68344585/Snapdragon_888_Reference_Design.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Z9hSKi"&gt;Qualcomm teased the Snapdragon 888, its latest 5G-equipped flagship smartphone processor, on the first day of its Snapdragon Tech Summit. But at the day two keynote, the company provided all of the details on the new chipset, which will be the brains powering almost every major 2021 Android flagship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y9KveO"&gt;First off, the basic specs: the new processor will feature Qualcomm’s new Kryo 680 CPU, which will be one of the first devices to feature &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/5/26/21267893/arm-cortex-a78-mali-g78-cpu-gpu-designs-smartphones-2021-samsung-qualcomm-apple"&gt;Arm’s latest customized Cortex-X1 core&lt;/a&gt; and promises up to 25 percent higher performance than last year’s chip with a maximum clock speed of 2.84GHz. And the company’s new Adreno 660 GPU promises a 35 percent jump on graphics rendering, in what it says is the biggest performance leap for its GPUs yet. The new CPU and GPU are also more power-efficient compared to those on the Snapdragon 875, with a 25 percent improvement for the Kyro 680 and a 20 percent improvement on the Adreno 660.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="LIPU5J"&gt;&lt;q&gt;25 percent faster CPU and the biggest GPU performance jump yet for Qualcomm&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vYhpfn"&gt;Another key difference between the Snapdragon 888 and last year’s 865 is that Qualcomm has finally integrated its 5G modem directly into the SoC. That means manufacturers won’t have to deal with finding the space (and power) for a second external modem. Specifically, the Snapdragon 888 will feature &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/19/21142381/qualcomm-x60-modem-5g-phones-faster-power-efficient-5nm-carrier"&gt;Qualcomm’s 5nm X60 modem&lt;/a&gt;, which the company announced back in February, and it will enable better carrier aggregation and download speeds up to 7.5 Gbps on new devices. The Snapdragon 888 will also support Wi-Fi 6 as well as the new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/23/21231623/6ghz-wifi-6e-explained-speed-availability-fcc-approval"&gt;6GHz Wi-Fi 6E standard&lt;/a&gt;, which should boost that rollout by making it the default on most Android flagships. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LdtnwNqp5q7047kNwkKFGZ0I_VY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22137067/Snapdragon_888_Mockup.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="OTWpU2"&gt;As is tradition for a Snapdragon update, Qualcomm is also putting a big emphasis on its camera improvements. The new Spectra 580 ISP is the first from Qualcomm to feature a triple ISP, allowing it to do things like capture three simultaneous 4K HDR video streams or three 28-megapixel photos at once at up to 2.7 gigapixels per second (35 percent faster than last year). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="SViRM7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Capture three simultaneous 4K HDR video streams at once&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="G0tDND"&gt;It also offers improved burst capabilities and is capable of capturing up to 120 photos in a single second at a 10-megapixel resolution. Lastly, the upgraded ISP adds computational HDR to 4K videos, an improved low-light capture architecture, and the option to shoot photos in 10-bit color in HEIF. That said, it’ll be up to phone manufacturers to build cameras that can take advantage of the new features. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lsXwcb"&gt;The final major changes come in AI performance, thanks to Qualcomm’s new Hexagon 780 AI processor. The Snapdragon 888 features Qualcomm’s sixth-generation AI Engine, which it promises will help improve everything from computational photography to gaming to voice assistant performance. The Snapdragon 888 can perform 26 trillion operations per second (TOPS), compared to 15 TOPS on the Snapdragon 865, while delivering three times better power efficiency. Additionally, Qualcomm is promising big improvements in both scalar and tensor AI tasks as part of those upgrades. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M4m24b"&gt;The Snapdragon 888 also features the second-generation Qualcomm Sensing Hub, a dedicated low-power AI processor for smaller hardware-based tasks, like identifying when you raise your phone to light up the display. The new second-gen Sensing Hub is dramatically improved, which means the phone will be able to rely less on the main Hexagon processor for those tasks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T9agPT"&gt;All of this adds up to a substantial boost in Qualcomm’s — and therefore, nearly every Android flagship’s — capabilities for what our smartphones will be able to do. The first Snapdragon 888 smartphones are expected to show up in early 2021, which means it won’t be long before we’ll be able to try out the next generation of Android flagships for ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/21672519/qualcomm-snapdragon-888-cpu-gpu-details-performance-ai-isp-photography-specs-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/21672519/qualcomm-snapdragon-888-cpu-gpu-details-performance-ai-isp-photography-specs-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-02T09:58:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-02T09:58:37-05:00</updated>
    <title>You can get Super Mario Odyssey for free when you buy a Switch Pro controller</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QEymqFc87va0KlcMU1RcjCLNT_g=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68344142/jbareham_170221_1475_0010.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0MvlTM"&gt;Just when you thought retailers had put up their best deals for Black Friday and Cyber Monday, Walmart comes in with this excellent Switch Pro controller bundle. &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FNintendo-Switch-Pro-Controller-with-Super-Mario-Odyssey-Full-Game-Download-Code%2F925436036&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Priced at $70&lt;/a&gt; (the regular price for this controller), you’ll get a free download code for &lt;em&gt;Super Mario Odyssey&lt;/em&gt; for the Nintendo Switch with purchase. That $60 game has so far avoided any big price cuts this holiday season, so it’s great to see it included here. If you’re gifting a Nintendo Switch for the holidays, this seems like the perfect pairing (&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0887P21Z2/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;just don’t forget a microSD card&lt;/a&gt; to expand the console’s paltry 32GB of storage).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vM7SxK"&gt;The Switch Pro is usually a bit of a bitter pill to swallow given the price, but if you don’t have the game, this deal registers as an instant buy for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="VjCBTb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10057685"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1UmcFQ"&gt;Best Buy is offering the lowest price that I’ve seen on the Beats Powerbeats Pro wireless earbuds today. Normally $250, they reached $160 at one point during Black Friday. &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1725415497762193875" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;But right now, the lava red color, which looks pretty great, is $150&lt;/a&gt;. These are a good option if you work out a lot and want earphones that will stay put in your ears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WhcPDG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10058925"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OKkut2"&gt;The rarely discounted and sometimes difficult-to-find SteelSeries Arctis Pro Wireless gaming headset for PC, PS4, and PS5 is within $10 of its best price at Amazon. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B079YBKT3H/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;You can pick one up in black for $240&lt;/a&gt; (normally $330). That’s obviously still a lot of money (much more than many other great gaming headsets cost), but if you’ve had your eye out for this model, now seems like a good time to think about picking one up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="BWp56J"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10062316"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2020/12/2/22016568/nintendo-switch-pro-controller-super-mario-odyssey-steelseries-arctis-pro-wireless-headset-amazon"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2020/12/2/22016568/nintendo-switch-pro-controller-super-mario-odyssey-steelseries-arctis-pro-wireless-headset-amazon</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
