<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-06-20T13:07:19-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-20T13:07:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-20T13:07:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>FCC updates how some emergency alerts will look on phones</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_2mQ3GKF0B_0fH5PD4D7xQ5M_Zc=/0x0:525x350/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69478483/wea_test_graphic_phone_only_081018.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: FEMA&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Yi4lRU"&gt;The Federal Communications Commission (FCC) said it has combined two categories of text message alerts into one: the “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/3/17931750/fema-presidential-alert-test-reminder-trump-public-alert-warning-system"&gt;Presidential Alerts&lt;/a&gt;” and alerts from the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA). The two will now be in a  new “National Alerts” category,  active on all devices that receive Wireless Emergency Alerts (WEA). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AdpkBY"&gt;The goal of the alerts is to warn the public of natural disasters and other crisis situations, “and are of ever-increasing importance given the emergencies and disasters Americans have faced in recent years,” the FCC said in a &lt;a href="https://docs.fcc.gov/public/attachments/DOC-373365A1.pdf"&gt;news release (pdf)&lt;/a&gt;. The false alert in Hawaii in 2018, where residents were &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/13/16888390/hawaii-missile-emergency-alert-false-alarm"&gt;warned of an imminent ballistic missile threat that wasn’t real&lt;/a&gt;, highlighted the need for improvements to its alert system, the agency said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dn0kUG"&gt;The new rules provide states with a checklist of information for their own Emergency Alert Systems, and encourages states to form committees to help administer alerts on the state level. Under the new rules, government agencies can now report false emergency alerts to the FCC’s 24/7 Operations Center, and gives guidance on how alert originators can repeat an alert transmission. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="41HbpQ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hstoday.us/subject-matter-areas/emergency-preparedness/fema-and-fcc-plan-nationwide-emergency-alert-test-for-aug-11/"&gt;Later this summer&lt;/a&gt;, FEMA and the FCC will conduct a nationwide test of the wireless alerts and the Emergency Alert System (EAS) that sends alerts to radios and televisions. Both tests are scheduled for 2:20PM ET on August 11th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xVQyb4"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qjMQT4"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/20/22542541/fcc-updates-emergency-alerts-phones-fema"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/20/22542541/fcc-updates-emergency-alerts-phones-fema</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-20T12:00:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-20T12:00:52-04:00</updated>
    <title>Airspeeder says it had the first successful test flight for its electric flying racecar</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oij4YByFd3gQTCPU7n40utvGicE=/0x0:1346x897/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69478341/airspeeder.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://airspeeder.com/news/worlds-first-flying-racing-car-makes-historic-flight#2" target="_blank"&gt;Airspeeder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="speakable-summary"&gt;Airspeeder says its electric “flying” race car, the Alauda Mk3, has had its first unpiloted test flights in southern Australia. The craft, an electric vertical takeoff multicopter (abbreviated eVTOL for &lt;strong&gt;e&lt;/strong&gt;lectric &lt;strong&gt;v&lt;/strong&gt;ertical &lt;strong&gt;t&lt;/strong&gt;ake &lt;strong&gt;o&lt;/strong&gt;ff and &lt;strong&gt;l&lt;/strong&gt;anding) was remotely controlled and the test flights took place under the supervision of Australia’s Civil Aviation Safety Authority. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BdaKPp"&gt;The ultimate goal for Airspeeder and Alauda Aeronautics (the former is the racing series, the latter is the manufacturer), both founded by entrepreneur Matthew Pearson, has been to build flying vehicles for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/11/16761748/alauda-flying-car-race-australia"&gt;purpose of racing them&lt;/a&gt;, which the companies say is the next step. According to Airspeeder’s website, the “successful execution of these flights means that uncrewed electric flying car Grand Prixs will take place in 2021 at three soon-to-be-revealed international locations.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="t0AEv6"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aq6JDIL12Xg?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="psy1NZ"&gt;According to&lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22670224/WORLD_S_FIRST_FLYING_RACING_CAR_MAKES_HISTORIC_FIRST_FLIGHTS_.pdf"&gt; Airspeeder&lt;/a&gt; (pdf), the unpiloted Mk3 weighs 130 kilograms (about 286 pounds), can go from zero to 62 mph in 2.8 seconds, and climb to 500 meters. It has a removable battery, which its pit crews have been able to replace in under 20 seconds. It can fly for 10 to 15 minutes on one battery pack, the company says, and it’s equipped with lidar and radar to create a “virtual forcefield” to help prevent collisions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oRnSB7"&gt;Airspeeder says its initial EXA Series races, which it’s planning for later this year, will include up to four teams with two remote pilots per team.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/20/22542459/airspeeder-alauda-evtol-flying-car-race"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/20/22542459/airspeeder-alauda-evtol-flying-car-race</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-20T09:13:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-20T09:13:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>PSA: If you enrolled in an energy saver program, your smart thermostat may adjust itself</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6Hg9JNt-JdMuQ31ww61smMIsNFA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69472181/dseifert_201115_4301_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nest Thermostat&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VW5PrM"&gt;Texas’ energy grid, which &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/texas-freeze-power-grid-failure-electricity-market-incentives-11613777856"&gt;failed spectacularly over the winter&lt;/a&gt; during a stretch of historically cold weather, will be put to the test again this weekend, as temperatures across much of the state are forecast to be in the upper 90s. Despite &lt;a href="https://www.houstonchronicle.com/politics/texas/article/AbbottFailedTexas-ERCOT-heat-Texas-electricity-16249076.php"&gt;assurances from Gov. Greg Abbott&lt;/a&gt; that “everything that needed to be done was done to fix the power grid in Texas,” earlier this week the Electric Reliability Council of Texas (ERCOT) &lt;a href="https://www.houstonchronicle.com/business/energy/article/ERCOT-issues-intermittent-conservation-alerts-16246788.php"&gt;urged customers to adjust thermostats&lt;/a&gt; to 78 degrees or higher and cut back on electricity use for several days. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q1FUqG"&gt;Texas residents with smart thermostats are &lt;a href="https://enrollmythermostat.com/faqs/texas-faq/"&gt;eligible for a number of programs&lt;/a&gt;, sweepstakes, and discounts which effectively allow energy providers to adjust their thermostats remotely during periods of high energy demand. Known as demand-response programs, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/spavis/status/1405872205091704833?s=21"&gt;some Texans were taken by surprise&lt;/a&gt; this week, as their thermostats were turned up without any action from them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="UKAd4j"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;texans with smart thermostats have lost the ability to control the temperature in their own homes!   their smart thermostats are being controlled by their utility company and fixed at very high levels (&amp;gt;80 °F) which could be dangerous if those homes have elderly people &lt;a href="https://t.co/qZvG3OnJQu"&gt;pic.twitter.com/qZvG3OnJQu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Sarah Pavis (@spavis) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/spavis/status/1405872205091704833?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 18, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2MF4FF"&gt;But that’s the way these seasonal programs, typically offered via utility companies across the country, are intended to work. Nest owners can also &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/google-nest/seasonal-savings-nest-thermostat/"&gt;opt-in to programs directly via Google&lt;/a&gt;, Nest’s parent company, even if their local utility isn’t participating in such a program. Raising or lowering thermostats by a few degrees, can, in theory, reduce the strain on the energy grid and prevent the need for rolling blackouts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lm5oeJ"&gt;According to a Google spokesperson, what’s happened in Texas “is related to energy programs managed by local utilities that are working as intended. These programs are not exclusive to Nest Thermostats, and users must opt in to these programs through their utility provider. Users can also opt out any time.” The spokesperson added that if an enrolled customer wants to manually adjust the temperature during a so-called &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/googlenest/answer/9232355/sign-up-for-rush-hour-rewards-or-stop-participating-in-an-event-android?hl=en"&gt;Rush Hour Rewards event&lt;/a&gt;, they should be able to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sm5cjM"&gt;A spokesperson for Honeywell, which also makes smart thermostats, also said customers enrolled in an energy savings program that allows for their thermostats to be adjusted remotely can override the change using the thermostat or the corresponding app. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WhILsP"&gt;We reached out to electric companies in Texas to try to get more details on what was happening. A spokesperson for TXU Energy in Dallas said the company “did not activate our demand response program this week.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9hNgd9"&gt;Alejandra Diaz of CenterPoint Energy, which is based in Houston and has more than 2 million residential customers (according to &lt;a href="https://www.centerpointenergy.com/en-us/corporate/about-us/company-overview/fast-facts"&gt;its website&lt;/a&gt;) wrote in a response to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that on June 16th the company “conducted a test curtailment event from 2 p.m. to 5 p.m.,” and that such tests occur twice a year. The utility issued a notification to a company called EnergyHub, “to initiate energy curtailment for their residential customers who have agreed to participate in the program.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V1mRQZ"&gt;Then, according to CenterPoint, “EnergyHub adjusted the thermostat setpoint” for enrolled customers and the test concluded by 5PM local time. &lt;a href="https://www.accuweather.com/en/us/houston/77002/june-weather/351197"&gt;According to AccuWeather&lt;/a&gt;, the high temperature in Houston on June 16th was 90 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hJ0SVB"&gt;Many Texas electricity customers are enrolled in a program called “Smart Savers Texas,” which is overseen by EnergyHub, which operates the demand response program on behalf of Texas utility companies. The terms of the program, according to EnergyHub’s FAQ:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="neGdeH"&gt;By participating in the Program, you agree to allow EnergyHub, Inc. and your thermostat provider to remotely access your thermostat to make brief, limited adjustments to your thermostat temperature setting at times of peak electricity demand in the summer. You may benefit by seeing a reduced electricity bill. You can opt out of these temperature adjustments at any time&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="8e6ADA"&gt;It’s likely that many people enrolled in this program were not aware of these terms; it’s well-established that many people don’t read the fine print on such agreements. &lt;a href="https://www.khou.com/article/news/local/texas/remote-thermostat-adjustment-texas-energy-shortage/285-5acf2bc5-54b7-4160-bffe-1f9a5ef4362a"&gt;And according to news station KHOU&lt;/a&gt;, some customers enrolled in the Smart Savers program in exchange for a sweepstakes entry, which makes it seem even less likely that people knew their thermostats could be adjusted remotely. Some companies offer discounts or rebates on smart thermostat purchases, or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/4/22/4253594/nest-adds-extra-features-and-rebate-in-power-company-partnerships"&gt;discounts on their electric bills&lt;/a&gt;; but the conditions aren’t always clear, and sometimes involve a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dellcam/status/1406355868355022856"&gt;lengthy list&lt;/a&gt; of terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NgmddP"&gt;The thermostat companies claim that their devices can be adjusted manually even after they’ve been adjusted remotely, but reports across social media reports suggest this wasn’t the case for many customers in Texas the past few days. At the very least, making people’s homes hotter during a major heat wave event — whether it’s because of a device not functioning as intended, or an energy program that might save a few pennies— seems like a bad idea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="erpqPP"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: June 20th 9:12AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added more detail about energy savings programs and comments from company spokespersons&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/18/22540015/psa-energy-saver-program-smart-thermostat-adjust-temperature-heat"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/18/22540015/psa-energy-saver-program-smart-thermostat-adjust-temperature-heat</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-20T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-20T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Motorola Moto G Stylus 5G is a good phone with a too-short shelf life</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;For $399, it doesn’t do enough to stand apart from the less expensive 4G-only version&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="8RBjOF"&gt;The Motorola Moto G Stylus 5G, as you may have pieced together, is a phone with a built-in stylus and 5G. It’s a slightly upgraded version of the 4G-only, 2021-edition Moto G Stylus (I’m sorry, that’s really how these phones are named).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a3xsw4"&gt;The Stylus 5G includes a few more hardware upgrades in addition to 5G connectivity, including a bigger battery, more storage and RAM (256GB and 6GB on the version I tested, respectively), and a newer Snapdragon 480 processor. There’s a new stylus-friendly GIF creator mode, which is fun. Fun is good! But it more or less feels like the same phone: the rear camera array is identical with the exception of a different macro sensor, its 6.8-inch screen is the same, and overall dimensions are similar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2I5Inz"&gt;This puts the G Stylus 5G in a kind of awkward spot. At $399, it sits between the $279 G Stylus and the $1,000 Galaxy Note 20 (the next step up if you want a stylus with your phone), but it doesn’t go far enough to clearly offer more than the budget-friendlier version. Performance and battery life are a bit better, but these aren’t really weak spots for the 4G version. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="E8esrM"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10611736"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UwjuEC"&gt;Having 5G is nice, too, but the value is diminished when you consider that the G Stylus 5G is only guaranteed two years of security updates. That’s about when 5G in the US will start getting good, so most of us can get away with a 4G device for the next couple of years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sa4Oq8"&gt;It all adds up to a good phone without a compelling case to recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8hI0xGclHIrjtsqT6cIuvbWOVKQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22668420/DSC00884.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The phone’s 1080p LCD panel lacks the nice contrast of an OLED.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SCCNLW"&gt;Moto G Stylus 5G screen and performance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="G42hlE"&gt;The G Stylus 5G is a big phone — big with a capital B. Its 6.8-inch display is about as large as they come, at least until all of our phones start folding and expanding into weird little Transformer-style tablets. It’s a 1080p LCD panel that’s just fine — lacking the nice contrast of OLEDs but still usable in bright daylight conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x6EiVo"&gt;Battery life is very good, thanks to a large 5,000mAh cell. Using it on Wi-Fi I’ve gotten four hours of screen-on time out of it and it’s only down to 36 percent. You could certainly get two days’ worth of use out of it — including relatively heavy use on cellular data — and even a full day of very demanding use seems reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="OQBitH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;For $400, you really should get more than a couple of years of support for your device&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GRDdsH"&gt;Performance is good, too; jumping between apps is quick and smooth, and heavier tasks like zooming in and out of Google Maps shows only a bit of stuttering. There’s minimal but noticeable shutter lag in the camera app, which feels like a problem this phone shouldn’t have, but not enough to ruin anyone’s day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9bCsgx"&gt;The G Stylus 5G ships with Android 11 and will only be supported with one major OS platform update and two years of security updates. That’s an unfortunately short lifespan, especially considering that Samsung’s Galaxy A-series phones are now guaranteed four years of security updates. For $400, you really should get more than a couple of years of support for your device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TC96mMxTbWcSHzpUnUOfN5jRZFY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22665397/cat_dot_jay_peg.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The phone’s stylus features are basic but make it easier to do things like add handwriting to an Instagram story post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BpeVmv"&gt;A couple of side notes on the Stylus 5G’s 5G connectivity: at launch it will work on Verizon and T-Mobile’s 5G networks but will operate as 4G-only on AT&amp;amp;T. Motorola says AT&amp;amp;T 5G support will be available “in the coming months.” It’s not compatible with any of the networks’ mmWave 5G (the super fast, hard-to-find variety), but that’s not a big loss. More importantly, it &lt;em&gt;will &lt;/em&gt;work with the C-band 5G frequencies Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T will start using at the end of the year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ieQogj"&gt;The Stylus 5G’s stylus features are basic but adequate. The capacitive stylus is spring-loaded into the phone’s lower right corner and automatically brings up a quick menu of options when you remove it. If you’re on the lock screen, you can jot down a note without having to unlock the device, which is handy. You won’t find productivity features or neat tricks like wireless control a la the Note series, but rather some handy shortcuts to grab a GIF or doodle on a screenshot. They’re useful and fair for the price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GcjxHvfsnOaYN8CnqzG1DW4Fqt4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22668421/DSC00854.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are standard wide, ultrawide, macro, and depth cameras on the Stylus 5G’s rear panel.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Rmh1q3"&gt;Moto G Stylus 5G camera&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="tYNxtw"&gt;The Stylus 5G offers three rear cameras — a 48-megapixel f/1.7 standard wide, 8-megapixel f/2.2 ultrawide, and a 5-megapixel macro — along with a 2-megapixel depth sensor and 16-megapixel selfie camera. The 4G G Stylus has a 2-megapixel macro camera, but that’s the only difference between them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dNVTnE"&gt;Much like the 4G version, the Stylus 5G takes good photos in abundant light with a surprising level of detail, thanks to the way it processes 48-megapixel images into 12-megapixel files. The ultrawide camera is nice to have, though its images can be a little noisier in challenging lighting conditions, and the macro camera is still underwhelming, despite the modest resolution boost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="oQhLW0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10611787"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="1KAPDa"&gt;The main camera is prone to some drastic color shifts with even slightly different compositions of the same scene and subject — in one shot my orange cat is orange, and in the next one taken at a slightly different position, he suddenly looks blue. This happens more frequently in mixed lighting conditions, which many cameras will struggle with, but it popped up just often enough in my testing to annoy me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/genvJDVaBrf66KgQdM0ipRAmHI8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22668423/DSC00841.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Moto G Stylus 5G doesn’t quite do enough to stand out.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="KNeY5b"&gt;The 4G-only G Stylus is a good deal for $279, and there’s nothing really wrong with the $399 G Stylus 5G, but it’s harder to justify its higher cost. With only a couple of years of security updates guaranteed, this phone will only see the beginning of truly good 5G in the US. It’s a nice step-up option if you’re inclined toward a stylus phone and the Note isn’t in your budget, but for most people, I’d recommend either sticking with the 4G-only model for a couple of years or looking into a 5G phone with a little more longevity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="sh9bnJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Stylus enthusiasts on a budget have a good option in the Moto G Stylus 5G&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2CluFg"&gt;If you’re more interested in the big screen and battery than the stylus, you could save quite a bit and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22268805/motorola-moto-g-power-2021-review"&gt;go with the Moto G Power (2021)&lt;/a&gt;. Its processor isn’t as good and you miss out on the ultrawide camera, but if you want to cover the basics for a couple of years, it will do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZPBRnt"&gt;On the other hand, if you can afford to spend a little more and you do want to get more than a few years out of your phone, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22399456/samsung-galaxy-a52-5g-review-camera-screen-specs-price"&gt;Samsung Galaxy A52 5G is a great pick&lt;/a&gt;. It has a big, lovely screen, 5G, and comes with a generous support policy. Stylus enthusiasts on a budget have a good option in the Moto G Stylus 5G, but most others could do better elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xFoQr1"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="tEe3CX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10611746"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22538663/motorola-moto-g-stylus-5g-review-specs-screen-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22538663/motorola-moto-g-stylus-5g-review-specs-screen-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-19T15:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-19T15:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facial recognition software used to verify unemployment recipients reportedly doesn’t work well</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4bwyt4x6JP1uBqJPnxa9BZG2rmM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69476410/acastro_180730_1777_facial_recognition_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kkg1l6"&gt;The facial recognition program used by some two dozen US states to to verify people seeking unemployment benefits is working inconsistently, leading to many people being denied benefits or having their applications put on hold, &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/5dbywn/facial-recognition-failures-are-locking-people-out-of-unemployment-systems"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bbeLCb"&gt;The identity verification service ID.me is intended to help reduce unemployment fraud, and uses biometric data and official documents to verify people. But according to &lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt;, some who have applied for unemployment have reported that ID.me has &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=(to%3Aidme)&amp;amp;src=typed_query&amp;amp;f=live"&gt;failed to identify them&lt;/a&gt; correctly, and that they have had difficulty reaching someone at ID.me to remedy the problem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ipu6K7"&gt;In a lengthy email response to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, ID.me CEO Blake Hall said the company uses “1:1 Face Matching to match the selfie image to the photo on the government ID. This is similar to how Apple uses FaceID to unlock phones and analogous to how a TSA agent would compare your face to your photo ID at an airport.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gog1gg"&gt;He added that the algorithms the company uses for Face Match “operate at ~99.9% efficacy.” Hall also said the company was not aware of “eligible individuals” who couldn’t verity their identity with its software, and that wait times for a video chat with a company representative “has been consistently under 30 minutes all week.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ltIF1s"&gt;With millions of people unemployed due to the coronavirus pandemic, state offices have dealt with a surge of claims over the past year. Some states reported a &lt;a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/business/economy/washington-halts-unemployment-payments-for-two-days-after-finding-1-6-million-in-fraudulent-claims-amid-coronavirus-pandemic/"&gt;sharp rise in fraudulent claims&lt;/a&gt; last spring, and the Department of Labor &lt;a href="https://www.oig.dol.gov/public/reports/oa/viewpdf.php?r=19-21-002-03-315&amp;amp;y=2021"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; (.pdf) in February that between March and October of last year it had identified more than $5 billion of potentially fraudulent unemployment payments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HBLrOL"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update June 20th 9:24AM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Added comment from ID.me CEO&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/19/22541427/facial-recognition-software-verify-unemployment-benefits-id-me"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/19/22541427/facial-recognition-software-verify-unemployment-benefits-id-me</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-19T10:47:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-19T10:47:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook to update its community standards to clarify what it considers satire</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KLqqKk1CBPUcd05hbDLZZOWJoAo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69475706/acastro_180319_1777_facebook_data_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SQvU4x"&gt;Following a recommendation from its Oversight Board, Facebook says it will update its community standards to be clearer about how it handles satirical content, the company said in &lt;a href="https://transparency.fb.com/oversight/oversight-board-cases/comment-related-to-armenian-people-and-the-armenian-genocide/"&gt;a blog post&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nOfpPR"&gt;“We’ll add information to the Community Standards that makes it clear where we consider satire as part of our assessment of context-specific decisions,” according to the post.  “This change will allow teams to consider satire when assessing potential Hate Speech violations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cjsmOa"&gt;The update comes after the &lt;a href="https://oversightboard.com/news/288225579415246-announcing-the-board-s-next-cases-and-changes-to-our-bylaws/"&gt;Oversight Board determined&lt;/a&gt; that Facebook was wrong to remove a user’s comment with a reference to the Turkish government, based on the &lt;a href="https://memerino.me/two-buttons"&gt;two buttons meme&lt;/a&gt;. The Oversight Board described it: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="aUqNoi"&gt;This meme featured the same split-screen cartoon from the original meme, but with the cartoon character’s face substituted for a Turkish flag. The cartoon character has their right hand on their head and appears to be sweating. Above the cartoon character, in the other half of the split-screen, there are two red buttons with corresponding labels, in English: “The Armenian Genocide is a lie” and “The Armenians were terrorists who deserved it.” The meme was preceded and followed by “thinking face” emoji.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="pjk1Bh"&gt;Facebook removed the post, citing its &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/communitystandards/cruel_insensitive"&gt;Cruel and Insensitive Community Standard&lt;/a&gt;, which says it will remove posts that target “victims of serious physical or emotional harm,” which includes the use of memes and gifs. Facebook later reclassified the removal so it fell under its &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/communitystandards/hate_speech"&gt;Hate Speech Community Standard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D1Qn0d"&gt;The Oversight Board pointed out in its recommendation that while Facebook has said it will make exceptions for satire, it doesn’t specify how or what qualifies as satire in its guidelines. Facebook said in its post that in addition to making its guidelines around satire clearer, it would “initiate a review of identical content with parallel context,” and may take further action. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ao3guy"&gt;This marks the latest instance of Facebook following the guidance of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/23/21530524/facebooks-new-oversight-board-platform-governance"&gt;its fledgling Oversight Board&lt;/a&gt;. Earlier this month, Facebook said would &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/3/22474738/facebook-ending-political-figure-exemption-moderation-policy"&gt;end its so-called “newsworthiness” policy&lt;/a&gt;, which allowed politicians to skirt many of its content rules. Going forward the company “will not treat content posted by politicians any differently from content posted by anyone else,” Facebook’s Nick Clegg said in a &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/06/facebook-response-to-oversight-board-recommendations-trump/"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/19/22541349/facebook-update-community-standards-satire-oversight-board"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/19/22541349/facebook-update-community-standards-satire-oversight-board</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-19T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-19T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The slow transitions of a lingering pandemic</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="NYC has mark the end of the COVID-19 restrictions" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8veOUHyTHXNn4fNMqX0li5ZnWgk=/0x0:5341x3561/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69475596/1323971899.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Pedestrians walk through NYC on June 16, the day before COVID-19 restrictions lifted in the state.  | Photo by Kena Betancur/VIEWpress&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="AYB7Un"&gt;With COVID-19 restrictions &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/michael-brown-europe-australia-coronavirus-pandemic-coronavirus-vaccine-78a0c659eccb7680ba6773bbdb8f01e8?utm_campaign=SocialFlow&amp;amp;utm_medium=AP&amp;amp;utm_source=Twitter"&gt;lifting in some places&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/16/covid-outbreaks-in-chinese-ports-could-cause-global-goods-shortages"&gt;outbreaks popping up in others&lt;/a&gt;, the pandemic has officially entered the weird zone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BSzanL"&gt;Okay, there’s nothing official about it, but the entire world is in a strange transition time right now — and likely will be for a while. Unlike the jump-cut into the pandemic, or even the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/3/22364637/pandemic-edge-fear-hope-vaccines-surge-antivirus-newsletter"&gt;suspenseful vaccine ramp-up&lt;/a&gt;, this time is more hopeful, less frantic, but also stretched out in an uneven mess. Places, populations, and even industries are moving at different paces as they move back to some semblance of normality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="1CtwS7"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9360449"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KmCpwC"&gt;It’s like the entire globe is playing by a perverse version of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yes,_and..."&gt;“yes, and.”&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Yes&lt;/em&gt;, more people are vaccinated in the US than before, &lt;em&gt;and &lt;/em&gt;immunocompromised people are &lt;a href="https://slate.com/technology/2021/06/immunocompromised-covid-vaccine-unprotected-autoimmune-condition.html"&gt;still at risk&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Yes,&lt;/em&gt; the vaccines that we have are stunningly effective, &lt;em&gt;and &lt;/em&gt;they are in such short supply that many countries are &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/nepal-coronavirus-pandemic-health-1493a03ed4adb7be582d892b98efef76?utm_campaign=SocialFlow&amp;amp;utm_source=Twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=AP"&gt;absolutely desperate to get them&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wIbH2b"&gt;Here in the US, one of the most visible transitions is the vanishing act of various COVID-19 regulations. New York lifted &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/15/nyregion/coronavirus-restrictions.html"&gt;most restrictions this week&lt;/a&gt;, and Disneyland reopened to everyone, &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/how-to/disneyland-is-now-open-for-everyone-how-to-get-tickets-and-park-reservations/"&gt;without mask requirements&lt;/a&gt;. People in those areas are enjoying a return to offices, and restaurants and blessed normalcy — especially in regions where case rates are low. At the same time, parts of the country where vaccination rates have stayed low face the &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/07/world/us-south-covid-vaccine.html"&gt;potential of summer surges&lt;/a&gt;. Tensions between different regions will linger as long as disparities remain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="99ryXh"&gt;In the pharmaceutical and research realm, there’s a different shift. The flurry of clinical trials and lab work that accompanied vaccine development is now slowing. There are still thousands of questions, but the biggest and most urgent — can we make a vaccine? — has been answered. Now, research focuses have shifted and split. Some are still working on vaccines and boosters, others are investigating new &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/17/health/covid-pill-antiviral.html?partner=slack&amp;amp;smid=sl-share"&gt;COVID-19 drugs&lt;/a&gt; or seeking to understand the virus’s origins and mechanics, and others have gone back to different projects entirely. With vaccines, the biggest issues are now monitoring and distribution, not research and development. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="EBMthj"&gt;&lt;q&gt;most people are stuck somewhere in the wide gap between caution and abandon&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BCbZZD"&gt;How people feel about all of these changes is another factor entirely — personal shifts in priorities, fears, and emotions are going to play a huge role in this next phase of the pandemic. As vaccinations go up and case numbers go down, eventually, we’ll get used to the coronavirus, and it will &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22445906/social-end-pandemic-covid-adjustment-death-vibes"&gt;cease to be an unknown threat&lt;/a&gt;. We’ll stop thinking about it every day — some people already have. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LcoZHo"&gt;In the meantime, most people are stuck somewhere in the wide gap between caution and abandon. Each person will eventually move past their own personal marker for the pandemic era. It might come when they get that second shot or step into a theatre for the first time or leave a mask sitting on the table at home. As with all transitions, something will end, and something else will take its place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K7HSXL"&gt;As a quick note before we get into what happened with COVID-19 this week, I also wanted to note that you might see some new (small) changes to this newsletter. Eventually, we’ll shift the newsletter over to a weekday instead of a Saturday. And starting next week, I’ll be handing over the reins to Nicole Wetsman, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s health reporter. She’s been filling in periodically, but I’m thrilled to have her writing to you more regularly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mrP5mX"&gt;Some things won’t change, at least not yet. We’ll keep covering the pandemic and keep you up to date with what’s going on in the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="myGY4G"&gt;Thank you so much for joining us each week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gHfsse"&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="p315gQ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/health/2021/06/16/majority-covid-19-hospital-patients-us-now-unvaccinated-younger/7684857002/"&gt;People hospitalized with COVID-19 now have one overwhelming thing in common. They’re not vaccinated.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hEoMyi"&gt;In the US, there’s more proof that vaccines are overwhelmingly effective. Doctors and health systems are increasingly reporting that the COVID-19 patients showing up for treatment are not vaccinated. (Elizabeth Weise and Aleszu Bajak/&lt;em&gt;USA Today&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6QQF2f"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/stephaniemlee/black-deaths-covid-hospitals-segregation"&gt;Struggling Hospitals Could Explain Why So Many Black Patients Have Died Of COVID-19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4uV0lG"&gt;A study published this week found that one reason for the horrifying disparities in COVID-19 deaths in the US might come down to a paucity of healthcare resources in hospitals that serve Black patients. (Stephanie M Lee/&lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="odMcn4"&gt;Development &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ywGPWg"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/curevacs-covid-19-vaccine-misses-efficacy-goal-mass-trial-2021-06-16/"&gt;CureVac fails in pivotal COVID-19 vaccine trial with 47% efficacy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TrFqao"&gt;A different mRNA vaccine just tanked a clinical trial, only showing 47 percent efficacy against the virus. It’s a setback for the vaccine, which some hoped would help bolster the global supply. (Ludwig Burger/ &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y6aKJc"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2021/06/16/pfizer-vaccine-engineers-supply/"&gt;Inside Pfizer’s race to produce the world’s biggest supply of COVID vaccine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JWcSdM"&gt;A look inside the company’s race to produce its new vaccine on an unprecedented scale. (Christopher Rowland/&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VU1obY"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/17/health/covid-pill-antiviral.html?partner=slack&amp;amp;smid=sl-share"&gt;A Pill to Treat Covid-19? The U.S. Is Betting on It.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9aFAk2"&gt;$3 billion has now been set aside to help researchers dig into a treatment for COVID-19. Instead of a vaccine, which prevents the virus from taking hold, a treatment would combat the disease when a person actually has it. (Carl Zimmer/&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="grbPRu"&gt;Perspectives &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="nA0VxG"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22535642/covid-misinformation-india-asha-whatsapp"&gt;India’s fighting a battle against COVID-19 on WhatsApp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hQZsiF"&gt;Accredited social health activists are the foot soldiers of India’s rural healthcare system. Lately, they’ve also taken on the daunting task of fighting COVID-19 misinformation, mostly in local WhatsApp groups. Take a peek inside their efforts to bust misinformation in their villages. (Sanket Jain/&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="QQTHAI"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The phones were ringing, pagers going off, doors opening and closing, IV pumps beeping, ventilators oscillating, and then there was Karl, with a respectful smile, just quietly and efficiently moving bodies onto a metal gurney, and then covering them with a black tarp.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Mx5Ebo"&gt;&lt;em&gt;—&lt;/em&gt; Courtney Martin, head of maternity services at Loma Linda University Medical Center, writes about Karl, a vital worker during the pandemic. Maria L La Ganga helped &lt;a href="https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2021-06-17/when-covid-deaths-occur-karl-gives-victims-dignified-exit"&gt;tell his story in the&lt;em&gt; Los Angeles Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="IOqaIp"&gt;Perspectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Vw2L5J"&gt;To the people who have received the &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/covid-vaccine-tracker-global-distribution/?sref=ExbtjcSG&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Antivirus%3A%20This%20week%20in%20COVID-19%20research&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=Revue%20newsletter"&gt;2.51 billion vaccine doses&lt;/a&gt; distributed so far — thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cbalD2"&gt;To the more than 177,201,586 people worldwide who have tested positive, may your road to recovery be smooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sp0gru"&gt;To the families and friends of the 3,836,036 people who have died worldwide — 600,880 of those in the US — your loved ones are not forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TiEK5k"&gt;Stay safe, everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/19/22539188/transitions-pandemic-antivirus-covid"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/19/22539188/transitions-pandemic-antivirus-covid</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mary Beth Griggs</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-19T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-19T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The best pre-Prime Day deals for Father’s Day weekend</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RCR1disG9Y7Ooe85b5Y-oeyJmM4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69475577/vpavic_042018_3979_0075.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jyVmZW"&gt;Next week is when Prime Day 2021 begins. We’ll be here early on Monday and continue scouring deals through Tuesday night, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22535681/amazon-prime-day-tech-news-deals-date-time-2021"&gt;bringing you the best deals on the tech&lt;/a&gt; we know you’ll like. However, before that, on Sunday, is Father’s Day. If you’ve already gotten a gift for the dad in your life, hopefully you‘ll be able to celebrate together in some manner. But, if you haven’t yet, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22410178/fathers-day-best-gift-ideas-tech-gadgets-tools"&gt;it’s never too late to get one through our thoughtfully-curated gift guide&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="KV0Wut"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="05aw2d"&gt;Get $150 off Apple’s Magic Keyboard for the 12.9-inch iPad Pro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="h4HtK0"&gt;Best Buy is offering a rare discount on the Magic Keyboard for the 12.9-inch iPad Pro (that fits even the latest M1-equipped version). Normally $349, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1736544054881862306#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;it’s $199 for all of Saturday&lt;/a&gt;. Usually, it’s just the 11-inch model that sees a big discount. This keyboard has USB-C passthrough charging, it’s sturdy, and it has an excellent trackpad and keyboard. Keep in mind, though, that it’s going to add a good amount of weight and thickness while attached to your iPad Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="p3yolB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10295314"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="Z9q0SC"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/acxOn1fPEghXkzEBxtcUdbY8R4U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22667782/Philips_Hue_Bundle_Father_s_Day.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Philips&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="PmV4VD"&gt;Whether for Father’s Day or for yourself, Philips Hue is offering solid deals on two smart light bundles. &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.philips-hue.com/en-us/p/hue-white-and-color-ambiance-3-pack-e26/046677562786" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The first is a three-pack of standard E26 white and color ambiance bulbs for $100&lt;/a&gt; (usually $135). If you want to turn the color in your bathroom to blue and your living room to green, these are the bulbs for you. They’re Bluetooth-enabled, too, so you don’t need a Hue bridge accessory to use them, which is appealing. Though, if you want more instantaneous and seamless functionality, you may want to eventually get that Hue Bridge at some point — and these bulbs will work just fine with it once you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nkTs5g"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10613537" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_portrait_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3wHAfk"&gt;The other Philips Hue deal is slightly more niche, but still good. If you buy Philips Hue’s Ligthstrip Plus V4 80-inch model for $80 (located at the &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.philips-hue.com/en-us/products/promotions/fathersday" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;bottom of this page&lt;/a&gt;), the company will toss in a 40-inch extension at no extra cost. These two items would normally cost $105.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="8GMm0i"&gt;
&lt;p id="aY1ro2"&gt;In case you haven’t already seen it in our deals coverage, Best Buy is offering the best prices on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/24/21192146/apple-ipad-pro-review-2020-lidar-a12z-processor-speed-camera-trackpad-keyboard" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;previous-gen iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt; through Sunday, June 20th. If you have a free My Best Buy account, you can get $150 off most 11-inch and 12.9-inch configurations, whether you want a Wi-Fi or LTE-connected iPad. The base 11-inch model with 128GB of storage costs $600 — the same price as the iPad Air with half that amount of storage. The 256GB 11-inch model is just $100 more at $700. If you want a 12.9-inch iPad Pro, the 128GB base model costs $850.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6ibQ2o"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9515999"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="rST98l"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9737960"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="eRvGTP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/6/19/22540334/apple-ipad-pro-12-9-magic-keyboard-philips-hue-smart-bluetooth-bulbs-prime-day-deals-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/6/19/22540334/apple-ipad-pro-12-9-magic-keyboard-philips-hue-smart-bluetooth-bulbs-prime-day-deals-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-19T09:35:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-19T09:35:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>PayPal raising merchant fees on some of its transactions </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gyjtyzmvnMwilkqXjc_vYxwlcRs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69475547/acastro_180410_1777_paypal_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Qrf2vJ"&gt;PayPal said Friday it is raising fees for some of its newer products “to better align our pricing with the value that our products and services provide,” &lt;a href="https://newsroom.paypal-corp.com/2021-06-18-Upcoming-Changes-for-Some-US-Businesses"&gt;according to a blog post &lt;/a&gt;by senior vice president Dan Leberman. The changes will affect how much PayPal merchants pay per transaction, and take effect August 2nd. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hEqRKC"&gt;“PayPal has become more than just a button or payment processor to be a full commerce platform capable of driving growth for businesses,” according to the blog post. “Consumers are nearly three times more likely to complete their purchase when PayPal is available at checkout.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SCE7Mg"&gt;In the past, PayPal has had a &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-06-18/paypal-gains-after-announcing-price-increases-on-some-products"&gt;flat rate&lt;/a&gt; for sellers processing payments, charging 2.9 percent of a transaction price, plus a 30-cent fee. The new, higher rates will apply to the company’s newer products, like PayPal Checkout, and Pay with Venmo. According to its &lt;a href="https://s1.q4cdn.com/633035571/files/doc_financials/2021/q1/Q1-21-PayPal-Earnings-Release.pdf"&gt;first quarter earnings report&lt;/a&gt; (pdf), PayPal has 392 million active accounts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uae7rK"&gt;Here’s how the new fee schedule breaks down:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="2QIQqP"&gt;For PayPal digital payments with its PayPal Checkout, Pay with Venmo, PayPal Credit, Pay in 4, PayPal Pay with Rewards, and Checkout with crypto, the new rate for online transactions will be 3.49 percent plus $0.491 per transaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="krc04z"&gt;For in person payments with PayPal and Venmo QR code transactions over $10, the rate will be 1.90 percent plus 10 cents, and for transactions $10 and less, the rate will be 2.40 percent plus 5 cents. For certain in-person debit and credit transactions the rate will be 2.29 percent plus 9 cents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="HeuVRz"&gt;The rate for online credit and debit card transactions will be 2.59 percent plus $0.491 per transaction without its chargeback protection, and with chargeback protection the rate will be 2.99 percent plus 49 cents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="5Bq8Qr"&gt;The fee for charity transactions will be 1.99 percent plus 49 cents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="beLM1i"&gt;For US merchants who have custom, non-standard pricing, rates will remain unchanged&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="0jEpMM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rRuOec"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="square-stripe"&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="lpEiZv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xKPbcz"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/19/22541286/paypal-raise-seller-fees-transactions-online-payments"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/19/22541286/paypal-raise-seller-fees-transactions-online-payments</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-19T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-19T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Mark Mothersbaugh on composing music you won’t tire of in Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="34th Annual BMI Film, TV &amp;amp;amp; Visual Media Awards - Red Carpet" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QH9d0YC5vwBqwru5NOG2ZFXuCDo=/0x622:3114x2698/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69475441/956744398.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Frazer Harrison / Getty Images for BMI&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UYtS3U"&gt;If you’ve spent some time playing &lt;em&gt;Ratchet &amp;amp; Clank: Rift Apart&lt;/em&gt;, you might feel like you’re playing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22523093/ratchet-clank-rift-apart-review-ps5"&gt;a blockbuster family-friendly action movie&lt;/a&gt; — and that’s not just because of the game’s many perfectly timed set pieces. &lt;em&gt;Rift Apart&lt;/em&gt; is also backed by a sweeping score composed by the legendary musician Mark Mothersbaugh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U6JITq"&gt;You might recognize Mothersbaugh as the co-founder of the band Devo or as the composer of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jMEj9kQg3F8"&gt;Nickelodeon’s &lt;em&gt;Rugrats&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. But I suggest you also scroll through his &lt;a href="https://www.imdb.com/name/nm0006205/"&gt;IMDb page&lt;/a&gt;. He’s been a jaw-droppingly prolific composer with work stretching back to the 1980s, and he has credits on films (&lt;em&gt;The Lego Movie&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Thor: Ragnarok&lt;/em&gt;), TV series (&lt;em&gt;What We Do in the Shadows, Dawson’s Creek&lt;/em&gt;), and even other video games (&lt;em&gt;Skate 3&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Sims 2&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="6ngNDF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Something you want to listen to for God knows how many hours”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FY9mCK"&gt;I recently had a chance to talk to him about his involvement with &lt;em&gt;Rift Apart&lt;/em&gt; and what it’s like for him to compose a video game. One key aspect, he says, is that music in a game has to be “something you want to listen to for God knows how many hours.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fb5b6g"&gt;That makes sense — you might hear a song over and over again as you’re exploring a level or world, and games can often last dozens of hours. “It has to be something that, if you go away and you hear it in your head, you enjoy that, and it’s not something that’s irritating,” he says. “Because if a piece of music is inferior or not great, and you listen to it long enough, you can get really pissed off at everything, including the game that you were hearing it in.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SDsfek"&gt;I’m only a few hours into &lt;em&gt;Rift Apart&lt;/em&gt;, but so far, I’d say Mothersbaugh succeeded in making the music enjoyable to listen to over and over again. Take &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=55PRv_e00wc&amp;amp;t=85s"&gt;the game’s main theme&lt;/a&gt;: the expansive orchestral anthem wouldn’t feel out of place in the latest &lt;em&gt;Marvel&lt;/em&gt; epic, and I haven’t tired of hearing it yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5i6ggH"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/55PRv_e00wc?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="clfVMe"&gt;The decision to use a full orchestra for the score was intentional, Mothersbaugh says, as it acted as a “glue” to keep the game’s universe feeling cohesive. Throughout the soundtrack, though, he and the audio team added electronic elements and certain melodies to give different areas and planets unique identities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vz9FVN"&gt;I’m currently working through a mining-themed world, for example, and there’s a lot of heavy percussion to evoke the sounds of an active mine. But when I hop into one of the game’s special “pocket dimensions,” which are optional puzzle platformer rooms (kind of like the FLUDD-less levels in &lt;em&gt;Super Mario Sunshine&lt;/em&gt;), the music takes on a more ethereal tone as I jump on disappearing platforms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NsEEBd"&gt;Mothersbaugh also has to think about game music differently because of the interactivity of the medium, as opposed to a static film. “You’re always gonna see that film in one shape or one size,” he explains. Video games, on the other hand, can be “plastic and amoebic and alive.” And as a result, the music is “intimate to each person because it’s developing with them, and they’re part of it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OTNNln"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s kind of like an insight into your world.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xMZCnp"&gt;Mothersbaugh’s music doesn’t just add color to a world the player is exploring, though. He says the way music builds in a video game can reflect how it takes shape in his own head. “When you start level one — boom — the game starts, and you’re hearing the very first pass on a piece of music,” he says. As the characters advance through the levels and improve their abilities, the sounds get more layered and complex. This is meant to mirror a composer discovering and improving on their music. “It’s kind of like an insight into your world,” Mothersbaugh says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wQT3X4"&gt;This concept of music you can listen to repeatedly is particularly challenging for Mothersbaugh, who has a low tolerance for music that he doesn’t like. “If I listen to something I wrote, and an hour later, I can’t stand it anymore, then I’m kinda like, ‘You know what? This doesn’t deserve to be anywhere.’” A day before our interview, he happened to hear the soundtrack again at a listening party. “I thought, ‘Oh, this is good. This is a strong score,’” he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hQ8Ojz"&gt;&lt;small&gt;Ratchet &amp;amp; Clank: Rift Apart &lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;is available now on the PS5. If you want to hear the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;Rift Apart&lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt; soundtrack for yourself, it’s available &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;a href="https://soundtracks.lnk.to/riftapart"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;on many streaming services&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/19/22535021/mark-mothersbaugh-ratchet-and-clank-rift-apart-music-composer"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/19/22535021/mark-mothersbaugh-ratchet-and-clank-rift-apart-music-composer</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
