<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-19T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-19T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-19T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Falcon and the Winter Soldier is a brief respite in a post-Thanos world</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QLrT1ybgPb6uSSczuP0KUaeuIfg=/234x0:2766x1688/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68992444/mackie_fatws.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dl85xz"&gt;For the vast majority of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/21591343/falcon-winter-soldier-premiere-date-disney-plus-sebastian-stan-anthony-mackie-august"&gt;Bucky Barnes’&lt;/a&gt; 106 years on Earth, his life has consisted of running from fight to fight without a second to sit down and simply exist. Now, Bucky Barnes is faced with a new reality he doesn’t know how to navigate — what happens after the knuckles are bandaged and the bad guy is dead? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s2g462"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/c/482924/705882/9358?sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/a&gt; spent 11 years building up to its climactic battle between Earth’s mightiest heroes (and a couple of pals from space) and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/4/17319992/thanos-plan-avengers-infinity-war-historical-precedent-science-malthus"&gt;Mad Titan, Thanos&lt;/a&gt;. There were some hiccups along the way — Ultron nearly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/4/22/8464479/avengers-age-of-ultron-review"&gt;destroyed the world&lt;/a&gt;, countless other villains like Loki, Red Skull, and all of Hydra tried to kill the Avengers a few times — but everything boiled down to Thanos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l6C58r"&gt;He’s no longer a threat (in this universe, anyway). Millions of people are back on Earth after being snapped from existence. The world is trying to move on from the last five years. New regulations are being drawn up in government, banks are trying to figure out how to help people with finances after five years of being away, but superheroes are stuck in a moment of suspension. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="opqviX"&gt;The next big thing is around the corner — it always is — but for now, Marvel Studios is using its new television universe on Disney Plus to take a step back and let its heroes decompress as they try to figure out their place in a strange, new world. &lt;em&gt;The Falcon and the Winter Soldier&lt;/em&gt;, which debuts today,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;is a perfect example. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oR_2jAsXiWQOaAA060O_pq-BT54=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22379903/sam_bucky.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hVCO1X"&gt;[&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re reading a write-up of a new Marvel show, you know what lies ahead. Here’s your warning for minor spoilers that appear in the first episode.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;] &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UUs4JY"&gt;At the outset of the show, Captain America is gone, and his two best friends are navigating a world without him. Sam Wilson (Falcon) has rejoined the Air Force and is trying to stop terrorists from gaining power. Bucky Barnes (Winter Soldier) is undergoing therapy, living as a normal civilian in New York City for the first time since before he left to fight in World War II. Both are trying to acclimatize to their new lives, dealing with stuff they didn’t have to when the world was on the brink of extinction. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8xquiv"&gt;In one instance, Sam is trying to help his sister in Louisiana get a loan for the houseboat they grew up in but is now getting too expensive to keep up. In between pitiful requests for selfies from an Avenger-fanboy banker, the duo are consistently told they don’t have enough income for the bank to issue a loan. Confused, said banker repeatedly asks how Sam earned an income when he was part of the world’s most famous superhero group (“did Stark pay you when he was around?”) and how he could possibly be so broke all things considered. Even if Sam disappeared for five years (hence, no recent income), that just makes him like half the world’s population who also disappeared. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zbwqxj"&gt;It’s a wonderful scene. &lt;em&gt;The Falcon and the Winter Soldier &lt;/em&gt;shines best when it’s putting forth questions people have kicked around in the back of their minds or in conversations with friends for more than a decade. How do the Avengers get paid? What do they do on their time off? Do they go on dates with non-Avengers? Do they pick up part-time jobs when the world doesn’t need saving? &lt;em&gt;How do the Avengers live when there’s nothing to avenge&lt;/em&gt;? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nfsVc0"&gt;It’s a big part of what makes comic books fun week after week, month after month. The intimate lives of superheroes when the masks are removed and the high-tech gear is taken off is just as important as the extensive CGI fight sequences. In &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/5/22315094/wandavision-finale-marvel-mcu-scarlet-witch-doctor-strange-captain"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, those are the small moments between Wanda and Vision in what &lt;em&gt;could &lt;/em&gt;have been their post-Thanos life. If &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167550/hawkeye-premiere-date-marvel-disney-plus-jeremy-renner-hailee-steinfeld-wandavision"&gt;Marvel’s upcoming &lt;em&gt;Hawkeye &lt;/em&gt;series&lt;/a&gt; finds its inspiration in Matt Fraction’s beloved &lt;em&gt;Hawkeye &lt;/em&gt;comic, it’s rooftop barbecues, sipping coffee in the morning, and looking for new cars to buy. In &lt;em&gt;The Falcon and the Winter Soldier&lt;/em&gt;, it’s Sam helping his nephews catch fish on the dock or Bucky trying online dating. Hell, Bucky in therapy is something ripped right out of Tumblr; that’s a compliment. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TLV7wuUZ4PDkB-gz32po0J0bBzQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22379905/sam_cap_shield.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="0xWcLO"&gt;Everyone is trying to figure out their identity just months after half the world’s population returned, and they’re trying to do it with undeniable legacies hanging over their heads. Without Steve Rogers (Captain America) and Tony Stark (Iron Man), two of the country’s greatest heroes are gone and a hole is left in their place. Sam doesn’t want to become the new Captain America. Bucky, aside from processing the guilt and trauma he received after his years of operating as the Winter Soldier, is being monitored by the government. The world might need a new Captain America to feel safe, but replacing Steve Rogers isn’t as simple as pointing to a new guy and saying “you’re it.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wWVE8S"&gt;Well, not to Sam. By the end of the episode, the government introduces a new Captain America (most &lt;a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-us-agent-wyatt-russell-john-walker-falcon-and-winter-soldier-explained"&gt;likely John Walker&lt;/a&gt;, who becomes US Agent and has his own colorful history). While the government tries to find a replacement for Steve Rogers back home, Sam is preparing to take on a new threat, one that will require Bucky’s help. Without a Steve or a Tony set to lead the charge, it’s up to them to stop whatever threat comes their way — even if that means putting the trials and tribulations of day-to-day life on hold. As Bucky tells his therapist, he’s never known life without running from battle to battle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yoSgRb"&gt;It’s here that &lt;em&gt;The Falcon and the Winter Soldier &lt;/em&gt;has all the elements of a typical MCU movie. The pilot opens with a 10-minute action sequence (including the appearance of a &lt;em&gt;Winter Soldier &lt;/em&gt;favorite) and sets up the kind of mission-based action movie that Marvel fans love. It looks good, feels expensive, and teases a much more traditional MCU experience. Whereas &lt;em&gt;WandaVision &lt;/em&gt;screamed experimental and abstract (in comparison to the greater MCU-at-large), &lt;em&gt;Falcon and the Winter Soldier &lt;/em&gt;can nestle perfectly in between every &lt;em&gt;Captain America &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Avengers &lt;/em&gt;installment. There are big fights, bigger explosions, and the promise of more bad guys. I mean, the episode opens with &lt;a href="https://www.superherohype.com/tv/486409-the-falcon-and-the-winter-soldier-brings-back-georges-st-pierre-as-batroc"&gt;Falcon fighting Batroc.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hqZ9iC"&gt;There’s no question things are about to get explosive for the boys again. But it’s the quieter moments — Bucky trying to have a date with a girl at a bar without taking his gloves off because he doesn’t want to flash his metal arm, or Sam goofing around with his nephews — that make &lt;em&gt;Falcon and the Winter Soldier &lt;/em&gt;feel special. We’ve spent so long as fans getting to know the big-name superheroes that now feels like a perfect instance to get to know characters we didn’t get enough time with over the last decade: Wanda, Vision, Bucky, Sam, Clint Barton (Hawkeye). In fanfiction, one of the most popular settings is the Avengers crew living together in &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2021/1/26/22250482/wandavision-sitcom-coffee-shop-au"&gt;Avengers (nee Stark) Tower&lt;/a&gt;. People want to imagine their favorite superheroes going about their days just like anyone else. I love Sam Wilson and Bucky Barnes just as much as I love stories about Falcon and Winter Soldier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jRfq8c"&gt;If &lt;em&gt;Falcon and the Winter Soldier &lt;/em&gt;winds up being Bucky and Sam palling around and figuring out who they are outside of battle — in between big fight sequences, of course — I’ll be happy. After all, we adore the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YZD_EyT2FYc"&gt;party scene in &lt;em&gt;Avengers: Age of Ultron&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;for a reason. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="axZ1ah"&gt;
&lt;aside id="8DAjsP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Disney Plus","description":"$6.99 per month or $69.99 if you pay annually","label":"Subscribe","url":"https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/c/482924/972430/9358?subId1=VergeFalconWinterSoldierTest&amp;amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.disneyplus.com%2Fwelcome"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="VlBOp2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y4YVfI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22337849/falcon-winter-soldier-episode-1-recap-explainer-marvel-mcu"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22337849/falcon-winter-soldier-episode-1-recap-explainer-marvel-mcu</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-19T07:17:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-19T07:17:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>‘Anti-capitalist’ Verkada hacker charged by US government with attacks on dozens of companies</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xEae8tdDJfnXPrC34ZZQysBsxK0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68992350/acastro_180109_1777_0002_v3.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gBHzmA"&gt;A Swiss computer hacker named Till Kottmann has been &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-wdwa/pr/swiss-hacker-indicted-conspiracy-wire-fraud-and-aggravated-identity-theft"&gt;charged&lt;/a&gt; by the US government with multiple accounts of wire fraud, conspiracy, and identity theft. The indictment accuses Kottmann and co-conspirators of hacking “dozens of companies and government entities,” and posting private data and source code belonging to more than 100 firms online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ujRUfZ"&gt;The 21-year-old Kottmann, who uses they / them pronouns and is better known as Tillie, was most recently connected to the security breach of US firm Verkada, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/9/22322122/verkada-hack-150000-security-cameras-tesla-factory-cloudflare-jails-hospitals"&gt;exposed footage&lt;/a&gt; from more than 150,000 of the companies’ surveillance cameras. But the charges filed this week date back to 2019, with Kottmann and associates accused of targeting online code repositories (known as “gits”) belonging to major private and public sector entities, ripping their contents and sharing them to a website they founded and maintained named &lt;a href="http://git.rip/"&gt;git.rip&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="k1p39y"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Kottmann is linked to data breaches from Microsoft, Intel, Nissan, and more&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ub3zxp"&gt;Git.rip has since been seized by the FBI, but &lt;a href="https://therecord.media/verkada-hacker-charged-in-the-us-for-hacking-more-than-100-companies/"&gt;previously&lt;/a&gt; shared code and data belonging to numerous companies including Microsoft, Intel, Nissan, Nintendo, Disney, AMD, Qualcomm, Motorola, Adobe, Lenovo, Roblox, and many others (though no firms are explicitly named in the indictment). The exact nature of this data varied in each case. A rip of hundreds of code repositories maintained by German automaker Daimler AG &lt;a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/mercedes-benz-onboard-logic-unit-olu-source-code-leaks-online/"&gt;contained the source code&lt;/a&gt; for valuable smart car components, for example, while a breach of Nintendo’s systems (which Kottmann &lt;a href="https://www.tomsguide.com/uk/news/companies-source-code-leak"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; did not originate from them directly but which they reshared through a Telegram channel) offered gamers rare insight into &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/30/21347074/nintendo-gigaleak-controversy-history-preservation-archives"&gt;unreleased features from old games&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yJormt"&gt;In interviews &lt;a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/mercedes-benz-onboard-logic-unit-olu-source-code-leaks-online/"&gt;about&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/source-code-from-dozens-of-companies-leaked-online/"&gt;earlier&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/nissan-source-code-leaked-online-after-git-repo-misconfiguration/"&gt;breaches&lt;/a&gt;, Kottmann noted repeatedly that the data they found was usually exposed by companies’ own poor security standards. “I often just hunt for interesting GitLab instances, mostly with just simple Google dorks, when I’m bored, and I keep being amazed by how little thought seems to go into the security settings,” Kottmann &lt;a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/mercedes-benz-onboard-logic-unit-olu-source-code-leaks-online/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;ZDNet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;in May 2020. (“Google dorks” or “Google dorking” &lt;a href="https://exposingtheinvisible.org/guides/google-dorking/"&gt;refers&lt;/a&gt; to the use of advanced search strings to find vulnerabilities on public servers using Google.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s6K9JC"&gt;In the case of the Verkada breach, Kottmann and their associates &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-09/hackers-expose-tesla-jails-in-breach-of-150-000-security-cams?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;reportedly&lt;/a&gt; found “super admin” credentials that gave them unfettered access to the company’s systems that were “publicly exposed on the internet.” These logins allowed the hackers to look through the live feeds of more than 150,000 internet-connected cameras. These cameras were installed in various facilities including prisons, hospitals, warehouses, and Tesla factories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="04Nbwo"&gt;Kottmann said they were motivated by a hacktivist spirit: wanting to expose the poor security work of corporations before malicious actors could cause greater damage. Kottmann &lt;a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/source-code-from-dozens-of-companies-leaked-online/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;BleedingComputer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;last June that they didn’t always contact companies before exposing their data, but that they attempted to prevent direct harm. “I try to do my best to prevent any major things resulting directly from my releases,” they said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZIuMzH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Kottmann said they were motivated by an anti-capitalist ideology&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7QtLyT"&gt;After the Verkada breach, Kottmann &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-09/hackers-expose-tesla-jails-in-breach-of-150-000-security-cams?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; their reasons for hacking were “lots of curiosity, fighting for freedom of information and against intellectual property, a huge dose of anti-capitalism, a hint of anarchism — and it’s also just too much fun not to do it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YrfNh2"&gt;The US government, not surprisingly, takes a dimmer view of these activities. “Stealing credentials and data, and publishing source code and proprietary and sensitive information on the web is not protected speech — it is theft and fraud,” Acting U.S. Attorney Tessa M. Gorman said in a &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-wdwa/pr/swiss-hacker-indicted-conspiracy-wire-fraud-and-aggravated-identity-theft"&gt;press statement&lt;/a&gt;. “These actions can increase vulnerabilities for everyone from large corporations to individual consumers. Wrapping oneself in an allegedly altruistic motive does not remove the criminal stench from such intrusion, theft, and fraud.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BLbw3n"&gt;The indictment includes as evidence, numerous tweets and messages sent by Kottmann using handles including @deletescape and @antiproprietary. These include a tweet sent on May 17, 2020 saying “i love helping companies open source their code;” messages to an unnamed associate soliciting “access to any confidential info, documents, binaries or source code;” and tweets sent on October 21 in which Kottmann said that “stealing and releasing” corporate data was “the morally correct thing to do.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HVWDCt"&gt;Kottmann is currently located in Lucerne, Switzerland, where their premises were recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22328344/tillie-kottmann-hacker-raid-switzerland-verkada-cameras"&gt;raided by Swiss authorities&lt;/a&gt; and their devices seized. Whether or not they will be extradited to the US is unclear. &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-19/verkada-hacker-charged-with-wire-fraud-identity-theft-in-u-s?"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that Kottmann has retained the services of Zurich lawyer Marcel Bosonnet, who previously &lt;a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/europe/switzerland-could-grant-edward-snowden-asylum-if-he-testifies-against-nsa-9718462.html"&gt;represented&lt;/a&gt; Edward Snowden. The charges against Kottmann carry up to 20 year prison sentences. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/19/22339625/tillie-kottmann-swiss-hacker-verkada-charged-us-government-verkada"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/19/22339625/tillie-kottmann-swiss-hacker-verkada-charged-us-government-verkada</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-19T06:37:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-19T06:37:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>NFL significantly expands streaming deals as Amazon nabs Thursday Night exclusive</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="NFL: FEB 07 Super Bowl LV - Chiefs v Buccaneers" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jJsVesxcwJoAa-nX_ZLkbGCJcOw=/0x0:4800x3200/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68992237/1231052043.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Super Bowl LV was the most-streamed NFL game ever.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Cliff Welch/Icon Sportswire via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QNNUMS"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://nflcommunications.com/Pages/NFL-COMPLETES-LONG-TERM-MEDIA-DISTRIBUTION-AGREEMENTS-PROVIDING-FANS-GREATER-ACCESS-TO-NFL-GAMES-THAN-EVER-BEFORE.aspx"&gt;NFL has signed&lt;/a&gt; long-term television and digital media rights agreements that greatly expand availability to a variety of streaming platforms. Notably, Amazon has scored exclusive rights to Thursday Night Football in the first ever all-digital package. The deal begins with the 2023 season and extends through 2033.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4bOA6L"&gt;“NFL games are the most watched live programming in the United States, and this unprecedented Thursday Night Football package gives tens of millions of new and existing Prime members exclusive access to must-watch live football on Prime Video,” said Mike Hopkins, SVP of Prime Video and Amazon Studios in a press release announcing the deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9jTAmP"&gt;The ten-year deal is rumored to cost Amazon about $1 billion per year, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/03/18/nfl-media-rights-deal-2023-2033-amazon-gets-exclusive-thursday-night.html"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt;’s sources&lt;/a&gt;. Amazon has been the NFL’s streaming media partner since 2017, streaming games on its Prime Video and Twitch platforms. Amazon Prime memberships cost $119 per year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OM7ZCi"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Rumored to cost Amazon about $1 billion per year&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="O1Sv5R"&gt;The NFL has also expanded its digital distribution deals to include ESPN Plus, Paramount Plus, Peacock, and Fox Digital platforms in order to augment broadcasts on CBS, Fox, NBC, and ESPN/ABC. The move should help the NFL reach a younger audience after viewership fell seven percent in the pandemic-stricken 2021 season. CBS’s AFC games will now also stream on Paramount Plus, Fox’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/17/21184294/fox-tubi-acquisition-streaming-wars-news-sports-xumi-comcast-pluto-viacomcbs"&gt;Tubi service&lt;/a&gt; will stream NFC games, and Peacock will stream Sunday Night Football. All games that appear on ABC and ESPN will also stream on ESPN Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YSmiCb"&gt;“These new media deals will provide our fans even greater access to the games they love. We’re proud to grow our partnerships with the most innovative media companies in the market,” said NFL Commissioner Roger Goodell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eRp7PJ"&gt;Beyond digital, the NFL says it remains committed to showing games for free on over-the-air broadcast television, signing new, 11-year deals with CBS, Fox, NBC, and ESPN / ABC that run through 2033. The major broadcast and cable TV packages for Sunday afternoon games, Sunday Night Football, and Monday Night Football are staying with the same networks. CBS, FOX, and NBC will each televise three Super Bowls through 2033 while ESPN/ABC will now carry two. The 2021 Super Bowl was the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274255/super-bowl-55-2021-most-streamed-nfl-game-record"&gt;most-streamed NFL game ever&lt;/a&gt;, but also the least watched overall in more than a decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iHuHL7"&gt;In total, the NFL’s new media deals are thought to be worth over $100 billion, making it the most valuable media deal for any US sports league, according to &lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IfWRFQ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/19/22339636/nfl-streaming-deals-amazon-peacock-paramount-tubi-espn-plus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/19/22339636/nfl-streaming-deals-amazon-peacock-paramount-tubi-espn-plus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Thomas Ricker</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-18T20:38:53-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-18T20:38:53-04:00</updated>
    <title>Inexplicably, YouTube says extremely racist Steven Crowder video isn’t hate speech</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hJh317FmJaD6VnJbs6fRqG6_8ps=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68991001/Screen_Shot_2021_03_18_at_4.38.41_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Steven Crowder’s YouTube channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZMiIyo"&gt;YouTube removed an extremely racist video from conservative commentator Steven Crowder &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22336028/youtube-steven-crowder-racist-video-removed-covid-misinformation-policies"&gt;this week&lt;/a&gt;, citing violations of the platform’s COVID-19 misinformation policy — not its hate speech policy — as the reason for the removal. Inexplicably, though, the video did not violate the company’s hate speech policies at all, &lt;a href="https://onezero.medium.com/youtube-explains-why-a-racist-video-didnt-violate-its-hate-speech-rules-3d74befde097"&gt;the company told &lt;em&gt;OneZero&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, despite Crowder and his co-hosts making numerous racist comments about Black farmers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q5i4jZ"&gt;“Our hate speech policy prohibits content promoting hatred against groups based on their race,” a YouTube spokesperson tells &lt;em&gt;OneZero&lt;/em&gt;. “While offensive, this video from the Steven Crowder channel does not violate this policy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y2R1pw"&gt;If you were curious, here is &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/2801939?hl=en"&gt;YouTube’s full hate speech policy&lt;/a&gt;. And if you want to hear the offensive comments from Crowder’s show, &lt;em&gt;Media Matters&lt;/em&gt; clipped them in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JasonSCampbell/status/1371856007203336194"&gt;this tweet&lt;/a&gt;. I will warn you that they are awful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bGsF9f"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;On YouTube, Steven Crowder and his co-hosts go on a wildly racist tirade against Black farmers. &lt;a href="https://t.co/dbnKNN2Lch"&gt;https://t.co/dbnKNN2Lch&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/iUsm2hjknb"&gt;pic.twitter.com/iUsm2hjknb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Jason Campbell (@JasonSCampbell) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JasonSCampbell/status/1371856007203336194?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uQNDpd"&gt;This means YouTube has a ridiculously high bar for hate speech, as &lt;em&gt;OneZero’s&lt;/em&gt; Will Oremus points out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="e864"&gt;You’re free to mock, caricature, and belittle people based on their race, just as long as you don’t come right out and say you literally hate them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="2TH1sT"&gt;While you could argue that YouTube’s just enforcing the policies it has, not the policies you might want, remember that YouTube has the ability to change those policies whenever it likes. That’s what it did &lt;a href="https://blog.youtube/news-and-events/our-ongoing-work-to-tackle-hate"&gt;nearly two years ago in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, updating its hate speech policy “by specifically prohibiting videos alleging that a group is superior in order to justify discrimination, segregation or exclusion based on qualities” including race and gender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8fUiQU"&gt;That &lt;em&gt;should &lt;/em&gt;mean that hate speech doesn’t have to rise to the level of “promoting hatred” (the language YouTube used to &lt;em&gt;OneZero&lt;/em&gt;) to result in a policy violation, or to stop promoting Crowder as a YouTube Partner. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="27XT0F"&gt;Speaking of which, YouTube &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; said in that 2019 post that it would take action on hate speech that comes “right up to the line” as well, warning that “Channels that repeatedly brush up against our hate speech policies will be suspended from the YouTube Partner program.” In 2020, after Crowder’s YouTube Partner status was originally reinstated, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/12/21365601/youtube-steven-crowder-monetization-reinstated-harassment-carlos-maza"&gt;YouTube told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; it would “take appropriate action” if there were more violations on his channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6BMPCr"&gt;What will it take now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="hUzYUt"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"YouTube decides that homophobic harassment does not violate its policies","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/4/18653088/youtube-steven-crowder-carlos-maza-harassment-bullying-enforcement-verdict"},{"title":"YouTube will let Steven Crowder run ads after year-long suspension for harassment","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/12/21365601/youtube-steven-crowder-monetization-reinstated-harassment-carlos-maza"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22339030/youtube-racist-steven-crowder-video-does-not-violate-hate-speech-policies"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22339030/youtube-racist-steven-crowder-video-does-not-violate-hate-speech-policies</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-18T20:05:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-18T20:05:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>Cricut completely unravels subscription plans that would limit its crafting machines</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M_tYVaTbfkX-oO2gb_frNm5DCzQ=/298x0:3850x2368/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68990913/Screen_Shot_2021_03_15_at_11.39.19_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Cricut&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="31mCVT"&gt;Cricut has announced &lt;a href="https://inspiration.cricut.com/dear-cricut-community-from-ashish-arora-ceo/"&gt;in a new blog post&lt;/a&gt; that its automated cutting and printing craft machine will no longer require a subscription for unlimited uploads next year. The company took a step back when it announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334798/cricut-postpones-subscription-unlimited-uploads"&gt;it would postpone the change&lt;/a&gt; until 2022. But now Cricut CEO Ashish Arora is reversing the company’s plans entirely, guaranteeing Cricut machines will work how they’ve always worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DghOpX"&gt;“We’ve made the decision to reverse our previously shared plans. Right now, every member can upload an unlimited number of images and patterns to Design Space for free, and we have no intention to change this policy. This is true whether you’re a current Cricut member or are thinking about joining the Cricut family before or after December 31, 2021,” Arora writes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YdeAxv"&gt;Limits on uploads to Cricut’s required Design Space app were a contentious issue for regular Cricut crafters. While Design Space can work as separate creation software, many users prefer to create their art in other applications and bring them into Design Space to finalize them, before their Cricut cuts them out of paper, fabric and other materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R9yaDX"&gt;In Cricut’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22332212/cricut-crafting-machine-design-space-upload-limit"&gt;controversial plan&lt;/a&gt;, the company offered 20 Design Space uploads per month for free, and locked unlimited uploads behind a paid Cricut Access subscription. The move did not go over well with users, who were not only used to having unlimited uploads for free, but also wanted to avoid additional costs, or being forced to use Design Space for the entirety of their projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dxW241"&gt;Cricut’s original response seemed to satisfy a lot of its customers, but now the company has gone a step further and made its subscription plan what it started out as, an add-on, rather than a requirement for normal use.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22338801/cricut-crafting-machines-backlash-no-more-subscription-needed"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22338801/cricut-crafting-machines-backlash-no-more-subscription-needed</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-18T18:54:07-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-18T18:54:07-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook is working on a version of Instagram for kids under 13</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JlTaBeWU5zGNFfskedMaZcYo6uo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68990588/acastro_190919_1777_instagram_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fgxoSP"&gt;Head of Instagram Adam Mosseri confirms that a version of the popular photo sharing app for children under 13 is in the works, &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/facebook-instagram-for-children-under-13"&gt;&lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;. The Facebook-owned company knows a lot of kids want to use Instagram, Mosseri said, but there isn’t a “detailed plan yet,” according to &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nTYa6R"&gt;“But part of the solution is to create a version of Instagram for young people or kids where parents have transparency or control,” Mosseri told &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/em&gt;. “It’s one of the things we’re exploring.” Instagram’s current policy bars children under 13 from the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Ytrhwa"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Kids are increasingly asking their parents if they can join apps that help them keep up with their friends. A version of Instagram where parents have control, like we did w/ Messenger Kids, is something we’re exploring. We’ll share more down the road.&lt;/p&gt;— Adam Mosseri   (@mosseri) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mosseri/status/1372691059348631555?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 18, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sWBT7H"&gt;“Increasingly kids are asking their parents if they can join apps that help them keep up with their friends,” Joe Osborne, a Facebook spokesperson said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Right now there aren’t many options for parents, so we’re working on building additional products — like we did with Messenger Kids — that are suitable for kids, managed by parents. We’re exploring bringing a parent-controlled experience to Instagram to help kids keep up with their friends, discover new hobbies and interests, and more.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Oe7pue"&gt;&lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/em&gt; obtained a message from an internal messaging board where Instagram vice president of product Vishal Shah said a “youth pillar” project has been identified as a priority by the company. Its Community Product Group will focus on privacy and safety issues “to ensure the safest possible experience for teens,” Shah wrote in the post. Mosseri would oversee the project along with vice president Pavni Diwanji, who oversaw YouTube Kids while she was at Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b0aUmA"&gt;Instagram &lt;a href="https://about.instagram.com/blog/announcements/continuing-to-make-instagram-safer-for-the-youngest-members-of-our-community"&gt;published a blog post&lt;/a&gt; earlier this week describing its work to make the platform safe for its youngest users, but made no mention of a new version for kids under 13. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uL8Geb"&gt;Targeting online products at children under 13 is fraught not only with concerns about privacy, but legal issues as well. In September 2019, the Federal Trade Commission &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/4/20848949/google-ftc-youtube-child-privacy-violations-fine-170-milliion-coppa-ads"&gt;fined Google $170 million&lt;/a&gt; for tracking the viewing histories of children to serve ads to them on YouTube, a violation of the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). TikTok precursor Musical.ly was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/27/18243312/tiktok-ftc-fine-musically-children-coppa-age-gate"&gt;fined $5.7 million&lt;/a&gt; for violating COPPA in February of 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BfgWHq"&gt;Facebook launched an ad-free version of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/4/16725494/facebook-messenger-kids-app-launch-ios-iphone-preview"&gt;Messenger chat platform for kids in 2017&lt;/a&gt;, intended for kids between the ages of 6 and 12. Children’s health advocates criticized it as harmful for kids and &lt;a href="https://commercialfreechildhood.org/wp-content/uploads/archive/devel-generate/gaw/FBMessengerKids.pdf"&gt;urged CEO Mark Zuckerberg to discontinue&lt;/a&gt; it. Then in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/22/20706250/facebook-messenger-kids-bug-chat-app-unauthorized-adults"&gt;2019, a bug in Messenger Kids&lt;/a&gt; allowed children to join groups with strangers, leaving thousands of kids in chats with unauthorized users. Facebook quietly closed those unauthorized chats, which it said affected “a small number” of users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3ifrpk"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 18th, 7:46PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Added tweet from Adam Mosseri.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22338911/facebook-instagram-kids-privacy-coppa"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22338911/facebook-instagram-kids-privacy-coppa</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-18T18:26:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-18T18:26:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>OnePlus CEO announces there will be a third, less-expensive phone called the OnePlus 9R</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AVfLkW2GbidnSi3b0DwDHMPALOA=/0x0:534x356/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68990435/1616062102_oneplus_9r.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: OnePlus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UbXIal"&gt;A third phone in the upcoming OnePlus 9 series has been confirmed by the company’s CEO, in &lt;a href="https://www.news18.com/news/tech/exclusive-oneplus-9r-signals-return-of-the-flagship-killer-gaming-credentials-and-made-for-india-3547673.html"&gt;an interview with &lt;em&gt;News18&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/03/18/oneplus-ceo-confirms-affordably-priced-oneplus-9r-coming-to-india/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The announcement, which is coming just five days before the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22334396/oneplus-9-march-23rd-event-rumor-announcement-roundup-smartwatch-cameras"&gt;OnePlus 9 and 9 Pro are set to be fully revealed&lt;/a&gt;, confirms rumors that OnePlus would also be announcing a less expensive phone in addition to its new flagships. So far, though, the phone is only confirmed to be coming to India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yJZe5R"&gt;In the interview, OnePlus CEO Pete Lau says that the company wants “to go even further” than it did with the OnePlus Nord, in regards to the included tech and design. Depending on how closely you follow OnePlus, you may remember the Nord as a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21337235/oneplus-nord-review-specs-features-camera-performance-battery-life-90hz-screen-oled"&gt;mid-range phone that was available in Europe and India&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22214280/oneplus-nord-n10-5g-review"&gt;as a budget phone released in the US&lt;/a&gt;. Which part of the price-to-performance spectrum OnePlus is targeting isn’t clear yet, though some of Lau’s comments indicate that it may be closer to the mid-range end. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="MPEI7P"&gt;&lt;q&gt;We expect gaming phones to be specced out with the latest and greatest&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YngCTR"&gt;He says the phone will feature 5G, and talks &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; about gaming in relation to the 9R, saying that the company wants the phone to provide “fast and smooth experiences” for “heavy gameplay.” The “smooth experiences” and “smooth scrolling” references suggest that, like with its recent budget phones, OnePlus will probably include a 90Hz or faster display. As for the gaming focus, that may be more of a marketing focus than a hardware one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fPfgl2"&gt;The 9R &lt;a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/oneplus-9-lite-snapdragon-865-will-launch-alongside-oneplus-9-9-pro"&gt;is rumored to have a Snapdragon 865&lt;/a&gt;, a processor from last year — where usually we expect gaming phones to be specced out with the latest and greatest chips. For example, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321496/asus-rog-phone-5-ultimate-review-gaming-phone-snapdragon-888-ram-specs-features"&gt;ROG Phone 5&lt;/a&gt; has the Snapdragon 888, up to 18GB of RAM, and a 144Hz screen. None of that is exactly cost-friendly, so perhaps OnePlus’s claims that it’ll be for heavy gamers should be taken with a grain of salt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="84HkgV"&gt;The rest of the interview is light on concrete details, with Lau not talking about pricing or availability outside of India, but it does give an idea of what OnePlus is thinking about for the 9R. With the event just around the corner, it may not long before we find out for sure. If you’re curious about the higher-end 9 and 9 Pro, you can read &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22334396/oneplus-9-march-23rd-event-rumor-announcement-roundup-smartwatch-cameras"&gt;our pre-announcement information roundup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22338504/oneplus-9r-less-expensive-phone-confirmed-india-5g"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22338504/oneplus-9r-less-expensive-phone-confirmed-india-5g</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-18T17:49:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-18T17:49:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>Among Us’ new Airship map launches on March 31st</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mXTYakAcOOLc_oWiUoBg503JgLE=/522x0:6147x3750/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68990221/mm6b5H.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Innersloth&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="AiuFu0"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Among Us&lt;/em&gt;’ new Airship map will be available on March 31st as part of a free update coming to the hit social deduction game. Developer InnerSloth says the Airship map is the game’s biggest yet, with new tasks and the ability to pick which room you start in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SBznMB"&gt;You can get a preview of the new map in &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/ixfokUG711U"&gt;this trailer&lt;/a&gt;, which released &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22168243/among-us-innersloth-new-map-airship-early-2021"&gt;during The Game Awards&lt;/a&gt; in December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Tm51y5"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ixfokUG711U?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NGpSS5"&gt;The new update will also add what InnerSloth is calling a “preliminary” account system to help with moderation. Accounts have been in the works for a while, and InnerSloth wanted to make sure to take the time to implement them thoughtfully, &lt;a href="https://innersloth.itch.io/among-us/devlog/232933/-march-31-the-airship-releases"&gt;according to a blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="APmB9D"&gt;“A proper moderation system is one that is extremely difficult and time consuming,” the studio said. “It is not as easy as just having a ‘report’ button and having an algorithm ban someone after a certain number of reports.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="doggER"&gt;Perhaps most importantly, InnerSloth is also teasing that there will be new free hats in the update. (Though I’m not sure I’ll ever change from the red beanie, my personal favorite.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WMi6Ra"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;  MARCH 31  &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TheAirship?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#TheAirship&lt;/a&gt; is coming.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; this NEW map is our biggest one yet, including:&lt;br&gt; • all new tasks&lt;br&gt; • different starting rooms&lt;br&gt; • preliminary account system&lt;br&gt; • more!!!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;wake up ur crew it's almost time to eject impostors&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; ️ Dev log: &lt;a href="https://t.co/bWP008pKmr"&gt;https://t.co/bWP008pKmr&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/ZcTZFjsu3n"&gt;pic.twitter.com/ZcTZFjsu3n&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Among Us ✨ New map - MARCH 31 (@AmongUsGame) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AmongUsGame/status/1372624267326685186?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 18, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5BLkLt"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Among Us&lt;/em&gt; was first released in 2018, but it blew up last year as people turned to the game during the pandemic. (Roughly half a billion people &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22196330/among-us-half-billion-players-november"&gt;reportedly played it in November&lt;/a&gt;.) The game became so popular that InnerSloth even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/23/21453499/among-us-2-sequel-popular-canceled-developers-innersloth"&gt;canceled a planned sequel&lt;/a&gt; to focus on the original.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kPKCvZ"&gt;The game is currently available for PC, iOS, Android, and Switch, with an Xbox port on the way &lt;a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2020/12/10/among-us-coming-soon-to-xbox-game-pass-for-pc/"&gt;sometime this year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="rIBiT7"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Among Us developers explain why new features are taking a while","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/20/22241461/among-us-developers-innersloth-new-features-blog"},{"title":"Nearly half a billion users played Among Us in November","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22196330/among-us-half-billion-players-november"},{"title":"Among Us is so popular that its developers just canceled the sequel","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/23/21453499/among-us-2-sequel-popular-canceled-developers-innersloth"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22338782/among-us-airship-map-accounts-update-innersloth"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22338782/among-us-airship-map-accounts-update-innersloth</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-18T17:47:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-18T17:47:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>Congress tries to get the FTC in fighting shape</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="House Committee On Foreign Affairs Hears Testimony From Secretary Of State Blinken" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RVm45MMGxw_8xcTNHNFRjg4D8Co=/0x0:6691x4461/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68990209/1231636131.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Ting Shen-Pool / Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6M2sh0"&gt;On Thursday, House Judiciary Committee lawmakers held a hearing with some of the most prominent players in antitrust enforcement today. Two Federal Trade Commission leaders and two state attorneys general currently suing Facebook for violating antitrust law testified before the committee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XHZm6R"&gt;But while lawmakers have spoken extensively about breaking up companies like Facebook and Google, law enforcement agencies are the ones with real power to unwind tech mergers, even if their dwindling budgets and measly resources make it more difficult to do so. On Thursday, members of Congress signaled that they want to help them bring more lawsuits against Big Tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="nr1FJT"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHAT IT MEANS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="o13oXu"&gt;In previous hearings, committee chairman Rep. David Cicilline (D-RI) and others have made sweeping statements about setting new rules of the road for tech companies in order to spur more competition in the market. But on Thursday, it became apparent that helping enforcers do their jobs may be Congress’ first point of focus when it comes to reform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="feBNlD"&gt;At the top of Thursday’s hearing, Cicilline asked the witnesses how Congress could help modernize merger enforcement and encourage agencies like the DOJ and FTC to take on more cases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ruvbFS"&gt;“Today’s hearing is an opportunity to take additional steps… by identifying reforms to develop and clarify the antitrust laws to confront America’s monopoly problem,” Cicilline said in his opening remarks Thursday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rk9tsI"&gt;It’s something Republicans seem eager to take on as well. Ranking Member Rep. Ken Buck (R-CO) said Thursday that he supports “increasing rigorous enforcement” of antitrust law and “reforming burdens of proof for Big Tech mergers involving a monopoly platform” — basically, making it easier for law enforcement to bring lawsuits against violating tech companies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aNcjUf"&gt;But FTC Acting Chair Democrat Rebecca Slaughter told lawmakers that their work shouldn’t stop there. “I firmly believe that effective enforcement is a complement, not an alternative, to thoughtful regulation,” she said.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SFZFqT"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE HIGHLIGHT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="1edB6s"&gt;During Thursday’s hearing, I spoke with Sen. Amy Klobuchar (D-MN) about Congress’ priorities when it comes to antitrust reform. I asked Klobuchar if Congress should prioritize helping enforcers and providing them with more resources when it comes to antitrust reform.&lt;strong&gt;   &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kYxXVK"&gt;“That’s something you can do while making the case for the changes to law,” Klobuchar said. “I was so close to getting that done at the end of the year.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VcFUeD"&gt;Klobuchar touted her antitrust package with Sen. Chuck Grassley (R-IA) called the “Competition and Antitrust Law Enforcement Reform Act.” That bill would provide law enforcement with more resources to take competition cases to court, mirroring much of what the House Judiciary Committee discussed on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SLtXCp"&gt;Klobuchar is also giving a virtual talk on antitrust reform on Friday with EU Executive Vice President Margrethe Vestager. I asked Klobuchar what lessons the US could take from the EU’s competition efforts in the tech space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UPbsV1"&gt;“They have gone about this in a way where they’re seriously looking at competition policy,” Klobuchar said. “They’re calling it competition policy, and they’ve been aggressive about it, going up to these gateway companies. I think that’s the overall thing that one can learn. Let’s face it, US policy has been sleepy. For years, it was kind of close your eyes to what’s happening with things like [Facebook’s] purchases of WhatsApp and Instagram.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="e96ole"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHAT’S NEXT?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="wBG7Dx"&gt;With all of the House’s hearings coming to an end, it means we could start seeing legislation introduced in the near future. Earlier this month, Klobuchar told CNN’s Brian Fung that she plans to hold a series of competition hearings in the Senate as well looking into tech’s dominance, like app store fees and Facebook and Google’s dominance of the ad market. Those hearings haven’t been scheduled yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pd5Ecr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22338763/facebook-google-antitrust-cicilline-ftc-slaughter-monopoly"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22338763/facebook-google-antitrust-cicilline-ftc-slaughter-monopoly</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-18T17:30:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-18T17:30:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>A streamer is staying live for as long as people keep subscribing</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LUOCKf5UFHFnbECUX_Sk3qa7xbo=/116x41:1324x846/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68990091/Screen_Shot_2021_03_18_at_4.39.49_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RBy64i"&gt;Twitch streamer &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/ludwig"&gt;Ludwig Ahgren&lt;/a&gt; has been live since March 14th, and today marked the fourth continuous day of his broadcast. The reason? Every time someone subscribes to his channel, it adds 10 seconds to the amount of time he plans to remain live. In other words: Ahgren is running an uncapped subathon because he’ll stay up as long as viewers keep subscribing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pu1ynU"&gt;Since he’s one of the most popular streamers on Twitch — with 1.8 million followers as of this writing — it means Ahgren’s going to be live for at least a couple more days. (As of this writing, he’s got another 57 hours to go.) Yesterday, when he went to sleep for the night in his red racecar bed, he even managed to become the top streamer on Twitch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="IpX51A"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Number 1 and 2 streamers on twitch tonight&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Badass &lt;a href="https://t.co/dpVpEaEZCt"&gt;pic.twitter.com/dpVpEaEZCt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— ludwig (@LudwigAhgren) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LudwigAhgren/status/1372127176716292101?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 17, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6VZ34V"&gt;This isn’t actually against Twitch’s TOS. A Twitch spokesperson emailed &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; a statement, clarifying that they, too, have been watching the stream pretty closely and maintaining that Ahgren isn’t violating any of their rules. “Our &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/p/legal/community-guidelines/"&gt;Community Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; do not prohibit sleeping on stream, however we expect streamers to take proper precautions to ensure their stream and chat are being monitored and attended to,” wrote a spokesperson. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ofHMWd"&gt;While he’s been awake, Ahgren’s been streaming games with friends; while he’s asleep, his mods have been running videos chosen by the community. As Nathan Grayson &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/twitch-stars-never-ending-stream-shows-no-signs-of-stop-1846488273"&gt;wrote in &lt;em&gt;Kotaku&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: “It’s basically a big, bleary-eyed slumber party where everyone’s just vibing.” (While subathons are a thing in the Twitch community, they rarely go longer than, say, &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/LivestreamFail/comments/bmc789/shroud_gifts_giantwaffle_100_subs_extending_his/"&gt;30-something hours&lt;/a&gt;.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iCF53I"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://player.twitch.tv/?channel=ludwig&amp;amp;autoplay=false&amp;amp;parent=www.theverge.com&amp;amp;parent=iframe.ly&amp;amp;parent=iframely.com&amp;amp;parent=cdn.iframe.ly&amp;amp;parent=if-cdn.com" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="T9SQWn"&gt;Twitch is a wonderfully immediate place online. You can see and interact with the people on your screen in real time, which feels like a kind of intimacy. Ahgren’s stream is well on its way to becoming an event in Twitch’s history, akin to Twitch Plays Pokémon and any of its other site-wide memes. It’s incredible to me that as big as it is, Twitch still has its own distinct culture and its own set of stars who seem to do stunts like this just because they seem cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jnRTbW"&gt;But historicizing can wait. Right now, Ahgren’s live, and it’s wonderful. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22338680/ludwig-ahgren-twitch-subathon"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22338680/ludwig-ahgren-twitch-subathon</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bijan Stephen</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
