<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-01T18:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T18:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T18:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Qualcomm’s new G3x platform could usher in a new wave of Nintendo Switch-alikes</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_LyH46o_IfUxc2SVcMJXvU0QLNA=/0x0:5625x3750/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70217068/Snapdragon_G3x_gen_1_Handheld_Gaming_Lifestyle_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Snapdragon G3x Handheld Gaming  Developer Kit. &lt;/em&gt; | Image: Qualcomm&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SutTDa"&gt;Qualcomm is upping its investment in gaming with a new Snapdragon G3x Gen 1 Gaming Platform, which manufacturers can use to make Nintendo Switch or Steam Deck-like handheld gaming devices. The Snapdragon G3x Gen 1 is an Android-based platform designed to let you play Android games, stream games from a console or PC, or play games via cloud gaming services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0jTm6l"&gt;The basis of the platform is the new G3x chip. It has an Adreno GPU, similar to Qualcomm’s existing smartphone chips, which will let you play games at up 144fps. It also supports sub-6Hz 5G, mmWave 5G, and Wi-Fi 6E for speedy networking. If you want to connect G3x-powered devices to other screens, the chip supports output to a 4K display or tethering to a mixed reality headset over a USB-C port. The G3x also includes the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/4/22313214/qualcomm-snapdragon-sound-announced-high-res-audio"&gt;Snapdragon Sound&lt;/a&gt; platform, which is designed to improve audio quality when you listen to music with supported wireless headphones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="k2ZlTw"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Qualcomm partnered with Razer on a development kit&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SxQovf"&gt;To help sell its vision of what it thinks the G3x platform can do, Qualcomm has partnered with Razer on a developer kit device. (You may have already seen the device, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/30/22809800/qualcomm-razer-games-console-handheld-snapdragon-g3x-developer-kit-leak"&gt;which leaked on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;.) The handheld runs on the G3x chip, has a 6.65-inch OLED screen that supports 120Hz refresh rates, and has a 5MP webcam on the front so that players can livestream their faces while playing a game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wEXRcU"&gt;Interested developers register to get the kit through Razer’s website starting Wednesday. But it’s not a Razer device, the company told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “This is not a Razer hardware announcement,” Justin Cooney, Razer’s director of global partnerships, said in a statement. “The Snapdragon G3x&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;developer kit is a Qualcomm device. Working together with Qualcomm in this collaborative partnership, we aim to bring more publishers and developers to the table and achieve our joint vision for creating the future of portable gaming.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kURfT6"&gt;It’s unclear when we might see actual devices from other OEMs. “We’re really just focusing on the developer community right now,” Qualcomm’s Micah Knapp said in a briefing with reporters. “The devices are really up to the OEM in terms of when they can go out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b4RZ7G"&gt;Qualcomm has seen success with its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/25/21147912/qualcomm-snapdragon-xr2-vr-ar-xr-platform-reference-design-announcement"&gt;AR / VR-focused XR platform&lt;/a&gt; — its XR2 chip powers &lt;a href="https://www.qualcomm.com/news/onq/2020/10/29/oculus-quest-2-how-snapdragon-xr2-powers-next-generation-vr"&gt;Meta’s Quest 2 standalone VR headset&lt;/a&gt;. We’ll have to wait and see if the G3x ends up powering something similarly popular. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22789752/qualcomm-g3x-chip-platform-android-razer-developer-kit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22789752/qualcomm-g3x-chip-platform-android-razer-developer-kit</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T18:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T18:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Qualcomm’s Snapdragon 8cx Gen 3 is its latest attempt to hit a Windows on Arm home run</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EE9EPiueHWmXD11KCORtBB4vVzw=/469x0:5532x3375/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70217074/Snapdragon_8cx_Gen_3_Hero_Image.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MDxx2e"&gt;Qualcomm has announced its latest flagship chip for PCs: the Snapdragon 8cx Gen 3, which, as the name implies, succeeds &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/3/21409500/qualcomm-8cx-gen-2-5g-chips-arm-window-laptops-ifa-2020"&gt;last year’s 8cx Gen 2 model&lt;/a&gt; and offers some substantial jumps in performance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mC6ra7"&gt;The 8cx Gen 3 is the first chip for Windows computers built on a 5nm process and promises up to 85 percent better CPU performance and up to 60 percent faster GPU performance compared to the 8cx Gen 2. Additionally, Qualcomm boasts that its new chip offers “60 percent greater performance per watt over the competitive x86 platform” — although the company is notably quiet on which x86 platform its comparing things to. Qualcomm also touts that the chip supports “multi-day battery life,” although again, it didn’t provide too many details. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GLYkkDJZ6z7xP-FTFhd0tTYDm6E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23056637/Snapdragon_8cx_Gen_3_Compute_Platform_Chip.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fTFWEM"&gt;As one might expect for a major Qualcomm laptop chip, a major feature on the 8cx is connectivity, with Qualcomm offering support for its Snapdragon X55, X62, or X65 5G modems (depending on what kind of 5G capabilities manufacturers want to offer). Additionally, the 8cx Gen 3 will support Wi-Fi 6 and 6E for when you’re not out and about. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yT0NRu"&gt;The usual AI improvements are here, too: there’s Qualcomm’s Spectra ISP, which promises better autofocus, auto-white balance, and auto-exposure for videoconferencing, as well as noise and echo cancellation features for better audio. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fhSnb2"&gt;Additionally, Qualcomm has been touting the power and battery life of its laptop chips since it first announced the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/6/18128630/qualcomm-snapdragon-8cx-announcement-technology-summit-maui"&gt;original 8cx&lt;/a&gt; back in 2018; the chips haven’t really taken off, outside of modified versions appearing in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/23/21526702/microsoft-surface-pro-x-2020-review-arm-windows-10-apps-features-specs-price"&gt;Microsoft’s Surface Pro X laptops&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jLmL1j"&gt;And those computers that &lt;em&gt;have &lt;/em&gt;shipped with Qualcomm’s silicon haven’t made much of a dent on the Intel and AMD x86 hegemony for Windows, with slow developer support and none of the revolutionary advances that Apple’s own Arm-based M1-series chips have brought to its computers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ukoiwU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Qualcomm’s next-gen CPU for PCs will take on Apple’s M-series chips in 2023","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/16/22785181/qualcomm-next-gen-cpu-pc-apple-m1-competitor-2023"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="DsBZKP"&gt;Maybe the 8cx Gen 3 will change that. But it’s hard not to feel like the 8cx Gen 3 isn’t anything but a stopgap when &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/16/22785181/qualcomm-next-gen-cpu-pc-apple-m1-competitor-2023"&gt;Qualcomm is already teasing its &lt;em&gt;next&lt;/em&gt; next-generation Windows PC chips for 2023&lt;/a&gt;. Those chips, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22229497/qualcomm-apple-nuvia-acquisition-cpu-chip-design-data-center"&gt;designed by the Nuvia team&lt;/a&gt; that Qualcomm bought for $1.4 billion earlier this year, are “designed to set the performance benchmark for Windows PCs” with leadership in “sustained performance and battery life,” in addition to offering a competitive processor to Apple’s excellent M-series chips. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aAs1KJ"&gt;In addition to the 8cx Gen 3, Qualcomm also announced a new Snapdragon 7c Plus Gen 3 platform. Unlike its flagship cousin, the 7c Plus Gen 3 is still built on a 6nm process but promises up to 60 percent better multi-threaded CPU performance and 70 percent better graphics than the  7c Gen 2. Like the 7c Gen 2, the 7c Plus Gen 3 is meant for entry-level Windows PCs and Chromebooks, so it’s not quite as powerful as the new 8cx Gen 3. In addition to the performance boosts, though, Qualcomm is also adding an integrated Snapdragon X53 modem, enabling 5G on Qualcomm’s entry-level laptop chips for the first time. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811736/qualcomm-snapdragon-8cx-gen-3-announcement-laptop-arm-chip-processor"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811736/qualcomm-snapdragon-8cx-gen-3-announcement-laptop-arm-chip-processor</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T17:53:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T17:53:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon Alexa can now respond to running water and bleeping appliances</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8RMe-HD8fMCWJ5C6IK-QE-WNipo=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70217040/dseifert_201025_4263_00011.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EXx0BO"&gt;Amazon has expanded sound detection for routines, as well as made Alexa’s prescription refill skill available to Amazon Pharmacy customers. The company described the changes in its &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/b/?node=23689535011"&gt;Alexa monthly roundup for November&lt;/a&gt;, which also includes mentions the US rollout of Conversation Mode, and that the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22693503/amazon-echo-show-15-smart-display-wall-price-specs-features"&gt;wall-mountable Echo Show 15&lt;/a&gt; will start shipping &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22786975/amazon-echo-show-15-release-date-preorder-smart-display-alexa"&gt;next week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ois3Mv"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22696536/amazon-alexa-echo-recognize-sounds-teach-ai"&gt;Amazon first announced&lt;/a&gt; its plans to support custom sounds at its fall event back in September, but it doesn’t look like you’re able to program custom sounds just yet — Amazon has simply added two new sounds you can tell Alexa to recognize. With the new update, the device can listen out for the sounds of water running and appliances beeping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gPQSrS"&gt;If you want Alexa to detect the chime of your dryer, for example, you can set up a routine for Alexa to send you a notification when your dryer has turned off. Previously, the device could only recognize dogs barking, babies crying, snoring, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/20/17883428/amazon-alexa-guard-alarm-ring-smart-home-security-price"&gt;glass shattering, as well as smoke alarms beeping&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="bkHQih"&gt;&lt;q&gt;You can now say, “Alexa, refill my medications,” if you’re an Amazon Pharmacy customer&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kibeqN"&gt;Additionally, if you’re an Amazon Pharmacy customer, you can now say, “Alexa, refill my medications,” when you need a refill on your prescriptions. Alexa will provide you with updates on when your medications are delivered, and you can also ask Alexa to call Amazon Pharmacy if you need any assistance. In the past, the ability to request refills through Alexa was only available to &lt;a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/devices/new-ways-to-manage-your-medications-at-home-using-alexa"&gt;Giant Eagle Pharmacy customers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0bkmLe"&gt;Amazon has also fully rolled out Conversation Mode for the third-gen Echo Show 10 in the US, something that it &lt;a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/devices/conversation-mode-helps-interactions-with-alexa-feel-more-natural"&gt;started adding to devices in November&lt;/a&gt;. You can opt in to the feature by saying, “Alexa, join the conversation.” After that, you can speak more “naturally” with Alexa without using a wake word. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DqesLE"&gt;Amazon also notes that anyone in the room can talk with Alexa — they just have to face the device’s camera. During Conversation Mode, Alexa will respond if directly addressed and will also pause if it gets interrupted. You’ll know that Conversation Mode is on by the blue border that appears around the Echo Show’s screen. When you want to turn it off, simply say, “Leave this conversation.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22812495/amazon-alexa-custom-sound-detection-live"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22812495/amazon-alexa-custom-sound-detection-live</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T17:29:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T17:29:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>A new Matrix Resurrections trailer is all about change</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E-X1-fMVDra6Rr0MIQUb-NaStnA=/345x0:1568x815/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70216933/trinity_melting.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IgYs_NDyaLs&amp;amp;t=42s" target="_blank"&gt;Warner Bros.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Muw3RG"&gt;Let’s get something out of the way: this is &lt;em&gt;The Verge,&lt;/em&gt; and if there is any movie we are going to cover the shit out of, it’s &lt;em&gt;The Matrix Resurrections &lt;/em&gt;— even if its new trailer is long on melting / morphing faces and short on clues about the plot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oQC179"&gt;The latest trailer, titled “Déjà Vu,” opens with a voiceover from Trinity (Carrie-Anne Moss) with a line from the first movie, when she explains that “déjà vu is usually a glitch in the Matrix. It happens when they change something.” That sentence repeats several times. We see a black cat cross Neo’s path just like in the first movie, and we see a series of screen wipes, moving between younger and older versions of characters, including Neo — in the birthing goo pod — Trinity, Morpheus (hi, Laurence Fishburne!), Agent Smith, The Merovingian, and others.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JhpKVJ"&gt;Like the first &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22640826/matrix-4-trailer-resurrections-release-date"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Matrix Resurrections&lt;/em&gt; trailer released in September&lt;/a&gt;, we hear Jefferson Airplane’s &lt;em&gt;White Rabbit&lt;/em&gt; playing in the background (there is no &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SocialKimLy/status/1435964170483093508?s=20"&gt;rubber duck&lt;/a&gt; in this latest clip, unfortunately). In case you didn’t pick up on the theme, the trailer helpfully shows the word CHANGE, while hearing a voice question, “Why use old code to make something new?” and another observe that “maybe this isn’t the story we think it is.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hWWZ4P"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge’&lt;/em&gt;s managing editor encouraged me to blog my feelings about this latest trailer, even though I warned her the feelings would be mostly “lust and also more lust” because look, I am Gen X, and Keanu Reeves is our mascot, and I feel compelled to protect and respect him at all costs even in the worst of movies. This film looks like a fine use of his cheekbones and soulful brown eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s8G92z"&gt;And this trailer probably should have been the first one released for &lt;em&gt;Resurrections&lt;/em&gt; because it reminds you of how much we missed the black leather-clad, hair-gelled&lt;em&gt; Matrix&lt;/em&gt; crew while hinting at a whole new direction. This is slightly off-topic, but it is sort of nice to see a few crows’ feet around Neo’s eyes as he looks around, bewildered, at the Matrix — much the way I expect most of Gen X would regard it were we ever to be unplugged. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NJalD3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Matrix Resurrections&lt;/em&gt; hits theaters on December 22nd. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nB11d0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22812697/new-matrix-resurrections-trailer-warner-bros-keanu-reeves"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22812697/new-matrix-resurrections-trailer-warner-bros-keanu-reeves</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T16:59:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T16:59:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Frances Haugen is kicking Congress into gear on 230 reform</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Facebook Whistleblower Frances Haugen Testifies At Senate Hearing On Big Tech" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T0Kq3VQjUzTmRP0kI5ZgIAt15nA=/0x1:6978x4653/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70216804/1356609708.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Alex Wong/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="L6tl5o"&gt;Facebook whistleblower Frances Haugen testified for the second time before Congress on Wednesday. But instead of explaining Facebook’s harms, Haugen provided guidance on how to fix the problems the platform created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sps4TG"&gt;Specifically, House lawmakers on &lt;a href="https://energycommerce.house.gov/committee-activity/hearings/hearing-on-holding-big-tech-accountable-targeted-reforms-to-techs-legal"&gt;the Energy and Commerce Committee&lt;/a&gt; requested Haugen’s input on a slew of recently introduced measures to reform tech’s controversial legal liability shield under Section 230 of the Communications Decency Act. Both Republicans and Democrats have a stake in the game, but their deep divides over what kind of online content should stay up or down has stalled any chance of pushing reforms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WGar0j"&gt;But House Democrats are more optimistic now than ever in their abilities to clamp down on hate speech and harmful content. In an interview on Wednesday, Rep. Tom Malinowski (D-NJ) said that Congress’ work to regulate tech was largely paused due to its work in passing President Joe Biden’s Build Back Better agenda. “We had to deal with infrastructure,” Malinowski said. “Today’s hearing is a signal that the 230 reform will likely be on our agenda through next year.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Qcwhty"&gt;&lt;q&gt;House Democrats are more optimistic now than ever in their abilities to clamp down on hate speech &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="36Dq5s"&gt;Rep. Mike Doyle (D-PA) echoed Malinowski’s enthusiasm in an interview with &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2021/12/01/can-congress-unite-section-230-reform-this-top-democrat-has-hope/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post &lt;/em&gt;on Wednesday&lt;/a&gt;. “The fact that this has been discussed and debated and [we’ve] had hearings ad nauseam and Congress has not acted is not acceptable to me,” Doyle said. “So my goal at this hearing is to start moving legislation forward.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZR3jWo"&gt;Wednesday’s hearing paired its high-profile witness, Haugen, with four Democratic proposals to change Section 230. These bills, like Malinowski’s Protecting Americans from Dangerous Algorithms Act, provide more targeted changes to the law than many of the proposals that come before them — mainly in their focus on algorithmic amplification of harmful content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qKMQbB"&gt;“There’s a growing realization that the algorithms are the problem,” Malinowski told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;in an interview on Wednesday. “Through their recommendation algorithms, the social media companies have created a perfect machine for driving people to political extremes and even to violence.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I8oDHO"&gt;Committee leaders, including Doyle and Rep. Frank Pallone (D-NJ), are betting on a bipartisan outrage over algorithms to help them pass moderation reform over the next few months. In his opening remarks, Doyle pointed out that Rep. Cathy McMorris Rodgers (WA), the top Republican on the subcommittee, issued a discussion draft that would remove platform immunity for amplification earlier this year. Without Republican support, any 230 reforms would likely be dead in the water when passed off to the Senate, and its razor thin Democratic majority, for approval. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UKapFS"&gt;“There’s a bipartisan desire to reform the courts’ interpretation of Section 230,” Doyle said on Wednesday. “And the American public wants to see us get things done.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zDlMcj"&gt;Still, some civil rights activists fear that any changes to Section 230, including those targeting algorithmic amplification, could cause more harm than good. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9kLipF"&gt;“We don’t want to chill amplification that is benign or beneficial, but also don’t want to prevent accountability when platforms’ actions cause harm even in the absence of personalized recommendations, or outside of carve-outs for important subjects like civil rights,” Matt Wood, Free Press Action vice president and general counsel, said at Wednesday’s hearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="AF2aFj"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Congress needs to do its due diligence and legislate responsibly. Lives are at stake.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iQf8t6"&gt;Other activists fear Congress may be moving too fast and without properly considering the consequences for vulnerable communities when they last changed the law. After Trump signed SESTA / FOSTA in 2018, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/11/17188772/trump-sesta-fosta-bill-switter-sex-workers-mastodon"&gt;sex workers were forced off websites&lt;/a&gt; like Backpage.com where they screened clients, despite the bill’s stated purpose to combat sex-trafficking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FYOgtM"&gt;“It’s irresponsible and unconscionable for lawmakers to rush toward further changes to Section 230 while actively ignoring human rights experts and the communities that were most impacted by the last major change to Section 230,” said Evan Greer, director of Fight for the Future. “The last misguided legislation that changed Section 230 got people killed. Congress needs to do its due diligence and legislate responsibly. Lives are at stake.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MYRyUk"&gt;The committee plans to hold a second hearing next week as it ramps up its efforts to pass meaningful reforms. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22812719/frances-haugen-congress-section-230-moderation-reform"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22812719/frances-haugen-congress-section-230-moderation-reform</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T16:48:03-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T16:48:03-05:00</updated>
    <title>Jack Dorsey’s Square is changing its name to Block</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gMMz1WsssE0ZT9hIYYMRqVFl6Z8=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70216769/Block_lockup_reverse_black_1920x1080.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Block’s new logo.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Block&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iiP503"&gt;Square, a financial services company co-founded by now-former Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey, is changing its name to Block, the company announced Wednesday. Square has grown beyond just offering financial services — it took a majority stake in the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/4/22313108/square-inc-tidal-majority-stake-jack-dorsey-jay-z"&gt;music streaming service Tidal&lt;/a&gt; this year, for example — which Block is using as the justification for the new name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z5O7iR"&gt;“The change to Block acknowledges the company’s growth,” the company said &lt;a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/52543725/en"&gt;in a press release&lt;/a&gt;. “Since its start in 2009, the company has added Cash App, TIDAL, and TBD54566975 as businesses, and the name change creates room for further growth. Block is an overarching ecosystem of many businesses united by their purpose of economic empowerment, and serves many people—individuals, artists, fans, developers, and sellers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ErY9wW"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Block is &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Square?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Square&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CashApp?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@CashApp&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/spiralbtc?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@spiralbtc&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TIDAL?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@TIDAL&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TBD54566975?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@TBD54566975&lt;/a&gt;, and our foundational teams who support them. We’re here to build simple tools to increase access to the economy. &lt;a href="https://t.co/CkVKxHPkqy"&gt;https://t.co/CkVKxHPkqy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/RMOnxCLP9Y"&gt;pic.twitter.com/RMOnxCLP9Y&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Block (@blocks) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/blocks/status/1466154290137894912?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 1, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0qavbe"&gt;Block says there will be no organizational changes as a result of the new name, though the company’s Square Crypto initiative is being rebranded to Spiral. The new Block name is expected to legally go into effect “on or about” December 10th. Its ticker symbol, SQ, will “not change at this time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZC3NYI"&gt;The changes are being announced just two days after Dorsey, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22617551/jack-dorsey-bitcoin-unite-country-world-peace-cryptocurrency"&gt;a noted Bitcoin enthusiast&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/29/22807651/jack-dorsey-steps-down-twitter-ceo-parag-agrawal-replacement"&gt;resigned as CEO of Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. Previously, he had served as the CEO of both Twitter and Square simultaneously. He remains the CEO of Block.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HY7d5K"&gt;The new Block name arrives just over a month after Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/28/22745234/facebook-new-name-meta-metaverse-zuckerberg-rebrand"&gt;changed its name to Meta&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22812752/square-changing-name-block-jack-dorsey-cash-app-tidal-crypto-spiral"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22812752/square-changing-name-block-jack-dorsey-cash-app-tidal-crypto-spiral</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T16:33:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T16:33:25-05:00</updated>
    <title>Nvidia’s new RTX 2060 12GB graphics card is coming to quell shortages</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8qp0LNsB1xk-mnQHnJ-zAoU1oPA=/0x0:2076x1384/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70216706/rtx_2060_desktop_nvidia.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang unveiling the RTX 2060 graphics card in 2019.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Nvidia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JY8x3p"&gt;In February 2021, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278562/nvidia-rtx-2060-gtx-1050-ti-gpu-shortage-global-chip"&gt;Nvidia committed to reissuing some of its older GPUs&lt;/a&gt; — namely the RTX 2060 and GTX 1050 Ti — to give gamers a couple of low-cost options that scalpers or crypto miners (hopefully) won’t see much use for during the chip shortage. The company is following through on at least part of that promise by releasing a new variant of the RTX 2060 that has 12GB of video RAM, doubling the memory of the standard configuration originally released in 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gQ0yXd"&gt;Nvidia says that various models should become available starting Tuesday, December 7th. The specs for revised Founders Edition GPU are &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-us%2Fgeforce%2Fgraphics-cards%2Frtx-2060%2F%23specs&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F1%2F22812618%2Fnvidia-new-rtx-2060-12gb-vram-graphics-card-gpu-release-date-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available right here&lt;/a&gt;. Note the slightly higher base clock speed and the slightly increased CUDA cores (2,176 versus 1,920 in the standard RTX 2060). Its specs looks similar to the RTX 2060 Super in some ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vayu9e"&gt;Nvidia didn’t share a starting cost for the 12GB RTX 2060 Founders Edition, though it told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that “it is a premium version of the RTX 2060 6GB and we expect the price to reflect that.” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/1/7/18171616/nvidia-rtx-2060-gpu-349-ray-tracing-budget-entry-level-ces-2019"&gt;The RTX 2060 6GB launched in 2019 for $349&lt;/a&gt;. It also shared that OEMs will be making their own custom versions of the 12GB RTX 2060. We’ll update this post once we hear back about pricing info for various models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cRfOsm"&gt;Having this card is great for people who’ve felt the burn of GPU restocks not going their way and who don’t want to give in to paying ridiculously high prices in the secondary market for cards that shouldn’t cost that much in the first place. The RTX 2060 won’t be great for running games with ray-traced graphics (despite it being capable of the feature), but with its power, most games should run well on medium graphical settings at 1080p resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="nH5bSF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The true price of a PS5 or GPU, November 2021 edition","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22797788/price-ps5-xbox-nvidia-amd-rtx-gpu-scalpers-ebay-update"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="KeI0FG"&gt;The PC market is one of many areas that has felt the sting of the chip shortage, spurred by the global pandemic. Things like graphics cards and consoles are still in high demand, despite no longer being new to market. And with many of the RTX 30-series GPUs already costing a premium at retail, it has become tough to buy what you want, and to do so at a normal price. Many retailers are zeroed out of stock completely, and bots and eagle-eyed shoppers (most of whom hope to flip the products for a profit) will likely beat you to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ButCo0"&gt;I’m skeptical that Nvidia releasing one entry-level (at this point) GPU can help to reverse the tide of the price-surged secondary market. But I’m definitely happy that it’s trying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yUEU0n"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22812618/nvidia-new-rtx-2060-12gb-vram-graphics-card-gpu-release-date-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22812618/nvidia-new-rtx-2060-12gb-vram-graphics-card-gpu-release-date-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T16:29:42-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T16:29:42-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple Music’s terrible year in review is giving me serious Spotify Wrapped FOMO</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vxXlbpT5wvDkYX9-p0DnxQGOA20=/160x0:1888x1152/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70216672/PR_2021_TopArtist_B_1_2048x1152.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EO66Nl"&gt;It’s December 1st, which for Spotify users, means the annual tradition of the music &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811900/spotify-wrapped-2021-music-recap-iphone-android%5D"&gt;streaming service’s Spotify Wrapped roundup&lt;/a&gt;: customized, flashy infographics of the top songs, playlists, artists, and podcast that you’ve listened to over the last year, chock-full of data, mood boards, and just a sprinkling of judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VswuKS"&gt;I, unfortunately, do not use Spotify. Instead, I pay Apple $10 per month for Apple Music, Spotify’s biggest competitor. And so while virtually everyone I know on Twitter and Instagram is spending the entirety of today putting their personal taste in music on blast, I get... a playlist of the songs that I listened to the most this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="WEfbNO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Spotify Wrapped 2021 is here to take over your social media","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811900/spotify-wrapped-2021-music-recap-iphone-android"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/86vZG15pgepbcvNaYWnWuNc_pyw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055670/Screen_Shot_2021_12_01_at_11.20.54_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is fine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pnZduy"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/5/20997218/spotify-wrapped-year-end-decade-review-apple-music-streaming-audio-service"&gt;Spotify has been eating Apple’s lunch&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;em&gt;years&lt;/em&gt; now with Wrapped, which has practically become its own internet holiday each year. And yet, it took Apple four full years to even launch its bare-bones Replay feature, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/13/20963520/apple-music-replay-listening-history-view-share-albums-songs"&gt;which debuted in 2019&lt;/a&gt; and hasn’t been meaningfully updated since. (I’ve been using kludged together Smart Playlists on iTunes for years to try to poorly replicate the Spotify experience.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="l76p7F"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Spotify beats Apple at its own game with its Wrapped year in review feature","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/5/20997218/spotify-wrapped-year-end-decade-review-apple-music-streaming-audio-service"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="t3X0QJ"&gt;2021 is no exception, with Spotify offering what feels like its most lavish recaps yet. My wife (who is a Spotify user) spent the morning showing off her bespoke playlist to me, which included (among other things) specially curated songs for specific moods, rankings of where she placed among global Doja Cat listeners, a color-changing “audio aura,” and an interactive quiz. All of it is designed to be shared and shown off on other social media platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OALJLqwI2guTQOxG3P5H6-lbCVw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23055820/jepg.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;My wife’s far cooler Spotify Wrapped recap.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="v1QqJA"&gt;And it’s not just music listeners, either. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/doddleoddle/status/1466096651869863966"&gt;Artists seem&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AVABandOfficial/status/1466085854925836290"&gt;love Spotify Wrapped, too&lt;/a&gt;, with their own customized recaps showing off how many millions of times their fans streamed their music around the globe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XoJRg6"&gt;It’s not that Apple Music couldn’t do its own version of Wrapped; Apple certainly has the data, and I find it extremely hard to believe that the $2.79 trillion company can’t find the space in its budget to task a team of designers and engineers into building a similar tool. Or maybe it could try to buy Last.fm, which already does a whole bunch of music trends based on customers’ listening habits, if it wanted to offload some of that work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="opMASI"&gt;And there are plenty of reasons for Apple to do exactly that &lt;em&gt;besides&lt;/em&gt; my annual dose of social media FOMO: Apple has made no secret of its ambitions for recurring service revenue to serve as a key part of its future going forward. And yet, instead of jumping on the easy marketing win and massive user goodwill that a more robust replay feature could offer, year after year after year, Apple just chooses to do the absolute bare minimum. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="7Tmtzi"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Ah yes, Spotify Wrapped day, or as I like to think of it “punishment for being an Apple Music user while everyone else gets to have fun with their music recaps” day.&lt;/p&gt;— Chaim Gartenberg (@cgartenberg) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cgartenberg/status/1466073033462923267?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 1, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="w2OUY0"&gt;Look at it another way: Spotify, every year, manages to get millions of people to spend days posting algorithmically generated Spotify advertisements to every corner of their social media presences, without even offering any free giveaways or incentives. Why &lt;em&gt;wouldn’t&lt;/em&gt; Apple Music be trying to get a piece of that action?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="EFxX8U"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Since I'm an Apple Music user, you please just imagine my Spotify Wrapped to be whatever artists you think cool people listen to&lt;/p&gt;— Monica Chin (@mcsquared96) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mcsquared96/status/1466080039070539780?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 1, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uwoUym"&gt;It’s not even like Apple has to worry about angering Spotify by shamelessly ripping off one of its most popular features: Spotify &lt;em&gt;already&lt;/em&gt; thinks &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22457400/spotify-horacio-gutierrez-apple-app-store-interview-decoder"&gt;Apple is a “ruthless bully”&lt;/a&gt; that monopolizes the App Store to favor its own services and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/13/18263453/spotify-apple-app-store-antitrust-complaint-ec-30-percent-cut-unfair"&gt;has filed an antitrust complaint in the EU&lt;/a&gt; to that end. It’s not like there’s a good, healthy corporate relationship to ruin here. If Instagram could shamelessly copy stories from Snapchat, Apple can figure out how to replicate its own version of Wrapped. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eKvUUn"&gt;In fact, it’s increasingly surprising year after year that seemingly no one is copying Spotify’s absurdly popular data visualizations. With a few exceptions like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22798429/xbox-museum-20th-anniversary-stats-achievements"&gt;Microsoft’s recent 20th anniversary Xbox retrospective&lt;/a&gt;, there are still virtually no takers on following Spotify’s lead here. Where’s Netflix’s flashy look back at the shows you binged over the year, or PlayStation’s deep dive into how many hours you spent trying to beat Pride and Joy Prototype in &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/em&gt;? The closest comparison I can think of is Goodreads’ “Your Year In Books,” which also functions more as a straight list than the comprehensive experience that Spotify has created here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="liJQX9"&gt;But for now, I’m once again spending December filled with envy as my Spotify-using friends get to show off all their favorite songs, left hoping with increasingly futile optimism that maybe Apple Music will figure things out next. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22812079/apple-music-year-in-review-spotify-wrapped-social-media"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22812079/apple-music-year-in-review-spotify-wrapped-social-media</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T16:02:34-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T16:02:34-05:00</updated>
    <title>HMD Global backs out of Nokia 9 PureView Android 11 upgrade, blames camera system</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Nokia 9 PureView" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OgDw6J8vmWJnNazmzV-cxiM1vRg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70216530/bfarsace_190210_3229_0005.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nokia 9 PureView was launched in 2019 with a rare five-camera system.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tcIFwQ"&gt;HMD Global is not only reneging on its promise to bring Android 11 to the Nokia 9 PureView, but it is also dangling a discount for a new phone at customers who just found out their current devices are no longer supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RboZRa"&gt;These are customers who paid between $599 and $699 for the premium Nokia 9 PureView back in 2019 after it made quite a splash with its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/2/24/18234962/nokia-9-pureview-cameras-5-features-specs-multiple-price-release-date-photos-hands-on-mwc-2019"&gt;quintuple rear camera array at World Mobile Congress&lt;/a&gt; that year. At the time, Nokia was even known as the best phone brand for receiving fast software updates, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/2/20844444/android-updates-still-take-forever-study-says"&gt;according to Counterpoint Research&lt;/a&gt;, so customers understandably might have felt they could trust Nokia and HMD Global. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HD1C0N"&gt;As one of the devices in the &lt;a href="https://www.android.com/intl/en_in/one/"&gt;Android One program&lt;/a&gt;, the Nokia 9 PureView runs a near-stock version of Android 9 and is supposed to get at least two years of OS upgrades and three years of security updates. Although the phone got upgraded to Android 10 in December 2019, it has not received any other OS updates since. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EHL5As"&gt;HMD Global said it is unable to update the Nokia 9 PureView with Android 11 because “[i]ncompatibilities between the camera and the software would have led to a compromised experience that does not meet our high standards,“ &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nokia.com%2Fphones%2Fen_us%2Fnokia-9-upgrade&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F1%2F22811988%2Fhmd-global-nokia-9-pureview-android-11-software" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;according to its statement&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps because its quintuple cameras were co-developed with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/12/21289574/light-camera-company-exits-smartphone-business"&gt;Light, the camera company that has quit smartphone photography&lt;/a&gt;, HMD Global just cannot overcome this technical challenge. That said, the company said the phone will continue to receive security updates.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uImLeyLTb-iHesU6EO6GZjGjQEs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/14130617/bfarsace_190213_3229_0067.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;HMD blames the 9 PureView’s unique camera array for being unable to update it to Android 11&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="iGvNKt"&gt;Rather than let current owners trade in their now-unsupported devices, HMD Global comes across as trying to profit on those affected customers by asking them to buy a new Nokia phone. “[F]or those of you looking to make the jump to Android 11,” &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nokia.com%2Fphones%2Fen_us%2Fnokia-9-upgrade&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F1%2F22811988%2Fhmd-global-nokia-9-pureview-android-11-software" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;according to its website for Nokia 9 PureView owners&lt;/a&gt;, “we’re offering a 50% discount on Nokia XR20, or another device depending on regional availability.” First of all, the midrange &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nokia.com%2Fphones%2Fen_us%2Fnokia-xr-20%3Fsku%3DVMA750D9FI1CN0&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F1%2F22811988%2Fhmd-global-nokia-9-pureview-android-11-software" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nokia XR 20&lt;/a&gt; is hardly a substitute for the premium Nokia 9 PureView, and you need to jump through some hoops just to get that discount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VE7U5O"&gt;At a time when Android phone makers are trying to differentiate themselves by modeling after Apple’s four-year-plus software support for iPhones, cases like HMD Global backpedaling on the Nokia 9 PureView’s update just remind us not to take these promises too seriously. Bigger companies like Samsung might have more resources to deliver on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295639/samsung-galaxy-device-2019-four-years-security-updates"&gt;four years of security updates&lt;/a&gt; for its huge portfolio of devices, but smaller outfits like HMD Global and &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/motorola-software-updates-rant/"&gt;Motorola just don’t have a good track record&lt;/a&gt;. While software support is something to consider when making a phone buying decision — especially when we’re holding onto our phones longer between upgrade cycles — it should not be &lt;em&gt;the &lt;/em&gt;deciding factor for an Android because it just might not happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YwO2fv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pmzOZe"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811988/hmd-global-nokia-9-pureview-android-11-software"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22811988/hmd-global-nokia-9-pureview-android-11-software</id>
    <author>
      <name>Gloria Sin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-01T15:54:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-01T15:54:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook removes block on searches for Kyle Rittenhouse</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Kyle Rittenhouse Found Not Guilty In Kenosha Protest Shootings" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KZBa8z29Tc5k-QA_UoOUdR408lQ=/187x0:5103x3277/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70216479/1236665464.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Kyle Rittenhouse can rejoin Facebook if he wants, after being acquitted of murder charges in November. | Photo by Sean Krajacic - Pool/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lWnTO7"&gt;Facebook on Wednesday removed a block on searches for the name Kyle Rittenhouse that it had put into place following his arrest for an August 2020 shooting in Wisconsin that left two people dead and a third seriously injured. Last month, a jury in Kenosha acquitted Rittenhouse on all charges. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OUH9SW"&gt;In the days following the shooting, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/27/21404518/facebook-search-kyle-rittenhouse-blocked-kenosha-shooting"&gt;the company removed Rittenhouse’s profile&lt;/a&gt; from Facebook and Instagram and blocked users from creating new profiles using his name, to prevent copycats from spreading misinformation. By the end of that week, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/27/21404518/facebook-search-kyle-rittenhouse-blocked-kenosha-shooting"&gt;Facebook was blocking searches for “Kyle Rittenhouse&lt;/a&gt;,” as well as removing expressions of praise or support for him on the platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qE1uhZ"&gt;“After the verdict in Kenosha we rolled back the restrictions we had in place that limited search results from returning content related to key terms including Kyle Rittenhouse,” Sally Aldous, spokesperson for Facebook parent company Meta, said in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge. &lt;/em&gt;“While we will still remove content that celebrates the death of the individuals killed in Kenosha, we will no longer remove content containing praise or support of Rittenhouse.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Kr9P6k"&gt;The changes were rolled out in the days following the verdict, Aldous said. “Given the granularity of these policies as well as the wide public interest in these events, we anticipate enforcement at scale will be especially challenging,” she said, adding that Rittenhouse himself does not currently have any accounts on Meta’s platforms — which include Facebook and Instagram — but in theory he would now be able to rejoin them. Like all users, however, he would be subject to the company’s community standards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aCoNQf"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="otg4Bf"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XQyMz1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yFNEhb"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22782911/rittenhouse-verdict-policy-facebook-praise-block-page"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/1/22782911/rittenhouse-verdict-policy-facebook-praise-block-page</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
