<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-07T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-07T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-07T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Alienware’s M15 R5 is its first AMD-based gaming laptop in over a decade</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-UH-XwL5q9IIRfdfYs7u7uamLjY=/0x0:2160x1440/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69088309/alienwarem15r5lede.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RcZ5Tu"&gt;Alienware has announced the latest revision to its flagship gaming laptop lineup, the 15-inch Alienware M15 R5. It’ll start shipping on April 20th in the US, costing $2,229.99 to start. The company is going big with its messaging that it’ll host AMD’s fast Ryzen 5000 H-series processors (up to the octa-core Ryzen 9 5900HX) and up to Nvidia’s RTX 3070 graphics chip. Dell says this is the first Alienware laptop since 2007 to feature an AMD processor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GG4Xam"&gt;In case you haven’t noticed, AMD’s processors have been on a tear in the past year, delivering great performance without compromising on efficiency when you aren’t gaming. This is just the latest company to join along the likes of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321471/asus-rog-zephyrus-g15-gaming-laptop-review"&gt;Asus&lt;/a&gt;, Lenovo, and even Dell with its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21328344/dell-g5-15-se-review-2020-gaming-laptop-amd-ryzen"&gt;G5 15 SE&lt;/a&gt;, to name a few. AMD-touting laptops are already among some of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22295181/best-gaming-laptop"&gt;best gaming laptops you can buy&lt;/a&gt;. Yet Alienware is possibly the most well-known gaming brand to go AMD yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="q0sGxs"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Big boost clocks&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SV1J9c"&gt;The base configuration of the M15 R5 has the octa-core Ryzen 7 5800H processor and Nvidia’s RTX 3060. You can upgrade to the Ryzen 9 5900HX octa-core processor and the RTX 3070. Both the RTX 3060 and 3070 have a total graphics power level of 115W with 10W of extra boost available for up to 125W of maximum graphics power. Interestingly, the 3060 has a higher base and boost clock (base: 1,387MHz, boost: 1,702MHz) than the 3070 option does (base: 1,110MHz, boost: 1,560MHz). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r1JWLj"&gt;Either way, these are some of the highest clock speeds we’ve seen yet in a reasonably thin 2021 gaming laptop. Alienware is pushing the boost clocks nearly all the way to the ceiling, and it’s great that it’s transparent about these power specs, since &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22266921/nvidia-requiring-companies-share-clock-speed-power-gaming-laptop-rtx-30-series-gpu-specs"&gt;Nvidia now requires that manufacturers share it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Alienware M15 R5" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dfMrwvr3yTE2o6ne4aOc9aiYSo8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22425146/m15r5tilt.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Ryzen Edition will ship in this silver configuration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="vycfFh"&gt;Speaking of dimensions, the R5 is thicker and heavier than the previous R4 generation. The base configuration weighs 5.34 pounds (up to 5.93 pounds, depending on the components inside). The R4’s base configuration weighed 4.65 pounds, for comparison. The R5 is 19.25mm thick at its front (up to 22.85mm thick near the hinge), 272.5mm deep, and 356mm wide. Each configuration will ship with an 86Wh battery, like what shipped in the M15 R4 and R3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BPCP0y"&gt;Screen-wise, the R5 can be configured with a range of high-refresh-rate displays. The base FHD screen has a 3ms response time screen with a 165Hz refresh rate, and your options for upgrading are either a dimmer 300-nit 1080p panel with a faster 360Hz refresh rate, 1ms response time, and only 100 percent sRGB color coverage, or a brighter 400-nit QHD screen that has a 240Hz refresh rate, 1ms response time, 100 percent DCI-P3 color gamut, plus G-Sync, which should deliver the smoothest experience even if your framerate dips. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Alienware M15 R5" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/u8ZNx3elRaRztqbZyTWPlgJOUXg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22421558/m15r5inpost.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The M15 R5 looks similar to the previous two generations.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Y6X0UV"&gt;If you want to output to a separate display, the laptop’s HDMI 2.1 port means it can display up to 120 frames per second at 4K resolution if your monitor (or TV) supports it. This laptop also features an 2.5Gbps Ethernet port, two USB-A 3.2 Gen 1 ports, one USB-A 3.2 Gen 2, one USB-C 3.2 Gen 2 port, and a headphone jack. There’s no Thunderbolt port, but that Intel technology might find its way into an Intel-based version later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KIr2w0"&gt;Dell says this is the first Alienware laptop to feature fast 3,200MHz DDR4 RAM, and it’s also user-configurable with two SO-DIMM slots. This is a move in the right direction, as the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21459895/alienware-m15-r3-gaming-laptop-review-intel-rtx-nvidia-15-inch"&gt;M15 R3&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://hothardware.com/reviews/alienware-m15-r4-review"&gt;R4&lt;/a&gt; both had their RAM soldered onto the board, making it impossible to upgrade after you bought it. There are two M.2 slots inside so you can upgrade storage post-purchase, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oic6c0"&gt;The company says the laptop’s paint has been engineered for “increased stain-resistance and premium surface feel.” This model can be configured to feature Cherry’s Ultra-Low Profile mechanical switches. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22333684/alienware-m15-m17-gaming-laptops-cherry-mx-ultra-low-mechanical-keyboard-switches-price"&gt;Dell announced this keyboard collaboration for the M15 R4&lt;/a&gt;, and it’ll be available as a $150 add-on for this new model, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wwEDy5"&gt;If you’re looking for a more budget-friendly gaming laptop with a new Ryzen 5000 H-series processor, check out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22132051"&gt;Dell’s $899 G15 that was also just announced&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22367807/alienware-m15-r5-15-inch-gaming-laptop-amd-ryzen-edition-specs-features-price-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22367807/alienware-m15-r5-15-inch-gaming-laptop-amd-ryzen-edition-specs-features-price-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-07T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-07T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Dell’s speckled G15 brings high-end AMD Ryzen processors to value-minded gamers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Dell G15 Ryzen Edition" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IlncbVhgpTl5ELQw8owsn-rw1cs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69088327/g15lineup.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Budget-friendly gaming laptops are looking better than ever&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WfNhlU"&gt;Alongside the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22131848"&gt;Alienware M15 R5 Ryzen Edition&lt;/a&gt;, Dell is also launching a more affordable 15-inch Dell G15 Ryzen Edition gaming laptop. It’s for people who still want to experience AMD’s fast Ryzen 5000 H-series processors, along with an Nvidia RTX 3060 graphics chip, but for less. If the M15 R5’s $2,229.99 starting price is too high, the G15’s $899.99 entry-level configuration might be a more reasonable price point for you to jump in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f1czH6"&gt;The G15’s speckled design might look familiar to you. That’s because Dell actually launched the Intel-based version of this model already, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319292/dell-g15-gaming-laptop-2021-announced-china-paint-speckles-specs"&gt;but in China first&lt;/a&gt;. This new Ryzen-based laptop is landing first in China as well, on April 30th, followed by a May 4th release elsewhere around the globe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Dw7cHg"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There’s an Intel version, too, but it’s running last-gen chips&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FRKvJz"&gt;The starting configuration of the G15 Ryzen Edition will be fairly barebones in terms of RAM and storage, shipping with 8GB of 3,200MHz DDR4 RAM, and 256GB of NVMe M.2 capacity. It packs plenty of power otherwise for a $900 laptop, with a Ryzen 5 5600H hexa-core processor and an Nvidia RTX 3060 with 6GB of VRAM. In case you want something more powerful, the CPU be tweaked up to the Ryzen 7 5800H octa-core CPU, RAM can be added (either through Dell or by opening the laptop yourself), and you can configure it with up to 2TB of solid-state storage. The more powerful processor can also come with a bigger six-cell 86Wh battery, though you’ll get a three-cell 56Wh pack at the $900 mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GJfDip"&gt;At launch, the G15 can also be configured with a 120Hz refresh rate FHD panel at a fairly standard 250 nits of brightness, or a brighter 300-nit screen with a faster 165Hz refresh rate. Dell says a 360Hz refresh rate screen will be available later in the spring. Dell says the new G15 has adopted an “Alienware-inspired” thermal design to keep it running efficiently, and it certainly looks the part. It’ll come in at least two speckled colors at launch, a green and a grey. Later this year, an all-black model will be available.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Dell G15" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eDa_LwrJ4rKWAvkVlxxAn-aydXM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22422232/g15ryzenlede.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The G15 takes some cues from Alienware’s M15 series of much pricier gaming laptops.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dbdemy"&gt;This laptop ships by default with non-backlit, spill-resistant keyboard, but there are some upgrades you can make here. The first step up adds orange backlighting beneath the entire keyboard and emphasizes WASD. If orange doesn’t do it for you, there’s a four-zone RGB backlit keyboard that you can customize for a more colorful presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wb4zdQ"&gt;If the Ryzen Edition G15 is anything like last year’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21328344/dell-g5-15-se-review-2020-gaming-laptop-amd-ryzen"&gt;G5 15 SE&lt;/a&gt; in terms of performance, I’m excited to test it out. Assuming that it does, even the lower-end model should be reasonably powerful for people trying to stretch their dollar as far as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cAhgPX"&gt;If you really want the Intel version, Dell says a variant of it will launch in the US on April 13th for $799.99, but it’ll feature a last-gen 10th Gen Intel processor. Dell included this bit of information practically as a footnote, to give you an idea of how much emphasis it’s putting behind Ryzen this time around. The starting model features a Core i5-10200H quad-core CPU with Nvidia’s GeForce GTX 1650 graphics chip. Upgrading can net you the vastly more powerful Core i7-10870H octa-core CPU with the RTX 3060, and you can get Thunderbolt ports. Dell didn’t share the price for the high-end Intel model.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22368010/dell-g15-amd-ryzen-edition-15-inch-gaming-laptop-release-date-price-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22368010/dell-g15-amd-ryzen-edition-15-inch-gaming-laptop-release-date-price-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-07T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-07T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Dell’s new gaming monitors support variable refresh rate for consoles, not just PC</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Dell 34-inch gaming monitor" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OmjYOONQ7N0xGIb4UlnUe9msbPs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69088306/dell34inchcurved.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dell’s new 34-inch curved screen is a behemoth.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="cpImm2"&gt;Dell has announced four gaming monitors, three of which are curved, that are releasing in the US between late May and late June. It unfortunately isn’t sharing prices for them yet, but the company says that all of them support AMD FreeSync Premium or Premium Pro, as well as variable refresh rate (VRR). VRR should make them as good of a fit for consoles like the Xbox Series X and PS5 (though the latter console hasn’t actually received its promised VRR update yet). This feature limits screen tearing as the frame rate adjusts due to hits or gains to performance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cI02fV"&gt;Starting off big, the company has a new 34-inch ultrawide, curved gaming monitor (pictured above, model S3422DWG) that has a 1800R curve, which won’t envelop your peripheral vision as much as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21590961/samsung-odyssey-g9-review-ultrawide-monitor-price-specs"&gt;Samsung’s extra-curvy 1000R Odyssey G9 monitor&lt;/a&gt;. This model will release first in China on May 7th, then North America on May 27th, and finally on June 22nd in Asia-Pacific regions. It has a WQHD (3440 x 1440) resolution, VA display with a 144Hz refresh rate. Dell touts that it has DisplayHDR 400, though &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2017/12/12/16767160/vesa-displayhdr-specification-screen-monitor-hdr10-400-600-1000-standard"&gt;that’s not the spec you should be looking for to provide a bright, vibrant HDR image&lt;/a&gt;. This one supports 90 percent of the DCI-P3 color range.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Dell 32-inch curved gaming monitor" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HwMiNdw-HrNj675sCtsViYeyKUQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22424421/dell32inchcurved.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s the 32-inch curved screen Dell will release on June 22nd.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="L61OJ2"&gt;Dell’s also making a 32-inch curved QHD gaming monitor (model S3222DGM) that has a VA panel with a 165Hz refresh rate and a 2ms response time. It’s making a 27-inch version (model S2722DGM) that has the same specs, except it’s actually slightly more curved at 1500R than the 1800R 32-inch model. These will both release in China on May 7th, and availability will open up globally on June 22nd.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Dell gaming monitor" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ltA_hAVt9aGP4TyeGJ47d0jJv8Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22424427/dell25inchgamingmonitor.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dell’s 24.5-inch monitor seems like an awesome choice, but we don’t know the price.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="N1Fchk"&gt;It might look similar to the last image above, but the fourth monitor being announced today might especially appeal to people who have an Nvidia graphics card. It’s a non-curved 24.5-inch FHD gaming monitor (model S2522HG) with an IPS panel with G-Sync compatibility in addition to FreeSync Premium. It has a 240Hz refresh rate and a 1ms response time. This one will release in China on May 7th, and it’ll be available in other regions on May 27th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aU2OmM"&gt;As usual, each of Dell’s new monitors have have stands that offer a full range of motion, including height, pivot, swivel, and tilt adjustments.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22369872/dell-gaming-monitor-curved-vrr-variable-refresh-rate-gsync-freesync"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22369872/dell-gaming-monitor-curved-vrr-variable-refresh-rate-gsync-freesync</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-07T07:11:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-07T07:11:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>The long-lost Lord of the Rings adaptation from Soviet Russia is a glorious fever dream</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cvphTEtltYqwNFik-wI3GM6fJ_0=/0x69:1370x982/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69087955/Screen_Shot_2021_04_07_at_11.14.22_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 1991 made-for-TV film features glorious low budget special effects and shonky costumes. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1F3Fm5"&gt;You may think you’re familiar with &lt;em&gt;The Lord of the Rings, &lt;/em&gt;but nothing can quite prepare you for an adaptation of J.R.R. Tolkien’s classic fantasy text made in the Soviet Union. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EARurJ"&gt;The made-for-TV film first aired on Leningrad Television in 1991 and was thought to be lost to time, as first reported by &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/apr/05/soviet-tv-version-lord-of-the-rings-rediscovered-after-30-years"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. But the station’s successor, 5TV, recently unearthed a copy from its archives, and uploaded the entire work to YouTube in &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vquKyNdgH3s&amp;amp;ab_channel=%D0%9F%D1%8F%D1%82%D1%8B%D0%B9%D0%BA%D0%B0%D0%BD%D0%B0%D0%BB%D0%A0%D0%BE%D1%81%D1%81%D0%B8%D1%8F"&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oLevCLNnLmg&amp;amp;ab_channel=%D0%9F%D1%8F%D1%82%D1%8B%D0%B9%D0%BA%D0%B0%D0%BD%D0%B0%D0%BB%D0%A0%D0%BE%D1%81%D1%81%D0%B8%D1%8F"&gt;parts&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="yhXZVZ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Low budget special effects and Soviet mood music&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bZOBUu"&gt;With a running time of around 1 hour and 50 minutes, this adaptation focuses only on the first book of Tolkein’s trilogy, &lt;em&gt;The Fellowship of the Ring&lt;/em&gt;, and is a riot of low-budget special effects, bizarre camera work, and Soviet mood music. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7dch2c"&gt;Rather than the epic Hollywood fantasy captured so well by Peter Jackson, this adaptation feels like a weird fairy tale told by a pipe-smoking madman in the woods. In other words: it captures a completely legitimate aspect of &lt;em&gt;The Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt;, just not one we’re necessarily used to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T62CET"&gt;If you’ve not got time to watch the whole thing, here are a few choice moments, as helpfully identified and time-stamped by YouTube user Chris Staecker in &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vquKyNdgH3s&amp;amp;lc=Ugy0nG5qmlHawj74T2N4AaABAg"&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oLevCLNnLmg&amp;amp;lc=UgyBqlAITgmcRGCkKcJ4AaABAg"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="K4D1QX"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/vquKyNdgH3s"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The opening sequence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Featuring music composed by Andrei Romanov of Russian rock group Akvarium, an incredibly bleary shot of the One Ring, and snippets of the Nazgûl riding through the snow.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y8ZDufERZcPjXdnhGY3BoAhujvQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22426320/Screen_Shot_2021_04_07_at_11.10.43_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="mdInJL"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/vquKyNdgH3s?t=439"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gandalf’s arrival at Bilbo’s birthday party and a fireworks display&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Look, when we said the special effects weren’t up to much, we meant it. Gandalf is missing his familiar staff and wizard’s hat, but otherwise looks perfectly wise and / or smug. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2sYHxAkPIPgDA9eqgBF9mTOz0p0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22426321/Screen_Shot_2021_04_07_at_11.12.08_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="TvAt26"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/vquKyNdgH3s?t=1272"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sméagol fights Déagol, claims the One Ring and turns into Gollum&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;. &lt;/strong&gt;For the Soviet adaptation there’s none of that “slow transformation into a hideous shadow of his former self” for Sméagol. Nope: he puts on the ring and suddenly he’s mister green skin sneaky hands. And why exactly is the chorus going “rrrrrrr” over and over in the background? That, my friend, is a little thing called ambience. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fKj3q7zMgSgB9OC7o_DurHUYudk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22426322/Screen_Shot_2021_04_07_at_11.14.22_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="U6EGjP"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/vquKyNdgH3s?t=2127"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The hobbits set out on their adventure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. If this bit looks like behind the scenes footage from a 1990s theater troupe that’s because it is. Where did the sleigh come from? Why is that one hobbit arguing with a mouthful of food? Who gives a damn. Skip forward also to see them trapped in the Old Forest. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UHBQNZEbKSelrky6ENvU5JD27iI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22426324/Screen_Shot_2021_04_07_at_11.19.15_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="TiZvcR"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/vquKyNdgH3s?t=2509"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s old Tom Bombadil, that merry fellow!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Here he is: one of the oddest of Tolkien’s characters, a mysterious figure &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/mw9uKzy4GRs"&gt;who might be god&lt;/a&gt;, and who was left out of Peter Jackson’s adaptation for being extraneous to the plot. He can certainly be removed from the story without much damage but it’s still a joy to see him here with his wife Goldberry. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gDRtZ-GVJVlO-uk1gjM8COpG7ew=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22426325/Screen_Shot_2021_04_07_at_11.22.16_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="GBQXKO"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/oLevCLNnLmg?t=700"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frodo meets Aragorn at The Prancing Pony&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. As Staecker notes, the creators have, by this point, given up on trying to make the hobbits look smaller than the other characters. Soviet Aragorn has decidedly less sexy mystique than Viggo Mortensen, but really who doesn’t. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2xkVJcpZhZXT02Skon2rqEU53Fc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22426327/Screen_Shot_2021_04_07_at_11.26.45_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="bW4CAr"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/oLevCLNnLmg?t=1586"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The council of Elrond&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It feels more like a scene from one of Shakespeare’s history plays than the lush elegance of Jackson’s Rivendell but it does the job. Skip forward to see Saruman warn Gandalf of the coming &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/oLevCLNnLmg?t=1960"&gt;orc army&lt;/a&gt;, beautifully rendered as little dudes in horned helmets swiping at nothing at the bottom of the screen.  &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OdHc_tAJln_g1J-4VEIukkzRifg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22426331/Screen_Shot_2021_04_07_at_11.31.22_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="Pztk7m"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/oLevCLNnLmg?t=2061"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gandalf makes his escape with the help of the eagles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;. &lt;/strong&gt;Could they have picked a less bug-eyed bird toy to depict the eagle? Maybe. But why don’t &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; go make an adaptation of &lt;em&gt;The Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt; with a budget of $50 and see if you can do any better. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZzUBy1nRy43LQuZ11s9LBu8ILbU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22426334/Screen_Shot_2021_04_07_at_11.34.18_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="TDViC4"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/oLevCLNnLmg?t=2510"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Battling orcs in Moria&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Orcs here are less monstrous creatures and more just “some dudes I guess.” What’s lacking in special effects is more than made up for with shaky camera work. Skip forward to see them traversing The Bridge of Khazad-dûm, and Gandalf is dead I guess?? &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r2mkW-7dvBW2OjI-D0UlW47r7wE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22426336/Screen_Shot_2021_04_07_at_11.36.07_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="yb01oh"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/oLevCLNnLmg?t=2865"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enter Galadriel and the magic ... of dance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;. &lt;/strong&gt;This is pretty much how I remember this scene from the books. Elves are immortal and live forever in weird enclaves. That means you’re basically a cult. The hobbits, meanwhile, are stunned by how good they are at dancing and then get drugged. Skip forward a few minutes and you can see Galadriel &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/oLevCLNnLmg?t=3363"&gt;get tempted by the One Ring&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/583HagW_ywQBD-pHuRlm1AfJYnM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22426338/Screen_Shot_2021_04_07_at_11.40.14_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="LRp11R"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/oLevCLNnLmg?t=3527"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frodo breaks an apple in two with his hands!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;No, I know this scene is otherwise a bit boring and is mainly about Boromir getting weird and clingy but the apple thing is still cool. Have you ever tried to do this? It’s damn hard. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XhbiySGB_uwWzY2RWcjHv98bkIo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22426341/Screen_Shot_2021_04_07_at_11.45.11_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="kx22nd"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/oLevCLNnLmg?t=3749"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frodo and Sam are doing it for themselves&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;. &lt;/strong&gt;Everyone else is corrupted by power: only friendship remains! I absolutely love the ending here, particularly the music choice. This is really what &lt;em&gt;The Lord of the Rings &lt;/em&gt;is about at heart: just guys being dudes. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kCTjr6NcDTJBY_ojn7_1ajzoiW0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22426344/Screen_Shot_2021_04_07_at_11.47.29_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="YwGGtE"&gt;And that’s it! What’s really amazing to consider is that this adaptation also aired only a decade before the first of Peter Jackson’s blockbuster trilogy. If only the Soviet Union had survived a little longer we could have seen similar renditions of &lt;em&gt;The Two Towers&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Return of the King&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/4/7/22371380/soviet-era-lord-of-the-rings-tv-adaptation-low-budget-delight"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/4/7/22371380/soviet-era-lord-of-the-rings-tv-adaptation-low-budget-delight</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-07T06:48:45-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-07T06:48:45-04:00</updated>
    <title>DJI Air 2S with improved camera sensor leaks in new images</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8d9XsqAjICobP5yxh3rh3wjJcVk=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69087883/EyWpLsQXEAAQEYJ.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Air 2S appears to have dropped DJI’s “Mavic” branding.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/rquandt/status/1379694956030394374" target="_blank"&gt;Roland Quandt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4JcNsV"&gt;DJI’s unannounced Air 2S drone has leaked in a series of images &lt;a href="https://www.techniknews.net/news/dji-air-2s-drohne-alle-informationen-zur-neuen-drohne-exklusiv/"&gt;posted by &lt;em&gt;TechnikNews&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rquandt/status/1379694956030394374"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WinFuture&lt;/em&gt;’s Roland Quandt&lt;/a&gt;. The images come after the drone &lt;a href="https://dronedj.com/2021/03/15/dji-air-2s-hits-the-fcc-an-upgraded-dji-mavic-air-2/"&gt;was listed in an FCC filing last month&lt;/a&gt;, suggesting that a launch can’t be far away. The DJI Air 2S is expected to be an upgraded version of last year’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21243887/dji-mavic-air-2-2020-drone-flight-photography-video-review-price-specs-features"&gt;Mavic Air 2&lt;/a&gt;, with an improved camera and compatibility with new DJI accessories like its &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.dji.com%2Fproduct%2Fdji-fpv-goggles-v2&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F7%2F22371404%2Fdji-air-2s-photo-leak-news-rumors-features-specs-upgraded-camera-mavic" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;V2 Goggles&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.dji.com%2Fproduct%2Fdji-motion-controller&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F7%2F22371404%2Fdji-air-2s-photo-leak-news-rumors-features-specs-upgraded-camera-mavic" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Motion Controller&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4xnELX"&gt;Let’s start with the camera sensor. The new renders, as well as a teaser trailer shared earlier in the week by reliable leaker OsitaLV, show a drone with a 1-inch, 20-megapixel sensor. Although that’s lower resolution than the 48-megapixel 1/2-inch sensor found in the Mavic Air 2, its larger physical size should have big performance benefits, especially in low light. The sensor has similar specs to what we saw in the &lt;a href="http://v"&gt;Mavic 2 Pro&lt;/a&gt;, which offered excellent image quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="O3EJAW"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="und" dir="ltr"&gt;so？ &lt;a href="https://t.co/VtbHXoXDIx"&gt;pic.twitter.com/VtbHXoXDIx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— OsitaLV (@OsitaLV) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OsitaLV/status/1379049739115622402?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 5, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8fhsOP"&gt;If &lt;a href="https://dronedj.com/guides/dji-air-2s/"&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="https://dronedj.com/2021/03/28/djis-coming-air-2s-works-with-v2-goggles-in-fpv-source/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;DroneDJ&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are accurate, the Air 2S should also work with DJI’s new V2 Goggles and motion controller, which released alongside its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22308345/dji-fpv-review-first-person-drone-price"&gt;FPV drone&lt;/a&gt; last month. Compatibility with the goggles would allow the drone to be piloted from a first-person perspective, in addition to regular flight using the app. The Air 2S isn’t expected to be capable of the kind of acrobatic flight you can get out of the DJI FPV, but the goggles should provide a more immersive flying experience for those who want it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fJo05h"&gt;Other more minor changes include the loss of the “Mavic” branding in its name, and an upgrade to version 4 of DJI’s ActiveTrack standard, &lt;a href="https://www.techniknews.net/news/dji-air-2s-drohne-alle-informationen-zur-neuen-drohne-exklusiv/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;TechnikNews&lt;/em&gt; notes&lt;/a&gt;, which should make it better at tracking subjects during filming. There’s also support for DJI’s newer, lower-latency OcuSync 3.0 standard. Although it’s battery is the same capacity at 3,500mAh, the Air 2S appears to be slightly heavier than the Mavic Air 2 by 30 grams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WFyH0X"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Updated with additional and new 4K Renders&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DJIAir2s?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#DJIAir2s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/9G7WQlM8IH"&gt;https://t.co/9G7WQlM8IH&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/uRGPBzEiSJ"&gt;pic.twitter.com/uRGPBzEiSJ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Nils Ahrensmeier (@NilsAhrDE) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NilsAhrDE/status/1379547519768727556?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 6, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div id="tbn5Ph"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10336946"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22371404/dji-air-2s-photo-leak-news-rumors-features-specs-upgraded-camera-mavic"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22371404/dji-air-2s-photo-leak-news-rumors-features-specs-upgraded-camera-mavic</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-07T04:33:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-07T04:33:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft support pages for Surface Laptop 4 suggest imminent launch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2bZjR1gLtNwsSWsvUdIuP22PCkQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69087737/akrales_191017_3723_0044.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The first Surface Laptop with an AMD processor was the 15-inch Surface Laptop 3, pictured. &lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BOv3vh"&gt;A pair of Microsoft support pages have appeared for the unannounced Surface Laptop 4, suggesting a launch may be imminent. One is a placeholder for an &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fdownload%2F102923" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AMD version&lt;/a&gt; of the laptop, while the other is for an &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fdownload%2F102924" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Intel model&lt;/a&gt;. Both were &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/_h0x0d_/status/1379685933453168640"&gt;spotted by WalkingCat&lt;/a&gt;, an often reliable source of gadget leaks, who speculates that we might see them launched at a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/_h0x0d_/status/1379677699942195203"&gt;Surface event as soon as next week&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZEDBhH"&gt;The Microsoft support page doesn’t give many more details on the laptop, but a &lt;a href="https://winfuture.de/news,121617.html"&gt;report from &lt;em&gt;WinFuture&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; last month &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319854/microsoft-surface-laptop-4-specs-features-release-price-leak"&gt;fills in the details&lt;/a&gt;. The AMD processors used will reportedly be from its 4000 mobile series, and will include the Ryzen 5 4680U and the Ryzen 7 4980U. That’s a step up from the 3000-series chips used in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/21/20923620/microsoft-surface-laptop-3-15-inch-review-windows-test-price-specs-features"&gt;2019’s Surface Laptop 3&lt;/a&gt;, but anyone hoping to see AMD’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22225474/amd-ryzen-5000-series-mobile-processors-ces-2021"&gt;brand new Ryzen 5000 mobile processors&lt;/a&gt; here might be disappointed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WdHv2e"&gt;On the Intel side, &lt;em&gt;WinFuture&lt;/em&gt; notes we should see 11th-gen chips like the Core 15-1145G7 and the Core i7-1185G7. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L7gpe2HLxy465FLpcOx1XRPoFCU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22426297/image__4_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fdownload%2F102923" target="_blank" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener"&gt;Microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The support page lists drivers for the unannounced laptop.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="4CcZvw"&gt;Otherwise, the specs and form-factor of the Surface Laptop 4 are reportedly broadly in line with previous models. There’ll apparently be 13.5- and 15-inch models available, with a maximum of 32GB of RAM and 1TB of storage. Their screens should maintain that excellent 3:2 aspect ratio. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xs4jiX"&gt;Microsoft is yet to make any official announcements about when its new laptops could be launched, but considering the support pages are already live a release can’t be far away. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22371335/surface-laptop-4-amd-processor-cpu-specs-rumors-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22371335/surface-laptop-4-amd-processor-cpu-specs-rumors-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-07T03:00:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-07T03:00:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sennheiser’s new microphones play well with phones and cameras alike</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XsjW2PdcwpDPtp0f1slIjRvez9o=/0x0:591x394/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69087669/image4_37.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Sennheiser&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LgKryE"&gt;Sennheiser is introducing some new mics for creators to use on consumer-level cameras and phones, including an update for its popular camera-mounted MKE 400 shotgun microphone and new phone-friendly lavaliere microphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DGv6Uf"&gt;The updated MKE 400 shotgun microphone looks to be an upgrade in many ways from the previous version — it’s got a new design, which incorporates a windscreen (it also comes with a furry wind sock), a built-in headphone port, and, blessedly, can automatically turn on or off with your camera. It also now comes with a free wind blocker for when it gets really breezy. That should help reduce the number of times you finish recording, only to realize that you didn’t actually capture the audio you were hoping for (something I’ve absolutely done before). &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bvGaGVhKltEJs_82obxloBUnTuA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22414170/image2_33.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Sennheiser&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The updated MKE 400, with a built-in windscreen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EgHRTw9cTnBaKjlvGPQujet5npg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22414179/product_detail_x1_desktop_MKE_400_Sennheiser_01.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Sennheiser&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The previous version of the MKE 400.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6S51pW"&gt;It’s also now designed to work with mobile devices like phones or tablets; it comes with both a standard TRS cable meant for DSLRs or mirrorless cameras, as well as a TRRS cable that should work when plugged into a phone’s headphone jack. Or, more likely, a 3.5mm to USB-C or Lightning adapter. With the microphone’s built-in headphone jack, you should even still be able to monitor when shooting with a phone (or with a camera that only has a mic-in and no headphone out). &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VVK5z4MeS1bFkT3yF-opQtvFhx0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22414165/image5_39.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Sennheiser&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The TRS and TRRS cables will make it easy to use the microphone with both phones and cameras.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5DlG5i"&gt;The new features should help make Sennheiser’s microphone a more compelling competitor to Rode’s latest mics — the older version of the MKE 400’s lack of auto on/off and comparatively outdated design made it a tough sell when compared to something like a &lt;a href="http://en.rode.com/microphones/videomicpro"&gt;Rode VideoMic Pro&lt;/a&gt;. It's nice to see Sennheiser catch up with the rest of the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L4ZoPr"&gt;All the upgrades to the MKE 400 do come at a bit of a cost in the battery department, though: Sennheiser estimated that the old MKE 400 would last 300 hours off a single AAA battery, while the new version only advertises 100 hours of use off of two AAAs. The mic still retails for the same $199.95.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8reTV2i9qxW_W-X3q1jYFtErLh0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22414126/image3_35.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Sennheiser&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The USB-C version of the XS Lav.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="VWVlGu"&gt;Meanwhile, Sennheiser’s new XS Lav mics are meant to be worn on a shirt collar or lapel and could be useful for creators looking to get better audio, but who don’t want to use a large shotgun-style microphone. The clip-on mics comes in two versions: one with a 3.5mm TRRS plug, and one with a USB-C plug for dongle-free use with phones or computers. Sennheiser had &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fen-us.sennheiser.com%2Fclipmic-digital-mobile-recording&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F7%2F22362462%2Fsennheiser-mke-400-shotgun-lavaliere-microphone-camera-phone" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;previously made a lavalier mic&lt;/a&gt; for iPhones that plugged in via Lightning, but it seems like to be no longer widely available. (You can find one that mysteriously looks just like it &lt;a href="https://apogeedigital.com/products/clipmic-digital"&gt;at Apogee&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F0MwBU"&gt;The USB-C version should be the most widely-compatible, as it’ll be useful for both Android phones and single-audio-port computers (plugging it into a combination headphone jack on, say, a MacBook would make it difficult to use headphones, but you could use the USB-C port instead). iPhone owners will want to look at the XS Lav with the 3.5mm connector, though an adapter will be required. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OtYGfm"&gt;The 3.5mm version costs $49.95, and the USB-C version costs $59.95 — both are less expensive than the $79 &lt;a href="http://www.rode.com/microphones/smartlav-plus"&gt;Rode smartLav Plus&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N66z03"&gt;Both the MKE 400 and XS Lav USB-C can also be purchased as part of a “Mobile Kit,” which adds $30 to the price and includes a tiny tripod and phone clamp mount. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22362462/sennheiser-mke-400-shotgun-lavaliere-microphone-camera-phone"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22362462/sennheiser-mke-400-shotgun-lavaliere-microphone-camera-phone</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-07T02:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-07T02:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Polestar is building a zero-emissions car without ‘cop-out’ carbon offsets</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wl9TuR4ji5DmXu38yVlm84iNnIE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69087608/ahawkins_200803_4114_0011.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Andrew Hawkins / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6O0HIn"&gt;Swedish electric performance automaker Polestar says it will build the world’s first truly zero-emissions vehicle without relying on carbon offsets, which it described as a “cop-out.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9SEIDg"&gt;The company, which was spun out of Volvo and Volvo’s parent company Geely, framed its effort to cut carbon emissions by changing the way its cars are made as a “moonshot goal” that would result in the world’s first carbon neutral vehicle by 2030. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9cc0x9"&gt;Carbon offsets, like tree planting, have become a standard way for car companies and other businesses to write off their carbon emissions by investing in renewable energy or conservation projects aimed at bolstering forests’ ability to naturally store carbon. But there’s &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/features/2020-nature-conservancy-carbon-offsets-trees/"&gt;growing evidence&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href="https://features.propublica.org/brazil-carbon-offsets/inconvenient-truth-carbon-credits-dont-work-deforestation-redd-acre-cambodia/"&gt;offsets haven’t succeeded&lt;/a&gt; in slowing global warming and have instead given companies license to keep polluting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="s9D982"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There’s growing evidence that offsets haven’t succeeded&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HElRP3"&gt;“Offsetting is a cop-out,” says Thomas Ingenlath, Polestar CEO, in a statement. “By pushing ourselves to create a completely climate-neutral car, we are forced to reach beyond what is possible today. We will have to question everything, innovate and look to exponential technologies as we design towards zero.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3sFw9r"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311210/fedex-carbon-neutral-2040-2-billion-electric-vehicles-planes"&gt;FedEx&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22169798/united-airlines-emissions-carbon-capture-climate-change-goal"&gt;United&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/14/21137782/delta-carbon-neutral-greenhouse-gas-emissions-climate-change-airlines"&gt;Delta&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-amazon-com-climatechange/uber-jetblue-join-amazon-backed-climate-pledge-idUSKBN28C24H"&gt;JetBlue&lt;/a&gt; said they would eliminate all of their emissions over the next several decades. And &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/8/21427196/uber-promise-100-percent-electric-vehicle-ev-2030"&gt;Uber&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/17/21294040/lyft-electric-vehicle-ev-100-percent-2030"&gt;Lyft&lt;/a&gt; have pledged to go carbon neutral within a similar timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XDobFs"&gt;The automaker makes two cars: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/17/16487290/polestar-volvo-hybrid-electric-revealed"&gt;the $155,000 hybrid coupe Polestar 1&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21365032/polestar-2-hands-on-first-drive-electric-android-automotive-photos-range"&gt;all-electric fastback sedan Polestar 2&lt;/a&gt;. The Polestar 3, an electric crossover SUV, is expected to be released in late 2021. After its first vehicle, the company has said it will only produce electric vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wbwzAs"&gt;The real challenge for Polestar will be the elimination of carbon emissions from its production process and supply chain. Several major automakers have pledged to phase out gas-powered vehicle production by a certain target date, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/28/22254116/general-motors-carbon-neutral-vow-2040-tailpipe-emissions-ev"&gt;General Motors&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/24/21300974/ford-carbon-neutral-2050-climate-change-fuel-efficiency"&gt;Ford&lt;/a&gt;, and Polestar’s parent company, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/16/20915841/volvo-xc40-recharge-electric-suv-specs-miles-range-reveal"&gt;Volvo&lt;/a&gt;. But automobile production, including the mining of the rare earth minerals that go into lithium-ion batteries, is an intensely carbon-heavy process. Even reducing those emissions, to say nothing of eliminating them, will be a hugely consequential task. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7NKDul"&gt;Polestar, as a boutique operation, may have more flexibility to achieve its goals than other larger — and thus, less nimble — companies. The company announced its so-called Polestar 0 project as part of its first annual review, in which it also said that sustainability declarations would be applied to all future Polestar models. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZRKyxU"&gt;Sustainability declarations, popular in industries like &lt;a href="https://www.sustainablefoodtrade.org/declaration-of-sustainability/"&gt;food&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.linkedin.com%2Fpulse%2Fglobal-sustainability-declaration-fashion-industry-dr-anna-brismar%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F7%2F22370302%2Fpolestar-carbon-neutral-electric-car-no-offsets" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;fashion&lt;/a&gt;, is a checklist of all the carbon emissions and waste associated with a product or process. Starting with the Polestar 2, the company says it will list on its website the carbon footprint and traced risk materials associated with the production of each of its vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5RarFE"&gt;“Today, Polestar 2 leaves the factory gates with a carbon footprint,” Ingenlath said. “In 2030 we want to present a car that does not.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22370302/polestar-carbon-neutral-electric-car-no-offsets"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22370302/polestar-carbon-neutral-electric-car-no-offsets</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-07T01:00:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-07T01:00:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>Fujifilm’s new Instax Mini 40 is a $100 vintage-looking toy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q-82uPh6kdH1o4wPpWGf_N9GmZk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69087526/bfarsace_20210405_4506_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Instax Mini 40 is an entry-level instant film camera with only two settings and two buttons.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="A8bKM7"&gt;Fujifilm has announced the newest addition to the Instax Mini line of instant cameras, the &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1630507-REG%2Ffujifilm_16696875_fujifilm_instax_40.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Mini 40&lt;/a&gt;. Much like the Instax Mini 11, which was released last March, the Mini 40 is an entry-level instant film camera with only two settings and two buttons. But what sets this camera apart is its vintage film camera look, complete with a plastic faux leather body and metallic-looking plastic rails. It’s a $100 toy camera that instantly creates printed memories — and of course, it’s a blast to play with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2EtQVw"&gt;Beyond the vintage camera look, the Mini 40 has the same mechanics as the $70 Mini 11. Pushing the large silver button under the lens compartment will pop the lens out and turn the camera on. Selfie mode is activated by pulling the outermost part of the lens out about half an inch more. And when you’re ready to pack it away, push the lens back into the camera to turn it off. The camera’s all-plastic housing makes it very light and easy to take anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/su1HmM-B_pPOPcaevCGWCc7xzZU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22425061/bfarsace_20210405_4506_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;To turn on the Instax Mini 40, you push the silver button under the lens.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RfRu2DE4CJY_g-ro5UNnEyNF5LQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22425063/bfarsace_20210405_4506_0006.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Instax Mini 40 has a plastic faux leather body and metallic-looking plastic rails.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AHh0LG"&gt;There are two shooting modes on the Instax Mini 40: normal and selfie. Selfie mode adjusts the focal distance of the camera to allow subjects closer to the lens to be in focus. Beyond that, you have very little control. The flash will fire with every shutter press, and an Instax Mini film sheet will roll out to a mechanic hum. The results are unpredictable beyond knowing the printed photo will be slightly soft with a high contrast and be bound within the icon Polaroid frame. The magic comes when you place the print on a table, forget about it, and are reminded of a great memory no less than a minute and a half later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8xulc3"&gt;When using any Instax camera, I can’t help but notice the amount of plastic used in each one of the 10-photo film cartridges. Although there is a recycling logo on the cartridge, it is in Japanese, and I am unable to tell what number plastic it is made from. In the US, many municipalities have specific plastic numbers they can and cannot recycle, and without this number clearly labeled on these photo cartridges, I was unable to know if I would be able to recycle them here in Brooklyn, New York. I reached out to Fujifilm for more information and will update this article if I get it. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nbWXmmjRiKuMibtY6ZEiOipn3oY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22425059/bfarsace_20210405_4506_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Selfie mode is enabled by pulling out the frontmost element of the lens.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="vwTT52"&gt;Play both informs my creative style and relieves me of stress — which, as a person who is tasked with reviewing cameras, is hard to always satisfy when using a camera. But the Mini 40, much like the Mini 11, has so few options, a very lightweight feel, and, at times, such unpredictable results that I can sit back and just have fun when using it. Any further thought about photographic theory while using the Mini 40 is excessive and rarely yielded me better results. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/F19V-VpmCbHsym-J75kFYokFILg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22425058/bfarsace_20210405_4506_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The shutter button is located under the viewfinder on the front of the camera.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dQJUBC"&gt;At $100, the Mini 40 is a tad more expensive than the almost-identical Mini 11. Besides its new vintage look, there would be little reason to spend the extra $30. But if looking the film photographer part is important, the Mini 40’s design will stand out. Once Fujifilm addresses the amount of plastic used in every one of the 10-shot film packs, I will really be able to have a carefree experience with this camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5D3PCr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22367999/fujifilm-instax-mini-40-review-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22367999/fujifilm-instax-mini-40-review-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Becca Farsace</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-07T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>NIU announces its first electric kick scooter starting at $599</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iQ_6VAu9d8prknMW2CFerPG9_os=/419x0:3301x1921/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69087400/NIU_Kick_Scooter_Regenerative_Braking.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1O7r5S"&gt;NIU, maker of popular, affordable electric mopeds, showed off its first-ever electric kick scooter. The new two-wheeler will be available starting this summer in China, Europe, and North America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LQ4wNq"&gt;The NIU Kick Scooter will come in two variants, Pro and Sport. In the US, the Pro scooter will have a top speed of 19.8mph, while the Sport version will have a top speed of 17.4 mph. In Europe, both versions will have a regulated top speed of 25 km/h (15.5 mph). The Pro will have a range 31 miles (50 km) on a single 7.5-hour charge, while the Sport will have a range of 25 miles (40 km) on a single 5.5-hour charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="9hhwKo"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The NIU Kick Scooter will come in two variants, Pro and Sport&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Gf3Hui"&gt;For the drivetrain, NIU is offering a 350W motor and 486Wh lithium-ion battery pack for the Pro kick scooter, while the Sport will be powered by a 300W motor and 365Wh battery pack. Both scooters are water resistant, foldable, and come with app connectivity via Bluetooth and regenerative braking. The cheapest version of the scooter will start at $599, though NIU has yet release any more details about pricing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="RqgUrC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10432850"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fjF29e"&gt;NIU is mostly known in North America for its popular $2,000 electric mopeds, which have been used by shared mobility companies like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/16/18677586/revel-mopeds-scooter-nyc-review"&gt;Revel&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22248805/lime-electric-moped-scooter-niu-washington-paris"&gt;Lime&lt;/a&gt;. The mopeds are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/6/21051352/china-niu-electric-scooters-mopeds-ces-2020"&gt;available for purchase&lt;/a&gt; in a handful of US cities, including San Francisco, San Diego, Austin, Chicago, Washington, DC, Miami, Fort Lauderdale, and Honolulu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fpiabm"&gt;A pre-sale for the kick scooter starts in June 2021, with delivery scheduled in the US and Europe in July 2021. Global retail sales will begin in August 2021, with the scooter able to be purchased online or in any of NIU’s dealerships and stores in Europe and North America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PUb4Ea"&gt;Electric scooters are plentiful in the US, with models from Segway-Ninebot, Inokim, Acton, Unagi, and others widely available from a number of different retailers. Battery-powered mopeds, however, are a bit harder to come by in North America. Major manufacturers, like Gogoro, tend to focus sales on higher volume markets like China, while the US is left to languish thanks to its car-centric infrastructure. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22370419/niu-electric-kick-scooter-pro-sport-specs-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22370419/niu-electric-kick-scooter-pro-sport-specs-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
