<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-07-13T18:21:09-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-13T18:21:09-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-13T18:21:09-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google is capping Meet’s formerly unlimited group video calls to an hour for free accounts</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/66C9_sYdpJ3fjTaNDILcpt3z5cQ=/63x0:1938x1250/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69578363/Google_Meet_1.max_2000x2000.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Cn0avv"&gt;Google has brought an end to its effectively “unlimited” group video calls in Meet for free Gmail accounts, &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/meet/answer/7317473?hl=en#zippy=%2Cparticipant-limits%2Cmeeting-length-limits"&gt;according to support pages&lt;/a&gt; spotted by &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/07/12/google-meet-group-limit/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Now users with free accounts logging on to Meet will have group calls capped at an hour rather than the previous 24-hour meeting duration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HoFSlY"&gt;Google’s unlimited group meeting offer was helpful because so many traditionally in-person functions moved online due to COVID-19. Not having to worry about a call cutting out or creating new meeting links meant you could leave your video call on during long family get-togethers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="jPw8I0"&gt;&lt;q&gt;One-on-one calls are still unlimited&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="S7vUYF"&gt;Meet was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/29/21240509/google-meet-video-conferencing-free-gmail"&gt;opened up to non-enterprise users in April&lt;/a&gt; last year to better compete with Zoom, and at the time Google promised to keep unlimited meetings in place &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/26/21457293/google-meet-limit-meeting-free-plans-september-zoom"&gt;until September 30th, 2020&lt;/a&gt;. The company later extended that window into &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/29/21494189/google-meet-limit-calls-minutes-march-2021"&gt;March of 2021&lt;/a&gt;, and then again &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/31/22359774/google-meet-unlimited-calls-free-users-june-30-60-minute-limit"&gt;until the end of June&lt;/a&gt;. Google still allows one-on-one calls to last as long as you need, but heading into the second pandemic summer, longer group calls will now cost extra — like a currently $7.99 per month subscription to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575523/google-workspace-tier-us-brazil-canada-japan-mexico"&gt;Google’s Workspace Individual tier&lt;/a&gt; ($9.99 a month after January 2022).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cfnjZW"&gt;Like Google, Zoom’s one-on-one calls are unlimited and free, but group calls have been handled differently. Zoom has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22176502/zoom-lifting-40-minute-meeting-limit-holidays-free-hanukkah-christmas-eve-new-years-kwanzaa"&gt;periodically expanded beyond its 40 minute meeting limit&lt;/a&gt; during specific holidays like Christmas, Hanukkah, and New Year’s Eve. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tHieWB"&gt;Meet, Zoom, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439924/microsoft-teams-personal-version-launch-available-download"&gt;Microsoft Teams&lt;/a&gt; all started out as business communications products that were adopted by non-business users in the early days of the pandemic. Now that some of the freebies are going away, it’ll be interesting to see which services people stick with.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22576137/google-meet-group-meeting-cap-one-hour"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22576137/google-meet-group-meeting-cap-one-hour</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-13T18:01:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-13T18:01:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Mercedes-Benz’s new Roadster has a flippy touchscreen</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oOwsfNijIe-diDHbrCQkkvFdGxo=/65x0:575x340/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69578271/mercedes_screen.0.gif" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JvvaH4"&gt;Large touchscreens are commonplace in new cars these days, and the bigger these rectangular screens get, the fewer things you can do with the hardware to really differentiate from the competition. Perhaps that’s why, in the new 2022 AMG SL Roadster, Mercedes-Benz is taking the screen out of the dashboard, anchoring it to the center console, and letting it electronically flip up and down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IHKUzn"&gt;That’s right, Mercedes-Benz’s newest car has a flippy screen. The company said it designed the 11.9-inch portrait touchscreen this way in order to help fight glare — the AMG SL Roadster is a convertible, after all — but it’s also clearly a flashy parlor trick that seems to say, “Hey, we did something different from Tesla.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wB9RXf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10650931"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="alx7Ni"&gt;The new AMG SL Roadster also has a digital instrument cluster that’s a bit different from the rest. The 12.3-inch screen behind the steering wheel is tucked away in a “visor” that Mercedes-Benz says is “aviation-inspired.” Basically it’s a screen embedded even &lt;em&gt;deeper&lt;/em&gt; into the dashboard than normal which — of course — helps fight glare. (Something tells me there was a common theme in the most recent customer feedback sessions...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ahGmJ0"&gt;The move to bigger screens in cars has put a big emphasis on software, which is why automakers from Polestar to Ford are turning to tech giants like Google for help. But similar to the current state of the smartphone market, the hardware has really converged. That’s paved the way for funky new ideas to stand out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mga9u9"&gt;Much like, say, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/21/21146465/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-review-folding-glass-flip-phone-screen-camera-price"&gt;Samsung’s folding phones&lt;/a&gt;, this articulating screen feels more like an idea thrown at a wall than something that will actually become desirable (I’m personally dying to know how well it stands up to being poked and prodded — it presumably won’t wobble, but you never know). But it’s an interesting risk for Mercedes-Benz to take nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22576101/mercedes-benz-amg-sl-roadster-touchscreen-articulating"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22576101/mercedes-benz-amg-sl-roadster-touchscreen-articulating</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-13T17:21:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-13T17:21:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook groups can now designate Group Experts</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gZ6K3TaKgQdPlbZWjz1i0iV398I=/0x0:890x593/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69578066/CD21_430_NRP_New_Tools_to_Support_Experts_Community.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Facebook&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TA3JHY"&gt;Facebook is introducing a new feature called “Group Experts” today, which will allow admins to designate which members are highly knowledgeable about the group’s topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K9SqGE"&gt;Beyond the bragging rights, Group Experts will have a badge next to their name emblazoned with the proof of their elevated status. This badge will show up on posts, comments, and in the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/community/whats-new/introducing-qa-engage-community/"&gt;Q&amp;amp;A feature&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TfyqeD"&gt;Group Experts will be selected by group administrators, and experts will only be given this extraordinary power once they have accepted the nomination. Admins can revoke the expert status, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TOf2zm"&gt;Facebook is testing ways to make it easier for admins to find these experts, by prompting specific users, currently in the gaming and fitness spaces, to add which games or activities they’re knowledgeable about. Group admins can search these topics to find their new Group Experts. This tactic works as a growth driver for groups as well, since the new experts will be able to invite followers who have recently interacted with their main page to join the group too.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HH1adTSVlq4NXYjPw5ZwSYtggTo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22715780/CD21_430_NRP_New_Tools_to_Support_Experts_Badge.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Facebook&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="YJyeGM"&gt;However, if a group nominates an untrustworthy expert or if that group is willfully engaged in posting misinformation, it will exclusively be up to the admins to remove them from their expert status. For instance, groups that push anti-vax agendas would likely not nominate conventional doctors or public health officials as experts. So while the “expert” tag designates the trust of admins, it doesn’t objectively qualify someone as a real expert. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ph35DN"&gt;When asked about additional moderation tools to ensure Group Experts provide accurate information, a Facebook spokesperson listed the established ways the company deals with misinformation on the platform, like &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/journalismproject/programs/third-party-fact-checking/how-it-works"&gt;third-party fact checkers&lt;/a&gt; and reducing distribution for content flagged as misleading. They added that members can always report content to group admins.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22576073/facebook-group-experts-badge-misinformation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22576073/facebook-group-experts-badge-misinformation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dave Gershgorn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-13T16:52:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-13T16:52:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Nintendo Switch’s Joy-Con drift problem, explained</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kzoVx2ujUuxfRfxN0iJGbLs_ovo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67590808/jbareham_180301_2346_nintendo_switch_0126.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QtpnJ2"&gt;Nintendo Switch owners have been &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch/comments/cczxwz/i_know_its_been_said_a_billion_times_but_nintendo/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=ios_app"&gt;experiencing problems&lt;/a&gt; with the console’s removable Joy-Con controllers for years now, with users &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch/comments/92oc0i/nintendo_needs_to_either_sort_out_joy_con_build/"&gt;reporting weird joystick drifting&lt;/a&gt; problems that cause false inputs and have been &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch/comments/cayjls/nintendo_fix_your_controllers/"&gt;steadily growing over time&lt;/a&gt; as original Switch machines grow older. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r5NaS1"&gt;Ever since a &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/joy-con-drift-is-becoming-a-real-problem-on-the-switch-1836417809"&gt;report by &lt;em&gt;Kotaku&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from July 2019 shined a light on the Joy-Con drift issue, Nintendo has changed its policies significantly. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/23/20707849/nintendo-will-reportedly-fix-joy-con-drift-for-free-even-out-of-warranty"&gt;The company will now repair drifting Joy-Con controllers for free&lt;/a&gt;, even if your controllers are outside the regular warranty. But Nintendo hasn’t changed the design of the controllers, and it’s still an issue today, even on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/7/10/20689379/nintendo-switch-update-fcc-change-cpu-nvidia-tegra-soc-nand"&gt;refreshed Switch models&lt;/a&gt; that launched last year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oUHvnm"&gt;If you’re looking for more information on the problem, here’s the current situation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gdby1K"&gt;What is “Joy-Con drift”?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Vm4JjL"&gt;Joy-Con drift is an issue that Switch owners have been encountering over the last few months that causes the analog sticks on the controllers to randomly move around and input commands to the console, even when they’re not being physically moved. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="wwL5N6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Phantom inputs&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Hx42ve"&gt;Anecdotally, the issue seems to affect left Joy-Con controllers (which tend to be used for movement in most games) more than the &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch/comments/8tia7s/drifting_joystick_on_right_joycon/"&gt;right half&lt;/a&gt; of the controller set. Although, there are reports of users experiencing it on both joysticks. A quick (and extremely unscientific) poll of &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; staffers revealed that some Switch owners have reported multiple controllers encountering the issue, while others have never experienced it, which seems to be mirrored by reports around the internet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="R7iyMK"&gt;What causes Joy-Con drift?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="EJelw3"&gt;There are two potential causes for drift: some users blame the issue on either dust or debris making their way into the controller underneath a rubber cap that’s designed to keep the interior clean. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q9Mzpl"&gt;Others have &lt;a href="https://imgur.com/gallery/58bBc43#88PnO9v"&gt;completely disassembled the controller&lt;/a&gt; and found worn-down contacts, which might be causing the issue due to repetitive use. It’s also possible that neither of those theories is correct or that it’s a combination of factors that cause stick drift over time. Without Nintendo clarifying the situation, &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch/comments/cfqp0a/for_joycon_drift_it_doesnt_make_any_sense_for_the/"&gt;it’s tough to tell&lt;/a&gt; exactly what’s wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="NI65h3"&gt;How do I fix the issue?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="BNpxpb"&gt;As mentioned above, it’s not fully clear what’s causing the issue, which makes fixing it tricky. A possible solution is to make sure you’re running the latest Switch software or to &lt;a href="https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/22340/~/how-to-calibrate-the-controllers"&gt;recalibrate your analog sticks&lt;/a&gt; to make sure it’s not a software issue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l79GZP"&gt;Some users &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch/comments/8tia7s/drifting_joystick_on_right_joycon/"&gt;have also tried&lt;/a&gt; using compressed air or isopropyl alcohol to fix the problem, although success seems to vary greatly. Others have taken the more drastic step of fully replacing the joystick entirely — a far more difficult fix that will void your warranty, if it works at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="7vlguG"&gt;What is Nintendo doing about impacted controllers?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="OFZxmt"&gt;Following the outrage over the issue in July 2019, Nintendo has begun to fix impacted controllers free of charge. &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/8xzzva/internal-nintendo-memo-instructs-customer-service-to-fix-joy-con-drift-for-free"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vice News&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that Nintendo has directed its customer support team to fix Joy-Con controllers for free and issue refunds for previous repairs, even if you’re no longer under warranty. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hk47Zi"&gt;Nintendo now &lt;a href="https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/ask/ht/789"&gt;even has a dedicated area of its support website&lt;/a&gt; for Joy-Con repair requests: just fill out the form and Nintendo will coordinate your return, confirm that the controllers have the issue, and either repair or replace the controllers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YQ1YHy"&gt;Otherwise, Nintendo offers a standard warranty of 90 days (for accessories, which seems to include separately purchased Joy-Con controllers) and 12 months (for consoles, which seems to include Joy-Con controllers that are included with a Switch).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="BV1lt6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Nintendo offers repairs, but they’re not cheap&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mfUHPx"&gt;If you’re outside the warranty, Reddit users had previously &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch/comments/95ftyv/just_found_out_it_would_cost_40_with_shipping_to/"&gt;reported costs of $40 for an out-of-warranty repair&lt;/a&gt;, which is nearly the cost of a replacement single Joy-Con controller. (They run for $50 individually or $80 as a pair.) As of now, there haven’t been any announcements of an extended warranty for controllers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6wlHIh"&gt;When the issue was first revealed, Nintendo commented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="pFEMb9"&gt;At Nintendo, we take great pride in creating quality products and we are continuously making improvements to them. We are aware of recent reports that some Joy-Con controllers are not responding correctly. We want our consumers to have fun with Nintendo Switch, and if anything falls short of this goal we always encourage them to visit &lt;a href="http://support.nintendo.com/"&gt;http://support.nintendo.com&lt;/a&gt; so we can help.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="oFj3Cn"&gt;Is anyone suing Nintendo?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="FYyHLQ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch/comments/cfbzi0/a_classaction_lawsuit_has_been_filed_against/"&gt;Back in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, law firm Chimicles Schwartz Kriner &amp;amp; Donaldson-Smith &lt;a href="https://chimicles.com/cskd-files-class-action-lawsuit-against-nintendo-of-america-inc-relating-to-joy-con-drifting-issues/"&gt;filed a class action lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; against Nintendo, alleging that the Joy-Con controllers are defective due to the drift issues, and the firm is actively seeking more Switch owners to join the suit. That suit is still in progress, with the &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch/comments/j3fu5w/nintendo_joycon_drift_class_action_lawsuit/"&gt;firm recently requesting&lt;/a&gt; that users send in videos of drift to help prove to Nintendo that the issue has caused problems for customers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kRPNlC"&gt;Additionally, a second class action suit &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/nintendo-joy-con-lawsuit/"&gt;has been filled in California&lt;/a&gt; over the same issue in October 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="V7uBOg"&gt;Is drift a problem on the Switch Lite?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="2EapNG"&gt;It’s unclear if the Switch Lite is as affected when it comes to controller stick drift — reports from across the internet vary, and there doesn’t seem to have been the same level of outcry (or a Nintendo replacement program) for the smaller Switch model. But the Switch Lite doesn’t have removable controllers, so if it does suffer from similar issues with stick drifting, the situation could be far worse. In that scenario, users won’t be able to swap out a controller to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="nH7aht"&gt;Does the OLED Switch fix Joy-Con drift?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="2FObzy"&gt;Nintendo refuses to confirm one way or the other if the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/6/22456337/nintendo-switch-oled-model-specs-date-price"&gt;newly announced OLED Switch&lt;/a&gt; will feature design changes to fix Joy-Con drift more permanently, but it’s not looking good. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/10/22570868/nintendo-oled-switch-joy-con-drift"&gt;In a statement provided to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the company said that “Joy-Con controller configuration and functionality did not change with Nintendo Switch (OLED model),” while an FAQ posted to its UK website notes that “the Joy-Con controllers included with Nintendo Switch (OLED model) are the same as the controllers currently available.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XDBfGl"&gt;That all seems to indicate that the OLED Switch’s controllers are the same hardware as the existing Switch controllers, albeit in a new white color scheme. If that’s the case, then they’ll likely be susceptible to the same Joy-Con drift issues that existing models face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1iGYuz"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, July 24th, 2019: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added info Nintendo may be quietly fixing Joy-Cons with this issue for free.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7QTN53"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, October 6th, 2020: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added updated information on the current state of Joy-Con drift issues, Nintendo’s repair policy, and a new class action suit against the company. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hNZVdK"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, July 13th, 2021: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added information on the OLED Switch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21504741/nintendo-switch-joy-con-drift-problem-explained"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21504741/nintendo-switch-joy-con-drift-problem-explained</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-13T16:23:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-13T16:23:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google fined €500 million in France over bad faith negotiations with news outlets</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oncuGGHWJQkZjy9sX6CNt3OdFHM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69577807/acastro_180508_1777_google_IO_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DfLsJs"&gt;Google is being charged with a historic &lt;a href="https://www.autoritedelaconcurrence.fr/fr/communiques-de-presse/remuneration-des-droits-voisins-lautorite-sanctionne-google-hauteur-de-500"&gt;€500 million ($589 million) fine from the French Competition Authority (FCA)&lt;/a&gt; for failing to comply with &lt;a href="https://www.autoritedelaconcurrence.fr/fr/communiques-de-presse/droits-voisins-lautorite-fait-droit-aux-demandes-de-mesures-conservatoires"&gt;an April 2020 order&lt;/a&gt; to negotiate fairly with news publishers over the use of, and payment for, their articles and other content (&lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/07/13/google-fined-500-million-euros-in-france-over-news-copyright-row.html"&gt;via CNBC&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wNE2hZ"&gt;News publishers gained the ability to request payment for the use of their content on third-party platforms with the passage of the European Union’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/26/18280726/europe-copyright-directive"&gt;controversial Copyright Directive&lt;/a&gt;, which was adopted by France in 2019 and generally tries to shift power toward content producers rather than the platforms that reshare their work. Article 11 of the directive, colloquially called the “Link Tax,” gives publishers the right to ask for payment for snippets of articles and other content linked in places like Google News.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4GpDH4DEsenQ_tlHnZS05W5LYN4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13697407/Screen_Shot_2019_01_17_at_6.11.09_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Credit: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google’s test search results it claimed it may use after the EU’s Copyright Directive was adopted.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="madUjw"&gt;In the lead-up to the passage of the directive, &lt;a href="https://searchengineland.com/eu-copyright-directive-nearing-final-form-as-google-tests-stripped-down-news-serps-310494"&gt;Google tested blank content previews&lt;/a&gt; and no search descriptions as a kind of vague threat of what it might be forced to do in a post-Article 11 world. The FCA viewed that as &lt;a href="https://www.autoritedelaconcurrence.fr/fr/communiques-de-presse/droits-voisins-lautorite-fait-droit-aux-demandes-de-mesures-conservatoires"&gt;an abuse of Google’s monopoly on search&lt;/a&gt; and ordered the company to comply with the rules and actually negotiate for the right to display articles. Apparently, those negotiations haven’t gone well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i5lk7q"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.autoritedelaconcurrence.fr/fr/communiques-de-presse/remuneration-des-droits-voisins-lautorite-sanctionne-google-hauteur-de-500"&gt;According to the FCA&lt;/a&gt;, Google forced its deals with publishers to be focused on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276544/google-news-showcase-uk-argentina-launch-license-paywall-content"&gt;News Showcase&lt;/a&gt;, a product that doesn’t encompass all the places publishers’ articles can appear across Google’s platforms. Secondly, the FCA claims the company isn’t willing to negotiate sharing revenue from the ads sold against other places publisher content might appear, like the links and search description you see when you pull up search results. Both issues were supposed to be addressed in the FCA’s big-picture order to negotiate “the remuneration due to [publishers] under the Neighbouring Rights Act for the resumption of their protected content,” but it seems Google didn’t see it that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tYkXpU"&gt;In response to news of the fine, Google tells CNBC&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;that it was actually about to finalize an agreement with the Agence France-Presse (AFP), France’s cooperative news wire organization, “that includes a global licensing agreement, as well as the remuneration of their Neighbouring Rights for their press publications.” It seems like this is more than just an issue of poor timing, but at least in this statement provided to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, Google is sticking to its guns — and claiming it doesn’t make much money from news search results in the first place:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="hQKD41"&gt;While we are committed to complying with the Copyright Directive and the FCA’s orders, this fine ignores the significant efforts we have made to reach agreements and the reality of how news works on our platforms: Google last year generated less than 5 million Euros in revenue-not-profit from clicks on ads against possible news-related queries in France. We want to find a solution and reach definitive agreements but this fine is out of all proportion to the amount of money we make from news and we will be reviewing the decision in detail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="whelym"&gt;Google has two months to address the issues raised by the FCA by offering payments for the use of “protected content” to publishers. If it doesn’t, it faces an additional €900,00 ($1 million) per day in penalties on top of its already multimillion-dollar fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yniydp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575647/google-fine-500-million-french-authorities-news-showcase"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575647/google-fine-500-million-french-authorities-news-showcase</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-13T16:15:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-13T16:15:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter will let you change who can reply to a tweet after you post it</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wGfEtxGtwBm72U9O_Q9VbcHi6Bc=/53x0:3266x2142/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69577773/E6MtvqeUYAIrcdC__1_.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tap the three dots menu to change who can reply to your tweet.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Twitter&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PFYfpr"&gt;Twitter is rolling out the ability to let you change who can reply to a tweet after you have posted it, the company announced Tuesday. You could already limit who replied to your tweets thanks to a feature &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/11/21362514/twitter-reply-limiting-features-all-users-harassment-rollout-available-now"&gt;rolled out widely in August&lt;/a&gt;, but you had to set that preference while writing the tweet — with this update, you can change who can reply at a later time, which could be a helpful way to reduce harassment. The feature will be available globally on iOS, Android, and the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MubEhh"&gt;To change who can reply, click or tap the three-dot menu on a tweet and look for the option in the menu that appears. You can make it so that everyone can reply, only people you follow can reply, or only people you mention in your tweet can reply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wDZK11"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Your Tweets = Your space. Now you can change who can reply to you even after you Tweet. &lt;a href="https://t.co/rNWJk6zWTr"&gt;https://t.co/rNWJk6zWTr&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/3HFSjAotg7"&gt;pic.twitter.com/3HFSjAotg7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Twitter Safety (@TwitterSafety) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TwitterSafety/status/1415025551773892608?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 13, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="v1rJ9L"&gt;The feature is the latest example of how Twitter is working to give users more control over who can interact with what they post. On July 1st, Twitter showed off some ideas it’s considering that would &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22558731/twitter-trusted-friends-facets-features-pre-announce"&gt;give users further control&lt;/a&gt;, such as the ability to tweet to “Trusted Friends,” and a way to tweet from different “facets” of your online personality, such as your work self and your joke-y self. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="eOPeZE"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Twitter is for real rolling out its reply-limiting feature to all users","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/11/21362514/twitter-reply-limiting-features-all-users-harassment-rollout-available-now"},{"title":"Twitter considers letting you limit tweets to ‘trusted friends’","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22558731/twitter-trusted-friends-facets-features-pre-announce"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575998/twitter-tweet-change-who-can-reply-after-you-post"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575998/twitter-tweet-change-who-can-reply-after-you-post</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-13T15:53:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-13T15:53:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>GM drops wireless charging from some SUVs due to chip shortage</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yXjN59R86Cm54_OO8v9hmeLK6FY=/41x0:1240x799/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69577616/2021_Chevrolet_Traverse_005.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Hi5U8G"&gt;General Motors is dropping wireless smartphone charging from some new SUVs because of the global microchip shortage. It’s the latest feature to get the axe at the company due to the low supply of semiconductors, as GM has already &lt;a href="https://www.thedrive.com/tech/41307/gm-pulls-hd-radio-from-2021-silverado-and-sierra-pickups-over-chip-shortage"&gt;pulled HD radio from some models&lt;/a&gt;, along with &lt;a href="https://www.thedrive.com/news/41008/gm-drops-auto-stop-start-from-v8-silverados-and-sierras-due-to-chip-shortage"&gt;auto start-stop&lt;/a&gt; and a fuel management module that made &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331766/gm-pickups-semiconductor-shortage-fuel-economy-emissions"&gt;pickup trucks slightly cleaner and more efficient&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rAx3Mz"&gt;Certain trims of the 2021 Chevy Tahoe and Suburban, as well as the 2021 GMC Yukon, made after July 12th will no longer include a wireless charging pad, as was first reported by the &lt;a href="https://gmauthority.com/blog/2021/07/2021-full-size-gm-suvs-to-lose-wireless-phone-charger/"&gt;GM Authority blog&lt;/a&gt;. But GM tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that certain 2022 Buick Enclaves, Chevy Traverses, and Cadillac XT5s and XT6s made after August 2nd are also affected. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K4Za6t"&gt;Buyers of these vehicles will get a $75 credit instead of the wireless charging option. (GM is offering a similar $50 credit for vehicles that are missing the HD radio feature.) The company is expected to make these vehicles without wireless charging pads through the rest of the respective model years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="91BMM0"&gt;“Our supply chain organization continues to make strides working with our supply base to mitigate the near-term impacts of the semiconductor situation,” the company said in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “GM continues to leverage every available semiconductor to build and ship our most popular and in-demand products, including our highly profitable full-size trucks and SUVs for our customers. However, the semiconductor situation continues to remain fluid globally.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0hnemi"&gt;The chip shortage is wreaking all sorts of havoc in the auto industry. Some companies have chosen to reduce overall production as a result, like Ford, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266483/ford-f150-production-slowdown-semiconductor-chip-shortage"&gt;shuttered some F-150 assembly lines&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xjRLVj"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The chip shortage is wreaking all sorts of havoc in the auto industry&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nvT5BT"&gt;The resulting lack of supply is driving up prices, though, creating &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22423479/semiconductor-shortage-new-car-truck-prices-sales"&gt;an extremely hot new car market&lt;/a&gt;. So many automakers like GM are still trying to get vehicles to dealers even if they’re missing some features. Nissan, for instance, is making &lt;a href="https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3132505/carmakers-are-stripping-out-digital-bells-and-whistles-global"&gt;some vehicles without navigation systems&lt;/a&gt;. Some new Ram pickups no longer come with an intelligent rear-view mirror that improves blind spot monitoring. French automaker Renault is shipping some cars with a smaller entertainment screen and has also dropped wireless charging from certain models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IwyUKA"&gt;There are a number of things driving the chip shortage, but many automakers made the situation worse for themselves when they initially lowered production targets in 2020 because of the pandemic. When sales rebounded quickly, they found themselves in a position where chips that &lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt; getting made were now going elsewhere. Automakers are especially vulnerable because they tend to use older, larger semiconductors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MCXlz1"&gt;It may only get worse, too. While some automakers were initially optimistic that the harshest impact would be felt in the first half of 2021, Volkswagen recently warned that the &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/volkswagen-sees-global-chip-shortage-worsening-in-second-half-11625861486"&gt;second half of this year could be brutal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pgRRAQ"&gt;In May, Ford CEO Jim Farley &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22444294/ford-f150-lightning-pickup-truck-jim-farley-interview"&gt;said on an episode of &lt;em&gt;Decoder&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that the company is considering going directly to the chip makers to cut deals, as opposed to going through suppliers. “I think boots on the ground in places like Taiwan and China and Asia are going to be more important for us,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mVWZj7"&gt;Farley also said that, moving forward, he thinks his company “[has] to move to 22nm or smaller, more advanced [semiconductors], more importantly, we have to be in a position to know inside the company what to choose and customize off the shelf computes to work for us.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575836/gm-wireless-charging-cadillac-chevy-tahoe-chip-shortage"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575836/gm-wireless-charging-cadillac-chevy-tahoe-chip-shortage</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-13T15:39:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-13T15:39:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>Discord buys AI anti-harassment company</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wyQRuJ6HS4oNpD52YXn1hL-tZsI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69577524/acastro_200318_1777_discord_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Lh7aG2"&gt;Discord has &lt;a href="https://medium.com/sentropy/sentropy-x-discord-1ed5c4269896"&gt;purchased a company&lt;/a&gt; working on AI tools to detect harassment online. The company, Sentropy, monitors online networks for abuse and harassment, then offers users a way to block problematic people and filter out messages they don’t want to see. Its first product, Sentropy Protect, was initially focused on &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/02/09/sentropy-launches-tool-for-people-to-protect-themselves-from-social-media-abuse-starting-with-twitter/"&gt;helping users clean up their Twitter feeds&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="igHY7h"&gt;The company is now shutting down its independent tools and &lt;a href="https://medium.com/sentropy/sentropy-x-discord-1ed5c4269896"&gt;joining Discord&lt;/a&gt;, where it plans to help the hugely popular chat app “expand and evolve its [trust and safety] capabilities.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b6N7s8"&gt;It could be a good pairing. Discord has a huge network, with more than 150 million monthly users, and servers can be a real challenge to moderate. The service is made up of more than 19 million individual communities, and that scale requires the work of both &lt;a href="https://discord.com/moderation"&gt;volunteers&lt;/a&gt; and teams within Discord to properly moderate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L6zpJz"&gt;Tools like the ones Sentropy built could help both groups better monitor for bad behavior on the networks they oversee. Discord will use the acquisition to expand its abilities to detect and remove bad content and grow its safety team, according to a company spokesperson. They said trust and safety is a “key priority” for Discord.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575809/discord-ai-anti-harassment-company-sentropy-acquisition-buy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575809/discord-ai-anti-harassment-company-sentropy-acquisition-buy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-13T15:23:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-13T15:23:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Quibi’s zombie corpse rises again to claim eight Emmy nominations</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8cqpOc_qNw6Xez1eRb3N0TLMuwI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69577421/acastro_200403_3960_quibi_0004.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="175MLE"&gt;Quibi wasn’t long for this world, but its spirit refuses to let us move on from its chaotic memory. Despite &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/22/21529392/quibi-shut-down-date-december-tv-shows-movies-streaming"&gt;shutting down in December&lt;/a&gt;, the doomed streaming service scooped up several Emmy nominations today for its shortform originals across three categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lVlUuB"&gt;The service received &lt;a href="https://www.emmys.com/sites/default/files/Downloads/73rd-nominations-network-v1.pdf?q=1&amp;amp;q1="&gt;eight nominations&lt;/a&gt; for three of its series, including &lt;em&gt;Die Hart&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Mapleworth Murders&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Reno 911! &lt;/em&gt;As was the case when a handful of Quibi originals &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/21345262/quibi-emmy-award-short-form-nominations-strategy-competition-streaming"&gt;were nominated&lt;/a&gt; for Emmy awards last year, the service cleaned up in shortform content categories, which makes a lot of sense considering it doesn’t exactly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/21345262/quibi-emmy-award-short-form-nominations-strategy-competition-streaming"&gt;have a ton of competition&lt;/a&gt; in the arena. Its nominations by category are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="bLCaOf"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outstanding Actor in a Short Form Comedy or Drama Series&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LOp92n"&gt;Pete Devon in &lt;em&gt;Bonding&lt;/em&gt; (Netflix)&lt;br&gt;Kevin Hart in &lt;em&gt;Die Hart&lt;/em&gt; (Quibi)&lt;br&gt;John Travolta in &lt;em&gt;Die Hart&lt;/em&gt; (Quibi)&lt;br&gt;John Lutz in &lt;em&gt;Mapleworth Murders&lt;/em&gt; (Quibi)&lt;br&gt;J.B. Smoove in &lt;em&gt;Mapleworth Murders&lt;/em&gt; (Quibi)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6VKqWY"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outstanding Actress in a Short Form Comedy or Drama Series&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="McOsgm"&gt;Nathalie Emmanuel in &lt;em&gt;Die Hart&lt;/em&gt; (Quibi)&lt;br&gt;Keke Palmer in &lt;em&gt;Keke Palmer’s Turnt Up With The Taylors&lt;/em&gt; (Facebook Watch)&lt;br&gt;Paula Pell in &lt;em&gt;Mapleworth Murders&lt;/em&gt; (Quibi)&lt;br&gt;Kerri Kenney-Silver in &lt;em&gt;Reno 911!&lt;/em&gt; (Quibi)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zdVzTI"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outstanding Short Form Comedy, Drama or Variety Series&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zQHTmD"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Carpool Karaoke: The Series&lt;/em&gt; (Apple TV)&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Late Night With Seth Meyers: CORRECTIONS&lt;/em&gt; (YouTube)&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Randy Rainbow Show&lt;/em&gt; (YouTube)&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reno 911! &lt;/em&gt;(Quibi)&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stephen Colbert Presents Tooning Out The News&lt;/em&gt; (Paramount+)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="8SFp4t"&gt;After Quibi called it quits last year, many of Quibi’s originals were scooped up and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395533/roku-originals-quibi-content-tv"&gt;rebranded as Roku Originals&lt;/a&gt; for the platform’s free and ad-supported service the Roku Channel. Unlike the original platform, Roku will not stream them with Quibi’s Turnstyle formatting, which adjusted the viewer’s point of view based on the orientation of their phone. Roku announced earlier this year that 75-plus originals would come out on the service this year, including a dozen previously unreleased shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OehS9g"&gt;Quibi had thrown mountains of money behind wooing A-list celebrities and talent for its series. While Roku is unlikely to pump the same amount of money into the future development of many of the shows it acquired in its Quibi deal, it does appear to be willing to cough up enough cash to produce future entries of the content haul’s crown jewels. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="604CsG"&gt;The company &lt;a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210608005476/en/Roku-Orders-Second-Season-of-Kevin-Hart%E2%80%99s-%E2%80%98Die-Hart%E2%80%99-from-Laugh-Out-Loud"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; in June that it was ordering a second season of Kevin Hart’s &lt;em&gt;Die Hart&lt;/em&gt; titled &lt;em&gt;Die Harter&lt;/em&gt;. Colin Davis, Roku’s head of original scripted programming, said in a statement at the time that the series “exploded out of the gate and after a spectacular debut weekend, has quickly become one of the most watched Roku Originals on The Roku Channel” after premiering on May 20th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575906/quibi-emmy-nominations-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575906/quibi-emmy-nominations-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-13T15:15:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-13T15:15:44-04:00</updated>
    <title>New report suggests corporate climate change pledges aren’t that valuable</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A trader monitors offers in the Standard &amp;amp;amp; Poor’s 500 stock index options pit at the Chicago Board Options Exchange (CBOE) on August 24, 2015 in Chicago, Illinois.&amp;amp;nbsp;" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Xxa08oRo8sJt9IY6Gow9eWztFsg=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69577379/485109234.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A trader monitors offers in the Standard &amp;amp; Poor’s 500 stock index options pit at the Chicago Board Options Exchange (CBOE) on August 24, 2015 in Chicago, Illinois.&amp;nbsp; | Photo by Scott Olson/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7c3Snm"&gt;Many S&amp;amp;P 100 companies that claim to care about climate change are either ignoring or derailing policies that could provide solutions to the crisis, a new report finds. A whopping 92 percent of companies on the S&amp;amp;P 100 index in 2019 have pledged to cut down their own planet-heating emissions, but just 40 percent are actually pushing lawmakers to address the climate crisis, and 21 percent have advocated against science-based climate policy over the past five years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="jKCOuv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Corporations and lawmakers alike will need to do much more to meet the scale and urgency of the climate crisis&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yK1YTK"&gt;So while companies might sell themselves to consumers as planet-friendly, they’re not necessarily having the same conversations with decision-makers who are most responsible for tackling the crisis. Netflix, for example, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22353098/netflix-greenhouse-gas-emissions-climate-change-goals"&gt;plans to slash its greenhouse gases&lt;/a&gt; dramatically by the end of next year, but the streaming giant has yet to publicly advocate for any specific science-based climate policies, &lt;a href="https://www.ceres.org/practicingRPE/netflix"&gt;according to Ceres&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XD7zsn"&gt;Corporations and lawmakers alike will need to do much more to meet the scale and urgency of the climate crisis. Scientists &lt;a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/sr15/chapter/spm/"&gt;have found&lt;/a&gt; that global greenhouse gas emissions need to drop to essentially zero within a few decades to avoid a future on Earth to which life will struggle to adapt. But proposals by the Biden administration to overhaul US infrastructure and make the economy cleaner and greener are &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-senate-braces-hell-fight-over-bidens-infrastructure-plan-2021-07-12/"&gt;stalling&lt;/a&gt; in Congress. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xn7Uzr"&gt;It could also be bad for business for companies fail to live up to their climate pledges, says the nonprofit group Ceres that published the report. “Those companies that are not actively lobbying for science-based climate policies are effectively working against themselves, making it extremely challenging for them to achieve the bold targets they have set to clean up their own business operations, risking both their reputations and their financial performance,” Steven Rothstein, Ceres managing director of the Ceres Accelerator for Sustainable Capital Markets, said in a statement. After all, companies are facing &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/news/public-statement/lee-climate-change-disclosures"&gt;mounting financial risks from climate catastrophe&lt;/a&gt;. Oatly, while not an S&amp;amp;P 100 company, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22392621/oatly-climate-change-monoculture-risk-factors-ipo"&gt;recently disclosed&lt;/a&gt; that its oats are vulnerable to climate-induced disasters.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="2bQ2fH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Companies have flip-flopped on climate change &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NLGlmL"&gt;Some companies have flip-flopped on climate change over the past several years, especially as political winds changed. Twelve of the companies Ceres assessed have both lobbied for and against policies aimed at stopping climate change. Take Ford: it previously &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/1/28/14425792/ford-trump-fuel-economy-standards-risk-million-us-jobs"&gt;supported Trump’s efforts&lt;/a&gt; to weaken fuel efficiency standards. But it switched sides to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/25/20727261/trump-emissions-rollback-ford-volkswagon-honda-bmw-california-deal"&gt;back California’s stricter standards in 2019&lt;/a&gt; and then announced plans to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/24/21300974/ford-carbon-neutral-2050-climate-change-fuel-efficiency"&gt;reach carbon neutrality&lt;/a&gt; — cutting down and offsetting all of its emissions — by 2050.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nkz6hr"&gt;Other companies are guilty of climate inaction by association, according to the report. About three-quarters of S&amp;amp;P 100 companies are members of the US Chamber of Commerce, which Ceres says “has long resisted the policies the nation needs to make its economy more sustainable.” Apple is the only company Ceres assessed that abandoned the chamber over its position on climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BZDakL"&gt;Protesting inaction might be just what the US Chamber of Commerce and companies need to make changes. It’s not just Apple. Companies are facing more pressure from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453516/amazon-workers-pollution-petition-letter-demand"&gt;employees&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/5/21166275/climate-change-new-label-brands-neutral-certified"&gt;consumers&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22399329/amazon-shareholders-plastic-packaging-waste-pollution"&gt;activist shareholders&lt;/a&gt; who are concerned about the environment. Shareholders have even recently pushed fossil fuel companies like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455387/big-oil-gas-shell-exxon-chevron-climate-change"&gt;Chevron and Exxon&lt;/a&gt; to hasten efforts to work more sustainably. There are plenty of ways to push for change, and every strategy will likely have to play a role in saving the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VmZSab"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575651/corporate-climate-change-pledges-lobbying-report-s-p-100-index"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575651/corporate-climate-change-pledges-lobbying-report-s-p-100-index</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
