<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-11T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>How you can help astronomers hunt for undiscovered worlds</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T8o0DsFLRooVZkQv2rbYY0H2D5k=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68803027/Feed_Image.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kIFBQf"&gt;Astronomers discovered the stars closest to our Solar System more than 100 years ago. There’s the three-star &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/chandra/images/alpha-centauri-a-triple-star-system-about-4-light-years-from-earth.html"&gt;Alpha Centauri&lt;/a&gt; system about four light-years away and &lt;a href="https://astrobiology.nasa.gov/news/barnards-star/"&gt;Barnard’s star&lt;/a&gt; about six light-years out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tTyif2"&gt;But our celestial neck of the woods might be more crowded than we ever thought possible. In the past 25 years, astronomers have been identifying new objects that are also just a few light-years away: mysterious worlds known as brown dwarfs. Too large to be a planet but too small to become a star, brown dwarfs put out very little visible light, yet they glow brightly in the infrared. New infrared-enabled telescopes can image brown dwarfs effectively and have led to a raft of new discoveries — including &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/WISE/news/wise20130311.html"&gt;a pair of dwarfs&lt;/a&gt; just past Barnard’s star. This pair is now the third-closest known system to ours. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ohYnHh"&gt;There are untold thousands of unidentified brown dwarfs hiding in telescope imagery right now, but they aren’t exactly easy to pick up: they register as tiny smudges against a sea of other stars, galaxies, and photographic aberrations. It takes a careful human eye to spot them, so researchers interested in brown dwarf discovery find themselves in a bind: how to manually sift through millions of images of the night sky?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qm8y33"&gt;A few years back, a group of astronomers came up with a clever solution to that problem: a worldwide citizen-science effort that allows anyone with an internet connection to search through telescope imagery for new worlds. The project leverages an age-old trick to tease movement out of celestial imagery, and it’s allowed volunteers to locate thousands of new brown dwarfs. The effort may unearth worlds even closer to our Solar System than Alpha Centauri and could even turn up the Bigfoot of our Solar System: a hypothesized Planet 9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dnRbQA"&gt;Check out the video above to see how world-hunting works, and &lt;a href="https://www.zooniverse.org/projects/marckuchner/backyard-worlds-planet-9"&gt;try it out for yourself&lt;/a&gt; on the project website. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="KZfQxX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Verge Science on YouTube","description":"The home base for our explorations into the future of science.","label":"Subscribe!","url":"http://bit.ly/2FqJZMl"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/science/22254948/planet-9-discovery-brown-dwarf-nasa-solar-system-astronomy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/science/22254948/planet-9-discovery-brown-dwarf-nasa-solar-system-astronomy</id>
    <author>
      <name>William Poor</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T08:45:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T08:45:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Call of Duty League will look very different in its second season</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Call of Duty League - Launch Weekend" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nevRALAyQHFhUA_9phy1x7_gVws=/98x0:4303x2803/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68803008/1196607733.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Hannah Foslien/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TxVO1a"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt; League kicked off its inaugural season last year with a bang. The CDL launched with an ambitious vision to merge esports with city-based teams, and it all started with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/24/21078871/call-of-duty-league-opening-weekend-esports-activision-blizzard"&gt;a live event at the Minneapolis Armory&lt;/a&gt;. Not long after, that vision was forced to change. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pFTxvZ"&gt;Like most gaming leagues around the world, the CDL was forced to shift to an online format, eschewing in-person events. Perhaps surprisingly, the season was still a success; the league says last year’s finals between Dallas and Atlanta was the most-watched &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt; match ever, with a peak of 330,000 viewers. (The winning team even won &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/27/21401584/call-of-duty-league-cdl-championship-throne"&gt;an actual throne&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uwws6s"&gt;According to CDL commissioner Johanna Faries, the league was able to learn from the experience of running a remote competition last year and make some notable changes for season 2, which starts today. “There’s so much that we’ve done structurally with the season, but also strategically with how we celebrate our community and deliver world-class experiences, that I’d argue will be more of an improvement over last year,” Faries tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ht9PrE"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Nadeshot on getting back into Call of Duty with the Los Angeles Thieves","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/6/21552513/100-thieves-call-of-duty-league-cdl-la-nadeshot-interview"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RWfOx6"&gt;The list of changes for season 2 is large. The league is adopting a new structure centered on five “major” tournaments throughout the year, and it has &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.espn.com%2Fesports%2Fstory%2F_%2Fid%2F29779791%2Fcall-duty-league-moving-4-4-season-2&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F11%2F22276595%2Fcall-of-duty-league-cdl-2021-season-preview-johanna-faries-interview#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;shifted to 4 vs. 4&lt;/a&gt; competition, meaning each team had to drop a starting player from its roster. Games will also be played on PC this year, and — in one of the more unique aspects of competitive &lt;em&gt;COD&lt;/em&gt; — the game itself will shift to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21612873/call-of-duty-black-ops-cold-war-review-zombies-warzone-multiplayer-impressions"&gt;last year’s &lt;em&gt;Black Ops Cold War&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Other changes are slightly smaller in scope, like the ability for teams to design their own jerseys. There’s even a new team: Optic Gaming has moved from LA to Chicago, opening up a spot for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/6/21552513/100-thieves-call-of-duty-league-cdl-la-nadeshot-interview"&gt;the new Los Angeles Thieves&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="US2N0l"&gt;Faries says players and teams are involved in all of these decisions, particularly the ones that impact them most directly, like the roster changes. “Players and teams were exceedingly involved in that process,” she says of the move to 4 vs. 4. “We tend to mine for feedback pretty rigorously. We don’t like to make decisions in a silo or a vacuum. And I love that the outcome was well received, but we had a sense that that would be the outcome given how collaborative the process was.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WFVeFO"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DrQM5Q_jMxs?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Fy0nVM"&gt;The structural changes, meanwhile, were put in place to ensure that there are still plenty of big moments throughout the regular season, while also making each individual match feel important. “We love this notion of stage-based play, where nearly every month there’s going to be a new run at winning a major tournament in the regular season,” Faries explains. “That said, what’s also good about it is that every match is going to matter.” Teams will earn points from every match, and the top eight clubs will make it to the playoffs at the end of the season. “It all adds up,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uGAspA"&gt;The 2021 season is also kicking off at an opportune time. &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt; is arguably as popular as it’s ever been. Not only was &lt;em&gt;Black Ops Cold War&lt;/em&gt; one of the top-selling titles of 2020, but the franchise has also reached new audiences through &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty Mobile&lt;/em&gt; and the battle royale &lt;em&gt;Warzone&lt;/em&gt;. It’s not clear how the CDL plans to take advantage of that, but Faries admits that there’s “such an opportunity” to bring new fans into the league through those games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tdAcuT"&gt;Of course, the other big question is when the league will return to in-person events. Faries says that having teams based in cities around the world playing matches in home arenas is still the ultimate vision for the CDL. “We all want that,” she says. “We’re going to do it when it’s safe to do so, responsible to do so.” So while the 2021 season will start out online, the future of the league depends on both the global popularity of &lt;em&gt;COD&lt;/em&gt; and tapping into those major cities across the globe. “The two working together is really where the power of the vision of the CDL comes from.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22276595/call-of-duty-league-cdl-2021-season-preview-johanna-faries-interview"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22276595/call-of-duty-league-cdl-2021-season-preview-johanna-faries-interview</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T08:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T08:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tern HSD P9 review: the everything e-bike</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;A midtail cargo bike for the whole family&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="gt7YoQ"&gt;The best measure of an electric bike is how easily it slots into your everyday life. By that metric, the Tern HSD P9 is one of the better ones I’ve tested. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u85wvq"&gt;Tern let me borrow one at the end of July, and I rode it at least 12 miles every day around my suburban New Jersey neighborhood for about a month and a half. I took my son to daycare, went to the grocery store, the farmer’s market, the liquor store, the drug store, and a variety of other places too menial to remember. It kept me socially distant from my neighbors as I rode around town and kept me out of my car, which I always appreciate. And whether I was hauling dual panniers loaded with groceries or just myself, the ride quality was impeccable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l65OxH"&gt;To be clear, this isn’t the fastest, most powerful, or even the best-looking e-bike I’ve ever ridden. But it was a solid workhorse that got the job done. That’s mostly due to the Bosch Active Line Plus mid-drive motor, one of the best on the market today, silently churning away between the cranks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uZ2Peb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10334626"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xjnKEF"&gt;But it’s also because the HSD is an extremely flexible e-bike. The low-step frame combined with the adjustable handlebars and seat post, as well as a custom SunTour front suspension fork, help make this a bike that can easily be passed around among family members or friends. Riders of all shapes and sizes will feel at ease on the HSD. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F3Frk3"&gt;If it looks a bit shrunken down for a cargo bike, that’s by design. Those in need of something larger can level up to the Tern GSD, which has an extended rack that can carry even more stuff than the HSD. (I’m testing a GSD right now, and I’m very infatuated with it.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="IFka33"&gt;&lt;q&gt;If it looks a bit shrunken down for a cargo bike, that’s by design&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jtTctO"&gt;During my month-and-a-half test period, the HSD barely demanded my attention, nor did it draw any stares from passers-by or take up too much space in my garage. (I got one looky-loo from a lady who was impressed with the fingernail red paint job.) And while the $3,199 price tag means this won’t be an affordable option for many, you do get a lot of bike for that price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6BS6ed"&gt;Regardless, when it comes to cargo bikes, I try not to compare it to other non-electric bikes, but rather to the car I am trying to replace. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wR-HPXOjlyEwtv2E4163cKHZH2w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21870576/ahawkins_200825_4180_0034.0.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MyRzySaRCRvLT_lGIE0EPn557j0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21870575/ahawkins_200825_4180_0040.0.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BzcvFwZkGHqu4v1dXSoFbLtf1wU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21870568/ahawkins_200825_4180_0098.0.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zMY4vHGvK_wLokFkMhojoMFgqPM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21870578/ahawkins_200825_4180_0025.0.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Rf7WIR"&gt;Tern got its name when several founding members of the company were hanging out poolside after a bike conference in Las Vegas, drinking beer and talking about the 2010 surfing documentary &lt;a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1407927/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;180° South&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which includes a deep discussion about how people live with nature. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rizl40"&gt;Cycling through some possible names for their nascent company, the group eventually settled on Tern, the name for an Arctic migratory bird that is lightweight, a global traveler, and long-lived. It was also a homophone for “turn,” which fed into the group’s idea of “turning around and moving forward to face the challenges head-on,” according to Tern’s website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZSnkir"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Terns are Arctic migratory birds that are lightweight, global travelers, and long-lived&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="o6AFMq"&gt;Tern, which is headquartered in Taipei, Taiwan, fancies itself an urban transportation company, but it’s mostly known for its non-electric, folding bikes. In August 2014, the company announced its first electric bike, the eLink, which weighed 46 pounds (21 kg) and could fold in under 10 seconds. The following year, Tern launched its first lineup of electrified models using BionX motor systems. Later, the company shifted to using more popular powertrain systems by Bosch and Bafang. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xrQqDN"&gt;The HSD P9, which first came out in 2019, is described as “enormously useful [and] surprisingly small.” Indeed, the HSD is a great bike for anyone looking for cargo-carrying power without those cumbersome cargo bike specs. It’s not exactly lightweight, clocking in at roughly 56 lbs. But when compared to electric cargo bikes from companies like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/8/20791435/radwagon-electric-cargo-bike-review-car-replacement"&gt;Rad Power Bikes&lt;/a&gt; (73 lbs), &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/26/21269590/carqon-cargo-bike-review-price-specs"&gt;Carqon&lt;/a&gt; (88 lbs), or &lt;a href="https://www.urbanarrow.com/"&gt;Urban Arrow&lt;/a&gt; (104 lbs), the HSD P9 is practically a featherweight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MyIcYhKuX4sYzQg3hntO08h3QJ4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21870566/ahawkins_200826_4180_0128.0.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="751kW5"&gt;Speaking of specs, here’s what you need to know about the Tern HSD P9:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="1u2JZz"&gt;Motor: Bosch Active Line Plus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="GFgZBF"&gt;Top speed: 20 mph (32 km/h)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="VYdgw5"&gt;Range: 26–69 miles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uvuVgv"&gt;Battery: 36V 11Ah (400 Wh)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="5X79xj"&gt;Weight: 56.5 lbs (25.7 kg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="aY6imz"&gt;Brakes: Shimano hydraulic disc brakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WD4dK1"&gt;Tires: 20 inches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="mLEZPw"&gt;Extras: SunTour suspension front fork&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2Jrlt4"&gt;Price: $3,199&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vLT3lL-OiZlHdRX3lmcIrF25C7s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21870580/ahawkins_200825_4180_0019.0.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MJrcQK"&gt;The HSD P9 is a Class 1 electric bike in the US, meaning it’s pedal-assist with no throttle and a top speed of 20 mph. There were times when I missed the twist throttle, especially when getting started from a standstill on a steep incline with a kid and extra cargo on the rear rack. But I also understand why some manufacturers abhor the throttle — and honestly believe that throttles will eventually run into regulatory issues in the future — so I try not to begrudge any bike for its exclusion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oTyGU1"&gt;HSD stands for “haul stuff daily” — or if you’re out of earshot of your kids, “haul shit daily.” Arleigh Greenwald, the eponymous Bike Shop Girl who recently got a job as a product manager at Tern (congrats, Arleigh!), &lt;a href="https://bikeshopgirl.com/tern-hsd-the-crossover-of-electric-bikes/"&gt;calls the HSD&lt;/a&gt; “the crossover of electric bikes,” and I wholeheartedly agree. If Riese and Muller’s Load 75 is the Cadillac Escalade of e-bikes and the RadWagon is the Chevy Suburban, then Tern’s HSD is definitely the Toyota Rav4 — a highly capable daily driver with just enough space for a kid and some cargo.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="33cpZs"&gt;&lt;q&gt;HSD stands for “haul stuff daily”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YLX9s7"&gt;The HSD isn’t completely incognito — just look at that cherry red paint job. It does have some interesting design touches, from the “HSD” logo carved out of the frame below the head tube to the rear rack that also doubles as a stand for when you want to park the bike vertically. That’s a great space-saver for anyone who keeps their bike in their apartment, for example. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lzg20E"&gt;Tern makes a couple of folding bikes, like the Vektron, BYB, and fantastically named Verge. I would classify the HSD as a quasi-folding bike since it lacks the full folding capabilities of Tern’s other models. The handlebars can fold down, but that’s about it. Still, it’s a useful feature if you need to transport the bike in the back of your car, for example. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZkwmAZ"&gt;The rear rack is rated for 132 lbs, while the whole bike can carry a combined weight of 374 lbs. Tern sent me two of its Cargo Hold 37 panniers, each of which can hold several big grocery bags. When empty, the bags can be cinched tightly to the side of the bike. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YqA7Cy"&gt;Performance-wise, I wasn’t that impressed with the 400Wh battery pack. While Tern claims the HSD has a range of 69 miles (110km), I found myself needing to recharge the battery after as little as 30 miles of riding on mostly flat surfaces with a few steep hills mixed in. This may seem paltry, but it’s fairly standard across e-bikes, especially while riding in the highest setting offered. This is my preferred riding style, and I know that’s true for many others. That said, more range would be nice, especially considering the HSD’s $3,199 price tag. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/in1L_t3ByfNTUgXKOFZWrgSUO2A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21870573/ahawkins_200825_4180_0048.0.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TlWHZl"&gt;The battery, while not integrated in the frame like I would prefer, was neatly stored behind the seat post, parallel to the rear rack. It’s a placement that I think is fairly unique to Tern, and it avoids the unsightliness of a bulging battery pack perched on the downtube. Plus, it helps distribute the weight to the back of the bike, which helps prevent it from toppling over when parking it vertically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s04u3M"&gt;The HSD’s small, fast wheels mean there’s a much lower center of gravity than most cargo bikes, which made cornering much more fun. And it’s shorter than the average road bike, which makes it easier to maneuver and store. The upright seating position gave me a good vantage point to see the cars around me, which made me feel safer while I rode. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="anHeyc"&gt;I find myself torn over the value proposition of the Tern HSD. It’s a smaller, lighter cargo bike than most, which is certainly an advantage, and yet, it costs noticeably more than other, more powerful cargo bikes. What do you get for that extra cash? Easy storage is nice, but most of that cost is for the Bosch mid-drive motor. The German company arguably makes one of the most reliable and dependable systems in the world — and that comes at a price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cIqCaP"&gt;Overall, the Tern HSD P9 is a sturdy electric cargo bike that’s easy on the eyes and easy to stash away when needed. It’s highly adaptable and has a decently powerful drivetrain that shrinks most hills down to size. While I don’t think the HSD is for everybody, I do believe that it aspires to be easy and approachable enough that anyone can ride it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BFDi7x"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Andrew Hawkins / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Iiy6vu"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22274747/tern-hsd-p9-ebike-review-electric-cargo-bike-price-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22274747/tern-hsd-p9-ebike-review-electric-cargo-bike-price-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T06:44:05-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T06:44:05-05:00</updated>
    <title>Instagram bans prominent anti-vaxxer Robert F. Kennedy, but Facebook page remains active</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ufIisGyjuh50ystlC9Ak90E55ds=/0x0:4261x2841/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68802684/1093808886.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Joe Scarnici/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DSjqhU"&gt;Facebook-owned Instagram has permanently banned Robert F. Kennedy Jr, a prominent anti-vaccine activist who had over 800,000 followers on the platform, &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/instagram-bans-robert-f-kennedy-jr-over-covid-19-vaccine-misinformation-11613029259?mod=pls_whats_news_us_business_f"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;. A spokesperson for the service said his account was removed “for repeatedly sharing debunked claims about the coronavirus or vaccines.” His account on Facebook, however, is still live, with Facebook &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/digital/news/instagram-bans-robert-f-kennedy-jr-vaccine-misinformation-1234905740/"&gt;telling &lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that it has no plan to remove the page “at this time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qmwJXb"&gt;Kennedy has been cited as one of the top spreaders of COVID-19 misinformation by the nonprofit organization Center for Countering Digital Hate (CCDH), the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt; notes. He also founded Children’s Health Defense, which &lt;a href="https://252f2edd-1c8b-49f5-9bb2-cb57bb47e4ba.filesusr.com/ugd/f4d9b9_fddbfb2a0c05461cb4bdce2892f3cad0.pdf"&gt;CCDH calls&lt;/a&gt; a leading anti-vaccine charity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="GvZw0Z"&gt;&lt;q&gt;His Facebook and Twitter pages are still live&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Q62dAz"&gt;Kennedy’s removal from the platform comes just a few days after Facebook announced it’s stepping up efforts to combat vaccine misinformation on its platforms. Although it banned anti-vaccination ads &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21514535/facebook-anti-vaxx-ad-ban-moderation-covid-19-vaccine"&gt;last October&lt;/a&gt;, and started removing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/3/22150425/facebook-covid-19-vaccine-coronavirus-misinformation-ban"&gt;vaccine misinformation in December&lt;/a&gt;, this week it said it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/8/22272883/facebook-covid-19-vaccine-misinformation-expanded-removal-autism"&gt;expanding the list&lt;/a&gt; of false COVID-19 and vaccine-related claims it would remove. In particular, it will remove posts that claim COVID-19 is man-made, or that vaccines are dangerous or ineffective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FWKPWD"&gt;Children’s Health Defense has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/18/21373530/robert-kennedy-childrens-health-defense-facebook-zuckerberg-fact-checking-lawsuit"&gt;previously challenged&lt;/a&gt; Facebook’s vaccine fact-checking initiatives. In a lawsuit filed last year, the group claimed that initiatives like fact-checking labels placed on its page created a “falsely disparaging” image of the organization. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="az8Ur0"&gt;Although Kennedy’s Instagram account has been removed, his pages are still live on Facebook and Twitter, with hundreds of thousands of followers between them. On Facebook itself he has over 300,000 followers, with 215,000 followers on Twitter. As of this writing, his most recent posts on both platforms contain links to Children’s Health Defense.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22277880/robert-f-kennedy-jr-instagram-banned-covid-19-vaccine-misinformation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22277880/robert-f-kennedy-jr-instagram-banned-covid-19-vaccine-misinformation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T05:02:49-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T05:02:49-05:00</updated>
    <title>Discord iOS update makes it easier to steal memes from Twitter</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mDVBbs0fisUCZrUXbbA6o-i1Ljg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68802537/acastro_210129_1777_discord_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GO5hjj"&gt;Meme thieves rejoice! Discord’s latest &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/discord-talk-chat-hang-out/id985746746"&gt;update on iOS&lt;/a&gt; adds a new option to make it easier to save images from Twitter embeds, handy if you want to save memes from tweets dropped in the server. Or, as the changelog for version 60.0 of the iOS app puts it, “Meme-stealing powers are about to go super saiyan.” To use it, long press on the tweet in question, and then select “Save Image.” It’s a lot simpler than the &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/discordapp/comments/jb457z/help_save_failed_check_your_system_network_and/gaadubs?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3"&gt;workarounds people were previously forced to use&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QkY4uX0hFNYk_kj86xf5ovOtOeY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22296898/IMG_0407.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot: Discord&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The changelog shown in Discord’s latest iOS version.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1eSXCh"&gt;There’s no mention of the feature for the service’s Windows or Android apps, which both also received updates this week. However, on Android it already seems to be possible to save images from tweets by tapping the image to make it fullscreen, and then using the download button on the top of the screen. Although the new iOS feature allows you to download static images, it doesn’t appear to work with gifs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8z8s9S"&gt;As well as the new feature for meme thieves, Discord now supports mobile screen share on iPad “so you can now do art together, play mobile games on your tablet, and watch Robert get his math homework wrong for the 5th time from the comfort of your bed.” You can read the full changelog in Discord’s settings menu on desktop and mobile.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/2/11/22277855/discord-ios-update-twitter-image-embed-save-meme-stealing"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/2/11/22277855/discord-ios-update-twitter-image-embed-save-meme-stealing</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-11T04:37:50-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T04:37:50-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft tried to acquire Pinterest, FT reports</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P0U7lTqcZExaXNBK1KbliNbXHTc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68802499/acastro_180507_1777_microsoft_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FJeGdt"&gt;Microsoft has reportedly held talks with Pinterest in an attempt to acquire the social network. &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/f88b8474-e791-4efb-a9f6-54c8222680fe"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that the software giant approached Pinterest in recent months about a deal, but that the talks are “currently not active.” Had a deal taken place, it would have been Microsoft’s biggest to date, given Pinterest is valued at $51 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fDwlAN"&gt;Microsoft’s potential interest in Pinterest could signal an emerging strategy for its continued cloud push, though. The Windows maker has been trying to convince more big online services to use its Azure cloud offerings. Amazon’s AWS dominates this part of the market, and big names like Pinterest could draw in additional Azure customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="3qXKcQ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Microsoft wanted a similar deal for TikTok&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QRHSDB"&gt;It’s an approach we saw &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/3/21352309/microsoft-tiktok-acquisition-deal-why-us-countries-data"&gt;Microsoft attempt with TikTok&lt;/a&gt;. While not successful, a TikTok deal would have offered Microsoft valuable data and an outlet for its myriad of other services, and also act as a giant ad for its partners and resellers that try to convince businesses to go with Azure and not AWS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GbOmzK"&gt;Microsoft has acquired some significant companies under CEO Satya Nadella. A $7.5 billion deal saw &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/4/17422788/microsoft-github-acquisition-official-deal"&gt;GitHub join Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; a few years back, and Microsoft’s $26.2 billion &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/6/13/11920938/microsoft-linkedin-acquisition-why-report"&gt;acquisition of LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; was Nadella’s first major acquisition. Microsoft is also in the late stages of finalizing its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21449178/microsoft-xbox-bethesda-zenimax-media-acquisition-xbox-game-pass"&gt;Bethesda acquisition&lt;/a&gt;, valued at $7.5 billion.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22277845/microsoft-pinterest-acquisition-azure-cloud-services-rumors"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22277845/microsoft-pinterest-acquisition-azure-cloud-services-rumors</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T23:40:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T23:40:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Mandalorian star Pedro Pascal will play Joel in HBO’s The Last of Us TV show</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="2020 Vanity Fair Oscar Party Hosted By Radhika Jones - Arrivals" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-DsRO3g_SrQ6og70hbdA5NAkIs8=/0x0:3752x2501/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68801906/1205218466.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Frazer Harrison/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GUc7cB"&gt;Pedro Pascal, who you might recognize as &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt; himself&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;has been cast as Joel in HBO’s TV adaptation of &lt;em&gt;The Last of Us, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2021/02/pedro-pascal-star-joel-the-last-of-us-hbo-series-video-game-playstation-1234691935/"&gt;as first reported by &lt;em&gt;Deadline&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The casting was confirmed shortly after by &lt;em&gt;The Last of Us&lt;/em&gt; creative director (and an executive producer and writer for the show) Neil Druckmann.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="sr63TN"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Aaaaand there’s the other half. Stoked to have Pedro aboard our show! &lt;a href="https://t.co/Etsjvfb2Wi"&gt;https://t.co/Etsjvfb2Wi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Dr. Uckmann (@Neil_Druckmann) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Neil_Druckmann/status/1359710048302206976?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eIR5od"&gt;Pascal’s confirmed casting comes just hours after the news that Bella Ramsey, who played the fan-favorite ruler Lyanna Mormont in &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22277372/the-last-of-us-ellie-game-of-thrones-bella-ramsey-hbo-lyanna-mormont"&gt;will play Ellie&lt;/a&gt;, Joel’s surrogate daughter. (Pascal also had a role on &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones &lt;/em&gt;— he played Oberyn Martell, the Red Viper of Dorne.) It also comes shortly after the news that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22277540/star-wars-severs-ties-the-mandalorian-gina-carano-cara-dune"&gt;Lucasfilm has severed ties&lt;/a&gt; with one of Pascal’s co-stars on &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt;, Gina Carano.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W_XloP5mnDYQ63iT_p3ZckJhmtw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22296668/joel_and_ellie_last_of_us.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Naughty Dog&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Joel and Ellie, as seen in PlayStation exclusive&lt;/em&gt; The Last of Us.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="PLjmM8"&gt;The first game in &lt;em&gt;The Last of Us&lt;/em&gt; series focuses largely around Joel and Ellie’s relationship, and it seems likely that the initial run of the show will keep the focus on the two characters as well. In addition to Pascal and Ramsey, the series already has  some other notable talent on board — &lt;em&gt;Chernobyl’s &lt;/em&gt;Craig Mazin is set to be a writer and executive producer, and Kantemir Balagov, who directed indie WWII drama &lt;em&gt;Beanpole, &lt;/em&gt;is set to direct the pilot episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="o9qWKN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"A Game of Thrones fan favorite will star as Ellie in HBO’s adaptation of The Last of Us","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22277372/the-last-of-us-ellie-game-of-thrones-bella-ramsey-hbo-lyanna-mormont"},{"title":"Star Wars severs ties with The Mandalorian star Gina Carano","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22277540/star-wars-severs-ties-the-mandalorian-gina-carano-cara-dune"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="SvActO"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22277687/mandalorian-star-pedro-pascal-joel-hbo-the-last-of-us-tv-show"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22277687/mandalorian-star-pedro-pascal-joel-hbo-the-last-of-us-tv-show</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T23:12:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T23:12:30-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s own iOS apps were begging for updates that don’t exist, but the company says it was because of a bug</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/__hrh68YFX878KTHrhosh2yjV8w=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68801190/acastro_180427_1777_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration: Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MuPfVU"&gt;Google hasn’t updated many of its iOS apps in weeks, perhaps to avoid potential criticism from what might be revealed from Apple’s new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/14/22174017/apple-app-store-new-privacy-labels-ios-apps-public"&gt;mandatory App Store privacy labels&lt;/a&gt;. But for a little while on Wednesday, some of Google’s own iOS apps seemed to be &lt;em&gt;complaining&lt;/em&gt; about the wait: we were seeing confusing notices inside Gmail, Google Maps and Google Photos saying that the apps were out of date — even though there aren’t newer versions of the apps available (&lt;a href="https://spencerdailey.com/2021/02/10/google-itself-is-now-telling-users-their-apps-are-out-of-date-despite-no-updates-being-available/"&gt;via Techmeme editor Spencer Dailey)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t7nTVe"&gt;But we aren’t seeing the notices now, and Google says they were there because of a bug. “We’ve identified a bug and an update has been rolled out to resolve this issue,” Google said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ImE1t5"&gt;While the notice was appearing, you could see it when you tried to try log into your account. After you typed in your email address, you might have seen this warning message: “You should update this app. The version you’re using doesn’t include the latest security features to keep you protected. Only continue if you understand the risks.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/50aalyYUtKLX_c0TUpk7oOY5cs0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22296132/Image_from_iOS.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Google’s notice informing a &lt;/em&gt;Verge&lt;em&gt; staffer that their app is out of date.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="oFBvQQ"&gt;After you tapped the continue button, you could use the app as normal — they would still work. But without additional context, users could have worried that they didn’t have the latest and most secure version of an app. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uW99uX"&gt;Google had promised its apps would start including the new mandatory Apple app privacy labels in a blog post &lt;a href="https://blog.google/technology/safety-security/our-work-keep-you-safe-and-control-your-privacy"&gt;on January 12th&lt;/a&gt;, and the company has technically kept its word. Google Authenticator and Stadia, for example, have been updated with the labels, and in our testing with those two apps, we didn’t see the “this app is out of date” message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CA05Pb"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 10th, 11:12PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: We aren’t seeing the notices anymore, and Google told &lt;/em&gt;The Verge&lt;em&gt; that they were due to a bug.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22277304/google-ios-apps-out-of-date-update-message"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22277304/google-ios-apps-out-of-date-update-message</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T22:34:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T22:34:16-05:00</updated>
    <title>Star Wars severs ties with The Mandalorian star Gina Carano</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Premiere Of Disney+’s “The Mandalorian” - Arrivals" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/s-y1zJDsFYYKcSaD6UIlKYldi9Y=/0x32:3000x2032/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68801711/1187548006.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Rodin Eckenroth/FilmMagic&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oO1gr8"&gt;Disney has severed ties with Gina Carano, who played Cara Dune on &lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt;, the company announced on Wednesday evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HHsgPL"&gt;“Gina Carano is not currently employed by Lucasfilm and there are no plans for her to be in the future,” a Lucasfilm spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZRvt8K"&gt;Carano has recently come under scrutiny for several posts published on social media, including an anti-Semitic post on her Instagram. Some of the content from Carano’s tweets are captured in screenshots, seen below in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DinsDarksaber/status/1359547737453207555?s=20"&gt;this tweet&lt;/a&gt;. Lucasfilm’s spokesperson denounced Carano’s social media posts, telling &lt;em&gt;The Verge, &lt;/em&gt;“&lt;em&gt;﻿&lt;/em&gt;her social media posts denigrating people based on their cultural and religious identities are abhorrent and unacceptable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5aqOrb"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;She's transphobic, anti-mask, alt-right who parrots QAn*n conspiracies, doesn't believe in systematic racism, and now shares anti-semitic images. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/starwars?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@starwars&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Disney?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Disney&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FireGinaCarano?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#FireGinaCarano&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/wi4rbwXwvs"&gt;pic.twitter.com/wi4rbwXwvs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ara   • she/they (@DinsDarksaber) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DinsDarksaber/status/1359547737453207555?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="o6EJUg"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;WHY IS GINA CARANO NOT TRENDING SHE LITERALLY POSTED NAZI PROPAGANDA ON HER INSTAGRAM STORY LMAOOOO &lt;a href="https://t.co/G1C5lJ3Quf"&gt;pic.twitter.com/G1C5lJ3Quf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Parker   ⚓️ || #BLM (@parkerbnelson) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/parkerbnelson/status/1359556852896460800?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uK1zq6"&gt;This isn’t the first time Carano has been criticized for posts made on social media. In September, she listed her pronouns as “beep / bop / boop” on her Twitter bio, which &lt;a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/arts-entertainment/tv/news/star-wars-mandalorian-gina-carano-trans-pronouns-bio-twitter-disney-b436015.html"&gt;was condemned for being transphobic&lt;/a&gt;. She removed them after a conversation with co-star Pedro Pascal.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22277540/star-wars-severs-ties-the-mandalorian-gina-carano-cara-dune"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22277540/star-wars-severs-ties-the-mandalorian-gina-carano-cara-dune</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T21:57:32-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T21:57:32-05:00</updated>
    <title>PlayStation Network was down around the globe for more than an hour</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="PlayStation controllers" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Hv2U1elC3ued7Vi1vs1U-ik3il0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68801370/vpavic_191127_untitled_0059_Edit.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zQv5dc"&gt;Sony’s PlayStation Network experienced a global outage on Wednesday evening that appeared to last for more than an hour. On the &lt;a href="https://status.playstation.com/"&gt;PlayStation Network status page&lt;/a&gt;, every service except PlayStation Video was marked as experiencing issues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xvDNgn"&gt;Tens of thousands of users reported issues with PlayStation Network &lt;a href="https://downdetector.com/status/playstation-network/"&gt;as shown by DownDetector&lt;/a&gt;, where &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Rocket League &lt;/em&gt;and many other games all saw spikes in user reports as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PRd4S3"&gt;We saw reports in a wide variety of languages on Twitter, and PlayStation Japan officially confirmed the outage as well. Multiple publishers, including Bethesda, &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; maker Epic Games, Rockstar, and Sega, posted tweets alerting players about the outage while it was happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Kro0ad"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;⚠️The PSN is currently experiencing a service interruption.  Please check here for status updates: &lt;a href="https://t.co/2O1UsSG0YR"&gt;https://t.co/2O1UsSG0YR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Bethesda Support (@BethesdaSupport) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BethesdaSupport/status/1359678714938855428?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="QQsWii"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;PSA: We are aware that PSN is down and players are unable to connect to Rocket League. Please see the PlayStation Network status page for updates.&lt;a href="https://t.co/6fsLVVbDcF"&gt;https://t.co/6fsLVVbDcF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Rocket League (@RocketLeague) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RocketLeague/status/1359678985119166467?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="rVORIj"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;PlayStation Network is currently experiencing an outage. As PlayStation works to resolve this issue, you can keep up with the status here:&lt;a href="https://t.co/rNAFmWENN3"&gt;https://t.co/rNAFmWENN3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Fortnite Status (@FortniteStatus) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FortniteStatus/status/1359675175210524672?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="YTIy90"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;PlayStation®Network is experiencing issues.  For more information, please refer to: &lt;a href="https://t.co/PAlbCbBceR"&gt;https://t.co/PAlbCbBceR&lt;/a&gt; *BK&lt;/p&gt;— Rockstar Support (@RockstarSupport) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RockstarSupport/status/1359676101174378498?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="7XtHYl"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We are aware of the Playstation network error adventurers are currently experiencing, making them unable to log into Black Desert Console. We are looking into the matter and hope to have the issue resolved as quickly as possible. Thank you for your patience in the matter. &lt;a href="https://t.co/h9zv15Jlg2"&gt;pic.twitter.com/h9zv15Jlg2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Black Desert Console (@PlayBlackDesert) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PlayBlackDesert/status/1359680809121296384?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="iDyk7y"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Hello Pilots! We’re aware that the PlayStation Network may not be available at this time. We appreciate your understanding as we tackle this unforeseen issue, and apologize for the inconvenience. Thank you for your patience. &lt;a href="https://t.co/621ZodthEM"&gt;https://t.co/621ZodthEM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— MOBILE SUIT GUNDAM BATTLE OPERATION 2 (@GBO2EN) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GBO2EN/status/1359684353878417408?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="6fshfL"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We are aware that PlayStation Network is experiencing issues and are monitoring the situation. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NWPS4?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#NWPS4&lt;/a&gt; players may be impacted.&lt;/p&gt;— Neverwinter (@NeverwinterGame) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NeverwinterGame/status/1359674291093073920?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="D6wRiu"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="ja" dir="ltr"&gt;【"PSN"障害発生のお知らせ】2/11 10:52頃より、“PSN”にて障害が発生しております。『PSO2』のゲームサーバーに問題は発生しておりません。 &lt;a href="https://t.co/akX4Q3IPJ7"&gt;https://t.co/akX4Q3IPJ7&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/PSO2?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#PSO2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— PhantasyStarOnline2 (@sega_pso2) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sega_pso2/status/1359684335771676675?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="LuAvIl"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="ja" dir="ltr"&gt;【PlayStation Network障害発生のご案内】&lt;br&gt;ただいま、PSN（PS Storeを含む）をご利用いただけない場合がございます。&lt;br&gt;ご利用のお客様にはご不便をおかけし大変申し訳ございません。調査及び復旧作業を行っておりますので、いましばらくお待ちいただきますよう宜しくお願い申し上げます。 &lt;a href="https://t.co/X5YRssDa0D"&gt;pic.twitter.com/X5YRssDa0D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ask PlayStation JP (@AskPS_JP) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AskPS_JP/status/1359681622703034370?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZlonsE"&gt;During the outage, two of us here at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; had trouble playing games on PlayStation Now. Oddly, though, I was able to hop into a &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; match, a colleague was able to play &lt;em&gt;Destruction AllStars&lt;/em&gt;, and my editor was able to download content without issues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aHYSnc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 10th, 9:57PM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: the PlayStation Network status page shows that services have returned to normal, so we have made changes to this post accordingly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22277439/sony-playstation-network-global-outage"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22277439/sony-playstation-network-global-outage</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
