<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-15T11:26:44-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T11:26:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T11:26:44-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitch says passwords weren’t exposed in massive data breach</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/A4VEkwYODEuYKUZOu_cJUMwS82Y=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69999719/acastro_200901_1777_twitch_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ebknHa"&gt;Twitch has definitively stated that passwords weren’t exposed in last week’s major data breach. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HeWPKD"&gt;“Twitch passwords have not been exposed,” Twitch said in an update to its webpage about &lt;a href="https://blog.twitch.tv/en/2021/10/15/updates-on-the-twitch-security-incident/"&gt;the security incident&lt;/a&gt;. “We are also confident that systems that store Twitch login credentials, which are hashed with bcrypt, were not accessed, nor were full credit card numbers or ACH / bank information.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6tR4Vv"&gt;Last week, what appeared to be leaked source code for Twitch &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/6/22712250/twitch-hack-leak-data-streamer-revenue-steam-competitor"&gt;hit the web&lt;/a&gt;, and in Friday’s update, Twitch confirmed that was the case. “The exposed data primarily contained documents from Twitch’s source code repository, as well as a subset of creator payout data,” the company said. Twitch claims that the information exposed “only affected a small fraction of users, and the customer impact is minimal,” and it says it is following up directly with those who were affected. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TqITPK"&gt;Sources who spoke to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; last week painted a picture of a company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/7/22714160/twitch-hack-security-data-breach-problems"&gt;with bad security practices&lt;/a&gt; and detailed a previously unreported security problem that took place in 2017. On Thursday, &lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt; reported on &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/pkb7qg/urgent-pizza-untold-story-of-the-largest-twitch-hack-in-history"&gt;another massive hack&lt;/a&gt; that happened in 2014. In Friday’s update, Twitch said it has “taken steps to further secure our service.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="TMSK5U"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Twitch’s security problems started long before this week’s hack","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/7/22714160/twitch-hack-security-data-breach-problems"},{"title":"Twitch source code and creator payouts part of massive leak","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/6/22712250/twitch-hack-leak-data-streamer-revenue-steam-competitor"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728217/twitch-passwords-data-breach-secure"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728217/twitch-passwords-data-breach-secure</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T11:09:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T11:09:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>ZmBIZI’s $550 Z2 phone pays you for your data usage</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HzIRy1GZvCR0i5xnYHyUYlIdLa0=/0x0:2522x1681/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69999652/image__1___1_.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The ZmBIZI Z2 is a the $550 4G phone that pays you for the personal data you share on your phone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HflYoT"&gt;We live so much of our lives on our smartphones these days that our mobile devices are just full of valuable data that we often unknowingly and freely give to all the major tech companies: our spending habits, our personal preferences, our locations, and much more. Since we can’t really live without our phones, and tech companies aren’t going to stop monetizing our data without a fight, we might as well get our cut of the data pie. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3ooKny"&gt;That’s the premise of ZmBIZI phones, the LA-based and minority-owned startup backed by the &lt;a href="https://streetcredcapital.com/portfolio-item/zmbizi/"&gt;fintech lender Street Cred Capital&lt;/a&gt; that is trying to make our phones work for us. Both its new phone, the Z2, and its proprietary software are designed to share the profit that your mobile data generate, back with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oUyqmx"&gt;I spoke with ZmBIZI co-founder &lt;a href="https://www.gq.co.za/culture/entertainment/alpesh-patel-the-african-connection-16554524"&gt;Alpesh Patel&lt;/a&gt;, the former director of sales at Motorola in Africa and founder of Mi-Fone in Africa, who explained ZmBIZI’s ambitions on both the hardware and software fronts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZoyxnN"&gt;ZmBIZI is putting its bets on its new $550 unlocked 4G phone, the Z2. It has a high-resolution, 6.67-inch Full HD+ LCD display (1080 x 2400 pixels; 20:9 aspect ratio), a MediaTek Helio P60 processor, 8GB RAM, and 128GB of storage. The version I saw through a Zoom video call has a glossy fuchsia back cover with transparent cut-outs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fdwasm"&gt;Like many phones these days, the Z2 has multiple cameras on the back. It has a 64-megapixel rear camera, a 16-megapixel wide-angle, 5-megapixel macro, and a 0.3-megapixel photosensitive one. The Z2 is powered by a 4,400mAh battery, has a dual-SIM slot, but has no 3.5mm audio jack. According to &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/news/this-startups-flagship-smartphone-pays-you"&gt;PCMag’s research, this phone is likely a rebrand of Cubot X50&lt;/a&gt; with some tweaks. PCMag also notes that it will work best on AT&amp;amp;T’s network, will have limited coverage on T-Mobile, and is unlikely to work at all on Verizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mk4JnC"&gt;Most importantly, the Z2 can accept contactless payments through NFC, which means it can be used as a point-of-sale terminal for someone running a food truck without additional hardware, for example. This is actually the first phone &lt;a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210616005325/en/Visa-Launches-its-First-U.S.-Tap-to-Phone-Pilot-in-Washington-D.C.-to-Support-Region%E2%80%99s-Black-Owned-Small-Businesses"&gt;Visa has partnered with to pilot its Tap to Phone&lt;/a&gt; program in America. This means customers can just tap their existing forms of payment (card or Apple or Google Pay) rather than download a third-party app like Venmo to pay or use a card swiping dongle from Square. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OnR7PacRrSulpTnWKQ_A0q-pKEQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22928858/ZmBIZI_Z2_back.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;ZmBIZI&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The ZmBIZI Z2 has quad cameras on the back, with a 64-megapixel main camera.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="S8fgQ4"&gt;The main selling point of this phone is that you can earn ZmBIZI Coins by using partnered apps or doing organic smartphone tasks on the Z2. It’s similar to using cash-back websites like Rakuten to shop, where you get money back by buying at their partnered retailers. Each ZmBIZI coin is equivalent to $0.01 USD, and when you’ve accumulated at least $20 USD, then you can move your coins onto a digital Visa debit card preloaded on the phone, which enables you to use that money in the real world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Us7qjW"&gt;The website and press materials claim you can make an average of $10 per month from the Z2, but that number feels very optimistic. Patel explained the payment scheme this way: when you buy something with your credit card on your phone, the retailer will share a fraction of the 3.5-percentage processing fee with ZmBIZI, and ZmBIZI will share 1/5 of that amount, evenly divided by the number of its users. This is the amount you can expect. Perhaps other things you do on the phone, such as viewing ads, will offer bigger payouts, but it’s hard to tell over a short Zoom call with limited app demonstrations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5dww2f"&gt;Based on what I could see over Zoom and the company’s website, the Z2 homescreen has a circular launcher that ZmBIZI plans to serve custom ads to its users, so they can watch and get paid. This feature is more of a concept rather than a reality at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IfnTlI"&gt;The Z2’s list of curated apps with rewards is long and often strange; you can see the complete list by hovering your mouse over different app icons on its &lt;a href="https://zmbizi.com/"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. For example, you can get paid by doing something very simple, like using Yahoo Search rather than Google to search the web, because they have a paid partnership. There’s also an aptly named app called Earn Money, which gives you tasks like snap photos around your neighborhood and surveys to complete to earn your rewards. Perhaps you’d prefer the Smilecheck app, where “the more you smile, the more you get paid” — my guess is that you’d be feeding the AI valuable facial recognition information. It’s not clear whether each app will disclose how and where it will be using the information it collects about you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sbqIaS"&gt;Some of these coin-earning tasks are essentially asking you, the user, to allow yourself to become a data guinea pig, but I’m not sure the minimal reward will be worthwhile. I used to do &lt;a href="https://surveys.google.com/google-opinion-rewards/"&gt;Google’s Opinion Rewards surveys&lt;/a&gt; for fun until I got bored answering the same few questions, never redeemed my Google Play points, and have since lost track of my account. With the Z2, I guess even if you stop participating in the data collection, you’ll still be able to use the $550 Z2 as a fully functioning phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="21FqN5"&gt;Who knows if the company will be able to realize its vision of paying its users for their data usage or if the startup will just fold. Back in 2017, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/7/14841604/freedompop-free-mobile-plan-android-smartphone-v7"&gt;FreedomPop V7 phone in Europe&lt;/a&gt; had promised a “free mobile plan for life,” but it offered such low data limits (200 megabytes) that made the company pivot its strategy again. Or the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/21/22635779/ceo-saygus-smartphone-company-fraud"&gt;Saygus company&lt;/a&gt; that raised money in 2006 for a new phone that was never made and ended up defrauding investors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V0sYht"&gt;If you don’t mind taking a bet on ZmBIZI, you can pre-order the unlocked ZmBIZI Z2 directly from its &lt;a href="https://zmbizi.com/"&gt;website &lt;/a&gt;now (the phone should be available for sale by November 2021).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1XDpTh"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N0c52c"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22725407/zmbizis-z2-phone-data-pay-back-fintech-privacy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22725407/zmbizis-z2-phone-data-pay-back-fintech-privacy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Gloria Sin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T11:08:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T11:08:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>Mobile app helps people manage their blood pressure</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Hello Heart app and blood pressure monitor." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0RPsJe2n6F_S_U_Ut7IHg1i13GM=/0x0:880x587/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69999648/Monitor_mock1_with_phone_overlapping.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Hello Heart&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vsr8mg"&gt;People with high blood pressure who used a smartphone app and at-home monitor were able to drive down their blood pressure, &lt;a href="http://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.27008?utm_source=For_The_Media&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=ftm_links&amp;amp;utm_term=101521"&gt;a new study&lt;/a&gt; showed. The program, called Hello Heart, lets people track their blood pressure, weight, and physical activity and offers tips on how to manage blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JbURGh"&gt;Around half of adults in the United States have high blood pressure, but only around a quarter of those people have the condition under control. It can be a tricky condition to manage, particularly if people are only getting measurements taken in the doctor’s office — where it can be higher (from the stress of a doctor’s visit) or lower (through a condition called masked hypertension) than it is at home. But it can be dangerous and puts people at risk for heart disease and stroke. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WtplHK"&gt;Digital health approaches to managing blood pressure, which give people resources to track the condition at home, are appealing to doctors and researchers because they could be widely distributed. The Hello Heart program includes a blood pressure monitor that automatically sends readings directly to an app. The app monitors trends and automatically gives users strategies to improve their blood pressure with things like diet and exercise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R8KmBm"&gt;After one year using the program, over 85 percent of people with stage two hypertension, a condition that puts people at risk for heart disease, had reductions in their systolic pressure — which measures the amount of force blood puts on artery walls while the heart is squeezing. They stayed at lower levels over the course of three years, according to the study, which was published in the journal &lt;em&gt;JAMA Network Open&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J5BAbR"&gt;The app was also effective for people with less serious conditions: around half of people with elevated blood pressure had reductions after a year, as did around 70 percent of people with stage one hypertension. People who signed into the app more frequently saw greater impacts and tended to have lower blood pressure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tIY82X"&gt;This analysis of the Hello Heart program included over 28,000 participants. People who had certain employer-based health insurance plans and a diagnosis for high blood pressure were asked if they wanted to participate. They ranged in age from 43 to 58, and most lived in areas with higher socioeconomic status. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1JjOy7"&gt;Most notably, the study tracked participants for up to three years — the authors said they believe it's the first long-term study of a digital blood pressure management program. Following participants over an extended period of time helps researchers check that the impact of a program like this isn’t just short-lived and can help people manage their blood pressure in the long term. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T40xeG"&gt;“This is the first peer-reviewed, published study reporting the long-term experience of a digital health application for blood pressure management,” said study author Alexis Beatty, a cardiologist and associate professor at the University of California, San Francisco, in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gxd9yr"&gt;Hello Heart is currently only available through employer wellness programs — it’s offered by some companies as part of their health benefits. People who don’t work for a company offering Hello Heart aren’t able to use it, but it’s still possible to &lt;a href="https://www.heart.org/en/health-topics/high-blood-pressure/understanding-blood-pressure-readings/monitoring-your-blood-pressure-at-home"&gt;monitor blood pressure at home&lt;/a&gt; without an app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="seq7js"&gt;Despite the promising results, the authors note that the people who used the program were middle-aged and that the vast majority weren’t low-income. It’s hard to say if the app would work as well in groups of people more likely to have serious complications with blood pressure, like&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;older people or people who didn’t have health insurance, they wrote in the study. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QmhchB"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22727938/digital-blood-pressure-management-program-study"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22727938/digital-blood-pressure-management-program-study</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T10:57:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T10:57:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>You can now order the new Nintendo 64 and Sega Genesis controllers for Switch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R56AKlVhZWOudvESqo3NBJvRqAY=/4x0:1597x1062/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69999507/switch64genesiscontrollers.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="J4iihA"&gt;To faithfully play the Nintendo 64 and Sega Genesis games coming to Nintendo Switch Online, you’re going to want the original controllers. Nintendo has posted pages for both the revised &lt;a href="https://store.nintendo.com/nintendo-64-controller.html"&gt;Nintendo 64&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://store.nintendo.com/sega-genesis-control-pad.html"&gt;Genesis controllers&lt;/a&gt;, and you can buy one right now if you’re a Nintendo Switch Online subscriber. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O3zPP3"&gt;Each one costs $49.99 and includes USB-C charging. In the case of the N64 controller, it includes built-in rumble for games that support it, like &lt;em&gt;Star Fox 64&lt;/em&gt;. Both controllers are set to ship on October 25th, and Nintendo is limiting account holders to four of each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7gD6vp"&gt;Nintendo Switch Online is the paid service that nets you cloud save backups and access to &lt;em&gt;Tetris 99&lt;/em&gt;, retro SNES and NES games, and other content. The cost of that membership is going to go up for people who want access to N64 and Genesis games. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728113/nintendo-switch-online-plus-expansion-pack-price-n64-genesis-animal-crossing"&gt;My colleague Chaim Gartenberg has all of the pricing details for you here.&lt;/a&gt; Though, you don’t need to purchase these controllers to be able to play the new games being added to the plan.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728144/nintendo-64-sega-genesis-controllers-switch-online-expansion-pack-buy-order"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728144/nintendo-64-sega-genesis-controllers-switch-online-expansion-pack-buy-order</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T10:57:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T10:57:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>Animal Crossing is getting a big update and paid DLC on November 5th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_B8gibp0z-dPWhUopCPjoIosbw8=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69999505/20211015_ACNH_Update_scrn_001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brewster is back.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EmIqrT"&gt;Nintendo just wrapped up a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g6LdBAbT1Xw"&gt;huge Direct presentation&lt;/a&gt; focused on new content coming to &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing: New Horizons,&lt;/em&gt; including the game’s major 2.0 update and a significant paid DLC expansion. Both will be available on November 5th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BGYVHu"&gt;Let’s start first with the free update, which brings back a lot of familiar faces for longtime &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing&lt;/em&gt; fans. You’ll be able to visit Brewster in his coffee shop, The Roost, Kapp’n will be able to whisk you away to mysterious islands (while serenading you along the way), Katrina the fortune-teller will appear on Harv’s Island, and the odd, noise-making Gyroids have returned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PMWhvS"&gt;There are also some great new features for people who have already sunk hours (or hundreds of hours) into &lt;em&gt;New Horizons.&lt;/em&gt; There are new house exterior options, storage expansions, hairstyles, KK Slider songs, things you can buy with Nook Miles, and even a pro camera app for the NookPhone that lets you take photos from a new perspective. Perhaps one of the most significant updates is that you’ll be able to cook food using ingredients that you grow, meaning you can set the table for a fun (virtual) dinner with your friends. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/anBFN7QURGPPI_lkIbKEsVi07Jg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929423/20211015_ACNH_Update_scrn_009.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Nintendo&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Make some food for your friends.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="VWWUoD"&gt;But for players who want to do even more in &lt;em&gt;New Horizons&lt;/em&gt;, Nintendo is also releasing a paid expansion, &lt;em&gt;Happy Home Paradise&lt;/em&gt;. In the DLC, you’ll travel to an archipelago of islands and help visitors build the paradise home of their dreams on a resort. For example, if a bear wants a house with plush bears, you’ll be able to place the furniture they want in the house but also decorate it however you want to try and make the paradise home that matches what they’re looking for. You’ll also be able to decorate the resort itself. And as part of the DLC, you’ll eventually gain new house decorating techniques, like partitions, that you can bring back to your home on your main island. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T28rGIKU1AK6NeBd0YChdbN3glU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929425/20211015_ACNH_HHP_scrn_006.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Decorate a vacation home in &lt;/em&gt;New Horizons&lt;em&gt;’ upcoming DLC.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="YNtenS"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Happy Home Paradise&lt;/em&gt; DLC will cost $24.99, and you can preorder it starting October 29th. It will also be included as part of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728113/nintendo-switch-online-plus-expansion-pack-price-n64-genesis-animal-crossing"&gt;the Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack subscription&lt;/a&gt;, which launches on October 25th and will cost $49.99 for one person for 12 months or $79.99 for a family membership for 12 months. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="toJmkU"&gt;Nintendo also announced that the &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing&lt;/em&gt; Series 5 amiibo cards will launch on November 5th. Each pack will cost $5.99 and comes with six cards each.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22727354/animal-crossing-switch-update-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22727354/animal-crossing-switch-update-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T10:45:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T10:45:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Roku Streaming Stick 4K review: keeping it simple, now with Dolby Vision</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Now with Dolby Vision and slightly faster performance&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="ZdvB02"&gt;Roku has replaced its Streaming Stick Plus, long one of the top recommendations for an affordable 4K streaming player, with the new Streaming Stick 4K. The name is different, but the hardware looks practically identical on the outside — not that design has any significance in this case. Like its predecessor, the 2021 model plugs into an HDMI port behind your TV and is forever hidden away from everyone watching entertainment on the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nD9QRp"&gt;What’s more important are its upgraded capabilities: the new device is faster, offers improved Wi-Fi performance, and adds support for Dolby Vision and HDR10 Plus. (The older stick was released before Vision settled into must-have status.) And it costs the same $49.99 as before. You can also buy the Streaming Stick 4K Plus, which bundles the same exact hardware with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22391174/roku-voice-remote-pro-review-features-price"&gt;Roku’s Voice Remote Pro&lt;/a&gt; that I reviewed (and liked) a few months ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="m76TAR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10808854"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dlMFlD"&gt;But aside from quicker boot-up times and apps loading a hair faster, nothing about the experience of &lt;em&gt;using&lt;/em&gt; this Roku feels any different. It’s the same simplistic Roku software that has helped the company amass an enormous active user base and stay neck and neck with Amazon as the leading streaming platforms. Roku continues to refrain from overhauling its familiar grid-of-apps homescreen, instead focusing on smaller tweaks and new sections like “Featured Free” that highlight free-to-stream content — mostly to the benefit of the company’s own ad-supported Roku Channel. But the comprehensive universal search, which prioritizes free content and your existing subscriptions over paid options, remains as excellent as ever. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qWcijC"&gt;The Streaming Stick 4K looks very similar to the Stick Plus. Whereas that device was mostly glossy, this one is all matte black plastic except for the “Roku” lettering. (Does any of this even matter when you’ll never see the thing after plugging it in?) They’re mostly the same size — the newer stick is just barely thinner — and there’s still a MicroUSB port for plugging in the power cable. The included USB power cord also houses a long-range Wi-Fi receiver, so you’ll definitely want to use that instead of another USB cable you might have laying around. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6WlJ1ZK_rt4tMAYhlWrKhvXJ26U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929116/IMG_0032.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roku’s Streaming Stick 4K will compete against Amazon’s Fire TV Stick 4K Max.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nzIumX"&gt;With the standard Streaming Stick 4K, Roku includes its regular voice remote with shortcut buttons for Netflix, Disney Plus, Apple TV Plus, and Hulu. There’s no headphone jack on this base remote; you’ll need the Voice Remote Pro for that and other features like hands-free voice commands, a rechargeable battery, and built-in remote finder. But this one covers all the essentials and has basic TV controls for power and volume. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vpxECh"&gt;There’s a lot of hand-holding during the initial setup of a Roku device, the bulk of which actually happens through a web browser and not the device itself. After activating the Streaming Stick 4K with an email link, I was asked which of the top streaming apps I wanted to be installed, and Roku also presents additional app recommendations based on categories (free movies, live, news, comedy, sports, etc.) in which I signaled interest. That’s all well and good, but before everything was done, there’s also a screen with info about over 20 free trials for streaming services. Many of these were for subscriptions handled directly by The Roku Channel. That’s where things started feeling a little spammy, but soon after, I was dropped into the same-as-ever app grid homescreen. When it does come time to log into streaming apps on the Roku, you can now use voice dictation to enter your email and password. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8MjsK9ykEJLVbluqwKcfn_ZRf6Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929121/Screen_Shot_2021_10_14_at_12.31.09_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roku makes streaming app suggestions based on your selections at setup.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="p4V1cp"&gt;From a powered-off state, Roku says the Streaming Stick 4K boots up 30 percent faster than the previous model. I can’t say that’s something I often pay attention to on most streaming gadgets, but the software definitely loaded up swiftly. There’s a more powerful quad-core processor in the new stick, but the company isn’t really making any big claims about it speeding up everyday navigation and responsiveness. Combined with the Stick 4K’s improved Wi-Fi reception — the long-range receiver can now pull down speeds up to twice as fast as before — apps worked smoothly and streams got started without any delays. But whereas Amazon recently brought Wi-Fi 6 to its similarly priced Fire TV Stick 4K Max, the Roku is still on Wi-Fi 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="hnqN15"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10808858"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rpubll"&gt;Dolby Vision is the main reason to upgrade to the Streaming Stick Plus from an older Roku model. There’s now a vast selection of content using the HDR format across popular streaming services like Netflix, Disney Plus, Vudu (which is now Roku’s default rental store), and others. And the Streaming Stick 4K played it all back without any problems — not that I’d expect otherwise. HDR10 Plus is more of a factor if you have a Samsung TV and it’s still more limited in content selection. During my time with the unit so far, I didn’t run into any overheating issues that the Streaming Stick Plus could occasionally be susceptible to. Also remember that Roku’s players now support Apple’s AirPlay 2, making it easy to play content to the device from an iPhone, iPad, or Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kCuhHj1o2L0R8snbZLenL0jrk9A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929123/IMG_0034.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Both devices offer Dolby Vision HDR at a low cost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6mX2Jg"&gt;But at the end of the day, this is a slightly faster Roku (with more robust Wi-Fi) that’s now up to speed on HDR formats. So the reasons for buying it are the same as any other Roku: there’s the extremely simple user interface, and you’re getting a wide selection of apps without any obvious content holes. And you’re paying an appealingly low price for all of it, though not everyone is a fan of &lt;a href="https://foundation.mozilla.org/en/privacynotincluded/roku-streaming-sticks/"&gt;Roku’s level of data collection and sharing with advertisers&lt;/a&gt;, which helps keep the price of these devices so low. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="IJ8l7b"&gt;By now you probably know which streaming platform you favor the most: Roku’s the easiest to use but lacks any substantial smart home controls, Fire TV offers a ton of value (and Alexa) for similarly low prices, Google TV has the best recommendations, Apple TV has the most reliable performance, and products like the Nvidia Shield add gaming and the freedom to tinker with software. The Roku Streaming Stick 4K is a very safe evolution of one of the company’s bestselling products, and it delivers on the improvements that were needed like Dolby Vision. If your Roku is feeling sluggish or can’t get the most from your new 4K HDR TV, it’s a fine time to upgrade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RzZBkC"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22727963/roku-streaming-stick-4k-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22727963/roku-streaming-stick-4k-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T10:43:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T10:43:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to use iOS 15’s new Focus modes</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dpkQp-pUcc5TNGEA14QrcPezeJA=/0x0:700x467/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69999461/ios15_iphone12_pro_settings_focus_crop__1_.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EUGjjn"&gt;These days, it is way too easy to be pulled from your work by notifications and other distractions. In order to help you keep your attention where you want it, Apple has added new Focus features to iOS 15. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K1bBad"&gt;The idea is to keep you “in the moment” by filtering out apps or notifications that you don’t want popping up during specific times. The nice thing is that you can create different profiles to keep you from being disturbed, depending on whether you’re at home, at work, getting ready for bed, driving, or for any other activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h134kI"&gt;When you first start to set Focus up, it can seem a little daunting. There are a lot of choices, and a lot of ways you can tweak it. In fact, it may take a while before you get the combination of settings that works best for your lifestyle. But in the end, it will be worth it — it will mean that you won’t be sidelined during times you need to concentrate, and you won’t be bothered by irrelevant notifications when you’ve got other activities in hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You’ll find your new Focus button in the Control Center." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fqKUrOXcxaTA1c1p2DPG0B19mCA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929129/IMG_2E41D6D8A9B5_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You’ll find your new Focus button in the Control Center.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Tap on Focus, and you’ll see all your various profiles." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rl5IDdE5v4QvQ4Ma02QaTzhVCBQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929128/IMG_C5F6B766D9B7_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tap on Focus, and you’ll see all your various profiles.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Ho2e9P"&gt;Begin to focus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="eF8B9R"&gt;You access Focus mode via your Control Center (swipe down from the upper right corner). You’ll see the Focus button with a moon icon next to it. If you tap the icon, then the main Do Not Disturb profile will be active. If you tap anywhere else in the button, you’ll see a selection of other profiles that you can activate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jQRtvY"&gt;Tap on the three dots to the right of each button, and you can set the length of time you want that Focus profile to be active. Or you can tap the Settings button to tweak the settings for that Focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eWvVZu"&gt;But perhaps the best way to start is to go to Settings &amp;gt; Focus, where you can set up all the various Focus profiles you are planning to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="V15dui"&gt;Set up your profiles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="2FOIon"&gt;When you first open the Focus page in your settings, you’ll see a list of several profiles, starting with the basic Do Not Disturb and then going on to Personal, Sleep, and Work. If you tap on the plus sign in the upper right corner of the screen, you’ll find the others, including Driving, Fitness, Gaming, Mindfulness, and Readings. If none of those suit, you  can create a custom profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SnxcpV"&gt;In addition, there is a toggle that lets you can share the profiles across your various Apple devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZzsXlc"&gt;We’ll look at some of the profiles in a moment, but let’s start by tapping on Do Not Disturb. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The main Focus page lets you set up a variety of profiles." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hqdOC1YwPCOLESS0988eW6n5CQE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929013/IMG_42A19892FE43_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The main Focus page lets you set up a variety of profiles.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The initial Do Not Disturb profile offers a basic template." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZPj2xJKtdw0Ss8ckp20CEX2-DS4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929035/IMG_917D02D42034_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The initial Do Not Disturb profile offers a basic template.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="FIYrZd"&gt;Do Not Disturb&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="21ARpr"&gt;The first thing you’ll see on top of the Do Not Disturb page (and, in fact, on top of all the profile pages) is the toggle to turn the mode on and off. After that, there are a variety of filters that you can tweak to determine when and how Focus will be set up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="l6AgJT"&gt;Allowed notifications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="JafgFu"&gt;Focus lets you specify people or apps that can continue to notify you even if you have Do Not Disturb active. For example, you may want to allow calls to come in from family members, or notifications from your work Slack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3FV9dc"&gt;To make these exceptions, tap on the People or Apps box to get to the Allowed Notifications page. (It doesn’t really matter which you tap; you’ll end up on the same page.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can allow specific apps to continuing notifying you during Focus times." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sEQxI-DYvD0_AMxW9F-grctJC9o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929036/IMG_12BD6DF55162_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can allow specific apps to continuing notifying you during Focus times.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Tap on the plus sign and you get a list of apps to choose from." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/49kc4VfarFcKI73BMb04EpaMdpY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929037/IMG_698503BFB14C_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tap on the plus sign and you get a list of apps to choose from.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id="GkJBIZ"&gt;Allowed apps&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="zPsxL8"&gt;If you’re choosing one or more apps, then tap the App tab and then the plus button. You’ll get a list of your installed apps; check off those you want to add to the Allowed Notifications list, and select Done at the top right of the page. You’ll now see your chosen apps listed under Allowed Apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="poPpBl"&gt;If you change your mind for any of your apps, you can just tap the minus sign next to each icon or select the “Remove All” link on the upper right of the Allowed Apps section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RHtNdN"&gt;You can also allow Time Sensitive notifications to come through by toggling it on. Time  Sensitive notifications are from apps you’ve individually tagged as important enough to break through any filter, no matter what. To select which apps are that important to you, you have to leave Focus and go to Settings &amp;gt; Notifications; select the app or apps you want to qualify — say, Calendar — and make sure Time Sensitive notifications is toggled on for that app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can also select which people can still contact you." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p2aIH9ToanE_9iOj1t68um-wDGI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929042/IMG_092F5ED1AB24_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can also select which people can still contact you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Tap “Calls From” to choose general categories of contacts." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SUhzR5d2dv_4o12ZaWz4KYlDboA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929044/IMG_4EC82D8508B0_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tap “Calls From” to choose general categories of contacts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id="4o02dF"&gt;Allowed people&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="tjHRzU"&gt;The way you allow notifications from specific people to break through the set Focus mode is pretty much the same as with the apps: select the plus sign under the People tab to add from your list of contacts. You can also allow incoming calls from various categories of people: either everyone who calls, no one (if you really want not to be disturbed), people who are tagged as favorites, or anyone in your contact list. You can also allow through any calls that are repeated within three minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Ym6FGI"&gt;Other options&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="pXCwk4"&gt;There are also a variety of other options. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="2WPEQX"&gt;You can choose to share your focus status — so if somebody texts you, they will get a display saying that you have notifications silenced. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JvSCV9"&gt;You can hide notifications from your homescreen pages or your lock screen. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AdypEo"&gt;You can have only specific homescreens be active during certain times of the day — for example, you can put all your gaming apps on one homescreen, and keep that screen hidden when you’re at work. To do that, tap on the Home Screen button in your profile, toggle on Custom Pages, and then choose which page or pages you want to be available when that profile is active. (Pro tip: to hide those custom extra homescreens when you’re &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; in a Focus mode, long-press on your homescreen to put it in editing mode, then tap the dots at the bottom. Uncheck the screens you don’t want to show.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="From the profile’s main screen, select Home Screen and then toggle on Custom Pages." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fySmiX4tfuvb0YJwuvuZKwWO_pE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929209/IMG_09CF86ED709C_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;From the profile’s main screen, select Home Screen and then toggle on Custom Pages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uhqUZnABBt0X2pxhJli2CyvfUaM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929210/IMG_F356B3B5F40F_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can then choose which screens you want available when the profile is active.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="I9svS1"&gt;You can arrange to have the focus mode turn on automatically during specific times and on specific days — for example, from 9AM to 5PM on weekdays. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="oSnWz5"&gt;You can even — and this is really nice — arrange to have it activate when you are at specific locations or when you’re using specific apps by selecting “Add Schedule or Automation” at the bottom of the mode settings page. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="“Add Schedule or Automation” brings you to a page where you can arrange for Focus to automatically start." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5GTcZYkDbTsvm80u2zz9vXOJclk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929026/IMG_675B90AF3D63_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Add Schedule or Automation” brings you to a page where you can arrange for Focus to automatically start.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="For example, you can have a Focus profile automatically start when you are at a specific location." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bAnKcuSxlDLTKLXlH-KxtGKC63E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929028/IMG_F33D365A26CE_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;For example, you can have a Focus profile automatically start when you are at a specific location.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XBnb8F"&gt;That brings you to the New Automation page where, for example, you can have it activate whenever you’re at work, or when you’re watching a Netflix video. And if this is something that happens often — for example, when you go to work or read in the evenings — activate Smart Activation, which will (hopefully) learn your habits and turn on Do Not Disturb when you need it. (If it gets things wrong, you can always turn it off.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="q0BLRx"&gt;Focus profiles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="OOCtg7"&gt;In order to use the profiles, you need to set them up to fit your needs. I listed the ones available at the beginning of this article; in order to get used to them, let’s try setting up two: Personal and Driving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EOHqUO"&gt;When you tap on a profile that has not yet been set up, you are presented with a set of screens that walk you through the initial processing, including which people and apps should be allowed to notify you when the Focus is active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The preset Focus profiles use wizards to help you start using them." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DItlkXxSgopkn8OgxDK1vmqmqeY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929022/IMG_D59C1674EB50_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The preset Focus profiles use wizards to help you start using them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="After the initial setup, you can continue to filter each profile." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/v5xPrDVIP-F7vLzxVVPf5ZJPEbw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929023/IMG_CB5C5AB66007_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the initial setup, you can continue to filter each profile.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7R325M"&gt;After that, you are dropped into the Focus page for that profile, which will be similar to the Do Not Disturb setup described above. In Personal, you can not only tweak the allowed notifications but decide whether you want to share your Focus status, hide the notifications on your homescreen or lock screen, or create an automation that will turn it on and off at a certain time, in a certain place, or with a certain app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zlrFO6"&gt;Some of the other presets are more specific. For example, when I created a Focus for driving, the opening page of the wizard told me that it was silencing alerts and notifications while I was driving; that it would turn on automatically when I was driving; and that it would arrange auto-reply to let people know why I wasn’t responding to notifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Profiles such as “Driving” offer specialized filters." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RE2ZL_O7aPofaUdH2GCZjeiYxXc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929018/IMG_06093F59A446_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Profiles such as “Driving” offer specialized filters.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can decide what will cause the profile to automatically start." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/acMGfIxQ6X6xhTu0OLaQ0DduTn0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929020/IMG_0ABB49FDE07B_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can decide what will cause the profile to automatically start.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="svlOjw"&gt;And the Driving Focus page had a few differences as well. Allowed notifications include people but not apps (under the assumption that you’re not playing with apps while you’re at the wheel). There is an auto-reply option that lets you edit the message that will be sent to people who try to contact you while the Focus is on. And you can choose how the app will know you’re driving: automatically (based on detected motion), if the CarPlay app is activated, if the phone is connected to a car’s Bluetooth, or when you turn it on manually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3nyeg1"&gt;If none of the presets work for you, you can create a custom profile by tapping on the plus sign in the upper right corner of the main Focus screen and choosing Custom. You will be asked to name your new profile and to choose a color and icon to represent it.  After that, the process is pretty much the same as for Personal, except that you can also tweak the name and appearance of the Focus in the profile’s screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="UEUvja"&gt;So what next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Nu0Ltz"&gt;Now, when you tap the Focus icon in your Control Center, it will activate all the various features you’ve created for your profile. Note that the last profile that was active will be the one that is featured: for example, if you last used your Driving profile, the Focus button will have the car icon. Touch the icon to active it, or touch the word Focus to switch to a different profile. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n5qtBR"&gt;The new Focus app in iOS 15 can be very useful by helping you concentrate when you need to, by letting you relax when you want to, by keeping unwanted calls and texts from waking you at night, and by keeping you safe from distractions when driving. It may take a while to figure out which profiles you want to set up, and to discovering what combination of factors works for you. But once you’ve got it working, Focus can really make things easier for you.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22726456/ios-15-iphone-focus-distractions-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22726456/ios-15-iphone-focus-distractions-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T10:37:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T10:37:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nintendo Switch Online’s N64 and Sega Genesis ‘expansion pack’ launches October 25th for $49.99 per year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b7rpTpqB-yMNZmw6WqtznEJEhJI=/146x0:1601x970/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69999439/image.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TojyjK"&gt;Nintendo has announced the price and release for its upcoming Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack subscription tier, which adds Nintendo 64 games, Sega Genesis games, and bundled access to the new paid &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing: New Horizons — Happy Home Paradise&lt;/em&gt; DLC. It’ll cost $49.99 per year for an individual subscription or $79.99 for a shared family membership. The service will officially launch on October 25th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I9DzGv"&gt;Those prices are a big jump from the regular Switch Online subscription, which costs $19.99 per year for a single membership or $34.99 per year for a family subscription. The Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack subscription tier offers the same benefits as the standard Switch Online service — including online multiplayer, classic NES and SNES games, cloud saves, and other perks. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8_t16bfCPIMiOnWunsHrek0xwxE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929332/Screen_Shot_2021_10_15_at_10.32.07_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="yykZH6"&gt;But the Expansion Pack subscription also adds access to other retro titles from the Nintendo 64 and Sega Genesis. Today’s pricing announcement included news that the premium subscription service would also bring bundled access to the new paid &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing: New Horizons&lt;/em&gt; DLC (which is set to cost $24.99 on its own).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HgNZlP"&gt;At launch, the Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack service will include several of the most popular N64 games, including &lt;em&gt;Super Mario 64&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time&lt;/em&gt;, and&lt;em&gt; Mario Kart 64.&lt;/em&gt; Additional titles are also planned for the future, like &lt;em&gt;Banjo-Kazooie&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; Pokémon Snap&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Majora’s Mask&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and&lt;em&gt; Paper Mario. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tz4miX"&gt;The higher $49.99 per year price point also puts Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack more in line with other major subscription costs from competitors like Sony and Microsoft (PlayStation Plus and Xbox Live Gold both cost $59.99 per year, albeit with fewer perks than Nintendo’s retro game offerings). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ETU2Zh"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update October 15th, 10:44AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added release date information. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728113/nintendo-switch-online-plus-expansion-pack-price-n64-genesis-animal-crossing"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728113/nintendo-switch-online-plus-expansion-pack-price-n64-genesis-animal-crossing</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T10:21:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T10:21:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>The US has set a date to reopen its borders to vaccinated foreign visitors</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-CANADA-HEALTH-VIRUS-TRAVEL-TOURISM" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gWPzUJnw6W9V-pvnYoI0npzqe6k=/0x0:3600x2400/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69999344/1234594574.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The US-Canada border reopened to vaccinated visitors | Photo by Jason Redmond/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="m4WZqE"&gt;The White House is expected to announce Friday that the US is reopening its land and air borders to vaccinated foreign nationals on November 8th, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/exclusive-us-partly-lift-international-travel-curbs-nov-8-official-2021-10-15/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qlKs6h"&gt;As part of COVID-19 restrictions, non-essential travelers from more than 30 countries have been barred from entering the US since March 2020. This latest news comes as the White House announced Tuesday that the US was ending restrictions at the borders and ferry crossings with Mexico and Canada for foreign nationals vaccinated against COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Br9ePb"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22584359/canada-border-reopen-non-essential-travel-us-citizens-vaccinated"&gt;Canada began allowing&lt;/a&gt; vaccinated US visitors into the country for non-essential travel in August. Travelers seeking to enter Canada will be required to fill out a questionnaire using the ArriveCAN app and need to demonstrate a quarantine plan in case they don’t meet Canada’s requirements for quarantine exemption. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W2zwaz"&gt;Last month, the White House said the US would end restrictions on air travel from more than 30 countries in early November but didn’t provide a date. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RSRW1J"&gt;Non-US air travelers will be required to show proof of vaccination before boarding a flight and proof of a recent negative COVID-19 test. For foreign visitors crossing into the US at a land border, only proof of vaccination will be required. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sFAVlK"&gt;The White House didn’t immediately reply to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aqUa0m"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7qZNGJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0QOyBE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22727979/us-date-reopen-borders-vaccine-foreign-visitors"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22727979/us-date-reopen-borders-vaccine-foreign-visitors</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T10:04:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T10:04:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>Xbox Series X mini fridge preorders begin on October 19th for $99.99</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E3I5xLjGDLef-N2u1aBe6dOZOTI=/47x0:554x338/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69999240/xboxminifridge.0.gif" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UQbTur"&gt;Microsoft’s Xbox Series X-shaped mini fridge will be available to preorder next week. The Xbox Mini Fridge will be priced at $99.99 (£89.99 / €99) and available to preorder on October 19th in the US, UK, Canada, and Europe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g0ZaTr"&gt;The mini fridge is expected to ship at some point in December, and Microsoft has partnered with &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fc%2Fxbox-series-x-video-games%2F-%2FN-fd2hh%3FNao%3D0&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target in the US&lt;/a&gt; and Canada, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.game.co.uk%2Fwebapp%2Fwcs%2Fstores%2Fservlet%2FHubArticleView%3FhubId%3D2862757%26articleId%3D2868421%26catalogId%3D10201%26langId%3D44%26storeId%3D10151&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F15%2F22727969%2Fxbox-series-x-mini-fridge-price-release-date" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Game in the UK&lt;/a&gt;, and Game Stop EU, Micromania, or Toynk in Europe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bP4Rb29q1MT5bNDdjnADB16-KEQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929277/17315_Front_Open.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Xbox Mini Fridge can hold up to 12 cans of drink.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Eym0nPuSaFmw9qXPo7iA6G4YIFU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22929279/17315_4.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inside the mini fridge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hHqyJQ"&gt;The Xbox Mini Fridge can hold up to 12 cans of drink, and has two shelves inside the door designed to hold snacks. It even has a USB at the front to charge devices, and also comes equipped with a DC power adapter so it can be portable. The mini fridge was first &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/13/22532185/xbox-series-x-mini-fridge-available-holiday-2021"&gt;teased at E3&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year, following Microsoft’s promise to make one after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/4/2/22364073/microsoft-xbox-series-x-mini-fridge-skittles-twitter-brand-poll"&gt;defeating Skittles in a Twitter poll&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o2ZrIZ"&gt;The Xbox Mini Fridge is the result of Microsoft really leaning into the initial memes about the boxy and fridge-like shape of the Xbox Series X. Microsoft has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2020/3/16/21181399/microsoft-xbox-series-x-size-fridge-comparison-measurements"&gt;joked about the shape&lt;/a&gt;, and the company’s mini fridge &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/13/22532185/xbox-series-x-mini-fridge-available-holiday-2021"&gt;announcement at E3&lt;/a&gt; even called it “the world’s most powerful mini fridge” with “Xbox Velocity Cooling Architecture.” Microsoft even gave away a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/28/21538654/microsoft-xbox-series-x-fridge-competition"&gt;full-sized, Series X-shaped fridge last year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q9Zyhy"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22727969/xbox-series-x-mini-fridge-price-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22727969/xbox-series-x-mini-fridge-price-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
