<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-06-25T13:10:27-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-25T13:10:27-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-25T13:10:27-04:00</updated>
    <title>Why Windows 11 is forcing everyone to use TPM chips</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tErjIeOi0dqDJILpD1cCV_7KKsQ=/100x0:1180x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69504823/windows11darkmode.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yqWTro"&gt;Microsoft announced yesterday that Windows 11 will require TPM (Trusted Platform Module) chips on existing and new devices. It’s a significant hardware change that has been years in the making, but Microsoft’s messy way of communicating this has left many confused about whether their hardware is compatible. What is a TPM, and why do you need one for Windows 11 anyway?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R2pQfb"&gt;“The Trusted Platform Modules (TPM) is a chip that is either integrated into your PC’s motherboard or added separately into the CPU,” &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fsecurity%2Fblog%2F2021%2F06%2F25%2Fwindows-11-enables-security-by-design-from-the-chip-to-the-cloud%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;explains David Weston&lt;/a&gt;, director of enterprise and OS security at Microsoft. “Its purpose is to protect encryption keys, user credentials, and other sensitive data behind a hardware barrier so that malware and attackers can’t access or tamper with that data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="vTirEX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Windows 11 is free, but your CPU might not be officially supported ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22549725/microsoft-windows-11-cpu-support-tpm-hardware-requirements"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="OQphEK"&gt;So it’s all about security. TPMs work by offering hardware-level protection instead of software only. It can be used to encrypt disks using Windows features like BitLocker, or to prevent dictionary attacks against passwords. TPM 1.2 chips have existed since 2011, but they’ve typically only been used widely in IT-managed business laptops and desktops. Microsoft wants to bring that same level of protection to everyone using Windows, even if it’s &lt;a href="https://portswigger.net/daily-swig/bitlocker-sleep-mode-vulnerability-can-bypass-windows-full-disk-encryption"&gt;not always perfect&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cBna7U_j3oWLNtBmFiubpY3vdXs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22681635/tpmchip.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A dedicated TPM chip you probably don’t actually need for Windows 11.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hX28nA"&gt;Microsoft has been &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fsecurity%2Fblog%2F2021%2F03%2F30%2Fnew-security-signals-study-shows-firmware-attacks-on-the-rise-heres-how-microsoft-is-working-to-help-eliminate-this-entire-class-of-threats%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;warning for months&lt;/a&gt; that firmware attacks are on the rise. “Our own Security Signals report found that 83 percent of businesses experienced a firmware attack, and only 29 percent are allocating resources to protect this critical layer,” says Weston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NczTiG"&gt;That 83 percent figure seems huge, but when you consider the various phishing, ransomware, supply chain, and IoT vulnerabilities that exist, the broad range of attacks becomes a lot clearer. Ransomware attacks hit the headlines weekly, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/24/22545675/ransomware-cryptocurrency-regulation-hacks"&gt;ransomware funds more ransomware so it’s a difficult problem to solve&lt;/a&gt;. TPMs will certainly help with certain attacks, but Microsoft is banking on a combination of modern CPUs, Secure Boot, and its set of virtualization protections to really make a dent in ransomware. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cjUKsl"&gt;Microsoft is trying to play its part, particularly as Windows is the platform that’s often most affected by these attacks. It’s widely used by businesses worldwide, and there are more than 1.3 billion Windows 10 machines in use today. Microsoft software has been at the core of devastating attacks that made global headlines, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/2/22210667/solarwinds-hack-worse-government-microsoft-cybersecurity"&gt;like the Russia-linked SolarWinds hack&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/5/22316189/microsoft-exchange-server-security-exploit-china-attack-30000-organizations"&gt;Hafnium hacks on Microsoft Exchange Server&lt;/a&gt;. And while the company isn’t responsible for forcing its clients to keep its software patched, it’s trying to be more proactive about protection.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WQFFXgpRx2nyANrz1qgnEmfgM_I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22681637/Windows_11_PC_Devices.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft is pushing modern Windows 11 PCs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SnRMhA"&gt;Microsoft has a habit of struggling to move Windows into the future in both hardware and software, and this particular change hasn’t been explained well. While Microsoft has required OEMs to ship devices with support for TPM chips since Windows 10, the company hasn’t forced users or its many device partners to turn these on for Windows to work. That’s what’s really changing with Windows 11, and combined with Microsoft’s Windows 11 upgrade checker, it has resulted in a lot of understandable confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8vphth"&gt;Microsoft’s &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fwindows%2Fwindows-11%23pchealthcheck" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Windows 11 website lists&lt;/a&gt; the minimum system requirements, with a link to &lt;a href="http://aka.ms/CPUlist"&gt;compatible CPUs&lt;/a&gt; and a clear mention that a TPM 2.0 is required at a minimum. (It’s not.) The PC Health Check app that Microsoft asks people to download and check to see if Windows 11 runs will flag systems that do not have Secure Boot or TPM support enabled or devices that have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22549725/microsoft-windows-11-cpu-support-tpm-hardware-requirements"&gt;CPUs that aren’t officially supported&lt;/a&gt; (anything older than 8th Gen Intel chips).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PmzreL"&gt;That’s left many trying to figure out if their device supports TPM or not, confusion with BIOS settings, and even people rushing to buy separate TPM modules they don’t need. Some are even scalping TPM 2.0 modules on eBay!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5JQ4Ex"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Thanks to Windows 11, people are scalping TPM2.0 modules as well now.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;$24.90 ➡ $99.90 in just 12 hours &lt;a href="https://t.co/9TTHC2c47w"&gt;pic.twitter.com/9TTHC2c47w&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Shen Ye (@shen) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/shen/status/1408284995131645956?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 25, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zViYBC"&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/compatibility/windows-11/"&gt;Hidden away on Microsoft’s site&lt;/a&gt; is what’s really happening here. The true minimum requirements are TPM 1.2 and a 64-bit dual-core CPU that’s 1GHz or greater. TPM support can be enabled through practically any modern CPU in the BIOS settings of a machine. You shouldn’t need a separate module unless your CPU is &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RNOS4n"&gt;Microsoft is promoting TPM 2.0 and performing checks for 8th Gen or newer Intel chips because these are the requirements for certified OEM hardware — the machines you’ll find in stores with an inevitable Windows 11 sticker. The reality is that Windows 11 will install on devices with TPM 1.2 enabled, and practically any CPU that meets the 64-bit dual-core 1GHz or above standard — you’ll just have to navigate a notification telling you the “upgrade is not advised.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nXZuEk"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;it’s not super obvious and every BIOS varies. On mine it’s literally just “PTT.” &lt;a href="https://t.co/CrmSGEgARN"&gt;pic.twitter.com/CrmSGEgARN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Tom Warren (@tomwarren) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/1408209347914653706?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 24, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bvUZYX"&gt;Microsoft doesn’t even mention this true TPM 1.2 minimum in its blog post &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fsecurity%2Fblog%2F2021%2F06%2F25%2Fwindows-11-enables-security-by-design-from-the-chip-to-the-cloud%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;outlining this new security effort today&lt;/a&gt;, nor does the company offer any details on the CPU support that many seem to be stumbling into. If you’re having issues with the PC Health App checker for Windows 11, make sure you have “PTT” on Intel systems enabled in the BIOS, or “PSP fTPM” on AMD devices. The company’s system checker should be less confusing soon, though: shortly after we published this story, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dwizzzleMSFT/status/1408479215813480449"&gt;Weston tweeted that it will now be more specific&lt;/a&gt; about why your PC isn’t passing muster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Gx5Qm4"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We just made updates to the Windows 11 PC Health Check App. It now provides more detailed info on requirements not met. This should help in cases where folks assumed CPU compat issues were TPM related  &lt;a href="https://t.co/hTWMe16DWO"&gt;https://t.co/hTWMe16DWO&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/eZLTZMOdjT"&gt;pic.twitter.com/eZLTZMOdjT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— DWIZZZLE (@dwizzzleMSFT) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dwizzzleMSFT/status/1408479215813480449?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 25, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jUPlfI"&gt;What Microsoft is trying to achieve here will benefit the Windows ecosystem in years to come, alongside its new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21571069/microsoft-pluton-processor-security-windows-pc"&gt;efforts for Xbox-like security on Windows&lt;/a&gt;. Microsoft just totally dropped the ball on explaining that to everyone on day one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0mG7EN"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, 2:26PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added that Microsoft updated its PC Health Check app, shortly after we published this story, to be more specific about why your computer isn’t meeting Windows 11 system requirements.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22550376/microsoft-windows-11-tpm-chips-requirement-security"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22550376/microsoft-windows-11-tpm-chips-requirement-security</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-25T12:10:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-25T12:10:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google is warning users when its search results might be unreliable</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tScRA_91bd-x49huKXHHZrozeeY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69504561/acastro_180508_1777_google_IO_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fPdcrq"&gt;Google will now tell users when search results are rapidly changing around a breaking story. Some searches will now bring up a warning that “it looks like these results are changing quickly,” and a subheading will explain that “if this topic is new, it can sometimes take time for results to be added by reliable sources.” &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/search/new-notice-search-rapidly-evolving-results/"&gt;In a blog post&lt;/a&gt;, the company suggests that users might want to check back later when it’s found more results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IDYFqV"&gt;The notice is initially appearing on US-based English-language results “when a topic is rapidly evolving and a range of sources hasn’t yet weighed in.” Google will expand the tool’s presence to other markets in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vvKn2Q"&gt;“While Google Search will always be there with the most useful results we can provide, sometimes the reliable information you’re searching for just isn’t online yet,” the company explains. “This can be particularly true for breaking news or emerging topics, when the information that’s published first may not be the most reliable.” &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2021/6/24/22549157/google-unreliable-search-results-changing-quickly-misinformation-conspiracy-theories"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Recode&lt;/em&gt; reported on&lt;/a&gt; the feature yesterday, following up on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/noUpside/status/1407724577120165890"&gt;a tweet from&lt;/a&gt; Stanford Internet Observatory researcher Renee DiResta. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A Google search result for “ufo filmed traveling 106 mph” with the warning label." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Df4jsFyslSYhbJZTSsPjjIRvMl8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22681491/Screen_Shot_2021_06_24_at_2.59.58_PM.max_1000x1000.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="h7jiDc"&gt;A sample Google search screenshot features the query “ufo filmed traveling 106 mph,” an apparent reference to a recent &lt;a href="https://www.the-sun.com/news/3133158/ufo-video-police-helicopter-wales-uk/"&gt;tabloid story&lt;/a&gt; about a 2016 UFO sighting in Wales. (Currently, that precise search result does not actually include the warning.) “Someone had gotten this police report video released out in Wales, and it’s had a little bit bit of press coverage. But there’s still not a lot about it,” Google search public liaison Danny Sullivan told &lt;em&gt;Recode&lt;/em&gt;. “But people are probably searching for it, they may be going around on social media — so we can tell it’s starting to trend. And we can also tell that there’s not a lot of necessarily great stuff that’s out there. And we also think that maybe new stuff will come along.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rf21cA"&gt;That whimsical example aside, Google has inadvertently showcased incorrect information &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/3/16413082/google-4chan-las-vegas-shooting-top-stories-algorithm-mistake"&gt;after mass shooting events&lt;/a&gt; — where early official reports are often inaccurate and deliberate misinformation is common. (This is sometimes exacerbated &lt;a href="https://datasociety.net/library/data-voids-where-missing-data-can-easily-be-exploited/"&gt;by “data voids,”&lt;/a&gt; or keywords that have few search results and can be easily hijacked by bad actors.) This warning won’t necessarily stop bad content from surfacing, and it’s not clear exactly how Google determines a sufficient range of sources. But it could remove some of the false legitimacy that high Google placement can confer on early, unreliable search results.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22550430/google-search-results-changing-quickly-warning-breaking-news"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22550430/google-search-results-changing-quickly-warning-breaking-news</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-25T11:55:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-25T11:55:52-04:00</updated>
    <title>Everything you need to know about the Pentagon’s big UFO report... for now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JGjUQ6Q1lGKJM1OZDqPTf7C6PMo=/0x251:1454x1220/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69504421/Screen_Shot_2021_06_25_at_7.57.35_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Department of Defense/US Navy&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Jz1cto"&gt;A highly anticipated report on the Pentagon’s research into Unidentified Aerial Phenomena (UAP), aka UFOs, will be released as early as today. There’s going to be a book-load of background on the Pentagon’s new UAP task force, which examines unknown objects through a national security lens. The Defense Department said last year it takes “any incursions by unauthorized aircraft into our training ranges or designated airspace very seriously...” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yMQQlN"&gt;The government’s UAP program and the upcoming report have spawned a news cycle that has shot UFO conspiracies back into the mainstream. Despite the hype, the report will almost certainly not contain proof of aliens. Here’s what we know so far. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="9roQWH"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When will this Pentagon UFO report come out? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Sg1oZr"&gt;The Senate Intelligence Committee squeezed in a comment within last year’s massive COVID-19 relief bill that &lt;a href="https://www.intelligence.senate.gov/publications/intelligence-authorization-act-fiscal-year-2021"&gt;asked the Pentagon&lt;/a&gt; to cough up classified and unclassified versions of a UAP report in 180 days, or no later than Friday, June 25th. So it’s coming very soon. By Thursday, the unclassified version hadn’t been finished yet and was expected to be posted online by the deadline on Friday, one Defense Department press officer said at the time.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="F4tL0R"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UAP? Why not say UFO?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="tFPuor"&gt;They’re basically the same thing. UAP stands for unidentified aerial phenomena, which is a new fancy way of saying unidentified flying objects. Naming a Pentagon program after UFOs would be far too silly for a big, very serious government intelligence program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B7bg1E"&gt;More seriously, putting “objects” in the name could be too limiting of a word for a program that deals with the unknown. Can we really consider them “objects” if we’re only seeing strange shapes through fuzzy camera footage from military aircraft? “Phenomena” would be a bit more accurate. It’s defined as “a fact or situation that is observed to exist or happen, especially one whose cause or explanation is in question.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="G8TULb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did this start?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="cwgFOk"&gt;Depends on how far back you want to go. The US has dabbled in UFO research for decades, and various documents have been made public over the years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R0j299"&gt;The Air Force had &lt;a href="https://www.archives.gov/research/military/air-force/ufos"&gt;Project Blue Book&lt;/a&gt;, which closed in 1969 after investigating more than 12,500 UFO sightings. The CIA &lt;a href="https://www.theblackvault.com/documentarchive/ufos-the-central-intelligence-agency-cia-collection/"&gt;dumped a trove&lt;/a&gt; of historical UFO records in January, &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/pkdqjy/you-can-now-easily-download-all-cia-ufo-documents-to-date"&gt;revealing&lt;/a&gt; more government attempts to explain unidentified aerial phenomena in the years following Project Blue Book’s end. None of these historical records link any unexplained phenomena to extraterrestrial activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="hqSxxI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Pentagon takes UAP “incursions... very seriously”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="m9Tjnn"&gt;The government says it’s generally interested in UAPs / UFOs out of national security concerns. In one statement from August last year, the Defense Department said it takes “any incursions by unauthorized aircraft into our training ranges or designated airspace very seriously and examine each report. This includes examinations of incursions that are initially reported as UAP when the observer cannot immediately identify what he or she is observing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v5l4Vw"&gt;Public fascination with UFOs generally &lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2014/06/the-man-who-introduced-the-world-to-flying-saucers/372732/"&gt;dates back to 1947&lt;/a&gt;, when an amateur pilot flying his plane near Mount Rainier in Washington state reported sights of nine “saucer-like” objects darting across the sky. His recollection of what he saw spawned &lt;a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20080413203646/http://www.mimufon.org/historical_folders/nicap_pages/ReportOnWaveOf1947.pdf"&gt;a wave of press attention&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ckR4Fi"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But how did the most recent round of UFO... sorry — UAP — discourse start? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="HA6AJt"&gt;It started in 2017, when stories published by &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/16/us/politics/pentagon-program-ufo-harry-reid.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2017/12/16/pentagon-ufo-search-harry-reid-216111/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Politico&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; confirmed the existence of the Advanced Aerospace Threat Identification Program (AATIP), a classified Pentagon project that began in 2007 to investigate unidentified phenomena and ended in 2012. Formally established under the Defense Intelligence Agency (DIA) and later transferred to the Defense Department’s headquarters, it was reportedly run primarily by former military intelligence official Luis Elizondo, who has said he resigned in 2017 over what he considered internal opposition to government-funded UAP research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lhmAh3"&gt;(It’s worth noting that both the &lt;em&gt;NYT&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Politico&lt;/em&gt; reports have been criticized as being credulous toward &lt;a href="https://theintercept.com/2019/06/01/ufo-unidentified-history-channel-luis-elizondo-pentagon/"&gt;Elizondo’s claims&lt;/a&gt; and overly accepting of the remote possibility that UAPs can be attributed to alien activity. A recent &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22463659/ufo-videos-navy-alien-drone"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vox&lt;/em&gt; article&lt;/a&gt; does a good job of laying out some of the surrounding context and is worth a read.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PxFtKJ"&gt;AATIP also gathered studies on wild ideas straight out of science fiction, from nuclear propulsion to invisibility cloaking, warp drives, metallic glasses, programmable matter, etc., &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/29/18187178/pentagon-research-documents-invisibility-cloaking-wormholes-warp-drive-department-of-defense"&gt;according to a list&lt;/a&gt; of AATIP research products that was sent to Congress in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Senate Minority Leader Harry Reid..." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W_Cy3JFDGsm8fXGsotARXmAAFrw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22681246/610710962.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo By Bill Clark / CQ Roll Call&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="UYY26K"&gt;According to the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Politico&lt;/em&gt; reports, AATIP’s initial “black” budget of $22 million — a minuscule amount compared to other Pentagon budgets — was pushed by former Nevada senator and space phenomena enthusiast Harry Reid. Most of that funding reportedly went to a Las Vegas-based space company owned by hotel chain magnate and UFO enthusiast Robert Bigelow, a &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22463659/ufo-videos-navy-alien-drone"&gt;campaign donor&lt;/a&gt; to and longtime friend of Reid. Bigelow told the&lt;em&gt; Times &lt;/em&gt;that his company, Bigelow Aerospace, modified storage buildings at its headquarters to make room for mysterious “metal alloys” that were recovered during work on the AATIP contract. Though the&lt;em&gt; Times&lt;/em&gt; never attributed the alloys’ origins to aliens, &lt;a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/the-truth-about-those-alien-alloys-in-the-new-york-times-ufo-story/"&gt;the claim also received criticism&lt;/a&gt;. Nothing on these alloys has been revealed since. Bigelow hasn’t talked publicly about them since his interview with the&lt;em&gt; Times, &lt;/em&gt;and a Freedom of Information Act request filed to the DIA in early 2018 remains open with no records turned over (yet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Jt9sQX"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Detect, analyze and catalog UAPs that could potentially pose a threat to U.S. national security”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IwTIZf"&gt;While AATIP is now defunct, it has a successor. In June 2020, the Senate Intelligence Committee &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/jgx573/senate-intelligence-committee-confirms-the-us-navy-has-a-ufo-task-force"&gt;confirmed&lt;/a&gt; the existence of the Unidentified Aerial Phenomena Task Force, situated within the Office of Naval Intelligence. The Pentagon &lt;a href="https://www.defense.gov/Newsroom/Releases/Release/Article/2314065/establishment-of-unidentified-aerial-phenomena-task-force/"&gt;confirmed and announced&lt;/a&gt; the task force a few months later, describing in a statement the body’s mission “to detect, analyze and catalog UAPs that could potentially pose a threat to U.S. national security.” Last December, the intelligence committee gave the Pentagon six months to produce a report detailing the task force’s findings on UAPs. That’s the one due on June 25th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="xVWbdV"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will the report include? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="IMbhJT"&gt;It’s very unlikely the looming Pentagon report will tell us what the objects are, and it doesn’t sound like US intelligence officials know much about them. A &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/03/us/politics/ufos-sighting-alien-spacecraft-pentagon.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; report&lt;/a&gt; published on June 2nd says intelligence officials behind the report haven’t found any evidence attributing the phenomena to aliens, but they can’t rule it out either. The &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; also says intelligence officials swiftly ruled out any possibility of the objects being secret US aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UGa4gu"&gt;The classified version of the report was delivered to Congress on June 2nd, per a person familiar with it. The unclassified version — still in the works, according to the DoD press officer — is expected to be a fairly straightforward assessment of what the Pentagon’s UAP task force knows about the phenomena and what it doesn’t know. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="nd3ZEX"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are there any videos of the UFOs?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Z3Zjhw"&gt;Yep, there are four videos — three were declassified and released via the Freedom of Information Act by the Navy in 2020 after being leaked in 2007 and 2017, and one was leaked and later authenticated by the Defense Department in 2019. The videos show four separate incidents. Reid, the former senator and UAP hawk, said disclosure of the three videos “&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SenatorReid/status/1254836730546384897?s=20"&gt;only scratches the surface&lt;/a&gt; of research and materials available” to the Pentagon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2UnIVS"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Pentagon UFO videos: FLIR, GIMBAL, and GOFAST|102729" data-volume-uuid="4089203ee" data-volume-id="102729" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-161" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="k6E6AJ"&gt;The three declassified black-and-white videos, titled FLIR, GOFAST, and GIMBAL, are the most tantalizing. Captured by instrument cameras aboard Navy fighter aircraft in 2004, 2014, and 2015, they appear to show tiny, pill-shaped objects whizzing through the air. One of them appears to rotate midflight. Two videos show the objects speeding over ocean waters, coming with commentary from the pilots: “Look at that thing, dude!” one pilot yells. “It’s rotating,” says another. “There’s a whole fleet of them... They’re all going against the wind.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="NMCv05"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What could the UFOs be?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="BIhWE9"&gt;We don’t know yet. There are five main theories on what the UAPs are: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="c1OHHH"&gt;Something extremely benign like a drone or large bird&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="tZgSbc"&gt;Top-secret US technology that the Navy and other agencies don’t know about&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ifQ5qn"&gt;Foreign technology from US adversaries like Russia or China&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qI5Uha"&gt;Some kind of illusion, like a camera defect or &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/06/world/europe/flying-ship-cornwall.html"&gt;mirage&lt;/a&gt;, which are optical illusions caused by atmospheric conditions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="KkOja2"&gt;Aliens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="EgET50"&gt;Intelligence officials ruled out the possibility that the UAPs were glimpses of secret US technology in action, according to the &lt;em&gt;Times &lt;/em&gt;report. And it’s worth noting that the UAPs can be any number of those five theories (with aliens being the most controversial and polarizing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="0OmoQP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It might simply be a distant plane”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OoxoTn"&gt;Mick West, a pseudoscience debunker, told CNN that characteristics of the Naval aircraft videos make the objects appear more interesting than they should be. “It never really does anything interesting, and it might simply be a distant plane,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MickWest/status/1396136405349269511"&gt;he said&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r119JWI04Ls&amp;amp;ab_channel=MickWest"&gt;In a YouTube video&lt;/a&gt;, West rebutted the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;’ use of the term “Glowing Auras” in the headline of its 2017 story to describe UAPs recorded on thermal video cameras, which sometimes makes objects look like they’re glowing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="k3ya1I"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“All options have to be on the table.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aBsgwe"&gt;Elizondo, the very vocal former AATIP director, would beg to differ with West’s assessment. He hasn’t claimed UAPs represent alien technology, but his colorful descriptions to the press continue to hype up that prospect: “We’re dealing with a technology that could be 50-1,000 years ahead of us,” he &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/washington-post-live/2021/06/08/ufos-national-security-with-luis-elizondo-former-director-advanced-aerospace-threat-identification-program-aatip/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post &lt;/em&gt;in a live interview&lt;/a&gt; last week. “At the end of the day, we don’t know what we’re dealing with. All options have to be on the table.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1wEdCA"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is Blink-182 involved?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="8VPUnK"&gt;Not exactly. But Blink-182’s former lead singer, Tom DeLonge, is. DeLonge is obsessed with UFOs. Don’t even get him started on UFOs, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=heUCtu_fq18&amp;amp;ab_channel=MrSnrub"&gt;he warns in this undated interview on UFOs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iOy9Ab"&gt;DeLonge is so obsessed with unidentified phenomena that he left his punk-rock band bank in 2015 to start an organization in 2017 called To the Stars Academy of Arts &amp;amp; Sciences (TTSA), a research and media company based in Las Vegas — yes, the same city as Bigelow’s space company. TTSA is relevant because it’s where Elizondo and Chris Mellon, former Democratic staff director of the Senate Intelligence Committee and former deputy assistant secretary of defense for intelligence, wound up after leaving their government posts. The company pushed for and promoted the release of the three Navy videos and actually worked with Bigelow and various government agencies to investigate UAP. The organization signed an agreement with the US Army in 2019 to study “exotic metals” recovered under the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Fl6Rrz"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“TTSA has decided to restructure its operations”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NxiESw"&gt;But TTSA ran into problems during the COVID-19 pandemic, and Elizondo and Mellon left the company earlier this year, &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1710274/000149315221004131/form1-u.htm"&gt;according to a Securities and Exchange Commission filing&lt;/a&gt; from February. “TTSA has decided to restructure its operations to scale back its initiatives in science and tech commercialization and to place a greater emphasis on the operations of its entertainment business,” the filing said. It’s unclear what came of the Army agreement after TTSA’s shift away from UAP research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="4zhXHT"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But come on... it’s aliens, right?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="mP2VPR"&gt;Probably not. The slow drip of news from the Pentagon on UAPs has allowed a ton of &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/think/opinion/pentagon-s-ufo-footage-obama-s-curiosity-ratchet-expectations-big-ncna1268222"&gt;alien hype&lt;/a&gt; to fester. Does that mean aliens don’t exist anywhere in the universe? No. There are multiple ongoing projects to look for alien life, or signs of past alien life, well beyond UFOs. To name a few: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289668/nasa-mars-perseverance-rover-success"&gt;NASA’s Perseverance rover&lt;/a&gt; on Mars, a &lt;a href="https://pweb.cfa.harvard.edu/news/cfa-scientists-collaborate-new-study-search-universe-signs-technological-civilizations"&gt;joint academic hunt for technosignatures&lt;/a&gt; coming from distant corners of the universe, or any of the hundreds of research programs &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/23/22545453/alien-planets-view-earth-astronomers-journal-nature"&gt;examining exoplanets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dQEeLN"&gt;While an outcome involving aliens might be fun, it’s &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/astronaut-chris-hadfield-calls-alien-ufo-hype-foolishness/"&gt;most&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/30/opinion/ufo-sightings-report.html?partner=slack&amp;amp;smid=sl-share"&gt;likely&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://blogs.scientificamerican.com/observations/a-word-about-those-ufo-videos/"&gt;not going to happen&lt;/a&gt; in today’s UAP saga.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22550116/uap-ufo-pentagon-report-aliens"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22550116/uap-ufo-pentagon-report-aliens</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-25T11:33:58-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-25T11:33:58-04:00</updated>
    <title>Here are two podcasts from our Windows 11 coverage</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tY3Pw3BFITeX-bNZjmse_0d9hRo=/0x0:1650x1100/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69504359/windows11main.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xnoEEN"&gt;On Thursday, we saw the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/24/22546791/microsoft-windows-11-announcement-features-updates"&gt;official reveal of Windows 11 at Microsoft’s event&lt;/a&gt;, which showed off a redesign of the Microsoft operating system — including a replaced Start menu, updated app store, and lots more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jvOUrq"&gt;This week on&lt;em&gt; The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s flagship podcast, &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/the-vergecast"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;we&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;dedicate a majority of the show to talk about &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/microsoft"&gt;Windows 11&lt;/a&gt;. Co-hosts Nilay Patel and Dieter Bohn and &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; senior editor Tom Warren discuss the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/24/22548950/microsoft-windows-11-skype-onenote-live-tiles-cortana"&gt;biggest changes from Windows 10 to 11&lt;/a&gt;, the complications of bringing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/24/22548428/microsoft-windows-11-android-apps-support-amazon-store"&gt;Android apps to Windows with Amazon’s app store&lt;/a&gt;, and how Microsoft’s stance on being an open platform &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/24/22549007/microsoft-windows-11-satya-nadella-remarks-apple"&gt;has evolved among the other tech giants&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jb4s6f"&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="200" scrolling="no" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm?e=VMP9322407846&amp;amp;light=true" width="100%"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RARQ6f"&gt;We also have a sort of companion piece to this week’s show: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22549385/microsoft-satya-nadella-interview-windows-11-decoder"&gt;Nilay spoke with Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella&lt;/a&gt; on our other podcast, &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/decoder"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Decoder with Nilay Patel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, to chat about Windows as a platform, what Microsoft’s responsibilities are, and how he thinks the various antitrust bills in Congress will affect Microsoft’s plans for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ccx5uN"&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="200" scrolling="no" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm?e=VMP3710346080&amp;amp;light=true" width="100%"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bisrWQ"&gt;I would suggest listening to the interview with Satya Nadella first, as Nilay makes a few references to the interview in the &lt;em&gt;Vergecast&lt;/em&gt; episode. Both episodes together cover everything you need to know about the new update of Windows announced this week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="L1dolF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"The Vergecast","description":"The podcast you need to make sense of the week in tech news","label":"Subscribe","url":"https://pod.link/430333725"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22550346/vergecast-456-microsoft-windows-11-announcement-satya-nadella-interview"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22550346/vergecast-456-microsoft-windows-11-announcement-satya-nadella-interview</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Marino</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-25T11:22:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-25T11:22:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon acquires encrypted messaging app Wickr</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VN-TzdSqLMdRsg91tiRP7eyPM10=/4x0:4924x3280/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69504312/1232270762.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Jeff Halstead/Icon Sportswire via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Bfl2Dv"&gt;Wickr, the encrypted messaging app founded in 2012, has been purchased by Amazon, the company &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/security/aws-welcomes-wickr-to-the-team/"&gt;announced today&lt;/a&gt;. The terms of the deal were not disclosed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OvoPHE"&gt;“We’re excited to share that AWS has acquired Wickr, an innovative company that has developed the industry’s most secure, end-to-end encrypted, communication technology,” Stephen Schmidt, Amazon Web Services’ vice president, wrote. With a nod to the company's ever-deepening relationships with the military, and Washington in general, Schmidt added that Wickr’s features give “security conscious enterprises and government agencies the ability to implement important governance and security controls to help them meet their compliance requirements.” Schmidt himself has a background in this space: his LinkedIn &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephenschmidt1/"&gt;profile&lt;/a&gt; notes he spent a decade at the FBI. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fvE2Zs"&gt;Wickr’s app — like secure messaging competitor Signal — has been popular with journalists and whistleblowers; it's also been a go-to for criminals, &lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/epnapp/amazon-acquires-encrypted-messaging-app-wickr"&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt;. It’s unclear if the proximity to the tech monolith will impact the app’s popularity for free users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ygW8SR"&gt;In Amazon’s case, Schmidt indicates the acquisition was at least partially influenced by the need to preserve information security while working remotely. “With the move to hybrid work environments, due in part to the COVID-19 pandemic, enterprises and government agencies have a growing desire to protect their communications,” he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="54vlBU"&gt;Schmidt says AWS will be offering Wickr services effective immediately. Current Wickr users shouldn’t see significant changes for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22550361/amazon-wickr-aws-secure-messaging-encryption"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22550361/amazon-wickr-aws-secure-messaging-encryption</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bryan Menegus</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-25T11:02:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-25T11:02:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>Fortnite’s new virtual concert might be its trippiest yet</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QZtrQr6-_2scW0MEcxi4Y9V_1o4=/0x0:3240x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69504241/Fortnite_20210625085348.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mRwckH"&gt;Ever since &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/2/18208223/fortnite-epic-games-marshmello-concert-exciting-bizarre-future-music"&gt;Marshmello first took the virtual stage in &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, developer Epic Games has experimented with different ways to bring music into the game. That could mean &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/23/21233637/travis-scott-fortnite-concert-astronomical-live-report"&gt;a gigantic Travis Scott stomping around the battle royale island&lt;/a&gt; or even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/8/21423004/fortnite-party-royale-concert-series-dominic-fike"&gt;building a separate space dedicated explicitly to live performances&lt;/a&gt;. This week’s musical experience featuring English band Easy Life is yet another new technique: a strange world built in&lt;em&gt; Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;’s creative mode. It might be the trippiest virtual concert yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="neQ73F"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Fortnite’s experimental story is an attempt to create ‘the entertainment experience of the future’","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22338403/fortnite-story-narrative-interview-donald-mustard-epic-games"},{"title":"Fortnite is launching a concert series it hopes will become a ‘tour stop’ for artists","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/8/21423004/fortnite-party-royale-concert-series-dominic-fike"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pFYuGF"&gt;It starts out normal enough. Players are ushered into a virtual re-creation of The O2 Arena in London, where the band welcomes you via gigantic screen. From there, things get progressively weirder. First, you’re pushed into a room that slowly fills with water before you’re flushed down a gigantic toilet into a surreal desert filled with massive tube TVs. It’s a bit like a pop art take on Salvador Dalí. Subsequent locations are just as odd: you’ll dance inside the corpse of a huge monster, ride a hoverboard across a twisted city straight out of &lt;em&gt;Inception&lt;/em&gt;, and then float amid the stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid c-image-grid__odd c-image-grid__odd-first-wide"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cb9t9UjBTCSjPJJ0p094Mgp0Kes=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22681124/Fortnite_20210625084911.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YzgEEhpfSXlI8EmMEcoAvulSROo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22681089/Fortnite_20210625090538.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yWqM5fMjZpV8RWcBuCcPXmeJi80=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22681210/Fortnite_20210625085727.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="innItU"&gt;Each area is also outfitted with lots and lots of screens where you can watch the band. There are TVs floating in the sky and even some wedged between the ribs of the deceased monster. It’s kind of like watching a series of music videos while hanging out in a bunch of weird virtual spaces. You can dance, run, and jump, but there are no guns or ways to mess with other players. The videos also match the theme of the locations: when you’re in the desert, for instance, all of the band are buried to their necks in sand. At the end, a sense of normalcy resumes, with players transported to a luxury box back at the arena, like you’re waking up from a dream. The whole thing lasts about 20 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QrD6ld"&gt;The Easy Life event, which runs until 7PM ET on June 27th, presents an interesting middle ground for &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; concerts. The Travis Scott and Marshmello shows were impressive but were also huge undertakings; the entire battle royale game comes to a halt in order to accommodate them. (That’s likely the reason there have only been two since 2019.) Meanwhile, concerts in party royale — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/30/21242668/fortnite-party-royale-social-space-metaverse-travis-scott"&gt;a violence-free social space that debuted in 2020&lt;/a&gt; — are relatively simple, as players can gather together to watch a performance on a big screen. Easy Life’s show, meanwhile, has the best of both worlds. It was built in &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;’s &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt;-like creative mode, so it exists in its own space distinct from the main game, but it’s also much stranger and more interactive than the party royale events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iWgAFI"&gt;Music is clearly a big part of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;’s plans as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22417697/apple-epic-fortnite-app-store-antitrust-trial-day-1"&gt;it continues to shift into something much more ambitious than a multiplayer shooter&lt;/a&gt;. “Our lofty goal is to create the entertainment experience of the future,” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22338403/fortnite-story-narrative-interview-donald-mustard-epic-games"&gt;Epic’s chief creative officer Donald Mustard told me in March&lt;/a&gt;. And utilizing the creative seems like a good way to make these experiences both more interesting and more regular. At the very least, it’s a chance to listen to an up-and-coming band while riding a hoverboard across some skyscrapers.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22550240/fortnite-easy-life-concert-o2-arena"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22550240/fortnite-easy-life-concert-o2-arena</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-25T10:22:12-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-25T10:22:12-04:00</updated>
    <title>UK antitrust watchdog investigating Amazon and Google over fake reviews</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NSvDmpli0c9roK5vI-hjdFn3gb0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69503997/acastro_181114_1777_amazon_hq2_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tSRFlx"&gt;The UK’s Competition and Markets Authority (CMA) is probing whether Amazon and Google broke consumer laws by failing to take action against fake reviews on their sites, the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/cma-to-investigate-amazon-and-google-over-fake-reviews"&gt;agency announced Friday.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1yhtNr"&gt;“We are investigating concerns that Amazon and Google have not been doing enough to prevent or remove fake reviews to protect customers and honest businesses,” Andrea Coscelli, the CMA’s chief executive, said in a statement. “Our worry is that millions of online shoppers could be misled by reading fake reviews and then spending their money based on those recommendations.” She added that it was unfair to businesses that adhere to the rules if other businesses can give their own products fake 5-star reviews. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7wheaY"&gt;An Amazon spokesperson said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; on Friday that the company devotes “significant resources to preventing fake or incentivized reviews” from appearing on its platform, adding that the company works to ensure reviews accurately reflect a customer’s experience with a product. “We will continue to assist the CMA with its enquiries and we note its confirmation that no findings have been made against our business,” the spokesperson said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7qqBOR"&gt;In a &lt;a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/how-amazon-works/creating-a-trustworthy-reviews-experience"&gt;June 16th blog post&lt;/a&gt;, Amazon said some “bad actors” were using external platforms to buy and sell fake reviews, and it blamed social media companies it said had been slow to act in flagging fake reviews on their own platforms — although it noted the response time had improved somewhat over the last year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kQqfGb"&gt;“While we appreciate that some social media companies have become much faster at responding, to address this problem at scale, it is imperative for social media companies to invest adequately in proactive controls to detect and enforce fake reviews ahead of our reporting the issue to them,” the blog post reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DaVSdR"&gt;Amazon recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/17/22538779/amazon-sunvalley-tek-ravpower-vava-taotronics-pulled-store"&gt;removed several gadget brands’&lt;/a&gt; storefronts from its site following a &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/fake-reviews-and-inflated-ratings-are-still-a-problem-for-amazon-11623587313"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; investigation&lt;/a&gt; into fake reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aTg7Y5"&gt;A Google spokesperson said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; on Friday that it has strict policies that clearly state that reviews must be based on real experiences, “and when we find policy violations, we take action— from removing abusive content to disabling user accounts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZezrMt"&gt;Once it concludes its investigation, the CMA can take enforcement action if it finds Amazon or Google broke UK consumer protection laws, which could range from getting commitments from the tech firms to change how they handle fake reviews to possible court action. The CMA noted that, at this stage, it “has not reached a view” on whether the companies broke any laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7adHW2"&gt;The investigation is the UK regulator’s latest attempt to scrutinize fake reviews on US tech platforms. In April, Facebook removed 16,000 groups that were trading fake reviews after the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/cma-intervention-leads-to-further-facebook-action-on-fake-reviews"&gt;CMA raised concerns&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3CZ2pp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cbPtjS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nfPEJr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sF48ml"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22550171/uk-antitrust-watchdog-investigating-amazon-google-fake-reviews"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22550171/uk-antitrust-watchdog-investigating-amazon-google-fake-reviews</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-25T10:12:12-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-25T10:12:12-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft’s Panos Panay on building Windows 11 during a pandemic, Android, and the leak</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AQi48XT8wsTqfHHsaJ4cMU3xFWY=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69503946/Panos_Panay_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="NhV8Zu"&gt;The big &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/15/22535123/microsoft-windows-11-leak-screenshots-start-menu"&gt;Windows 11 leak&lt;/a&gt; earlier this month was never part of Microsoft’s plan. Developers at the company have spent the majority of the pandemic working from home and secretly building a new version of Windows that’s designed for a post-pandemic era. “It didn’t really leak. It was some early weird build,” says Microsoft’s Windows and devices chief Panos Panay in an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “It didn’t matter, when something like that gets out incomplete, you’re like: okay.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z1JrPc"&gt;Panay describes it as just another test of patience in the distinctive journey of how Windows 11 came to be. Just months before the pandemic began, Panay stood onstage and introduced the world to two new dual-screen devices: the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/2/20889000/microsoft-surface-neo-windows-10x-hands-on-features-price-photos-release-date"&gt;Surface Neo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21428763/microsoft-surface-duo-review"&gt;Surface Duo&lt;/a&gt;. These were supposed to revolutionize the way we work on the go — then the pandemic hit, and the world stopped going anywhere. Panay says he still believes in dual-screen devices, but the world of PCs has changed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bcFMPevTNZw1fOQabEDKCqhp0RQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19247635/akrales_190930_3649_0115.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft’s Surface Neo device.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="zeHGBr"&gt;“You have to step back and consider what’s most important for people right now, and so much has changed over the last 18 months,” explains Panay. “A lot of the time spent over the last 18 months&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;[within Microsoft]&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;was looking at Windows and what it means to be for what’s next [with hybrid work].”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B8TRBc"&gt;Microsoft was planning to ship Windows 10X, a simplified version of Windows made for dual-screen devices, on its Surface Neo device. The company quickly pivoted toward &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/4/21246561/microsoft-windows-10x-single-screens-windows-usage-demand-coronavirus-pandemic"&gt;promising Windows 10X for laptops&lt;/a&gt; once the pandemic began and then eventually reworked the OS into Windows 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3GhSzN"&gt;The PC market had its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225356/pc-sales-shipments-2020-growth-idc-canalys-remote-work"&gt;first big growth spurt in a decade during 2020&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s clear Microsoft saw a big opportunity in the reported 75 percent year-over-year increase in the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/4/21246561/microsoft-windows-10x-single-screens-windows-usage-demand-coronavirus-pandemic"&gt;time spent in Windows 10&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;All signs are pointing toward a mix of working from home and the office, and Windows 11 is the result.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;“The PC started to move from fitting into people’s lives to shifting our lives to fit into the PC,” says Panay.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_OcrdhinUDzFoBkEbHtpt-BLM6o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22681057/Wondows_11_Start.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new Windows 11 Start menu.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="gDZNqD"&gt;Windows 11 was born out of a pandemic, and that influence is clear. “We designed this product living through the pandemic worldwide,” says Panay. Windows engineers used Microsoft Teams to communicate daily, and that way of working has clearly inspired at least one Windows 11 feature: universal mute. A new mute button appears on the taskbar in Windows 11, and it works across apps to prevent embarrassing microphone moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hpZSeN"&gt;It almost feels like time away from the office made Microsoft realize some of the other pain points in Windows for remote workers. This is highlighted best in a new Windows 11 feature that will finally group your apps on the screen you left them on if you’re using multiple monitors or connecting up a laptop to a monitor. (In Windows 10 currently, your apps will often be randomly rearranged when you disconnect or reconnect a monitor.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/z28RbJ29WRoywRhihamjB5AEcRQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22681063/mute_unmute.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Windows 11’s new universal mute button.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="B6vqo8"&gt;The distinction between work and play has blurred considerably during the pandemic, and Windows 11 seems designed to tackle both states equally well. For the former, Microsoft Teams is integrated directly into Windows 11. Android apps will also run alongside Windows apps and offer access to the mobile and tablet apps that aren’t typically associated with the productivity world of Windows.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;“Think about it this way: what is it that you want to do with your device, and where do you want to do it?” asks Panay. “Ultimately, Android plays a key role in that.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1y9OEG"&gt;Microsoft has been trying to get tablet and mobile apps onto Windows for years, and whether developers share that same desire remains to be seen. Microsoft is now supporting UWP, PWA, win32, and Android apps in its own app store, which is good news for developers and consumers alike. It’s a far more open store and a significant change that could see additions like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22550103/microsoft-new-windows-app-store-steam-welcome"&gt;Steam being part of the Windows store&lt;/a&gt; one day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="abQ3lI"&gt;Windows 11 isn’t finished yet, though. Microsoft now has months of testing to complete before a wide release is available in October. And yes, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/24/22546801/microsoft-windows-11-free-upgrade-details"&gt;upgrades for existing Windows 10 users are free&lt;/a&gt;. “I’m proud of what the team has done, and I feel super proud of that team holding together and getting to this point today,” says Panay.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22550134/microsoft-windows-11-panos-panay-interview"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22550134/microsoft-windows-11-panos-panay-interview</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-25T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-25T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Hybrid work is coming to big tech. Its contractors might not be so lucky</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="FRANCE-ECONOMY-HEALTH-VIRUS" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nJeccnQcyc1wYovV-Wtr19gpbMM=/0x0:5453x3635/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69503849/1229318293.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by CHRISTOPHE ARCHAMBAULT/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pRoNjf"&gt;In fits and starts, the US is reopening — in many cases to the chagrin of office workers who have settled into work-from-wherever setups they’ve had the past 16-ish months to perfect. And given the willingness of many of those same workers to quit rather than go back to full-time cubicle life, many companies have offered some form of “hybrid” arrangement as a compromise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rrj36O"&gt;It seems that benefit isn’t being extended to all workers, though. Amazon, Apple, Facebook, Google, and Microsoft were short on concrete answers as to which contingent workers — which comprise sizable, sometimes majority portions of their workforce, and perform functions from hospitality and security to content moderation and coding — if any would be allowed to work remotely. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="CCIz44"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10619076"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sbMzdw"&gt;Each of these tech giants appear to be instituting some version of partial remote work for corporate employees, with some minor variations. &lt;a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/workplace/amazon-updates-return-to-office-guidance"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://blog.google/inside-google/life-at-google/hybrid-approach-work"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2021/03/22/the-philosophy-and-practice-of-our-hybrid-workplace/"&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; each announced these changes publicly on their corporate blogs, while internal memos to the same effect within Facebook and Apple were reported on by the &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-lets-more-employees-choose-full-time-remote-work-or-return-to-the-office-11623258049"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465846/apple-employees-return-office-three-days-week-september"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, respectively. All instituted a future of what Microsoft hazily described as “working from home part of the time (less than 50%) as standard for most roles,” and its competitors as some variation of requiring three days per week in the office. Apple took the extra step of mandating which three days — Monday, Tuesday, and Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WerBel"&gt;There are of course, caveats in both directions. Some roles were flagged by Facebook and Amazon as not being remote work-applicable: jobs like hardware engineers and data center workers. On the other hand, nearly all of these companies noted that eligible employees could remain fully remote if they were granted that permission by their manager. Google even &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/google-rolls-out-tool-to-show-its-employees-compensation-changes-for-transferring-offices/"&gt;developed a tool&lt;/a&gt; that will show remote workers how much it plans to shave off their salaries if they go the remote option and move somewhere with a lower cost of living. (Thanks?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nA3t6B"&gt;Missing from any of these memos or announcements, though, was any mention of whether remote work options were available to the legions of contractors that help these companies function. Spokespeople for most of these companies sidestepped the question. “When it comes down to our contractors and partners, I wouldn’t be able to speak on their behalf or how they would implement our policy,” an Amazon spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge.&lt;/em&gt; Facebook provided a similar answer. Facebook’s spokesperson did not respond to a request for a list of which agencies they used for contract labor so that we could ask each company about its remote work policies, while Amazon declined to provide one citing “confidentiality reasons.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T8YErj"&gt;A spokesperson with Google stated that temporary staff would likely be required to come in the same days as the teams of employees that oversee them, while the companies that employ its contingent “vendors” had already determined which jobs could or could not perform their work remotely. The same spokesperson was not able to provide an approximate percentage for how many of these vendors would have that benefit extended to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Hzmjz"&gt;Through an external communications agency, a spokesperson for Microsoft wrote that aforementioned corporate blog was “all the company has to share.” Apple did not respond to multiple requests for information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9qnZ98"&gt;It’s logical to defer to these external agencies, but it also belies how much leverage tech companies have in these relationships. Microsoft has previously &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/076474aa0b1b47b6b4790dbf98ed6108"&gt;required&lt;/a&gt; firms it works with provide paid childcare leave for its contractors; Google too has &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/google-require-suppliers-give-benefits-workers/"&gt;mandated&lt;/a&gt; contractors receive at least $15 per hour, healthcare, and parental leave. Facebook has also &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2019/05/compensating-and-supporting-contractors/"&gt;instituted&lt;/a&gt; “well-being and resiliency training” for its contractor moderators. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IBDFO2"&gt;It’s also a bit hard to believe — especially in instances where these workers would be reporting to these companies’ facilities — that these companies lack any direct oversight over who is coming into their offices at a time when indoor capacity limits are not only a matter of corporate policy, but often a matter of state mandate too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KgpBMi"&gt;The issues of remote work for contractors is also not a new one — and much earlier in the pandemic it caused quite a bit of bad PR for several of these companies. Facebook took heat from having some of those same content moderators working from the office back in November, a month where the US was seeing around 100,000 new cases of covid daily — and from awarding monetary bonuses to employees &lt;a href="https://theintercept.com/2020/03/17/facebook-coronavirus-bonus-contractors/"&gt;but not to contractors&lt;/a&gt;. Google was requiring some contractors to report to work in person in March of 2020, sparking internal &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/17/21184495/google-employees-memo-contract-workers-coronavirus-covid-19"&gt;backlash from its own employees&lt;/a&gt;; it also rescinded job offers to around 2,000 contractors — citing the economic downturn — while apportioning $1,000 each for employees to purchase desks and other items for their from-home workspaces. Around the same time, hundreds of contractor jobs with Apple were reportedly suspended without pay — only to be restored after a contingent of unionized janitors and the Wall Street Journal began &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-commits-to-paying-contractors-after-some-were-told-theyd-lose-work-11585667276"&gt;asking questions&lt;/a&gt;. Most of this &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/m7j7mb/amazon-delivery-drivers-are-overwhelmed-and-overworked-by-covid-19-surge"&gt;barely holds a candle&lt;/a&gt; to what Amazon’s considerably more frontline delivery contractors experienced, as a whole country, trapped inside, dramatically increased its online purchasing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iqZlJx"&gt;This is all relevant insofar as it illustrates that the two-tiered system of employment within these companies is alive and well, but also that these very big, very wealthy companies, supposedly staffed by the best and brightest, had many, many months to consider a return to office plan that would be transparent and comprehensible. Contractors themselves, and a news media willing to report on them, has been asking how tech companies will handle this disparity in benefits &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/03/09/tech-contractors-coronavirus/"&gt;essentially since the pandemic began&lt;/a&gt;. A year and a half later, there’s still no clear answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kDduGv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22545717/big-tech-hybrid-work-remote-contractors-google-apple-amazon-facebook-microsoft"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22545717/big-tech-hybrid-work-remote-contractors-google-apple-amazon-facebook-microsoft</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bryan Menegus</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-25T09:27:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-25T09:27:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>eBay coupon takes 15 percent off certified refurbished gear</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-B6aBars7oFy7sWnogajYF8v71g=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69503632/akrales_190716_3546_0185.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bose Noise Canceling Headphones 700&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wm1pg6"&gt;If you’re in the market for a set of headphones, a security camera, phone charger, or other gear and don’t mind buying something that’s certified refurbished, eBay is taking an additional 15 percent off the price of many items (up to $150) with a coupon code. You ca&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ebay.com%2Fe%2F_electronics%2Ffourth-of-july-certified-refurbished-coupon%3Fmkcid%3D1%26mkrid%3D711-53200-19255-0%26siteid%3D0%26campid%3D5338794975%26customid%3DVergeDeals062521%26toolid%3D10001%26mkevt%3D1&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F6%2F25%2F22550009%2Febay-coupon-refurbished-sale-apple-tv-4k-nintendo-eshop-sony-wh1000xm4" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;n view everything that qualifies he&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ebay.com%2Fe%2F_electronics%2Ffourth-of-july-certified-refurbished-coupon&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F6%2F25%2F22550009%2Febay-coupon-refurbished-sale-apple-tv-4k-nintendo-eshop-sony-wh1000xm4" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;re&lt;/a&gt;; we’ve highlighted some of our favorites below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EiPSBI"&gt;In addition, we’ve got a selection of new headphones, smart thermostats, smartwatches, and more in today’s roundup, so there should be something for almost everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ojnXgQ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10623742"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="ffq1ug"&gt;Jabra’s Elite 75t are &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ebay.com%2Fitm%2F164105789375%3Fepid%3D27041444938%26hash%3Ditem2635779fbf%253Ag%253AfX0AAOSwCctfMo%257EF%26_trkparms%3D%252526rpp_cid%25253D609d7b5cf2b4a7bb16f4e18e%26var%3D464078687824&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F6%2F25%2F22550009%2Febay-coupon-refurbished-sale-apple-tv-4k-nintendo-eshop-sony-wh1000xm4" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;down to just $64&lt;/a&gt; with the &lt;strong&gt;JULY4SAVINGS&lt;/strong&gt; coupon code on this certified refurbished pair (from $75). Check out our review &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/15/21066947/jabra-elite-75t-review-wireless-earbuds-airpods-alternative"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="TtNdgS"&gt;The Sennheiser Momentum 3 are &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ebay.com%2Fitm%2F373499660075%3Fepid%3D8034384288%26mkcid%3D1%26mkrid%3D711-53200-19255-0%26siteid%3D0%26campid%3D5338794975%26customid%3DVergeDeals062521%26toolid%3D10001%26mkevt%3D1&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F6%2F25%2F22550009%2Febay-coupon-refurbished-sale-apple-tv-4k-nintendo-eshop-sony-wh1000xm4" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$213 in certified refurbished condition&lt;/a&gt; with the &lt;strong&gt;JULY4SAVINGS&lt;/strong&gt; coupon code on eBay (from $250). Read our review &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/5/20843395/sennheiser-momentum-wireless-3-review-release-date-news-specs-features-noise-cancelling-headphones"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="jBSCSZ"&gt;If you’re looking for a new set of noise-canceling headphones, Newegg has Sony’s excellent WH-1000XM4 for $260, nearly matching the lowest price we’ve seen on them. Check out our review &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22523584/sony-wf-1000xm4-wireless-earbuds-headphones-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gwwIDb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10613511"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="6Yj4u5"&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy Buds Pro offer great sound quality and comfort, plus effective noise cancelation. You can get the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bluetooth-Wireless-Cancelling-Charging-Resistant/dp/B08MWWNGYG?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;silver model for $165&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bluetooth-Wireless-Cancelling-Charging-Resistant/dp/B08MWZHHKP?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;black&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bluetooth-Wireless-Cancelling-Charging-Resistant/dp/B08MWY75DH?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;violet&lt;/a&gt; colors for $5 more on Amazon today (normally $200). Check out our review &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22231848/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="GYjlhC"&gt;Newegg also has a &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=44583&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fnintendo-50-00%2Fp%2FN82E16832074004%3Fnm_mc%3DAFC-RAN-COM%26cm_mmc%3DAFC-RAN-COM%26utm_medium%3Daffiliates%26utm_source%3Dafc-The%2BWirecutter%26AFFID%3D3249826%26AFFNAME%3DThe%2BWirecutter%26ACRID%3D1%26ASUBID%3DAwgAAAAAAAAAADEn%26ASID%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fwww.nytimes.com%252Fwirecutter%252Fdeals%252F%26ranMID%3D44583%26ranEAID%3D3249826%26ranSiteID%3D7m8EnekPF5E-iN2tDcWC0Fn67ojgj4j1WA" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$50 Nintendo eShop Gift Card for $45&lt;/a&gt; when you use the &lt;strong&gt;93XRH33&lt;/strong&gt; promo code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="tQckrd"&gt;Amazon has some leftover Prime Day sales on smart thermostats, including the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08HRWWCTR?ref_=Oct_DLandingS_D_d2299fb4_NA&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nest Thermostat for $100 (from $130)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/ecobee-SmartThermostat-Voice-Control-Black/dp/B07NQT85FC/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ecobee SmartThermostat for $211&lt;/a&gt; (from $250). Check out our reviews of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21725036/google-nest-thermostat-2020-review"&gt;Nest&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/3/18646398/ecobee-smartthermostat-review-alexa-announcement-price-specs-features"&gt;Ecobee&lt;/a&gt; for more info.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="i7kJi3"&gt;Costco has the &lt;a href="https://www.costco.com/apple-watch-se-40mm-gps.product.100457716.html"&gt;Apple Watch SE for just $240&lt;/a&gt; (members only), a discount of $30 from its regular price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="t5dAOo"&gt;For sharing your tunes, AT&amp;amp;T has the &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.att.com/buy/accessories/speakers/ultimate-ears-wonderboom-2-speaker-black.html?source=ECAuAT10600aff12A&amp;amp;wtExtndSource=5513721&amp;amp;CI=CJ_AFFILIATE&amp;amp;RI=CJ1&amp;amp;RD=37922269&amp;amp;tfn=aff&amp;amp;cjevent=6a0b300fd57611eb802016ad0a1c0e12" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ultimate Ears Wonderboom 2 speaker for $65&lt;/a&gt;, a discount of $35 off its regular price. Check out our review &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/6/4/18647361/ultimate-ears-wonderboom-2-bluetooth-speaker-update-waterproof-stereo-battery-99"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="dYgD04"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="tA03nK"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/6/25/22550009/ebay-coupon-refurbished-sale-apple-tv-4k-nintendo-eshop-sony-wh1000xm4"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/6/25/22550009/ebay-coupon-refurbished-sale-apple-tv-4k-nintendo-eshop-sony-wh1000xm4</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
