<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-03T13:09:16-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T13:09:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T13:09:16-05:00</updated>
    <title>Sony announces six PlayStation VR games, including Doom 3 for VR</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Doom 3 VR Key Art" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CIu3fg73pA0lRjvYpWGJtd4ZR9o=/85x0:1003x612/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68904502/VR_DAY_ANNOUNCE_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SU3oN0"&gt;Sony has announced a new slate of PlayStation VR games for later this year. It includes a virtual reality adaptation of &lt;em&gt;Doom 3&lt;/em&gt;, as well as titles from a few successful VR studios and a couple of relative newcomers to VR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VTSM1P"&gt;Sony announced a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22296998/sony-ps5-next-gen-vr-headset-virtual-reality-features"&gt;new generation of PSVR&lt;/a&gt; for its PlayStation 5 console last month. The headset will come with a redesigned controller, a single cord instead of the original cable box, and a higher-resolution screen, among other upgrades. But Sony hasn’t unveiled the headset or offered many details, and it’s said the device won’t arrive in 2021. So today’s games will be launching for PSVR — with the promise of a better experience down the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gFgfcZ"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UgrBa7Xzv_o?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WhJOpE"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doom 3 VR&lt;/em&gt;, the only title with a precise release date, will launch on March 29th for PlayStation 4 and PlayStation 5. It’s a “retooled” port of the original 2004 shooter and its two expansions, designed for PSVR’s gun-like Aim accessory. A short trailer offers a preview of the gameplay and updated graphics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DDC92d"&gt;This is the second &lt;em&gt;Doom&lt;/em&gt; game for PSVR, following the 2017 VR original &lt;em&gt;Doom VFR&lt;/em&gt;. It’s also not the first time &lt;em&gt;Doom 3&lt;/em&gt; has appeared in VR. The game was originally promised as part of the Oculus Rift headset launch, but it was canceled &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/5/5/5682892/oculus-responds-to-zenimax-intellectual-property-accusations"&gt;amid a lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;em&gt;Doom&lt;/em&gt; rights holder ZeniMax. (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21449178/microsoft-xbox-bethesda-zenimax-media-acquisition-xbox-game-pass"&gt;ZeniMax was acquired&lt;/a&gt; by Sony’s rival Microsoft last year.) More recently, a modding team &lt;a href="https://uploadvr.com/doom-3-oculus-quest/"&gt;unofficially ported &lt;em&gt;Doom 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to the Oculus Quest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="NVciTM"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zoOAuUly3-I?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=2&amp;amp;start=2" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="w88tkv"&gt;Vertigo Games, creator of zombie VR shooter &lt;em&gt;Arizona Sunshine&lt;/em&gt;, will be bringing its cooperative followup &lt;em&gt;After the Fall&lt;/em&gt; to PSVR as well. &lt;em&gt;After the Fall&lt;/em&gt; was announced a couple of years ago, and it was &lt;a href="https://www.roadtovr.com/co-op-vr-shooter-fall-delayed-early-2021/"&gt;expected to launch in 2020&lt;/a&gt; on both PSVR and PC-based VR. It was delayed in part because of the coronavirus pandemic, rescheduled for early 2021 — a window Sony is reiterating here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JozeJV"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EEkjvHVUXto?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pbquP0"&gt;PlayStation VR will also be supporting &lt;em&gt;I Expect You To Die 2&lt;/em&gt; — a sequel to the wildly successful escape room title, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22252566/i-expect-you-to-die-sequel-announced-vr-game-release-date"&gt;originally announced for Steam in January&lt;/a&gt;. The game promises the same richly interactive spy-themed puzzles as &lt;em&gt;I Expect You To Die&lt;/em&gt;, which has proven one of the most enduringly popular VR games since its launch in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3JgMdJ"&gt;The other games don’t have the same immediate name recognition, but they’re intriguing additions to the PSVR catalog. &lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/03/03/ps-vr-action-adventure-fracked-launches-this-summer/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fracked &lt;/em&gt;is developed&lt;/a&gt; by nDreams, the studio behind kayak-based stealth shooter &lt;em&gt;Phantom: Covert Ops&lt;/em&gt;. Continuing the sports-plus-guns formula, its new game is an action shooter built around skiing — alongside climbing, zip lines, and old-fashioned duck-and-cover combat. It’s also apparently about a fracking facility that’s been “taken over by an army of gun-wielding, interdimensional maniacs.” (It’s unclear whether the maniacs are pro- or anti-fracking.) The game will be released this summer for PlayStation Move controllers on both generations of Sony consoles, but with improved frame rates and resolution on the PlayStation 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TBEvMs"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PiwgUwtJjEA?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ioNMuO"&gt;In a slightly calmer vein, there’s &lt;em&gt;Song in the Smoke &lt;/em&gt;by &lt;em&gt;Galak-Z &lt;/em&gt;developer 17-Bit. It’s &lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/03/03/embrace-the-primal-wilderness-of-ps-vr-survival-game-song-in-the-smoke/"&gt;a VR survival game&lt;/a&gt; that focuses on crafting, hunting, scavenging, and exploration in a mysterious world. A trailer shows off some gorgeous landscapes and creature design, as well as mechanics like archery. It’s launching at an unspecified point in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="yUl7gw"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5JE5uh74rZw?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vHQwlI"&gt;Sony also &lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/03/03/expansive-jrpg-inspired-mmo-zenith-is-coming-to-ps-vr/"&gt;announced the 2021 release&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;em&gt;Zenith&lt;/em&gt;, an anime-influenced massively multiplayer roleplaying game funded on Kickstarter last year. It’s set in a high-tech fantasy world that’s designed for players to climb and glide around, in addition to fighting with a VR-adapted version of conventional RPG combat.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311254/sony-psvr-showcase-vr-games-doom-3-i-expect-you-to-die-ps4-ps5"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311254/sony-psvr-showcase-vr-games-doom-3-i-expect-you-to-die-ps4-ps5</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T13:08:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T13:08:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>NFTs, explained</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CUwmt6PC9yCHDThvasRp_NBDs7Q=/0x70:1252x905/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68904498/Screen_Shot_2021_03_02_at_3.21.50_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.cryptokitties.co/kitty/896775" target="_blank"&gt;Cryptokitties.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="w5m7vj"&gt;There’s nothing like an explosion of blockchain news to leave you thinking, “Um… what’s going on here?” That’s the feeling I’ve experienced while reading about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/1/22308075/grimes-nft-6-million-sales-nifty-gateway-warnymph"&gt;Grimes getting millions of dollars for NFTs&lt;/a&gt; or about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287956/nyan-cat-crypto-art-foundation-nft-sale-chris-torres"&gt;Nyan Cat being sold as one&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m3ofto"&gt;You might be wondering: what is an NFT, anyhow?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qq4l9b"&gt;After literal hours of reading, I think I know. I also think I’m going to cry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vM2Wj0"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Okay, let’s start with the basics. What is an NFT? What does NFT stand for?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="XAkRR1"&gt;Non-fungible token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8lwjaI"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That doesn’t make it any clearer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jBCh6D"&gt;Right, sorry. “Non-fungible” more or less means that it’s unique and can’t be replaced with something else. For example, a bitcoin is fungible — trade one for another bitcoin, and you’ll have exactly the same thing. A one-of-a-kind trading card, however, is non-fungible. If you traded it for a different card, you’d have something completely different. You gave up a Squirtle, and got a 1909 T206 Honus Wagner, which &lt;em&gt;StadiumTalk&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.stadiumtalk.com/s/most-expensive-baseball-cards-985687df1bbe45c5"&gt;calls “the Mona Lisa of baseball cards.&lt;/a&gt;” (I’ll take their word for it.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HudKGN"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do NFTs work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MbvoGM"&gt;At a very high level, most NFTs are part of the Ethereum blockchain. Ethereum is a cryptocurrency, like bitcoin or dogecoin, but its blockchain also supports these NFTs, which store extra information that makes them work differently from, say, an ETH coin. It is worth noting that other blockchains can implement their own versions of NFTs. (&lt;a href="https://dappradar.com/blog/tron-introduces-nft-standard-trc-721"&gt;Some already have&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ifr4y9"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s worth picking up at the NFT supermarket?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VbHk7K"&gt;NFTs can really be anything digital (such as drawings, music, your brain downloaded and turned into an AI), but a lot of the current excitement is around using the tech to sell digital art. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vAcH3qsbkwApyVu4-Zl-AJ1hXFA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22341197/doge.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://opensea.io/assets/0x3b3ee1931dc30c1957379fac9aba94d1c48a5405/576" target="_blank"&gt;NyanCat on OpenSea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dogecoin isn’t an NFT. But this GIF of a dogecoin is.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Go0IlP"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You mean, like, people buying my good tweets?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4V58lf"&gt;I don’t think anyone can stop you, but that’s not really what I meant. A lot of the conversation is about NFTs as &lt;a href="https://www.adweek.com/media/nfts-guide-nonfungible-tokens-cryptomedia-trend-ownership-internet/"&gt;an evolution of fine art collecting&lt;/a&gt;, only with digital art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qaSIX4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do people really think this will become like art collecting?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ig7cLB"&gt;I’m sure some people really hope so — like whoever paid almost $390,000 for a &lt;a href="https://niftygateway.com/itemdetail/primary/0x948b3515d81034a3c16d5393c6c155946c93c103/1"&gt;50-second video by Grimes&lt;/a&gt; or the person who paid $6.6 million for &lt;a href="https://niftygateway.com/itemdetail/secondary/0x12f28e2106ce8fd8464885b80ea865e98b465149/100010001"&gt;a video by Beeple&lt;/a&gt;. Actually, one of Beeple’s pieces &lt;a href="https://onlineonly.christies.com/s/beeple-first-5000-days/lots/2020"&gt;is being auctioned at Christie’s&lt;/a&gt;, the famou—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q3dcQxqw8oMubtaqyVI6ZzIM37o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22341206/Screen_Shot_2021_03_02_at_3.31.26_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Beeple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yoink!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="i77Dld"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sorry, I was busy right-clicking on that Beeple video and downloading the same file the person paid millions of dollars for.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jNNHsj"&gt;Wow, rude. But yeah, that’s where it &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/nfts-boom-collectors-shell-out-crypto/"&gt;gets a bit awkward&lt;/a&gt;. You can copy a digital file as many times as you want, including the art that’s included with an NFT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wmQtyf"&gt;But NFTs are designed to give you something that can’t be copied: ownership of the work (though the artist can still retain the copyright and reproduction rights, just like with physical artwork). To put it in terms of physical art collecting: anyone can buy a Monet print. But only one person can own the original.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nWoqGE"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No shade on Beeple, but the video isn’t really a Monet.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZBUNfq"&gt;What do you think of &lt;a href="https://niftygateway.com/itemdetail/secondary/0x4140783cc1ba30653a0777126b122931e233ba14/1300010027"&gt;the $3,600 Gucci Ghost&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zeTKAEvLmop3TJky4G1whbuRXB0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22341209/GucciGhost.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF by Trevor Andrew&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This last sold for $3,600, but the current owner is asking for $16,300.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lGn9Ci"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Also, if I got a Monet, I could appreciate it as a physical object. With digital art, a copy is literally as good as the original.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4WyUKa"&gt;But the &lt;em&gt;flex &lt;/em&gt;of owning an original Beeple...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="juDtL1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the point?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6d92bZ"&gt;That really depends on whether you’re an artist or a buyer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dt7KYi"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m an artist.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cZ1eqE"&gt;First off: I’m proud of you. Way to go. You might be interested in NFTs because it gives you a way to sell work that there otherwise might not be much of a market for. If you come up with a really cool digital sticker idea, what are you going to do? Sell it on the iMessage App Store? No way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LIsq2g"&gt;Also, NFTs have a feature that you can enable that will pay you a percentage every time &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-02/nft-art-boom-is-the-same-concept-as-the-photography-market?sref=M8H6LjUF"&gt;the NFT is sold or changes hands&lt;/a&gt;, making sure that if your work gets super popular and balloons in value, you’ll see some of that benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u7oBax"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m a buyer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GwjNxk"&gt;One of the obvious benefits of buying art is it lets you financially support artists you like, and that’s true with NFTs (which are way trendier than, like, Telegram stickers). Buying an NFT also usually gets you some basic usage rights, like being able to post the image online or set it as your profile picture. Plus, of course, there are bragging rights that you own the art, with a blockchain entry to back it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GVWIC6"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No, I meant I’m a &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;collector&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zYjdCo"&gt;Ah, okay, yes. NFTs can work &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-02/nft-art-boom-is-the-same-concept-as-the-photography-market?sref=M8H6LjUF"&gt;like any other speculative asset&lt;/a&gt;, where you buy it and hope that the value of it goes up one day, so you can sell it for a profit. I feel kind of dirty for talking about that, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KuKmlZ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So every NFT is unique?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="91YTgt"&gt;In the boring, technical sense that every NFT is a unique token on the blockchain. But while it could be like a van Gogh, where there’s only one definitive actual version, it could also be like a trading card, where there’s 50 or hundreds of numbered copies of the same artwork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="09JRP3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who would pay hundreds of thousands of dollars for what basically amounts to a trading card?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TQVHLe"&gt;Well, that’s part of what makes NFTs so messy. Some people treat them like they’re the future of fine art collecting (read: as a playground for the mega-rich), and some people treat them like Pokémon cards (where they’re accessible to normal people but also a playground for the mega-rich). Speaking of Pokémon cards, Logan Paul just sold some NFTs relating to a million-dollar box of the—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b1JJGI"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please stop. I hate where this is going.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/laUmvyGGiD-HsDas7TBDZall_n4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22341219/Screen_Shot_2021_03_02_at_3.39.12_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image by Logan Paul&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You’ve activated my trap card (which sold for $17,000).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Mv0A8X"&gt;Yeah, he sold NFT video clips, which are just clips from a video you can watch on YouTube anytime you want, &lt;a href="https://shopnfts.net/"&gt;for up to $20,000&lt;/a&gt;. He also sold NFTs of a Logan Paul Pokémon card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gh63Tc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who paid $20,000 for a video clip of Logan Paul?!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LWkQs7"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Calvinn_Hobbes/status/746227239755251712?s=20"&gt;A fool and their money are soon parted&lt;/a&gt;, I guess?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t8ZNFb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It would be hilarious if Logan Paul decided to sell 50 more NFTs of the exact same video.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MXPBux"&gt;Linkin Park’s Mike Shinoda (who also sold some NFTs that included a song) &lt;a href="https://www.inputmag.com/culture/linkin-park-mike-shinoda-happy-endings-nft-interview"&gt;actually talked about that&lt;/a&gt;. It’s totally a thing someone could do if they were, in his words, “an opportunist crooked jerk.” I’m not saying that Logan Paul is that, just that you should be careful who you buy from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="611ErY"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can I buy this article as an NFT?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cw2A6d"&gt;No, but technically anything digital could be sold as an NFT. deadmau5 has sold digital animated stickers. William Shatner has sold &lt;a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/william-shatners-nft-collectibles-sell-out-at-warp-speed"&gt;Shatner-themed trading cards&lt;/a&gt; (one of which was apparently an X-ray of his teeth).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1DjDJOZf5-4jdVe9fHSNlrMuXD0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22341226/Screen_Shot_2021_03_02_at_3.43.12_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image by &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://niftygateway.com/itemdetail/secondary/0xa20f75be9427995e596788c29a10c7d734671251/5600020053" target="_blank"&gt;deadmau5 and Mad Dog Jones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This one I like. Maybe not for $700, but...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="e0DpEJ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gross. Actually, could I buy someone’s teeth as an NFT?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2y73FL"&gt;There have been some attempts at connecting NFTs to real-world objects, often as a sort of verification method. Nike has patented a method to &lt;a href="https://thenextweb.com/hardfork/2019/12/10/nike-blockchain-sneakers-cryptokick-patent/"&gt;verify sneakers’ authenticity using an NFT system, which it calls CryptoKicks&lt;/a&gt;. But so far, I haven’t found any teeth, no. I’m scared to look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DRUxvr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Look? Where? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YEbiIN"&gt;There are several marketplaces that have popped up around NFTs, which allow people to buy and sell. These include OpenSea, Rarible, and Grimes’ choice, Nifty Gateway, but there are plenty of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NwUvnp"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’ve heard there were kittens involved. Tell me about the kittens.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zszcnd"&gt;NFTs really became technically possible when the Ethereum blockchain added support for them &lt;a href="https://ethereum.org/en/developers/docs/standards/tokens/erc-721/"&gt;as part of a new standard&lt;/a&gt;. Of course, one of the first uses was &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CryptoKitties"&gt;a game called CryptoKitties&lt;/a&gt; that allowed users to trade and sell virtual kittens. Thank you, internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WkghYZ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I love kittens&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vgMnW6"&gt;Not as much as &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/cryptokitties-bought-a-digital-cat-for-172000/"&gt;the person who paid over $170,000 for one&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Uedrnj7kfMuTOKIghiRp4yUtLOk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22341171/Screen_Shot_2021_03_02_at_3.21.50_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.cryptokitties.co/kitty/896775" target="_blank"&gt;Cryptokitties.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;My face when I’m worth $170K.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="yFaF1c"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arrrrrggggg!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JD0ynI"&gt;Same. But in my opinion, the kittens show that one of the most interesting aspects of NFTs (for those of us not looking to create a digital dragon’s lair of art) is how they can be used in games. There are &lt;a href="https://venturebeat.com/2021/02/26/the-deanbeat-how-non-fungible-tokens-nfts-will-change-games/"&gt;already games&lt;/a&gt; that let you have NFTs as items. One even sells virtual plots of land as NFTs. There could be opportunities for players to buy a unique in-game gun or helmet or whatever as an NFT, which would be a flex that most people could actually appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Kk4a1a"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Could I pull off a museum heist to steal NFTs?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-wuFlpK8EGVxFIUYTKb0hFd3pBM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22341161/robbery.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Wallace and Gromit: The Wrong Trousers&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This image is not an NFT. Yet.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rBINrG"&gt;That depends. Part of the allure of blockchain is that it stores a record of each time a transaction takes place, making it harder to steal and flip than, say, a painting hanging in a museum. That said, &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/business-49177705"&gt;cryptocurrencies have been stolen before&lt;/a&gt;, so it really would depend on how the NFT is being stored and how much work a potential victim would be willing to put in to get their stuff back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GAPTND"&gt;Note: Please don’t steal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fnhPUz"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Should I be worried about digital art being around in 500 years?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VIQPdV"&gt;Probably. Bit rot is a real thing: image quality deteriorates, file formats can’t be opened anymore, websites go down, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227535/nyt-bitcoin-millions-forgot-passwords-digital-wallet"&gt;people forget the password to their wallets&lt;/a&gt;. But physical art in museums is also &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ETAcIbzOTYs"&gt;shockingly fragile&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W6zH8E"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I want to maximize my blockchain use. Can I buy NFTs with cryptocurrencies?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QU56ST"&gt;Yes. Probably. A lot of the marketplaces accept Ethereum. But technically, anyone can sell an NFT, and they could ask for whatever currency they want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6ZmGbU"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will trading my Logan Paul NFTs contribute to global warming and melt Greenland?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MOtuLt"&gt;It’s definitely something to look out for. Since NFTs use the same blockchain technology as cryptocurrencies, they could also end up using a lot of electricity per transaction. There are people working &lt;a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/computing/networks/ethereum-plans-to-cut-its-absurd-energy-consumption-by-99-percent"&gt;on mitigations for this issue&lt;/a&gt;, which is great because I don’t want to set the world on fire for CryptoKitties, much less Logan Paul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="23nZ0d"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can I build an underground art cave / bunker to store my NFTs?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rhQ69E"&gt;Well, like cryptocurrencies, NFTs are stored in digital wallets (though it is worth noting that the wallet does specifically have to be NFT-compatible). You could always put the wallet on a computer in an underground bunker, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UXB6fZ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you tired of typing “NFT”?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cNFTvl"&gt;Yes.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22310188/nft-explainer-what-is-blockchain-crypto-art-faq"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22310188/nft-explainer-what-is-blockchain-crypto-art-faq</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T12:53:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T12:53:38-05:00</updated>
    <title>With ‘Starbase’ and a new Starlink factory, Musk deepens foray into Texas</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Musk, Bezos Space Race Gets a Boost From Anti-Poverty Tax Break" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OKm0N_LwIVeIAPO0OZ-w7gba7fU=/0x0:7596x5064/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68904433/1230332039.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;SpaceX’s Boca Chica Starship plant is growing rapidly.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UbNcOW"&gt;Pieces of SpaceX’s ambitious plans to expand its sizable foothold in Texas were on full display this week in three very different corners of the internet. CEO Elon Musk speculated on Twitter about a proposed city in Texas named Starbase, while new job descriptions on the company’s website hinted at an anticipated “state of the art” factory for mass-producing Starlink satellites. And the company made its latest move in a protracted legal fight for a methane-rich piece of land that will supply fuel for Starship. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ayh16n"&gt;Here’s a breakdown of the latest details. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Ao8BGh"&gt;Starbase, Texas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="OC5xLD"&gt;Musk, who has said he’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/5/22155743/elon-musk-moving-texas-tesla-spacex-california"&gt;moving to Texas&lt;/a&gt; and committed to more projects in the state last year to spite California’s pandemic restrictions, said on Tuesday he’s aiming to create a city called “Starbase” in Texas, teasing a new idea on Twitter as his space company expands its footprint elsewhere in the state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BuJ6AA"&gt;That footprint, first planted in the Lone Star state over a decade ago, is growing rapidly under Musk’s dogged effort to build a “gateway to Mars.” SpaceX is headquartered in Hawthorne, California, but development for its Mars rocket Starship is primarily based in the more business-friendly state of Texas. Local and state incentives and wealth of prime real estate for building reusable, orbital-class rockets have catered to Musk’s speedy development timeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kcpZMC"&gt;“Creating the city of Starbase, Texas,” he tweeted on Tuesday, adding in a response to a Twitter user that Starbase would encompass “an area much larger than Boca Chica” —  the small community in south Texas that’s currently home to SpaceX’s growing test and production facility for Starship. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="W5uTb8"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Creating the city of Starbase, Texas&lt;/p&gt;— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1366848696298561536?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 2, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3ur58e"&gt;SpaceX hasn’t made any official effort to rename Boca Chica, besides approaching county officials with the idea of incorporating a city in recent days, officials in Cameron County said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Oq2oX7"&gt;“If SpaceX and Elon Musk would like to pursue down this path, they must abide by all state incorporation statutes,” Cameron County Judge Eddie Treviño said in a statement. “Cameron County will process any appropriate petitions in conformity with applicable law.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="FGCc9b"&gt;Starlink factory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="vMSAnv"&gt;Musk’s Starbase tweet came as SpaceX posted a new job opening for remote engineers in Austin, where it said the company is “breaking ground on a new, state of the art manufacturing facility” that will aim to “manufacture millions of consumer facing devices that we ship directly to customers (Starlink dishes, Wi-Fi routers, mounting hardware, etc).”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N0gq9d"&gt;“Up to 25% travel to SpaceX Headquarters in Los Angeles, until Austin facility is fully established,” one of the job requirements for the position read. The Starlink manufacturing facility would become Musk’s second Austin-based venture. Last year, Musk announced that Tesla would build Gigafactory Texas, a $1 billion, 4-5 million square foot facility currently under construction. Musk has said it will “basically be an ecological paradise” for the public and the company’s expected workforce of 5,000 employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eaRtCO"&gt;Musk’s shift from California seems to be accelerating SpaceX’s growth in Texas that began several years ago. In 2013, Texas created a Spaceport Development Corporation that has since doled out $13.2 million in economic incentives for SpaceX. And the company’s rocket engine development facility in McGregor, Texas, first leased in 2003, is &lt;a href="https://www.virtualbx.com/feature-story/mcgregor-mclennan-county-waco-support-spacexs-plan-to-upgrade-testing-facility/"&gt;undergoing&lt;/a&gt; a $10 million upgrade, with $2 million in subsidies from local governments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="NvqmuF"&gt;La Pita Wells&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Vm3xuQ"&gt;Two LLCs created by SpaceX, Dogleg Park and Lone Star Mineral Development, have been buying up dozens of properties in Boca Chica surrounding the company’s Starship plant. A few miles from Boca Chica, Lone Star secured an oil and gas lease from a company called Sanchez Oil and Gas Corporation to revive two inactive wells dubbed La Pita Wells. SpaceX plans to use the wells to extract methane, one of the two propellants used for its new Raptor engine that powers Starship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8PPzpz"&gt;But in true SpaceX fashion, the situation has gotten complicated. Lone Star’s bid to operate the wells now faces a legal fight. Dallas Petroleum Group, an oil and gas company operating in South Texas, says it owns the wells. In a lawsuit waged against SpaceX’s LLCs and Sanchez, Dallas Petroleum Group is demanding that the court force Sanchez to put the wells back in DPG’s name. SpaceX’s Lone Star argues that the wells have been inactive for years, making them ripe for a new lease. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="sCWMzU"&gt;&lt;q&gt;SpaceX has “a unique ability to utilize the natural gas with different economic incentives”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sDcAhE"&gt;In a closing statement filed on Monday, Lone Star attorneys said DPG “is not really planning to operate the La Pita Wells,” and its lawsuit to overturn Lone Star’s lease is “part of its plan to extract money from SpaceX.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pK0iM7"&gt;“The hope is that [SpaceX] can produce these properties by reentering these inactive wells and restoring the production for use in connection with their rocket facility operations,” an attorney for Lone Star said during a January hearing. In the Monday filing, Lone Star attorneys noted SpaceX and its LLC “have a unique ability to utilize the natural gas with different economic incentives...”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xsGWwg"&gt;On SpaceX’s careers page, the company is looking for legal counsel who can help “negotiate complex construction and vendor contracts related to space/airport infrastructure development.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JFWxsl"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bGJl1B"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uXmOtk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OxxGRk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q30lEC"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yaySxq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9RlyOB"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xxhkyV"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K1zdsq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22309889/elon-musk-city-texas-starbase-starlink"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22309889/elon-musk-city-texas-starbase-starlink</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T12:49:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T12:49:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>Vaio Z (2021) review: carbon tax</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;A lightweight laptop with a sky-high price&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="R7XYXG"&gt;The Vaio Z is, speaking pragmatically, a proof of concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FBAa27"&gt;There are two things about it that are groundbreaking — at least on paper. The first is that it’s made entirely of carbon fiber. While plenty of high-end laptops, including the Dell XPS 13, have sheets of carbon fiber across their palm rests and other materials on the sides, the Vaio Z includes &lt;em&gt;contoured&lt;/em&gt; carbon fiber, meaning the material is molded around the edges, and the whole thing is carbon fiber. (Vaio says the Z is the first laptop to use contoured carbon fiber, though the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/5/31/3054260/gigabyte-x11-carbon-fiber-laptop-lightest-announcement"&gt;2012 Gigabyte X11&lt;/a&gt; also claims an all-carbon fiber build.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uIfy17"&gt;The second is, at 2.11 pounds, the Vaio Z is the lightest laptop to include an Intel H-Series chip. (That refers to the lightest-possible configuration. I was sent a slightly heavier one at 2.32 pounds.) H-Series processors are high-performance chips most commonly found in gaming laptops and workstations. It’s highly unusual to see one in a thin and light laptop, especially one that’s just over two pounds; machines of this size generally include the lower-powered U-Series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MU0cMb"&gt;This model includes the quad-core Core i7-11375H, the current flagship of Intel’s brand-new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225370/intel-11th-gen-h-series-chips-ultraportable-gaming-laptop-ces-2021"&gt;“Tiger Lake H” series&lt;/a&gt;. When announcing the chip at CES, Intel claimed it would offer the fastest single-thread performance on the market, with boost clock speeds up to 5GHz. That’s an impressive prospect, especially in a 2.3-pound chassis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xV03PE"&gt;But the third thing to understand about the Vaio Z is that it’s not cheap. The base model is — I’m not kidding — $3,579 for a Core i7-11375H, a 14-inch 4K screen, 16GB of RAM, and 512GB of storage. You can go all the way up to a $4,179 system with 32GB of RAM and 2TB of storage. I was sent a model in the middle, with 32GB of RAM and 1TB of storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="79cNfS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10370468"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pbMz6W"&gt;A laptop of that price isn’t a realistic purchase for most people, even if it’s spectacular. So instead, I’m going to use this review to explore two questions that concern the future of the luxury laptop market — questions the Vaio Z is setting out to answer: one, is contoured carbon fiber the future? And two, can a 2.32-pound laptop with an H-Series processor work? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="vS4s5A"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Vaio claims that the Vaio Z is sturdier and feels nicer than other laptops&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KFLbhK"&gt;Unfortunately, as of this writing, the answer to both of those questions is “not yet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EHgHTm"&gt;We’ll start with the build. Vaio’s elevator pitch is that the contoured carbon fiber is both stronger than other common materials (like magnesium alloy and aluminum alloy) that other premium laptops are made of, and ideal for combining rigidity with a light build. Carbon fiber also allows manufacturers to tailor stiffness and flexibility to specific regions of the laptop (using the number of layers and direction of lamination). Vaio claims, consequently, the Vaio Z is sturdier and feels nicer than other laptops close to its weight. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Vaio Z from the left side, half open." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_2wc3Oml1UXhM5w8m5cu6-tbQ2A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22341486/mchin_210225_4449_0017.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Carbon fiber laminate on all four sides.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="R86ymx"&gt;Sturdiness and rigidity are difficult claims to verify with a review unit for obvious reasons. Vaio says the Z has passed MIL-STD 10H torture tests, including drop tests, pressure tests, and body-twist tests among others. There aren’t a ton of 2.3-pound laptops out there, and I don’t doubt that the Vaio Z may be objectively better-built than the rest of that class. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BV1KZm"&gt;But does it feel &lt;em&gt;sturdy&lt;/em&gt;? Not really. There’s a &lt;em&gt;significant&lt;/em&gt; amount of flex in the keyboard and screen. While I usually have to push pretty hard to get keyboards to bend, the area under the Shift key trampolined with a firm thumb press. The display is so bendy that I was careful when torquing it because I was legitimately afraid of snapping it in half. I know most people aren’t actively trying to bend their laptops, but I would be afraid that putting too much weight on this unit could damage the screen and keyboard over time. Vaio told me this product is still in the preorder stage, and chassis quality may improve closer to its shipping date. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Vaio Z keyboard seen from above." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2MLhAKqCb8gZndUzoE6zJ7XyMxQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22341482/mchin_190527_4449_0005.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The key tops are concave.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="AM0FLT"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The lid and bottom have a plasticky texture&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YsgICJ"&gt;The carbon fiber’s texture is certainly unique. I like the feel of the palm rests. But the lid and bottom have a plasticky texture. I wouldn’t guess that the Z was a $3,500 laptop just from holding it, especially right after holding a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review"&gt;MacBook&lt;/a&gt; or an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21546784/dell-xps-13-late-2020-review-design-specs-price-features"&gt;XPS 13&lt;/a&gt;. The other thing to note is that the whole chassis is a fingerprint magnet — the lid, the sides, the palm rests, the keyboard. I could wipe the prints off easily, but they were always back in abundance after a few hours of use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eDnKCo"&gt;The carbon fiber does contribute to one significant benefit, though: the Vaio Z is unbelievably light. It’s so light that picking it up messes with your mind; it’s hard to believe there’s anything inside. This would certainly be the best laptop to buy if you’re looking for the lightest of the light. But if you’re looking for a sturdy, rigid form factor, I’m dubious. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Vaio Z lid seen from above." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cj1M2lF4F-3Q9qlDnJ01saU4cWY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22341480/mchin_190527_4449_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vaio has been using multilayer carbon fiber in laptops since 2003. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="DwMnas"&gt;On to the second question: has Vaio managed to put H-Series power in a U-Series form factor?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vKtBI3"&gt;In a literal sense, yes. The laptop works. And the one thing I do appreciate is the battery life. I averaged six hours and 57 minutes of continuous office multitasking with the display at 200 nits of brightness and Battery Saver on. That’s less juice than I get from the M1 MacBook Pro, but it’s fine as Intel H-Series processors go. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="CHsyMC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10370480"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zOgYq8"&gt;But in terms of raw power, results are mixed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DJo4x6"&gt;I ran several benchmarks to see how this brand-new chip stacks up against some of the more powerful thin systems out there — particularly, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review"&gt;Apple’s M1-based MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22287698/razer-book-13-review-design-specs-price-features"&gt;Razer Book 13&lt;/a&gt;, which is powered by one of Intel’s top Tiger Lake U-Series chips. Note that while both of these models are heavier than the Vaio Z, they’re also less than half its price. So I was hoping it would solidly outperform them under the heavy loads that you’d want an H-Series processor for. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="1p4y54"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10370542"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8M5hqj"&gt;The Z beat the Razer Book in our Adobe Premiere Pro export test by a bit less than a minute — a victory, to be sure, but not a margin to write home about. More disappointingly, it lost to the MacBook Pro by a similar margin on that test. Apple’s laptop also came out ahead in every other test I ran apart from Cinebench’s single-core benchmark. (That’s expected; single-core performance is what Intel claims is so great about this chip.) That’s not a great argument for spending multiple thousands more on the Vaio Z, even with its impressive chassis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JtIeDE"&gt;One issue seems to be that the Vaio Z’s 65W charger is insufficient for the types of loads most users would want an H-Series processor for. During several Adobe Premiere Pro exports and several runs of Cinebench multicore, the laptop’s battery drained even though it was plugged in. (Nothing else was running during these tests.) This could be a problem if you’re hoping to run intense loads for long periods of time, especially if you’re not always starting at a full charge. More importantly, it means power delivery may have been limiting the Vaio Z’s performance on these tasks. (Vaio tells me this is by design; it wanted to keep the charger small and portable.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Vaio Z on a table with three potted plants in the background, open and angled to the left. The screen displays a red flower on a blue background." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IEKTcfBDI60216ossUTofd9B8VU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22341484/mchin_190527_4449_0007.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The fold-under hinge is supposed to provide a more ergonomic typing experience.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HwVjqx"&gt;To Vaio’s credit, the Z has impressive cooling for such a small machine. Neither the chassis nor the CPU ever reached a worrisome temperature. But the dual fans were mega-loud during heavy loads, and sometimes under lighter ones as well. My mom could hear the unit from the next room over while it was running a Premiere export. She told me later that she “thought it was going to take off.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xAo3mN"&gt;For the benefit of folks with deep pockets who are considering buying this laptop, I’ll run through the rest of the specs. The highlight is the backlit keyboard, which provides 1.5mm of travel. It’s excellent — comfortable, smooth, and not at all loud. You also get a webcam with a convenient physical privacy shutter, which supports Windows Hello. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Vaio logo below the bottom left corner of the Vaio Z keyboard seen from above." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lYFy0LsSwzAOpaqMDY_zMwi5CYk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22341481/mchin_190527_4449_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vaio says it “aimed for a comfortable keystroke that feels as if it is absorbed by your fingertips.” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Vaio Z open, seen from the right side." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VCeEWccGJtdc2zhZuP2AiO11YGI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22341485/mchin_210225_4449_0016.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The charger delivers up to 65W and weighs 0.36 pounds.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="asxvkg"&gt;Audio is standard laptop fare: it gets impressively loud without audible distortion, but percussion and bass are almost nonexistent. You can swap to “Movie Mode” and “Gaming Mode” in the Dolby Audio software that comes preloaded on the Vaio Z, and I preferred listening to my music on these profiles. They strengthen the background music beneath the vocals and give everything a stronger surround quality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="aMINTD"&gt;&lt;q&gt;I wish there was a USB-A&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="guENJx"&gt;Connectivity includes two USB Type-C ports (supporting Thunderbolt 4, power delivery, and DisplayPort 1.4), a headphone jack, a security lock slot, and an HDMI. I know the Vaio’s space is limited, but I wish there was a USB-A port in there. You also get a nice 3840 x 2160 non-touch display and a roomy touchpad (though it has physical clickers on the bottom, which I always find to be a huge pain). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="6chViE"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Vaio SX14 review: Lots of ports mean business","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/5/18295153/vaio-sx14-review-lots-of-ports-mean-business"},{"title":"The Vaio SX12 offers too little for too much","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/28/21153098/vaio-sx12-review-display-design-price-specs-features"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="9WwMeh"&gt;I have two strong opinions about the Vaio Z: one, it’s an impressive feat of engineering, and two, it’s still too expensive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w0tsAX"&gt;Vaio’s achievements with contoured carbon fiber are commendable. It’s unusual to see, whether Vaio is the first to do it. And the fact that there’s a 2.32-pound laptop on shelves at all, let alone one housing an H-Series processor, makes me optimistic about the future of the market. It’s been a very cool device to use, one I’m grateful to have experienced first-hand. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mQrsKl"&gt;But the performance bump the Core i7-11375H delivers in this form factor isn’t enough of an improvement to justify a multithousand-dollar premium over all kinds of more affordable models on the market today, whether they contain M1 chips, AMD chips, or chips from Intel itself. Neither is the contoured carbon fiber — which, while cool, won’t bring a concrete benefit to most customers. At half its price, the Vaio Z would be in the conversation; at $3,579, I’m happy to commend it from afar. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="Ki2HU2"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22310002/vaio-z-2021-laptop-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22310002/vaio-z-2021-laptop-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T12:01:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T12:01:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix has created a TikTok clone that lets people scroll through funny clips</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-L6M6C0wZPPdQXe6jtJ_Y3pTa5A=/0x0:6000x4000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68904062/FAST_LAUGHS_PHONE_COMP_in_Jerry_v1__0_00_00_13_.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="g8d0U3"&gt;Netflix is launching a new mobile feature that gives subscribers the opportunity to get their fill of laughs in for the night without having to watch a whole TV show or movie. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ej1yBK"&gt;&lt;a href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/fast-laughs-is-here"&gt;Fast Laughs&lt;/a&gt;, currently only available for iOS device owners in select countries, looks and feels like TikTok or Instagram Reels. Different short clips — taken from shows like &lt;em&gt;Big Mouth &lt;/em&gt;or stand-up specials from comedians like Jerry Seinfeld and Ali Wong — play directly within the Netflix app. If one of the shows, films, or specials sparks interest, people can add said title to their saved list to watch later. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YnibdL"&gt;“We’re always looking for new ways to entertain and make discovery easier for members,” &lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Patrick Flemming, director of product innovation at Netflix, said, adding that Fast Laughs is a “new full-screen feed of funny clips from a wide variety of Netflix titles, ranging from films and series to our deep bench of stand-up specials.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="R1sbB7"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XqS1TPyQVbo?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="15EuP4"&gt;Adding Fast Laughs makes sense for Netflix, considering the growth and prominence of TikTok in the market right now. Netflix’s last few earnings reports have specifically &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22238877/netflix-200-million-subscribers-q4-earnings-bridgerton-emily-paris-cobra-kai-queens-gambit"&gt;referenced TikTok as a major competitor&lt;/a&gt;. It’s not that Netflix and TikTok make the same type of content, but people are spending more time on TikTok — and therefore less time on Netflix. Giving iPhone users something else to scroll through on their phones, and turning that into more time spent on the app by convincing people to make their way through &lt;em&gt;Big Mouth &lt;/em&gt;again, is a smart business move. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eKhSYg"&gt;It also helps Netflix highlight just how much content is on the platform. Netflix has invested heavily in stand-up comedy, &lt;a href="https://www.vulture.com/2021/01/kevin-hart-netflix-deal.html"&gt;struck multipicture deals&lt;/a&gt; with comedians like Adam Sandler and Kevin Hart, and is building up its slate of animation. Since there’s so much content, a lot of it can get lost on the platform. This is one way to give subscribers a tiny glimpse of things they may have missed. That’s the key difference between TikTok and Netflix’s Fast Laughs: Netflix isn’t trying to launch a new platform to provide entertainment, but instead use a new feature to keep people on its current platform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PuTRmE"&gt;To access Fast Laughs, customers can use the bottom navigation menu to click on the Fast Laughs tab. The company will start testing Fast Laughs on Android devices soon. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311418/netflix-tiktok-clips-funny-movies-tv-shows-streaming-big-mouth-seinfeld"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311418/netflix-tiktok-clips-funny-movies-tv-shows-streaming-big-mouth-seinfeld</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Project Gucciberg offers classic audiobooks read by an AI deepfake of Gucci Mane</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xI4bq-LxCYRp7NxqKYSf9FIVoUU=/58x0:1456x932/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68903995/Screen_Shot_2021_03_03_at_3.23.47_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Project Gucciberg: AI’ced up.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="AVFiCB"&gt;Ever wanted to have Leo Tolstoy’s &lt;em&gt;Anna Karenina&lt;/em&gt; or Franz Kafka’s &lt;em&gt;Metamorphosis&lt;/em&gt; read to you by trap god Gucci Mane, creator of such hits as “Lemonade” and “Wasted”? Well, a) that’s an awfully specific desire, and b) it’s your lucky day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3YwiaK"&gt;&lt;a href="https://projectgucciberg.mschfmag.com/"&gt;Project Gucciberg&lt;/a&gt; is the latest drop from viral factory MSCHF, and it does exactly that. Using machine learning, MSCHF created an audio deepfake of Gucci Mane reading a selection of classic texts from &lt;em&gt;Little Women&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;Beowulf&lt;/em&gt;. They’re all free to listen to and come with book covers that blend in perfectly with the artwork of Gucci Mane’s prolific discography. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LL1JyZ"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; of Project Gucciberg is luridly straightforward, but the &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; is harder to answer. If you’re not familiar with MSCHF, I recommend our profile of the outfit &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21320127/mschf-products-jesus-shoes-puff-chicken-office-business"&gt;from last year&lt;/a&gt;. Essentially, they’re a group of VC-funded creators who make weird things designed to go viral online, like squeaky chicken bongs and Air Max 97 sneakers filled with water from the River Jordan, some of which are sold for a nominal fee. Then they ??? and profit (presumably by selling their services to companies who want things &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; made to go viral online). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="2juBwl"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Gucci’s pronunciation follows a very particular cadence”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="72eMqh"&gt;Speaking to &lt;em&gt;The Verge, &lt;/em&gt;MSCHF’s Dan Greenberg didn’t go into the motivation behind Project Gucciberg but was more than happy to talk about the mechanics. Audio deepfakes are now pretty common (listen to this clone of Joe Rogan for a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/17/18629024/joe-rogan-ai-fake-voice-clone-deepfake-dessa"&gt;good example&lt;/a&gt;), to the point where they’ve been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/27/21339898/deepfake-audio-voice-clone-scam-attempt-nisos"&gt;used to commit fraud&lt;/a&gt;. To make one, you just need a lot of sample data of your target speaking and the right neural networks to learn and copy their mannerisms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G1JWlM"&gt;Greenberg says MSCHF collected around six hours of audio of Gucci Mane talking from podcasts, interviews, and the like. They then created transcriptions of the clips to help with the text-to-speech (TTS) process. This required creating a “Gucci pronunciation key/dictionary to better capture the idiosyncrasies of Gucci Mane’s particular argot.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YFhuR8hrgOrFW2BVwIgBzhTS7A0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22342344/Screen_Shot_2021_03_03_at_3.24.09_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The redesigned book covers of Project Gucciberg are a delight to behold. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Ek5Ps6"&gt;“Gucci’s pronunciation follows a very particular cadence — he uses a much greater variety of vowel sounds, for instance, than your average TTS reader would,” says Greenberg. “The dictionary breaks words up into phonemes (discrete vocal gestures) that our model then uses as building blocks ... So for a simple example, we need our model to know what syllables to elide, or flow into each other across words: it needs to know to say “talm ‘bout” not ‘talking about,’ and the Gucci dictionary { T AH1 L M B AW1 T } gets us there where the written words ‘talking about’ do not.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EAS8Lx"&gt;The results are impressive: the deepfake certainly sounds like the man himself, though the results are not always totally coherent or of the greatest quality. “Our fake Gucci Mane often sounds like he’s speaking through a bad mic, or over a low-quality internet stream, and part of this is because in the training data he often is doing exactly that,” says Greenberg. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xLrRsC"&gt;Exactly why Gucci was chosen for this project came down to two factors, says Greenberg: one, the rapper has a distinctive voice, and two, the Project Gucciberg pun was &lt;a href="https://www.gutenberg.org/"&gt;too delicious&lt;/a&gt; to ignore. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="ccysC6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The law has yet to offer an opinion on the legality of creating audio deepfakes of Gucci Mane&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ueeILN"&gt;Greenberg adds that MSCHF didn’t approach Gucci to ask for permission to use his voice. As a disclaimer on the site slyly points out, the whole project raises interesting questions about copyright in the age of AI fakes. ”We didn’t write the books, and we deepfaked the voice,” it says. “Is this copyright infringement? Is it identity theft? All of the training data (recordings) used to make Project Gucciberg were publicly available on the web. Gucciberg lives in that lovely grey area where everything’s new and anything goes.” It certainly is! &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;has attempted to reach out to Gucci Mane via his record label for a response, and we’ll update this story if we hear back. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w8Dq6o"&gt;Is Project Gucciberg anything more than a quick click and a lol? Well, not really. But that’s MSCHF’s business, and they’re very good at it. While listening to more than a few minutes of the resulting audio is a little disorientating, Greenberg suggests there may be unique benefits to the coming world of on-demand deepfake celebrity audiobooks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q9k14b"&gt;“Every once in a while ... the extreme casualness of Gucci Mane’s narration really does put the text in a new light,” he says, speaking about the benefits of listening to the deepfake version of Kafka’s &lt;em&gt;Metamorphosis&lt;/em&gt;. “Gregor Samsa really comes across as just another guy who doesn’t want to get out of bed, you know?”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311184/project-gucciberg-ai-audio-deepfake-classic-audiobooks-mschf"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311184/project-gucciberg-ai-audio-deepfake-classic-audiobooks-mschf</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T11:18:42-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T11:18:42-05:00</updated>
    <title>Steam sensation Valheim sold 5 million copies in one month</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3PWRW0eOMTugyzQMBG1-BaKQhaA=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68903652/screenshot_ygg2.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Iron Gate Studio&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KF2SBF"&gt;Breakout early access sensation &lt;em&gt;Valheim&lt;/em&gt;, the Nordic-themed survival title &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22286507/valheim-steam-pc-game-2-million-sales"&gt;taking the gaming world by storm&lt;/a&gt;, has sold more than 5 million copies since it launched on Steam on February 2nd, developer Iron Gate Studio announced on Wednesday. At a retail price of $19.99, that’s roughly $100 million in revenue before accounting for Valve’s cut and other expenses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KQRjfN"&gt;The Swedish studio developed the game &lt;a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/valheim-how-a-5-person-team-created-the-most-popular-game-on-steam"&gt;with a team of just five people&lt;/a&gt; and released it on Steam’s Early Access platform in February, where it’s battled its way to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295589/valheim-peak-player-record-steam-terraria-fallout-among-us"&gt;top five most played games on the entire platform&lt;/a&gt; with more than 500,000 concurrent players at one point last month. (It’s &lt;a href="https://steamcharts.com/"&gt;currently sitting at No. 4&lt;/a&gt; on the Steam charts, behind only &lt;em&gt;Counter-Strike: Global Offensive&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Dota 2&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;PlayerUnknown’s Battlegrounds&lt;/em&gt;.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ouB7i5"&gt;The closest analog to &lt;em&gt;Valheim&lt;/em&gt;’s success is &lt;em&gt;PUBG&lt;/em&gt;, which holds the record of highest concurrent player count on Steam at more than 3.2 million. Like &lt;em&gt;PUBG&lt;/em&gt;, which arguably pushed the battle royale genre into the mainstream with its then-unprecedented 100-player take on competitive survival shooters, &lt;em&gt;Valheim &lt;/em&gt;is combining the crafting and survival sim mechanics from popular games like &lt;em&gt;Minecraft &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Rust &lt;/em&gt;and giving them new life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nvotQP"&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Valheim&lt;/em&gt; continues to attract critical and player acclaim, with over 115,000 positive user reviews on Steam,” Iron Gate and its publisher, Coffee Stain Publishing, write in a press release. “It has also been climbing the ranks of the 250 top reviewed games of all time on the platform, now sitting at number 39. On Twitch, &lt;em&gt;Valheim&lt;/em&gt; has maintained a steady stream of viewers, and fans have now spent more than 35M hours watching &lt;em&gt;Valheim&lt;/em&gt; gameplay, and over 16,266 years playing.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311338/valheim-five-million-copies-sold-valve-steam-early-access-success"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311338/valheim-five-million-copies-sold-valve-steam-early-access-success</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T11:17:31-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T11:17:31-05:00</updated>
    <title>AMD announces $479 Radeon RX 6700 XT, says it will have ‘significantly more GPUs available’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VaLOsppB0KkY_9XRPWzASo5GiW0=/100x0:1500x933/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68903632/amd_6700_xt_render.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="P2SjUv"&gt;AMD has heard you loud and clear: you can’t buy its excellent &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21572796/amd-radeon-rx-6800-review-4k-gaming-test-benchmarks"&gt;RX 6800&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21571414/amd-radeon-rx-6800-xt-review"&gt;6800 XT&lt;/a&gt; graphics cards at anything close to their retail prices. Today, the company’s announcing a new GPU that might (but probably won’t?) change that: the Radeon RX 6700 XT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eZMH7X"&gt;“With the AMD Radeon RX 6700 XT launch, we are on track to have significantly more GPUs available for sale at launch,” AMD tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge. &lt;/em&gt;Even better: AMD claims it’ll begin refreshing stock of RX 6000 GPUs and Ryzen 5000 CPUs every week &lt;a href="https://www.amd.com/en/direct-buy/"&gt;on its own website&lt;/a&gt;, where it’ll sell them at their retail prices. We’ve been waiting for that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227040/nvidia-amd-gpu-shortage-rtx-3080-3070-3060-ti-3090-rx-6800-xt"&gt;for nearly two months&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LwvwNK"&gt;The new RX 6700 XT will arrive on March 18th for a suggested retail price of $479. In a normal, sane year, that would slot it between Nvidia’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/27/21534142/nvidia-geforce-rtx-3070-review"&gt;$500 RTX 3070&lt;/a&gt;, which we called “the 1440p sweet spot,” and Nvidia’s bang-for-the-buck &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21726429/nvidia-geforce-rtx-3060-ti-review"&gt;$400 RTX 3060 Ti&lt;/a&gt;, where you might have to dial down the settings here and there. It’s also a full $100 less than AMD’s $579 RX 6800, which we found had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21572796/amd-radeon-rx-6800-review-4k-gaming-test-benchmarks"&gt;enough oomph for entry-level 4K gaming&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s48Wsz"&gt;This isn’t a sane period for GPU buyers, though. In December, the actual street prices of the $400 3060 Ti, the $500 3070, and the $579 RX 6800 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/6/22155611/price-ps5-xbox-series-x-nvidia-rtx-3080-3070-3090-3060-amd-rx-6800-xt-scalpers-ebay"&gt;were $675, $819, and $841, respectively&lt;/a&gt; — and that was &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; Trump’s tariffs pushed Nvidia and AMD’s board partners &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/13/22228470/nvidia-evga-zotac-raise-prices-rtx-3080-3070-3060-3090"&gt;to raise their retail prices&lt;/a&gt;. “We know it’s crazy out there, we’re doing everything we can,” says AMD’s Nish Neelalojanan, a director of product management. That not only includes more stock at AMD.com but also additional supply for board partners and manufacturers that’ll sell gaming PCs later on. AMD wouldn’t say how much of that stock is being allocated toward GPUs that’ll be sold at AMD.com, though. It says it doesn’t set its partners’ retail prices either.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZSUHzUPijsuZ0E1FzJqhmQvIg9k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22342449/amd_6700_xt_render_2.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6vqHgL"&gt;Assuming for a moment that AMD pulls it off, managing substantially greater availability &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301391/nvidia-rtx-3060-launch-supply-demand-newegg-shuffle"&gt;than Nvidia’s recent debut&lt;/a&gt;, the RX 6700 XT sounds like it could be a compelling pick. With 230 watts of power, 12GB of video memory, and 40 compute units (compared to 60 for the RX 6800 and 80 for the RX 6800 XT), AMD’s promising you’ll be able to play all of the latest games at maximum settings at 1440p resolution. With a fast enough CPU, AMD suggests you should be able to hit 212 fps in &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt;, 272 fps in &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;, and 360 fps in &lt;em&gt;Rainbow Six Siege&lt;/em&gt;, enough for esports gamers to justify some of the fastest monitors on the market. AMD says it should be fast enough for ray tracing at 1440p as well.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zF1wjGMgqlStmwqg15VuB7kxo30=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22342451/amd_1440p_bench_6700_xt.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CF7Qix"&gt;The company’s early benchmarks (see above) show it pulling ahead of Nvidia’s 3070 and 3060 Ti, though not in all games. It’s worth noting these numbers were generated using the frame rate boost of AMD’s Smart Access Memory (generically known as Resizable BAR), something that’s only just &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/26/22302679/nvidia-rtx-3060-resizable-bar-support-30-series-gpus"&gt;starting to roll out to Nvidia’s graphics cards&lt;/a&gt; and generally requires newer CPUs to work. That said, AMD also just announced that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22310745/amd-ryzen-3000-smart-access-memory-resizable-bar"&gt;it will begin rolling out Resizable BAR to its Ryzen 3000-series processors&lt;/a&gt;, not just the newer Ryzen 5000 ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pRZHcD"&gt;The new card will require two power connectors, an 8-pin and a 6-pin, and the GPU should be clocked somewhat faster than in earlier RX 6000-series cards at up to 2424MHz. It’s got a 192-bit memory bus, down from 256-bit for the company’s other 6000-series cards.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q1N_nd4yAVbO5kZoI5uU2rShRgM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22342489/3.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="OCRVqm"&gt;Clearly, we’ll have to test the RX 6700 XT’s performance ourselves, but nothing matters more than availability — and where that availability will leave the card’s actual price by the time you can buy one. AMD claims cards will be available on March 18th from all of the usual board partners, 40 different system builders, and AMD.com, with prebuilt systems including the HP Omen 25L and 30L desktops coming later this spring and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2ZGZ6A"&gt;While AMD’s own version is a dual-fan card with the same basic reference design as the RX 6800 and 6800 XT, it appears many of AMD’s partners are opting for three-fan designs. Those generally carry a premium price as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6UJI8C"&gt;And in case you’re wondering, AMD has no plans to nerf the crypto mining performance of the RX 6700 XT the way Nvidia did for Ethereum &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289154/nvidia-rtx-3060-ethereum-mining-drivers-limit-cryptocurrency"&gt;with the RTX 3060&lt;/a&gt;. “We have no plans to limit the product in that way,” AMD told journalists this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ovuT9j"&gt;You can watch the company’s 20-minute presentation, including a tease of &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil Village&lt;/em&gt; with ray tracing, in the video below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MIoq50"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jjBqaGLRycc?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="tcwZbI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Nvidia GeForce RTX 3060 review: $329 with an asterisk sign","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22300659/nvidia-geforce-rtx-3060-review"},{"title":"Nvidia says it won’t nerf the Ethereum mining performance of existing GPUs","url":"https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/2/18/22290362/nvidia-will-not-reduce-3060-ti-3070-3080-3090-eth-mining"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="njqGXJ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, 11:36AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;that the HP Omen and other prebuilts will arrive later this spring.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22310653/amd-radeon-rx-6700-xt-price-release-date-availability-gpu-graphics"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22310653/amd-radeon-rx-6700-xt-price-release-date-availability-gpu-graphics</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T11:05:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T11:05:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>AMD is bringing Smart Access Memory’s frame rate boosts to Ryzen 3000 processors</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4jv78usm_TtIkzcLbO31RbKLA-4=/401x0:4720x2879/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68903568/AMD_Ryzen_5000_Series_Lidded_5.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HKjujS"&gt;The bar has just been lowered (in a good way!) for Resizable BAR, the PCI-Express graphics feature that lets CPUs directly access a GPU’s onboard memory to improve gaming frame rates. That’s because AMD just announced it’s bringing the tech to its last-gen Ryzen 3000 series processors, not just the new Ryzen 5000 chips that initially launched with the feature. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mRQm3d"&gt;AMD originally debuted the feature as “AMD Smart Access Memory,” and you specifically needed an AMD Ryzen 5000 CPU and an AMD Radeon RX 6000 graphics card to make it work. That wasn’t a particularly easy sell, considering both have been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227040/nvidia-amd-gpu-shortage-rtx-3080-3070-3060-ti-3090-rx-6800-xt"&gt;incredibly hard to find&lt;/a&gt; at retail since they first debuted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CQvjHX"&gt;But it &lt;em&gt;was &lt;/em&gt;an easy sell for Nvidia and Intel, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226560/nvidia-resizable-bar-support-intel-amd-smart-access-memory-feature"&gt;which announced in January that they’d be adopting Resizable BAR&lt;/a&gt; with initial support for Nvidia’s RTX 3000-series laptop GPUs, and later rolling out to RTX 3000-series desktops when paired with both AMD and a selection of both 11th Gen and 10th Gen Intel CPUs. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/26/22302679/nvidia-rtx-3060-resizable-bar-support-30-series-gpus"&gt;Nvidia just launched support for the new RTX 3060 desktop graphics card last week&lt;/a&gt;, with its other new GPUs coming in late March (though you’ll need a motherboard update, too).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QB39jF2p2lvq2Gb2tk_QO5SjV_U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22342442/amd_smart_access_memory_ryzen_3000.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pFOxuZ"&gt;With Ryzen 3000, AMD’s actually promising up to 16 percent more performance, compared to the 10 percent both AMD and Nvidia previously offered, though it will really depend on the game. &lt;a href="https://www.techspot.com/article/2178-amd-smart-access-memory/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;TechSpot&lt;/em&gt; discovered&lt;/a&gt; that some games could see a 20 percent boost on the AMD CPU+AMD GPU side of things, while other games actually had reduced performance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vcCbJ2"&gt;Because of the possible downsides, Nvidia decided to only turn it on for certain games where there’s a benefit, with the first wave including &lt;em&gt;Assassin’s Creed Valhalla, Battlefield V, Borderlands 3, Forza Horizon 4, Gears 5, Metro Exodus, Red Dead Redemption 2, &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Watch Dogs: Legion.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GRb723"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l5GeZU"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22310745/amd-ryzen-3000-smart-access-memory-resizable-bar"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22310745/amd-ryzen-3000-smart-access-memory-resizable-bar</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-03T10:43:17-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T10:43:17-05:00</updated>
    <title>FedEx will spend $2 billion to become carbon neutral by 2040</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XgC1tkM31zCbTdLjekw9cRnLHGk=/0x0:1350x900/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68903401/Sustainability_Image_small.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1WpkXr"&gt;FedEx will spend $2 billion in “initial investments” to become carbon neutral by 2040, the company &lt;a href="https://newsroom.fedex.com/newsroom/sustainability2021/"&gt;announced today&lt;/a&gt;. The move comes as many of the world’s biggest automakers are also pledging to phase out carbon-emitting vehicles within the next several decades. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rTSeMI"&gt;FedEx claims it is the largest cargo airline in the world, with more than 650 aircraft in operation. As such, it has a particularly large carbon footprint, making its pledge to go completely carbon neutral a uniquely massive challenge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="MoFN9x"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The money will be spent in three key areas&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qnh5I2"&gt;The money will be spent in three key areas: vehicle electrification, sustainable energy, and carbon sequestration. FedEx will also donate $100 million to Yale University’s efforts to devise new ways to achieve carbon sequestration, which is the process of capturing and storing CO2 from the atmosphere. The company said that, initially, it will fund research to help “offset greenhouse gas emissions equivalent to current airline emissions.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tiq3n5"&gt;But most of the funds will be spent on buying new electric delivery vehicles to replace FedEx’s largely gas-powered fleet. The phase-out will take place over the next several years, with the goal set for 50 percent of FedEx Express pickup and delivery vehicle purchases to be electric by 2025. By 2030, 100 percent of those vehicle purchases will be electric. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zfFrVI"&gt;But the real challenge will be to eliminate the carbon output of FedEx’s air operation. While UPS is known for its ground delivery service, FedEx is mostly recognized for its global air express freight. And while there has been a lot of progress in rolling out new electric ground delivery vehicles, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/14/17686706/electric-airplane-flying-car-battery-weight-green-energy-travel"&gt;process for eliminating emissions from the aviation industry&lt;/a&gt; has been much slower. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="T6Ujc5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Electrifying ground vehicles is simple compared to building a fleet of non-polluting airplanes&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0rVNTs"&gt;That’s probably why FedEx’s goal of becoming completely carbon neutral is so far off in the future. Global automakers like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/2/22308851/volvo-electric-cars-only-2030-online-sales"&gt;Volvo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287284/ford-electric-vehicles-ev-europe-2030"&gt;Ford&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/28/22254116/general-motors-carbon-neutral-vow-2040-tailpipe-emissions-ev"&gt;General Motors&lt;/a&gt;, and others have set similar deadlines within the next decade. But electrifying ground vehicles is simple compared to building a fleet of non-polluting airplanes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="beZioD"&gt;FedEx currently operates 118 all-electric trucks and 364 commercial hybrid trucks, the company says. That is a tiny fraction of the overall 43,000 motor vehicles the company has in operation currently. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uAKeNa"&gt;The company says it will also seek to eliminate the carbon produced by its packaging and shipping facilities. This can be achieved through “carbon–neutral shipping offerings and sustainable packaging solutions,” as well as investments in renewable energy.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BaEvHk"&gt;Notably, FedEx did not say it would purchase carbon offsets as a way to achieve full neutrality, though its investment in Yale University’s research project could be seen as such. Purchasing offsets has become a standard way for car companies and other businesses to write off their carbon emissions by investing in renewable energy or conservation projects aimed at bolstering forests’ ability to naturally store carbon. But there’s &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/features/2020-nature-conservancy-carbon-offsets-trees/"&gt;growing evidence&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href="https://features.propublica.org/brazil-carbon-offsets/inconvenient-truth-carbon-credits-dont-work-deforestation-redd-acre-cambodia/"&gt;offsets haven’t succeeded&lt;/a&gt; in slowing global warming and have instead given companies license to keep polluting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aaLEhl"&gt;FedEx, which is based in Memphis, Tennessee, is the latest giant corporation to make a specific pledge to go carbon neutral. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22169798/united-airlines-emissions-carbon-capture-climate-change-goal"&gt;United&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/14/21137782/delta-carbon-neutral-greenhouse-gas-emissions-climate-change-airlines"&gt;Delta&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-amazon-com-climatechange/uber-jetblue-join-amazon-backed-climate-pledge-idUSKBN28C24H"&gt;JetBlue&lt;/a&gt; said they would eliminate all of their emissions over the next several decades. And &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/8/21427196/uber-promise-100-percent-electric-vehicle-ev-2030"&gt;Uber&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/17/21294040/lyft-electric-vehicle-ev-100-percent-2030"&gt;Lyft&lt;/a&gt; have pledged to go carbon neutral within a similar timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z4nuUZ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311210/fedex-carbon-neutral-2040-2-billion-electric-vehicles-planes"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311210/fedex-carbon-neutral-2040-2-billion-electric-vehicles-planes</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
