<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2020-12-15T12:01:56-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-15T12:01:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-15T12:01:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>EA Play won’t come to Xbox Game Pass for PC until 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eNo788jRd4zAGdlsbzgCnMluiz0=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68516669/XGP_EAPlay_HERO.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EOh1g2"&gt;PC gamers subscribed to Xbox Game Pass for PC or the pricier Xbox Game Pass Ultimate tier will need to wait just a little while longer until they have access to EA Play on Windows machines. Today, Microsoft announced that EA Play would arrive on PC as part of Xbox Game Pass sometime in 2021. Originally, the partnership was supposed to &lt;a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2020/12/15/update-on-ea-play-xbox-game-pass-for-pc-2021/"&gt;go into effect today&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GpXa0q"&gt;“We established this partnership with Electronic Arts because they are as passionate as we are about helping people and communities discover great games, and we knew we could provide a great experience for members by working together. In order to deliver on that, we need more time to provide the Xbox Game Pass experience,” reads &lt;a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2020/12/15/update-on-ea-play-xbox-game-pass-for-pc-2021/"&gt;a Microsoft blog post published Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DhGcrZ"&gt;EA Play is an online video game subscription service that provides access to a library of first-party EA games — including &lt;em&gt;Battlefield V&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Sims 4 — &lt;/em&gt;plus 10-hour trials for new releases like &lt;em&gt;Madden NFL 21 &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;FIFA 21&lt;/em&gt;. EA Play was previously known as EA Access &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/14/21368737/ea-access-origin-subscription-rebrand-exclusives-price-drop"&gt;before the company rebranded in August&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZcjL9h"&gt;EA Play is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/29/21493265/ea-play-xbox-game-pass-release-date-subscription"&gt;already part of Xbox Game Pass for consoles as of November&lt;/a&gt;, allowing Xbox One owners plus those who’ve been able to get their hands on an Xbox Series X / S console to download and play games from EA Play on Xbox hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22176296/ea-play-xbox-game-pass-release-delayed-subscription"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22176296/ea-play-xbox-game-pass-release-delayed-subscription</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-15T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-15T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google Meet adds live captions on the web for French, German, Portuguese and Spanish</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ksQ7UT1EQC3LJGUx3Ghl2fKFCHQ=/0x171:1024x854/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68516592/Google_Meet.max_2800x2800.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="cBnkZL"&gt;Google Meet is adding live captions on the web in four languages to make meetings more inclusive, the &lt;a href="https://workspaceupdates.googleblog.com/2020/12/additional-language-support-for-live-captions.html"&gt;company announced today&lt;/a&gt;. Live captions in Spanish, French, German, and Portuguese will be available across all versions of Meet starting today. Meet rolled out real-time captions in English last year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8WJhYP"&gt;“We know from our work with teachers and parents over the years how essential caption tools can be for students with learning disabilities, as well as English-language learners in both K-12 and higher education,” Google Workspace project manager Philip Nelson wrote in a blog post announcing the update. “By expanding live captions to more languages, we can help more students feel empowered to participate, and help more teachers share a space that is both accessible and inclusive.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0ZZ1A3"&gt;Google has continued to add updates to Meet as the platform has seen booming growth during the coronavirus pandemic, such as providing attendance reports with viewership data for live streamed events and allowing users to “raise” their hands in larger meetings. The company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/29/21494189/google-meet-limit-calls-minutes-march-2021"&gt;earlier announced&lt;/a&gt; it was extending unlimited Meet calls in its free version through March 31st for Gmail accounts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fNNkji"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/29/21531711/google-alphabet-ad-revenue-youtube-waymo-cloud-search"&gt;Google said in October&lt;/a&gt; that Meet had 235 million daily meetings and more than 7.5 billion daily video calls in the third quarter of 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22175268/google-meet-live-captions-french-german-portuguese-spanish"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22175268/google-meet-live-captions-french-german-portuguese-spanish</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-15T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-15T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Nomad’s new leather MacBook Pro sleeves are luxurious but pricey</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/B23XwTLixrhWFayQZQMAtkaQSDg=/114x0:1926x1208/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68516593/Untitled_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="khMIkp"&gt;Accessory company Nomad is expanding its case lineup once again with its first &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fnomadgoods.com%2Fproducts%2Flaptop-sleeve-horween-leather-rustic-brown-macbookpro-16-inch&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2020%2F12%2F15%2F22176171%2Fnomad-new-leather-macbook-pro-sleeves-luxury-expensive-price-release-date-hands-on#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MacBook Pro sleeves&lt;/a&gt;, available today. The cases might be the nicest that Nomad has made so far, but with a starting price of $229.95 (for the 13-inch model) and $249.95 (for 16-inch MacBook Pros), they’re also the most expensive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s8gWsh"&gt;The MacBook Pro cases are made out of the same brown Horween leather that Nomad uses for most of its products. But instead of the plastic shell the company uses on its iPhone cases (which I’m less of a fan of), the new cases are just solid expanses of leather on the outside, backed by EVA foam to keep your computer safe, with a final layer of microfiber cloth for the interior. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pCv-YUSEApsGPFEllca5PMHQq3o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22171815/_DSC7173.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The USB-C charging cutout on the side of the Nomad MacBook Sleeve.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Kj282O"&gt;I’ve been able to use one of the cases for the past few days, and I’ve been pretty impressed by the quality. The leather looks and feels great, and Nomad has been pretty thoughtful about some of the details, like the hidden magnetic snaps that keep the case shut or the small cutout on the side that allows for accessing the USB-C ports for charging or docking your laptop while it’s still in the case. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6EtRlf"&gt;Sliding a MacBook in or out of the case is easy, and the case itself feels solid enough, although there are likely more durable options, if protection is the number one priority — especially given the cost. Additionally, as an owner of a MacBook Pro with just two USB-C ports, I did have to think about which direction I was placing my laptop inside the case to line up the ports with the charging cutout. And while that cutout is useful, I did have some concerns that it would provide a good avenue for dust or debris to make its way inside the case over time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NWVl91"&gt;Given the current state of the world, I haven’t been able to extensively test how the leather holds up in the stress of a daily commute, but the company does promise that the exterior should develop a nice patina over time, similar to its other cases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MgfHcI"&gt;The leather laptop cases are designed specifically to fit Apple’s 13-inch and 16-inch MacBook Pros (from the 2016-era design), although you’ll likely be able to fit other similarly sized laptops, too. Just be aware that it might be a bit tighter or looser than you prefer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1KlSBF"&gt;The cases are available now on Nomad’s website. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WdWR8P"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22176171/nomad-new-leather-macbook-pro-sleeves-luxury-expensive-price-release-date-hands-on"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22176171/nomad-new-leather-macbook-pro-sleeves-luxury-expensive-price-release-date-hands-on</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-15T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-15T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google Photos will soon be able to add a 3D effect to 2D photos</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Blxfa-J7pTGf92NpYiKwv5lFVoo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68516599/acastro_180427_1777_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration: Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0hwFDQ"&gt;Google Photos will soon be able to take your 2D images and make them appear as if they’re 3D, the company announced in a blog post on Tuesday. Google is calling these types of images “Cinematic photos,” and they’re a new type of image the app can show as part of its Memories feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TpYDO0"&gt;Here’s a GIF from Google comparing a 2D image to a Cinematic photo. I think the feature looks pretty impressive:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UqlpIT2NQMLsH7n-Z-9iyZTrYas=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22171944/ezgif_2_b86c3878385a.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="WIOWAI"&gt;To make Cinematic photos, “we use machine learning to predict an image’s depth and produce a 3D representation of the scene—even if the original image doesn’t include depth information from the camera,” Jamie Aspinall, a Google Photos product manager, writes in Tuesday’s blog. “Then we animate a virtual camera for a smooth panning effect—just like out of the movies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nGf0qt"&gt;Google says Google Photos will automatically make Cinematic photos, and they’ll appear in the recent highlights section above your photo grid. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fUNcNm"&gt;The company is also adding new themes for Memories. Now, you’ll be able to see Memories about important people in your life, and soon, Google Photos will show you Memories about your favorite things (Google gave the example of sunsets) and activities (such as baking or hiking). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iCmtUO"&gt;These new features in Memories will be rolling out to users over the next month, according to Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Iq3ZTo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Google Photos will end its free unlimited storage on June 1st, 2021","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/11/21560810/google-photos-unlimited-cap-free-uploads-15gb-ending"},{"title":"Google Photos now lets you set a changing wallpaper that pulls images from your memories","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/3/22150151/google-photos-wallpaper-update-live-background-memories"},{"title":"Improved Google Photos editor is rolling out now on Android","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/30/21495793/google-photos-editing-tools-app-update-machine-learning-suggestions-android"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22176313/google-photos-2d-3d-photos-cinematic-memories-activities-things"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22176313/google-photos-2d-3d-photos-cinematic-memories-activities-things</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-15T11:56:29-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-15T11:56:29-05:00</updated>
    <title>It’s not as easy to get a Cyberpunk 2077 refund as CD Projekt Red suggested</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Cyberpunk 2077" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3oLDizJXjp-I8vE0mQOBKYSDlNc=/63x0:738x450/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68516541/cyberpunk_2077_800.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: CD Projekt Red&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="h21efq"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; developer CD Projekt Red has confirmed it has no special refund agreement with Microsoft or Sony, despite saying dissatisfied players should return their copies of the game in a statement. It means players are covered by both platforms’ standard refund policies, which, in the case of Sony, explicitly prohibits refunds if you’ve already started playing a game “unless the content is faulty.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p8SpLo"&gt;The confirmation came from the company’s senior vice president of business development, Michał Nowakowski, on an &lt;a href="https://www.cdprojekt.com/en/wp-content/uploads-en/2020/12/call-transcript_en.pdf"&gt;investor call&lt;/a&gt; held on Monday evening. “Microsoft and Sony have refund policies for every product that is released digitally on their storefronts,” Nowakowski said. “Despite several articles I’ve seen that things are being set up just for us, it’s actually not true — these policies are in place and have always been in place; they’re not offered specifically for us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="bFk0iu"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“They’re not offered specifically for us.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="q20ogQ"&gt;“Anyone who has purchased any title on the PlayStation network or the Microsoft storefront can ask for a refund, and if it’s made within certain boundaries, usually related to time, usage and so on, can ask for that refund,” he continued. “Our procedure here with Microsoft and Sony is not different than with any other title released on any of those storefronts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J3jIT4"&gt;The investor call followed widespread reports that the game has serious performance problems on older consoles. &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2020/12/9/22166912/cyberpunk-2077-base-ps4-xbox-one-bugs-issues-glitches-performance-trees-bushes"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Polygon&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that players have been experiencing “glitches, frame rate issues, major pop-in and more.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NJ1vjh"&gt;Confusion about refunds arose after reports circulated that players were successfully claiming them for the game, despite already having downloaded and played it. One &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/cyberpunkgame/comments/kb92ne/psa_sony_is_issuing_refunds_even_past_the_2_hour/"&gt;poster on Reddit&lt;/a&gt; reported they received a refund from Sony despite having played “well over 10 hours” of the game, and other commenters said they’d had similar success. The reports were notable since Sony’s &lt;a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/support/store/ps-store-refund-request/"&gt;official rules about refunds&lt;/a&gt; state, “If you have started to download or stream the purchased content you will not be eligible for a refund unless the content is faulty.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fzcjjc"&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.xbox.com/en-US/help/subscriptions-billing/buy-games-apps/refund-orders"&gt;Microsoft’s rules&lt;/a&gt;, meanwhile, don’t specifically mention not being able to refund a game after you’ve started playing it. Instead, they outline a 14-day window after purchase in which a customer may be eligible for a refund. We have contacted both Microsoft and Sony to get clarification on their refund policies. Policies around refunds for boxed copies are governed by the individual store where a copy was purchased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fyOQJz"&gt;Then, on Monday morning, CD Projekt Red issued a statement suggesting anyone who’d bought the game for PS4 or Xbox One could return their copy if they’re not pleased with the game. “If you are not pleased with the game on your console and don’t want to wait for updates, you can opt to refund your copy,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CyberpunkGame/status/1338390123373801472/photo/1"&gt;the statement read&lt;/a&gt;. It gave an email address for players to contact if they had any problems. It prompted speculation that CD Projekt Red had made a special agreement to allow players to return the game despite the usual rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PDYGkV"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="und" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://t.co/jtF5WKCiro"&gt;pic.twitter.com/jtF5WKCiro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Cyberpunk 2077 (@CyberpunkGame) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CyberpunkGame/status/1338390123373801472?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 14, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="EDfSZE"&gt;We now know this is not the case, and it seems many players found that out when they’ve tried to request refunds. &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2020-12-15-the-cyberpunk-2077-refund-situation-is-a-mess-of-mixed-messages"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eurogamer &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; that players have had mixed results from trying to request refunds from Microsoft and Sony. One &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mgs2master2/status/1338533404615135235"&gt;user on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; posted screenshots of a conversation with Sony customer support in which they were refused a refund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jnM2JY"&gt;On the same investor call, Nowakowski offered some explanation for how the game managed to release with as many problems as it has on older consoles. The executive suggested the team had been too preoccupied with optimizing the game for “PC and next-gen performance rather than current-gen,” and added, “We definitely did not spend enough time looking at that.” However, he denied there being any undue pressure to release the game when they did.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22176279/cyberpunk-2077-performance-issues-refunds-microsoft-sony-ps4-xbox-one"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22176279/cyberpunk-2077-performance-issues-refunds-microsoft-sony-ps4-xbox-one</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-15T11:48:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-15T11:48:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>Walmart will use fully driverless trucks to make deliveries in 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uJqG9X3Xj9c5gBwSUp2NsFTU0NY=/0x0:6720x4480/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68516473/gatik_self_driving_vehicle_use_for_lead_image__1_.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eR8xcg"&gt;Walmart will use fully autonomous box trucks to make deliveries in Arkansas starting in 2021. The big-box retailer has been working with a startup called Gatik on a delivery pilot for 18 months. Next year, the two companies plan on taking their partnership to the next level by removing the safety driver from their autonomous box trucks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XYnR4c"&gt;Gatik, which is based in Palo Alto and Toronto, outfitted several multitemperature box trucks with sensors and software to enable autonomous driving. Since last year, those trucks have been operating on a two-mile route between a “dark store” (a store that stocks items for fulfillment but isn’t open to the public) and a nearby Neighborhood Market in Bentonville, Arkansas. Since then, the vehicles have racked up 70,000 miles in autonomous mode with a safety driver. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="HuLGIB"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Gatik describes its approach to self-driving hardware and software as “radically divergent”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CsbQF5"&gt;Next year, the companies intend to start incorporating fully autonomous trucks into those deliveries. And they plan on expanding to a second location in Louisiana, where trucks with safety drivers will begin delivering items from a “live” Walmart Supercenter to a designated pickup location where customers can retrieve their orders. Those routes, which will begin next year, will be longer than the Arkansas operation — 20-miles between New Orleans and Metairie, Louisiana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E7mIG2"&gt;“Our trials with Gatik are just two of many use cases we’re testing with autonomous vehicles, and we’re excited to continue learning how we might incorporate them in a delivery ecosystem,” said Tom Ward, Walmart’s senior VP of customer product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k9OXyU"&gt;Gatik describes its approach to self-driving hardware and software as “radically divergent.” In a Medium post, Gatik CEO and co-founder Gautam Narang described the process that gives the company the confidence to pull safety drivers out of its vehicles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="cuKz1I"&gt;We decompose the massive monolithic DNNs into micro-models whose intended functionality is restricted to a very specific explainable task, and build rule-based fallback &amp;amp; validation systems around them. Given extensive knowledge of Gatik’s well-defined ODDs and hybrid architecture, we are able to hyper-optimize our models with exponentially less data, establish gate-keeping mechanisms to maintain explainability, and ensure continued safety of the system for unmanned operations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="KWwnJ8"&gt;Walmart is working with a variety of self-driving companies in its search for the best fit for the company’s massive retail and delivery operations. In addition to Gatik, the big-box company is working with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/25/17611760/waymo-walmart-self-driving-vehicles-groceries-discounts"&gt;Waymo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/10/21557603/cruise-walmart-autonomous-vehicles-delivery-arizona"&gt;Cruise&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/10/21004678/nuros-driverless-delivery-robots-walmart-houston"&gt;Nuro&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/8/18173776/udelv-self-driving-delivery-walmart-baidu-ces-2019"&gt;Udelv, Baidu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/14/18087898/ford-walmart-postmates-self-driving-grocery-delivery-miami"&gt;Ford, and Postmates&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22176179/walmart-fully-driverless-box-truck-delivery-gatik"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22176179/walmart-fully-driverless-box-truck-delivery-gatik</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-15T11:45:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-15T11:45:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Months later, the great Twitter hack still boggles my mind</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FZ0hzmegFR0txJnol34qnenW5D0=/0x2:2048x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68516442/VRG_ILLO_1777_twitter_bitcoin_verified.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Grayson Blackmon / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ceT25e"&gt;One of the wildest stories of the year was the day some of the most-followed Twitter accounts on the planet posted cryptocurrency scams because of a massive unprecedented hack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ibDhao"&gt;Elon Musk was the first hacked account most people noticed. “I’m feeling generous because of COVID-19,” a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/15/21326200/elon-musk-bill-gates-twitter-hack-bitcoin-scam-compromised"&gt;now-deleted 4:17PM ET tweet said&lt;/a&gt;. “I’ll double any BTC payment sent to my BTC address for the next hour. Good luck, and stay safe out there!” The tweet also included an address where people could send bitcoin. But because Twitter scammers regularly use Musk’s name and image to post cryptocurrency scams, it was hard to tell if the tweet was just Musk mocking them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dN1wqG"&gt;It quickly became clear that, yes, Musk was hacked, and it wasn’t just him. The company accounts of Coinbase, Gemini, and Binance had posted suspicious tweets shortly before Musk did. Then a deluge of tweets appeared: Apple, Barack Obama, Bill Gates, Floyd Mayweather, Jeff Bezos, Joe Biden, Kanye West, Michael Bloomberg, Uber, Warren Buffett, Wiz Khalifa, and others all posted tweets like Musk’s in short order. Some accounts posted multiple tweets while under the hackers’ control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xlfXWn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:9315987"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5V11rG"&gt;Presumably, many of these accounts are protected by things like two-factor authentication and strong passwords that would make them very hard to break into. The fact that they were all posting the scam suggested that the attackers had access to some kind of internal Twitter tool to bypass that security — and Twitter &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/3/16603620/rogue-twitter-employees-trump-account-deletion"&gt;confirmed that was the case&lt;/a&gt; later that evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wAMqFd"&gt;Notably, President Donald Trump’s account wasn’t co-opted to post the scheme. Since we live in a world where Trump can move markets and make international headlines with one 280-character missive on Twitter, it’s likely a good thing that his account wasn’t taken over. While we don’t know if the hackers even attempted to tweet as Trump, his account reportedly has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/16/21327782/trump-twitter-hacked-massive-attack-bitcoin-scam"&gt;extra protections&lt;/a&gt; that may have prevented an intrusion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1iwzKE"&gt;The chaos was funny, in its way. For a little while, it appeared that Twitter had stopped verified accounts from posting new tweets. That meant &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; and the majority of our staff weren’t able to tweet, so we briefly relied on former &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; staffer Casey Newton’s unverified wrestling-focused Twitter account (which currently has 207 followers) to share &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SuplexCasey/status/1283529700615221248"&gt;updates about the attack&lt;/a&gt;. Other unverified accounts &lt;a href="https://ftw.usatoday.com/2020/07/twitter-hack-bitcoin-verified-blue-checks-accounts-locked-joke-tweets"&gt;filled our timelines with jokes&lt;/a&gt; about a world free of blue checkmarks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OZjy7r"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;society if we didn’t unfreeze verified accounts &lt;a href="https://t.co/3P9D9kzb7u"&gt;pic.twitter.com/3P9D9kzb7u&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— vampire workday (@imbobswaget) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/imbobswaget/status/1283531817077952519?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 15, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="SF9wT3"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;the blue checks can't post, it's time for the proletariat revolution on twitter dot com&lt;/p&gt;— zoë o   (@zoenone0none) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/zoenone0none/status/1283528258730983426?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 15, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KuwQel"&gt;About two weeks after the hack, it became clear that this was the work of a teenager. Three people were charged for the attack &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/31/21349920/twitter-hack-arrest-florida-teen-fbi-irs-secret-service"&gt;on July 31st&lt;/a&gt;, including a 17-year-old from Florida who authorities claimed was the “mastermind” of the operation. A 16-year-old from Massachusetts was served a search warrant by federal agents &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/2/21418437/twitter-hack-16-year-old-massachusetts-investigation-findings"&gt;in September&lt;/a&gt; to investigate their potential involvement; this person “appears to have played an equal, if not more significant, role” than the 17-year-old, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/09/01/technology/twitter-hack.html#click=https://t.co/Lovgzaol8X"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="imJ2HR"&gt;Those involved were able to steal over $118,000 worth of bitcoin by duping people into sending the cryptocurrency to the addresses included in the scam tweets, according to &lt;a href="https://www.dfs.ny.gov/Twitter_Report"&gt;a report&lt;/a&gt; by New York’s Department of Financial Services. Because of the way bitcoin is designed, the transactions aren’t reversible, so there’s no way to return that money to the people it was stolen from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4p3xjC"&gt;Their attack didn’t use “any of the high-tech or sophisticated techniques often used in cyberattacks–no malware, no exploits, and no backdoors,” the report said. Instead, the hackers accessed internal Twitter tools by tricking Twitter employees into giving them login credentials. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JNjs83"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/company/2020/our-continued-work-to-keep-twitter-secure.html"&gt;Twitter says&lt;/a&gt; it has strengthened its internal security and invested in new tools and training for employees and contractors. But months later, it’s still hard to fathom how a group of motivated hackers brought one of the most influential social networks on the planet to its knees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SlaRLg"&gt;Thank goodness it was apparently just a bunch of bitcoin-obsessed hackers behind the attack and that they didn’t use their unprecedented access to, say, start a war. In some ways, given Musk’s Twitter run-ins with the Securities and Exchange Commission and an unsuccessful defamation suit, it’s fitting that they chose his account to tell us what they were doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4Unzsa"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sbuflo"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ynCpME"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WdhBns"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22163643/twitter-hack-bitcoin-scam-july-2020-elon-musk"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22163643/twitter-hack-bitcoin-scam-july-2020-elon-musk</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-15T11:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-15T11:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The year in scams</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JbNqaeAEKHwjNrcFuq59Mmzou6A=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68516351/VRG_ILLO_4330_001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo illustration by William Joel / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="d8iHSq"&gt;In February, a cab driver in Northern California was transporting a 92-year-old woman to the bank when &lt;a href="https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2020-02-16/cab-driver-woman-25000-scam"&gt;she told him she was taking out $25,000 to send to the IRS&lt;/a&gt;. The driver, Raj Singh, thought this sounded suspicious. Perhaps it was an IRS scam? The woman didn’t believe him, but she agreed to stop by the police station just in case. There, a law enforcement officer convinced her Singh was right — scammers were trying to steal her money. The woman went home, Singh got a $50 gift card for his troubles, and that was the last time anything good happened in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lNOTqh"&gt;In the ensuing months, we’ve been through a pandemic, an economic crisis, senseless police shootings, nationwide protests, a tsunami of misinformation, and an extremely fraught election. Scammers haven’t slept on the opportunities. Moments of crisis are ripe for exploitation, and con artists have been capitalizing on the widespread confusion to present concrete solutions to our troubles. (Hint: the solutions typically involve sending the scammers lots of cash.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GysXD8"&gt;In the background, the government has been running a grift of its own. &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/how-ruths-chris-got-an-extra-helping-of-small-business-aid-money-11587312001"&gt;Money for small businesses went to large corporations&lt;/a&gt;. The second stimulus check was promised and never delivered. &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2020/09/27/us/donald-trump-taxes.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times &lt;/em&gt;got a hold of Donald Trump’s tax returns&lt;/a&gt;, revealing he paid $750 his first year in the White House, far less than my last medical bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vFqXOA"&gt;The system is rigged to benefit the top 1 percent, which makes low-level scammers more relatable. When the odds are stacked against you, it can be tempting to cut corners, legally speaking. If 2020 taught us anything, it’s that the system is the real scam. Con artists are merely society’s id, acting out our worst instincts to get ahead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P7tt0y"&gt;Which brings us to March. The pandemic was not yet a pandemic, but things were starting to get weird. At the start of the month, I met up with José Castañeda, a Google spokesperson, for coffee and instinctively tried to shake his hand, which traumatized both of us because we didn’t have hand sanitizer. Neither here nor there, but that was also the last time I had human contact. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z3idXz"&gt;Out in Tennessee, two brothers were not so ill-prepared. On March 1st, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/14/technology/coronavirus-purell-wipes-amazon-sellers.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=RelatedLinks&amp;amp;pgtype=Article"&gt;Matt and Noah Colvin began driving around Chattanooga&lt;/a&gt; clearing out the hand sanitizer supply from every department store in the area, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/14/technology/coronavirus-purell-wipes-amazon-sellers.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=RelatedLinks&amp;amp;pgtype=Article"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Then they went to Kentucky and did the same thing. All told, they ended up with 17,700 bottles of sterilizing goodness, which they listed on Amazon for $8 to $70 each. Amazon took down the items and started suspending sellers for price gouging. The brothers were either entrepreneurs or pandemic profiteers, depending on how you interpret the American Dream. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KR2rzJ"&gt;By April, economic prospects were even worse, and &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/05/08/economy/april-jobs-report-2020-coronavirus/index.html"&gt;20.5 million Americans lost their jobs&lt;/a&gt;. The government decided to send $1,200 checks to people who made less than $99,000 (&lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/personal-finance/coronavirus-stimulus-check-questions-answers-2020-4#will-i-get-a-stimulus-check?"&gt;or less than $136,500 as a household&lt;/a&gt;), but then the checks were delayed &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/coming-to-your-1200-relief-check-donald-j-trumps-name/2020/04/14/071016c2-7e82-11ea-8013-1b6da0e4a2b7_story.html"&gt;because Trump needed to have his name printed on every single one&lt;/a&gt;. Genius PR stunt, but dick move. There was supposed to be a second stimulus check, but that hasn’t happened because politicians are constitutionally incapable of doing anything useful after the Thanksgiving holiday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gMWmED"&gt;In the meantime, the government announced it was handing out $670 billion in forgivable loans for small businesses, as part of the &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2020/7/13/21320179/ppp-loans-sba-paycheck-protection-program-polling-kanye-west"&gt;Paycheck Protection Program, meant to keep workers on payroll&lt;/a&gt;. The money ran out quickly and many small businesses were left to die, partly because massive restaurant chains like Ruth’s Chris Steak House and Shake Shack somehow qualified for $20 million and $10 million, respectively. (Both companies were eventually shamed into returning the money.) Other recipients included private equity firms and companies with close ties to President Trump, &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/21320361/small-business-closing-covid-coronavirus-ppp-entrepreneur-economy-stimulus-loans"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Vox&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Just a coincidence, I am sure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3YWyQr"&gt;As businesses stayed shuttered and life moved permanently online, grifters hawked fake COVID-19 cures on all the big tech platforms. There were &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/9/21285364/amazon-marketplace-mask-price-gouging-n95-3m-ppe"&gt;faux N95 masks on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/instagram-muscleman-arrested-for-allegedly-peddling-fak-1842507108"&gt;fake COVID-19 pills on Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.latimes.com/business/story/2020-06-17/worst-covid-19-coronavirus-crowdfunding-projects"&gt;dubious nose-only masks on Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;, and dangerous &lt;a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/culture-news/qanon-conspiracy-theorists-coronavirus-mms-bleach-youtube-twitter-944878/"&gt;bleach-drinking videos on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. Tech companies banned health misinformation but had varying degrees of success in actually keeping it off the platforms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3MU1t4"&gt;The one bright spot in recent weeks has been that &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/20/health/pfizer-covid-vaccine.html?name=styln-coronavirus-vaccines&amp;amp;region=TOP_BANNER&amp;amp;block=storyline_menu_recirc&amp;amp;action=click&amp;amp;pgtype=Article&amp;amp;impression_id=495c1b20-34da-11eb-9e0f-55046f1deaea&amp;amp;variant=1_Show"&gt;Pfizer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/30/21726554/moderna-covid-vaccine-fda-pfizer-biontech"&gt;Moderna&lt;/a&gt; applied for emergency Food and Drug Administration authorizations for their COVID-19 vaccines. This could stop scammers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/19/21186098/phone-scam-cdc-coronavirus-covid-19-vaccine-reservation-police"&gt;who were calling people to try to get them to reserve a vaccine&lt;/a&gt; over the phone. But then again, probably not. Before the announcements, scammers were claiming to be from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Now, they can say they’re with the drug companies. It’s 2020, after all, and people are nothing if not adaptable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8LU2Dx"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rYxuNd"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22149080/2020-scams-grifters-covid-19-fake-masks-sanitizer-cure"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22149080/2020-scams-grifters-covid-19-fake-masks-sanitizer-cure</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-15T11:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-15T11:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Fold review: a folding screen filled with potential</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;A neat product that is not ready&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="Yz5BBF"&gt;The Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Fold is awesome… as a concept. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rh2nea"&gt;Come on, it’s a display that folds in half. You can carry it around like a tablet. You can prop it up and use it like a Surface Pro. You can fold it halfway and use it like a clamshell laptop. You can fold it slightly and hold it like a hardcover book. And everyone who sees you whip it out of your briefcase will ask “Wow, what’s that?” And you can tell them “Oh, nothing. Just the world’s first foldable PC.” Picture it. There’s no way you won’t feel like the coolest person in your meeting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8IS1LA"&gt;So should you buy it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TOZZN4"&gt;I mean, no. Before we get into this: definitely not. It’s a whopping $2,499, not including the stylus and keyboard. (Bundles with both accessories start at $2,749 on &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lenovo.com%2Fus%2Fen%2Flaptops%2Fthinkpad%2Fthinkpad-x1%2FX1-Fold-G1%2Fp%2F22TP2X1X1F1&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22175087%2Flenovo-thinkpad-x1-fold-review#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Lenovo’s website&lt;/a&gt;.) That’s more than anyone needs to spend even to get a very good laptop — and there are a few too many problems with the X1 Fold for me to put it in that category. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DPHFgh"&gt;But! I do like the idea. The folding form factor certainly makes life easier, and I have no doubt that we’ll see more devices like this in the future — assuming manufacturers can work out some of the kinks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Wns9e4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10227336"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Fold in tablet mode, displaying The Verge’s homepage." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cXjQAcIZ9Emaz3NCg1IidXLmDk4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22146149/akrales_201203_4316_0184.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s too early to spend $2,500 on this, but I can’t wait for the next generation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="PDH7tG"&gt;A travel pro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="GSc8Rs"&gt;Here’s how a day with the X1 Fold went for me. In the morning, before signing on for work, I lay on the couch and used the Fold as a mini clamshell (that is, folded at 90 degrees with the keyboard on the bottom half of the screen) to catch up on emails. Someone had sent me an interesting YouTube video overnight. I unfolded the laptop into a 13.3-inch tablet, setting the keyboard aside, and watched it fullscreen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ehjlET"&gt;Then, work time. I popped out the built-in kickstand and propped the unfolded ThinkPad up on my kitchen table, laying the keyboard out in front of it. I used multiple windows in split-screen, with Slack and Spotify over top, the way I’d use any standard 13-inch laptop. In the early afternoon, I had an hour-long Zoom meeting, so I headed back over to the couch and folded the thing into a book shape, with Zoom on one side and Slack on the other. After that, back to work — but I didn’t feel like going back to the table, so I folded the ThinkPad back into mini-clamshell mode and used it that way on the couch for the rest of the day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Fold closed, standing upright on a table." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qtw2tG1Zn_nZiyouGFnAya3UJuU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22146174/akrales_201203_4316_0025.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The X1 Fold supports Wi-Fi 6 and 5G (optional).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The ThinkPad X1 Fold in a tent form factor." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vpYRGCDBDxA23pEREPb8-WqADDM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22146156/akrales_201203_4316_0128.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are three ports: two USB 3.2 Type-C Gen 2 and a micro SIM slot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The ThinkPad X1 Fold logo." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tnT3WXZekEF94JSlHRmbXH1843s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22146158/akrales_201203_4316_0108.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The back frame is made of carbon fiber plates and magnesium alloy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Dotva3"&gt;This is all just to illustrate how many different uses there are for this form factor. I can’t say that a folding screen has ever been at the top of my “Laptop Features I Need” list — but after using the X1 Fold for a week, I would love to own one of these. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bSXsYX"&gt;There’s no laptop I’d rather bring on a business trip than the X1 Fold, and that’s due to a couple of design choices in addition to the versatile form factor. For one: it’s really, really nice. The device is clad in an authentic black leather cover with a sturdy kickstand integrated into it. The ThinkPad logo adds a sleek splash of red. It all looked very out of place in my drab apartment. The only parts that look a tiny bit cheap are the bezels, which are large and rubber. Those are necessary to protect the sides of the display from clinking against each other, and they also give you something to hold while you’re using the Fold as a tablet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OjKPPM"&gt;A folding display also makes for a great travel companion. Folded in half, this ThinkPad is about the size of a hardcover book: 9.3 x 6.23 x 1.09 inches and 2.2 pounds (299.4 x 236 x 11.5 mm and 999g). The keyboard fits inside the folded device (magnets keep it secure), and it has a snug sleeve for the stylus on its side. I easily slipped the whole affair into my purse and would have loved carrying it around a trade show or conference under my arm. Any time I brought this somewhere, I thought, “Man, I wish I’d had this in college.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="whlduM"&gt;And with the leather cover, I was never worried about bumping or scratching the Fold — something that can be stressful with devices this expensive. (Lenovo says its product underwent MIL-STD 810H testing and is resistant to conditions including humidity, dust, sand, extreme temperatures, and mechanical shock. This certainly promises a much higher level of durability than we’ve seen from folding phones thus far.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Fold stands on a table in book mode." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lcWyn3ap_l2yvzr48KyMxy44MNg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22146172/akrales_201203_4316_0052.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lenovo says the Fold has been tested against “12 military-grade certification methods and 27 procedures.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="q1UGiA"&gt;The Fold&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="FLr6iy"&gt;With foldable devices, there’s always one big question. The answer to that question is no: you can’t see the crease while you’re using the Fold (though it’s visible when the device is turned off). The exception is when it’s partially folded like a book. The lighting in the middle and the lighting on the sides is a bit uneven in that case. But credit where credit is due: when you’re using the Fold flat, there is no crease to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="stUE22"&gt;The hinge itself, which Lenovo says it spent years developing, is quite sturdy and didn’t give me any problems. The ThinkPad requires two hands and a bit of a firm tug to open. But on the plus side, it always stayed exactly in the position I put it in without any slips or wobbles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M3ToAm"&gt;Flat, the display is a 13.3-inch OLED with 2048 x 1536 resolution. That’s a 4:3 aspect ratio, which is unusual for a laptop but feels quite roomy compared to a traditional 16:9. I could easily stack two or even three Chrome windows side by side, often with Slack, Zoom, or another app over top, without having to zoom out. And I didn’t notice any jelly scroll (where one side of the screen is able to change pixels faster than the other side), which was a problem with some &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/19/18508023/samsung-galaxy-fold-inside-screen-battery-hinge-mechanism-open-foldable"&gt;early foldable phones&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3zFo1J"&gt;The viewing experience is a luxury. The panel reproduces 100 percent of the sRGB color gamut, 100 percent of Adobe RGB, and 95 percent of DCI-P3. It’s great for watching videos and movies; even the dock icons pop with color. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Fold’s center hinge, folded into tent mode." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Jl2dQDx_38ZBGOy53qtcG8dy8cY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22146147/akrales_201203_4316_0197.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A foldable graphite layer helps with cooling.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Lenovo X1 Fold partially folded, from above." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/U2AZrGJmghJY-lbfG7-DDu0ooxw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22146148/akrales_201203_4316_0192.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Under the screen are “multiple layers of mechanical support” to prevent creasing and bubbling in the screen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BSz4lZ"&gt;On the downside, good luck using this thing outside. Not only is it quite glossy, but it only reached 289 nits at maximum brightness. That’s not a problem for indoor work, but it’s still a bit of a letdown for the price since some premium business laptops offer 1,000-nit options for less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="j6iE7P"&gt;Performance and software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="U5zS7T"&gt;Lenovo has come up with some neat software tricks to improve the Fold experience. There’s an app called Pen Settings where you can map the buttons on Lenovo’s stylus: they can do everything from copy / pasting to erasing, toggling music and volume, and pulling up various applications. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XYawCM"&gt;You can also use Lenovo’s Mode Switcher (which pops up whenever you fold or unfold the device) to split the screen in half, essentially creating two separate displays on either side of the crease. This is most useful in the mini-clamshell form if you want to have one application running up top and one on the bottom. But you can also use it when the Fold is flat, the same way you’d use the Windows split-screen feature. And if you split the screen in Mode Switcher, the Fold preserves that layout when you move between portrait and landscape orientations, whereas elaborate arrangements of tabs and apps sometimes get scattered everywhere otherwise.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ifpJpE"&gt;These are nice touches, and they show that Lenovo has really thought through the potential this form factor has, rather than just slapping a hinge onto a Surface Pro. But when it comes to performance, there are signs that this product is still in an early stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FWjwLf"&gt;There’s a lot to commend Lenovo for here. I get stressed out just thinking about the tasks this computer has. Not only does it need to know whether it’s in portrait or landscape mode (like any regular tablet), but it also has to detect whether it’s folded, how much it’s folded, and where the keyboard is — and then resize its interface accordingly. Given all that, I’m quite impressed that this thing (mostly) works. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="YF2HHd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10227391"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Iwtf5V"&gt;Mostly. But it’s not seamless, and there are some areas where the Fold and Windows 10 aren’t quite seeing eye to eye yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5547fR"&gt;For example: every so often when I had the Mini Keyboard connected, the Fold forgot it was there and sent up the on-screen keyboard anyway when I selected a textbox with the stylus. You can turn the on-screen keyboard off in Settings if this annoys you, but it’s still a glitch that’s disappointing to see. On the other hand, occasionally, the on-screen keyboard didn’t come up immediately when I wanted it to, and I’d have to prod the text box a few times before the Fold got the hint. And the little writing box, which is supposed to pop up whenever you tap a text field with the stylus, seemed to come somewhat randomly: it didn’t appear at some times when I wanted it, and it did pop up at some times when I didn’t (like if I had just highlighted something in a Google Doc). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g2mXuQ"&gt;There were two occasions, both after a restart, where the Fold didn’t realize it was in mini-laptop mode and tried to expand across the whole screen. I had to remove and replace the keyboard before the Fold detected it. (Lenovo is aware of that issue and says it’s working on a fix.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="Y786sW"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There are some areas where the Fold and Windows 10 aren’t quite seeing eye to eye yet&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DdcEZl"&gt;Most annoyingly, I wasn’t able to video chat in Zoom or WebEx using mini-laptop mode because my video feed (like the tablet’s camera) was sideways. That’s not a Lenovo-specific problem — some other Windows convertibles also don’t properly rotate their cameras if you flip them around during video calls. But it’s still something I hope Zoom and WebEx are able to fix. Were it not for this issue, mini-laptop mode would be the ideal form factor for remote meetings (WebEx on the top half, notes on the bottom). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6vnlsG"&gt;I have faith that Lenovo will iron out these kinks as time goes on. But at present, they are here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NKtFFF"&gt;The X1 Fold doesn’t have as heavy-duty of a processor as you’ll find in some other ThinkPads. It’s powered by the Intel Core i5-L16G7, one of Intel’s “Lakefield” CPUs. These are “hybrid” processors, efficient chips designed for small and light devices. They’re Intel’s answer to the Arm chips in phones, tablets, and now MacBooks. (Microsoft’s dual-screen &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/2/20889000/microsoft-surface-neo-windows-10x-hands-on-features-price-photos-release-date"&gt;Surface Neo&lt;/a&gt; is supposed to be getting one, too.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The ThinkPad X1 Fold’s onscreen keyboard." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/14sRhSqHLR5LkaepYudp80jv_PM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22146173/akrales_201203_4316_0045.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Intel Core i5-L16G7 has five cores: one fast Sunny Cove core that can boost up to 3GHz and four Tremont cores that can boost up to 1.8GHz.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="l6Qq5u"&gt;Occasional glitches aside, I was pleasantly surprised by the performance here. Multitasking in a dozen apps and Chrome tabs was no problem, and I could do some scrolling and browsing during a long Zoom call without anything freezing up. Of course, that’s also true for plenty of devices you can get for a few hundred bucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j3QeVW"&gt;And the Fold also dragged its feet on some tasks where other premium business laptops (not to mention high-end consumer laptops that are half this price) do better. It takes a good few seconds to boot up, for example, and I sometimes got impatient waiting for it to find things in File Explorer and send windows to fullscreen. Webpages were a &lt;em&gt;bit &lt;/em&gt;slower than I’m used to. The ThinkPad also takes a few seconds to rearrange itself between modes — and mini-clamshell mode, in particular — but I’m willing to forgive that since it’s a brand-new use case for Windows 10. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JlINjT"&gt;Battery life, though, was quite disappointing. Running the X1 Fold through my sustained workload (around 12 Chrome tabs and apps, occasional Spotify and YouTube streaming and Zoom calls, 200 nits of brightness), I averaged four hours and 50 minutes on the Better Battery profile and five hours and 35 minutes on the Battery Saver profile (with Intel’s battery-saving features enabled). That’s not necessarily unexpected for a laptop with an OLED display and only a 50Whr battery. But it’s not good for a $2,500 device, especially one that’s meant to be used on the go. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/21/20923662/microsoft-surface-pro-7-review-tablet-specs-features-price-usb-c-windows-10"&gt;Surface Pro 7&lt;/a&gt;, which has a higher-resolution screen, got seven to eight hours in our testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HmwlGw"&gt;The final thing worth mentioning here is that Windows 10 is still a “meh” operating system for tablets. If you’ve never used a Windows tablet before, it’s quite different from using an iPad. Gesture controls are still fairly basic, especially compared to Apple’s shortcut offerings. Moreover, most Microsoft apps aren’t designed to be used on a tablet the way that iPad apps are, so you’ll be doing a lot of struggling to tap boxes and icons that are much smaller than your fingertip. And actions like rearranging tabs and dragging / dropping windows that are second-nature with a touchpad are difficult to do with your fingers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="SobMEV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The battery life is quite disappointing&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="K91XtB"&gt;Switching to Windows Tablet Mode helps with this a bit, but you have to dig into the Action Center to turn that on manually. The Fold doesn’t swap to it automatically when you disconnect the keyboard the way Surface Books do. (Again, it’s not a Fold-specific problem — in general, disconnecting Bluetooth keyboards from Windows convertibles doesn’t trigger Tablet Mode — but it’s inconvenient nonetheless.) And of course, Windows 10 doesn’t have any unique features that take advantage of the dual-screen setup; Microsoft is working on an operating system optimized for dual-screen hardware (including its own Surface Neo), but we don’t expect that to arrive until &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/20/21331063/microsoft-windows-10x-2021-spring-release-date-rumors"&gt;next spring&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g9td9c"&gt;The running theme here is that most of these issues are Microsoft’s fault, not Lenovo’s. The convertible laptops Microsoft makes use the same operating system. But the lack of tablet functionality makes more sense on Surface Books and Surface Pros, which can serve as tablets where needed but are still meant to function primarily as computers. The problem with the Fold is that it’s at its best as a tablet. The ideal X1 Fold customer will be using it as a tablet most of the time. Because there are two major reasons I don’t recommend this device as a primary laptop. Those reasons are...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vP97NN"&gt;The keyboard and touchpad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Fold in mini-laptop mode." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Cru_WHJULQQ2t0zO2JXGmZUJPQM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22146151/akrales_201203_4316_0169.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Mod Pen charges via USB-C. The Mini Keyboard charges wirelessly when it’s inside the Fold and can also charge with Micro USB.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TWWBAZ"&gt;The X1 Fold is beautiful to look at and, as a tablet, a marvel to use. But I still dreaded having to drive it for my actual work every day. That’s because the keyboard and touchpad are tiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PfPpj6"&gt;Now, I understand &lt;em&gt;why &lt;/em&gt;they’re tiny. Lenovo wanted to make a keyboard small enough to fit inside the folded device so it wouldn’t be an extra thing to carry around. And it certainly succeeded in making a keyboard that fits perfectly into the folded-up tablet. I was never concerned that it would fall out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f83vpb"&gt;But I &lt;em&gt;hate &lt;/em&gt;typing on it. The keys actually feel quite sturdy and have a satisfying click to them, but Lenovo essentially had to combine a number of keys to achieve its desired size. For example: the apostrophe / quotation key, usually to the left of Enter on a US keyboard, has been moved to the far right side of the keyboard above Enter. (It’s a half key, sharing a slot with colon / semicolon). Every time I needed to type an apostrophe, I had to consciously stretch my hand far to the right. Approximately 50 percent of my apostrophe attempts resulted in instinctively slamming Enter instead (as my colleagues who received numerous incomplete Slack messages can attest). I assume you’ll adjust to this after a while of using the Fold, but &lt;em&gt;boy&lt;/em&gt; is there a learning curve. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LiDcZd"&gt;It gets worse: Lenovo had to cram some keys that were already dual-purpose together, meaning that some buttons accommodate as many as four different symbols. Question mark / forward slash has been combined with period / greater than, so typing a question mark requires hitting all three of Shift, Fn, and period at the same time. Dash has been relegated to Fn+9, which also tripped me up. I had to go through this review and delete a bunch of accidental 9s I’d typed before I filed it. And backslash requires Fn+8, which would make the X1 Fold a huge pain for people in STEM fields who needs to use LaTeX and some other programming languages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Fold being used in book mode." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/53aTnyKa5m6HTKpa9YviMBxXOjo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22146152/akrales_201203_4316_0162.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lenovo says the Mod Pen gets 250 minutes of use from a five-minute charge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UaXi38"&gt;Again, I understand why the keyboard needed to be small. But I would rather carry the keyboard separately than have to press three keys to make a question mark. Lenovo could make a nice carrying case that fits the Fold, the keyboard, and the stylus, and I would be totally fine with that. The company could also create some more space by removing the touchpad — which it might as well because the touchpad is basically useless. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UdWb96"&gt;To put in context how tiny this thing is: if I place two fingers on it (and my fingers are quite small) there is almost no room above or below them. So as you can probably imagine, scrolling is a pain (you hit the plastic frame immediately) as is clicking / dragging, highlighting, and anything else that requires two moving fingers. (There’s nowhere close to enough room.) Laying out a big article, which involves copy-pasting text and moving a bunch of images around, was quite a struggle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Fold laid out in tablet mode on a bench." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pZMUuoIM1tH-CGaD5hiDi6rbQ2M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22146153/akrales_201203_4316_0157.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Fold comes with the Dolby Access app, where you can swap between profiles for different settings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1xGy4K"&gt;The touchpad also didn’t do what I needed it to as often as I wanted. It sometimes thought I was holding it down when I had let go, meaning I’d unintentionally move tabs around. And highlighting a segment of text or getting my cursor to land in an exact spot was often a trial-and-error process. Even with the touchpad on its lowest sensitivity, I rarely got the right location on the first go. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WfgAaq"&gt;I don’t use third-party peripherals with laptops I review, but this touchpad pushed that principle to its limit: I have never been closer to saying “Screw it” and plugging in a mouse to give myself a break. I ended up using the stylus for most of my navigation, but that’s suboptimal for some actions (rearranging tabs, doing anything in Google Docs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="2mL8HA"&gt;Overall, the X1 Fold is a spectacular device in a lot of ways. It’s good at the one thing it’s advertised for (folding). It’s beautiful, both to look at and to use. It’s sturdy. And the form factor is useful. It’s not a gimmick. I would love to own a tablet like this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ghXt1"&gt;The key word there is “tablet.” The X1 Fold isn’t a tablet. It has a laptop operating system and — more importantly — it’s priced like a laptop. It’s priced like a very expensive laptop. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kdHz05"&gt;And it’s not ready to fill that role yet. The battery life isn’t there yet. The keyboard and touchpad aren’t there yet. The software integration, while commendable, isn’t there yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="CAcL4I"&gt;The key word there is “yet.” Because with all that being said, I can’t wait for the second generation. Samsung’s first foldable phones were &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/19/18498904/samsung-galaxy-fold-review-screen-broken-issue-durability-foldable-phone-video-performance-price"&gt;riddled with issues&lt;/a&gt; — but just over a year and several iterations later, the company is selling a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21427462/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-2-review"&gt;folding device&lt;/a&gt; that’s very usable (albeit pretty expensive). I’m sure that’s going to be the case with foldable laptops as well. Lenovo has a groundbreaking idea, with a strong foundation to build on. I really hope it’s able to patch the Fold’s glitches without compromising on the components that are already exceptional. That would be a breathtaking device, one that would earn my unambiguous recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="wOVjis"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10227383"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="r1Zgcm"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22175087/lenovo-thinkpad-x1-fold-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22175087/lenovo-thinkpad-x1-fold-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-15T11:12:42-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-15T11:12:42-05:00</updated>
    <title>The MCU is so big Disney Plus is getting a new Legends clip show to help you keep track</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L2mI9rBqdHPu74PIWxe3fex0WZY=/0x50:3225x2200/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68516255/legends_logo_finish.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qdihak"&gt;Disney has announced that yet another new Marvel series is coming to Disney Plus: &lt;a href="https://www.marvel.com/articles/tv-shows/marvel-studios-legends-new-series-disney-plus"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marvel Studios: Legends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;The new ongoing series will “showcase individual characters viewers have come to know and love over the years and revisit some of their most iconic moments.” In other words, it seems like Marvel Studios is making its own clip show to recap the franchise before its major new releases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sMnQn6"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Legends&lt;/em&gt; will kick off with two episodes focusing on the characters of Wanda Maximoff and Vision, respectively, to help refresh viewers’ memories of the two heroes’ history in the previous Marvel films. The episodes will unsurprisingly debut on Disney Plus on January 8th, 2021 — just a week before &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22168373/wandavision-trailer-disney-plus-marvel-studios-elizabeth-olsen-paul-bettany"&gt;the first episode of &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is due to be released on January 15th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Hs6Enj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The 52 things Disney just announced","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167976/disney-investor-day-2020-biggest-announcements-plus-marvel-star-wars-pixar-animation"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="3URswf"&gt;The show is a tacit admission that Marvel’s interconnected world of movies and TV shows might just be starting to get a little too unwieldy for more casual viewers to keep track of. With 23 films already out and another 10 on the way, along with the upcoming deluge of Disney Plus shows (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167976/disney-investor-day-2020-biggest-announcements-plus-marvel-star-wars-pixar-animation"&gt;with 12 of those already announced&lt;/a&gt;), that’s a lot of character history and backstory that fans are expected to be at least passingly familiar with to keep up with the new content. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ZSXrG"&gt;The strategy is a familiar one: Marvel already uses similar one-page recaps in its own comics to help new readers catch up on ongoing series. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mF5YPF"&gt;It’s easy to imagine how Disney will leverage &lt;em&gt;Legends&lt;/em&gt; going forward: Falcon and Winter Soldier episodes that remind viewers of Bucky’s complicated history and how Sam Wilson ended up with Captain America’s shield, or an episode before &lt;em&gt;Loki&lt;/em&gt;’s debut tracking the time-traveling shenanigans of the fan-favorite villain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CP7cTW"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marvel Studios: Legends&lt;/em&gt; joins a dizzying array of Marvel shows set for Disney Plus, including &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; (January 15th), &lt;em&gt;The Falcon and the Winter Soldier&lt;/em&gt; (March), &lt;em&gt;Loki&lt;/em&gt; (May), &lt;em&gt;Ms. Marvel&lt;/em&gt; (late 2021), &lt;em&gt;Hawkeye&lt;/em&gt; (2021), &lt;em&gt;What If...?&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Moon Knight&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;She-Hulk&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Secret Invasion&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Ironheart&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Armor Wars&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;I Am Groot&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22176241/marvel-studios-legends-disney-plus-clip-show-recap-series-wandavision"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22176241/marvel-studios-legends-disney-plus-clip-show-recap-series-wandavision</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
