<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-08-05T14:40:04-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-05T14:40:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-05T14:40:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon’s office workers now won’t return until early 2022</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OJ_he9UhXKt5hoopMnBSu8CXubo=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69684517/acastro_180329_1777_amazon_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="INy2FQ"&gt;Amazon’s corporate workers &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/08/05/amazon-postpones-return-to-office-until-january-2022-.html"&gt;won't be returning to its offices until January 2022&lt;/a&gt;, the company has confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. This marks a delay of around four months, as the &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-06-10/amazon-wants-office-workers-back-3-days-a-week-in-september?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;company’s previous plan&lt;/a&gt; called for employees to return on a hybrid basis starting on September 7th, 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DTT7vm"&gt;Amazon released updated return-to-office procedures for its employees in June, and it tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that wearing masks will be optional for fully vaccinated employees but required for everyone else. The &lt;a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/workplace/amazon-updates-return-to-office-guidance"&gt;company’s news post&lt;/a&gt; about the return to office guidance stated that employees could expect a hybrid work model, with the standard being three days in the office and two remote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="k7u7J5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Many of Amazon’s workers have been working on-site throughout the pandemic&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mjgPIR"&gt;The news of Amazon pushing back its in-person working plans comes as many other tech companies are reconsidering how to bring workers back. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22607690/microsoft-proof-vaccination-covid-19-us-buildings-office-reopening"&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22598316/google-vaccination-requirement-return-offices-covid-19-delta-variant"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22598818/facebook-vaccine-requirement-us-office-employees"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; have all recently announced that their office workers would have to be vaccinated to return. Last month, Amazon said it &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/companies-covid-vaccine-mandate-11627582286"&gt;wouldn’t require its employees to be vaccinated&lt;/a&gt;, and its masking requirements for non-vaccinated employees implies that’s still its position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="76P9rB"&gt;Of course, many of Amazon’s workers, including its warehouse and Whole Foods staff, have been working on-site throughout the pandemic. In October 2020, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/1/21497941/amazon-disclose-workers-contract-covid-19"&gt;Amazon reported&lt;/a&gt; that from March 1st to September 19th, 2020, almost 20,000 of its frontline employees either tested positive or were presumed positive for COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DThBUM"&gt;In July 2021, Amazon said it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22584386/amazon-end-onsite-covid-19-testing-us-warehouses"&gt;halting its on-site testing program&lt;/a&gt; for its warehouses but that it would resume the tests if official health guidance changed. Amazon says it’s still following local regulations and guidance, but it decided to wind down its warehouse testing sites due to the widespread availability of testing in the US. This does, however, put the burden of finding and visiting a testing site onto the workers themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611439/amazon-office-employees-postpone-back-to-work-january-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611439/amazon-office-employees-postpone-back-to-work-january-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-05T14:29:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-05T14:29:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>The PS5 will be available online from Walmart at 3PM ET</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZeWLvDK0v971zrJhCmnST4gHYqk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69684459/acastro_210511_1777_psRestock_0006.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4G7DpQ"&gt;If you haven’t been able to secure a PlayStation 5, you might be in luck. Today, Walmart is opening up for orders for the PS5 promptly at 3PM ET / 12PM PT (online only); this includes the &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-PlayStation-5-Video-Game-Console%2F994712501" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$500 disc-based version&lt;/a&gt; of the console as well as the &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-PlayStation-5-Digital-Edition-Video-Game-Consoles%2F979738052" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$400 digital disc-less version&lt;/a&gt;. Remember, it’s usually the first who gets the worm, but not always. If you miss out on the first wave at Walmart, the retailer usually releases more in 10-minute intervals, with the next being at 3:10PM, 3:20PM, and so forth until it runs out of stock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="T2BM0q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"PlayStation 5 review: a big, confident step into next gen","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21550146/sony-playstation-5-ps5-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Wdz7DM"&gt;Also, if you don’t get lucky at first, persist! Sometimes, the “add to cart” button will pop up intermittently, so just be patient and watch closely. It’ll only help your chances of securing a console if you sign in to your Walmart account and ensure that all of your shipping and payment details are set so you can fly through checkout if you get a PS5 in your cart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gI5wAx"&gt;We’ll add more retailers to this post if any join in on the fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9FpTcg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10384391"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="WMKy7m"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9563999"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ArYNbs"&gt;If all you wanted was the console, well, you’re all set with the links above. But there are several games and accessories you could add to your cart right now that’ll let you have more fun with your PS5 when it arrives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="t2rSE8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10499033"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="HayHr1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10510093"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="WuxBee"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10687661"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="OMAPbI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10420564"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611564/sony-ps5-digital-disc-playstation-5-console-walmart-restock-buy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611564/sony-ps5-digital-disc-playstation-5-console-walmart-restock-buy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-05T14:10:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-05T14:10:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>Scarlett Johansson’s Black Widow lawsuit has unearthed a huge problem with streaming</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DwjrDBcyvWGixMe5vUB1t3ojU00=/0x0:2505x1670/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69684386/fbg7020_comp_v003_bf38a189.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Marvel Studios&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="urGHo9"&gt;This summer’s biggest Hollywood attraction is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/29/22600396/scarlett-johansson-suing-disney-black-widow-release"&gt;a multimillion-dollar battle between two of the industry’s best-known players&lt;/a&gt;: Scarlett Johansson and Disney. Johansson sued Disney last week over its day-and-date release of her Marvel superhero film &lt;em&gt;Black Widow&lt;/em&gt;, which put the movie on Disney Plus the same day it hit theaters, potentially depriving her of a huge box-office-infused paycheck. The aftermath has been chaotic, but it’s more importantly illuminated the myriad ways that streaming has forever changed the way we experience movies and the implications for the creatives and talent who make them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3amZ80"&gt;Movie contracts have traditionally been negotiated around box office results, with sizable bonuses tied to how well a film performed. This worked out well for both talent and studios. Studios saved a chunk of money up front and didn’t risk spending big on a flop, while actors, producers, and others involved in a film could look at box office results to see exactly what their production was worth and get paid accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GR0buB"&gt;But with the shift to streaming, things have had to change. Actors and producers working with a streamer like Netflix are typically paid a set fee, an industry attorney who negotiates contracts for top-level talent told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. (The attorney asked not to be named so as to speak freely about the topic.) If they’re lucky enough to have significant leverage, they could also potentially secure a bonus premium fee that’s a contractual dollar amount paid out over months or quarters. But it’s not performance-based like box office bonuses are. Netflix often pays out this prenegotiated sum in eight quarterly installments following a title’s release, the attorney said, while Apple tends to pay out a little quicker over 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8NSgME"&gt;Because the space is changing so quickly, part of this attorney’s role in contract negotiations now is to “read the tea leaves and project where the deals are going to go.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="3QEjds"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Lawyers have to “read the tea leaves and project where the deals are going to go”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qC7HLT"&gt;The old way of negotiating talent earnings has changed rapidly. According to Johansson’s complaint, terms of her &lt;em&gt;Black Widow&lt;/em&gt; release were initially finalized in 2017 — early enough that Disney Plus hadn’t been announced, and Johansson’s team evidently didn’t think it was necessary to negotiate terms around streaming. Her contract specified &lt;em&gt;Black Widow&lt;/em&gt; would debut with a “wide theatrical release,” but that it would be &lt;em&gt;exclusively &lt;/em&gt;theatrical appears to have been only an understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fzWLjb"&gt;While actors know now that they need to negotiate terms for streaming, determining their worth is more difficult than simply looking to box office receipts. Streaming services hold their performance data extremely close to the chest, and they’re reluctant to share specifics about engagement and earnings on specific titles. Data that &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; shared is often &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/netflixs-most-important-metric-2016-2"&gt;opaque&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/those-hbo-max-numbers-arent-what-they-seem-1846752112"&gt;obscured&lt;/a&gt;, or lacking context for how a title’s success (or failure) was measured by respective streamers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="57heDu"&gt;“I don’t see Netflix wanting to share how much of their subscriber base is growing and what their viewership is any time soon,” the attorney said. “But we would like to see it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OgDTRJ"&gt;This is one reason why industry analysts who spoke with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; expressed a need for greater transparency by not just Disney but all streamers about performance data of titles on their platforms. Without it, it’s difficult for talent to advocate for themselves in negotiations in a swiftly evolving streaming landscape, argued&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Karie Bible, a media analyst with Exhibitor Relations Co. who spoke with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; by phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2oGKRF"&gt;“The streamers are, for the most part, pretty darned nontransparent about numbers, about breakdowns, about demographics,” Bible said, adding that this information is not only crucial for analysts but agents, managers, and lawyers, too, who have traditionally negotiated based on box office performance. What this lack of transparency by streamers can lead to is not only mistrust, but possibly even more of what Bible described as “creative accounting” by companies who aren’t forthright during contract negotiations. And that could potentially mean lost earnings for talent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="pKfmjT"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The streamers are, for the most part, pretty darned nontransparent about numbers, about breakdowns, about demographics”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CkPVLk"&gt;Another thing to consider is that each individual streamer’s metrics for success are, by and large, unclear. Box office numbers offer a clear picture of how a movie performed relative to its budget and projected ticket sales. But with streaming, none of us really know what a win looks like — huge viewership numbers, new signups, repeat views — short of the company telling us that a movie was one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y3bqSZ"&gt;“I think we have to understand this lawsuit in the context of the redefined success metrics for any movie in the market today,” Daniel Loria, SVP of content strategy and editorial director at Boxoffice Pro, said by phone. “Unfortunately, we are all in the dark as to what that success means in the streaming era — not just the COVID era — but the streaming as a whole.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rS7K69"&gt;Like Bible, Loria added that it’s likely frustrating for people in the entertainment industry who stand to benefit from streamer-produced titles but are not getting enough transparency around data and seemingly arbitrarily concocted metrics for success, which can vary by company and service. That could lead to top-name talent thinking twice about engaging in these types of agreements, or at the very least demanding clauses that protect their earnings in the event that a film’s release rollout is changed by a streaming-adjacent studio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="1N57uy"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It seems right now like every studio is playing by a different set of rules and different metrics on what is financially successful and what isn’t”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Y4mNR8"&gt;“If the industry wants to redefine the metrics of success for a movie, it needs to be on the same page on what that definition is,” Loria said. “And it seems right now like every studio is playing by a different set of rules and different metrics on what is financially successful and what isn’t.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7tWKMB"&gt;Now, negotiations are not going to operate the same way for every actor. Streaming services are willing to shell out more for talent if they believe the production is likely to drive subscriptions to the service, the Hollywood attorney told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. That in itself presents a lot of opportunity for talent willing to join a production that may be a straight-to-streaming release, as we’ve seen play out on services like Netflix and Apple TV Plus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZqiM8E"&gt;“I think in our business, high-end talent has always had leverage and will continue to have leverage,” the attorney said. At the same time, the attorney pointed to a “maelstrom” of two significant influences, COVID-19 and a new streaming era, that has complicated contracts negotiated prior to either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mdfd7L"&gt;Whether Johansson’s lawsuit is settled out of court is less important than what we’ve learned from Disney’s response to it: streaming services are being intentionally obtuse about how owning every single element of production, including releases, and an insatiable appetite for streaming influence is impacting the entertainment industry. No one’s sure what success looks like today, and that’s made knowing who’s winning and who’s losing hard to size up. Short of streamers making that data more transparent and available, the people who make the stuff we watch are walking into negotiations blind. And ultimately, what’s bad for streaming is bad for viewers.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22611516/scarlett-johansson-disney-lawsuit-streaming-services-transparency"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22611516/scarlett-johansson-disney-lawsuit-streaming-services-transparency</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-05T13:40:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-05T13:40:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft is creating a single OneNote for Windows app with a visual refresh</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Vc5nlZr6dHvEz8M-5lbyXrKoAmE=/11x0:481x313/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69684082/OneNotePM_2_1628115749181.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new OneNote visual refresh.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OoQbrW"&gt;Microsoft is planning to unify its OneNote and OneNote for Windows 10 apps into a single OneNote app. The software maker is taking all the improvements in its UWP OneNote for Windows 10 app and bringing them over to the traditional OneNote desktop app instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vR4xvl"&gt;These improvements will appear in a series of updates over the next 12 months to the traditional OneNote desktop app that installs as part of Office. The updates include a visual refresh and “key existing features currently unique to OneNote for Windows 10.” It’s not clear which features from OneNote for Windows 10 will make their way over to the OneNote desktop app, but &lt;a href="https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/office-365-blog/what-s-coming-to-onenote/ba-p/2612960"&gt;Microsoft says&lt;/a&gt; “we are working to ensure that all the most loved features will continue to be a part of OneNote.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/atN17Waz5XGxl0nK3A1dbzb8sTw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22763938/image.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A mockup of the changes coming to OneNote on Windows.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6iCJnD"&gt;Existing users of the dedicated OneNote for Windows 10 app will be asked to upgrade to the full desktop OneNote app in the second half of 2022. “Advances in Windows and Office will allow us to unify the two apps so that you’ll have the simplicity of a single OneNote app on Windows while enjoying the interface and features you’re already familiar with,” explains the OneNote team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CISON3"&gt;While Microsoft won’t immediately kill off the UWP version of OneNote for Windows 10, the company does note that OneNote users should move to the desktop app by October 2025, when OneNote for Windows 10 will reach end of support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wxv5wS"&gt;These changes to OneNote on Windows won’t affect Microsoft’s other OneNote apps for macOS, iOS, Android, or the web. It’s simply Microsoft unifying its separate OneNote apps into something that hopefully has the best of the UWP and desktop worlds.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611531/microsoft-new-onenote-app-visual-refresh-single-app"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611531/microsoft-new-onenote-app-visual-refresh-single-app</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-05T13:38:26-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-05T13:38:26-04:00</updated>
    <title>The best gaming laptops in 2021: seven laptops to get your game on</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Best Gaming Laptops 2021: Asus ROG Zephyrus G15" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dFgjUrUVReawUz4BcRUID8XTWDI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68856650/akrales_210226_4440_0019.9.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our top picks from Asus, MSI, Razer, and more.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales/ The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The best gaming laptop at every size and price&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="SKtFh9"&gt;The best gaming laptops are changing every year. The early days of mobile gaming were largely desktop replacements — clunky chassis, multiple power bricks, and RGB lighting galore. But the top contenders now are different. Manufacturers are finally putting powerful specs in sleeker, more portable, and more professional builds. They have excellent, fast refreshing screens that are necessary for a great gaming experience. These laptops aren’t just great for gaming, but for everyday work as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qiHviH"&gt;The best gaming laptop of 2021 is the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321471/asus-rog-zephyrus-g15-gaming-laptop-review"&gt;Asus ROG Zephyrus G15&lt;/a&gt;. It can handle the most demanding games on the market today and also makes a great daily driver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VRi2QJ"&gt;We’ll be updating this page regularly as the best gaming laptops hit shelves throughout this year. Some exciting updates are on the way. AMD and Nvidia have announced their next-gen series of mobile processors and mobile graphics cards — the Ryzen 5000 series and the GeForce RTX 3000 series, respectively — and we’re already seeing them in premium gaming laptops across manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cGRnFN"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22217171/gaming-laptops-qhd-screens-display-fast-refresh-rate"&gt;QHD screen&lt;/a&gt; is another feature to watch for in the best gaming laptops. A growing number of manufacturers are releasing configurations with 1440p displays, even in gaming laptops under $2,000. These options can hit a sweet spot for many gamers: a better experience than 1080p without the price premium or raw horsepower required for a 4K display. You can expect decently high refresh rates from these panels as well, depending on the model. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a5KtNO"&gt;One more thing to keep in mind with the best gaming laptops is the power you can expect. Not all chips with the same name are created equal — the RTX 3070 in one laptop may not deliver the same frame rates as the RTX 3070 in another laptop due to its wattage (as well as other factors like the processor and cooling). Nvidia now requires companies to disclose clock speeds and graphics power on each model’s product page, but plenty of manufacturers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22266921/nvidia-requiring-companies-share-clock-speed-power-gaming-laptop-rtx-30-series-gpu-specs"&gt;haven’t done that yet&lt;/a&gt;. Your best bet, if you can’t find those numbers on a company’s website, is to read some reviews and make sure the model you’re considering will deliver the frame rates you’re looking for. We will note the wattage used in any laptops we review with the new RTX graphics cards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b1WSZi"&gt;If you’re looking for a more multipurpose device, check out our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21250695/best-laptops"&gt;best laptop&lt;/a&gt; page. If you’re an Android gamer, we’ve also got a list of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21296102/best-chromebooks"&gt;best Chromebooks&lt;/a&gt; you can buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="NqFABt"&gt;Best Gaming Laptop 2021&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="VQOCHc"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Gaming Laptop 2021: Asus ROG Zephyrus G15" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WQts40hc8DMLBo4BPnPjc4j4RSI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22341895/akrales_210226_4440_0125.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales/ The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Asus ROG Zephyrus G15 is the best gaming laptop of 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="oTToOm"&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321471/asus-rog-zephyrus-g15-gaming-laptop-review"&gt;Asus ROG Zephyrus G15&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="rE8ByG"&gt;The best gaming laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="dqOSgQ"&gt;Asus’s ROG Zephyrus G14 was our top gaming laptop pick for quite a while. It did just about everything right, and we weren’t sure whether Asus could ever replicate its resounding success. But somehow, the company managed to make the G14 just a bit bigger, and a heck of a lot better. In doing so, it’s created the ROG Zephyrus G15, the best 15-inch rig you can buy.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AsXGzm"&gt;At just over four pounds, the Zephyrus G15 is one of the lightest 15-inch gaming laptops you can buy. But you’re not making any compromises on performance for that portability: it’s powered by the top mobile chips that AMD and Nvidia have to offer, and includes a fast 165Hz QHD (1440p) display. Together, those components can handle even the toughest AAA titles at QHD resolution. The panel has excellent color reproduction as well, so your games will look great. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HMlhzT"&gt;But it’s not just the gaming; almost everything else about the G15 is great, too. The audio (pumped from a six-speaker array) has strong percussion and bass, the keyboard and touchpad have a satisfying click, the port selection leaves little to be desired, and the battery can last for a whopping eight and a half hours. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MktsFD"&gt;The G15 won’t be the laptop for everyone. There’s no webcam, which is a significant oversight, and some may prefer something more affordable, or with a flashier aesthetic. But as a package, the G15 is the one to beat. Not only is it the best gaming laptop you can buy, but it’s also one of the best laptops you can buy, period. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uMAFCa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10385239" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_square_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="qnyi8k"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best gaming laptop 2021: Asus ROG Zephyrus G14" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/g6h4assr_kNPJ14NeShE2YeeihU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21887081/mchin_181207_4189_0009.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Asus ROG Zephyrus G14 is the best gaming laptop of 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gXl1tL"&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/30/21197761/asus-rog-zephyrus-g14-review-gaming-laptop-specs-features-price"&gt;Asus ROG Zephyrus G14&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ibDYbq"&gt;The best gaming laptop in a 14-inch chassis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="PjVXGI"&gt;The ROG Zephyrus G14 is the best 14-inch gaming laptop you can buy. We most recently reviewed last year’s model, which includes AMD’s Ryzen 4000 series up to the eight-core Ryzen 9 4900HS and an Nvidia RTX 2060 GPU. There’s a brand-new model out featuring the Ryzen 5000 series and Nvidia’s RTX 30-series graphics, which we’re looking forward to getting our hands on ASAP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZvmPMM"&gt;For well under $2,000, the Zephyrus crams one of the most powerful mobile processors on the market into a super portable 14-inch chassis. With capable cooling to boot, the laptop delivers frame rates we’ve never seen in a laptop of this size before. It handled every game we threw at it without breaking a sweat.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LRoiIm"&gt;But aside from its excellent gaming performance, the G14 makes a great daily driver. The keyboard, touchpad, display, and port selection are all excellent. Even the battery life is good — something we almost never get to say about gaming laptops. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0yypId"&gt;There are a few downsides to the G14, but they’re fairly small and user-dependent. The most significant note is that it lacks a webcam; you’ll need an external one if you plan on taking video calls. There’s also some bleed in the backlighting, there’s no Thunderbolt connectivity (since it’s an AMD system, and that’s an Intel standard), and the fans can get louder than most under load. But these are very much nitpicks that won’t have a large impact on plenty of people’s gaming experience. Overall, we have very few complaints. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="cUw2US"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9505867"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="PEmMiz"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best gaming laptop 2021: Razer Blade Pro 17" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1Hw1GXC0JJNr36nQ6K4vzlWTH-k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21820230/mchin_181119_4158_0015.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Razer Blade Pro 17 is a monster of a gaming laptop.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="yzdsDK"&gt;3. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21405760/razer-blade-pro-17-2020-review"&gt;Razer Blade Pro 17&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="jT5h16"&gt;The best big-screen gaming laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="E8Fdz3"&gt;The Blade Pro 17 delivers some of the best gaming performance you can find in a laptop — but that’s not even its superpower. What makes Razer’s 17-inch flagship so impressive is it packs that unbelievable power into a thin and attractive chassis. It’s just 0.8 inches thick and only requires one charging brick — so you can carry it around in a backpack or briefcase without compromising on power. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jaBYbX"&gt;Gaming enthusiasts can opt for a model with a 300Hz screen — the highest refresh rate you can get on a laptop — while folks who want to combine gaming with some creative work can opt for a 120Hz touchscreen configuration. Both models come with a customizable per-key RGB keyboard, which adds a touch of color to the Pro’s design without being too obnoxious for the office. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AsGaDN"&gt;The Blade Pro 17 certainly isn’t cheap, but it’s the laptop to buy if you want the best of the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wsMJEI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9505921"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="XCwzkS"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best gaming laptop 2021: Asus ROG Strix G15 Advantage Edition" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4-MFImj_bClitaOWhNkct_TSxqo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22552472/mchin_20190821_4609_0010.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Asus ROG Zephyrus G15 Advantage Edition is powered by an impressive AMD processor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2kvoth"&gt;4. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22465565/asus-rog-strix-g15-advantage-edition-gaming-laptop-review"&gt;Asus ROG Zephyrus G15 Advantage Edition&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="SAASF8"&gt;The best big-screen gaming laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="HhOl4t"&gt;The ROG Strix G15 Advantage Edition is one of the few gaming laptops you’ll find that includes both an AMD processor and an AMD GPU. Not to worry — it delivers gaming performance on par with what you’ll see from laptops with Nvidia’s top GPUs. It also delivers one of the best gaming battery experiences we’ve ever seen — it was able to maintain playable frame rates on &lt;em&gt;Red Dead Redemption 2 &lt;/em&gt;for over an hour with no charger attached. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JHVLju"&gt;Speaking of battery, we averaged nine hours and 16 minutes of work use between charges, which makes the Strix G15 far and away one of the longest-lasting gaming laptops on the market. That’s doubly impressive because it’s powering a ton of flashy LEDs, including a per-key RGB keyboard and a colorful light strip around the front edge of the deck. If you’re looking for a jazzy, bold design and you’re all-in on AMD, the Strix G15 Advantage edition is the best gaming laptop for you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="p8WbEf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10641674"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="59mBsv"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best gaming laptop 2021: Dell G5 15 SE" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Na8N40bAkFQr8vsnVrWHMemA3q8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/20086153/cfaulkner_200714_4098_0004.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Dell G5 15 SE is the best gaming laptop you can buy for $1,000.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="MaGh3q"&gt;5. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21328344/dell-g5-15-se-review-2020-gaming-laptop-amd-ryzen"&gt;Dell G5 15 SE&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="DMtcRV"&gt;The best budget gaming laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="hCCjrZ"&gt;The Dell G5 15 SE offers a great gaming experience at a price range far below that of many competitors. You can buy it for around $1,000, and it doesn’t ask too many compromises for that price. While it only comes with a 60Hz screen, the hardware inside (especially AMD’s Ryzen 7 processor) is capable of maxing that out on all kinds of demanding games at native 1080p resolution, so you can reliably expect a playable experience from your favorite titles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q6ozmE"&gt;We’re also impressed by the G5’s connectivity. It includes a Mini DisplayPort, an HDMI, and an Ethernet jack — all ports you don’t see every day on laptops at this price point. Overall, if you’re looking for great value for your money, the G5 is your best bet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="cYdW6R"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9505968"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="UHt6xg"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best gaming laptop 2021: Razer Blade 15 Advanced" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JEuLWwA7yrXUTplilCC7i1YKquw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21922571/cfaulkner_200929_4214_0002.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Razer Blade 15 is the 15-inch gaming laptop to beat.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="n9BvYP"&gt;6. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21499199/razer-blade-15-advanced-edition-gaming-laptop-2020-review"&gt;Razer Blade 15 Advanced&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="wzRw2D"&gt;A great thin and light gaming laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="EcPuJg"&gt;The Blade 15 isn’t as powerful as its 17-inch sibling, but it may be a more pragmatic purchase for many people. If you’re looking for a balanced combination of performance and portability, the Blade 15 may hit that sweet spot. It still packs the top chips on the market and can come with a 300Hz display, but at just 4.7 pounds and 0.7 inches thick, it’s comparable in size to a number of 15-inch productivity machines like the Dell XPS 15. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w8vpQe"&gt;In addition to its reliable gaming performance, the Blade 15 works well as a productivity machine. We’re big fans of its keyboard, which is quite comfortable to use and has per-key RGB lighting, and the touchpad, which is roomy with a satisfying click. Our primary complaint is that this Blade got quite hot during our game testing — not only did the processor reach 99 degrees, but the hinge and palm rests were uncomfortable to touch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="sxB5RK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9591143"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="tOxdNl"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best gaming laptop 2021: Asus ROG Strix Scar 15" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aTzXemr0v3qrt3uxufTnb2q6HSA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22183653/mchin_190314_4347_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Monica Chin / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The ROG Strix Scar 15 is a colorful laptop with a premium price.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="E7sNUb"&gt;7. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22195676/asus-rog-strix-scar-15-review-gaming-laptop-specs-features-price"&gt;Asus ROG Strix Scar 15&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="7lPrCK"&gt;The best laptop with flashy RGB&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="SK7elL"&gt;If you’re looking for a “traditional” premium gaming laptop with colorful, flashy panache, the ROG Strix Scar 15 is for you. The Strix’s keyboard isn’t just one of the most comfortable that we’ve ever tested on a gaming laptop; it also has some of the coolest per-key RGB lighting we’ve ever seen with all kinds of effects. There’s also a colorful light strip wrapped around the front of the deck (customizable as well) and a colorful glowing logo on the lid. In short: if you use this in public, people will notice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DZuwqX"&gt;Of course, the Strix is great on the inside as well, delivering some of the best frame rates you’ll find from a 15-inch laptop with Intel’s and Nvidia’s top chips. You’ll get the full benefit of their power with a 300Hz screen option as well. And the Strix comes preloaded with various programs to help customize your gaming experience. You can personalize color profiles, bandwidth allocation, and more based on the type of game you’re playing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="YAnMj2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10355468"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="lXUZkA"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best gaming laptop 2021: Alienware Area 51-m" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NZxevzR3kbj2DNb2IcI0Txno8vg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16006213/akrales_190403_3328_0066.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Alienware Area-51m is a hefty, brilliant gaming device.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vU9B3g"&gt;8. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/4/18294631/alienware-area-51m-review-gaming-laptop-specs-price-features"&gt;Alienware Area-51m&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="tCRMB0"&gt;A gaming laptop with desktop-class parts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="SH9RLt"&gt;If money and desk space are no objects for you, you might be interested in the Alienware Area-51m. This hefty rig is essentially a desktop in laptop form. It pairs a desktop-class processor and a full-power mobile GPU with a 17-inch display and a full-size keyboard, delivering true desktop performance in a chassis that’s still (technically) portable. PC enthusiasts will also appreciate that you can update many of the components yourself, including the processor, RAM, and storage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kkFbwO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10355482"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SpWBsS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hDnH2j"&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="XBQ0Fw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22295181/best-gaming-laptop"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22295181/best-gaming-laptop</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-05T12:55:26-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-05T12:55:26-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple will reportedly scan photos stored on iPhones and iCloud for child abuse imagery</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The iPhone 12, in blue." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KsFKmmiIIY2DKiRyCwL_H-zqdNk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69683696/vpavic_4243_20201018_0121.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Eo4wHZ"&gt;Apple plans to scan photos stored on iPhones and iCloud for child abuse imagery, &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/14440f81-d405-452f-97e2-a81458f5411f?accessToken=zwAAAXsXFw3Akc8URA-B1AVFL9OX4qgUWPVBHw.MEQCIAlL-dncQ3QfMOhh2uX_WQcMbz9dxjkEyYqIbvpX7pNnAiBPOFPraAkWgtfFk9Z_X3XiV5f1-mI4Mvos0mL8SCQqUg&amp;amp;sharetype=gift?token=076dc4a2-d758-4db8-8114-bc29b71cf72f"&gt;according the &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The new system could help law enforcement in criminal investigations but may open the door to increased legal and government demands for user data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qCd5ME"&gt;The system, called neuralMatch, will “proactively alert a team of human reviewers if it believes illegal imagery is detected, who would then contact law enforcement if the material can be verified,” the &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt; said. neuralMatch, which was trained using 200,000 images from the National Center for Missing &amp;amp; Exploited Children, will roll out first in the US. Photos will be hashed and compared with a database of known images of child sexual abuse. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="pv6k39"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The system will be used first in the US&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VByGry"&gt;“According to people briefed on the plans, every photo uploaded to iCloud in the US will be given a ‘safety voucher,’ saying whether it is suspect or not,” the &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt; said. “Once a certain number of photos are marked as suspect, Apple will enable all the suspect photos to be decrypted and, if apparently illegal, passed on to the relevant authorities.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="id__uo580rn63xk"&gt;John Hopkins University professor and cryptographer Matthew Green raised concerns about the system on Twitter Wednesday night. “This sort of tool can be a boon for finding child pornography in people’s phones,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/matthew_d_green/status/1423075906894106625"&gt;Green said&lt;/a&gt;. “But imagine what it could do in the hands of an authoritarian government?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XIfczG"&gt;“Even if you believe Apple won’t allow these tools to be misused [crossed fingers emoji] there’s still a lot to be concerned about,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/matthew_d_green/status/1423079067805495296"&gt;he added&lt;/a&gt;. “These systems rely on a database of ‘problematic media hashes’ that you, as a consumer, can’t review.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6eIhPA"&gt;Apple already checks iCloud files against known child abuse imagery, like every other major cloud provider. But the system described here would go further, allowing central access to local storage. It would also be trivial to extend the system to crimes other than child abuse — a particular concern given Apple’s extensive business in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c8MhAK"&gt;The company informed some US academics about it this week, and Apple may share more about the system “as soon as this week,” according to two security researchers who were briefed on Apple’s earlier meeting, the &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt; reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vurNuE"&gt;Apple has previously &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446220/apple-privacy-ad-video-ad-tracking-transparency"&gt;touted&lt;/a&gt; the privacy protections built into its devices, and famously &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/2/17/11036306/apple-fbi-iphone-encryption-backdoor-tim-cook"&gt;stood up to the FBI&lt;/a&gt; when the agency wanted Apple to build a backdoor into iOS to access an iPhone used by one of the shooters in the 2015 attack in San Bernardino. The company did not respond to a request for comment on the &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt; report.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611305/apple-scan-photos-iphones-icloud-child-abuse-imagery-neuralmatch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611305/apple-scan-photos-iphones-icloud-child-abuse-imagery-neuralmatch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-05T12:45:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-05T12:45:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>A recall of Philips respiratory devices has left users stranded</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Illustration of hand reaching to grab a CPAP mask that is dangling out of reach.&amp;amp;nbsp;" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/80TDLkZLtBVuRUdudn5LPz8qZvg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69683573/acastro_210805_4695_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Over a month after the recall, people who rely on ventilators, CPAPs, and BiPAPs are unsure what to do &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="8c52yj"&gt;Ingrid Tischer needs a machine to sleep. For nearly 30 years, she’s been using BiPAP devices, which push pressurized air into her lungs so she gets enough oxygen through the night. In June, a friend texted to tell her that Philips Respironics, one of the world’s biggest producers of respiratory devices, had recalled many of its ventilators, CPAPs, and BiPAPs. Her machine was on the list.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AwipFp"&gt;The realization was terrifying. “I’d gotten through the wildfires, the pandemic, and then suddenly, it’s like, oh, the monster is not dead yet,” says Tischer. “But it feels like the call is coming from inside the house. It’s not out there. It’s in my home and on my face every night.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="POYkIq"&gt;During its &lt;a href="https://www.philips.com/a-w/about/news/archive/corpcomms/news/press/2021/philips-first-quarter-results-2021.html"&gt;earnings report in late April&lt;/a&gt;, Philips noted concerns about the sound dampening foam in several of its machines. The foam could break down, sending debris and potentially toxic chemicals through the device’s airway that can then be swallowed or inhaled by the user. The degradation of the foam is exacerbated by high heat and humidity, worsening the risks for people in areas impacted by wildfires and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22547454/2021-heat-wave-temperature-high-heat-dome"&gt;record heatwaves&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PwZB2N"&gt;On June 14th, the company issued &lt;a href="https://www.usa.philips.com/healthcare/e/sleep/communications/src-update"&gt;a recall notice&lt;/a&gt; for over a dozen of its ventilators and BiPAP and CPAP machines, which are used by millions of people at home, in hospitals, and in care facilities across the country. One model, the E30 ventilator, was on the list of ventilators &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/medical-devices/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-emergency-use-authorizations-medical-devices/ventilators-and-ventilator-accessories-euas"&gt;granted Emergency Use Authorizations&lt;/a&gt; by the FDA during the pandemic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FL6KLF"&gt;The FDA &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/medical-devices/safety-communications/certain-philips-respironics-ventilators-bipap-and-cpap-machines-recalled-due-potential-health-risks#actions"&gt;gave the recall a Class I designation&lt;/a&gt;, the most serious type. The classification means there’s a reasonable probability that use of a recalled product “will cause serious adverse health consequences or death.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uhNgjW"&gt;Philips estimates that 3 to 4 million devices are in use globally, around half of which are in the US. “We fully understand the impact that this is having on patients,” says Philips. “Our priority is to replace the foam in all the affected devices either by repair or replacement with like devices with the new foam.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="5mq4oJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Respiratory equipment is not like a car that’s faulty”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="l3u7bl"&gt;Yet over a month after the recall, people who rely on these devices to breathe are still scrambling to figure out what to do. Philips recommends that people &lt;a href="https://www.philipssrcupdate.expertinquiry.com"&gt;register their devices&lt;/a&gt; and follow the advice of their doctors when deciding whether to continue using them. But most people who use these devices can’t go without them, even temporarily. Just one night without a BiPAP is detrimental to Tischer’s health, and other people need their ventilators around the clock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wM8AfU"&gt;“Respiratory equipment is not like a car that’s faulty,” says Tischer. “You can stop driving the car, but you can’t just postpone breathing. So we were given a really ridiculous thing that they called a choice, which was use it or don’t.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BjjhLN"&gt;Tischer was able to get a replacement after several calls with her medical equipment provider, insurance company, and doctor, but others haven’t been so lucky. Alice Wong, a disabled activist who uses two of the recalled ventilators, hasn’t gotten very far in her search for replacements. She received bacterial filters from her equipment provider, but the FDA hasn’t fully evaluated how effective such filters are for dealing with the degraded foam. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6gafwJ"&gt;The existence of the recall has been poorly communicated. Wong found out about it through a Facebook group for people with neuromuscular disabilities, not through her doctor or Philips. She &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SFdirewolf/status/1404817855464415234"&gt;tweeted a thread&lt;/a&gt; to spread the word and started the hashtag #SuckYouPhilips to collect people’s stories. Several people have described a frustrating loop of conversations with doctors, less than sympathetic medical equipment suppliers, and insurers, while often being unable to reach Philips through its hotline. “Many people are getting the runaround while a few were able to get a replacement machine from another manufacturer immediately,” says Wong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hk7uj4"&gt;Philips says it is “working to address this issue as expeditiously as possible,” and has increased the production capacity of repair kits and replacements. The company couldn’t offer a timeline, but says it is “in discussions with the relevant regulatory authorities to obtain authorization to start deploying the repair kits and replacement devices that we are already producing in large quantities.” Philips also says it has stopped taking orders for sleep therapy devices for new patients while production capacity is focused on repair and replacement efforts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="JP23Bt"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Disabled people have always been considered disposable by society”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JYaNm3"&gt;The slow and convoluted process hasn’t been enough. “Disabled people have always been considered disposable by society,” says Wong, “and this is another ugly example of it.” She and others are calling on Philips to be more transparent about its plans for repairs and replacements. She says the company should pay for comparable machines from other manufacturers, reimburse people who purchased additional equipment out of pocket, and staff its phone line with people who have thorough information and resources. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rKj5Dh"&gt;But even that wouldn’t address the larger problems at play. A small number of companies produce the majority of durable medical equipment like ventilators, and patients have little choice which machines they end up with based on their insurance. When one of those companies announces its products have dangerous defects, there’s not much of a contingency plan for the people who rely on them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="hL77ud"&gt;Wong is exhausted from &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/first-person/2020/4/4/21204261/coronavirus-covid-19-disabled-people-disabilities-triage"&gt;living through a pandemic as a ventilator user&lt;/a&gt;, and the recall of devices she needs to live is another massive source of stress. “I have to breathe,” she says, “but breathing from a machine pumping carcinogenic particles into my lungs is my only option?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WnqCpr"&gt;
&lt;script src="https://code.jquery.com/jquery-3.6.0.js" type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script&gt;$(".c-entry-hero__image").html('&lt;style&gt;.vrg-video-lede {max-width: 800px;margin: 0 auto;} .vrg-label {height: 1px;width: 1px;overflow: hidden;position: absolute;} .vrg-inner-container {height: 100%; position: relative;padding-bottom: 100%;overflow: hidden;}@media screen and (max-width:768px){.vrg-inner-container {height: 100%;}} .vrg-media {position: absolute;top: 0;left: 0;width: 100%;height: 100%;} .vrg-media img {height: 100%;width: 100%;max-width: 100%;position: absolute;top: 0;left: 0;object-fit: cover;} .vrg-media video {height: 100%;width: 100%;position: absolute;top: 0;left: 0;object-fit: cover;display: inline-block;}&lt;/style&gt;&lt;figure class="vrg-video-lede" aria-label="media" role="group"&gt;&lt;span class="vrg-label"&gt;Video&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class="vrg-inner-container"&gt;&lt;div class="vrg-media"&gt;&lt;img src="https://volume-assets.voxmedia.com/production/3a9296a025f29934822e4182d9f80641/acastro_210805_4695_square.jpg" alt="Illustration of hand reaching to grab a CPAP mask that is dangling out of reach. "&gt;&lt;video src="https://volume-assets.voxmedia.com/production/528e0174e002dc919881a2a97aca0015/acastro_210805_4695_square.mp4" muted="" loop="" autoplay="" playsinline=""&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;');&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22609651/philips-recall-respironics-ventilators-cpap-bipap"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22609651/philips-recall-respironics-ventilators-cpap-bipap</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kait Sanchez</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-05T12:28:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-05T12:28:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>Here’s a closer look at Apple’s canceled AirPower wireless charger</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QQOmG8rcOgnCV7MM-h483vOKNfg=/0x117:3696x2581/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69683450/IMG_9512.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A working Apple AirPower prototype unit. | Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/1nsane_dev" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Giulio Zompetti&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tAI3fQ"&gt;Apple’s AirPower wireless charger was supposed to arrive with the unique ability to charge an iPhone, Apple Watch, and AirPods all at the same time. Unfortunately, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/3/29/18287383/apple-airpower-wireless-charger-cancelled"&gt;Apple canceled AirPower in March 2019&lt;/a&gt;, citing difficulties in bringing the product to life. Since then, we’ve seen a &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2020/08/21/airpower-prototype-teardown-likely-shows-why-apple-never-shipped-the-wireless-charger/"&gt;teardown of AirPower&lt;/a&gt;, some &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/1/3/21047896/zens-liberty-airpower-clone-16-coils-wireless-charging-pad-mat"&gt;AirPower clones&lt;/a&gt;, and Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22576245/iphone-12-reverse-wireless-charging-magsafe-battery-pack"&gt;MagSafe battery packs&lt;/a&gt;. Now, an Apple prototype collector has obtained a working AirPower unit for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tsrd3I"&gt;Speaking to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, Giulio Zompetti, a 28-year-old from Italy, says he has been able to purchase a prototype AirPower unit from Chinese e-waste sources. “The unit lacks all of its exterior housing, and shows this beautiful and heavy stainless steel chassis,” says Zompetti.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SReGJYMIH7HhoqSVyid8OhAZSYs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22763582/airpowerprototype.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/1nsane_dev" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Giulio Zompetti&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The controller circuits on an AirPower prototype.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5xgt0x"&gt;In photos supplied to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, you can see the AirPower mat powering a prototype iPhone, with its 22 coils on the front-facing side and 22 controller circuits on the rear. In order for this AirPower prototype to work, it has to be paired with special prototype iPhone hardware to activate the coils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rmfnSg"&gt;“It doesn’t work with production devices, because the coils are woken up by the device,” explains Zompetti, who says he’s been able to charge two prototype devices simultaneously so far. Zompetti says he received the unit in December and was able to interact with it initially through a serial lightning cable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="smo4LO"&gt;“It’s an engineering prototype, it’s not meant for plug and play,” says Zompetti. “When I connected my serial lightning cable to it, I could see some chars on the log, so once I fixed the BAUD rate, I was able to read a comprehensible log.” There’s even an interactive shell to interact with the AirPower, as part of the engineering of the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="tFjSoS"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;AirPower &lt;a href="https://t.co/bv8gi0NiiL"&gt;pic.twitter.com/bv8gi0NiiL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Giulio Zompetti (@1nsane_dev) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/1nsane_dev/status/1423277245381054472?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 5, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YaNDpV"&gt;Apple’s canceled AirPower pad was supposed to let you drop devices anywhere on it to charge thanks to multiple coils, without having to find that specific sweet spot. But various reports suggested &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/17/17869072/apple-airpower-overheating-issues"&gt;Apple was struggling with overheating issues&lt;/a&gt; during development. “I wasn’t able to reproduce the issue but still can’t say it isn’t there,” says Zompetti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vl6GFv"&gt;While we haven’t been able to independently verify the AirPower device as it’s extremely rare, Zompetti has a history of collecting Apple prototype hardware. He’s been collecting devices since March 2018, including a &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/3a89w8/this-is-a-rare-prototype-of-the-first-apple-watch"&gt;rare prototype of the first Apple Watch&lt;/a&gt;. “It became my main passion since then to find the most good looking prototypes,” says Zompetti. He’s collected around 35 units so far, with a variety of rare iPhone and iPod prototypes in his collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hwOLl0"&gt;This passion has seen Zompetti travel to engineers for help repairing old devices. “It’s almost always about finding broken or incomplete units and fixing them to bring them back to life” says Zompetti. An unreleased AirPower device is “definitely among the best” prototype hardware he’s found so far, he says.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611234/apple-airpower-wireless-charger-working-prototype"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611234/apple-airpower-wireless-charger-working-prototype</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-05T12:15:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-05T12:15:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>AMD’s Ryzen 5000 processors with integrated graphics are now available to buy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UKf8Kr9W-_WIBI0JVezWjK5HEj8=/401x0:4720x2879/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69683350/586681_vermeer_03_0014_5K.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bxMFDH"&gt;In April, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382081/amd-ryzen-5000-processor-apu-gpu-cpu-chips-oem-prebuilt-graphics"&gt;AMD announced&lt;/a&gt; versions of its Ryzen 5000 desktop CPUs with integrated graphics cards, but it only made them available for prebuilt OEM systems, promising that it would sell the chips to consumers later this year. Well, “later this year” is today, with AMD now offering its &lt;a href="https://www.amd.com/en/processors/ryzen-with-graphics"&gt;Ryzen 5000 G-Series&lt;/a&gt; APUs to anyone to buy, not just multimillion-dollar PC manufacturers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rX9Frc"&gt;Right now, only two of the Ryzen 5000 G-Series chips are available to purchase on AMD’s website: the eight-core Ryzen 7 5700G for $359 and the six-core Ryzen 5 5600G for $259. Both chips, like the standard Ryzen 5000 CPUs, are built on AMD’s 7nm process with its Zen 3 architecture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="yKPU2I"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A good option if you don’t need a powerful GPU&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UpSjC6"&gt;Right now, AMD is just selling those two models (the more powerful options in the Ryzen 5000 G-Series lineup). The Ryzen 3 5300G and Ryzen 3 5300GE are still listed on AMD’s site as “OEM only,” and the 35W GE versions of the 5700G and 5600G don’t seem to be available to purchase yet either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZDfdME"&gt;The new chips are otherwise identical to the OEM counterparts that shipped earlier this year, meaning that they still use AMD’s older Vega graphics platform, not its cutting-edge RDNA / Navi process that’s found on the latest Radeon GPUs. But if you don’t need ultra-powerful graphics to run the latest AAA games at ultra settings, the new chips might be a good option to consider (especially considering how difficult it is to get ahold of a new GPU these days). &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611066/amd-ryzen-5000-g-series-processor-graphics-gpu-cpu"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611066/amd-ryzen-5000-g-series-processor-graphics-gpu-cpu</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-05T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-05T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Free Guy is like a AAA game: fun, goofy, and doing narrative backflips to make a guy the lead</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4K7-OAqBJo1cPW5A7JE1-pFjXyA=/0x0:3072x2048/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69683233/DF_14069_R.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Alan Markfield&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="M6Yxwj"&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Free Guy&lt;/em&gt;, Millie (Jodie Comer) is a game developer on the outs working to prove that publisher Antwan (a strutting Taika Waititi) illegally stole game code from her and her partner, Keys (Joe Keery) to create &lt;em&gt;Free City&lt;/em&gt;, the most popular video game in the world. She infiltrates the game, hunting for the evidence to prove that her original idea was stolen — evidence that she thinks is hidden somewhere deep inside the game itself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ozhST4"&gt;And you would think that the movie is about her, right? But &lt;em&gt;Free Guy&lt;/em&gt; seems more focused on offering up Ryan Reynolds guilelessly moseying across the screen as the titular Guy, in what feels like a version of &lt;em&gt;The Lego Movie&lt;/em&gt; that swaps “charming, stop-motion-style Lego animation” for “video games” and throws in a heavy dose of &lt;em&gt;The Truman Show&lt;/em&gt; for good measure. The result is an enjoyable — albeit weird — but largely forgettable summer action movie. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8uH9rfhPV1nmQvgsocm1Yp4Ya7I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22763528/DF_26555_R.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Alan Markfield / 20th Century Studios&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="yXZCap"&gt;Guy (Reynolds) is an oblivious NPC in &lt;em&gt;Free City&lt;/em&gt;, an incredibly popular video game that most accurately resembles &lt;em&gt;GTA Online&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;where human players run missions, robbing banks to get cash and generally causing mayhem. Guy, on the other hand, works at the bank, stamping generic forms and hanging out with his best friend, a security guard named Buddy (Lil Rel Howery.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mNZxGq"&gt;But then his life changes when he runs into Millie, who awakens Guy to the possibilities of breaking his daily grind and being “the good guy” in the video game world of murderers and thieves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1xmEGN"&gt;Reynolds is charming as ever, with &lt;em&gt;Free Guy&lt;/em&gt; lending him the feature-length chance to turn his affable social media persona into the walking version of a smiley face. The problem is that Guy’s blank slate doesn’t leave much room for him to be an actual character: his entire character arc is just “being helpful,” and all his wants and desires are ingrained in his programming. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bQ8vEY"&gt;Comer’s Millie — who has the benefit of actual agency and drive — ends up carrying the film both as her in-game action hero character and as a frustrated programmer who’s trying to fight for the right thing. Too bad the film is structured around Guy and his less than dynamic character arc. A version of this film might have existed where she was the narrative lead and he was the lovable side character, and it probably would have been a lot more fun.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XMtvofl69Y5BGSEAbBm3wrhVgbY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22763531/DF_29489_R.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Alan Markfield / 20th Century Studios&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SDySJH"&gt;While &lt;em&gt;Free Guy&lt;/em&gt; hides its heroine behind a charming Ryan Reynolds, it wears its gaming influences proudly: popular streamers like Ninja, Pokimane, Jacksepticeye, DanTDM, and LazarBeam all make appearances to comment on Guy’s in-game adventure and lend the fictional &lt;em&gt;Free City&lt;/em&gt; game the cachet of a real-world success like &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;GTA&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OUKwOH"&gt;As a whole, &lt;em&gt;Free Guy&lt;/em&gt; is most successful when it lampoons the psychopathic tendencies of video game players in a real-world perspective. Living in &lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;, where near-feral players tear through cities, murdering countless thousands of virtual avatars and causing wanton destruction, &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; be horrifying. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="S0Be5f"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Living in a video game would be horrifying&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="M1nxxe"&gt;Guy’s quest to be the good guy makes sense when faced with all that, but &lt;em&gt;Free Guy&lt;/em&gt; isn’t quite willing to commit to that idea, descending back to standard action movie fare as soon as it suits the plot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XpnWrf"&gt;And that inconsistency appears throughout the film. &lt;em&gt;Free Guy&lt;/em&gt;’s villain —  scenery-devouring Taika Waititi, who looks to be having the most fun of anyone in the film (which is saying something in a movie starring the perpetually sunny Reynolds) — gives not one, but two speeches about corporate greed and spinning out endless sequels with familiar characters and properties to make money off an existing stable of IP instead of making something new and original. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wcKob5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Free Guy&lt;/em&gt; positions this as an ostensibly bad thing — only for the film to spin on its heels and throw in some of the most egregious cross-promotional references this side of &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/movies/22577229/space-jam-a-new-legacy-review"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Space Jam: A New Legacy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in the final act. (It is possible to pinpoint the exact second of the post-production process that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/20/18273142/disney-fox-acquistion-final-hulu-marvel-streaming-21st-century"&gt;Disney’s acquisition of 20th Century Fox&lt;/a&gt; was completed.) &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Hy-MpnnIFYeypm9FTdbzgMfVUcc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22763534/DF_09845_R2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Alan Markfield / 20th Century Studios&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="brGpas"&gt;After months away from theaters, &lt;em&gt;Free Guy&lt;/em&gt; is definitely an enjoyable way to spend an hour or two at the movies. But, like an overproduced video game, it almost has too much stuff, bouncing between action and romance and comedy and screeds against making too many sequels to really do any one of those things overly well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="snpW3e"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Free Guy&lt;/em&gt; hits theaters on August 13th.&lt;/h4&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22611123/free-guy-review-ryan-reynolds-jodie-comer-video-game-movie"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22611123/free-guy-review-ryan-reynolds-jodie-comer-video-game-movie</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
