<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-07-23T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-23T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-23T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to use the Green Screen effect on TikTok </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The TikTok music note logo against a dark background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/51y2KwuzxSmlgPbWSqaCGdMQoB4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69621591/acastro_190723_1777_tiktok_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EiXu4T"&gt;Green screens used to be reserved for those with access to, well, a green screen. This method has been around for a long time: allowing creators to superimpose a photo or video onto a background in a film or video. Traditionally, that means using a setup that has a large sheet of (usually) green material behind the subject. The solid color makes it easy to digitally remove that color in post-production and add whatever image or video should be there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tiHGcQ"&gt;Now the idea of green screens has gone digital as a way to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/11/21173608/zoom-video-conference-how-to-virtual-background-greenscreen"&gt;hide backgrounds in meetings&lt;/a&gt; or to create fun videos on social media. TikTok has taken this idea and run with it by creating an effect within the app that does basically the same thing. While not as polished as a traditional green screen, it still gets the job done and allows the creator to remain on-screen while showing the audience an image in the background of the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sJrlyC"&gt;The effect is a great way to spice up a video and provide an interesting visual. I use it regularly on &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@verge?"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s TikTok&lt;/a&gt; so the audience can see whatever object or topic I’m discussing. Even though I usually rely on the basic green screen option, which adds a photo to the background, there are plenty of different effects to choose from. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DPkkKz"&gt;Here’s how you can do it in TikTok: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="szxdyH"&gt;Tap the + icon in the bottom center of the screen to create a new video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PAjHcF"&gt;Click “Effects” in the bottom left corner. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZuJgfE"&gt;Choose “Green Screen” from the menu. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WbhXph"&gt;Browse all of the Green Screen effects and decide which one best suits what you want to do with your video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HhdS2PPfMFWwVtuwieZfSypJVns=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22733102/IMG_8204.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are a lot of different Green Screen effects to choose from.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xoloqhSj1sCXnf5atSAH_y7bwKU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22733109/IMG_8205.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Whatever image you choose will become the background.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QVDP0Q"&gt;The most common effects used are the simplest: they add a photo or video to the background that stays in place as the subject moves around the frame. But there are others that you can try that get pretty creative. You can add an image as a sticker that can be resized and moved around, or you can superimpose an image over your clothing to change your look. There’s even a feature to add parts of your face to a photo just in case, say, you want to pretend your dog can talk. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xv8Kup"&gt;The options are limitless once you use a little imagination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xp29ZPXSmiXT_EKiMlla9CBpyvo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22733122/IMG_8210.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Turn your pet into a terrifying creature using the face green screen effect.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1s-jThhWpinQ86akGDST1Kiip2c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22733129/IMG_8211.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Change your outfit up using a photo or design.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="FWb8Ky"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"The Verge on TikTok","description":"Join us for TikToks about the future of technology and science","label":"Follow us!","url":"https://bit.ly/3ho6J5U"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lxywow"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="shuC81"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22588655/tiktok-green-screen-effect-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22588655/tiktok-green-screen-effect-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kaitlin Hatton</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-23T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-23T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Communication around masks is still terrible  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Hg878s1W4atqjwt3OIS3Bk1FZkA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69621598/acastro_200512_1777_faceMask_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2AWBkY"&gt;When the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22434645/vaccines-masks-social-distancing-cdc-covid"&gt;long-awaited guidelines&lt;/a&gt; in May for when vaccinated people could stop wearing masks, some experts cautioned that the changes were coming &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/05/17/997422911/cdc-criticized-for-confusing-updated-mask-recommendation"&gt;too soon&lt;/a&gt;. We were still learning more about the vaccine’s protection, and epidemiologists were worried about coronavirus variants. If mask rules were lifted and cases spiked again, reinstating them would be difficult. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c41kyx"&gt;Well, cases are now rising again across the country in a Delta variant-fueled surge, and that’s making mask recommendations just as difficult to handle as people feared. The surge is most devastating in places with low vaccination rates, but it’s also hitting states and counties where most adults are vaccinated. So not long after lifting mask mandates, some places — like Los Angeles county — are &lt;a href="https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2021-07-18/la-county-indoor-masks-will-people-follow-rule"&gt;reinstating them&lt;/a&gt;. The American Academy of Pediatrics split from the CDC’s guidance (unchanged since May) and is &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/all-children-should-wear-masks-school-fall-even-if-vaccinated-n1274358?cid=sm_npd_nn_tw_ma"&gt;recommending&lt;/a&gt; that even vaccinated adolescents and teens wear masks in schools this fall. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jhcKlE"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tedcruz/status/1416812217492811777"&gt;conservative pushback&lt;/a&gt; to masking policies is back, too. The Los Angeles sheriff says he &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/07/17/world/los-angeles-sheriff-mask.html"&gt;won’t enforce&lt;/a&gt; the county’s mask mandate. Texas Gov. Greg Abbott says he won’t reimpose statewide masking. It would be “inappropriate to require people who already have immunity to wear a mask,” he &lt;a href="https://www.click2houston.com/news/local/2021/07/21/despite-rise-in-covid-19-cases-gov-greg-abbott-says-he-will-not-impose-another-mask-mandate-in-texas/?utm_source=facebook&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_campaign=snd&amp;amp;utm_content=kprc2"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;KPRC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in Houston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="iqPQGZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9360449"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CZMPOg"&gt;People across the political spectrum are &lt;a href="https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2021-07-18/la-county-indoor-masks-will-people-follow-rule"&gt;frustrated&lt;/a&gt; about the constantly changing direction. This whiplash and confusion is just the latest chapter in the mask communications drama that’s been going on for more than a year. Here in the US, there’s been poor public health messaging around face coverings from the very beginning of the pandemic. In April 2020, the White House and CDC first pivoted from telling people to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; wear masks to telling them to wear them. The inconsistency was bad for public trust, Rob Blair, an assistant professor of political science and international and public affairs at Brown University, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/3/21206728/cloth-face-masks-white-house-coronavirus-covid-cdc-messaging"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; at the time&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ufY8VQ"&gt;“What we have is inconsistent messaging, sometimes from the same source,” Blair said. “What we have is utter cacophony. That’s detrimental not only for the quality of the response, but for trust more generally.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VnABf5"&gt;Over a year later, we’re facing the same cacophony. It doesn’t help that the messaging is more complicated now that vaccines are widely available. Masks may not be as critical for vaccinated people if case rates are low, but they’re important where cases are high or rising — even though vaccinated people are protected from the worst of the disease. Kids under 12 are at lower risk from COVID-19 than adults, but they can’t be vaccinated yet, and masks are a big way to protect them. Faced with a confusing back-and-forth, people who gleefully threw out their masks may be reluctant to put them back on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j2Y9zX"&gt;“I think people will be disappointed that folks were having some hope and seeing the light at the end of the tunnel — and this would be a suggestion that we’re taking a step back,” Marcus Plescia, chief medical officer at the Association of State and Territorial Health Officials, &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2021/07/19/mask-mandates-returning/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6tysx2"&gt;As jarring as it may be to start wearing masks in more places again, the fact is that they’re still one of the simplest ways to protect against the spread of this disease. There’s also no denying that they’re still a highly politicized culture war flashpoint. The early flubs by the CDC and the initial obstruction by the Trump White House set the foundation for the mask turmoil of the past year. Now, at a key juncture in the United States’ response to the pandemic, it’s just as messy and high-stakes as ever. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SWNikc"&gt;Here’s what else happened this week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gHfsse"&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="pQw18F"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.statnews.com/2021/07/19/delta-vaccines-new-phase-pandemic/?utm_content=bufferb26fb&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_campaign=twitter_organic"&gt;How Delta is pushing the U.S. into a new phase of the Covid-19 pandemic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;COVID-19 vaccines protect against the variant, but Delta spreads fast through the unvaccinated. People are still going to get seriously ill, but older people are more likely to be vaccinated — so younger people are the ones in the hospital. (Andrew Joseph / &lt;em&gt;Stat News&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hJ8Du4"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2021/07/19/1016005828/new-data-leads-to-rethinking-once-more-where-the-pandemic-actually-began"&gt;New Data Leads To Rethinking (Once More) Where The Pandemic Actually Began&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Data on early COVID-19 cases led evolutionary biologist Michael Worobey, an expert in pandemic origins, to conclude that a natural origin is the likeliest explanation for the origins of the coronavirus. He thinks it’s less likely that it came from a lab. (Michaeleen Doucleff / &lt;em&gt;NPR&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m4jzvs"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/07/20/us/politics/delta-variant-usa.html"&gt;The Delta variant makes up an estimated 83 percent of U.S. cases, the C.D.C. director says.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;The variant is highly contagious and spreading rapidly, especially in parts of the country with low vaccination rates. (Sheryl Gay Stolberg / &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="odMcn4"&gt;Development &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="A2EVIO"&gt;&lt;a href="https://khn.org/news/article/covid-vaccine-novavax-vaccination-effort-from-zero-to-not-quite-warp-speed/"&gt;Novavax’s Effort to Vaccinate the World, From Zero to Not Quite Warp Speed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;At one point, Novavax was a frontrunner in the COVID-19 vaccine race. But research delays and shortages of manufacturing materials were big setbacks. It’s still a good vaccine, but it’ll arrive later than hoped. (Sarah Jane Tribble and Rachana Pradhan / &lt;em&gt;Kaiser Health News&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PvwM4X"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.statnews.com/2021/07/20/states-are-sitting-on-millions-of-surplus-covid-19-vaccine-doses-as-expiration-dates-approach/"&gt;States are sitting on millions of surplus Covid-19 vaccine doses as expiration dates approach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;A large batch of Pfizer vaccines is set to expire in August unless data on its shelf stability lets the data be pushed back. Federal officials rejected states’ requests to send extra doses to other countries, &lt;em&gt;Stat News&lt;/em&gt; reports. (Olivia Goldhill / &lt;em&gt;Stat News&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="grbPRu"&gt;Perspectives &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="XktzNL"&gt;I’m admitting young healthy people to the hospital with very serious COVID infections...One of the last things they do before they’re intubated is beg me for the vaccine. I hold their hand and tell them that I’m sorry, but it’s too late.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="DNxBgY"&gt;— Brytney Cobia, a doctor in Alabama, &lt;a href="https://www.al.com/news/2021/07/im-sorry-but-its-too-late-alabama-doctor-on-treating-unvaccinated-dying-covid-patients.html"&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; in a Facebook post about the strain of caring for COVID-19 patients at this stage in the pandemic.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="IOqaIp"&gt;More than numbers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="4tzoD2"&gt;To the people who have received the 3.5 billion vaccine doses distributed so far — thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vdsoGE"&gt;To the more than 192,174,864 people worldwide who have tested positive, may your road to recovery be smooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SbHqHe"&gt;To the families and friends of the more than 4,130,345 people who have died worldwide — 609,879 of those in the US — your loved ones are not forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pYEI4E"&gt;Stay safe, everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Oj4SXs"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22588755/covid-mask-guidance-bad-delta-surge"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22588755/covid-mask-guidance-bad-delta-surge</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-23T07:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-23T07:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Fly a drone? The FAA’s new TRUST test is easy — and mandatory</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/B2CZlWRAfTaai8sJbiQ5BboQrn4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69621539/vpavic_201214_4405_0360.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Ryan Loughlin&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Every single recreational pilot in the US needs to take it ASAP&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="012Tqu"&gt;If you’ve flown a drone for fun in the USA anytime in the past month, chances are you were breaking the law. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="od63z9"&gt;That’s because on June 22nd, the FAA finally released a mandatory knowledge test every recreational pilot legally needs to complete. It’s called TRUST, short for The Recreational Unmanned Aircraft Systems Safety Test, and trust is the operative word since the FAA isn’t planning to start issuing $1,000+ fines right away. Authorities aren’t likely to stop you in the street. But they could. Legally, you now need to carry a test completion certificate to fly a drone for fun. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="86DCDl"&gt;The good news: The test is free, incredibly easy, teaches you the rules as you go, can be taken as many times as you want, and I’d be surprised if it takes you over 10 minutes to get a perfect score. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E8J0cP"&gt;After chatting with the FAA last week, here’s a brief FAQ we whipped up about the test, and most every other basic burning question about how to legally fly drones in the US. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="mjvfCQ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do I legally fly a drone in the US? TL;DR, please.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="CHQRmX"&gt;&lt;em&gt;If and only if&lt;/em&gt; you’re flying solely for fun, the federal government has a fairly small list of rules as of today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="M662lk"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://faadronezone.faa.gov/"&gt;Register your drone&lt;/a&gt; if it weighs more than 0.55 pounds (249g) and label your drone if so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Q8QPqT"&gt;Take the new mandatory test, and carry a copy of your completion certificate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BEILIL"&gt;Never let your drone out of your sight, unless you’ve got a buddy right next to you watching it the whole time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Ll3Fjp"&gt;Never fly over 400 feet above ground level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rua0X2"&gt;Never fly in controlled airspace (typically near airports, but check &lt;a href="https://www.faa.gov/uas/recreational_fliers/where_can_i_fly/b4ufly/"&gt;the B4UFLY app&lt;/a&gt;) without using the FAA’s electronic systems to get authorization first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ax99sS"&gt;Proactively stay away from any aircraft with an actual pilot; emergency response, law enforcement, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wv1XBt"&gt;Follow the safety guidelines of either the FAA or a “community-based organization.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="GeuRad"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What about flying at night, or over people, or into fireworks? Didn’t I hear those were all illegal? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rVLLiv"&gt;You might have, and there may be &lt;em&gt;local&lt;/em&gt; laws you’ll still need to follow. For example, many stadiums, parks (and &lt;a href="https://www.nps.gov/articles/unmanned-aircraft-in-the-national-parks.htm"&gt;all US national parks&lt;/a&gt;) have a ban on drones, and some places (like the state of Tennessee) don’t let you fly through fireworks, either. California doesn’t let you fly over another person’s property to snap photos of them, to ward off paparazzi. Here are &lt;a href="https://jrupprechtlaw.com/drone-laws-state/"&gt;a couple&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://uavcoach.com/drone-laws-california/"&gt;handy collections&lt;/a&gt; of drone laws by state. Most orgs also frown on flying under the influence, near power lines, or other dangerous behavior, and you’ll want to &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/04/us/elegant-tern-eggs-drone-crash-california.html"&gt;stay &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; away from protected wildlife.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UF9n3A"&gt;But flying at night, or over people? Those aren’t necessarily against federal law if you’re flying for fun — only if you’re making money with your drone under the FAA’s Part 107 instead. And even Part 107 pilots have been able to do those things &lt;a href="https://www.faa.gov/uas/commercial_operators/operations_over_people/"&gt;since April 2021&lt;/a&gt;, as long as they follow &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203398/faa-remote-id-rules-location-night-over-people"&gt;certain additional rules&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="037sm9"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do I never let a drone out of my sight if I’m flying it through my smartphone screen? Or an FPV headset?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qJPAph"&gt;Yeah, I’ve had a pretty hard time with this myself. But it’s also something the FAA’s been pretty clear about for years — it expects you, or a “visual observer” right next to you, to be able to see the drone with your naked eye at all times. It’s known as the visual line of sight rule, or VLOS for short. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4xV7WP"&gt;It makes sense, because it’s still the best way to avoid mid-air collisions right now. Your FPV camera can only face forward, but your drone can move in any direction. And while pricey drones with ADS-B sensors can provide early warnings about manned aircraft, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22234029/faa-american-robotics-beyond-visual-line-of-sight-remote-observer-waiver"&gt;automatic sense-and-avoid is rare&lt;/a&gt;. Even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/11/21009994/skydio-2-review-self-flying-autonomous-drone-camera-crash-proof-price"&gt;self-flying drones like Skydio&lt;/a&gt;, with cameras pointed every which way, aren’t generally programmed to dodge other aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7YeSUBed-jrMrCglJAzXjw3SRYc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22338217/vpavic_4455_20210227_0063.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An FPV headset by DJI.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="t2S8Hs"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does that mean I’m breaking the law if I set a self-flying drone to “follow me” mode?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tHNlcz"&gt;Technically, yes. The FAA says unless you’re looking backwards the whole time or have a visual observer following you, too, you’re not maintaining visual line of sight, and you don’t know if there are other aircraft your drone might hit (or that might hit your drone). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fqOxwZ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s talk about the test. Why do I have to immediately take a mandatory test I’ve never heard of before?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5moaiH"&gt;It came as a surprise to me too! Technically, it was supposed to be here long ago. When Congress reauthorized the FAA’s authority in 2018, it carved out a new chunk of law to make it easier for people to fly drones for fun — as long as they passed an “aeronautical knowledge and safety test” that the agency had 180 days to deliver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hSZtMX"&gt;It’s been a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; longer than 180 days, but the test is here now, and the FAA is encouraging every single drone pilot to take it as soon as possible — and carry proof of completion with you. Unless you’ve got a fancier remote pilot certificate like Part 107, anyhow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QLoMk4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What, is the FAA going to fine me if I don’t carry a card? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qmV92Z"&gt;It absolutely could, even if it’s not terribly likely. The FAA says it’s not like they’re out there writing tickets, and the goal is education. If you aren’t familiar with the law and don’t have a certificate to show, the plan is to explain it to you first. Oh, and you can just save a photo of the card in your phone; a digital copy is good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nleaOF"&gt;But if you’re openly flaunting the law and refuse to take the test, the agency can fine you up to a maximum of $1,548 per violation, possibly including Part 107 violations that you wouldn’t normally worry about when flying for fun. That’s because you’re not actually covered under the recreational exception if you don’t complete the test, the FAA tells us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WqXcSg"&gt;Just take the test. It’s so ridiculously easy to comply, you should just get it over with now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PFh4bw"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How easy are we talking?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SP40BG"&gt;Here’s a sample question. You tell me: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="Ch1tDk"&gt;True or false: checking your drone after each flight is a good idea because it is a time when damage can be identified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1XvXf-cCR2rz0kxL8h9cx6ZHzQ8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22735175/checking_your_drone.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A sample TRUST question.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5RZlDz"&gt;The entire test took me around eight minutes to complete, including the time it took to snap a few screenshots. There’s no need to study, either: the test itself shows you the material, then quizzes you immediately after to see if you were paying attention. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y2TYfx"&gt;Also... I’m not sure you can fail? Each quiz points out which answers you got wrong and why, and you can just take it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NXbCKe"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I see. So... where can I take the TRUST test?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bzidHg"&gt;The FAA keeps an updated list of partner websites &lt;a href="https://www.faa.gov/uas/recreational_fliers/knowledge_test_updates/"&gt;right here&lt;/a&gt;, and you can pick whichever you like best. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ozZOmt"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does the FAA keep a log of who’s taken the test?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sz0J6t"&gt;Not at all, they say. Your certificate doesn’t expire, either, because the FAA doesn’t keep track of anything beyond a unique number generated at the time you take the test. “Neither the test administrator, nor the FAA, will maintain personally identifiable information about the recreational flyer so it is not possible to re-print or re-issue your original certificate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eHl4AM"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If Congress mandated this test in 2018, have I been breaking the law by flying drones before now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w1BAYD"&gt;You couldn’t take a test that didn’t exist. Until now, the FAA says, it was good enough to register your drone and follow either the FAA’s published safety guidelines or those of an established aeronautical organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CPhaoR"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I need to register my drone? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xSVAtu"&gt;Yes — unless it weighs less than 0.55 pounds (249g), like a lot of toy-grade drones and lightweight prosumer craft like the Hubsan Zino Mini Pro and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22277238/dji-mini-2-drone-review-price-specs-features"&gt;DJI’s Mini 2&lt;/a&gt;, which we recently called our favorite drone under $500. If it weighs more, you need to register them and label them with your registration number. FAA pro tip: recreational fliers can re-use the same registration number for every drone they own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zThSUL"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doesn’t the recreational exception under 49 US &lt;/strong&gt;§ &lt;strong&gt;44809&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;state you need to register your drone, period, regardless of how much it weighs?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BQFaLT"&gt;Well, aren’t you well-read! But no, the FAA isn’t suddenly forcing your Mavic Mini into a federal database — I asked, and the agency told me straight-up you still don’t need to register drones under 0.55 pounds. (Legal eagles can follow § 44809 to § 441 and then to &lt;a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/cfr/text/14/48.15"&gt;14 CFR 48.15 subpart (b)&lt;/a&gt;, which says that registration isn’t required if you’re flying a sub-0.55 lbs drone under § 44809 anyways.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QcQ1mE"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can I flash my test completion certificate to anyone complaining about my drone?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l1Fw7I"&gt;I guess you could try? The FAA and law enforcement can ask you to show proof of completion, but it’s not a license. If authorities or even local custodians tell you to leave because your drone is bugging people, maybe don’t give the flying community a bad name by insisting you have rights. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fDwESo"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m vaguely near an airport. Can I still fly my drone? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sgOwJD"&gt;It really depends on the airport, but if you’re not in the immediate flight path(s) or very close to the facilities, there’s a decent chance you can apply for an automatic airspace authorization just by tapping your info into a smartphone app &lt;a href="https://www.faa.gov/uas/programs_partnerships/data_exchange/"&gt;that supports LAANC&lt;/a&gt;, like Aloft or AirMap. (You’ll find more at that LAANC link.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AGfIKi4ZtIpPrQIE6as3s4W5rNc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22735190/0_height.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Feels bad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jHUwUD"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m not particularly close to an airport, but that LAANC app is telling me I can’t fly higher than 0 feet in my own backyard. WTF?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o4Ee6c"&gt;Ever heard the idea that the FAA has jurisdiction all the way down to the tip of a blade of grass? In your case, it might actually be true, and you won’t be able to legally fly even if you’ve got tall trees surrounding your house. It’s not that your drone would necessarily be dangerous below the treeline, but that there might not be enough of a safe buffer if your drone takes off in a direction you &lt;em&gt;didn’t&lt;/em&gt; intend for it to go, the FAA explains. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ccs3ay"&gt;It’s about risk mitigation, giving everyone time to alter course to avoid a collision. Or at least that’s the idea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qvImzS"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B4UFLY says there’s a TFR. What’s that?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PJkKBN"&gt;That’s a Temporary Flight Restriction, and you’ll want to obey. You don’t want to be the one whose drone got shot down for threatening a government official or interfering with an emergency operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qHfroK"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are drone laws really this simple now: take a 10-minute test, check an app, stay under 400 feet, never look away, don’t do anything stupid? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="mbU6eD"&gt;For now, if you’re flying for fun. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203398/faa-remote-id-rules-location-night-over-people"&gt;But just you wait until 2023&lt;/a&gt;, when many existing drones will need to be retrofitted to broadcast your location, your drone’s location, registration number, altitude, and speed — or else only fly in designated safe areas. &lt;a href="https://www.faa.gov/uas/getting_started/remote_id/"&gt;The Remote ID rule&lt;/a&gt; is currently scheduled to take full force in September 2023.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22589429/how-to-fly-drone-united-states-usa-trust-faa"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22589429/how-to-fly-drone-united-states-usa-trust-faa</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-23T07:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-23T07:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple MagSafe Battery Pack review:  convenience over capacity</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Perfectly designed for the iPhone, but not a lot of charge&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="mv1rms"&gt;Apple’s new MagSafe Battery Pack is a white rectangle you can stick to the back of an iPhone 12 to charge it. It’s Apple’s third run at designing an external battery solution for the iPhone and I like it better than the earlier battery cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="exfu7u"&gt;However, anybody considering spending $99 on this battery ought to keep one important fact in mind: even Apple cannot break the laws of physics. It is just as bound by the same rules of magnetism and electrons as everybody else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dOZZHa"&gt;Those laws require tradeoffs: A battery that could fully charge up most iPhone 12 models would be big. A battery small enough to not look odd on a phone wouldn’t have enough juice. Plus, electrons can only flow so fast without building up heat and degrading the battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="35Ynq9"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple can’t defeat the laws of physics&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QZnHT6"&gt;Apple found a balance between all those extremes and it maintains that balance with a tight software integration that aggressively manages how this battery charges your phone. The result is a gadget that’s singularly focused on the iPhone — sometimes to its own detriment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PPVBma"&gt;The best part about the MagSafe Battery is that it also serves as a fast-charging wireless MagSafe puck when it’s plugged in. So the big question is whether all that is enough to justify the price, especially compared to the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="IkVgoJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10664255"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="CY6cYp"&gt;The MagSafe Battery doesn’t have enough energy to fully charge an iPhone 12 Mini from zero to 100 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aDUiI9"&gt;In my testing, the MagSafe Battery was fully drained when my iPhone 12 Mini reached 83 percent, which took 130 minutes of charging. I didn’t have it plugged in for this test, which meant it charged at a relatively pokey 5W speed, so as to minimize heat and maximize the battery’s longevity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RJY99r"&gt;I used the iPhone very sporadically during the charging period (mostly to record the results every 15 minutes), though I did listen to a 15-minute podcast over Bluetooth which slowed the charging down a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4MSIBi"&gt;Bottom line: it’s a small battery and it will help you top up your iPhone, not fully charge it. On larger iPhone 12 models, it won’t even hit that 83 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;
&lt;aside id="3oG47H"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It performs better than its 1,460mAh rating would suggest&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The screen that appears when you attach the MagSafe Battery" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hHfQPO9Akof4nKcvPy2tOkdDU2w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22733362/DSC02778_dbohn_verge.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The screen that appears when you attach the MagSafe Battery.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The MagSafe Battery Pack on an iPhone 12 Pro Max" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sGKgdGSoVtUCmkvmzsTidUJvvb4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22733367/DSC02789_dbohn_verge.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The MagSafe Battery Pack on an iPhone 12 Pro Max.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RTf0Fe"&gt;There is a discussion to have about what the right way to talk about battery size is. The MagSafe Battery only has a 1,460mAh battery, but that number isn’t comparable to other batteries because it can push through more volts (7.62V). So the MagSafe Battery’s rated 11.13Wh (Watt-hours) is the number that actually matters. Meanwhile, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08TW7BRTJ/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Anker makes a 5,000mAh battery with wireless charging&lt;/a&gt; and magnets for under $50. It’s rated at 18.5Wh, so the differences are smaller than they first appear. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s5jxgt"&gt;The battery measurement discussion is interesting, but it doesn’t change the fact that the MagSafe Battery is simply small. It’s meant to be pocketable and easy to carry, and so you should think of it as something that can stretch your battery life just a little — not get you through multiple days away from a charger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="10L4qZ"&gt;As you might expect, the software experience with the MagSafe Battery is tightly integrated into the iPhone. There are big animations that show the charge of both your phone and the battery when you attach it. It shows up on the battery level widget, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0D1sYM"&gt;More interestingly, when you first attach the battery, your iPhone will pop up a notice that this battery won’t charge your phone above 90 percent — by design. Those last few percentage points put a lot of stress on batteries, and in this context it’s just not worth it. I think it’s a smart move, but if you absolutely want that last 10 percent, you can long press the battery icon in the Control Center and tell it to charge past 90 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="An Anker battery next to the MagSafe Battery" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lpqMfamewmQtoxQWS4fzM2o6JSY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22733391/DSC02736_dbohn_verge.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An Anker battery next to the MagSafe Battery.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Anker battery is a bit larger, but it also has a larger battery inside." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/g2C2x6Q9ZfJwS723cnSduTH_uyE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22733395/DSC02737_dbohn_verge.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Anker battery is a bit larger, but it also has a larger battery inside.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YkVmQo"&gt;I know this sounds both complicated and disappointing, but in use it’s actually the opposite. I would just slap the battery on the back of my phone when I was worried about battery life and didn’t sweat the details. The result was not needing to keep an eye on battery life as much as I usually do. It’s elegant instead of powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I63fDm"&gt;That’s all smart, but it only happens with the iPhone. It is certainly a nicer overall experience than you’d get with the Anker battery, which is thicker to boot. But the Anker has other advantages. Its battery is bigger, for one thing. It also has a USB-C port on it that both takes charge when plugged in &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; can be used to charge devices via a wire. It’s less elegant for iPhone users, but it’s much more versatile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="brd6xx"&gt;The Lightning port on the bottom of the MagSafe Battery means iPhone users can keep using the same charging cable, so it’s probably the right call to keep it. It’s just too bad that Lightning can’t charge in either direction like a USB-C port can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Apple MagSafe Battery Pack nearly perfectly fits the iPhone 12 Mini" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JtsqaOrbK1sEKzSO_o-PStYZwqE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22733335/DSC02729_dbohn_verge.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Apple MagSafe Battery Pack nearly perfectly fits the iPhone 12 Mini.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="klt8W8"&gt;The MagSafe Battery is designed to match the dimensions of the iPhone 12 Mini perfectly. It aligns exactly to the edges and is more comfortable to hold than I expected. If you have a larger iPhone, it will sit on the back a bit more awkwardly — it looks positively tiny on the iPhone 12 Pro Max. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;
&lt;aside id="OC1jUe"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Every battery pack looks silly attached to a phone&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The MagSafe Battery Pack looks a little funny on an iPhone 12 Pro Max" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qN3kfAlg7EpFcCtrEkA3jsg5da4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22733380/DSC02786_dbohn_verge.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The MagSafe Battery Pack looks a little funny on an iPhone 12 Pro Max.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1yuxtv"&gt;I &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/backlon/status/1417548597785202689"&gt;polled Twitter for questions&lt;/a&gt; about the battery and I was taken aback by the vitriol I saw in my replies — and elsewhere. It’s easy to make fun of how a battery pack looks on the back of a phone. It’s also easy to go after it for not providing enough charge. Having used it, I’m not sure I’d want it any larger and I certainly wouldn’t want it any smaller. To me, there’s no such thing as a good-looking external battery. At the end of the day, they’re all squarish or oblong hunks of plastic or metal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yodY2M"&gt;The white plastic has a matte finish that helps a little with grip, but I wouldn’t call it soft touch. I do wonder if it’ll pick up stains from blue jeans over time, but in the few days I’ve been testing it, it’s remained clean. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vJkFgB"&gt;It snaps on the back of a caseless iPhone with a satisfying snick. It’s as secure as I think can be fairly expected from something connected with magnets. It’d be nice if the alignment magnet was a little stronger, but I am glad that my iPhone doesn’t contain magnets so strong that it messes with credit cards. Physics!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8gnySp"&gt;You can intentionally shake off the battery or have it slip off when putting it in your pocket, but I didn’t have those problems. However, if you are planning on using it with a case, you absolutely need a MagSafe compatible case that itself has magnets on it. I use a very thin plastic case and that minimal layer was more than enough to stop the magnets from working effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The MagSafe Battery Pack shows how much charge it has left in an iPhone widget" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r2O_OrQpi14EUvmfjoI85z4PHeA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22733340/DSC02781_dbohn_verge.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The MagSafe Battery Pack shows how much charge it has left in an iPhone widget.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="Q6FsGU"&gt;After two days testing a couple different MagSafe Batteries on both an iPhone 12 Mini and iPhone 12 Pro Max, I came to a surprising conclusion. My favorite part isn’t the battery, it’s the MagSafe charger. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j4oeA8"&gt;When I think of the MagSafe Battery as a MagSafe charging puck that just happens to have a battery attached to it, I think it makes a little more sense as a product. Apple’s MagSafe puck costs $40 — that certainly doesn’t make the $99 asking price for this battery a deal, but it might be worth buying the battery instead of the puck for some people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aEKKns"&gt;I do have to point out that for $99 I would have expected Apple to at least include a Lightning cable. It doesn’t, nor does it include a charging brick. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wyPkVs"&gt;When plugged into a powerful enough wall charger, the MagSafe Battery can charge the phone at up to 15W, just like the standard MagSafe disc. The charger can fill up both itself and your iPhone. If you want to prioritize charging speed on the iPhone, you can plug &lt;em&gt;it&lt;/em&gt; in instead and then the iPhone will use reverse wireless charging to top up the battery. (Unfortunately and unlike Android phones, the iPhone’s reverse wireless charging doesn’t work for other devices, like AirPods.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The MagSafe Battery Pack can also wirelessly charge AirPods" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-CjsYo_ztMxG5Gs0F81pBS-1Azg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22733349/DSC02759_dbohn_verge.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The MagSafe Battery Pack can also wirelessly charge AirPods.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="p4evuG"&gt;The MagSafe Battery’s best feature is that it is a good MagSafe wireless charger. It’s also a decent battery — but only if you think of it as a small extender, one that trades longevity for size. Do I wish it had more capacity? Of course. I also wish it could have more capacity without getting any larger than it already is. I don’t begrudge physics and I get why Apple chose the size it did. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sk8y9b"&gt;But paying $99 for all the MagSafe Battery’s elegance and integration doesn’t make sense when there are much cheaper options that are less beholden to working with just one phone. A battery pack is going to look silly no matter what, you might as well get one that’s as versatile as possible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="cqxpBw"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="9wCW5f"&gt;Related: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="e4Xo0r"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Apple’s MagSafe Battery Pack doesn’t provide a lot of juice, but it sure is nice to use #shorts|103140" data-volume-uuid="06b797d44" data-volume-id="103140" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-228" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="93IP0G"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4MbIiO"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22588777/apple-magsafe-battery-review-size-iphone-12-mini"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22588777/apple-magsafe-battery-review-size-iphone-12-mini</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-23T06:34:22-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-23T06:34:22-04:00</updated>
    <title>MagSafe Battery Pack teardown confirms dual-cell design</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V9rYSCHC435mwbloA9qNNcfMKdA=/1x0:2149x1432/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69621406/J4hYWZ4XRA.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Screenshot: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p1hjrdPuMGo" target="_blank"&gt;Charger Lab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zWfE7C"&gt;A teardown of Apple’s new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575678/apple-magsafe-battery-pack-iphone-12-pro-mini-max"&gt;$99 MagSafe Battery Pack&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p1hjrdPuMGo"&gt;Charger Lab&lt;/a&gt; has given us our best look yet inside the new accessory, and revealed more details about how it works. For starters, it confirms recent speculation that it uses a pair of battery cells wired in series like &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ifixit.com%2FNews%2F34004%2Fthis-x-ray-teardown-really-smarts-iphone-11-smart-battery-cases&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F7%2F23%2F22590033%2Fmagsafe-battery-pack-teardown-dual-cell-design" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple’s previous Smart Battery cases&lt;/a&gt;, but it also gives us a look at the NFC circuitry and heat shielding within. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DguWsG"&gt;A dual-cell design is important, because it allows the voltage of the battery pack to be higher than a comparable single-cell design. While each individual cell is labelled as being 3.82 volts, the overall voltage of the battery pack is 7.62 with them wired in series. It means the pack should be capable of supplying more power than its 1,460mAh capacity would suggest when compared directly with the battery capacities of the iPhone itself, with a total power output of 11.13Wh. &lt;a href="https://appleinsider.com/articles/21/07/14/apples-magsafe-battery-pack-has-more-capacity-than-it-seems---heres-why"&gt;&lt;em&gt;AppleInsider&lt;/em&gt; has a good writeup&lt;/a&gt; of the science if you’re after more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TC4HBNfTLHpeD7OPmXiGfNZMv0g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22735219/J4hYWZ4XRA.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p1hjrdPuMGo" target="_blank"&gt;Charger Lab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The dual-cell design of the MagSafe Battery Pack.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="3qrhmO"&gt;Beyond the battery cells, the teardown gives us a good look at how the battery pack dissipates heat. In February, when &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/22290938/apple-magsafe-iphone-battery-pack-report"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; first reported&lt;/a&gt; the existence of the pack, it noted that development had been set back because the iPhone’s software kept thinking the accessory was overheating. It’s unclear if this problem was overcome with software or hardware fixes, but clearly a lot of effort has gone into keeping the pack cool while allowing it to supply enough power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="61wG0z"&gt;Unlike the right-to-repair advocates over at iFixit, Charger Lab doesn’t offer a repairability score at the end of its teardowns. But the amount of adhesive and concealed tabs holding the battery pack together don’t make it look very user serviceable. We’ll have more details on how it performs in practice in our forthcoming review.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/23/22590033/magsafe-battery-pack-teardown-dual-cell-design"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/23/22590033/magsafe-battery-pack-teardown-dual-cell-design</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-23T05:30:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-23T05:30:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>Arm’s cheap and flexible plastic microchip could create an ‘internet of everything’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rdthMNgd2zLNwWscUQPClfIr-KM=/0x84:2000x1417/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69621310/pragmatic_arm_plasticarm_plastic_chip_flexible.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Plastic chips would be flexible and cheap; meaning they could be printed pretty much anywhere. &lt;/em&gt; | Image: PragmatIC&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Jnb2rP"&gt;If you think microchips are ubiquitous now, appearing in everything from washing machines to lampposts, just wait until circuits can be printed onto plastic, paper, and fabric for the price of pennies. That’s what chip designer Arm is promising, with the company this week unveiling a new prototype &lt;a href="https://community.arm.com/developer/research/b/articles/posts/plasticarm-realising-the-full-potential-of-the-internet-of-things?"&gt;plastic-based microchip named PlasticARM&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SBhdBK"&gt;This isn’t the first flexible chip we’ve seen, but it is the most complex. PlasticARM contains a 32-bit Cortex-M0 CPU (the cheapest and simplest processor core in Arm’s Cortex-M family), as well as 456 bytes of ROM and 128 bytes of RAM. It’s comprised of over 18,000 logic gates, which Arm says is at least 12 times more than the previous plastic-based chip. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BKcUYg"&gt;The chip was designed in coordination with flexible electronics maker PragmatIC, and as the company’s designers explain in a &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-021-03625-w"&gt;paper published in &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, it doesn’t yet have the same functionality of silicon-based designs. For example, it’s only capable of running a trio of test programs hardwired into its circuits during fabrication, though Arm’s researchers say they’re working on future versions that will allow new code to be installed. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5KJMwIPh47KQ_T18v08MDmAogsk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22735203/plasticarm.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Arm&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Arm’s PlasticARM chip isn’t the fastest or most efficient, but it is the most flexible. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="O2EsHY"&gt;What makes PlasticARM and similar chips so special is their use of flexible components; in this case, metal-oxide thin-film transistors or TFTs. These can be printed onto surfaces that bend and flex without degrading, unlike processors based on brittle silicon substrates. This makes it possible to cheaply print processors onto materials like plastic and paper. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x5jmJ5"&gt;As Arm’s researchers explain in their paper, this would allow microchips to be put to all sorts of uses that would seem wasteful today. You might have chips printed into every milk bottle for example that detect spoilage, replacing the use of sell-by-dates. Arm says this will create a new “internet of everything,” with chips integrated into “more than a trillion inanimate objects over the next decade.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FE9v4g"&gt;Plastic-based chips have major drawbacks, though, and will certainly not replace silicon processors in the short term. They’re simply too inefficient in terms energy consumption, density, and performance. PlasticARM consumes 21 milliwatts of power, for example, but 99 percent of that is essentially wasted, with only 1 percent captured for computation. The chip is also comparatively large, with an area of 59.2 square millimeters. As noted by &lt;a href="https://www.anandtech.com/show/16837/plasticarm-get-your-next-cpu-without-silicon"&gt;&lt;em&gt;AnandTech&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, that’s around 1,500 times the size of a silicon-based Cortex M0 processor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dIbAKu"&gt;As Arm research engineer James Myers &lt;a href="https://www.newscientist.com/article/2284533-flexible-computer-processor-is-the-most-powerful-plastic-chip-yet/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;New Scientist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: “It won’t be fast, it won’t be energy efficient, but if I’m going to put it on a lettuce to track shelf life, that’s the idea.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/23/22590001/arm-plasticarm-cheap-flexible-plastic-microchip-internet-of-everything"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/23/22590001/arm-plasticarm-cheap-flexible-plastic-microchip-internet-of-everything</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-23T04:41:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-23T04:41:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>MacBook Air with 13-inch Mini LED display reportedly on the way for 2022</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tShVSGHktqXlxZJTYfxLn3SW0WA=/2x0:2039x1358/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69621226/vpavic_4291_20201113_0337_Edit.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 2020 MacBook Air. &lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ImFNZq"&gt;Apple plans to announce a redesigned MacBook Air with a 13.3-inch Mini LED display in the middle of 2022, according to a new investor note from reliable Apple analyst Ming-Chi Kuo seen by &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/07/22/kuo-apple-to-announce-new-macbook-air-with-13-inch-mini-led-display-in-mid-2022/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/07/22/mini-led-macbook-air-mid-2022/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The prediction is in line with Kuo’s &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/03/18/kuo-macbook-air-mini-led-2020-launch/"&gt;previous reports&lt;/a&gt;, but offers a more specific timeframe. It also suggests the new Air will have a slightly smaller display than the 14- and 16-inch MacBook Pros that are said to be on the way this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OWwrr6"&gt;Mini LED is a relatively new display technology that’s designed to offer some of the benefits of OLED — such as better contrast levels and improved dynamic range — without the risks of burn-in. It made its Apple debut &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22395449/apple-ipad-pro-2021-liquid-retina-xdr-mini-led-explainer"&gt;on this year’s 12.9-inch iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt;. Kuo has previously listed around &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/3/21163328/apple-macbook-pro-14-inch-imac-ipad-pro-mini-led-ming-chi-kuo"&gt;half a dozen Apple devices&lt;/a&gt; scheduled to migrate to the new displays, including a 27-inch iMac Pro, 14.1-inch MacBook Pro, 16-inch MacBook Pro, 10.2 iPad, and 7.9-inch iPad Mini. Apple is able to include the more premium displays because of cost-savings associated with using its own silicon, &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2020/12/02/kuo-two-macbook-pros-2021-and-macbook-air-2022/"&gt;according to Kuo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="hKFOye"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A new display, alongside MagSafe charging and a more powerful processor&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tQM0F2"&gt;Alongside the new display technology, the upcoming MacBook Air will &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/22/22244011/apple-new-macbook-air-design-magsafe-charger-report"&gt;reportedly feature  MagSafe charging&lt;/a&gt;, a thinner and lighter design, as well as two USB 4 ports. &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-18/apple-readies-macbook-pro-macbook-air-revamps-with-faster-chips?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; previously reported&lt;/a&gt; that the new Air will be powered by a “direct successor” to this year’s M1 processor. The new chip is said to include the same number of CPU cores, running at faster speeds, and an increased number of GPU cores. The current M1 processor is available with seven or eight GPU cores, while the new model will reportedly include nine or 10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AesMuF"&gt;The new MacBook Air is likely to follow &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22232393/macbook-pro-2021-arm-intel-touch-bar-magsafe-kuo"&gt;revamped MacBook Pros&lt;/a&gt;, due to arrive in the third quarter of this year. The laptops will reportedly be available with 14 or 16-inch displays (Mini LED, &lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/07/09/kuo-redesigned-macbook-pro-coming-later-this-year-with-mini-led-macbook-air-with-new-display-in-2022/"&gt;according to Kuo&lt;/a&gt;) with a new, more squared off design. MagSafe charging, HDMI ports, and SD card slots, are also &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-18/apple-readies-macbook-pro-macbook-air-revamps-with-faster-chips?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;said to be included&lt;/a&gt;. The MacBook Pro’s much derided OLED touch bar, could also finally be dropped with these models.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/23/22590004/macbook-air-mini-led-display-apple-silicon-2022-redesign"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/23/22590004/macbook-air-mini-led-display-apple-silicon-2022-redesign</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-23T00:01:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-23T00:01:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>GM’s Super Cruise getting fully automatic, hands-free lane changes and more for 2022</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NtI58S7AT2gDrUEVrpNsjb0CPOs=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69620839/2022_GMC_Sierra_Super_Cruise_Trailering_and_Automoatic_Lane_Change.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yIWT3A"&gt;General Motors’ Super Cruise, one of the best advanced driver assist systems on the market, is getting a big upgrade for 2022 and will be available on way more vehicles — including, for the first time, the Chevrolet Silverado and GMC Sierra half-ton pickup trucks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xYTLyO"&gt;To test out the new stuff, GMC had me out to GM’s Milford Proving Grounds to play with the new Super Cruise on the facility’s 4.5-mile banked circle track. Security at the facility is tight and our cameras were either confiscated or, in the case of my iPhone, covered in obnoxious red security tape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pnByMm"&gt;I soon understood the need for security when I spotted what appeared to be the upcoming 2023 Z06 mid-engined Corvette being tested, a whole bunch of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/20/21525290/hummer-ev-electric-truck-gmc-price-specs-range"&gt;GMC Hummer EV pickups&lt;/a&gt; and, curiously, a Tesla Model Y. (GMC wouldn’t say why, but I assume it was to check out the competition.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="8KfOw3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Available for the first time in the Chevy Silverado and GMC Sierra pickup trucks&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dz7JBF"&gt;There are three main new capabilities to the 2022 variant of Super Cruise, and I got to test two of them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="jRxRDJ"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Fully automatic lane changes&lt;/strong&gt;, meaning the car can determine when it’s safe to pass a slower car in front of you and execute all lane changes without involving the driver at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="71PliN"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Support for towing&lt;/strong&gt;, allowing for hands-free trailering (but you can’t tow &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; have automatic lane changes, it’s one or the other).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="tpYK4b"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upgrades to the navigation, to show Super Cruise-enabled roads on the in-vehicle navigation system during route selection.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="S2dpv4"&gt;I took the Sierra out onto the facility’s “highway” and a GM engineer followed in a chase car. After setting Super Cruise to 70mph, I settled in for a nice hands-free drive in a large circle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LAtrb5"&gt;Super Cruise, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/4/10/15224516/cadillac-super-cruise-hands-free-ct6-tesla-autopilot"&gt;debuted in 2017 in the Cadillac CT6 sedan&lt;/a&gt;, is capable of completely hands-free driving across more than 200,000 miles of divided highway across North America. It compares the vehicle’s position, taken from both GPS and on-board cameras, to its location in a lidar scan of the world. Once the vehicle knows where it is, and that it’s safe to activate, Super Cruise will take over both steering and acceleration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="itPlAE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The driver is still required to pay full attention&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wirslw"&gt;The driver is still required to pay full attention. The car uses an infrared vision system to ensure that the driver’s eyes remain on the road. Look away at your smartphone for too long and the system starts with warnings before disengaging entirely. But if you keep your eyes on the road, you won’t need to touch the steering wheel at all unless there’s a situation the system can’t handle.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lBb-OnIr2Y_it-NbAUpYzyT90Sk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22734129/super_cruise_2.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="FzPtle"&gt;And with the updates, you’ll be able to touch the wheel even less. After I pulled onto the highway and set my speed, the chase car sped past, moved into my lane, and then slowed down to less than 70mph. My Sierra noticed this and slowed down to match, but then it began scanning the left-hand passing lane to see if it was safe to move over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="deDoFJ"&gt;After a moment, the car beeped at me and popped up a message warning of the impending lane change and the vehicle swiftly moved to the left lane while simultaneously accelerating back up to my 70mph set speed. It wasn’t a dramatic move, but it was impressive to watch it in action. After passing the slower car, it moved back into the right lane and continued on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fpJTHV"&gt;The truck has four new wide-angle, long-range radar sensors to support the system, one on each corner of the vehicle. GM upgraded the two existing rear / side radars that were there to enable existing blind-spot monitoring features. The existing long-range radar for the adaptive cruise system is carried over. Between the seven different radar sensors, the car has 360-degree long-range coverage of the world around it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="UpW1nr"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Between the seven different radar sensors, the car has 360-degree long-range coverage of the world around it&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1a8UnM"&gt;2021 Cadillac Escalade models have an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/28/21111495/cadillac-super-cruise-automatic-lane-change-gm-update"&gt;older version of the lane change system&lt;/a&gt; where the car would change lanes if the driver activated the turn signal (though it didn’t require any interaction with the steering wheel), but this is a significant improvement on that. Just keep an eye on the road, and the car should be able to move around slower cars and trucks in your way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UTkZUD"&gt;The new trailering option is more complicated than it might appear at first glance. When you attach a trailer for the first time, the truck asks a series of questions like how long the trailer is. This helps the truck calculate the total length and weight of the vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N0ld0v"&gt;While in a normal curve, Super Cruise will stay closer to the inside lane line, which is how most humans drive. With the trailer attached, Super Cruise will instead work to keep the vehicle and trailer dead center in the lane. It’ll also leave more space between you and a vehicle in front (since the truck and trailer will take longer to slow down).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wg9LVp"&gt;All versions of Super Cruise use mapping data to determine if it should slow down for an upcoming curve. But it will be more conservative with a trailer attached, slowing down sooner and to a lower speed than without.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8qH7sB"&gt;A Sierra can haul 10,000 pounds without breaking a sweat, and that’s a significant amount of weight to entrust to the computer, but GMC’s engineers say it really works. In my 15-minute demo, I’m inclined to agree with them — though it was the definition of a controlled environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="aZjeux"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“democratization of technology”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4nDUjM"&gt;Company reps wouldn’t specify pricing nor what trim levels on which Super Cruise will be available. Phil Brook, GMC’s VP of marketing, said the addition of Super Cruise to Sierra was a “democratization of technology” and that they didn’t want to keep it buried at exclusively high trim levels. We’ll see about that, but expect Super Cruise to be an expensive option either way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="llEDjT"&gt;GM says the new Super Cruise will be available on a number of different vehicles, including the upcoming GMC Hummer electric pickup, the GMC Sierra and Chevrolet Silverado pickups, the Cadillac Escalade and XT6 SUVs, and the Cadillac CT4 and CT5 sedans. The 2022 Chevrolet Bolt EUV will receive an older version of Super Cruise that doesn’t include the lane change features. Owners of 2021 Escalade vehicles with Super Cruise equipped will also receive the new features in a future over-the-air update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pK6JZK"&gt;Of course, this was a contrived test on GM’s own test track. But, given the performance of Super Cruise in our own real-world testing and the company’s conservative, take-it-slow approach to rolling out the feature across its lineup, we expect the new features to work as advertised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kDY9Ay"&gt;None too soon, either. Arch rival Ford is planning to unleash its own hands-free Level 2 driving system, BlueCruise, later this year starting in 2021 versions of the Ford F-150 pickup and the Mustang Mach-E electric car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0j4Pmy"&gt;And, of course, there’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/6/18065540/tesla-navigate-on-autopilot-model-3-test-drive"&gt;Tesla’s Autopilot&lt;/a&gt; and the new beta version of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/10/22570081/tesla-fsd-v9-beta-autopilot-update"&gt;Full Self Driving features&lt;/a&gt; which also support automatic lane changes on the highway. However, the Tesla system requires the driver to keep their hands on the steering wheel to confirm that they’re paying attention instead of the completely hands-free driving that the camera-based driver monitoring systems from Ford and GM allow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TwqyIm"&gt;Though both Super Cruise and Autopilot have been around for a while, they haven’t been available in any pickup trucks — by far the most popular vehicles in America. The addition of Super Cruise to the Silverado and Sierra, and BlueCruise to the F-150, will bring these technologies (which might be old hat to Tesla owners) to an entirely new market of flyover truck buyers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="etU3rl"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="19kfgY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/23/22589285/gm-super-cruise-automatic-lane-change-gmc-chevy-silverado"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/23/22589285/gm-super-cruise-automatic-lane-change-gmc-chevy-silverado</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jordan Golson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-22T21:46:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-22T21:46:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>19 days after REvil’s ransomware attack on Kaseya VSA systems, there’s a fix</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tQoaKsq_WjCjakmuGxtITv_tgno=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69620454/acastro_170621_1777_0008.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ha4nVW"&gt;Just ahead of the July 4th holiday weekend, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22561252/revil-ransomware-attacks-systems-using-kaseyas-remote-it-management-software"&gt;a ransomware attack targeted organizations using Kaseya VSA remote management software&lt;/a&gt;. The outfit behind the attack, REvil, initially &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/5/22564054/ransomware-revil-kaseya-coop"&gt;requested a $70 million ransom&lt;/a&gt; and claimed to have locked down millions of devices. That was before REvil suddenly went offline on July 13th, disconnecting its servers, abandoning forums, and shutting down a page on the dark web used to communicate with victims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dcAOKF"&gt;Now, Kaseya &lt;a href="https://www.kaseya.com/potential-attack-on-kaseya-vsa/"&gt;says it has obtained a universal decryptor&lt;/a&gt; from a “third party” that can restore data encrypted during the attack. The company has not said how it came by this technology, telling &lt;a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/kaseya-obtains-universal-decryptor-for-revil-ransomware-victims/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bleeping Computer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that it could not confirm or deny any ransom payment had occurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="7TCWGm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Ransomware funds more ransomware, so how do we stop it?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/5/22564054/ransomware-revil-kaseya-coop"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="7qjRxU"&gt;On 7/21/2021, Kaseya obtained a decryptor for victims of the REvil ransomware attack, and we’re working to remediate customers impacted by the incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ApLpj4"&gt;We can confirm that Kaseya obtained the tool from a third party and have teams actively helping customers affected by the ransomware to restore their environments, with no reports of any problem or issues associated with the decryptor. Kaseya is working with &lt;a href="https://www.emsisoft.com/"&gt;Emsisoft&lt;/a&gt; to support our customer engagement efforts, and Emsisoft has confirmed the key is effective at unlocking victims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="trlXO1"&gt;&lt;em&gt;NBC News&lt;/em&gt; reporter Kevin Collier first reported the decryption tool’s existence and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kevincollier/status/1418326065265664022"&gt;speculates&lt;/a&gt; that one of three sources is likely behind the key: the US government, the Russian government, or a ransom payment to the attackers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C2JsfU"&gt;Kaseya says cybersecurity firm Emsisoft confirmed the restoration tool is “effective,” and now it’s working with victims of the attack to decrypt affected systems. It’s unknown how much help the tool will offer, coming several weeks after the attacks, but it’s better than nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DUiGat"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22589643/ransomware-kaseya-vsa-decryptor-revil"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22589643/ransomware-kaseya-vsa-decryptor-revil</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-22T18:34:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-22T18:34:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nomad could not resist draping the Apple MagSafe Battery Pack in leather </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eR8Yv5PA_p3D1OzappSnyxCJIVM=/0x0:2700x1800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69619953/nomad_magsafe_battery_pack_leather_case.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hYIuno"&gt;Frankly, now that we’ve seen &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/7/7/22563631/nomad-magsafe-leather-cover-charger-price"&gt;a leather case for your MagSafe charging puck&lt;/a&gt;, it’s all uphill from here. At least &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/7/19/22583859/apple-magsafe-battery-pack-thickness-size-shape-plastic"&gt;Apple’s new $99 MagSafe Battery Pack&lt;/a&gt; is something you’ll actually be carrying around and touching on a regular basis, where leather might make it nicer to hold. Perhaps you already have a matching leather case for your iPhone, too? It looks like a nice combo in photos. If you agree, Nomad is &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://nomadgoods.com/products/leather-cover-for-magsafe-battery-black" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently taking preorders for $30 each&lt;/a&gt;, shipping this November. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e6ofoO"&gt;(I blame Apple for only releasing the battery in white.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/shkPUKFfkxBYxDHpPmak3RWgBkc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22734484/nomad_leather_case_magsafe_battery.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="8yOFGK"&gt;While you can’t see it in pictures or the description, Nomad tells us it will actually have a hole for the battery’s charging port. One more note: while microsuction tape is much better (reusable, no sticky residue) compared to your traditional Scotch, you should probably know tape is what’s keeping this piece of leather on.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lbYpln"&gt;I think I’ll wait and see how strong the MagSafe Battery Pack’s magnets are, period, before I put any more leather on a phone. Stay tuned: Dieter’s currently working on that review. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p0zI4G"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, 8:15PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added Nomad’s confirmation that it will have a cut-out for the MagSafe Battery Pack’s charging port.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22589472/nomad-apple-magsafe-battery-pack-in-leather"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22589472/nomad-apple-magsafe-battery-pack-in-leather</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
