<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-23T12:02:17-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-23T12:02:17-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-23T12:02:17-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater remaster coming to PS5, Xbox Series X, and Switch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Yt57ibRzHT-wA7a7gyij2UQo5sw=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68862293/THPS_NextGen_004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tony Hawk in &lt;/em&gt;Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 1 and 2. | Image: Activision&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YqIlwn"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21419054/tony-hawk-pro-skater-1-2-review-xbox-pc-ps4"&gt;very good remaster&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;em&gt;Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 1 and 2&lt;/em&gt; is hitting next-gen consoles and the Nintendo Switch &lt;a href="https://blog.activision.com/tony-hawk/2021-02/Tony-Hawks-Pro-Skater-1-2-Platforms-Announcement"&gt;this year&lt;/a&gt;. The game will launch on the PS5 and Xbox Series X / S on March 26th, but there’s no specific release date for the Switch release beyond “2021.” The game was first released last year for PlayStation 4, Xbox One, and PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TwbcaL"&gt;On next-gen consoles, you’ll be able to play the game at 120fps at a 1080p resolution or at 60fps in 4K, &lt;a href="https://blog.activision.com/tony-hawk/2021-02/Tony-Hawks-Pro-Skater-1-2-Platforms-Announcement"&gt;according to a blog post&lt;/a&gt;. (The PS5 and Xbox Series X can run at a native 4K, while the Xbox Series S version can run at 1440p and upscale to 4K.) The next-gen version will also offer spatial audio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TLRreY"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Get ready to drop in and take &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/THPS?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#THPS&lt;/a&gt; 1+2 to the next level on New Platforms     Coming to PS5™, Xbox Series X|S - March 26 and on Nintendo Switch™ - Coming 2021. AVAILABLE NOW on PS4™, Xbox One, and PC. &lt;a href="https://t.co/NUVbECnx1e"&gt;pic.twitter.com/NUVbECnx1e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 1 and 2 (@TonyHawkTheGame) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TonyHawkTheGame/status/1364243630358220800?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 23, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VnlNdm"&gt;If you already own &lt;em&gt;Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 1 and 2&lt;/em&gt; on PS4 or Xbox One, you won’t necessarily be entitled to a free upgrade to the next-gen version, however. Activision spelled out the different upgrade scenarios &lt;a href="https://support.activision.com/tony-hawks-pro-skater-1-2/articles/tony-hawks-pro-skater-1-2-upgrade-and-purchase-faq"&gt;on its website&lt;/a&gt;, but here’s the gist:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="P2xJi0"&gt;If you own the Digital Deluxe versions of the older-gen games, you can download the next-gen upgrade for free. (Though if you live in Japan, the PS4 to PS5 upgrade will cost 100 yen, according to Activision.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="iHlZnk"&gt;If you originally bought the game digitally but &lt;em&gt;don’t&lt;/em&gt; have the Digital Deluxe version, you can pay $10 to upgrade to the “Cross-Gen Deluxe Bundle,” which includes content from the Digital Deluxe version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="eL0QB2"&gt;If you have the physical PS4 version of the game, you will be able to upgrade to the PS5 version, but you’ll need to you have your disc in your console to play the next-gen version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JxUv8q"&gt;If you have the physical Xbox One version, you’re out of luck — there’s no upgrade offer for the Xbox Series X / S version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="Y1Ol8Q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 1 and 2 is the perfect remaster","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21419054/tony-hawk-pro-skater-1-2-review-xbox-pc-ps4"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297221/tony-hawk-pro-skater-1-2-ps5-xbox-series-x-nintendo-switch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297221/tony-hawk-pro-skater-1-2-ps5-xbox-series-x-nintendo-switch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-23T12:01:27-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-23T12:01:27-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google Maps finally rolls out dark mode on Android </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mAlw93bRBMcAbNv0XF9rdoO5Ims=/50x0:952x601/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68862287/GoogleMaps_NightMode.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EQl6LS"&gt;The Google Maps app is getting a true dark mode, at least on Android. The company announced today that it is finally widely releasing the dark theme option that it’s been testing in the app &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2020/09/29/google-maps-dark-theme/"&gt;since September 2020&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DYchlH"&gt;The dark mode, which takes things much further than the previously available night mode color option, will be accessible in the app’s settings menu, under “theme.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nMyW0c"&gt;Google announced the dark mode rollout as part of a &lt;a href="https://t.co/RkceFy7Rrs"&gt;batch of new features&lt;/a&gt; coming to Android, including some updates to Android Auto. In addition to custom wallpapers, Android Auto is now going to feature games as well. &lt;em&gt;Trivia Crack&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Jeopardy!&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Song Quiz&lt;/em&gt;, and Google’s own Are You Feeling Lucky? will be available. The games can be accessed through the assistant by saying “Hey Google, play a game.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y1eYlrlMA_omPxiqIvjRmbQhw4E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22323100/Android_Auto_Play_A_Game.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ugQdxz"&gt;Android Auto is also getting a split-screen feature that will put Maps side by side with media controls, much like what &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/24/18693555/apple-ios-13-carplay-interface-update-hands-on-test-review"&gt;Apple started doing in CarPlay in iOS 13 in 2019&lt;/a&gt;. (Though this feature will only be available in cars with wider displays.) Google is adding shortcuts to the Android Auto launch screen, too, which will allow for quick access to weather or setting your home thermostat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bmStHZ"&gt;The Android Auto features will be available “in the coming days” on phones running Android 6.0 and above in compatible cars. Google Maps dark mode will roll out “soon.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wAlvZq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297204/google-maps-dark-mode-android-auto-split-screen-games"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297204/google-maps-dark-mode-android-auto-split-screen-games</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-23T12:01:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-23T12:01:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>The US offshore wind boom will depend on these ships</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ozn7qfx_6osRuaX7E33vkT8EfRo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68862285/acastro_210216_4409_windTurbine_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge | Images: Dominion Energy&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The race is on to build them &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="rOlD48"&gt;New offshore wind developments are poised to help the US usher in a new era in energy — but first, they need ships. More specifically, they need massive specialized vessels capable of erecting a skyscraper-sized turbine in the open ocean. Perhaps unsurprisingly, these are hard to come by. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4Adana"&gt;Wind turbine installation vessels are already in short supply globally. And in the US, policies aimed at protecting domestic shipbuilding make it even harder for wind farm developers to get their hands on those vessels. Unless the US figures out how to bridge that gap, it could be choppy waters ahead for the country’s offshore wind dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NTkolA"&gt;In the US, President Joe Biden has set a goal of “&lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/27/executive-order-on-tackling-the-climate-crisis-at-home-and-abroad/"&gt;doubling&lt;/a&gt;” offshore wind this decade, part of a broader effort to power the country’s electricity sector with purely clean energy by 2035. In order to meet those goals, the US will need to build up a lot more aquatic infrastructure off its shores. There are already plans for at least 16 wind projects off the East Coast of the US — they’re just awaiting permits — and they’ll need the services of these very specialized ships.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="F1zt3T"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s pretty insane. It’s a pretty limited market.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GnvhGI"&gt;“It’s pretty insane. It’s a pretty limited market,” says Claire Richer, director of federal affairs at American Clean Power Association (ACP), a group that represents the renewable energy industry in the US. If all of a sudden, all of the prospective US wind farm projects began construction at the same time, “then we have a problem,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CpPpnF"&gt;All of the offshore wind projects being developed around the world are vying for time with these vessels at a rate of up to $180,000 a day. The industry is still pretty nascent, providing  just &lt;a href="https://www.iea.org/reports/offshore-wind-outlook-2019"&gt;0.3 percent of power generation globally&lt;/a&gt;. But that’s expected to change because the potential is enormous. Offshore wind could one day generate 18 times the global electricity demand of today, according to the &lt;a href="https://www.iea.org/reports/offshore-wind-outlook-2019"&gt;International Energy Agency&lt;/a&gt;. It forecasts that offshore wind will be a trillion-dollar industry by 2040, growing by 13 percent each year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KC5TAz"&gt;The industry is already advancing at breakneck speeds; massive new turbines can harness more power than ever before. Take General Electric’s Haliade X, which became commercially available in 2020. At 853 feet tall, it dwarfs previous generations of turbines. Imagine the Statue of Liberty stacked on top of the Washington Monument, and you’ve got a sense of its size. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="GE’s Haliade X prototype" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Jp5qu707pQxXhLf6Y3CqCOYX1ZY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22322774/wind_offshore_haliade_x_prototype_aerial_3000px.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: GE&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;GE’s Haliade X prototype dwarfs older turbines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PNlclh"&gt;To put that monstrosity together at sea, you need a special kind of boat called a wind turbine installation vessel. These ships need to be big and strong enough to carry the turbine pieces from port to installation site. Once they’re on location, these giants have legs that can reach down to the seafloor. That steadies the vessel and lifts it up out of the water so it can act as a stable platform. On top of that platform is a crane powerful enough to lift turbine components and install them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1VjYxa"&gt;There were only 32 of these wind turbine installation vessels in the world in 2020, according to a recent &lt;a href="https://www.rystadenergy.com/newsevents/news/press-releases/the-world-may-not-have-enough-heavy-lift-vessels-to-service-the-offshore-wind-industry-post-2025/"&gt;analysis&lt;/a&gt; by Norwegian firm Rystad Energy. Even though more are being built, the global fleet won’t be enough to meet offshore demand beyond 2025, according to Rystad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TkiYzD"&gt;Building new vessels capable of constructing massive wind turbines can take several years. And despite the growing need, shipbuilders and offshore wind developers have been hesitant in the past to invest in new ships until upcoming projects have acquired the permits they need to begin construction — which slows things down even more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oriiuU"&gt;“It’s been this kind of a chicken and egg situation in the vessel market,” says Alexander Fløtre, a product manager for Rystad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="p72wLk"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Vessels in the existing fleet are becoming obsolete&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eVggJe"&gt;What’s more, some of the vessels in the existing fleet are becoming obsolete because turbines are growing increasingly gigantic. At 351 feet long, a single turbine blade for the Haliade X is already longer than the tower height of one of GE’s older turbines. Longer blades can generate more power, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/17/21293456/ge-200-meter-onshore-taller-wind-turbines-3d-printing"&gt;taller turbines&lt;/a&gt; can reach stronger winds at higher altitudes. So companies are competing with each other by building bigger turbines. “You see this race,” Fløtre says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yyLd0N"&gt;That makes the shortage of ships a bigger problem. So far, there are only 12 vessels in the world capable of installing next-generation wind turbines like the Haliade X, according to ACP. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HxeZex"&gt;There’s yet another challenge that’s specific to the US: none of the existing global fleet complies with &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/9/27/16373484/jones-act-puerto-rico"&gt;America’s Jones Act&lt;/a&gt;. The 1920 act requires vessels moving between two points in the US to be built, owned, crewed, and registered in the US. That also applies to a vessel transporting turbine parts from a US port to a project site that’s within federal waters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Dominion Energy hired the Luxembourg-flagged vessel Vole Au Vent to construct a pilot project off the shores of Virginia." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/u8rvn3dc7MTuTlobcnuPrFuCat0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22322863/CVOW_Turbine_2_Install_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Dominion Energy&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dominion Energy hired the Luxembourg-flagged vessel Vole Au Vent to construct a pilot project off the shores of Virginia.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OqR3v9"&gt;The first Jones Act-compliant wind turbine installation vessel is currently being built by Virginia-based utility Dominion Energy, but it won’t be ready until 2023, and it comes at an enormous cost of $500 million. That’s even more than what companies have bid to lease federal waters for offshore wind development, according to ACP’s Richer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cY8nG9"&gt;“Dominion’s installation vessel is going to have to be constantly working in order to recoup the cost of construction,” says Patrick Finn, a maritime tech analyst for the consultancy Thetius. Jones Act restrictions make shipbuilding significantly more expensive in the US, Finn says. A similar vessel built in South Korea might cost about half of what Dominion is paying, according to Finn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="4DCoFq"&gt;&lt;q&gt;There are only 12 vessels in the world capable of installing next-generation wind turbines&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="udJi4L"&gt;For Dominion, the steep cost may still be worth it. “There was a big need there that we saw in the US,” says Mark Mitchell, senior vice president for project construction at Dominion. “It’s an important step to support the industry coming to the US and it certainly provides an important option to install even our own project.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bvcmd1"&gt;Dominion will need the vessel to build its planned 2,640 MW wind farm off the coast of Virginia. After that, the vessel will eventually be hired out for other companies’ projects. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="voBPYf"&gt;There are ways to work around Jones Act requirements. Smaller “feeder” vessels that are already Jones Act-compliant can bring equipment and turbine components to foreign installation vessels stationed out at sea. Some companies are &lt;a href="https://www.windpowerengineering.com/abs-to-class-first-jones-act-compliant-offshore-wind-service-operation-vessel/"&gt;already designing&lt;/a&gt; new &lt;a href="https://splash247.com/wartsila-unveils-jones-act-hybrid-sov/"&gt;Jones Act-compliant vessels&lt;/a&gt; to service the construction or operation of new wind farms. If the foreign vessels aren’t transporting goods, then they won’t be in violation of the act. That’s how the US’s &lt;a href="https://www.popsci.com/future-energy-is-blowing-in-wind/"&gt;first offshore wind farm at Block Island&lt;/a&gt; was built. A second small wind farm, a 12 MW demonstration project Dominion built off the coast of Virginia, was just completed last year.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rr4naTSM5gdgxjL2qRVfCvuEUOA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22322736/2020_11_02_GustoMSC_NG_16000X_SJ_Dominion_Energy_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Dominion Energy&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A rendering of the first Jones Act-compliant wind turbine installation vessel being built by Dominion Energy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jaCJFN"&gt;In the future, turbines could even be &lt;a href="https://crew.udel.edu/industrializing-offshore-wind-power-generation/"&gt;assembled almost entirely at port&lt;/a&gt; and brought out to sea pretty much intact. Doing so could eliminate the need for a specialized wind turbine installation vessel. The US could use much cheaper vessels to transport the completed turbine and even repurpose Jones Act-compliant vessels used in the oil and gas industry. “It allows us to do it for less cost and faster,” says Willett Kempton, a professor at the University of Delaware who is leading research into this method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XrIiZw"&gt;Whatever route offshore wind developers choose, all of these options have the potential to spur a boom in US boatbuilding. “That’ll be a boost for the Gulf Coast economy, my hometown,” says Joseph Orgeron, co-founder of the company 2nd Wind Marine. “There will be quite a number of purpose-built ships that will have to be built in the US, just to take care of US offshore wind development over the next 20 years,” Orgeron says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="coqcIB"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A boom in US boatbuilding&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FPWi6A"&gt;Orgeron’s company provided the feeder vessels for the construction of the Block Island wind farm in 2016. Before that, his family’s business supplied vessels for oil and gas development in the Gulf of Mexico. That boom started declining in the 1980s, and their vessels were used more and more to take old oil and gas structures out of the Gulf. Now, the future of Orgeron’s business is in offshore wind.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="tvdINc"&gt;“That [industry], basically that could be fired back up,” Orgeron says. Only this time, they won’t be building new oil rigs or tearing down their hulking remains. Instead, they’ll build new giants for a new age of more sustainable energy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rVDC4o"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZFMBQR"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22296979/us-offshore-ships-wind-boom-installation-vessels"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22296979/us-offshore-ships-wind-boom-installation-vessels</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-23T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-23T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Stadia’s next exclusive is PixelJunk Raiders, releasing March 1st</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r8-ADL656mEd0AeQYNnVRyWl44A=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68862244/PJR_keyart.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Q Games&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xdsP4L"&gt;&lt;em&gt;PixelJunk Raiders&lt;/em&gt; is the next exclusive coming to Google’s Stadia cloud gaming service. The title, a third-person rougelite that sees you battle through procedurally generated alien environments, will release on the Stadia platform on March 1st. It’ll sell for $19.99 (€19.99), and it will be included free with a Stadia Pro subscription. An &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UJGyLNxTBQg&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be"&gt;announcement trailer&lt;/a&gt; bills &lt;em&gt;PixelJunk Raiders&lt;/em&gt; as “Only on Stadia,” suggesting this isn’t a timed exclusive &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UJGyLNxTBQg&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be"&gt;like &lt;em&gt;Crayta&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6ol4QT"&gt;The announcement notes that &lt;em&gt;PixelJunk Raiders&lt;/em&gt; supports Stadia’s State Share feature, which has previously been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22233066/stadia-state-share-hitman-3-world-of-assassination"&gt;used with the &lt;em&gt;Hitman&lt;/em&gt; games&lt;/a&gt; to let players to share specific parts of missions with one another. In &lt;em&gt;PixelJunk Raiders&lt;/em&gt;, the feature allows your “placed turrets, traps and gadgets to impact other players’ worlds.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ieJinB"&gt;&lt;q&gt;With support for Stadia’s State Share&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qCBeO7"&gt;The release of &lt;em&gt;PixelJunk Raiders&lt;/em&gt; comes exactly a month after Google announced its decision to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260803/google-stadia-game-development-studio-shut-down-jade-raymond"&gt;shutter its in-house game development studios&lt;/a&gt;, a division of multiple teams tasked with building original games for Stadia. Despite their closure, it seems Google still plans to bring exclusive titles to Stadia from third-party studios. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="22pPiy"&gt;Other previously announced exclusives for the service include games from &lt;em&gt;Rock Band&lt;/em&gt; developer Harmonix and &lt;em&gt;Until Dawn&lt;/em&gt; studio Supermassive Games, in a deal that was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/14/21323326/google-stadia-exclusive-game-deals-harmonix-rock-band-supermassive-until-dawn"&gt;announced last year&lt;/a&gt;. Uppercut Games was also announced as developing an exclusive title for Stadia. It’s unclear if these deals have been affected by Google’s recent studio closures.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22296898/google-stadia-pixeljunk-raiders-exclusive-price-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22296898/google-stadia-pixeljunk-raiders-exclusive-price-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-23T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-23T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google is expanding its Password Checkup tool to older devices</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i-IKMHhyLQl06SrfMgcR3CaNm-M=/120x0:2169x1366/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68862214/Screen_Shot_2021_02_23_at_11.09.50_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LFyQi5"&gt;Google is expanding its &lt;a href="https://blog.google/technology/safety-security/password-checkup/"&gt;Password Checker&lt;/a&gt; feature to older devices, the company announced today. Now, phones and tablets running Android 9 or newer will have access to the feature, which is part of Google’s autofilling password manager and which checks password strength or if any logins have been compromised in a data breach. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A3mnZK"&gt;It’s part of a new batch of updates Google is rolling out on Android, a list that also includes the ability to schedule text messages to send later on, a new version of TalkBack (Google’s screen reader for Android), and better support for Google Assistant to accomplish tasks even when your phone is locked.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aqLygUw6E_E26Uesg7SoRJPzhoI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22323069/ScheduleSend_Thumbnail_4K_01.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Messages’ new scheduled send feature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="gV6ikd"&gt;Scheduled text messages are exactly what they sound like: once you’ve updated Google’s Messages app, you’ll be able to tap and hold on the send button for a message to select the date and time that you’d like to send your text. The company envisions the feature as being useful for messaging friends and family members in other time zones. It’ll be available on devices running Android 7 or newer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lp24wm"&gt;A more substantial update, though, is coming to Google’s TalkBack screen reader, which allows blind and low vision users to more easily interact with their phones. In the latest update, Google is adding what is says were some of the most requested features: “more intuitive gestures, a unified menu, a new reading control menu and more.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JXgmhWS8anLHTFcxzeAduLdjUMc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22323071/Screen_Shot_2021_02_23_at_11.30.01_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new card UI for using Google Assistant on a locked phone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="C4C6wP"&gt;Lastly, Google is enhancing Assistant by adding new cards to glance at when you’re interacting with the voice assistant while your phone is locked. The goal is to make it easier to use Assistant to do things like setting alarms, sending texts, or playing a song, even when your phone isn’t in your hand. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297198/google-password-checkup-tool-older-devices-android-new-features-scheduled-send"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297198/google-password-checkup-tool-older-devices-android-new-features-scheduled-send</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-23T11:44:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-23T11:44:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>SNES hacker speeds up a game that originally ran at 4 frames per second</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1Hwy4sBqGwORIp3vwBpcLUQ7zqE=/88x0:1353x843/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68862129/Screen_Shot_2021_02_23_at_11.20.39_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YHOXI3"&gt;The Atari arcade cabinet game &lt;em&gt;Race Drivin’&lt;/em&gt; was ported to the Atari ST in the summer of 1991, and then ported again to the SNES a year later. It was the sequel to 1989’s &lt;em&gt;Hard Drivin’&lt;/em&gt;, and while it boasted numerous improvements over its predecessor — it could model a car with four wheels, as opposed to &lt;em&gt;Hard Drivin’&lt;/em&gt;s two — it was still not particularly fast. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m2GpGB"&gt;The SNES console port ran at a slideshow-y 4 frames per second. And when the Genesis port arrived in 1993, &lt;em&gt;Electronic Gaming Monthly&lt;/em&gt;’s January 1994 issue gave the game a capsule review. It reads in full: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="AJJa5f"&gt;This is another so-so entry in the driving scene where the truly innovative titles (Chase H.Q. II and Rock &amp;amp; Roll Racing) tend to stand out, while others like this get lost in the crowd. The scrolling is very choppy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="mMaGDy"&gt;It received mostly fours and fives (out of 10) from the magazine’s staff. (This in an issue with an editor’s letter about the California attorney general threatening to do something about violence in video games! &lt;em&gt;Night Trap&lt;/em&gt; was terrifying at the time!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0tzsQg"&gt;Anyway, &lt;em&gt;Race Drivin’&lt;/em&gt; ran at 4 frames per second on the original Atari ST hardware. Software engineer Vitor Vilela thought that wasn’t good enough and decided to do something about it using contemporaneous hardware — the Nintendo SA-1 processor. As &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/hacker-rewrites-crappy-snes-racer-to-improve-its-frame-1846328191"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kotaku&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;, the results show exactly how much more powerful the SA-1 chip was; Vilela managed to get around 30 frames per second using a conversion they developed specifically for it. Here’s what that looks like in action. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0jqLzR"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/i9_4mwd7cYg?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="x86Zmf"&gt;In the description of the video on YouTube, Vilela writes a little about how they managed to get this frankly very impressive feat working. “Just like my other conversions, this one moves the entire memory to the SA-1 side and moves almost the whole processing to the SA-1 CPU side,” they write. “With all optimizations included, the game runs up to 1000% faster compared with original.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="29FGTH"&gt;All the code Vilela wrote for this hack is available on &lt;a href="https://github.com/VitorVilela7"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;, along with the source code for the other hacks they’ve pulled off. It’s a shame that &lt;em&gt;EGM&lt;/em&gt; couldn’t have gotten its hands on this version of the game — it looks like something ported directly from an alternate future. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/2/23/22297151/snes-hack-race-drivin-atari-nintendo-vitor-vilela"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/2/23/22297151/snes-hack-race-drivin-atari-nintendo-vitor-vilela</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bijan Stephen</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-23T11:10:35-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-23T11:10:35-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here’s every game coming to the PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X in 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ctg6U9v5jr9RrXkzgL82pqnQOXQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67735830/vpavic_4261_20201023_0084.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;For the early adopters of next-gen hardware&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="cyuvuR"&gt;Just over two months after their release, the PS5 and Xbox Series X / S continue to be some of the most desirable gadgets in the world. While it’s still &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21451144/sony-ps5-preorder-microsoft-xbox-series-x-nvidia-rtx-3080-mess"&gt;very difficult&lt;/a&gt; to get your hands on a new console, those lucky enough to own one can enjoy something unprecedented in modern gaming history. For the first time, next-gen console owners can take their existing library — whether it’s physical, digital, or a mix of the two — and bring it to a next-gen platform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pNh3ro"&gt;That gives consumers unprecedented freedom in deciding where they want to play and what performance benefits are worthwhile enough to upgrade. And technologies like cross-platform play and now even cross-generation support will allow people to still play with their friends, even if they don’t upgrade to the latest gaming hardware. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="5uXjX1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Giving consumers unprecedented freedom in deciding where they want to play&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CveWHl"&gt;Yes, both consoles arrived within seven years of the last generation of console hardware. And while it’s likely within the first year of both consoles’ lifespan that many of the hottest titles may launch on last- and current-gen simultaneously, there’s still a good chunk of games that will be exclusive titles playable only a PS5 or Xbox Series X / S. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u79IWA"&gt;Besides 4K, the solid-state drives, and other spec changes, Microsoft and Sony have pledged to support close to every title in the existing console platforms’ libraries. Every Xbox, Xbox 360, and Xbox One game currently playable on existing Xbox One hardware (minus Kinect games) &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/16/21326805/xbox-series-x-xbox-one-game-support-backward-compatible-feature-kinect"&gt;will be playable on the Series X / S&lt;/a&gt;, while Sony is supporting a “vast majority” of PS4 games, totaling &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/16/21440748/ps5-playstation-5-99-percent-backward-compatible-ps4-games-jim-ryan"&gt;more than 4,000 titles&lt;/a&gt;. With both consoles early into their lifespan, it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22163921/ps5-playstation-5-xbox-series-x-old-games-next-gen-consoles"&gt;easy for many to return to older games&lt;/a&gt; to help fill the gap in between long wait periods for more titles to be added to each console’s library. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="dwgnjo"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The new consoles let you take a majority of your existing libraries with you&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nUlnZM"&gt;This changes the calculus a bit with regard to buying a new console. No longer do you have to abandon what you were playing on your old device and start anew. And thanks to some genuinely consumer-friendly initiatives like Xbox Smart Delivery and similar upgrade programs, plenty of the games we own now or are planning to buy in the next couple of months will not only work on the new platforms, but in most cases, they’ll also come with free upgrades from the standard PS4 and Xbox One versions. Sony also introduced the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/28/21538383/sony-playstation-plus-collection-available-games-november-free-bugsnax"&gt;PlayStation Plus Collection&lt;/a&gt;, a library of PS4 games available for free with its online subscription service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lmWX6y"&gt;That leaves us with one big issue: how do you know what new games are coming out for which platforms and when? There’s also the painstaking process of parsing whether a game company is giving out a free next-gen upgrade of a cross-gen title, charging a little extra, or releasing a next-gen-only game. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EsrpjD"&gt;2021 is packed full of new releases and full optimizations of cross-gen games that should further pad out what’s available to play on your new system of choice. We’ve compiled the list below to help you understand every game coming out during the first year of the PS5 and Xbox Series X / S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GM3UJT"&gt;This excludes games without release dates that may have been previously announced — like &lt;em&gt;Elder Scrolls VI &lt;/em&gt;and the &lt;em&gt;Fable &lt;/em&gt;reboot, for example — and any games that were released for either console in 2020, including launch titles. We’ve also chosen only to list release dates for games where the publisher has chosen a concrete date with both day and month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="hTe555"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:9552771"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4tQEqz"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update November 4th, 2020, 12:35PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added that &lt;/em&gt;ARK: Survival Evolved&lt;em&gt; recently released an Xbox Series X enhancement update that will be available to new console owners on launch day.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rC6OMy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; An earlier version of this post incorrectly stated &lt;/em&gt;Haven &lt;em&gt;would be a PS5-only release and that &lt;/em&gt;War Thunder &lt;em&gt;would be Xbox Series-only at launch. Those are incorrect; Haven is also coming to Xbox Series X and Xbox One and as part of Game Pass at launch, and &lt;/em&gt;War Thunder&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;is slated for PS5 mid-November. We regret the errors. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qPYdhq"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 15th, 2021, 5PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to add additional titles releasing in 2021 and update any games that may have been delayed into this year. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yywDTp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n76LJk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21538464/ps5-xbox-series-x-launch-games-list-new-release-holiday-2020-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21538464/ps5-xbox-series-x-launch-games-list-new-release-holiday-2020-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-23T11:08:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-23T11:08:47-05:00</updated>
    <title>Hyundai’s electric Ioniq 5 crossover could be the ultimate camping companion </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ELpDjqCjyUkxb6R-fkoGTqx0L58=/0x343:8272x5858/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68861940/Large_45011_HyundaiIONIQ5RedefinesElectricMobilityLifestyle.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;With two-way charging, the Ioniq 5 could supply power for a full range of electrical devices &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="ruqOH7"&gt;Hyundai unveiled the all-new Ioniq 5, an electric midsize SUV with nearly 300 miles of range and a two-way charging feature that is sure to make this a popular EV for outdoor activities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZwYhFA"&gt;The Ioniq 5, which will go on sale in the first half of 2021, is the first vehicle to be built on Hyundai’s new Electric-Global Modular Platform (E-GMP) that the automaker says will serve as the basis for an entire family of planned EVs. Hyundai and its sister company aim to sell 1 million EVs in 2025 in a bid to capture 10 percent of the global EV market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="Y9zHgH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Ioniq 5 looks like a promising start to that effort&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="11biRu"&gt;The Ioniq 5 looks like a promising start to that effort. The sharp-edged crossover SUV takes some of its design cues from the automaker’s 45 concept vehicle first unveiled in 2019, which was an homage to the &lt;a href="http://www.italdesign.it/project/pony-coupe/"&gt;1974 Pony Coupe&lt;/a&gt;, Hyundai’s first mass-produced car and first export.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SFdSwSzW0cSz4EdeDQk-z8CWwvY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22322702/Large_45018_HyundaiIONIQ5RedefinesElectricMobilityLifestyle.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GoKQJK9_O3_75ZPrOPv7a6988bs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22322701/Large_45019_HyundaiIONIQ5RedefinesElectricMobilityLifestyle.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9InLaq"&gt;In lieu of a traditional grille, the front of the car features Hyundai’s first clamshell hood and a front bumper with a distinctive V-shape that incorporates a set of unique daytime running lights. These small, pixel-like clusters also appear at the rear of the vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hG4bv9"&gt;But Hyundai packed the interior with a number of really interesting surprises. The center console can slide back as much as 140 millimeters, allowing either driver or passenger to enter and exit through whichever door they choose. This “universal island,” as Hyundai is branding it, could prove useful in especially tight parking situations. The movable console also provides access to the vehicle’s integrated 15-watt wireless phone charger, in addition to tons of extra storage space. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fRj7l9QV87rzGKfLwdOdV8UjoPI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22322727/hyundai_ioniq_universal_island.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sahpre"&gt;Most of the Ioniq 5’s interior touch points — seats, headliner, door trim, floor, and armrest — use eco-friendly materials, such as recycled PET bottles, plant-based yarns, and natural wool yarns, eco-processed leather with plant-based extracts, and bio paint with plant extracts. But unlike other EVs like the Polestar 2, Hyundai doesn’t go so far as to claim that its interior is 100 percent vegan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Up3WfZ"&gt;That said, it may be comfortable enough to take a nap (but not while driving, obviously). The driver and passenger seats recline enough to offer a “weightless” feeling, Hyundai claims. The design theme is “living space,” which is meant to emphasize the roomy interior where you can kick up your feet and relax. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2QzueS"&gt;The Ioniq 5 comes in standard and long-range configurations, with either 58 kilowatt-hours or 77.4 kilowatt-hours of respective battery capacity. Hyundai estimates that the driving range will fall between 470-480 kilometers, or just under 300 miles, based on the European Worldwide Harmonized Light Vehicle Test Procedure (WLTP). Hyundai has yet to certify its range estimates, but it’s helpful to remember that WLTP estimates are typically more optimistic than the EPA, so expect that number to be less when the Ioniq 5 reaches the states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5MNq5q"&gt;Still, this represents a serious improvement over Hyundai’s previous EV offerings. The Ioniq 5’s range is up nearly 20 percent from the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/17/18144959/hyundai-kona-ev-electric-suv-range-price"&gt;Kona EV&lt;/a&gt;, for example, which previously had the longest range among Hyundai’s EV lineup.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DXn6oZ4WkrgmFqrkmwu_egP85yI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22322728/ioniq_design_v2l_inside_pc.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="3WiSlL"&gt;EV ownership is often defined by how much time you need to spend charging the battery, and by that measure the Ioniq 5 sounds like it could be a winner. Hyundai says the EV supports up to 350kW DC fast charging and is capable of getting up to 80 percent in as little as 18 minutes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ol6KaA"&gt;The Ioniq 5 supports both 400-volt and 800-volt charging. In fact, Hyundai’s E-GMP platform offers 800V charging as standard, along with 400V charging, without the need for additional adapters. Hyundai says this multi-charging system is a “world’s first patented technology that operates the motor and inverter to boost 400 V to 800 V for stable charging compatibility.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="TbEyWC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;But that charging capability flows both ways — literally&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RUN8xn"&gt;But that charging capability flows both ways — literally. The Ioniq 5 boasts a two-way charging feature that Hyundai calls “vehicle-to-load,” which can supply up to 3.6kW of power. There are two charging ports, one located under the second-row seats and the other at the charging port on the exterior. Using a converter, customers can charge a range of electrical devices, including electric bicycles, scooters, or camping equipment. The outside port provides power even when the vehicle is turned off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qFYvnA"&gt;(&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=33qjeTyBswM"&gt;A commercial&lt;/a&gt; for the EV features actors using the Ioniq 5 to power a convection oven, treadmill, and half a dozen speakers, all while camping.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="80t6FK"&gt;This two-way charging feature is not unique to Hyundai, but it is rare for a passenger vehicle. The Ford F-150 Powerboost, a hybrid version of its full-size truck, can provide as much as 7.2kW of power through a built-in generator. But 3.6kW is a decent amount of output. To be sure, the Ioniq 5 doesn’t generate its own energy, so any power drawn from its battery will ultimately come off the vehicle’s range. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="l6wBPu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10357315"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZB8uHh"&gt;If you’re wondering how the Ioniq 5’s price compares to other electric crossover SUVs, like the Ford Mustang Mach-E, Volkswagen ID 4, or Tesla Model Y... well, so are we. Hyundai didn’t release any price information for the EV, unfortunately, though we expect it to be in the $30,000-$40,000 range, before tax incentives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PIGxv8"&gt;Unlike Tesla or General Motors, Hyundai is still eligible for the full $7,500 federal EV tax credit, which should help the automaker move a lot of units. Customers will also be looking for a range certification from the EPA and more details about partnerships with EV charging station operators before making their decision. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="apd3cs"&gt;For the first time in, well, forever, customers will have a range of options when it comes to shopping for midsize electric SUVs. And the Ioniq 5 is already looking like it will be a strong contender. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22296991/hyundai-ioniq-5-electric-suv-ev-battery-range-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22296991/hyundai-ioniq-5-electric-suv-ev-battery-range-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-23T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-23T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Valorant’s new tournament series is aimed at making its esports scene more diverse</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hgIFEdtGoY9_Nub1aZG8b7VjMvo=/96x0:1131x690/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68861829/0.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="m4QuIm"&gt;2021 is a big year for competitive &lt;em&gt;Valorant&lt;/em&gt;, with developer Riot kicking off an ambitious, yearlong esports circuit called &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/24/21612562/valorant-champions-tour-esports-2021"&gt;the &lt;em&gt;Valorant&lt;/em&gt; Champions Tour&lt;/a&gt;. But the company is also looking to make the scene more diverse with a separate competition called VCT Game Changers, which it says will “create competitive opportunities for women and marginalized genders within &lt;em&gt;Valorant&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2CDtjI"&gt;The program will include a series of “top tier” competitions throughout 2021, but perhaps more important is an academy series designed to foster new talent. Here’s how Riot describes it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="WG1o3u"&gt;The VCT Game Changers Academy program will host monthly tournaments, giving players even more opportunities to compete at the semi-pro and grassroots level. Academy events will be organized in partnership with GALORANTs, one of the largest communities within &lt;em&gt;Valorant&lt;/em&gt;. GALORANTs previously helped organize the “For the Women Summer Showdown” tournament in September 2020. Both the VCT Game Changers Series and Academy will help build the next generation of leaders who aspire to succeed with the competitive &lt;em&gt;Valorant&lt;/em&gt; community. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="ejWQgf"&gt;Women-centric esports competitions &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/22/20925850/girl-gamer-esports-festival-madrid-league-of-legends-fortnite-overwatch"&gt;aren’t a new phenomenon&lt;/a&gt;, as the scene is still largely male-dominated across the biggest games, whether it’s &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/2/14/17011504/overwatch-league-first-woman-player-geguri-shanghai-dragons"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/2/20751540/fortnite-world-cup-women-esports-gen-g-faze-clan-ewok"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. But as a relatively new game, having launched last year, &lt;em&gt;Valorant&lt;/em&gt; is in a potentially good place to cultivate a more diverse player base. In fact, there are already positive signs; when esports organization Evil Geniuses entered the professional &lt;em&gt;Valorant&lt;/em&gt; scene, it did so with a mixed-gender roster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yZ1sfL"&gt;“Competing in games as a woman can be a daunting task, oftentimes resulting in a very real competitive disadvantage,” &lt;em&gt;Valorant &lt;/em&gt;executive producer Anna Donlon said in a statement. “While we’re addressing this challenge in-game, with improvements to chat, voice communications, and mitigation of griefing, we also see an opportunity to take another step with esports.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WT8RwR"&gt;Riot says the program will be a “year-long effort.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="rlJvb1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"This 26-year-old CEO is helping esports grow up","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22291714/esports-evil-geniuses-ceo-nicole-lapointe-jameson-interview"},{"title":"This infamous Counter-Strike team helped pave the way for women in esports","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/24/20707166/les-seules-counter-strike-esports-women"},{"title":"No women competed at the Fortnite World Cup, but top players want to change that","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/2/20751540/fortnite-world-cup-women-esports-gen-g-faze-clan-ewok"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22296977/valorant-vct-game-changers-esports-tournament-women"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22296977/valorant-vct-game-changers-esports-tournament-women</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-23T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-23T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Razer’s Kiyo Pro doesn’t deliver all the goods a $200 webcam should</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;This lens-shaped webcam has some tricks up its sleeve, but at a high cost&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="ltQ2OA"&gt;Razer has released a swath of products so far during the pandemic, but its new Kiyo Pro might have the widest appeal of them all. It’s a new $199 webcam that looks like a lens ripped off a mirrorless camera, aimed to give Logitech’s Brio some good competition in the specs department. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2017/2/7/14531452/logitech-brio-4k-pro-webcam"&gt;four-year-old Brio&lt;/a&gt; is still the ideal choice if you value 4K capture and Windows Hello authentication, but the Kiyo Pro is no slouch, capable of streaming or recording 1080p footage at up to 60 frames per second, with an optional HDR mode that displays at 30 frames per second. Razer’s new webcam is a more compact alternative, and it has a few other features that might make it worth considering if you want a high-end webcam for more than just joining Zoom calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j37Vsy"&gt;The Kiyo Pro is being positioned as a good choice both for jumping into a meeting and for people who have hobbies or careers broadcasting their faces. It’s backing up that claim with a few features that I’ve been able to test over the past few days. One of them is its adjustable field of view (FOV), letting you swap between 80 degrees for a tighter crop of your face, a midrange 90-degree shot, or up to a super-wide 103 degrees. The latter option is nice if more than one person is in the shot or if you want to show off your living space. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xh8I4C"&gt;You can adjust these settings and more from within Razer’s Synapse, though annoyingly, that software didn’t always reflect changes I made to the settings in the camera preview. Strangely, I had to join a Zoom call to see changes take effect. I understand there are people who don’t want to fuss with software, and so you know, this is a plug-and-play device for Windows 10 and macOS. That said, it’ll be at a fixed FOV, and the suite of settings that I detail below won’t be available to you unless you get Razer’s software. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="IoKnK4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10355570"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="j3XFFf"&gt;This webcam features a 2.1-megapixel CMOS IMX327 autofocusing sensor with an f/2.0 aperture, covered in a sheet of Gorilla Glass 3, which is admittedly an odd feature for a camera that doesn’t move. It utilizes Sony’s Starvis technology, typically used in security cams, that makes it good at picking out details in low light and balancing light sources for a true-to-life picture. I was impressed with its ability to automatically make the dreadful lighting in my basement studio apartment look alright, with a few small tweaks by me in the brightness and saturation departments). So, I imagine people with ideal lighting will fare even better and possibly not have to adjust settings at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="PoiAjt"&gt;&lt;q&gt;noticeably smoother and more detailed than any laptop webcam&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aiFIRQ"&gt;During some Zoom calls with the Kiyo Pro, none of the participants were blown away by the visual fidelity. They did, however, remark that it’s noticeably smoother and more detailed in terms of color accuracy than any laptop webcam, and especially given my apartment’s lighting situation (almost all artificial lights, with little natural light coming in), my picture looked lively.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Razer Kiyo Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jz4Fh49d_k_KD3DsTQVRFtJtxjg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22320630/Kiyo_12200_R1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Razer&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Kiyo Pro connects via USB-C, shipping with USB-C to Type-A cable and a lens cover.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="OYIDfk"&gt;Even with a bright window behind me that usually gets over-exposed by just about any laptop’s webcam, this camera balanced my apartment’s lighting without blowing out the background or dropping off in terms of detail. If you’re a game streamer with a vibrant set of colorful LEDs set up around your rig, this feature should be beneficial to you, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="afQNKp"&gt;The autofocus works relatively quickly, and it didn’t have to spend long clearing up the shot when I held an object close to the sensor, then pulled it away so it could refocus on my face. However, the autofocus tends to jump around a lot, hunting for a clearer shot even if I’m barely moving. This was perhaps the most annoying part of the experience for me, but it’s a small consolation that Synapse lets you set it to manual focus if you don’t plan to move all that much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wpJWJp"&gt;This webcam features omnidirectional microphones, though I highly recommend using a dedicated microphone or a headset equipped with one instead. What’s built into the Kiyo Pro is good in a pinch, and there’s a good amount of bass and clarity in my voice, but it’s a little quiet and echo-y by default. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Razer Kiyo Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/N8bca6H4ql71R6eQMT4B48MpnuY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22319959/cfaulkner_210219_4432_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Resist the urge to twist the Kiyo Pro like a traditional camera lens. It’s unfortunately just for show.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="oYxWKH"&gt;Razer’s Kiyo Pro is a competent webcam with a few unique traits. At $200, it obviously can’t compete with the fidelity of a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21244380/webcam-camera-how-to-dslr-mirrorless-capture-card-usb-hdmi"&gt;DSLR or mirrorless camera that’s been repurposed as a webcam&lt;/a&gt; or even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21281765/webcam-phone-tablet-android-ios-pc-mac-how-to"&gt;a modern smartphone with webcam apps installed&lt;/a&gt;. But for the cost, it should stack up better than it does to Logitech’s Brio released in 2017. Instead, Razer made an equally pricey webcam with fewer features. If webcams ever become as tough to find in stock as they were in early 2020, it’ll be nice to have another option on the market. But presently, it’s tough to recommend this model outright.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22295235/razer-kiyo-pro-webcam-review-adjustable-field-of-view-streaming-zoom-video-calls-price-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22295235/razer-kiyo-pro-webcam-review-adjustable-field-of-view-streaming-zoom-video-calls-price-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
