<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2022-01-04T15:03:47-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-04T15:03:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-04T15:03:47-05:00</updated>
    <title>OPI announces Xbox-inspired nail polish that unlocks in-game content</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RtZHPhiBEmO4cQ1iNrYUebUOxIU=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70347332/OPI_xbox_Hero_Image.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The line consists of 12 colors with cheesy gaming-inspired names.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Xbox/OPI&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="irA3HC"&gt;OPI and Xbox are &lt;a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2022/01/04/xbox-opi-nail-polish-collection-spring-2022/"&gt;collaborating on a new lineup of gaming-inspired nail polishes&lt;/a&gt; that also unlock in-game content for &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt;. The vibrant line of 12 nail polish colors is available today in the US at Ulta Beauty. Purchasing colors in the line qualifies for redeemable codes to unlock an exclusive Ford GT livery in &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt; as well as an armor coating in &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Azl6cm"&gt;The OPI x Xbox collection colors have some unique names, ranging from lighthearted and fun to full-on gamer cringe: Quest for Quartz (rose quartz), Pixel Dust (shimmery mauve pink), Racing for Pinks (crème rose), Suzi is My Avatar (pink-nude), Trading Paint (crème apricot), Heart and Con-soul (crimson), The Pass is Always Greener (pastel green), Sage Simulation (sage green), You Had Me at Halo (shimmery blue and actually clever), Can’t CTRL Me (robin egg blue), Achievement Unlocked (what?), and NOOberry (please stop). They are offered in three different formulas: GelColor, Infinite Shine, and Nail Lacquer. Prices range from $10.50 to $13 each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mKBtXY"&gt;The polishes are at first exclusive in the USA to &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ulta.com%2Fp%2Fxbox-nail-lacquer-collection-pimprod2030261&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2022%2F1%2F4%2F22866727%2Fxbox-opi-halo-infinite-forza-horizon-5-nail-polish-dlc-news-announcement" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ulta Beauty&lt;/a&gt;, with global availability at more retailers opening up on February 1st — at which point the redeemable in-game content for &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite &lt;/em&gt;and&lt;em&gt; Forza Horizon 5 &lt;/em&gt;goes live&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://terms.snipp.com/Microsoft%20Activation%202005791/Microsoft%20Xbox%20OPI%20US%20-%20Ulta%20Promotions%20T&amp;amp;C's.pdf"&gt;OPI’s terms and conditions&lt;/a&gt; indicate that you have to buy $20 or more of qualifying products to earn the Forza Horizon 5 paint job, and customers have until March 31st to &lt;a href="https://ulta.opixboxrewards.com/"&gt;submit and claim the promo on the entry page&lt;/a&gt;. It is not yet clear how the downloadable coating for &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite &lt;/em&gt;can be redeemed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qDQXVw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10961225"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zfJTNu"&gt;This collaboration is one of many &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite &lt;/em&gt;cross-marketing tie-ins, where buying toys and collectibles like a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22820219/guilty-pleasures-ice-halo-dyson-sims"&gt;NERF gun&lt;/a&gt; or a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/HALO-Legends-Master-Spartan-Collection/dp/B085QM1NJX?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Master Chief figure&lt;/a&gt; comes with a redeemable code for weapon or armor coatings. Much like the popular &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/NERF-NER-Halo-MA40/dp/B08486XL7R?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;NERF Halo MA40 Assault Rifle&lt;/a&gt;, the best color of the bunch — You Had Me At Halo — is already &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ulta.com%2Fp%2Fxbox-nail-lacquer-collection-pimprod2030261&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2022%2F1%2F4%2F22866727%2Fxbox-opi-halo-infinite-forza-horizon-5-nail-polish-dlc-news-announcement" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;sold out at Ulta&lt;/a&gt;. Anyone else considering painting their nails just because that shimmery Spartan armor looks so sick?&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22866727/xbox-opi-halo-infinite-forza-horizon-5-nail-polish-dlc-news-announcement"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22866727/xbox-opi-halo-infinite-forza-horizon-5-nail-polish-dlc-news-announcement</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-04T15:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-04T15:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The latest Asus ROG Zephyrus G14 and G15 add a webcam</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Asus ROG Zephyrus G14 (2022)" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9xRxzxBtSjyOfYR0l1rtfpQvOB0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70347292/g14hero.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sure, you could play Titanfall 2, but many newer games should run just fine here.&lt;/em&gt; | Asus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8748Cg"&gt;Asus has delivered some big upgrades to its ROG Zephyrus G14 and G15 laptops for 2022. These lines have already been beloved for great battery life, solid performance for gaming and creative work, and aggressive pricing. The most notable feature improvements for both laptops include the Windows Hello IR camera (both laptops previously omitted a webcam), while the G14, with its 14-inch display, has a 50 percent bigger trackpad, along with a jump to 16:10 aspect ratio displays from its previous 16:9 (the G15, which has a 15.6-inch display, is still 16:9).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7flGRD"&gt;That’s not all, though. The G14 features up to AMD’s new Ryzen 9 6900HS processor, paired with a Radeon RX 6800S graphics chip. This offers 105W of graphical power by taking advantage of the AMD-exclusive SmartShift and SmartAccess Memory features that allocate power where it’s needed most. In fact, the G14 for 2022 seems to be an all-AMD affair, and it’s far from the only laptop like this announced at CES 2022. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22622823"&gt;Alienware’s M17 R5 Ryzen Edition&lt;/a&gt; might interest you if you want an even more powerful (and bigger) laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Asus ROG Zephyrus G14 and G15" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zLk0upBYfIV--uvJAUCGf49CB5A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23142273/g14g15together.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Asus&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;2022’s G14 and G15 sitting side-by-side.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="PfjAmb"&gt;On the other hand, the larger G15 can sport up to AMD’s Ryzen 9 6900HS and up to Nvidia’s new RTX 3080 Ti. While that model lacks the SmartShift feature, its GPU can be boosted to pull 120W of power, which should deliver great results that, like last year’s model, will likely defy its thin size. Both the G14 and G15 have MUX switches that’ll let you manually toggle between integrated and dedicated graphics options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SYMEga"&gt;Focusing on displays, the G14 has received more love than the G15, featuring (at the high end) a 16:10 aspect ratio QHD display with a 120Hz refresh rate, a peak brightness of 500 nits, 100 percent coverage of the DCI-P3 color gamut, and Dolby Vision support. A 16:10 1080p panel will also be available, featuring a 144Hz refresh rate, 450 nits of peak brightness, and 100 percent coverage of the sRGB color gamut. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eUsQyp"&gt;The G15’s display is still in the 16:9 aspect ratio, and it comes in one configuration: QHD resolution with a 240Hz refresh rate, 300 nits of peak brightness, and 100 percent coverage of the DCI-P3 color space. It’s worth noting that this display supports Dolby Vision and adaptive sync. All displays mentioned in this paragraph have a 3ms response time and are Pantone-validated for color accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Asus ROG Zephyrus G14" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-roaaPujzF3g5wlnVV42dPqs4Pw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23142277/g14topdown.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Asus&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A top-down view of the G14. Note the bigger trackpad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="tQ6uCk"&gt;The G14 and G15 start to look similar when it comes to the configurable RAM, storage, and port selection. Both can support up to 32GB of fast DDR5 memory clocked at 4,800MHz (up to 16GB of it will be soldered to the board, leaving one slot for you to use later on). You can use PCIe 4.0 M.2 2280-sized SSDs in the G14 and G15, though the G14 has only one slot (1TB max), and the G15 features two slots with RAID 0 support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S473lJ"&gt;Both laptops feature two USB-C 3.2 Gen 2 ports with DisplayPort 1.4 video output and PD charging at up to 100W. You’ll also find two USB-A 3.2 Gen 2 ports, an HDMI 2.0b port, a UHS-II microSD card reader, and a headphone combo jack. The G15 has an RJ45 ethernet port.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="odn2SP"&gt;As for battery life, Asus asserts that the G14’s 76Wh battery should offer over 10 hours of video playback. If this laptop is anything like previous versions, it should last nearly that long for other tasks, too. The G15’s 90Wh battery can last up to 14 hours by the same metric.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Asus ROG Zephyrus G15" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wTHKiHtFgtLstA6QSpRsBpVwsB8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23142280/g15animematrix.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Asus&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Both the G14 and G15 can be tricked out with the improved Anime Matrix LEDs to give your machine a unique look.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7QZXPi"&gt;Asus is giving people the option to buy the stock G14 or G15 or trick it out with the Anime Matrix LED lighting on the lid’s exterior for a flashier design. The company says it has increased the number of LEDs to 1,449 (a 19 percent boost) and “more than doubled” the number of holes in the matrix to allow for better-looking animations. To that end, it has added new animations, virtual pets, and mini games that can be controlled with a mouse. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uW1XQT"&gt;Asus says that these models won’t ship until mid to late 2022, and it didn’t share pricing for any of these models, but we’ll be testing them as soon as the company can accommodate us, so we can report as to whether these are 2022’s definitive gaming laptops or not.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22864968/asus-rog-zephyrus-g14-g15-gaming-laptop-2022-webcam-amd-16-10-aspect-ratio-specs-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22864968/asus-rog-zephyrus-g14-g15-gaming-laptop-2022-webcam-amd-16-10-aspect-ratio-specs-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-04T15:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-04T15:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Asus’ ROG Flow Z13 is a powerful gaming tablet that can connect to an RTX 3080</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Asus ROG Flow Z13" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WSUTXvZQDZP5V4NTLuq6Elkl6TI=/0x0:5935x3957/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70347301/z13flow3.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just playing co-op Spiritfarer while enjoying Asus-branded chips and soda. Hit me up on my Asus phone if you want to chill.&lt;/em&gt; | Asus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Vmw5Or"&gt;The iPad Pro is likely the most powerful gaming tablet you can currently buy — and likely the most popular — but Asus is announcing a Windows-based gaming tablet that may go toe-to-toe in terms of power but will vastly exceed Apple’s tablet in terms of game and accessory compatibility on day one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P1C9hp"&gt;The ROG Flow Z13 has been announced at CES 2022, and it’s a tablet with a 13.4-inch display and a kickstand. Impressively, Asus will offer configurations of the Z13 with Intel’s Core i9-12900H 45W processor and Nvidia’s RTX 3050 Ti with 40W of total graphics power — both of which are incredible achievements in a 12mm-thick tablet. The Z13 is essentially a high-end gaming laptop that’s been crammed into a much thinner form factor, complete with a few other trends from CES 2022, like fast DDR5 RAM and PCIe 4.0 storage. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Asus ROG Flow Z13" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jAQ0dom4aqGzkli-y6pIXOyHsJY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23142554/z13flow2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Asus&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The ROG Flow Z13 comes with a detachable keyboard that has per-key RGB backlighting.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="YgJkKn"&gt;The Z13 is a wholly original product in Asus’ lineup, but it builds on the coolest feature of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22249408/asus-rog-flow-x13-review-price-specs-features"&gt;Flow X13, Asus’ 2-in-1 laptop&lt;/a&gt;: being able to connect to an external GPU enclosure for faster, better graphics via a proprietary port. Asus’ XG Mobile eGPU kit can connect to the Z13 to deliver RTX 3080 graphics (or AMD’s Radeon RX 6850M XT, which is new for 2022) via the aforementioned proprietary port that connects directly to the card with a PCIe 3.0 connection with eight lanes for data throughput. That’s cool and all, but it’ll likely cost you a fortune. Last year, my colleague Monica Chin &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22249408/asus-rog-flow-x13-review-price-specs-features"&gt;priced the kit&lt;/a&gt; including the 2021 ROG Flow X13 and the XG Mobile eGPU at $3,299.99, and the Z13 will likely cost more given its thinner, more ambitious design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="cCEMQK"&gt;&lt;q&gt;This might be Asus’ most ambitious gamble for CES 2022&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="D38gk7"&gt;The ROG Flow Z13 can be configured with a 1080p IPS touchscreen with a 120Hz refresh rate and 100 percent sRGB coverage with 500 nits of brightness. For better picture quality, you can get a 4K IPS touchscreen with just a 60Hz refresh rate, which covers 85 percent of the DCI-P3 color space and has a peak brightness of 450 nits. Both screen types are Gorilla Glass-covered, validated by Pantone for color accuracy, and have a 16:10 aspect ratio, and all configurations of the Z13 come with a detachable keyboard that offers per-key RGB backlighting.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Asus ROG Flow Z13" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RGAJZ6ThswCKp2TdjBuicGEg8ss=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23142558/z13flow4.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Asus&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Xpxi3h"&gt;In terms of ports, the Z13 has one Thunderbolt 4 port with DisplayPort 1.4 for video output (it taps the integrated graphics) and up to 100W PD charging, while another USB-C 3.2 Gen 2 port can handle video (tapping the dedicated graphics) and PD charging. According to materials provided by Asus to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, there’s a third USB-C port that can handle video and PD charging, but it doesn’t clarify whether it utilizes integrated or dedicated graphics. To round out the I/O, there’s an eGPU port, one USB-A 2.0 port, a UHS-II class microSD card reader, an HDMI 2.0 port, and a headphone jack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rSNdY5"&gt;If you want to learn more about the Flow Z13 this week, including getting an in-depth look at the tablet, stay tuned to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. The Z13 will be available in Q1 or Q2 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22865259/asus-rog-flow-z13-detachable-tablet-rtx-graphics-intel-12th-gen-gaming-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22865259/asus-rog-flow-z13-detachable-tablet-rtx-graphics-intel-12th-gen-gaming-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-04T15:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-04T15:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Asus has announced the first 42-inch 4K OLED gaming monitor</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Asus PG42UQ gaming monitor" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kAp1l3IiO82PKoIOVPzcecGguYM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70347296/pg42uqdisplay.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Asus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="37cKVH"&gt;At CES 2022, Asus announced the ROG Swift OLED gaming monitor that comes in a 48-inch (PG48UQ) or a 42-inch (PG42UQ) size. Now, 48-inch OLEDs aren’t novel at this point, but the 42-inch size is a brand-new innovation for 2022. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/3/22856102/lg-97-42-inch-oled-4k-8k-qned-tvs-announced-features"&gt;LG debuted its 42-inch C2 OLED this week&lt;/a&gt;, and Asus says it’s the first company to adapt a similarly-sized model into its own product. Asus hasn’t shared a release date or price for these monitors, but you know the usual disclaimer about OLEDs: don’t expect them to be cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QAgHCw"&gt;The PG42UQ, like the 48-inch model, has a 4K (3840 x 2160) display, an impressive 1,000,000 to 1 contrast ratio, a lightning-fast 0.1ms response time, a 120Hz refresh rate, 10-bit color with 98 percent coverage of the DCI-P3 color space, and HDR10 support. In terms of ports, both sizes include two HDMI 2.1 ports, two HDMI 2.0 ports, one DisplayPort jack, audio inputs, and a USB hub. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4RZWwr"&gt;Additionally, Asus says that its displays are anti-glare and covered with a micro-texture coating to ensure you see the best color accuracy. These monitors also support variable refresh rate and auto low latency modes, both of which you’ll definitely want in a monitor that’ll likely cost as much as these will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OuqIwM"&gt;We’ve reached out to Asus to find out exactly which gaming-focused features these monitors will offer compared to your other option, which is just buying one of LG’s new 42-inch C2 OLED TVs.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22867178/asus-oled-gaming-monitor-42-48-inch-4k-hdmi-2-1-vrr-allm-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22867178/asus-oled-gaming-monitor-42-48-inch-4k-hdmi-2-1-vrr-allm-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-04T14:58:54-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-04T14:58:54-05:00</updated>
    <title>China launches iPhone and Android apps for its digital currency</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="E-CNY App" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y4e_BYJTjmcR5EJVt5qnFHmWhzg=/0x30:4536x3054/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70347284/1237534100.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Liu Junfeng / Costfoto/Future Publishing via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="A2PvGd"&gt;China has rolled out a pilot version of an app that allows users to store and pay with digital yuan, also known as e-CNY, as reported by the &lt;a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3162094/china-digital-currency-e-cny-wallet-lands-app-stores-ahead-winter"&gt;&lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. And no, the digital yuan isn’t a cryptocurrency — it was developed by the People’s Bank of China (PBOC) to replace banknotes and coins; thus, it isn’t a decentralized form of payment, nor will it operate on the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xnnz0d"&gt;Although it might sound like we already pay with digital cash when we use a credit card or an online payment service like PayPal and Apple Pay, the digital yuan isn’t anything like that. e-CNY is essentially physical cash converted into a digital form, and it’s been in the works since 2014. According to &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/03/05/chinas-digital-yuan-what-is-it-and-how-does-it-work.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, distribution of the digital currency will take place using a two-tier system that transfers e-CNY from the PBOC to commercial banks. Banks will then distribute the currency directly to consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ROAvbN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;As we get closer to the Beijing Olympics, China may use the currency as a way for visitors to easily make payments&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5lvPyq"&gt;Since the e-CNY isn’t a decentralized currency like bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies, it doesn’t promise the same kind of privacy. The &lt;a href="https://www.db.com/news/detail/20210714-digital-yuan-what-is-it-and-how-does-it-work"&gt;Deutsche Bank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; s&lt;/em&gt;ays it will have “controlled anonymity,” meaning users can choose to conceal their identities from counterparties, but it will still let the authorities monitor transactions for illegal activities like money laundering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jdVLGG"&gt;Digital payment apps like WeChat and AliPay already have a strong foothold in China, with around &lt;a href="https://www.statista.com/chart/17409/most-popular-digital-payment-services-in-china/"&gt;nine in 10 Chinese people&lt;/a&gt; saying they used either app within the past year. It might seem unlikely for the Chinese to want to switch over to the digital yuan, but China has been working hard to promote it. Within the past two years, cities throughout China have even been holding lotteries, distributing a total of &lt;a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3104832/chinas-shenzhen-giving-away-millions-sovereign-digital-yuan"&gt;10 million digital yuan (worth about $1.47 million USD at the time)&lt;/a&gt; to people in Shenzen in October 2020, &lt;a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3112724/chinese-city-hand-out-virtual-red-packets-part-digital-yuan"&gt;20 million digital yuan (or ~$3 million USD)&lt;/a&gt; in Suzhou in December 2020, and &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/02/24/chinese-city-chengdu-launches-6-million-digital-currency-test.html"&gt;40.2 million digital yuan (or ~$6.2 million)&lt;/a&gt; in Chengdu in February 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aJDOyi"&gt;Last September, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-09-14/digital-yuan-goes-head-to-head-with-alipay-wechat-in-beijing"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; covered a trade fair in Beijing, where attendees were shown how to sign up for an account, as well as the many ways to use the digital currency — this includes wearables that users can tap against scanners to pay with e-CNY. As noted in the report, users can fill up their AliPay account with the currency, which suggests both forms of payment might have more of a symbiotic relationship rather than a competitive one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BrnIQy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; even describes how some banks at the event demonstrated how foreigners could sign up for an e-CNY account using their passport and phone number, as well as convert foreign currency to e-CNY. As we get closer to the 2022 Beijing Winter Olympics, this may be a way for China to leverage the currency as a way for visitors to easily make payments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TGs3Jr"&gt;The new e-CNY app is available on both China’s Android and Apple app stores, but only people in 10 specific cities, including Beijing, Shenzen, Chengdu, and Shanghai, can use it. And as pointed out by &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2022/01/04/china-launches-digital-currency-app-to-expand-usage.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the app will be available to use during the upcoming Olympics.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22866757/china-digital-currency-yuan-iphone-android-apps"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22866757/china-digital-currency-yuan-iphone-android-apps</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-04T14:44:45-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-04T14:44:45-05:00</updated>
    <title>Qualcomm is expanding its automotive platforms with new Volvo, Honda, Renault deals</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZZl7gRUjGa16RvHEe_tWIbFLV8Q=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70347236/Snapdragon_Digital_Chassis_Render_01.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Qualcomm’s vision of a Digital Chassis vehicle | Image: Qualcomm&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="AK8n7L"&gt;Qualcomm has announced several new expansions of its partnerships with major car companies to provide hardware and software platforms for connected vehicles at CES 2022, partnering with Volvo, Honda, and Renault to add more functionality to their upcoming cars. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KS5BUT"&gt;Qualcomm already has a full suite of automotive platforms, which it collectively calls the Qualcomm Digital Chassis. The goal is to provide automakers with a variety of tools they can use to help make their cars more intelligent and more connected (although companies can pick and choose which of the platforms they want to use). &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zk1pmFKkiglDrR1_dyvXC9so1XQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23145116/Screen_Shot_2022_01_04_at_2.25.06_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XkRWU4"&gt;Those include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="XGdRJf"&gt;Snapdragon Ride, which provides driver assistance and automated driving technologies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xCqPeH"&gt;Snapdragon Cockpit, for in-car experiences, including SoCs and software solutions for powering multiple displays and audio / video / multimedia &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Xj2u6u"&gt;Snapdragon Auto Connectivity, for providing automakers with LTE, 5G, Wi-Fi, and GPS solutions for connecting cars to the internet, cloud, and other vehicles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DZoc6L"&gt;Snapdragon Car-to-Cloud Services, which provides security features and a platform for adding over-the-air updates and paid services, in addition to vehicle and user analytics, so that automakers can monetize more of their vehicles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="faJyzL"&gt;Honda, for example, announced at CES 2022 that it’ll be using Qualcomm’s third-generation Snapdragon Cockpit platform to power its Android-based infotainment system in upcoming cars coming to the US in the second half of 2022 and in early 2023. Volvo announced a similar plan at the conference, working with both Qualcomm and Google to offer Android infotainment systems in its upcoming Polestar 3 SUV and Volvo’s planned fully electric SUV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aQScAq"&gt;Renault, on the other hand, is planning a more comprehensive adoption of Qualcomm’s Digital Chassis, intending on using Qualcomm’s platforms for connectivity, driver assistance, cockpit experiences, and cloud services on upcoming Renault vehicles. The new deals join existing deals Qualcomm has with other major carmakers, including BMW, GM, Hyundai, and more. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22865630/qualcomm-automotive-platforms-digital-chassis-volvo-honda-renault-ces-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22865630/qualcomm-automotive-platforms-digital-chassis-volvo-honda-renault-ces-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-04T14:40:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-04T14:40:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix memo encourages recruiters to avoid talking about Dave Chappelle</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2edY7dh6opwAbkvMkj89qPuFFw4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70347211/acastro_181101_1777_netflix_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="M858JZ"&gt;Netflix sent recruiters talking points on how to avoid discussing &lt;em&gt;The Closer &lt;/em&gt;with job candidates, according to a leaked memo obtained by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. The memo tells members of the talent acquisition team not to comment on Dave Chappelle’s stand-up set, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/11/22720724/netflix-suspends-trans-employee-tweeted-dave-chappelle-the-closer"&gt;sparked a national conversation&lt;/a&gt; about transphobia, cancel culture, and comedy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7nZuww"&gt;“Find a way to respectfully end and move on from the topic if you’re pressed further on the topic in areas not covered in the talking points,” the memo reads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zk4iYW"&gt;In a section titled “&lt;em&gt;The Closer&lt;/em&gt; and employees,” Netflix encourages recruiters to state: “We value our trans colleagues and allies, and understand the deep hurt that’s been caused. We respect the decision of any employee who chose to walk out, and recognize we have much more work to do both within Netflix and in our content.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6SwsNc"&gt;The memo hints at concerns Netflix might have had regarding its ability to hire in the wake of the Dave Chappelle controversy. While the issue did not translate into a business problem for the company in terms of known account cancellations, it appears some executives worried it could dissuade talent from wanting to join the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mhiitz"&gt;Historically, Netflix prided itself on being able to hire and retain top talent by paying above market rates, according to CEO Reed Hastings’ book &lt;em&gt;No Rules Rules&lt;/em&gt;. But after the company released &lt;em&gt;The Closer&lt;/em&gt; and doubled down on its support of Chappelle, at least two trans engineers resigned. Another trans employee, B. Pagels-Minor, was fired. (The company said Pagels-Minor had allegedly leaked confidential information — a charge the employee denied.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hnx1Bi"&gt;In the memo, Netflix told recruiters to respond to questions about the termination by saying, “We have let go of an employee for sharing confidential, commercially sensitive information outside the company. We understand they may have been motivated by disappointment and hurt with Netflix, but maintaining a culture of trust and transparency is core to our company.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y9jI88"&gt;The memo says that if pressed, recruiters should add “this employee was the only person to access this specific information and admitted to sharing confidential information externally.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RYalNw"&gt;Pagels-Minor filed an unfair labor practice charge against Netflix after they were terminated. They have since settled with the streaming giant and voluntarily withdrawn the charge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KqKVrX"&gt;Read the full memo below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="iHmv6M"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10961237"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Og4oTF"&gt;Netflix declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22867109/netflix-memo-leaked-dave-chappelle-the-closer-recruitment-hiring"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22867109/netflix-memo-leaked-dave-chappelle-the-closer-recruitment-hiring</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-04T14:19:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-04T14:19:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>Today I learned about the attempts to make goldfish mech suits</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hQ5KbAnVjEnvfFp_g7naq4TydCA=/0x98:1302x966/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70347062/Screen_Shot_2022_01_03_at_17.19.53.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This robot follows the fish.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/ronen_segev" target="_blank"&gt;@ronen_segev&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="f3SbqE"&gt;Something interesting swam across my Twitter feed recently: a video of a goldfish that seemed to be controlling a robotic fish tank with wheels, with the contraption following the direction the fish was swimming. “Oh no,” I thought. “They gave this goldfish a robot, and now it’s unstoppable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Thfc6R"&gt;Thankfully, it doesn’t seem like it was done as a part of some evil plot. The goldfish mech suit was posted by Ronen Segev, a researcher on a team that was looking into how animals navigate. Helpfully, Segev links to &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0166432821005994?dgcid=author#fig0005"&gt;a full research paper&lt;/a&gt; in the Twitter thread, which should offer more insight into the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0uInJa"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;The fish were tasked to “drive” the vehicle towards a visual target in the terrestrial environment, which was observable through the walls of the tank. Indeed, the goldfish were able to explore the terrestrial environment, all while avoiding dead-ends and correcting inaccuracies. &lt;a href="https://t.co/RxPuzFbxkE"&gt;pic.twitter.com/RxPuzFbxkE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ronen Segev (@ronen_segev) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ronen_segev/status/1477889613045940224?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 3, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="g6c2Zu"&gt;The paper is officially titled “From fish out of water to new insights on navigation mechanisms in animals,” and its abstract describes why the researchers “trained goldfish to use a Fish Operated Vehicle (FOV).” They wanted to test its ability to do something familiar, navigating towards a target in an unfamiliar environment — in this case, land. To do this, the researchers tracked the fish’s movements with LIDAR, which let it “drive” towards a target that it could see outside of its tank. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VWqIPg"&gt;Returning to the Twitter thread, though, a comment caught my eye — no, not &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sandipb/status/1477982557388038144?s=20"&gt;the joke about &lt;em&gt;The Umbrella Academy&lt;/em&gt;’s Carmichael&lt;/a&gt;, though it did get a laugh out of me. It was a comment about how someone else had built a very similar contraption. In 2014, Studio diip &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YbNmL6hSNKw"&gt;released a video called Fish on Wheels&lt;/a&gt;, which was &lt;a href="https://www.studiodiip.com/portfolio-item/fish-on-wheels-2/"&gt;meant to show off computer vision tech&lt;/a&gt;. If you’ve watched Segev’s video, Fish on Wheels will seem pretty familiar; there’s a fish tank on wheels with a sensor that tracks the fish’s movement to steer the vehicle. (Can we call it a vehicle? Sure, why not.) Basically, Fish on Wheels is the same idea but built for a different reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x9PsYA"&gt;That’s when I started falling down the rabbit hole. Looking into Fish on Wheels led me to a third goldfish Gundam, this one made as part of Carnegie Mellon University’s Build18 engineering festival, according to &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_GDgmP1ac_A"&gt;a video posted of the project&lt;/a&gt; in 2017. &lt;a href="https://interestingengineering.com/video/this-goldfish-controls-a-robotic-tank-with-its-movement"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Interesting Engineering&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the robot was built in three days by students who “decided it would be awesome if he [the fish, named Walter] could hang out with us!” You can see the result below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="waazGm"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_GDgmP1ac_A?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cxurrh"&gt;And guess what — browsing &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/5pn4x1/my_friends_and_i_made_a_fish_controlled_robot/"&gt;a Reddit thread about that project&lt;/a&gt; unearthed &lt;em&gt;yet another&lt;/em&gt; person who made robotic fish bowls. This one was a 2004 art installation by Ken Rinaldo called “Augmented Fish Reality.” It featured &lt;em&gt;five&lt;/em&gt; robots controlled by &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Siamese_fighting_fish"&gt;betta fish&lt;/a&gt; and was “designed to explore interspecies and trans-species communication,” &lt;a href="https://www.kenrinaldo.com/portfolio/augmented-fish-reality/"&gt;according to Rinaldo’s website&lt;/a&gt;. Are there examples from even further back that I haven’t found? How do people &lt;em&gt;keep doing the same thing&lt;/em&gt; but seemingly for completely different reasons?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tla3rr"&gt;And after watching all these traveling fish, there’s one thing that I absolutely, desperately need to know: what would my cat do if he saw a goldfish rolling by in a robotic tank? &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22866037/goldfish-robot-mech-computer-vision-animal-navigation-til"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22866037/goldfish-robot-mech-computer-vision-animal-navigation-til</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-04T13:22:42-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-04T13:22:42-05:00</updated>
    <title>Anker’s new Nano II 100W USB-C charger is the smallest 100W GaN charger yet</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LaNOTmCNF-EbpnCbuXpRoPvAVoM=/20x0:797x518/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70346779/Screen_Shot_2022_01_04_at_1.14.13_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7hUU38"&gt;Anker has a new GaN charger that the company announced at CES 2022, the $79 Anker Nano II 100W (also known as the Anker 736 charger), which the company says is “the world’s smallest 100W gallium nitride wall charger.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="neTb2W"&gt;The new Nano II 100W charger offers a pair of USB-C ports and a single USB-A port, and it uses Anker’s second-generation GaN II technology that the company debuted earlier this year on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/24/22450999/anker-second-generation-nano-ii-gan-chargers-smaller"&gt;its other Nano II chargers&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="1p77cc"&gt;&lt;q&gt;More power in a smaller package&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="S4v4Ij"&gt;It’s also worth noting that the 100W output is only for a single device at once — if more than one gadget is plugged in, the Nano II 100W will divvy up wattage according. But the 100W output here is enough to charge most laptops at full speed, which is a nice improvement over Anker’s previous models. The new plug also features &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anker.com%2Fca%2Fpoweriq3&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2022%2F1%2F4%2F22866945%2Fanker-nano-ii-100w-usb-c-736-charger-smallest-ces-2022" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Anker’s PowerIQ 3.0 technology&lt;/a&gt; for optimizing charging, along with support for USB Power Delivery 3.0 PPS (programmable power standard), meaning it works with &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.samsung.com/global/galaxy/what-is/super-fast-charging/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung’s Super Fast Charging standard&lt;/a&gt;, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lCIOer"&gt;The new charger replaces Anker’s previous Nano II plug, the Anker Nano II 65W (also called the Anker 735 charger), which had a longer, thinner design and no fold-out plugs. The Nano II 100W, on the other hand, has a more traditional design to go with the increased 100W output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1l6ffI"&gt;The Anker 736 Nano II 100W is set to hit stores in March for $79. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22866945/anker-nano-ii-100w-usb-c-736-charger-smallest-ces-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22866945/anker-nano-ii-100w-usb-c-736-charger-smallest-ces-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-04T13:21:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-04T13:21:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>Anker’s new Video Bar is an all-in-one speaker, light, and webcam for your PC</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Anker Video Bar" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2ITSUZWRgTYxyX0pfjYUNXvJe1g=/0x0:900x600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70346773/videobar.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Anker&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9MFcsV"&gt;Anker has announced the B600 Video Bar, a nifty video conferencing toolkit that houses everything that meeting-goers need. It rests upon your monitor (or TV), and the webcam portion of the Video Bar features a 2K sensor capable of 30 frames per second capture. It offers field-of-view adjustment, autofocus, and like most fancy webcams these days, it supports an AI-powered zoom feature and image enhancement. Within the device, there’s also a microphone array. It uses an AI algorithm to make noisy environments sound quiet on the other end. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k8WRyk"&gt;The Video Bar also packs two features that aren’t commonly included with a webcam: a key light and speakers. I’d assume that a large percentage of people who work from home don’t have ideal lighting during their video calls, and this should help you look a bit more lively and, perhaps, a bit more professional. Anker touts a feature called MagicSight that’s offered in the Video Bar, which can make automatic lighting adjustments. There’s also a front-facing slider that can make lighting adjustments on the fly. More tweaks to color temperature and brightness can be made within an app. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PJOwkv"&gt;Those speakers that I mentioned early are just a nice perk. I doubt they provide amazing quality, but it’s probably going to be convenient for people who don’t like to manage cables. &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/ankers-new-2k-webcam-has-an-led-light-bar-to-make-you-l-1848227051"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;reports that the Video Bar will cost $220 and launch on January 25th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22866947/anker-b600-video-bar-webcam-key-light-speakers"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22866947/anker-b600-video-bar-webcam-key-light-speakers</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
