<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-20T16:23:33-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-20T16:23:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-20T16:23:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>eBay billionaire Pierre Omidyar is backing the Facebook whistleblower</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Facebook Whistle Blower Frances Haugen Testifies To Senate Committee" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Txo4c-dobgexlgcLWWsCNg7-Zl4=/0x0:3500x2333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70022327/1235714396.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Jabin Botsford-Pool/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ocL0Gm"&gt;Facebook whistleblower Frances Haugen &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/6/22711947/facebook-whistleblower-teens-safety-hearing-blumenthal-algorithms-harm"&gt;testified in front of Congress two weeks ago&lt;/a&gt; about the ways the company’s products can bring harm to users after leaking documents supporting her claims to &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-facebook-files-11631713039"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and the SEC. Now &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2021/10/20/tech-billionaire-aiding-facebook-whistleblower-516358"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Politico&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reports that the campaign to support Haugen’s advocacy has been aided by eBay billionaire Pierre Omidyar, as she takes on the place where she previously worked as a product manager assigned to the Civic Integrity group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ad8vAk"&gt;Omidyar is no stranger to the media, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/12/19/5227900/pierre-omidyars-news-project-gets-a-name-and-a-business-model"&gt;providing financial backing to&lt;em&gt; The Intercept&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, for example, and the open internet advocacy group &lt;a href="https://www.publicknowledge.org/"&gt;Public Knowledge&lt;/a&gt;. According to &lt;em&gt;Politico&lt;/em&gt;, when asked to comment, his advocacy group Omidyar Network &lt;a href="https://medium.com/omidyar-network/in-support-of-tech-whistleblowers-who-are-holding-tech-to-account-7fa5f66eac1c"&gt;pointed to an unbylined blog post&lt;/a&gt; that went up today titled “In Support of Tech Whistleblowers Who are Holding Tech to Account.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4HUA59"&gt;If you’re looking for a “why” behind the impactful rollout of Haugen’s testimony and the Facebook Files reported by the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://medium.com/omidyar-network/in-support-of-tech-whistleblowers-who-are-holding-tech-to-account-7fa5f66eac1c"&gt;the blog post&lt;/a&gt; lays out clear intentions for the machine behind everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AWTJTR"&gt;“With little competition, regulation, or other countervailing checks and balances, Big Tech has too much influence. Until recently, these platforms largely avoided meaningful public oversight, which has allowed them to do as they wish, often at the expense of consumers, start-ups, and their employees.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Em9htF"&gt;“Even as Big Tech’s reach has extended further and faster, it has remained largely opaque. We have had a nagging feeling that the harms they cause are known to them — and are far worse than the public could imagine. That has been validated as truth by a series of courageous whistleblowers who have spoken out and delivered evidence of wrongdoing and misconduct.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="p50VT4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Facebook encourages hate speech for profit, says whistleblower ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/3/22707860/facebook-whistleblower-leaked-documents-files-regulation"},{"title":"The whistleblower hearing hits Facebook where the company is weakest ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22710371/facebook-whistleblower-congress-hearing-instagram-kids-safety-privacy-blumenthal"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="EbP1se"&gt;The level of polish and coordination accompanying the rollout of the files has been evident, inviting open speculation about who is making Facebook’s nightmare month possible. Omidyar’s participation isn’t exactly a surprise — the Network &lt;a href="https://omidyar.com/news/roadmap-for-an-antitrust-case-against-facebook/"&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; a 39-page PDF last year titled “Roadmap for an Antitrust Case Against Facebook.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Oq3b6e"&gt;It’s unlikely that Omidyar and associated organizations are the only ones in play here either, as &lt;em&gt;Politico&lt;/em&gt; notes that Haugen’s schedule puts her, and her files, in front of a UK Parliament committee next week. Appearances in France and Belgium will follow next month, while &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/11/22721229/facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-instagram-oversight-board"&gt;an appointment with Facebook’s Oversight Board&lt;/a&gt; doesn’t have a date yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vI8mIW"&gt;That’s not even including an impending release of articles by multiple media outlets that Facebook communications VP John Pinette &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fbnewsroom/status/1450154006727200771"&gt;referred to as a “gotcha campaign”&lt;/a&gt; without describing what his company has been caught doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nSdMn1"&gt;Haugen’s method — and her proposed solutions for the problems she identifies — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/6/22712512/facebook-whistleblower-testimony-analysis-congress-instagram-whatsapp"&gt;can fall into more than one category&lt;/a&gt;. Still, a carefully executed media rollout has, so far, kept her claims from being ignored or forgotten. Senator Richard Blumenthal (D-CT) just &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22737081/facebook-instagram-mark-zuckerberg-testify-senate-child-safety-frances-haugen"&gt;sent out a request for Mark Zuckerberg and other Facebook execs to testify&lt;/a&gt; in response to the information revealed in the files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qiMSw4"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Facebook whistleblower hearing, explained|104211" data-volume-uuid="695bd1f60" data-volume-id="104211" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-271" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eGAdN6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22737042/facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-pierre-omidyar"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22737042/facebook-whistleblower-frances-haugen-pierre-omidyar</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-20T16:17:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-20T16:17:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla bucks chip shortage woes with another profitable quarter</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Tesla Model X redesign" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V259KuKqYZ2nsCvV02nNbB7F7fk=/90x0:2790x1800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70022625/MX_Exterior_Hero_Desktop.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Tesla&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MUDDl2"&gt;Tesla’s record third quarter brought its biggest three-month windfall ever, as the company &lt;a href="https://tesla-cdn.thron.com/static/TWPKBV_TSLA_Q3_2021_Quarterly_Update_SI1AKE.pdf"&gt;announced Wednesday&lt;/a&gt; that it turned a $1.6 billion profit. That’s despite a global semiconductor shortage and delays in the rollout of the refreshed Model S sedan and Model X SUV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8zXTeK"&gt;Tesla turned that profit on just over $13.7 billion in revenue, and did it while its average sales price continued to drop due to the increasing popularity of the more affordable Model 3 sedan and Model Y SUV. Tesla has also continued to increase the profitability of those vehicles — the company said Wednesday that the gross margin on its cars is up to nearly 30 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tbm6Py"&gt;Tesla’s success in the quarter stands in stark relief from the trouble other automakers have faced thanks to the chip shortage and larger global supply chain crunches. General Motors’ sales in the US dropped 33 percent compared to the same period last year, while Ford’s &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/10/04/fords-sales-improving-but-still-down-by-27point4percent-in-the-third-quarter.html"&gt;dropped about 27 percent&lt;/a&gt;. Tesla, meanwhile, increased its global deliveries to more than 241,000 in the quarter, continuing the automaker’s steady growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="1SRk47"&gt;
&lt;div id="datawrapper-1zGhU" data-analytics-viewport="datawrapper" data-iframe-fallback="https://img.datawrapper.de/1zGhU/full.png" data-iframe-fallback-width="700" data-iframe-fallback-height="600" data-iframe-fallback-alt="(billions in USD; green indicates profitable quarter)" data-iframe="https://datawrapper.dwcdn.net/1zGhU/1/" data-iframe-width="700" data-iframe-height="600" data-iframe-layout="responsive" data-iframe-title="Tesla's quarterly revenue and profit/loss" data-iframe-resizable=""&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;!function(){"use strict";window.addEventListener("message",function(a){if(void 0!==a.data["datawrapper-height"])for(var e in a.data["datawrapper-height"]){var t=document.getElementById("datawrapper-chart-"+e)||document.querySelector("iframe[src*='"+e+"']");t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data["datawrapper-height"][e]+"px")}});window.addEventListener('DOMContentLoaded',function(){var i=document.createElement("iframe");var e=document.getElementById("datawrapper-1zGhU");var t=e.dataset.iframeTitle||'Interactive graphic';i.setAttribute("src",e.dataset.iframe);i.setAttribute("title",t);i.setAttribute("frameborder","0");i.setAttribute("scrolling","no");i.setAttribute("aria-label",e.dataset.iframeFallbackAlt||t);i.setAttribute("title",t);i.setAttribute("height","400");i.setAttribute("id","datawrapper-chart-1zGhU");i.style.minWidth="100%";i.style.border="none";e.appendChild(i)})}()&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9LlJaq"&gt;By &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/2/22560608/tesla-q2-2021-deliveries-elon-musk"&gt;sourcing different chips and rewriting software on the fly&lt;/a&gt; to make them work, Tesla was able to avoid the same kinds of major headaches caused by the shortage. But its success in 2021 is also thanks to increased popularity of the Model Y SUV — which it &lt;a href="https://electrek.co/2021/08/23/tesla-tsla-starts-model-y-deliveries-europe/"&gt;just started selling in Europe&lt;/a&gt; and the UK — as well as a growing global presence. The company’s factory in China has been pumping out vehicles for more than a year now, and it has two more scheduled to come online in the near future in Texas and Germany. In fact, Tesla said Wednesday that it is already making some pre-production vehicles at the Austin, Texas factory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wOtNIt"&gt;“A variety of challenges, including semiconductor shortages, congestion at ports and rolling blackouts, have been impacting our ability to keep factories running at full speed. We believe our supply chain, engineering and production teams have been dealing with these global challenges with ingenuity, agility and flexibility that is unparalleled in the automotive industry,” the company wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GVOhlh"&gt;It wasn’t just a financially good quarter for Tesla, it was also a very busy one. In August, the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration opened a probe into the company’s Autopilot driver assistance system and its tendency to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22626819/tesla-autopilot-crash-emergency-vehicle-probe-nhtsa"&gt;crash into parked emergency vehicles&lt;/a&gt;, and two senators followed that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630954/markey-blumenthal-ftc-lina-khan-tesla-full-self-driving-musk"&gt;by asking the FTC to also investigate&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/8/22615539/tesla-cybertruck-production-delayed-2022-elon-musk"&gt;Cybertruck&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22653205/tesla-roadster-elon-musk-ship-delay-2023"&gt;next-gen Roadster&lt;/a&gt; were both delayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bs6GP1"&gt;Tesla also held an “AI Day” event where CEO Elon Musk detailed its artificial intelligence efforts and announced the company is starting to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22633514/tesla-robot-prototype-elon-musk-humanoid-ai-day"&gt;work on humanoid robots&lt;/a&gt;. Tesla said Wednesday that AI Day served its purpose as a recruiting event because it sparked an “overwhelming number of applications”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y62Gak"&gt;In September, the new head of the National Transportation Safety Board said she wanted Tesla to address “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/19/22682272/ntsb-official-tesla-safety-elon-musk-full-self-driving"&gt;basic safety issues&lt;/a&gt;” with its “Full Self-Driving” beta software before releasing it to more owners. Tesla went ahead and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/26/22693610/tesla-opens-full-self-driving-beta-software-more-customers"&gt;released it anyway&lt;/a&gt; — though it created a so-called “Safety Score” evaluation process that only allows drivers who drive a certain way to access the beta software. Tesla made owners sign &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22696463/tesla-fsd-beta-nda-video-clips-controversy-full-self-driving"&gt;nondisclosure agreements&lt;/a&gt; that discouraged them from sharing footage of the software performing poorly. But then Musk, speaking at Recode’s annual Code Conference, said owners &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22699361/elon-musk-tesla-full-self-driving-beta-nda-footage"&gt;weren’t following those instructions and backed off the practice&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SeWtHw"&gt;And just after the quarter ended, Musk announced that he was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22715458/tesla-move-headquarters-to-austin-texas"&gt;moving Tesla’s headquarters to Austin, Texas&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dgvnzz"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developing...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22736859/tesla-q3-earnings-profit-chip-shortage-sales-elon-musk"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22736859/tesla-q3-earnings-profit-chip-shortage-sales-elon-musk</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-20T16:06:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-20T16:06:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>VR treatment for lazy eye in children gets FDA approval</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q0z8ne3j2RHHxl3f9ANvf7tScfQ=/0x223:1348x1122/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70022560/easy_to_use.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Luminopia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QD26bT"&gt;The Food and Drug Administration approved a virtual reality-based treatment for children with the visual disorder amblyopia, or lazy eye, the company behind the therapy announced today. Patients watch modified TV shows or movies through a virtual reality headset to improve their vision. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O8ysu8"&gt;“We’re proud to be part of the FDA’s groundbreaking decision today, to approve a first-of-its-kind digital therapeutic that allows patients to watch their favorite TV shows and movies to improve their vision,” Scott Xiao, chief executive officer of Luminopia, the company that developed the tool, said &lt;a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20211020005896/en/Luminopia-Announces-FDA-Approval-of-Digital-Therapeutic-that-Uses-TV-Shows-to-Improve-Vision-in-Children-with-Lazy-Eye"&gt;in a statement&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="16kYlq"&gt;Around 3 percent of children have amblyopia, which develops when the brain and eyes stop communicating properly. The brain favors one eye, which leads to vision problems in the other eye. It’s the leading cause of vision problems in children. It’s usually treated by blocking the stronger eye with a patch or blurring drops, forcing the brain to rely on the weaker&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wpyFzx"&gt;Luminopia’s approach uses TV and movies to develop the weaker eye and train the eyes to work together. Patients watch the show or movie through a headset that shows the images to each eye separately. The images shown to the stronger eye have a lower contrast, and the images are presented with overlays that force the brain to use both eyes to see them properly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/N70MNtwRL4nYdx5jkXdKFWBCv9Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22942830/Screen_Shot_2021_10_20_at_3.29.20_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Ophthalmology, the journal of the American Academy of Ophthalmology&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An example of the video modifications used in the treatment.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HycKjd"&gt;Kids using the therapy and wearing glasses had more improvement in their vision than a similar group of kids who did not use the therapy and just wore corrective glasses full time during a &lt;a href="https://www.aaojournal.org/article/S0161-6420%2821%2900682-5/fulltext#appsec1"&gt;clinical trial&lt;/a&gt; of the technology. After 12 weeks watching the shows one hour per day, six days per week, 62 percent of kids using the treatment had a strong improvement in their vision. Only around a third of the kids in the comparison group had similar improvements over the course of the 12 weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BkSluz"&gt;Luminopia has over 700 hours of programming in its library, and it partnered with kids’ content distributors like Nelvana and Sesame Workshop to develop the tool. The authors of the clinical trial wrote that they think that the option to pick popular videos might be one reason users stuck to the program — people followed the treatment plan 88 percent of the time. Less than 50 percent of patients stick to eye patches or blurring drops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bivka5"&gt;With the approval, Luminopia joins &lt;a href="https://www.psychiatrictimes.com/view/digital-therapeutics-for-substance-use-disorders-from-research-to-practice"&gt;only a handful&lt;/a&gt; of companies with clearance to offer a digital therapeutic as a prescription treatment for medical conditions. Last year, the FDA approved a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/15/21292267/fda-adhd-video-game-prescription-endeavor-rx-akl-t01-project-evo"&gt;prescription video game&lt;/a&gt; called EndeavorRx, which treats ADHD in kids between eight and 12 years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tbzODw"&gt;Luminopia said in a statement that it plans to launch the treatment in 2022. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22736894/fda-vr-tv-movies-treatment-lazy-eye-amblyopia"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22736894/fda-vr-tv-movies-treatment-lazy-eye-amblyopia</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-20T15:58:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-20T15:58:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>Hyper’s new 245W USB-C battery pack and charger are here to help charge all your gear at once</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5TUdkT0CeMYrGnZ2TNVUnVtNhBg=/0x0:1200x800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70022497/unnamed.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="N3NMuz"&gt;Hyper has announced a &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.indiegogo.com%2Fprojects%2Fhyperjuice-245w-usb-c-battery-pack-gan-charger%3Futm_source%3DCE%2520Week%25202019%2520Media%26utm_medium%3Demail%26utm_campaign%3DIGG%2520245W%2520Press%2520Release%252010%252F20%252F21%2520%2528V5pTV6%2529%26_kx%3DOg8u1GQv7e7xvHJH0NQIEKiacDIMFRlM5SvWAf5Y_eTH8PB4Oyp4MB7tofUr_EYB.KdRC4D%23%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F20%2F22736571%2Fhyper-hyperjuice-245w-usb-c-battery-pack-charger-indiegogo" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;pair of over-the-top USB-C accessories&lt;/a&gt;: HyperJuice 245W USB-C Battery Pack and the HyperJuice 245W USB-C GaN Charger, each of which offers four USB-C ports for charging up all your gadgets at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SrEn4X"&gt;Despite the big “245W” in the names here, neither the new charger nor the new battery pack uses the recently released USB-C PD 3.1 spec that enables charging at up to 240W. Rather, the number refers to the total combined wattage that the new products can put out across the four total ports; each port still maxes out at 100W, though. (Which means that you won’t be able to use it for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734233/apple-140w-macbook-charging-brick-gan-usb-c-pd-3-1-third-party-chargers"&gt;140W fast charging&lt;/a&gt; on a new 16-inch MacBook Pro, for example.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M6srHZD-f53R-5CGdD8RcJip69I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22942909/Screen_Shot_2021_10_20_at_3.49.00_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="suC7g3"&gt;The HyperJuice 245W USB-C GaN Charger features four ports, each rated for 100W, although due to the vagaries of USB-C specs, the charging breaks down as follows: one device at up to 100W; two devices at up to 100W each; three devices with two at up to 100W and one at up to 45W; or four devices with one at 100W and three at 45W. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OkI1GE"&gt;Similarly, the battery pack also has various limitations; consult the following chart here for the breakdown of the various power distribution options. The battery pack itself is a 27,000mAh (100Wh) battery, meaning that it &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; fits under the maximum limit for bringing on planes. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WqF7FqvHAx_XUBlK-1nxLA-WH_g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22942766/Screen_Shot_2021_10_20_at_3.04.22_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6RZ0li"&gt;The two products aren’t the first high-wattage USB-C chargers or battery packs we’ve seen; Zendure released similar products last year, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21409482/zendure-supertank-pro-charger-review"&gt;its SuperTank Pro battery pack&lt;/a&gt; that’s so similar to the new HyperJuice that they appear to have identical displays and iconography. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jFgaL0"&gt;The new HyperJuice charger and battery pack &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.indiegogo.com%2Fprojects%2Fhyperjuice-245w-usb-c-battery-pack-gan-charger%3Futm_source%3DCE%2520Week%25202019%2520Media%26utm_medium%3Demail%26utm_campaign%3DIGG%2520245W%2520Press%2520Release%252010%252F20%252F21%2520%2528V5pTV6%2529%26_kx%3DOg8u1GQv7e7xvHJH0NQIEKiacDIMFRlM5SvWAf5Y_eTH8PB4Oyp4MB7tofUr_EYB.KdRC4D%23%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F20%2F22736571%2Fhyper-hyperjuice-245w-usb-c-battery-pack-charger-indiegogo" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;are available to back on Indiegogo&lt;/a&gt;, with shipping planned for December. The charger starts at $99 with early bird pricing, with an expected retail price of $199, while the battery pack starts at $149 with an expected retail price of $299.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22736571/hyper-hyperjuice-245w-usb-c-battery-pack-charger-indiegogo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22736571/hyper-hyperjuice-245w-usb-c-battery-pack-charger-indiegogo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-20T15:49:59-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-20T15:49:59-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook reaches settlement after being accused of discriminating against US workers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="facebook stock art" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Wl-iBYeT67w_wjE9HB8Ez5xewis=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70022463/acastro_180928_1777_facebook_hack_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uyvsuc"&gt;Facebook settled with the US Department of Justice following claims that it discriminated against US workers (via &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/10/19/facebook-settles-claims-it-discriminated-against-us-workers-for-jobs.html"&gt;CNBC&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/3/22150949/facebook-visa-law-justice-department-charged-guest-worker"&gt;The DOJ filed charges against Facebook in December 2020&lt;/a&gt;, alleging that Facebook reserved specific positions for temporary visa holders and discouraged US citizens from applying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nfvj66"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-labor-departments-reach-settlements-facebook-resolving-claims-discrimination-against"&gt;A report from the DOJ&lt;/a&gt; revealed that it’s fining Facebook $4.75 million in civil penalties and is requiring Facebook to pay up to $9.5 million to any victims of Facebook’s alleged discriminatory practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ff2YBu"&gt;Facebook also reached a separate agreement with the US Department of Labor. During an audit of Facebook’s PERM applications — the program that lets visa holders permanently work in the US — the DOL found potential recruitment violations that it’s going to investigate further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="j14UW5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Companies cannot set aside certain positions for temporary visa holders because of their citizenship or immigration status.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Zkca9E"&gt;In addition to paying two fines, Facebook will also have to train employees on the anti-discrimination policies of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as well as widely advertise its PERM positions. It’ll also have to start accepting resumes and applications electronically. It was previously urging applicants to apply by mail for visa-eligible positions. Accepting applications by mail and failing to make visa-eligible positions more visible were just a couple of ways that Facebook allegedly made it harder for US workers to apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AcAGPi"&gt;“Facebook is not above the law, and must comply with our nation’s federal civil rights laws, which prohibit discriminatory recruitment and hiring practices,” Kristen Clarke, the assistant attorney general of the DOJ’s civil rights division, said in a statement. “Companies cannot set aside certain positions for temporary visa holders because of their citizenship or immigration status.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JCZiAc"&gt;Facebook didn’t reply to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, but a Facebook spokesperson told CNBC&lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt;“While we strongly believe we met the federal government’s standards in our permanent labor certification (PERM) practices, we’ve reached agreements to end the ongoing litigation and move forward with our PERM program, which is an important part of our overall immigration program.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x05wkB"&gt;Facebook is going to have a fairly large bill this month (although it probably isn’t much for a &lt;a href="https://www.macrotrends.net/stocks/charts/FB/facebook/net-worth"&gt;billion-dollar company&lt;/a&gt;), as it racked up fines not only from the US government but also from the UK. The UK’s Competition and Markets Authority just slapped Facebook with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22736236/facebook-giphy-uk-cma-fine"&gt;$70 million penalty for deliberately withholding information about its Giphy acquisition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22736223/facebook-settlement-us-workers-discrimination"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22736223/facebook-settlement-us-workers-discrimination</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-20T15:36:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-20T15:36:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Mark Zuckerberg called to testify before the Senate following Instagram reports</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AxT5IOy_V84j4wFXExfuVxYrLJs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70022359/acastro_190919_1777_instagram_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LPpZKU"&gt;A top Democrat is demanding Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg or Instagram chief Adam Mosseri testify before the Senate to explain how the company plans to protect kids in light of new reports that platforms like Instagram can encourage harmful behavior in teens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5MvFvx"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.blumenthal.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/2021.10.20%20-%20Facebook%20and%20Instagram%20-%20Consumer%20Protection%20Invitation.pdf"&gt;In Wednesday’s letter&lt;/a&gt;, Sen. Richard Blumenthal (D-CT), chair of the Senate Commerce Committee’s subcommittee on consumer protection, called on the Facebook executives to testify in light of recent reporting from the &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-facebook-files-11631713039"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;on how the photo-sharing platform harms young users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kVIrlB"&gt;“Parents across America are deeply disturbed by ongoing reports that Facebook knows that Instagram can cause destructive and lasting harms to many teens and children, especially to their mental health and wellbeing,” Blumenthal wrote. “Those parents, and the twenty million teens that use your app, have a right to know the truth about the safety of Instagram.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="aflH3n"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Parents across America are deeply disturbed by ongoing reports that Facebook knows that Instagram can cause destructive and lasting harms”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="itGf5G"&gt;Facebook did not immediately respond to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gnQTWM"&gt;Facebook whistleblower Frances Haugen revealed herself as the source behind the &lt;em&gt;Journal’s &lt;/em&gt;reports earlier this month in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/3/22707860/facebook-whistleblower-leaked-documents-files-regulation"&gt;an interview with &lt;em&gt;60 Minutes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Later, Haugen appeared before Blumenthal’s committee to explain the internal reports and surveys she obtained while employed on Facebook’s Civic Integrity group to lawmakers. The hearing focused on documents suggesting that Facebook knew Instagram was “toxic” for teenage users and the platform’s algorithms could lead them to content that encouraged self-harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vJjbaM"&gt;During the hearing, Blumenthal called on Zuckerberg to testify regarding the Instagram revelations. “Rather than taking responsibility and showing leadership, Mr. Zuckerberg is going sailing,” Blumenthal said at the hearing earlier this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ect7Sg"&gt;The company has yet to confirm whether it plans to offer up Zuckerberg for testimony, but the subcommittee could force him to testify through a subpoena if he refuses. So far, Blumenthal has downplayed the possibility of a subpoena, &lt;a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/tech/2021/10/05/facebook-whistleblower-haugen-zuckerberg-congress-demands-answers/6011904001/"&gt;telling CNBC&lt;/a&gt;, “He has a public responsibility to answer these questions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bgWIo7"&gt;Over the last few weeks, Facebook has faced a new wave of criticism from lawmakers and consumer advocates. In light of Haugen’s leaks, Republicans and Democrats in both the House and Senate introduced new bills to make platforms like Facebook more liable to harms caused by algorithms by amending Section 230 of the Communications Decency Act. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yb8TvU"&gt;In light of this growing skepticism and regulatory threats, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735612/facebook-change-company-name-metaverse"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; reported on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt; that Facebook is planning to change its company’s name. The name change could be announced next week and would “reflect [Facebook’s] focus on building &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22701104/metaverse-explained-fortnite-roblox-facebook-horizon"&gt;the metaverse&lt;/a&gt;.” The proposed name change arrives as Facebook is bracing itself for more disclosures from Haugen, according to a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fbnewsroom/status/1450154004730707972?s=20"&gt;Monday Facebook Newsroom tweet thread&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xsCh0p"&gt;“Over the last 6 weeks, including over the weekend, we’ve seen how documents can be mischaracterized,” one tweet said. “Obviously, not every employee at Facebook is an executive; not every opinion is the company’s position.” Facebook has yet to release additional documents addressing these alleged mischaracterizations.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22737081/facebook-instagram-mark-zuckerberg-testify-senate-child-safety-frances-haugen"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22737081/facebook-instagram-mark-zuckerberg-testify-senate-child-safety-frances-haugen</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-20T15:05:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-20T15:05:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon offers up more data to tell third-party sellers which items will be popular</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7HVp6Jr_bnIZmVvwSY3fEt3feJE=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70022179/acastro_180329_1777_amazon_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HaR7MP"&gt;&lt;a href="https://press.aboutamazon.com/news-releases/news-release-details/today-amazon-accelerate-amazon-announces-product-opportunity"&gt;Amazon has announced a tool&lt;/a&gt; that will give sellers access to information about what shoppers are currently looking for and help make it easier to choose which products to create next. Amazon calls it the Product Opportunity Explorer and says that it’ll give sellers access to data and trends that will help them “identify opportunities to launch new, high-potential products to serve unmet customer demand.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xlP6va"&gt;With Amazon’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2019/9/19/20874818/amazon-allbirds-shoe-clone-copy-sneaker-206-collective-private-label"&gt;track record&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22311574/peak-design-video-amazon-copy-everyday-sling-bag"&gt;copying popular products&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22701965/amazon-fitbit-ecobee-basics-design-halo-view-smart-thermostat-clone-ripoff-regulators"&gt;selling them under its Amazon Basics brand&lt;/a&gt;, an obvious concern with this tool is where the data is coming from and how granular it is. While Amazon quotes a seller saying that they’re excited to get “recommendations specifically relevant” to their business, it’s easy to imagine other sellers being nervous that Amazon’s suggestions could direct businesses to rip off existing products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="2SvmM3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Amazon Basics’ history could make some sellers nervous about the company providing product development recommendations&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oA7K29"&gt;In its press release, Amazon says that the tool gives sellers “rich insights into what customers are searching for, clicking on, and buying, as well as not buying,” along with “detailed data on search volume and growth, sales history, and pricing trends.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rvqzVl"&gt;That sounds pretty general, but we reached out to Amazon to see how granular the sales data is — we’ll update the story if we hear back. For its part, Amazon has denied in the past that it abuses its dual role as a product developer and marketplace provider. The company says it doesn’t use private data from individual sellers to develop Amazon Basics products and that it has policies to prevent employees from doing so. Still, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/10/21558119/amazon-european-union-antitrust-charges-competition-commission-margrethe-vestager"&gt;the EU has accused Amazon&lt;/a&gt; of “systematically” using data from its marketplace that others can’t get. A&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22724152/amazon-india-search-result-rigging-reference-product-seller-data-report"&gt; recent report about Amazon India&lt;/a&gt; alleges even more egregious behavior there. The EU commission hasn’t released a report or findings stemming from the accusations, and Amazon has pushed back against both accusations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="4TzeC1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Amazon Basics ripped off accessories, now Amazon is coming for gadgets","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22701965/amazon-fitbit-ecobee-basics-design-halo-view-smart-thermostat-clone-ripoff-regulators"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="QP962K"&gt;There are also other minor concerns — if everyone has access to the same data or gets similar recommendations, could it start more algorithm-directed arms races between sellers to be the first to try to fill a perceived niche? And could Amazon risk damage to its relationship with sellers if the data predicts a product will do well, but it ends up totally flopping? The company may have the opportunity to figure those questions out before they become real problems, though; it will test the Product Opportunity Explorer in beta before releasing it for free to all sellers in 2022. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22736658/amazon-product-opportunity-explorer-tool-sellers-amazon-basics-data"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22736658/amazon-product-opportunity-explorer-tool-sellers-amazon-basics-data</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-20T14:19:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-20T14:19:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google Calendar’s new focus blocks can auto-decline meetings for you</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/u9ps3K922dDrXwTPBm98qyDHjbw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70021958/acastro_180427_1777_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration: Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Efdwml"&gt;It can be hard to block off focus time during the workday. To help make scheduling dedicated work blocks a bit easier, Google is adding &lt;a href="https://workspaceupdates.googleblog.com/2021/10/set-aside-time-for-focus-in-google.html"&gt;new dedicated focus time entries to Calendar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0AO6Ti"&gt;The focus time entries have a small headphones icon on your calendar and can be given a different color to help separate them from other things on your schedule. If you want, you can set focus time entries to automatically decline meetings that get scheduled during that block, which could help ensure that your focus time stays open and free from pesky meetings. Focus time entries will also appear in your &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22649975/google-calendar-time-insights-meeting-breakdown"&gt;“Time insights” panel&lt;/a&gt; so you can see how much of your time you’re spending in meetings and on focused work.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dpdjoulsvt7PRXxgS1saIcG69aU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22942589/Focus_time_calendar_entry_.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s what making a focus time entry looks like.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="D24M93"&gt;Focus time entries begin rolling out Wednesday to users on the Rapid Release track, but they won’t be available to every Calendar user; Google says they’re coming to Google Workspace Business Standard, Business Plus, Enterprise Standard, Enterprise Plus, Education Fundamentals, Education Teaching &amp;amp; Learning Upgrade, Education Standard, Education Plus, and Nonprofits customers.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22736837/google-calendar-focus-blocks-entries-auto-decline-meetings"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/20/22736837/google-calendar-focus-blocks-entries-auto-decline-meetings</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-20T14:18:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-20T14:18:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Verge guide to Android </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0RPhEQ2gf8DcC45Wj_-QyGTVV8E=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/60970401/acastro_190917_3668_android_package_content_0001.8.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="NlLamu"&gt;Google never stops issuing updates to its Android OS (well, unless your phone is old enough to have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735485/google-pixel-6-three-years-android-updates-security-feature"&gt;outlived its update period&lt;/a&gt;), and it has recently introduced its latest upgrade: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22724322/android-12-official-launch-date-pixel-phones-samsung-oneplus-xiaomi"&gt;Android 12&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xlBFrb"&gt;As always, the new OS is coming to Google’s Pixel phones first, and when it does come to Samsung and other Android devices, it will probably be tweaked somewhat by the manufacturer. But whether you have uploaded Android 12 into your Pixel or are still using Android 11 on another phone, we’ve assembled a guide that will help you make the most of your mobile life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZGKBzL"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;guide to Android&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;is a comprehensive resource that will help you learn how to use your Android phone’s best features and further educate you about this popular and flexible mobile operating system. We’ve separated out some of the new features found in Android 12, but you can also check out Android 101 and Hardware Help for tips that will apply to the majority of Android phones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="8kyKB9"&gt;&lt;q&gt;&lt;span data-author="-1"&gt;Everything you need to know about Android  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="momCET"&gt;We have advice and step-by-step instructions for beginners and experts. Our how-tos can teach you everything you need to know about some of your phone’s more advanced features. Take a look around and learn how to use Google Pay, send texts from your web browser, take screenshots, and even install &lt;em&gt;Fortnite &lt;/em&gt;(which isn’t as easy as it sounds). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="5jNJ7f"&gt;Be sure to check back regularly, as we’ll be updating &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;guide to Android&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;with new articles and tips over time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HH9hVN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RmHjHu"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/18/17718038/best-android-phones-user-guide-how-to-pixel-galaxy-moto-htc"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/18/17718038/best-android-phones-user-guide-how-to-pixel-galaxy-moto-htc</id>
    <author>
      <name>The Verge Staff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-20T13:44:40-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-20T13:44:40-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to preorder the Pixel 6 and 6 Pro</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ST3RH7o1_mOUSZxfGy4nhE4wo5I=/152x0:1768x1077/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70016186/lcimg_e5568f90_70f5_4d74_938b_5d1c34060e11.5.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can preorder Google’s just-announced Pixels.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="p512wU"&gt;Google’s new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22713338/google-pixel-6-event-top-announcements-tensor-processor-snapchat-pass"&gt;Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro are freshly announced&lt;/a&gt;, and they’re already up for preorder. These Pixels promise new designs, new cameras, a uniquely designed Google Tensor CPU, and more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="57DFat"&gt;This year’s Pixel phones come in two sizes: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22731034/google-pixel-6-pro-price-specs-features-release-date-hands-on"&gt;the standard Pixel 6 and the larger, triple-camera equipped Pixel 6 Pro&lt;/a&gt;. The base Pixel 6, with 128GB of storage, starts at $599, while the Pixel 6 Pro runs $899 and up if you prefer to go above the base 128GB. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="samX3I"&gt;WHAT’S NEW&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="jTBVbQ"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22731034/google-pixel-6-pro-price-specs-features-release-date-hands-on"&gt;Pixel 6 and 6 Pro&lt;/a&gt; look mostly nothing like prior iterations, with a metal and glass design highlighted by a rear camera bar that is slightly reminiscent of the classic Nexus 6P. These are big phones. The smaller Pixel 6, which cannot truly be considered small by any stretch of the imagination, has a 6.4-inch 2400x1080 OLED 90Hz display. The larger Pixel 6 Pro stretches its legs with a huge 6.7-inch 3120x1440 LTPO OLED 120Hz screen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lzGN0n"&gt;On the inside, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22710844/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-ai-speed-specs-details"&gt;Google’s brand new Tensor processor&lt;/a&gt; powers both, while the Pixel 6 gets 8GB of RAM, and the 6 Pro has 12GB. The new chips have a lot to prove for Google, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22727944/google-pixel-6-pro-cameras-computational-photography-features"&gt;just as the new camera systems do&lt;/a&gt; — with the Pixel 6 housing a dual-camera setup and the 6 Pro adding a third camera and lens to its rear bar. The phones match each other with 50-megapixel main cameras and a 12-megapixel ultrawide, but only the Pro counterpart gets a 48-megapixel sensor complete with telephoto 4x optical zoom. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kpMCfQ"&gt;Time will tell if all this hardware and new camera software brings the Pixels back to the top of the pack, but in the meantime, let’s look at how the Pixel 6 phones are configured and available for preorder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="x26RG3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here’s how the Pixel 6 compares to the Pixel 6 Pro","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22724481/google-pixel-6-pro-specs-comparison-price"},{"title":"Sundar Pichai and Rick Osterloh think the Pixel 6 is Google’s breakout phone","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22733159/sundar-pichai-rick-osterloh-google-pixel-6-interview-podcast"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="af9xF5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10816444"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Fl3bAs"&gt;WHERE TO PREORDER THE PIXEL 6 AND PIXEL 6 PRO&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="3iYB8E"&gt;&lt;a href="https://store.google.com/category/phones?hl=en-US"&gt;Google has kicked off its preorders on its own store&lt;/a&gt; first, right as the phone became official. The release date for the phones is Thursday, October 28th. Though, like most phone launches these days, delays may be expected. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZO9lWc"&gt;We will update this post as more options become available, but we can immediately see how some models are not available everywhere — if a 512GB Pixel 6 Pro is your jam, your only option is Google at this time. So far, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfO5wFAh05o" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fgoogle-pixel-6-5g-unlocked-128gb%2F-%2FA-84683612%3Fpreselect%3D83607398%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;subid1=vergepixel6preorders" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1665071-REG%2Fgoogle_ga02900_us_pixel_6_dual_sim_128gb.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22734748%2Fgoogle-pixel-6-pro-preorder-buy-how-to-price-availability-release-date" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H&lt;/a&gt; are all taking preorders for both Pixels with at least the base 128GB storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h4YOc6"&gt;Deals on new phones are tough to come by, but the best preorder deal going around for an unlocked Pixel 6 or 6 Pro is a free pair of Pixel Buds A wireless earbuds included with your purchase. The Pixel Buds A are Google’s budget-friendly earbuds, but they’re &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22465651/google-pixel-buds-a-series-earbuds-review-features-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a solid set that is more worthwhile than the more expensive Pixel Buds&lt;/a&gt; — and free is free. You can currently get this promo with all of those preorders from Google, Best Buy, B&amp;amp;H, and Target. Just note that some retailers like &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fgoogle-pixel-buds-a-series-wireless-headphones%2F-%2FA-83360244&amp;amp;subid1=vergepixel6preorders" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target may require you to add the Pixel Buds A to your cart manually&lt;/a&gt;, and they might be out of stock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="FfBJXi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10815891"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ZBa1GT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10815902"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gHSBMR"&gt;Carrier deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="qBhCBk"&gt;If you’re not shopping for an unlocked phone and prefer to utilize promos and payment plans from your carrier, there are some offers from the likes of AT&amp;amp;T, T-Mobile, Verizon, and Google’s own Fi service. Bear in mind that carriers give discounts as bill credits over time, attempting to rope you into service for 36 months or more. The Pixel 6 phones offered from &lt;a href="https://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8836598-13610485?sid=vergepixel6preorder&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.att.com%2Fbuy%2Fphones%2Fgoogle-pixel-6-128gb-stormy-black.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8836598-11365093?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.verizon.com%2Fsmartphones%2Fgoogle-pixel-6%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Verizon&lt;/a&gt; (including Verizon models bought on Google’s store) have radios for mmWave 5G, which cost upward of $100 more and may not give you faster speeds depending on where you live and use the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="bskHg6"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="fwxgST"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T is offering up to $700 off the &lt;a href="https://www.tkqlhce.com/click-8836598-13610485?sid=vergepixel6preorder&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.att.com%2Fbuy%2Fphones%2Fgoogle-pixel-6-pro-128gb-cloudy-white.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Pixel 6 Pro&lt;/a&gt; with a qualifying trade-in for new and existing customers, and 50 percent off of any Google-branded accessories purchased simultaneously. The base &lt;a href="https://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8836598-13610485?sid=vergepixel6preorder&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.att.com%2Fbuy%2Fphones%2Fgoogle-pixel-6-128gb-stormy-black.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Pixel 6&lt;/a&gt; 128GB model costs $15 per month over 36 months without a trade-in, but keep in mind that the mmWave-equipped model AT&amp;amp;T is selling is fully priced at $740 and not the base $599 of unlocked models using only Sub-6 5G. The $15 per month over 36 months will result in a total price of $540, reflecting the $200 AT&amp;amp;T will discount over time via bill credits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="X9W7Oc"&gt;Verizon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="pPtJqr"&gt;Verizon’s offers are similar promo, with up to $700 off a &lt;a href="https://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8836598-11365093?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.verizon.com%2Fsmartphones%2Fgoogle-pixel-6%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Pixel 6&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.kqzyfj.com/click-8836598-11365093?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.verizon.com%2Fsmartphones%2Fgoogle-pixel-6-pro%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Pixel 6 Pro&lt;/a&gt; with a trade-in— though this is limited to new customers switching over. Existing customers can get up to $350 off when trading in a phone and upgrading a line. If you’re shopping for more than one Pixel device, you can buy one and get a second Pixel 6 or 6 Pro for up to $700 off (given to you in billing credits over time; you’ll pay in full upfront) with eligible unlimited plans. The base Pixel 6 on a payment plan from Verizon will run $23.33 per month for 30 months, totaling $700 and a one-time $35 activation fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="74YwEQ"&gt;If you want to buy a Pixel 6 for Verizon’s network &lt;a href="https://store.google.com/config/pixel_6?hl=en-US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;direct from Google&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll also receive up to $100 in Google store credit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="O5sVYL"&gt;T-Mobile&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="hVohEb"&gt;T-Mobile is advertising the base &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fcell-phone%2Fgoogle-pixel-6%3Fsku%3D810029932646&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22734748%2Fgoogle-pixel-6-pro-preorder-buy-how-to-price-availability-release-date" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Pixel 6&lt;/a&gt; as free with a trade-in on its Magenta Max plan and the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fcell-phone%2Fgoogle-pixel-6-pro%3Fsku%3D810029931533&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22734748%2Fgoogle-pixel-6-pro-preorder-buy-how-to-price-availability-release-date" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Pixel 6 Pro&lt;/a&gt; up to $900 off under the same terms. Once again, these promotions involve buying the device as a Magenta Max subscriber or purchasing that service, paying the sales tax, trading in a qualifying phone that T-Mobile will offer a value on, and then receiving the allotted money back as monthly bill credits over 24 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bpnx5n"&gt;Note that T-Mobile’s offerings of Pixel 6 and 6 Pro do not have mmWave radios, only Sub-6 5G, and are thus the respective $599 and $899 base prices as Google advertised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="66aMs3"&gt;Google Fi&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="rwhuyq"&gt;Google’s own Fi service combines its &lt;a href="https://fi.google.com/about/promo-terms/?p=2021-october-pixel-6-series" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;free Pixel Buds A offer with $200 in bill credits&lt;/a&gt; if you transfer your number from another carrier after purchasing a &lt;a href="https://store.google.com/config/pixel_6?hl=en-US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Pixel 6&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://store.google.com/config/pixel_6_pro?hl=en-US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;6 Pro&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="JBudZu"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="g6O2gF"&gt; Related:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="BMdg22"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Google Pixel 2021|104330" data-volume-uuid="de13f1a62" data-volume-id="104330" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-734" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="wLjxTG"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Google Pixel 6 and 6 Pro hands-on: big screens, big ambitions, small price|104420" data-volume-uuid="0fd6d24c0" data-volume-id="104420" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-173" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22734748/google-pixel-6-pro-preorder-buy-how-to-price-availability-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22734748/google-pixel-6-pro-preorder-buy-how-to-price-availability-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
