<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-14T03:40:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-14T03:40:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-14T03:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sony announces the Xperia 1 III and Xperia 5 III with variable telephoto lenses</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Sony Xperia 1 III (left) and Xperia 5 III (right)" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a7FkaaE4Xrfob83bCtJNwx-_pOo=/0x100:3000x2100/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69123335/Xperia_1_III_sub6_group_frostedBlack.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Sony Xperia 1 III (left) and Xperia 5 III (right) | Sony&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Z6gPE7"&gt;Sony is announcing two new phones today, the Xperia 1 III and the Xperia 5 III. Both are the latest in Sony’s campaign to redefine the Xperia brand as a kind of sibling to its well-regarded Alpha digital cameras. As such, the camera system is once again the main focus, and Sony specifically is touting the “world’s first smartphone with a variable telephoto lens paired with a Dual PD sensor” and improvements to its already fast and accurate autofocus system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cmODbj"&gt;Pricing was not announced, but they should both be available in the US “this summer.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ss7nWW"&gt;Each phone has the basic specs you’d expect on a top-flight Android phone: three cameras on the rear, a Snapdragon 888 processor, and support for 5G. Actually, the 5G support is worth noting because these Xperia phones will be able to work on 5G networks in the US, something weirdly lacking on the last models. However, they’ll only work on the regular sub-6 networks on Verizon and T-Mobile, without support for AT&amp;amp;T’s 5G network. As is fairly usual for Sony, these will be sold directly rather than via carriers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tyTfUj"&gt;The phone also keep the Xperia design language Sony landed on with the original Xperia 1. They’re tall and narrow, with lots of glossy black and small curves on all the angles, giving them the most monolithic look of a smartphone today. I think they look great, but I’m also aware that they’re likely to cost a lot of money when Sony gets around to announcing the price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="keTqw8"&gt;In order to establish the Xperia brand, Sony has also been pushing a lot of other nice specs that are relatively hard to come by on other Android phones. The Xperia 1 III has a 4K OLED screen that now supports a fast (though locked) 120Hz refresh rate. There are dual speakers that are 40 percent louder and will work with Sony’s 360 Reality Audio format. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T4mUop"&gt;Sony is also enabling a special mode for the USB-C port that allows you to use a special cable to take an HD-resolution video signal from an SLR camera so you can use it as a monitor – much like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/26/22248440/sony-xperia-pro-5g-price-release-date-news-features"&gt;Xperia Pro can do with HDMI&lt;/a&gt;. That could also make them an interesting option for live streaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W6k4y8"&gt;They’ll come in both dual-SIM and SIM+microSD variants. And there’s even a good ol’ headphone jack and a shutter button. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="T6UIE3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10445216"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wi0KiD"&gt;There’s also the more standard fare, like wireless charging and a 4,500mAh battery. When plugged in and gaming the phones can redirect power away from the battery to reduce heat. Both phones will ship with Android 11, but as of right now there’s no clear commitment to future software updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RDXZt6"&gt;If you step down from the Xperia 1 III to the Xperia 5 III, you’ll get a very similar set of specs with a few exceptions. It’ll be smaller, of course. The larger phone has a 6.5-inch 21:9 display while the 5 has a 6.1-inch 21:9 display — at 1080p resolution instead of 4K. But it still has support for the periscope-style variable lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="De7yL3"&gt;But again, the big push is on the cameras and here Sony has done quite a bit to improve the hardware. Sony is using three 12-megapixel sensors on the back, and both the main and telephoto lenses support OIS. (The Xperia 1 III also gets a time-of-flight sensor.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jj59YD"&gt;Sony says it has lenses that are the equivalent to 16mm (f/2.2 ultrawide), 24mm (f/1.7 wide), and 70mm (f/2.3 telephoto), but that the telephoto can also reach to an f/2.8 105mm equivalent. That extra telephoto zoom comes thanks to a folded periscope lens design, and the Xperia is physically moving the lens elements to get different focal lengths. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="01653k"&gt;The idea is that photographers will mostly stick to those focal lengths, but should they want to zoom further or use a zoom level in between the Xperia phones will utilize digital zoom. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="eNimmC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10445221"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fbyQND"&gt;Beyond the fancy hardware, Sony has iterated on its software. Unlike Google, Apple, and even Samsung, Sony is putting its emphasis on technical features rather than computational photography. It is claiming some improved low-light performance in some situations, but really the main emphasis is on features like autofocus and shooting speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CKjGOt"&gt;These phones can take photos at up to 20fps with focus/exposure readings happening at 60fps. They also support 120FPS 4K in HDR. There’s still eye-tracking autofocus, but this year there’s real-time tracking for that autofocus. In a demo, Sony showed a subject turning around and when their eye was visible again, the camera adjusted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="QLRLA6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The hardware is excellent, but it may only get noticed by enthusiasts&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zqhm9U"&gt;Sony is finally integrating its pro camera app with the main camera app. There’s the “basic” mode like any smartphone, but it’s now quicker to get to the pro mode. Sony’s pro mode really is angled towards people who use Sony’s cameras, too: the interface is very similar. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1nmNxE"&gt;On paper, all of this sounds really great. We’ll need to review them to see if these specs can translate to great experiences. Previous Sony Xperia phones have also had great camera hardware specs, but for taking quick shots they have often missed the mark. Treating a smartphone camera as a pro SLR-style camera could limit their appeal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jJHp5Z"&gt;Sony’s tack with the Xperia line is to pack them to the gills with specs and features that will appeal to photographers and even videographers (there’s an excellent workflow-based video app included). In reality, however, Sony has struggled mightily to gain any measurable marketshare in the US. A lot of that has come down to higher prices than is the norm for even flagship Android phones, but some of it also comes down to availability. Without carrier partnerships or massive marketing budgets, these Xperia phones are more likely to appeal to camera enthusiasts than mainstream Android buyers. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22382887/sony-announces-xperia-1-iii-xperia-5-iii"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22382887/sony-announces-xperia-1-iii-xperia-5-iii</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-14T01:39:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-14T01:39:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>Canon announces EOS R3 pro mirrorless camera in development</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_5I8F-4sqPa9LkxkctrTQ1TnODM=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69123207/eosr3.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QLALPV"&gt;Last month Nikon &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/9/22322684/nikon-z9-flagship-mirrorless-camera-development-announced-2021"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; the development of its highest-end mirrorless camera to date, and now Canon has responded with the &lt;a href="https://global.canon/en/news/2021/20210414.html"&gt;announcement&lt;/a&gt; of the EOS R3, which ought to fit in a similar bracket. The R3 is still in development and details are thin, but it’s clear that it’ll be positioned above the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/9/21318398/canon-eos-r5-announced-8k-price-specs-release-date"&gt;EOS R5&lt;/a&gt;, which is currently Canon’s flagship mirrorless camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L1PkjC"&gt;Like Nikon’s upcoming Z9, the EOS R3 looks to be a hefty camera with a built-in vertical grip for shooting in portrait and landscape orientations. The body design and control layout is broadly similar to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/6/21054254/canon-eos-1d-x-mark-iii-professional-dslr-announcement-news-price-specs-ces-2020"&gt;EOS-1D X Mark III&lt;/a&gt;, Canon’s highest-end pro DSLR, and the body features dust and water resistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T1YASK"&gt;Canon says the EOS R3 will be the first camera to use a new 35mm full-frame stacked CMOS sensor with backside illumination, and its image processor and electronic shutter will allow for 30fps shooting with AF and AE tracking. Canon is touting the EOS R3’s autofocus capabilities, too. It’s the first digital camera from the company with eye-control AF, and a deep-learning algorithm has been used to improve recognition of human subjects from the torso up, which is said to help its performance in challenging situations like sports photography. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VboGJ1"&gt;That’s about it for details from Canon; the company hasn’t given any detailed specs, let alone a price or a release date. But together with Nikon’s Z9 and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/26/22250448/sony-alpha-1-camera-announced-specs-price-release-date"&gt;Sony’s new A1&lt;/a&gt;, the pro mirrorless camera wars are heating up — and the EOS R3’s name implies Canon may have something even higher-end in the pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22383187/canon-eos-r3-mirrorless-camera-development-announced"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22383187/canon-eos-r3-mirrorless-camera-development-announced</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-14T00:06:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-14T00:06:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>Ludwig ends his 31-day stream by breaking Ninja’s all-time sub record</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x_hJP-4_bvzHZvKLCvV5DI0UgZI=/229x0:2640x1607/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69123034/Screen_Shot_2021_04_13_at_9.04.34_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="g6Hjph"&gt;Near the end, Ludwig Ahgren slept a lot. Nestled in his race car bed with a blanket over his face and something new playing in the bottom corner of his screen, Ahgren exuded exhaustion. It was after all another day in the streamer’s Twitch subathon; he’d been live &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/28/22352226/ludwig-subathon-twitch-live-two-weeks-straight"&gt;since March 14th&lt;/a&gt;, and now there was less than an hour left on the clock. Though as he knew, this had happened before. A number close to zero was no guarantee that the stream would end. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sp1vah"&gt;Except this time was different, because he’d finally reached the limit he’d set for himself — 31 straight days of streaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QwBsrt"&gt;Since he started his subathon, Ahgren had become the most subscribed to streamer on Twitch. On the 13th, the day before he took his subathon live, he’d amassed 1,730 subs, per the stat site &lt;a href="https://twitchtracker.com/subscribers"&gt;Twitch Tracker&lt;/a&gt;. By April 1st, he had 160,138. As of April 4th, that number had jumped to 183,191. By the 13th, he had just shy of 262,000. When the stream ended on April 14th at 12AM ET, as more than 225,000 people watched, he had more than 282,000 subs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HrZEVh"&gt;At one point early on, Ahgren’s channel became the most viewed on the entire website while he was sleeping. It didn’t seem like the accolades were worth much, with 38 or so minutes remaining on the clock once again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Wtm9ay"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Ludwig had been live since March 14th&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jyL7S5"&gt;Though that was always subject to change at the whims of his fans, whose number had ballooned because his stunt had gone viral. Every subscription to his channel added 10 seconds to the clock, though anyone who tried to donate more than 100 subs was instantly banned. Ludwig had also said that the stream would end after 31 days no matter what — because I think he knew that given the chance the Twitch community would keep him live forever. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RiHCNW"&gt;Users in the chat swung between wanting him to stay live and wanting to free him; either way, the subathon had slipped into the realm of performance art by the time Ahgren woke up on April 1st, blinking slowly and taking in his fate. By the end of the day it was clear he would have to spend another night on air. On April 2nd, as the clock ticked down from 15 minutes, Ahgren’s mods were playing a digital marble race on stream with some of the 60,000-odd people in chat. On the morning of April 4th, as the timer hovered just under ten minutes, Ahgren slept while a lo-fi remix of Zelda’s Lullaby played.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OZqOJX"&gt;On the afternoon of the 13th, the final day, Ahgren’s sub count ticket upward again — he was trying to break Tyler “Ninja” Blevins’ all time subscription record of 269,154. The money from this day’s subs was pledged to the Humane Society and St. Jude’s, while a dollar from every single sub from the first 29 days of Ahgren’s stream had been pledged to the charity No Kid Hungry.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LXKbCB"&gt;And then he did it. “Relax! It’s fine now,” he said, listening to a speech from a football movie that was intended to hype up his viewers. This was it. This was the end. He’d done it, whatever it was he’d set out to achieve. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22362532/ludwig-twitch-subathon-ends-stream-ninja-subs-record"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22362532/ludwig-twitch-subathon-ends-stream-ninja-subs-record</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bijan Stephen</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-14T00:01:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-14T00:01:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Overwatch League is bringing back some live matches with a trio of events in China</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qY6-nlNd9QU77-tTPmHtkOlNkAc=/0x0:5760x3840/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69123020/NYXL_Fan_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A 2020 &lt;/em&gt;Overwatch&lt;em&gt; League match at the Hammerstein&amp;nbsp;Ballroom in New York.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo: steadyprime&amp;nbsp;for&amp;nbsp;NYXL.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ao1T5G"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League kicks off its fourth season this week, and while the majority of matches will be played remotely, today the league announced plans to hold multiple live events in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Or9Cj6"&gt;There will be three events spread across three cities — Hangzhou in June, Shanghai in July, and Guangzhou in August — and the league says they will take place in venues with reduced capacity “in order to comply with local safety requirements.” The events will be something of a hybrid between online and in-person competition. Here’s how OWL describes it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="MVt7Ip"&gt;The five China-based teams — Hunters, Charge, Spark, Valiant, and Dragons — plan to travel to each of the events to compete onstage, while the three Korea-based teams — NYXL, Fusion, and Dynasty — are not expected to travel. Matches taking place between a China-based team and a Korea-based team will feature the Chinese team competing onstage while their opponent competes from Korea remotely on our cloud tournament server.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="H24x3x"&gt;Like most esports leagues, OWL was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/22/21229380/overwatch-league-remote-cloud-production-studio-esports-blizzard"&gt;forced to pivot last year to online competition due&lt;/a&gt; to the ongoing pandemic; even the championship match &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/15/21324550/overwatch-league-owl-esports-grand-finals-championship"&gt;featured pro teams playing remotely&lt;/a&gt;. The change was particularly big for OWL, as the league — which features 20 squads based in 19 cities across North America, Europe, and Asia — was preparing for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/6/21122974/overwatch-league-season-3-preview-youtube-hero-pool-china-travel"&gt;its first season where teams would play matches in home venues&lt;/a&gt;. While the majority of the 2021 season is still expected to take place remotely, today’s news is an important step for OWL getting back to its original goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gcSQoK"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League’s 2021 season begins on April 16th, with &lt;a href="https://overwatchleague.com/en-us/schedule"&gt;a huge slate of matches&lt;/a&gt; throughout the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22380705/overwatch-league-2021-season-live-events-china"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22380705/overwatch-league-2021-season-live-events-china</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T21:00:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T21:00:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>The next Oculus Quest 2 update brings native wireless PC streaming and a 120Hz mode</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2agmEsdLvOaxP3_N7oh0SeRVYus=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69122363/akrales_200904_4160_0135.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nEXegS"&gt;&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=43993&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oculus.com%2Fblog%2Fintroducing-oculus-air-link-a-wireless-way-to-play-pc-vr-games-on-oculus-quest-2-plus-infinite-office-updates-support-for-120-hz-on-quest-2-and-more%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Oculus is announcing&lt;/a&gt; that wireless PC streaming, a 120Hz refresh rate, and improvements to Infinite Office will be coming to the Oculus Quest 2 with the v28 software update, which the company says will be rolling out soon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xYFi3f"&gt;Infinite Office is a feature that Oculus includes as part of Oculus Home, which lets users work in a virtual environment. With the v28 update, Infinite Office will have an experimental feature that allows users to add a virtual desk where their real-life desk is, letting users know where they can sit and put real-life physical objects down without having to leave VR. The Quest 2 will also be able to show a virtual representation of the Logitech K830 keyboard, though Facebook says that support for visualizing more keyboard models will be coming in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O4zs3e"&gt;Another feature coming with the update is the ability to stream games or applications from your desktop PC wirelessly. Oculus calls its wireless streaming feature Air Link, named after the Link cable that can be used to connect the headset to a PC. The feature will only work well with some network setups — the instructions to turn it on are pretty clear that you’ll need good Wi-Fi to get an acceptable experience, and that the Link cable will still provide the best visual quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8LlEM1"&gt;Facebook says that it hasn’t ruled out the possibility of bringing Air Link to the original Quest at some point in the future, but it does say that it’s “focused on optimizing Air Link to be the best possible experience for Quest 2 first.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="zfbBCd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to use your Oculus Quest 2 to play any PC VR game wirelessly","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22218827/oculus-quest-2-wireless-pc-vr-games-how-to"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="0hDalX"&gt;We do know that the original Quest hardware is capable of wireless PC streaming, because indie developer Guy Godin has built it into his app, Virtual Desktop. The app gives users a virtual space to use their computers in, and it also supports streaming games over Wi-Fi. This is, however, where we have to talk about the controversy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lAyS5e"&gt;If you thought the description of Virtual Desktop sounded a little like Facebook’s Infinite Office, you’re not alone — Godin &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21455665/facebook-oculus-vr-indie-developers-power-monopoly-concerns"&gt;has been talking about&lt;/a&gt; how Facebook has been essentially building his app idea into its own Oculus experience then offering it for free for a while now. His case may have been helped by the fact that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22301151/oculus-store-virtual-desktop-native-pc-vr-game-streaming-quest-2"&gt;Facebook blocked the update that allowed Virtual Desktop to be used wirelessly&lt;/a&gt; until early this year, requiring users to go through a complicated sideload procedure to get the functionality working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iwGvg0"&gt;&lt;a href="https://uploadvr.com/oculus-quest-air-link-120/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;UploadVR&lt;/em&gt; talked to Godin&lt;/a&gt; about Facebook introducing Air Link, and got this comment from him:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="ZxUTGH"&gt;“In 2017, Facebook copied the base functionality of Virtual Desktop on Rift and incorporated it in their platform, essentially making my app obsolete. I’m not surprised to see them do this again on Quest. They copied the fitness tracking app YUR last year and released Oculus Move; essentially killing the company. They also released App Lab as they saw how popular SideQuest was. That’s what they do. If you have a popular app on Quest today, expect Facebook to copy you and leave you in the dust. As for the fate of Virtual Desktop on Quest, we will have to see how Facebook’s solution competes. Judging by the number of issues plaguing Oculus Link today, I’m confident Virtual Desktop will remain a valuable solution for a while. I’ve also got a lot of cool features in the works that I can’t wait to share with the community.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="KDku86"&gt;Despite the warnings about Facebook copying ideas, he still seems confident in his ability to compete. It’s an open question as to how well Air Link will work initially, and how fast improvements will come. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hVu8K1"&gt;The update also includes an experimental mode for 120Hz refresh rates, up from the current 90Hz, and the original 72Hz. It’s a slight delay from Oculus’ &lt;a href="https://www.roadtovr.com/facebook-hints-oculus-quest-2-120hz-refresh-rate/"&gt;original estimated March launch&lt;/a&gt;. Oculus’ post hints that you many not immediately get to try it out — the Quest 2’s software will still run at 90Hz, so you won’t get to see what it looks like until developers release builds of their games and software that can run at the higher refresh rate. The wait may not be that long, though: Guy Godin &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/VRDesktop/status/1382116851551899648?s=20"&gt;has already tweeted&lt;/a&gt; that he’s got a 120Hz update for Virtual Desktop ready to go when v28 becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nqI4YB"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Yep, the 120hz update is ready to roll out whenever the Quest 2 update lands&lt;/p&gt;— Guy Godin (@VRDesktop) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/VRDesktop/status/1382116851551899648?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 13, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382805/oculus-quest-2-facebook-wireless-pc-streaming-120hz-infinite-office"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382805/oculus-quest-2-facebook-wireless-pc-streaming-120hz-infinite-office</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T20:25:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T20:25:44-04:00</updated>
    <title>The FBI is remotely hacking hundreds of computers to protect them from Hafnium </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vIktYOLmX1uIXO67xe4vKkX453o=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69122269/acastro_170621_1777_0008.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GW6zzM"&gt;In what’s believed to be an unprecedented move, the FBI is trying to protect hundreds of computers infected by the Hafnium hack &lt;em&gt;by &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-sdtx/pr/justice-department-announces-court-authorized-effort-disrupt-exploitation-microsoft"&gt;&lt;em&gt;hacking them itself&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, using the original hackers’ own tools (via &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/fbi-launches-operation-to-remotely-remove-microsoft-exchange-server-backdoors/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29"&gt;&lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IZA6V3"&gt;The hack, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319934/microsoft-hafnium-hack-exchange-server-email-flaw-white-house"&gt;which affected tens of thousands of Microsoft Exchange Server customers around the world and triggered a “whole of government response” from the White House&lt;/a&gt;, reportedly left a number of backdoors that could let any number of hackers right into those systems again. Now, the FBI has taken advantage of this by using those same web shells / backdoors to remotely delete themselves, an operation that the agency is calling a success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2oshaQ"&gt;“The FBI conducted the removal by issuing a command through the web shell to the server, which was designed to cause the server to delete only the web shell (identified by its unique file path),” explains &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-sdtx/pr/justice-department-announces-court-authorized-effort-disrupt-exploitation-microsoft"&gt;the US Justice Department&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bTMTaB"&gt;The wild part here is that owners of these Microsoft Exchange Servers likely aren’t yet aware of the FBI’s involvement; the Justice Department says it’s merely “attempting to provide notice” to owners that they attempted to assist. It’s doing all this with the full approval of a Texas court, according to the agency. You can read the unsealed search and seizure warrant and application &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/press-release/file/1386631/download"&gt;right here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lLKPWv"&gt;It’ll be interesting to see if this sets a precedent for future responses to major hacks like Hafnium. While I’m personally undecided, it’s easy to argue that the FBI is doing the world a service by removing a threat like this — while Microsoft may have been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319934/microsoft-hafnium-hack-exchange-server-email-flaw-white-house"&gt;painfully slow with its initial response&lt;/a&gt;, Microsoft Exchange Server customers have also now had well over a month to patch their own servers after several critical alerts. I wonder how many customers will be angry, and how many grateful that the FBI, not some other hacker, took advantage of the open door. We know that critical-but-local government infrastructure often has egregious security practices, most recently resulting in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/5/22368476/kansas-man-tamper-water-supply-remote-ellsworth-wyatt-travnichek"&gt;two local drinking water supplies being tampered with&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YGbdsw"&gt;The FBI says that thousands of systems were patched by their owners before it began its remote Hafnium backdoor removal operation, and that it only removed “removed one early hacking group’s remaining web shells which could have been used to maintain and escalate persistent, unauthorized access to U.S. networks.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F6ZFiG"&gt;“Today’s court-authorized removal of the malicious web shells demonstrates the Department’s commitment to disrupt hacking activity using all of our legal tools, not just prosecutions,” reads a statement from Assistant Attorney General John C. Demers, with the Justice Department’s National Security Division.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GTfpz7"&gt;Today is Patch Tuesday, by the way, and Microsoft’s April 2021 security update includes new mitigations for Exchange Server vulnerabilities, &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/current-activity/2021/04/13/apply-microsoft-april-2021-security-update-mitigate-newly"&gt;according to CISA&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re running a local Exchange Server or know someone who is, take a look.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382821/fbi-doj-hafnium-remote-access-removal-hack"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382821/fbi-doj-hafnium-remote-access-removal-hack</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T19:04:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T19:04:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>US carriers have thankfully abandoned at least one bad plan for RCS</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qR0YepDCoxN1VkapUXCRiSdAW6o=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69122020/VRG_ILLO_2411_Google_Messaging_3.0.gif" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span data-author="-1"&gt;GIF by Garret Beard and William Joel / The Verge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ppkPbJ"&gt;According to the telecom industry news site &lt;a href="https://www.lightreading.com/ossbsscx/verizon-atandt-t-mobile-blow-rcs-launch/d/d-id/768729"&gt;Light Reading, the big three US carriers are walking away from&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/24/20931202/us-carriers-rcs-cross-carrier-messaging-initiative-ccmi-att-tmobile-sprint-verizon"&gt;Cross Carrier Messaging Initiative&lt;/a&gt;. The CCMI was meant to be a joint effort to promote RCS, the next-generation messaging standard designed to replace SMS. But while that might seem like bad news on the face of it, what it actually means is that carriers have given up on a bad plan that would have been bad for consumers. Whether or not they will replace it with a &lt;em&gt;good &lt;/em&gt;plan remains, as ever with RCS, to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mUOqAt"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/24/20931202/us-carriers-rcs-cross-carrier-messaging-initiative-ccmi-att-tmobile-sprint-verizon"&gt;CCMI was launched in 2019&lt;/a&gt; and by all indications was a joint effort that was spearheaded by Sprint. It initially seemed like a mixed bag of news. At the time, any effort by carriers to support proper cross-compatibility in RCS was a good sign. But the bad part was the consortium planned on creating an Android app themselves for messaging features. If you’ve ever used an app designed by a major US carrier, you know that’s a recipe for a bad experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BaoIQK"&gt;Google was not part of the CCMI announcement, either, which was very strange given that Google is by far the biggest booster for the standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jTsU3N"&gt;However, after that announcement there was precious little information or movement. All the carriers seemed too busy hyping up 5G to give any real attention to the CCMI. Plus, T-Mobile was barreling down the path towards acquiring Sprint. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="gq804x"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The CCMI promised a custom Android app from the carriers&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dPxnpm"&gt;That acquisition happened and the one carrier that seemed enthusiastic for CCMI was subsumed into another. Then, last month, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/29/22356918/t-mobile-google-android-services-rcs-youtube-tv-pixel-storage-backup"&gt;T-Mobile announced a huge deal with Google&lt;/a&gt; that included switching Android phones over to Android Messages as the default RCS/SMS app. The writing was on the wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="plPW8g"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/29/22356918/t-mobile-google-android-services-rcs-youtube-tv-pixel-storage-backup"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Light Reading&lt;/em&gt; reached out to the third-party vendor, Synchronoss&lt;/a&gt;, that was originally going to handle the back-end logistics for the CCMI app (RCS can be run through a carrier’s server, Google’s server, or a third-party server). But while Synchronoss’ comment was noncommittal, Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T are now just telling it like it is. Here’s what Verizon told &lt;em&gt;Light Reading&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="KQ9F9S"&gt;The owners of the Cross Carrier Messaging Initiative decided to end the joint venture effort. However, the owners remain committed to enhancing the messaging experience for customers including growing the availability of RCS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="4xjEne"&gt;Reached for comment by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, AT&amp;amp;T gave us a nearly identical statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X9Kyk1"&gt;The rollout for RCS worldwide — and especially in the US — has been terribly slow and even more terribly confusing. Phones that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/9/18563641/pixel-3a-t-mobile-rcs-chat-rollout-broken-encryption"&gt;should be compatible weren’t&lt;/a&gt;, carriers that promised their RCS would interoperate with others didn’t build those systems, and Apple continued to stay absolutely silent on whether it would support RCS (and it continues to stay silent to this day). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aIanVz"&gt;However, Google has plodded along with its plan, making piece-by-piece efforts to broaden RCS adoption. It made &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/14/20964477/googles-rcs-chat-android-rollout-us-ccmi-texting-sms"&gt;RCS available to anybody on any carrier if they used Android Messages&lt;/a&gt; as their SMS app. It cut that deal with T-Mobile. It has even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/19/21574451/android-rcs-encryption-message-end-to-end-beta"&gt;begun testing end-to-end-encryption over RCS inside Android messages&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lBubJg"&gt;I will be the first in line to tell you that the rollout for RCS took what should have been a coordinated six-month effort that was a win for both carriers and Google and turned it into a multi-year slog that didn’t help anybody, least of all consumers. But the end of the CCMI is a sign that carriers might just be implementing more consumer-friendly RCS policies, not that they’re walking away entirely. T-Mobile made that deal with Google instead. Will all AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon continue to drag their feet on RCS? Almost definitely. But at least they won’t be foisting a carrier-made app on every Android user in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382715/us-carriers-ccmi-rcs-abandoned-sms-messages-texts"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382715/us-carriers-ccmi-rcs-abandoned-sms-messages-texts</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T19:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T19:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung teases ‘the most powerful’ Galaxy device is coming at its April 28th Unpacked event</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/swvJsSQ2sPat_1xDSNzq9dIQmyA=/0x32:3582x2420/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69121986/most_powerful_galaxy_tease.15.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MPRK9S"&gt;Samsung &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=81vXN2MOi0s"&gt;has announced&lt;/a&gt; a new Galaxy Unpacked event set for April 28th at 10AM ET, teasing the announcement of “the most powerful Galaxy” device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OWnPZr"&gt;The teaser, as is typical for these invitations, isn’t too forthcoming. But given the nature of the announcement and Samsung’s usual release cycle, there are a few hints we can suss out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KbGnAT"&gt;First, the description of whatever Samsung is announcing as “the most powerful Galaxy” would seem to rule out a phone, like the rumored Galaxy Z Fold 3. The most generous depiction of a mobile processor — even one as powerful as Qualcomm’s flagship Snapdragon 888 — still isn’t in the same ballpark as a true laptop processor. And despite recent headlines, &lt;a href="https://www.androidauthority.com/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-3-launch-date-1216922/"&gt;Samsung is still rumored&lt;/a&gt; to reveal the Z Fold 3 at a July event, potentially a replacement for the Galaxy Note’s high-end summer phone release spot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZAjmCt"&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy Book lineup of laptops, on the other hand, would fit the bill for a more powerful Galaxy device — and is long overdue for an update. The current models were announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/10/29/20938145/samsung-galaxy-book-flex-ion-laptops-design-wireless-charging-qled-hands-on"&gt;all the way back in 2019&lt;/a&gt; (although they didn’t hit US stores &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/4/21246560/samsung-qled-galaxy-book-flex-alpha-ion-available-now"&gt;until May of last year&lt;/a&gt;), and they still feature Intel’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/2/21408718/intel-11th-gen-tiger-lake-cpu-processor-announcement-laptops-fall"&gt;long-outdated&lt;/a&gt; 10th Gen processors. A Galaxy Book refresh that featured some of Intel’s new 11th Gen Tiger Lake chips — or even Intel’s newer 35W H-series variants — would easily take the crown as the new “most powerful” Galaxy product. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="UI9VkG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"New Samsung laptops rumored to include OLED screens and S Pen support","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22285268/samsung-galaxy-book-pro-360-oled-screen-s-pen-support-windows-intel"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="rMvYMo"&gt;Oh, and Samsung is already rumored to be working on a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22285268/samsung-galaxy-book-pro-360-oled-screen-s-pen-support-windows-intel"&gt;new Galaxy Book Pro line of laptops&lt;/a&gt;, which would feature 13.3-inch and 15.6-inch OLED panels, S-Pen support, and upgraded Intel CPUs. One of the new models — the Galaxy Book Pro 360 — is also said to include 5G compatibility. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GzDABZ"&gt;Lastly, if you wanted to get really creative, the glowing wedge of light seen in the invitation &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; sort of resemble an opened laptop (if you’re willing to squint a bit). We’ll find out for sure on April 28th, though — assuming one of Samsung’s characteristic leaks doesn’t arrive first. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CX81Os"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382512/samsung-galaxy-unpacked-april-28th-event-most-powerful-device-book-pro"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382512/samsung-galaxy-unpacked-april-28th-event-most-powerful-device-book-pro</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T17:28:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T17:28:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>Detroit man sues police for wrongfully arresting him based on facial recognition</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Eej5qpe8qSL7BEn6DYq6kMh8edw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69121479/acastro_180730_1777_facial_recognition_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / Th&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lO3tqz"&gt;A man who was falsely accused of shoplifting has &lt;a href="https://www.aclu.org/press-releases/michigan-father-sues-detroit-police-department-wrongful-arrest-based-faulty-facial"&gt;sued the Detroit Police Department&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/24/technology/facial-recognition-arrest.html"&gt;arresting him&lt;/a&gt; based on an incorrect facial recognition match. The American Civil Liberties Union filed suit on behalf of Robert Williams, whom it calls the first US person wrongfully arrested based on facial recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gMBe1c"&gt;The Detroit Police Department arrested Williams in 2019 after examining security footage from a shoplifting incident. A detective used facial recognition technology on a grainy image from the video, and the system flagged Williams as a potential match based on a driver’s license photo. But as &lt;a href="https://www.aclumich.org/en/press-releases/farmington-hills-father-sues-detroit-police-department-wrongful-arrest-based-faulty"&gt;the lawsuit notes&lt;/a&gt;, facial recognition is frequently inaccurate, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/20/21031255/facial-recognition-algorithm-bias-gender-race-age-federal-nest-investigation-analysis-amazon"&gt;particularly with Black subjects&lt;/a&gt; and a low-quality picture. The department then produced a photo lineup that included Williams’ picture, showed it to a security guard who hadn’t actually witnessed the shoplifting incident, and obtained a warrant when that guard picked him from the lineup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xP1S7G"&gt;&lt;q&gt;At least three Black men have faced arrest after a bad match&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dUbB9I"&gt;Williams — who had been driving home from work during the incident — spent 30 hours in a detention center. The ACLU later &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/24/21301759/facial-recognition-detroit-police-wrongful-arrest-robert-williams-artificial-intelligence"&gt;filed a formal complaint&lt;/a&gt; on his behalf, and the prosecutor’s office apologized, saying he could have the case expunged from his records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gvvWFo"&gt;The ACLU claims Detroit police used facial recognition under circumstances that they should have known would produce unreliable results, then dishonestly failed to mention the system’s shortcomings — including a “woefully substandard” image and the known racial bias of recognition systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1SHhzk"&gt;The department itself has acknowledged that Williams’ arrest was based on “sloppy investigative work” and other mistakes. But the complaint calls this incident part of a pattern, pointing to a second wrongful arrest involving a Black man misidentified by facial recognition tech. That man, Michael Oliver, &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/bv8k8a/faulty-facial-recognition-led-to-his-arrestnow-hes-suing"&gt;sued the department&lt;/a&gt; last year. Outside Detroit, at least &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/29/technology/facial-recognition-misidentify-jail.html"&gt;one other Black man&lt;/a&gt; has sued for a wrongful arrest based on facial recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ya8as0"&gt;Thousands of law enforcement agencies have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/26/21402978/clearview-ai-ceo-interview-2400-police-agencies-facial-recognition"&gt;allegedly used&lt;/a&gt; facial recognition tech to identify suspects. But a backlash has led several cities to ban the practice, while &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21288053/microsoft-facial-recognition-police-law-enforcement-pledge-regulation"&gt;Microsoft, IBM, and Amazon have pledged&lt;/a&gt; to keep their systems out of police hands.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382398/robert-williams-detroit-police-department-aclu-lawsuit-facial-recognition-wrongful-arrest"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382398/robert-williams-detroit-police-department-aclu-lawsuit-facial-recognition-wrongful-arrest</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T16:59:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T16:59:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>Gigabyte is announcing three gaming monitors with HDMI 2.1 and TV sizes</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RYlkbRoBSfYHMDCnUQH950AdxJs=/100x0:1180x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69121351/AORUS_4K_Gaming_Monitors_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Gigabyte&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DFyVGn"&gt;Gigabyte has announced three new 4K gaming monitors for its Aorus brand, each features HDMI 2.1, the somewhat hard-to-find display connector that allows for high refresh rate gaming at 4K  (&lt;a href="https://www.tweaktown.com/news/78707/aorus-fo48u-48-inch-4k-120hz-oled-gaming-monitor-with-hdmi-2-1-tech/index.html"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;TweakTown&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Besides having some of the best tech available in TVs or monitors, all three have desk-dominating sizes. According to &lt;a href="https://videocardz.com/press-release/aorus-announces-32-43-and-48-inch-4k-gaming-monitors-with-hdmi-2-1"&gt;a press release posted by &lt;em&gt;VideoCardz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the monitors will also feature VESA’s HDR 1000 standard and come in three sizes: 32, 43, and a mind-boggling (for a gaming monitor anyway; we’ll get back to that) 48 inches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wLJEa0"&gt;The 48-inch version is a little different, and it set off a firestorm of discussion at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, so let’s set it aside for just one moment. The 32- and 43-inch monitors, named the FI32U and the FV43U, respectively, will feature 144Hz panels. Gigabyte is also claiming that FI32U will have a 0.5ms response time, which looks to make it one of the faster 4K gaming monitors out there. While the FV43U has a slower 1ms response time, that’s probably something even the most eagle-eyed and competitive gamers would have issues noticing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z24FGI"&gt;The 48-inch model, dubbed the FO48U, is slightly different from the other two. Besides dropping the refresh rate from 144Hz to 120Hz, it’s also the size of a TV more at home in an entertainment center — specifically, the 48-inch model of LG’s CX OLED TVs, which shares many of the same specs as Gigabyte’s version, from the HDMI 2.1 inputs to the 120Hz refresh rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="a6iIbN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;If Gigabyte &lt;em&gt;is &lt;/em&gt;going for a TV experience, what is it offering that LG doesn’t already have?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="n3WiY5"&gt;So what’s going on here? Gigabyte is likely using the same OLED panels as LG. That makes it kind of hard to figure out why anyone would want to go with it over LG’s TV (especially since you could go out and buy LG’s version right now). And despite calling it a “monitor,” it doesn’t seem like Gigabyte expects many people to use this on a desk; its website specifically says it’s for “your gaming space or living room.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7dzcao"&gt;However, LG’s 48-inch TV has had great success in the last year as a monitor for people who apparently want to sit very close to the action. There’s no doubt it’d be immersive... at least, until you had to crane your neck to see the minimap or other HUD elements. But if Gigabyte &lt;em&gt;is &lt;/em&gt;going for a TV experience, what is it offering that LG doesn’t already have? G-Sync and FreeSync? LG’s got it. Cheaper price due to potentially less processing power and smart features? Gigabyte hasn’t announced pricing, but we’re skeptical that it’ll end up being cheaper. (The LG retails for $1,500.) Gaming (er, sorry, “tactical”) features, such as “black equalizer,” which supposedly makes enemies easier to see? Okay, fair point. LG’s TV is intended for watching movies and playing games, while Gigabyte appears to be adding a few more gamer-focused features. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1SZBQ2"&gt;This isn’t to say there’s no reason for it to exist. Some people might prefer its aesthetic over LG’s (maybe it’ll even have RGB to really sell it). Or maybe Gigabyte will surprise us, and it’ll be cheaper. Until we know pricing, it’s hard to judge. Still, it seems like if it stands out, it won’t be for its uniqueness — which is a shame, really, given how the other models seem to be offering a set of features that is hard to find elsewhere. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Hs0Hb"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; The initial version of the article stated that all the monitors used OLED panels. Gigabyte has confirmed only one, the FO48U, is OLED. We regret the error.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382201/gigabyte-aorus-4k-gaming-monitor-tv-oled"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382201/gigabyte-aorus-4k-gaming-monitor-tv-oled</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
