<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-11-19T07:05:04-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-19T07:05:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-19T07:05:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>Discord now lets you send up to 10 (accessible) memes at a time</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aXjN3uWTUzTmzTg2vuZJooLOURw=/0x0:989x659/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70164529/Discord_47Z2dGAzDg.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discord’s new alt text feature in action.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Discord&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Onzd9E"&gt;Discord has updated its Windows and macOS desktop clients to let users add alt text for image attachments, the service &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/discord/status/1461442402917359618"&gt;has announced on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a helpful accessibility feature for users that rely on screen readers and arrives alongside the ability to preview and upload up to 10 files at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iikH2v"&gt;The alt text accessibility feature can be found by clicking the small pen icon (“Modify Attachment”) on the top right of each individual preview before sending it in a text channel. Of course, the feature relies on people making the effort to manually add alt text in order for it to be useful. But it’s better than not having the option at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="z8niMl"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;big upgrades to attachments: now you can upload up to 10 files at a time on desktop, see previews, and add alt text for ppl with screen readers (plus a few more things). pretty big. &lt;a href="https://t.co/rptaHdlCem"&gt;pic.twitter.com/rptaHdlCem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Discord (@discord) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/discord/status/1461442402917359618?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 18, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="coSFer"&gt;Alt text support joins a number of other accessibility features Discord has added to its desktop apps in recent months. Other quality of life improvements include keyboard support for drag and drop, allowing users to organize their servers and channels without needing to use a mouse, and a slider that changes the speed of its text-to-speech feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fTV8jt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22791035/discord-alt-text-support-10-image-uploads-at-a-time"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22791035/discord-alt-text-support-10-image-uploads-at-a-time</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-19T06:22:12-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-19T06:22:12-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft’s new Xbox app for Windows finally solves game install headaches</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Jyqpy7-DHaNPw72dWOfRojubTI4=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70164389/Xbox_App_Preview_11_17_21.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qbFYla"&gt;Microsoft is now allowing testers to access a new Xbox app for Windows that greatly improves the game install process from the Windows store. As we &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/11/22776024/microsoft-xbox-app-windows-folder-install-uwp-options"&gt;reported earlier this month&lt;/a&gt;, the updated app allows PC gamers to install titles into any folder of their choice with unrestricted access to game files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GVWmQT"&gt;It’s an option that helps address many of the headaches of installing titles from Xbox Game Pass for PC, and it should also mean you can backup game files and restore them if need be. Previously, Microsoft forced games to install into a WindowsApps folder at the root of a drive, and it was locked down so you couldn’t modify files or freely move them around.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_kXLNPIu8qLH5HRoWb1ZQFs0PIE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23026938/dKIC0Le.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You now get options to manage where games are installed to.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="BxuIsB"&gt;The updated Xbox app now lets you choose a location, and, if you have existing games installed, you can move them onto secondary drives. I’ve tested the app and successfully moved &lt;em&gt;Forza Horizon 5&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Gears 5&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Microsoft Flight Simulator &lt;/em&gt;onto secondary drives. I can now fully access those files and folders, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GDbZ9N"&gt;Windows 10 and Windows 11 users can test the new Xbox app through the Xbox Insider Hub app from the store. You’ll need to join the “Windows Gaming” preview within the Xbox Insider Hub app to get the updated Xbox app. Microsoft does &lt;a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2021/11/18/advanced-installation-and-management-features-available-for-insiders-through-the-xbox-app-for-windows/"&gt;list a number of known issues&lt;/a&gt; for this early release though, including issues launching some games on external drives and a number of games that aren’t supported yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZMyu9e"&gt;You also still can’t add games downloaded from the Windows store into Steam, as there appears to be a permission issue preventing that. The Xbox app is still in preview, so that could be a bug that will be addressed before it’s widely available. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WwKWQD"&gt;Either way, Windows store game installs are finally getting more Steam-like, after years of issues and bugs for PC users. If you’ve been avoiding Xbox Game Pass for PC due to the Windows store, this new Xbox app should remove some of the associated headaches.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22791013/microsoft-xbox-app-windows-install-folders"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22791013/microsoft-xbox-app-windows-install-folders</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-19T06:09:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-19T06:09:30-05:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook is paying musicians and creators up to $50,000 to use its live audio features</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FR9fgumBj6VJf5OiXE9ojWJCmLQ=/0x0:890x593/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70164377/Live_Audio_Rooms_Rooms_Discovery_Stars_and_Fundraising_Side_by_Side.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook launched its Live Audio Rooms feature (above) to rival once-buzzy app Clubhouse. &lt;/em&gt; | Image: Facebook&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Mj6R0G"&gt;Social media conglomerate Meta continues its tactic of buying buzz, after CEO Mark Zuckerberg promised in July that the company would &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22577242/facebook-1-billion-payments-creators-2022"&gt;pay $1 billion&lt;/a&gt; to creators by the end of 2022. A report &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/facebook-hands-out-cash-to-creators-to-boost-clubhouse-rival"&gt;from &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; details how some of this money is being spent, with Meta-owned Facebook paying creators up to $50,000 to use the platform’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/21/22540508/facebook-live-audio-rooms-clubhouse-rival-spaces-greenhouse"&gt;Live Audio Rooms&lt;/a&gt; feature — a rival to the once-buzzy live audio app Clubhouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MdYGIT"&gt;When you make as much money as Meta does, buying success is a reasonable tactic, at least in the short term. The Meta-owned Instagram, for example, has been doing the same to boost its TikTok-rival Reels, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22777899/instagram-reels-bonus-program-35000-dollars-creators-tiktok-competitors"&gt;paying creators up to $35,000&lt;/a&gt; to post to the platform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="X2330R"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Meta promised to pay creators $1 billion by the end of 2022&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="EJPDjw"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;, the terms for using Live Audio Rooms are similarly generous. “Facebook is offering to pay musicians and other creators $10,000 to $50,000 per session on its five-month-old live audio product, plus a fee for guests of $10,000 or more,” says the publication, citing “people with direct knowledge of deal terms.” For this money, Facebook reportedly wants creators to host four to six sessions at least 30 minutes in length. Live Audio Rooms &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/21/22540508/facebook-live-audio-rooms-clubhouse-rival-spaces-greenhouse"&gt;launched in the US in June&lt;/a&gt;, with the feature sitting alongside &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394215/facebook-soundbites-audio-mark-zuckerberg-interview"&gt;other audio-focused products&lt;/a&gt; like podcasts, music, and short-form “Soundbites.” Established names who’ve appeared on Live Audio Rooms include singer Miley Cyrus and comedian Sherry Cola, though there’s no reporting that these individuals were paid to appear. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WM6mEw"&gt;You may have the impression that only Meta needs to pay creators to use its platform, but really this behavior is common across the entire industry (Meta just has deeper pockets than most). TikTok has its &lt;a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-gb/the-tiktok-creator-fund-is-now-live-across-europe-and-here-is-how-to-apply"&gt;Creator Fund&lt;/a&gt;, Snap has its &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/06/snapchat-revamps-creator-payouts-by-offering-chance-to-win-prizes-with-spotlight-challenges/"&gt;Spotlight program&lt;/a&gt;, and Twitter has a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22724450/twitter-spaces-accelerator-spark-clubhouse-creators"&gt;paid “accelerator” program&lt;/a&gt; for its audio feature Spaces. Indeed, pretty much every major platform offers financial incentives of some sort to attract and retain talent. The only question is who will stay when the money runs out.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22791007/facebook-live-audio-rooms-paying-creators-musicians"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22791007/facebook-live-audio-rooms-paying-creators-musicians</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-19T06:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-19T06:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>How Twitter got research right</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EjMsR1S8NaTfHxx9yQtd7ldliWY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70164337/acastro_200715_1777_twitter_0005.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zug8T1"&gt;It has not been a happy time for researchers at big tech companies. Hired to help executives understand platforms’ shortcomings, research teams inevitably reveal inconvenient truths. Companies hire teams to build “responsible AI” but bristle when their employees discover algorithmic bias. They boast about the quality of their internal research but disavow it when it makes its way to the press. At Google, this story played out in &lt;a href="https://www.platformer.news/p/the-withering-email-that-got-an-ethical"&gt;the forced departure of ethical AI researcher Timnit Gebru&lt;/a&gt; and the subsequent fallout for her team. At Facebook, it led to &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-facebook-files-11631713039"&gt;Frances Haugen and the Facebook Files&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t4DGna"&gt;For these reasons, it’s always of note when a tech platform takes one of those unflattering findings and publishes it for the world to see. At the end of October, Twitter did just that. Here’s &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/oct/22/twitter-admits-bias-in-algorithm-for-rightwing-politicians-and-news-outlets"&gt;Dan Milmo in the &lt;em&gt;Guardian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="mcVGqF"&gt;Twitter has admitted it amplifies more tweets from right-wing politicians and news outlets than content from left-wing sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0qEGLJ"&gt;The social media platform examined tweets from elected officials in seven countries – the UK, US, Canada, France, Germany, Spain and Japan. It also studied whether political content from news organisations was amplified on Twitter, focusing primarily on US news sources such as Fox News, the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed&lt;/em&gt;. […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fHWlw6"&gt;The research found that in six out of seven countries, apart from Germany, tweets from right-wing politicians received more amplification from the algorithm than those from the left; right-leaning news organisations were more amplified than those on the left; and generally politicians’ tweets were more amplified by an algorithmic timeline than by the chronological timeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="HNMZKC"&gt;Twitter’s &lt;a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/company/2021/rml-politicalcontent"&gt;blog post on the subject&lt;/a&gt; was accompanied by &lt;a href="https://cdn.cms-twdigitalassets.com/content/dam/blog-twitter/official/en_us/company/2021/rml/Algorithmic-Amplification-of-Politics-on-Twitter.pdf"&gt;a 27-page paper&lt;/a&gt; that further describes the study’s findings and research and methodology. It wasn’t the first time this year that the company had volunteered empirical support for years-old, speculative criticism of its work. This summer, Twitter hosted an open competition to find bias in its photo-cropping algorithms. James Vincent &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22617972/twitter-photo-cropping-algorithm-ai-bias-bug-bounty-results"&gt;described the results at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="RVCZhr"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://github.com/bogdan-kulynych/saliency_bias"&gt;top-placed entry&lt;/a&gt; showed that Twitter’s cropping algorithm favors faces that are “slim, young, of light or warm skin color and smooth skin texture, and with stereotypically feminine facial traits.” The second and third-placed entries showed that the system was &lt;a href="https://github.com/erickmu1/Twitter-Algorithmic-Bias"&gt;biased against people with white or grey hair&lt;/a&gt;, suggesting age discrimination, and &lt;a href="https://github.com/royapakzad/image-crop-analysis"&gt;favors English over Arabic script in images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="GneboW"&gt;These results were not hidden in a closed chat group, never to be discussed. Instead, Rumman Chowdhury — who leads machine learning ethics and responsibility at Twitter — &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KLwdzLiJywI"&gt;presented them publicly at DEF CON&lt;/a&gt; and praised participants for helping to illustrate the real-world effects of algorithmic bias. The winners were paid for their contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mSpO4o"&gt;On one hand, I don’t want to overstate Twitter’s bravery here. The results the company published, while opening it up to some criticisms, are nothing that is going to result in a full Congressional investigation. And the fact that the company is much smaller than Google or Facebook parent Meta, which both serve billions of people, means that anything found by its researchers is less likely to trigger a global firestorm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FY2895"&gt;At the same time, Twitter doesn’t &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to do this kind of public-interest work. And in the long run, I do believe it will make the company stronger and more valuable. But it would be relatively easy for any company executive or board member to make a case against doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JsT4JZ"&gt;For that reason, I’ve been eager to talk to the team responsible for it. This week, I met virtually with Chowdhury and Jutta Williams, product lead for Chowdhury’s team. (Inconveniently, as of&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/10/28/technology/facebook-meta-name-change.html"&gt; October 28th&lt;/a&gt;: the Twitter team’s official name is Machine Learning Ethics, Transparency, and Accountability: META.) I wanted to know more about how Twitter is doing this work, how it has been received internally, and where it’s going next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sVIKsz"&gt;Here’s some of what I learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IkHRZw"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Twitter is betting that public participation will accelerate and improve its findings&lt;/strong&gt;. One of the more unusual aspects of Twitter’s AI ethics research is that it is paying outside volunteer researchers to participate. Chowdhury was trained as an ethical hacker and observed that her friends working in cybersecurity are often able to protect systems more nimbly by creating financial incentives for people to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T022FV"&gt;“Twitter was the first time that I was actually able to work at an organization that was visible and impactful enough to do this and also ambitious enough to fund it,” said Chowdhury, who joined the company a year ago when it acquired her AI risk management startup. “It’s hard to find that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="yviwWk"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Often, only the loudest voices are addressed, while major problems are left to linger&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1WZeIL"&gt;It’s typically difficult to get good feedback from the public about algorithmic bias, Chowdhury told me. Often, only the loudest voices are addressed, while major problems are left to linger because affected groups don’t have contacts at platforms who can address them. Other times, issues are diffuse through the population, and individual users may not feel the negative effects directly. (Privacy tends to be an issue like that.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b39V4L"&gt;Twitter’s bias bounty helped the company build a system to solicit and implement that feedback, Chowdhury told me. The company has since announced it will stop cropping photos in previews after its algorithms were found to largely favor the young, white, and beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kAmzou"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responsible AI is hard in part because no one understands fully understands decisions made by algorithms&lt;/strong&gt;. Ranking algorithms in social feeds are probabilistic — they show you things based on how likely you are to like, share, or comment on them. But there’s no one algorithm making that decision — it’s typically a mesh of multiple (sometimes dozens) of different models, each making guesses that are then weighted differently according to ever-shifting factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qop5FK"&gt;That’s a major reason why it’s so difficult to confidently build AI systems that are “responsible” — there is simply a lot of guesswork involved. Chowdhury pointed out the difference here between working on responsible AI and cybersecurity. In security, she said, it’s usually possible to unwind why the system is vulnerable, so long as you can discover where the attacker entered it. But in responsible AI, finding a problem often doesn’t tell you much about what created it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s3sYdW"&gt;That’s the case with the company’s research on amplifying right-wing voices, for example. Twitter is confident that the phenomenon is real but can only theorize as to the reasons behind it. It may be something in the algorithm. But it might also be a user behavior — maybe right-wing politicians tend to tweet in a way to elicit more comments, for example, which then causes their tweets to be weighted more heavily by Twitter’s systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AnoQQc"&gt;“There’s this law of unintended consequences to large systems,” said Williams, who previously worked at Google and Facebook. “It could be so many different things. How we’ve weighted algorithmic recommendation may be a part of it. But it wasn’t intended to be a consequence of political affiliation. So there’s so much research to be done.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3ZqQFo"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There’s no real consensus on what ranking algorithms “should” do&lt;/strong&gt;. Even if Twitter does solve the mystery of what’s causing right-wing content to spread more widely, it won’t be clear what the company should do about it. What if, for example, the answer lies not in the algorithm but in the behavior of certain accounts? If right-wing politicians simply generate more comments than left-wing politicians, there may not be an obvious intervention for Twitter to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZomK2G"&gt;“I don’t think anybody wants us to be in the business of forcing some sort of social engineering of people’s voices,” Chowdhury told me. “But also, we all agree that we don’t want amplification of negative content or toxic content or unfair political bias. So these are all things that I would love for us to be unpacking.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BuXEYG"&gt;That conversation should be held publicly, she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DqW9Am"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Twitter thinks algorithms can be saved&lt;/strong&gt;. One possible response to the idea that all our social feeds are unfathomably complex and cannot be explained by their creators is that we should shut them down and delete the code. Congress now regularly introduces bills that would make ranking algorithms illegal, or make platforms legally liable for what they recommend, or force platforms to let people opt out of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TkQwRq"&gt;Twitter’s team, for one, believes that ranking has a future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZYK6LT"&gt;“The algorithm is something that can be saved,” Williams said. “The algorithm needs to be understood. And the &lt;em&gt;inputs&lt;/em&gt; to the algorithm need to be something that everybody can manage and control.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aQXO22"&gt;With any luck, Twitter will build just that kind of system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oD3e7x"&gt;Of course, the risk in writing a piece like this is that, in my experience, teams like this are fragile. One minute, leadership is pleased with its findings and enthusiastically hiring for it; the next, it’s withering by attrition amidst budget cuts or reorganized out of existence amidst personality conflicts or regulatory concerns. Twitter’s early success with META is promising, but META’s long-term future is not assured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="abz6qo"&gt;In the meantime, the work is likely to get harder. Twitter is now actively at work on a project to &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/16/twitter-taps-crypto-developer-to-lead-bluesky-decentralized-social-network-effort/"&gt;make its network decentralized&lt;/a&gt;, which could shield parts of the network from its own efforts to build the network more responsibly. Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey has also envisioned an “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22275441/jack-dorsey-decentralized-app-store-algorithms"&gt;app store for social media algorithms&lt;/a&gt;,” giving users more choice around how their feeds are ranked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="W4LoNz"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I’m not sure it’s feasible for us to jump right into a marketplace of algorithms”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ah0YTg"&gt;It’s difficult enough to rank &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; feed responsibly — what it means to make a whole app store of algorithms “responsible” will be a much larger challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6zVhn2"&gt;“I’m not sure it’s feasible for us to jump right into a marketplace of algorithms,” Williams said. “But I do think it’s possible for our algorithm to understand signal that’s curated by you. So if there’s profanity in a tweet, as an example: how sensitive are you to that kind of language? Are there specific words that you would consider very, very profane and you don’t want to see? How do we give you controls for you to establish what your preferences are so that that signal can be used in any kind of recommendation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hr7GPp"&gt;“I think that there’s a third-party signal more than there is a third-party bunch of algorithms,” Williams said. “You have to be careful about what’s in an algorithm.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="4WsLCB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Platformer by Casey Newton","description":"&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;This column was co-published with&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a class=\"ql-link\" href=\"https://www.platformer.news/\" target=\"_blank\"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Platformer&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;, a daily newsletter about Big Tech and democracy.&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;","label":"Subscribe here","url":"https://www.platformer.news/"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22790174/twitter-research-transparency-published-findings"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22790174/twitter-research-transparency-published-findings</id>
    <author>
      <name>Casey Newton</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-19T05:39:10-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-19T05:39:10-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter stops opening links in AMP on iOS and Android</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Twitter’s blue bird silhouette logo on a black background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/S5nTGmtbTqPI7Nzn4DaMquqnFfo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70164308/acastro_180827_1777_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lHPCJj"&gt;Twitter has quietly rolled back its support for Accelerated Mobile Pages (AMP) on mobile, according to a &lt;a href="https://developer.twitter.com/en/docs/twitter-for-websites/amp/overview"&gt;support page&lt;/a&gt; spotted by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/christian_wilde/status/1460929280486031367"&gt;SEO consultant Christian Oliveira&lt;/a&gt;. The support page originally detailed how Twitter would automatically send users of its mobile apps to the AMP version of a page from links posted on the social network. However, at some point since October 21st, Twitter updated the page with a notice saying it’s retiring the feature by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BXGXTT"&gt;According &lt;a href="https://searchengineland.com/twitter-rolls-back-amp-support-no-longer-sends-users-to-amp-pages-376168"&gt;to data from &lt;em&gt;SearchEngineLand&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, this retirement process appears to have been completed earlier this month. Now, attempting to visit a page from Twitter appears to send users directly to the regular web page, rather than an AMP version that may be available.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UWBnkMaf-RAycN4vl1V27C_A_6E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23026927/msedge_OX1DnKyNyR.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Twitter&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter’s notice saying it’s retiring the AMP feature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pXWd2B"&gt;Although Twitter notes that the AMP allows for “fast-loading, beautiful, high-performing mobile web experiences,” the technology has proved controversial since Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/10/7/9467149/google-accelerated-mobile-pages-caching-preview"&gt;introduced it in 2015&lt;/a&gt;. Much of the controversy centered around Google’s perceived control of the project, with some critics claiming that it amounted to Google’s attempt to &lt;a href="http://ampletter.org/"&gt;reinforce its control of the open web&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rjzIJn"&gt;But it also has more basic user interface problems for a platform like Twitter because of the way it can mess with URLs, when it makes pages appear to be from Google regardless of the website that created them. It’s an annoying situation that’s led to the creation of &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/amplosion-redirect-amp-links/id1585734696"&gt;browser extensions which&lt;/a&gt; automatically redirect AMP pages to the original article URL to reduce confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FWmGCh"&gt;Twitter’s support document doesn’t give a reason for its change in policy. A spokesperson was not immediately available to respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XmMM0n"&gt;The social network’s move follows a policy change from Google itself in May 2020 when it announced that it would &lt;a href="https://searchengineland.com/amp-wont-be-required-for-googles-top-stories-section-335276"&gt;no longer require news sites&lt;/a&gt; to offer AMP versions of their pages in order to be featured in its search engine’s Top Stories section. The move was a long time coming following a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/8/17095078/google-amp-accelerated-mobile-page-announcement-standard-web-packaging-urls"&gt;Google initiative launched in May 2018&lt;/a&gt; to take what the company had learned from AMP and turn its features into general web standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NHRvND"&gt;For more background on AMP, check out this &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/25/17898006/google-amp-future-malte-uble-interview-vergecast"&gt;2018 episode of The Vergecast&lt;/a&gt; featuring an interview with AMP’s former tech lead Malte Ubl.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22791002/twitter-amp-ios-android"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22791002/twitter-amp-ios-android</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-19T03:01:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-19T03:01:01-05:00</updated>
    <title>Halo Infinite’s Grappleshot helps make the familiar feel new</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Rga-H7rdmc3qs6nSTj9YVOaiikE=/200x0:2360x1440/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70164175/8KMUico.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Halo Infinite is a familiar but different Halo&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="f5Zasn"&gt;I wasn’t ready to start sneaking around a Banished warship in my first few minutes in &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;’s campaign, but there I was facing down an army of Grunts, Jackals, Brutes, and Elites. The initial thrill of the classic &lt;em&gt;Halo &lt;/em&gt;music and the familiarity of the enemies was a nostalgia overload for a good few minutes, but after it all wore off I noticed the new Grappleshot. Oh, boy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OzaTPE"&gt;I first played &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; 20 years ago, and while the combination of grenades, melees, and an assortment of weapons and vehicles still remains today, the Grappleshot is an entirely new addition that transforms the campaign mode. It’s an ideal companion that left me excited and wanting to upgrade it fully during my first few hours of the campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QMSLZ6PC8dB1lFIvTSCrddAVIHQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23024291/grappleshot.gif"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just Grappleshot Jackal shields to kill them easily.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vvnfDF"&gt;You’re introduced to the Grappleshot in the early missions in &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;, as you fight your way outside toward the open areas of the Zeta Halo that the Banished enemies have taken over. The first level is incredibly vertical, and it acts like a subtle training mode to gently nudge you into mastering the Grappleshot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mdpsSV"&gt;While you can run, jump, and shoot enemies freely without it, zip lining toward a Brute and punching them in the face is incredibly satisfying. If Jackal’s shields are annoying, just Grappleshot the shield to force them to lower it. It’s also great for instantly figuring out those “How do I get up there?” moments, where you can just aim and transport yourself to areas that would be impossible to get to otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VzzwXY"&gt;I’ve been playing around with the Grappleshot for months during the &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; multiplayer previews, and I was impressed with its mobility there, but it has unlimited uses in the campaign. That means it really comes into its own. You can use it to navigate around quicker or to propel yourself toward an enemy, and it can also be used to retrieve items like guns or fusion coils. There’s only a short cooldown in the campaign mode, so the possibilities for speed running are going to be endless. I can’t wait to witness what talented players manage to accomplish here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/N02jXTW4lN_cr_pIwmVsSN7rMaw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23024268/halozeta.gif"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;One part of the Zeta Halo.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="djao5x"&gt;The dark and eerie areas in the first few missions of &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite &lt;/em&gt;where you’re first introduced to the Grappleshot are what you’d expect from classic &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt;. There’s a clear storyline and structure, and plenty of Banished enemies to eliminate. If you’re new to the franchise, the story itself takes place 18 months after the events of &lt;em&gt;Halo 5&lt;/em&gt;, but the story and adventures really start to expand once you first venture outside onto the Zeta Halo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IK7HQj"&gt;It’s here where &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; really sets itself apart from &lt;em&gt;Halo &lt;/em&gt;games that have come before it. It still maintains a very &lt;em&gt;Halo: Combat Evolved &lt;/em&gt;look and feel, but you can freely explore the Zeta Halo, and it’s filled with items to discover, high-value targets to eliminate, outposts to conquer, and of course areas of the main storyline to complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cvBQTz9FI22213So84El-W6POeQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23024294/Xbox_Series_S___Xbox_Series_S_2021_11_18_14_23_19.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Zeta Halo surface.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kVbGGw"&gt;While it certainly looks and feels like an open-world &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; game at first glance, 343 Industries limits the areas of Zeta Halo you can explore until you’ve progressed and unlocked new areas. It’s difficult to tell right now exactly how big this map will be, but you can pan around and get a sense that there’s plenty to unlock. It certainly sounds vast, and I had to spend a few minutes simply standing still and appreciating the subtle audio of the environment and animals that surrounded me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JOeXLR"&gt;You can also earn armor upgrades, improve your Grappleshot abilities, and much more here. I only experienced a few upgrades during my initial preview of &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;, but there are upgrades to stun grappled enemies for several seconds, reduce the Grappleshot cooldown by 40 percent, deliver a shockwave blast when holding melee while you grapple, and even increase the radius of the shockwave blast. I can’t wait to unlock all of these options and see how truly powerful the Grappleshot can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/03v-pk1xkHTlnVHqLfT8CJPDn7U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23024230/Xbox_Series_S___Xbox_Series_S_2021_11_18_13_50_18.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Grappleshot upgrades look promising.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2Wk8h7"&gt;While you can explore the Halo Zeta surface and discover occasional skirmishes and battles, the first main campaign mission here is to infiltrate a huge tower that houses a Banished boss. It’s a dark, steam-filled location that really demonstrates just how good &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite &lt;/em&gt;looks running on the Xbox Series X, with lighting that requires you to activate a light on Master Chief’s helmet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CMg78r"&gt;Out of all the initial missions in &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;, I enjoyed this one the most and it left me wanting more. The boss battle introduces you to the threat sensor, a projectile you can use to track enemies through walls and terrain. The threat sensor is particularly useful against enemies that like to cloak and hide away, and you’ll find high-value targets out in the Halo Zeta that do exactly that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OjOTE4FhYNQ7I45pG22GBQPvLtI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23024250/Qi6iPb5.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite starts out dark, eerie, and steam-filled.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yYCiqs"&gt;You can choose to equip the threat sensor when you need it in place of the Grappleshot, and I’m curious to see how the campaign progresses to unlock extra equipment and abilities. The progression system works through Spartan Cores, which can be found throughout the main campaign missions or across Zeta Halo. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ewxGY9"&gt;Once you unlock more vehicles, you can also summon them freely from outposts that you’ve secured. You have to battle Banished forces to capture outposts, following their six-month occupation of the Ring. These outposts reveal new Banished structures, extra high-value targets, and you can use them to rally UNSC Marines who are willing to accompany you on missions and defeat enemies. If you rescue marines out in the field or capture Banished bases, you’ll also earn Valor — a resource that lets you unlock new weapons, vehicles, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XTs4Qu"&gt;I’ve only played the first few hours of &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; so far, and it already feels like there are many hours ahead of me. The Weapon, a new AI that bares a striking resemblance to Cortana, is introduced early on, and the fate of Master Chief and Cortana’s role in the story are still very much up in the air after just a few hours of gameplay. We’ll have a full review of &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; next month, where we’ll find out just how big Zeta Halo is and discover the secrets hidden within it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="yCVwar"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; already feels like a familiar but different kind of &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt;, and one that fans are going to enjoy exploring.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22789035/halo-infinite-campaign-preview"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22789035/halo-infinite-campaign-preview</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-18T21:08:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-18T21:08:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>Today, a jury got to hear Elizabeth Holmes’ lies for themselves</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Elizabeth Holmes Fraud Trial Continues" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/woga5pNJzxDg8H0U2qB6_pBgj-k=/0x0:3849x2566/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70163268/1353830876.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Justin Sullivan/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;In her own voice&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="Jp2uSH"&gt;Today we heard Elizabeth Holmes speak in court — through recordings made for &lt;a href="https://fortune.com/2014/06/12/theranos-blood-holmes/"&gt;a &lt;em&gt;Fortune&lt;/em&gt; article by Roger Parloff&lt;/a&gt;. In those recordings, Holmes claims that Theranos worked with the military, was currently working with pharmaceutical companies, that the company could do more than a thousand tests on its proprietary machines, and that the results were “at the highest level of quality.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T9lk29"&gt;None of this was true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="OIwZfY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Parloff has about 10 hours of taped conversations with Holmes&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xGurpP"&gt;Lying to reporters is not illegal, but it’s generally a bad idea since we tend to record our conversations. We’ve heard a lot about Parloff’s article in US v Elizabeth Holmes, because it was frequently sent to prospective investors as part of the materials Holmes supplied about the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4DdHhW"&gt;Parloff has about 10 hours of taped conversations with Holmes, the founder and former CEO of Theranos. He profiled Theranos after he noticed fancy celebrity lawyer David Boies had been arguing on behalf of a company Parloff had never heard of — and had won the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DIeQ9h"&gt;Parloff interviewed Holmes&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;— as well as a who’s who of Theranos notables, including former Secretary of State Henry Kissinger, former Stanford professor Channing Robertson, and Mark Laret, the CEO of UCSF Medical Center. He toured the Palo Alto headquarters of Theranos. He did not see the clinical lab. (Or, for that matter, any third-party analyzers.) He also toured the manufacturing facilities in Newark, California, which he said was “not a buzzing factory — no assembly lines or anything.” He went to a Walgreens and got his blood drawn with a fingerstick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LwSTMW"&gt;During the course of their conversation, Parloff pointed out that Quest Diagnostics did 600 different tests. He asked Holmes if Theranos did all those tests, too. “Our platform can yield — I’m thinking of the best way to say this — we can do all those tests, so we can provide data back to clinicians for all the same tests,” she responded. That was a lie — we’ve heard testimony that Theranos devices couldn’t perform more than a handful of tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="aGQMi6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;She went on to say that Theranos devices had been used in Afghanistan&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1gradp"&gt;Later, Holmes told Parloff that Theranos has “done work overseas for pharmaceutical companies and a little bit with foreign governments in the past, but right now we’ve got our work cut out for us here.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D0efta"&gt;She went on to say that Theranos devices had been used in Afghanistan, but he was not to ask her board member, Gen. James “Mad Dog” Mattis, about it — it was off the record, and besides, Mattis couldn’t talk about it. Earlier in the trial, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22689083/elizabeth-holmes-trial-james-mattis-testimony-theranos-fraud"&gt;Mattis testified&lt;/a&gt; that to his knowledge, Theranos devices were never used overseas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mes6y9"&gt;In another recording, Holmes said that she thought Theranos could do 1,000 tests on its proprietary machines. But only 200 tests are offered on the website, she claimed, because “we have operationalized certain tasks, expecting a certain set of ordering patterns.” The 200 are the most commonly-done ones, she said, “but we are adding to it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v3b72C"&gt;“Before the article comes out, we may have a new batch,” she added. This didn’t seem true, either — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/15/22676789/elizabeth-holmes-theranos-wire-fraud-erika-cheung-whistleblower"&gt;particularly given&lt;/a&gt; Theranos’ &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/29/22701542/theranos-elizabeth-holmes-celgene-bickering"&gt;struggles with quality.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="bv0wjM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;She seemed to be playing him&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mURsqv"&gt;As Parloff’s testimony went on, I noticed how well she seemed to be playing him. At one point, she emailed Parloff to tell him, “As you know we want to generally keep the focus off the hardware. A way to do this if you are referring to it/the automation in our lab is to use the word analyzers which is likely the best word to use besides analytical systems (rather than the word device).”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j6B4Pn"&gt;Sources don’t get to dictate vocabulary in journalism — at least, not in good journalism. It wasn’t the first time she played Parloff, either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sBsY2J"&gt;In one recording, she explained that the secrecy was because Theranos hadn’t finished filing its patents. “The fact we have a single device that can perform any test is a big deal,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="78f17d"&gt;“The next story is that it would be done by this device.” And it wasn’t just one story, she teased: the story after that would be about the decentralization of the devices. “Hopefully we have the opportunity to tell that story with you,” Holmes said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="hF8uS6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Parloff did more due diligence than most people who &lt;em&gt;invested&lt;/em&gt; in Theranos&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eqxwvb"&gt;What happened here is pretty obvious — Holmes dangled future exclusives in exchange for the opportunity to dictate the terms of the article, even down to the vocabulary that Parloff used. The word “device” appears twice &lt;a href="https://fortune.com/2014/06/12/theranos-blood-holmes/"&gt;in his story,&lt;/a&gt; and neither time is it in reference to Theranos machines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OoqKF4"&gt;Parloff wasn’t a chump, though; by the time he’d written the article, he’d already done more due diligence than most people who &lt;em&gt;invested&lt;/em&gt; in Theranos. He’d heard that Theranos labs were still using venipuncture and asked Holmes about it. She said it was a problem of scaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N59pxC"&gt;He pressed: it wasn’t because her system couldn’t run certain tests? She answered by saying it was a matter of volume. “Our biggest point on that is our whole business is about eliminating the need for people to do venipuncture unless they want to, in which case they can, but everything we do is about eliminating that,” Holmes told him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9GRVXS"&gt;The exchange that defense lawyers are most likely to focus on, however, wasn’t recorded. Parloff asked Holmes directly if she kept, for instance, a Siemens analyzer on hand for overflow. “And she said ‘unh-unh,’ like a nonverbal response that said no,” Parloff testified. This was corroborated only by his notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="mkLoFz"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The technology is capable of running all those tests.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2Wcbtw"&gt;Holmes also emailed Parloff &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22760601/theranos-pfizer-schering-plough-logo-memo"&gt;the faked Pfizer and Schering-Plough reports&lt;/a&gt; that Theranos actually wrote, complete with conclusions that praised Theranos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mX9J5R"&gt;When the article was published, Holmes was effusive in her praise. She did not request corrections or complain about its contents — frankly unusual for a profile of any tech company. (Ask me about the time Apple spokespeople called to complain not about my &lt;em&gt;facts&lt;/em&gt; but about my &lt;em&gt;tone&lt;/em&gt;!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8pOURz"&gt;Parloff continued talking to Holmes, probably because he was excited about getting more stories; he did get &lt;a href="https://fortune.com/2015/05/07/theranos-jump-starts-consumer-lab-testing/"&gt;one about an Arizona law&lt;/a&gt; that made it easier for patients to buy their own lab tests from places such as, well, Theranos. In 2015, she told him that as of that year, Theranos had started using third-party analyzers, because their Arizona lab wasn’t certified to perform Theranos’ lab-developed tests. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3lkLQU"&gt;“The technology is capable of running all those tests,” she told him, lying. As we found out earlier in the trial, Theranos’ devices couldn’t perform more than about a dozen tests. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="KBReag"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It was remarkable to hear the recordings of Holmes lying in her own voice&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="E3Y6KW"&gt;Later that year, Parloff went to another demo, this time in the Boies Schiller law offices in New York. Two devices were there to perform tests on him: potassium (which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22692600/elizabeth-holmes-theranos-bad-tests-complaints"&gt;didn’t work&lt;/a&gt; on Theranos devices, a former lab director testified) and Ebola. “Both machines were taking a long time, so I didn’t stay for the results,” Parloff said. He got his results that night. In another recording, Holmes instructed him not to say the same machine ran both of his tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EXqYmA"&gt;Then the sky fell. &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/theranos-has-struggled-with-blood-tests-1444881901"&gt;John Carreyrou’s &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal &lt;/em&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; published in October 2015. In the article, Carreyrou wrote that the majority of Theranos tests were done on third-party devices and Theranos devices were used for just 15 tests. Parloff immediately contacted Holmes. He asked how many tests Theranos could do as of December 2014. According to Parloff, Holmes lied again, saying, “50, 60, maybe 70, we can get you that number.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q4CzZB"&gt;It was remarkable to hear the recordings of Holmes lying in her own voice. We’ve &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/26/22747918/theranos-devos-due-diligence-fraud-trial"&gt;heard now&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/15/22783989/elizabeth-holmes-theranos-trial-investor-testimony"&gt;multiple investors &lt;/a&gt;about what &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/16/22786461/elizabeth-holmes-theranos-trial-brian-grossman-pfm-investor-testimony"&gt;she told them&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s been consistent: the platform could do basically, well, everything; pharma companies had validated it; it had been used in the battlefield. But those investors didn’t record like Parloff did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="Qut6Ub"&gt;The defense will argue that Parloff’s cooperation with the prosecution in this trial was sour grapes — a journalist trying to get back at a source who duped him, and who’s trying to pass his own mistakes off onto Holmes. Today, though, the jury got to hear Holmes’ lies in her own voice.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22790541/elizabeth-holmes-fraud-lies-recording"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22790541/elizabeth-holmes-fraud-lies-recording</id>
    <author>
      <name>Elizabeth Lopatto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-18T21:01:07-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-18T21:01:07-05:00</updated>
    <title>The NFT Bay asks if you would steal all the JPEGs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wBLGmte1fJB6_RrASUm1ZLkM-18=/77x0:1946x1246/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70163254/Screen_Shot_2021_11_18_at_14.21.58.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="id__hy46dbgzvam"&gt;In what may be one of the better pieces of performance art this year, Australian Geoffrey Huntley has &lt;a href="https://thenftbay.org"&gt;created a website&lt;/a&gt; that promises to let you torrent an entire blockchain’s worth of NFTs. It’s called, appropriately, The NFT Bay, and it’s an almost exact replica of the famous pirating site (with an added cheeky &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/pkpbay/nft-collector-sells-peoples-fursonas-for-dollar100k-in-right-click-mindset-war"&gt;DMCA takedown&lt;/a&gt; link). As a site, it seems to do what it says on the tin, but as a statement it could spark an interesting discussion around what it means if you claim ownership over something on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gADqzO"&gt;Pretty much every link on the site (except for the one that’s a Rick Roll) will eventually lead you to &lt;a href="https://thenftbay.org/description.html"&gt;the description page&lt;/a&gt;, which would look right at home on the real Pirate Bay (according to my friend, who is definitely not me because I’ve never pirated anything). At the bottom is an actual download link — clicking on it will get you the torrent, letting you download a file called “preview.jpg” which shows off a bunch of Bored Ape images, as well as zip files that supposedly contain all the NFTs from the Ethereum and Solana blockchains. All told, the download is just under 20TB. That is, to put it mildly, a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of image files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3WsiPw"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt; OMG WHO RIGHT CLICKED ALL OF THE &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NFTs?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#NFTs&lt;/a&gt;?☠️&lt;br&gt;  ‍☠️ &lt;a href="https://t.co/o0YRK78AkL"&gt;https://t.co/o0YRK78AkL&lt;/a&gt;  ‍☠️ &lt;br&gt;  &lt;a href="https://t.co/g74TFqzX0n"&gt;pic.twitter.com/g74TFqzX0n&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— geoff      (@GeoffreyHuntley) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GeoffreyHuntley/status/1461322836165885954?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 18, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AOu1TN"&gt;A familiar argument is playing out in the replies to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GeoffreyHuntley/status/1461322836165885954"&gt;Huntley’s announcement tweet&lt;/a&gt; — NFT haters point to it as a triumph that proves NFTs have no value, and crypto fans try to prove how unbothered they are by replying in droves that it’s actually the proof of ownership, not the image, that gives NFTs their value. Thinking that you’re getting the same thing by saving the JPEG is a right-click mindset, as they say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IhgNWo"&gt;I mean, good art is supposed to spark discussion, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7aEn0I"&gt;For his part, Huntley explains that part of his reasoning for making it was the fact that NFTs very often &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/25/22349242/nft-metadata-explained-art-crypto-urls-links-ipfs"&gt;don’t store any media&lt;/a&gt; on the blockchain, instead just linking to a version stored on a potentially fragile web server. He also gives a much more in-depth explanation behind the influences for The NFT Bay in &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/ghuntley/9261d469bc7b0e10789538ddd3609e0b"&gt;an FAQ on his GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/xgdxvw/someone-made-a-pirate-bay-for-nfts"&gt;in an excellent interview with &lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="QE5Tv9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10374749"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8Ac9b6"&gt;What I enjoy most about The NFT Bay, though, is that it both takes NFT-boosters at their word and pokes fun at the concept. “You want to claim ownership over something,” it asks. “On the internet, that means someone’s going to pirate it.” And Huntley’s announcement message of “OMG WHO RIGHT CLICKED ALL OF THE #NFTs?” takes the “you wouldn’t download a JPEG” meme (shared by both supporters and critics alike) and says “bet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="85E7je"&gt;But there remains an obvious question: &lt;em&gt;does it actually contain every NFT on the Ethereum blockchain&lt;/em&gt;? Regrettably, I don’t have an answer for you — trying to download the nearly 15TB zip file would put me &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/23/21591420/comcast-cap-data-1-2tb-home-users-internet-xfinity"&gt;so far over my data cap&lt;/a&gt; that Comcast would probably break down my door with a battering ram. However, others have shown that it is possible to download all the NFTs, so Huntley isn’t promising the impossible here (basically, your program would just have to find all the tokens on the blockchain and use the links they contain to download the media). Would it impact the artistic statement if someone finally finishes downloading it and discovers it doesn’t contain all the JPEGs? That’s probably something you’ll have to decide for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K3tp1p6tDnspU_RUWXq0kaQ6GJI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23025976/Screen_Shot_2021_11_18_at_15.22.13.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unfortunately my laptop doesn’t have a 20TB internal SSD.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="isCfGl"&gt;Unfortunately, it seems like you would have to go through the download process to experience the collection — as far as I can tell, the NFT Bay’s search function just returns the same results no matter what you put in it, despite the tantalizing checkboxes promising to let you see only CryptoPunks or Bored Ape Yacht Club images. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bEFVbR-v0k14WIPyRjm9BtJoYHs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23025985/Screen_Shot_2021_11_18_at_15.29.55.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;I cackled so hard when I first saw these checkbox, before I realized they didn’t live up to the promise.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="RH6qrG"&gt;I guess that’s what happens when you’re relying on outdated, centralized, Web 2.0 tech to distribute your stolen NFTs. That’s why I’ll be waiting for the web3 version of LimeWire to build my right-click collection.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22790131/nft-bay-pirating-digital-ownership-piracy-crypto-art-right-click"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22790131/nft-bay-pirating-digital-ownership-piracy-crypto-art-right-click</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-18T20:31:34-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-18T20:31:34-05:00</updated>
    <title>ConstitutionDAO loses $43 million auction of rare US Constitution copy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9RtajGW_xasXhrndyT7dedTguFA=/0x0:1746x1164/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70163155/constdao.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;One of 13 remaining copies of the Official Edition of the Constitution. | Image: Sotheby’s&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RYbxVr"&gt;A quickly assembled group of crypto enthusiasts who crowdfunded an astonishing $47 million in funds to bid for a rare copy of the US Constitution lost out to a bidder with deeper pockets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w02mBh"&gt;The group, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787993/constitutiondao-crypto-buy-us-constitution-copy-sothebys-ethereum"&gt;ConstitutionDAO&lt;/a&gt;, said in an update on Discord that they did not win the auction at Sotheby’s tonight, which sold for &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sothebys/status/1461497347377086467"&gt;a total of $43.2 million&lt;/a&gt;. The DAO’s organizers believed they would not have enough money to “insure, store, and transport the document” if they had made a higher bid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0tp3vD"&gt;The group assembled over the past week, mostly, it seems, because it seemed like a bunch of randos on the internet buying an important historical document would be a funny thing to do. Somehow, they managed to get enough interest to raise a huge sum in Ether. The organizers say they will refund all contributors, minus Ethereum network fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="y7HPhQ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="und" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://t.co/6GVxlkvJbj"&gt;pic.twitter.com/6GVxlkvJbj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— ConstitutionDAO ( ,  ) (@ConstitutionDAO) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ConstitutionDAO/status/1461498841820192771?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 19, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="f4O70j"&gt;“While this wasn’t the outcome we hoped for, we still made history tonight with ConstitutionDAO,” the organizers wrote in an update. “This is the largest crowdfund for a physical object that we are aware of—crypto or fiat. We are so incredibly grateful to have done this together with you all and are still in shock that we even got this far.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q2RmyH"&gt;The bidding process, which should have been a thrilling and potentially celebratory moment for the thousands of contributors who stayed online to watch, ended up being a chaotic and messy event. Bids were made in person through representatives who bid anonymously on behalf of potential buyers. Bidding quickly jumped to $30 million, then ticked up million by million over the following minutes, with two representatives slowly going back and forth, conferring with the final pair of potential buyers by phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nTIZyr"&gt;But no one knew which of the two representatives were bidding on behalf of ConstitutionDAO. In the group’s Discord, people spammed guesses about which of the two representatives was on their side. Even once the auction wrapped, no one knew who the winner was, and conflicting information trickled out through tweets and Twitter Spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XnIkFZ"&gt;More than 10 minutes after bidding ended, ConstitutionDAO organizers finally posted an official update stating that they had not won the bid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZOVDEr"&gt;Despite the loss, the DAO’s ability to raise so much money so quickly, to garner the excitement of thousands, and to push the price up against another wealthy party is the latest example of individuals organizing at a large scale online. We’ve increasingly seen &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22744728/money-fandom-cryptocurrency-retail-trades-stocks"&gt;consumers join together financially&lt;/a&gt; to stand up to larger interests — though not always in successful or entirely coherent ways — like when a bunch of Redditors sent the stock of GameStop and a handful of other companies soaring in early 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bSEvA8"&gt;If it had succeeded, the DAO planned to determine the document’s future by vote based on governance tokens passed out to contributors and distributed through the Ethereum blockchain. With a loss instead, the DAO has to tackle another logistical issue: returning $47 million in Ether and dissolving what had, for a brief couple of days, been a multi-million dollar organization.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22790452/constitutiondao-loses-auction-for-rare-us-constitution-copy-sothebys"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22790452/constitutiondao-loses-auction-for-rare-us-constitution-copy-sothebys</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-18T18:46:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-18T18:46:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>GeForce Now is about to start streaming PC games directly to LG’s TVs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0DMCjOlT537JnRH18nfmts6fygU=/103x0:1498x930/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70162769/LG_NVIDIA_GeForce_NOW_01.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A beta of GeForce Now is coming to some LG TVs running webOS.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: LG&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eA4eos"&gt;LG first said &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224359/google-stadia-nvidia-geforce-now-lg-tv-2021"&gt;in January&lt;/a&gt; that Nvidia’s GeForce Now cloud gaming service was headed to some of its TVs, and now, it’s finally here — though as a beta. LG is rolling out the beta this week for “select 2021 LG 4K OLED, QNED Mini LED, and NanoCell TV models in 80 markets,” &lt;a href="https://www.lgnewsroom.com/2021/11/lg-to-bring-nvidia-geforce-now-cloud-gaming-to-webos-smart-tvs/"&gt;according to a press release&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6PSxW5"&gt;GeForce Now lets you play PC games you own on other devices via the cloud, and this new webOS app will make it easier to use the service on a bigger screen. That said, games will be capped at 60fps and 1080p resolution — you won’t be able to play GeForce Now games in 4K via the webOS app. (That feature is currently &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/10/21/shield-tv-geforce-now-4k-hdr-gaming/"&gt;exclusive to Nvidia’s Shield TV set-top box&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oRbuaV"&gt;Every GeForce Now tier is supported, Nvidia tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, including the new tier that lets you play games on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/21/22738006/nvidia-rtx-3080-geforce-now-features-price-release-date-streaming-option"&gt;its dedicated RTX 3080 pods&lt;/a&gt;. Every gamepad-supported game works, too, the company says. If you don’t own any PC games yourself but still want to give the service a spin, there are more than 35 free-to-play games available on GeForce Now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kORakc"&gt;Nvidia says it plans to improve upon the current app by releasing updates in partnership with LG through 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22790223/geforce-now-lg-tv-webos-beta"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22790223/geforce-now-lg-tv-webos-beta</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
