<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-06-11T07:32:55-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-11T07:32:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T07:32:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>iOS 15 and macOS 12 take a small but significant step towards a password-less future</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/y1tUEPfMED8zmnB8NwlCuHcLUaY=/0x0:2159x1439/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69438671/chrome_IJmX1jx9w5.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the future you’ll be able to sign up for a service without needing to create a password at all.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JXCi8q"&gt;Apple’s upcoming iOS 15 and macOS Monterey will preview a new feature called “Passkeys in iCloud Keychain,” which is an attempt to help replace passwords with a more secure login process. Instead of logging into an app or website using string of text, &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/videos/play/wwdc2021/10106/?time=1141"&gt;a WWDC presentation&lt;/a&gt; showed how you could instead use Face ID, Touch ID, or a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22458935/two-factor-security-key-how-to-yubico"&gt;security key&lt;/a&gt;, to gain access. The Passkeys are then synced across your Apple devices using iCloud. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JC7rbm"&gt;Although passwords are currently the most popular way to secure accounts, they’re &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/24/18514225/passwords-fido2-authentication-webauthn-security-key-cybersecurity-online-browser-web"&gt;plagued with a host of problems&lt;/a&gt;. Passwords can be phished, forgotten, and they’re insecure if not used properly (think about the number of times you’ve been tempted to re-use one across multiple accounts). But Apple thinks its new Passkeys solution can solve these problems, as shown by the comparison table below.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rEhmlHS1ivntfPCHP9_ImpPUD1w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22652327/XiXVXmKMSV.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple argues its new system is more secure than regular passwords, and more convenient than security keys.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="VW56PC"&gt;In a demonstration, Apple showed how the new feature could remove the need to ever create a password to sign in to an app or website in the first place. Instead of creating a username and password during the sign-up process like normal, Apple authentication experience engineer Garrett Davidson just enters a username and allowed the app to register his Face ID as a Passkey. Then he showed how he could use Face ID to log into the app in future, or even log into his account via the service’s website. It works on Macs with Touch ID, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bMpgb5"&gt;The functionality rests on the WebAuthn standard, which Apple, Google, Microsoft, and others have been slowly adding support for over time. Last year Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/24/21301509/apple-safari-14-browser-face-touch-id-logins-webauthn-fido2"&gt;added support for it to offer password-less logins&lt;/a&gt; in Safari in iOS and macOS. But the new approach goes deeper, integrating WebAuthn into an app’s sign-up process, and syncing your credentials across Apple devices via iCloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JtSDu3"&gt;Behind the scenes, WebAuthn uses public key cryptography to let you log in without your private credentials ever having to actually leave your device. Instead, your phone or computer is only sending a “signature,” which proves your identity without having to share your secret private key.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vN020YCX-omYkcMK4E0cDg7yC3g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22652336/2ayp0HbOiQ.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;WebAuthn’s process means your most sensitive information never leaves your device when you log in.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LAkaoG"&gt;Apple admits that the feature is in its early stages. It’s only releasing in preview this year, and will be turned off by default in iOS 15 and macOS Monterey. Developers can enable it, but it’s not meant for widespread use. There’s also the obvious limitation that the feature relies on iCloud to function, so you’re out of luck if you need to log in to the same service on a Windows or Android device. Apple admits this is a problem, however, suggesting it’s  working towards improving cross-platform support in future. Apps and websites will also need to enable support for the new process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LMhC9S"&gt;But the move is another sign of the growing momentum behind ditching passwords. Microsoft has announced plans to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/11/20690359/microsoft-windows-10-passwordless-password-option-update"&gt;make Windows 10 password-less&lt;/a&gt;, and Google has been working to make it possible to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/12/20801954/google-passwords-chrome-fido2-webauthn-fingerprint-biometrics-screen-lock"&gt;sign into its services without passwords&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="82SeVg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22529266/passkeys-icloud-keychain-ios-15-passwordless-future-security-login"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22529266/passkeys-icloud-keychain-ios-15-passwordless-future-security-login</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-11T07:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T07:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The podcasting hype house from hell</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YbVdIT9n3sGWquLW9vpIyQUvpqE=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69438535/VRG_ILLO_4414_Podcast_HypeHouse_s.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;How China’s biggest audio platform funded one man’s frat boy dreams&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="jlN3r9"&gt;Imagine you’re a podcaster who’s been recording your show at CBS Radio, a venerable, if not unglamorous spot. One day, you’re instead offered the chance to start recording in a Beverly Hills home. The house has a pool, free food for the talent — that means you! — and the space to host blowout events. You know what you’d choose, and you know what podcaster Norm Steele chose: the Hollywood life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qf25Yz"&gt;When Steele walked into the HiStudios hype house for the first time, he found an oasis, one you wouldn’t expect to come with the territory of being a podcaster. Even the biggest podcaster in the world, Joe Rogan, records in a studio resembling an underground bunker. But here, alongside two studios equipped with hardware and support staff, was a vast view of Los Angeles and the cachet that comes with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dmX1gI"&gt;“It was the professional element,” Steele says when asked why he chose to work with HiStudios, a company spun out of the buzzy podcasting startup Himalaya. “Basically, me having shows that are on the verge of being something great, they had a purpose there. It was a nice place.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="Zgt4uM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;You’re the star at the podcasting hype house&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WoIgg0"&gt;Peter Vincer, the man behind the hype house and the CEO of HiStudios, gave me a lofty spiel ahead of the company’s launch in August 2019. He envisioned a global podcast network with influencers and athletes and shows that would become international hits. He name-dropped Mike Tyson, Penny Hardaway, and Zane and Heath, and he said the company had a deal with Studio71, which works with top YouTubers like Marques Brownlee. Vincer and his team would help launch their shows not just in the US, but in China, too, thanks to HiStudios’ ties to Himalaya, a US podcasting startup funded by the massive Chinese audio company Ximalaya. (Yes, it’s just a one letter difference and very confusing.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qQN9fM"&gt;It was a bold ambition, but everyone in the podcast space pitches &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. So after writing about HiStudios that summer, I didn’t hear or think much about them again. That is, until things started falling apart. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IUlRSv"&gt;“I don’t want to have nothing to do with this dude no more,” Steele says about Vincer now. “It’s real easy to get caught up in the allure of that house. He may have it clean one day, and next thing you know, you sign the bullshit contract with some dude, and you get took.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KsNqdY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CdfYJxLKopMVAGs3O-xvkpCCVAM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22650616/acastro_210609_4414_0006.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="I5Rz8y"&gt;The story of the hype house starts, as many do, with the promise of money. Specifically, the chance to cash in on the burgeoning podcast industry. Podcasting has been thrust into the limelight over the past few years. Nearly every big tech company — from Apple and Google to Spotify and Facebook — is now involved in the space, and radio companies like iHeartMedia, Cumulus, Audacy, and SiriusXM have incorporated podcasting into their radio businesses. And these would-be podcast hitmakers have signed huge names, like Kim Kardashian, the Clinton family, and Prince Harry and Meghan Markle, to their networks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="crhVkW"&gt;Collectively, these companies have spent billions of dollars on acquisitions in an attempt to become the dominant names in audio. The industry is expected to exceed $1 billion in revenue this year, according to &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/us-podcast-ad-revenues-grew-19-yoy-in-2020-set-to-exceed-1b-this-year-and-2b-by-2023-301289260.html"&gt;a recent study&lt;/a&gt;. But these companies are playing the long game, believing they can bring billions more dollars into the space through their own investments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TxM2Nl"&gt;Audio content is already huge in some countries, and in China, Ximalaya dominates. The company says 250 million people use its app every month; users spent more than 1.5 billion minutes listening in 2020. It &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1847738/000119312521143867/d118108df1.htm"&gt;filed to go public&lt;/a&gt; in the US in April this year and was &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinese-podcast-startup-ximalaya-files-us-ipo-2021-04-30/"&gt;reportedly valued&lt;/a&gt; at over $3 billion in 2018. So, of course, the company decided to try to replicate its success stateside through an offshoot called Himalaya. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eCSDP7"&gt;Himalaya announced its arrival in February 2019 with a podcast player and list of exclusive shows, including a partnership with the Dallas Mavericks. In a debut &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2019/digital/news/podcast-platform-himalaya-raises-100-million-launches-apps-with-tipping-function-1203130068/"&gt;Variety piece&lt;/a&gt;, the company boasted about a $100 million investment led by Ximalaya, as well as from General Atlantic and SIG. It really seemed like the company could find a place in the industry, if for no other reason than having cash in the bank. (Disclosure: General Atlantic is an investor in Vox Media, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s parent company.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tmVL2W"&gt;But with Vincer and the hype house, Himalaya got more than it bargained for. In less than a year, what was intended to be a schmoozy haven for creators turned into a perplexing world of cocaine, dog poo, and unpaid bills, according to more than a dozen people who spoke with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. All the stories centered on one man: Vincer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R20Lcr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WMUdUJPUGLc0uPI2aITQz1zISPw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22650239/acastro_210506_4554_0002.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="vDiA7y"&gt;Vincer had already made a name for himself when he was brought on at Himalaya, and not always for the best reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n1qDY4"&gt;One person remembers him as disrespectful and hard to work with at Castbox, a separate China-based podcasting company. Another alleges that he would get drunk and discuss sexual escapades at business dinners. Nick Quah, of the podcasting newsletter &lt;em&gt;Hot Pod&lt;/em&gt;, says he banned Vincer from his invite-only conference after he started drinking before noon and made attendees uncomfortable. (“He seems like a jackass,” Quah told me.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vziwLY"&gt;In another story recounted by two sources, Vincer allegedly walked up to a group of people at Podcast Movement, another industry conference, in 2018 while wearing a fanny pack. He then asked if anyone wanted drugs, which these people believed were in the bag strapped to his waist. “The thing that stuck with me was, ‘Okay so you’ve got [drug] options,’” says one person who asked to remain anonymous because of their continuing work in the industry. Vincer denies that all of this happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ffhPn1"&gt;Still, Vincer was brought on as Himalaya’s VP of global marketing and partnerships in August 2018. He spent his time wooing potential collaborators and doing his best to promote Himalaya as the next big thing in the podcasting business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="55qh0p"&gt;Himalaya pitched podcasters on a simple idea: we’ll sell your ads, market your show, and take a cut of revenue from whatever sales are made. This differs in a crucial way from other companies. Other networks will sell ads for a podcast, but often aren’t willing to risk their own cash to promote a program and help it grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="66vvtx"&gt;This marketing budget mostly meant swag. Charlie Worroll, the host and creator of &lt;em&gt;Crimelines&lt;/em&gt;, says Himalaya sent listeners who signed up for her premium Himalaya feed a merch box with &lt;em&gt;Crimelines&lt;/em&gt;-branded water bottles and enamel pins. The company also offered to run a banner ad for her show at the top of its app and highlighted it in a booklet handed out at Podcast Movement. Another podcaster, Jack Luna of true crime show &lt;em&gt;Dark Topic&lt;/em&gt;, says he was told he’d be paid for every person that followed him on the Himalaya app, and other creators say they were offered the same incentive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="sipdq8"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Himalaya saw potential in backing independent creators&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TK3MBq"&gt;“A lot of these quote unquote podcast networks are literally just ad sales ... and so Himalaya was really trying to set themselves out as a network where they’re promoting their independent shows,” Worroll says. Himalaya took a vested interest in her show’s success and wanted to see it grow by fronting these marketing costs. “I think Himalaya’s vision was great. It didn’t happen, but if it did, it would have been amazing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hh6xJ6"&gt;It soon became clear that Himalaya might not have as much money as it let on. At least one of the investments Himalaya announced at launch turned out to be exaggerated, according to &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/podcast-startup-himalaya-may-have-never-had-100-million-in-vc-funding-c5fb6b86-799a-45f3-bf9e-c0bf67ad1156.html"&gt;an &lt;em&gt;Axios&lt;/em&gt; report&lt;/a&gt; from September 2019. General Atlantic never invested directly in Himalaya Media, per the report, and had actually only invested in its parent company, Ximalaya. Another supposed investor, SIG, never confirmed its funding of Himalaya. It didn’t respond to &lt;em&gt;Axios&lt;/em&gt;’ request for comment in 2019, and it also didn’t respond to multiple recent requests for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RUTpuI"&gt;That confusion might have stemmed from Vincer, according to Richard Selah, a former Himalaya contractor and eventual CRO at HiStudios. Selah tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that Vincer made the $100 million figure up as a way to get more investment out of Ximalaya and build hype for the company. Selah says he and Vincer were in an Uber, and Vincer asked what was a “better number” for a PR piece: $50 million or $100 million. Selah suggested the higher figure, and he says Vincer went with it. “That’s where the $100 million came from,” Selah says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OPeZhm"&gt;The inaccurate figure was later repeated by Himalaya’s CEO, Yu Wang, to at least one prominent journalist in the space, James Cridland from &lt;em&gt;Podnews&lt;/em&gt;, which Selah witnessed during a podcast festival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QiEsK6"&gt;Vincer spoke with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; for this story and offered multiple explanations for the following reporting and allegations made against him. Most of which comes down to none of what follows happened, or, if it did to some degree, it wasn’t his fault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o8kKXk"&gt;“There were, of course, a lot of stressful moments,” Vincer says. “It was not easy, but our team banded together, and then it’s been growing and flourishing since.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ECK6fC"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Photography licensed for a specific feature — do not use without permission" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uPvY77rWOBB2_ijhRQQT4dFGO8s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22651089/4414_L1260143.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Richard Vogel&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A party at the house involved women carrying around snakes.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="ymbhKW"&gt;It’s simultaneously easy and incomprehensible to understand how Vincer has lasted in the industry for years. He’s charismatic, funny, and has conviction on whatever he’s selling you. Plus, he’s fun — if you’re the type of person who likes partying with your boss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oxKw54"&gt;Selah, the former CRO at HiStudios, for example, alleges that Vincer would do coke and drink to excess on every work trip they took together. Which, yes, is a major red flag for any corporate executive. But on the flip side, there might be free coke in it for you. Selah also alleges Vincer used an app to arrange meetups with sex workers during work trips. (Selah didn’t report any of this to Himalaya’s CEO, and Vincer denies everything.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8NS9Gx"&gt;“His personal lifestyle I felt was a runaway train waiting to leave the tracks, and it was just a matter of time before, you know, he would basically either take the company down or take himself down,” Selah says. “He’s just a bad guy, and unfortunately, he’s a bad guy wrapped up into this magnificent personality.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YXBYQL"&gt;Still, Vincer succeeded at Himalaya and ended up with a promotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SrSwsj"&gt;Himalaya spun out a new company called HiStudios to produce podcasts, court creators, make shows, and sell ads — pretty standard podcast network stuff. The company launched publicly in August 2019 with a focus on inking deals with influencers and athletes, and Himalaya gave the team a monthly budget in addition to whatever sales they made. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NamnjB"&gt;Vincer, an American who also speaks Mandarin, was put in charge as CEO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HcqEOw"&gt;In his telling of events, Vincer says HiStudios’ creation gave him — an entrepreneurial spirit — a place to run free. He “didn’t see eye to eye” with Himalaya’s COO, he says, and this gave Himalaya a separate business to fall back on if the app didn’t work out. Selah, however, says it was more like Himalaya wanted some distance from Vincer’s behavior, particularly after he allegedly lashed out at a subordinate employee, which Selah says he witnessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="Z65XzA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“His personal lifestyle I felt was a runaway train waiting to leave the tracks”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Pg3Vux"&gt;HiStudios’ main office was based in Austin, Texas, out of a WeWork and states away from Vincer, who lives in California. Vincer, however, also wanted to run branded studios out of Los Angeles to draw talent. He envisioned impressive places where influencers and athletes could record. What he ended up with was a hype house — a rental home in Beverly Hills that he rented for between $16,000 and $17,000 per month, depending on the lease year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CHMBXU"&gt;The house is tucked into the Los Angeles hills, surrounded by well-to-do neighbors, including a  bookstore owner and dermatologist. It’s in Beverly Hills and has the famous zip code — 90210 — for prestige. The home epitomizes 1960s California modern style with a gated driveway leading up to the front entrance, which includes two Greek-style pillars framing the door. It also features floor-to-ceiling windows and sliding doors, showcasing the backyard pool, and because the house is in the shape of an L, people in one room can see what’s happening on the other side of the house. It looks like a place designed to hang and live, not so much to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z6lqzc"&gt;Instead of building a traditional studio, HiStudios turned the rental home into a space where people could work and stay for extended periods of time. Someone who’d been to the home  says the LA house served as a real workplace where people could sleep if they were in town for business. Vincer says there was always one room for people to stay in, which helped the company avoid hotel fees. Vincer himself had a room that he occasionally stayed in while in town, he says, and another room was given to his assistant. The HiStudios team occasionally hosted clients for drinks at the Beverly Hills home, but never let it get out of hand, the source who visited the home says. People could work from the living room or by the pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z0HKXQ"&gt;“Everything was perfect at first,” says Steele, who leads the Digital Soapbox podcast and multimedia network and hosts a show called &lt;em&gt;The Gangster Chronicles&lt;/em&gt;. “We said, ‘Okay, we’re going to be recording in this cool mansion.” The house had two studios decked out with production equipment, which Himalaya funded, and a producer and studio manager would be on hand to help with production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Photography licensed for a specific feature — do not use without permission" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XtzpKkVla9e6R6H99pu6E1KloXM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22651091/4414_RJV02635.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Richard Vogel&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Attendees arrived at the HiStudios home for the launch of Leaves of Legend, Krayzie Bone’s cannabis line.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0ZkJ64"&gt;Podcasters could host events at the house, too. One night, in March 2020, the home turned into a venue for a cannabis launch party for Krayzie Bone, of Bone Thugs-N-Harmony, who regularly recorded a show at the house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IZmA9d"&gt;The event sounds like a stoner’s dream. Also a frat boy’s: naked women with body paint in the cannabis line’s colors danced and mingled with the crowd; a red carpet was rolled out for photo-ops; rappers performed; party guests smoked weed out of an ice sculpture that doubled as a bong; people passed around 24-karat gold and rose petal hand-rolled cigars; and women danced with fire and albino snakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UfGymc"&gt;“It was a beautiful spot — a great view, nice pool, perfect for throwing a party,” says Crystal Bauer Feldman, who owns the marketing agency Arcane Media and was hired to run the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6wkF02"&gt;On the outside, the house and party looked incredible and suggested the company was thriving. But behind the scenes, HiStudios was off to a more troubling start, as shows struggled to get off the ground and employees alleged that the party-like atmosphere had turned toxic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qqj4RS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Photography licensed for a specific feature — do not use without permission" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1JMuuR1owko2enLLO1by6M5STJo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22651086/4414_L1250955.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Richard Vogel&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Women greeted guests at the door with cannabis on a tray.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Photography licensed for a specific feature — do not use without permission" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/__B41VS909DwbN8zdy-bUXd6xSs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22651090/4414_L1260559.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Richard Vogel&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A key feature of the HiStudios house was its pool, which people have jumped into from the roof.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Photography licensed for a specific feature — do not use without permission" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WyPBpxnK0x_FcBaY2C9wiCKteB4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22651092/4414_RJV02743.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Richard Vogel&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The ice sculpture, advertising the cannabis brand, doubled as an ice bong.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="yR5il1"&gt;Multiple shows Vincer highlighted to build hype either never panned out or didn’t last long. Vincer says HiStudios and Studio71 created some shows that he “isn’t proud of,” and that Studio71 sent him “shitty shows” to work with. The Zane and Heath show he told me about at launch ended up being a “real bummer deal” for him with the hosts eventually switching networks, and Penny Hardaway’s show fell apart after he ran into trouble with the NCAA and a suspension of a player. “I can tell you that he was not into making a podcast after all that went down with his team,” Vincer says. Studio71 declined to comment, as did Zane and Heath’s talent agency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dZkuJt"&gt;Vincer’s behavior was allegedly hurting the company’s deals, too, prior to HiStudios’ public launch. Selah alleges Vincer slept through meetings or nearly missed them because of late nights spent partying or with sex workers. In one case, he alleges he and the team repeatedly called Vincer to wake up for a meeting with Nelson Mandela’s family foundation. He says the meeting was at 9AM, and Vincer came down to the hotel lobby that morning at 9:15 with a woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yIpI2g"&gt;Vincer denies this happening and says he’s close partners with Mandela Media now, although multiple requests to the team for confirmation went unanswered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rBqYuL"&gt;“Peter Vincer should never manage people ever again in his lifetime, let alone even own a dog,” Selah says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mksixC"&gt;HiStudios employees also allege they were on the receiving end of harassment throughout their time at the Los Angeles house, according to a lawsuit filed in fall 2020. Four former HiStudios employees, including the company’s former VP of marketing, studio manager, creative director, and assistant to the CEO, allege the company facilitated and encouraged open drug use and other inappropriate workplace behavior, including inviting sex workers to events, over the course of nearly a year. These former employees describe events in which they say they were subjected to ridicule, abuse, and sexual questions that ultimately led to their alleged wrongful terminations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="1PBqfh"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Four former employees filed a lawsuit against HiStudios and Himalaya last year&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xABahp"&gt;Two women who worked at HiStudios say in the lawsuit that Vincer constantly brought up sex around them. Alexa Passer, who worked as the vice president of marketing for HiStudios, alleges that Vincer would routinely ask her questions about her sex life, including the size of her boyfriend’s penis. Passer says he once introduced her boyfriend to a group of colleagues as the guy “who Lexy is fucking,” according to the lawsuit. On another occasion, Vincer allegedly attempted to get Passer to arrange a fivesome between him, her, her boyfriend, and two women she met at a bar after a work dinner. When the women eventually walked away from the group, Vincer allegedly said to Passer, “Of course you couldn’t get it done, like everything else.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UWuOo2"&gt;Vincer says that all the plaintiffs’ employment contracts were terminated for just cause, and all the defendants have since responded to the lawsuit, denying the allegations and, in one filing, requesting the case be thrown out. The lawsuit is still pending and a trial date is set for April 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nZs0KO"&gt;The lawsuit also alleges that when looking to hire a studio manager for the company’s hype house, Vincer gathered team members around a computer and clicked through LinkedIn profiles of women, asking aloud how big their breasts were and whether they were attractive. He passed on any person of color, the lawsuit claims, because that “wasn’t the look he was going for.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W1rz8n"&gt;“I don’t do that,” Vincer says&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;in response. “A lot of people compare me to Michael Scott, and I’m obsessed with &lt;em&gt;The Office&lt;/em&gt;, and I always have been. I make very Michael Scott-y jokes, but no, that’s not the type of character I am. Everyone that knows me knows I’m not like that. That’s not me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qioTuw"&gt;Another plaintiff, Misti Taylor, was eventually hired for this studio manager role, which involved her sleeping and living at the house for prolonged periods of time, according to the lawsuit. Taylor alleges that drug use was common, and that Vincer’s children were present while people smoked marijuana and drank excessively. Vincer is also said to have repeatedly made inappropriate sexual comments to Taylor, including asking whether she had “wild sex parties” or “orgies” in the house while she lived in it over the holiday season. The lawsuit claims she was eventually fired because Vincer said she gave off “bad vibes” and placed the Christmas tree in the wrong spot in the house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qKzf3n"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WR7mxr-g4Z9onCZJrWFDy2rVSFA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22651221/pcheung_210216_4414_0004.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Philip Cheung for &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The house sits in the hills of Los Angeles with a view of the city.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Qm2KyC"&gt;Vincer says the above incidents didn’t happen and that he fired Taylor because she deleted security footage from the home during her stay, and when he let her go, he alleges that she took control of the house’s connected thermostats and turned the heat up to “like 90 [degrees]” and started playing death metal music over speakers. “It really was like a horror movie,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pACkBf"&gt;One of Taylor’s lawyers, Nick Rosenthal, says he “doesn’t know anything” about the smart house allegations, but “even if everything that Mr. Vincer just said was true, none of that excuses sexually harassing your employees.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y4hKTt"&gt;One male employee also claims to have been the subject of abuse. Dylan Fussman, Vincer’s former assistant and a plaintiff, alleges that he was told to hire sex workers and purchase drugs, so Vincer wouldn’t carry the risk of doing it himself. Fussman would sleep at the house and allegedly was woken up one morning around 3 or 4AM and told to prepare lines of cocaine for clients. Vincer denies this happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JYxMyh"&gt;Another HiStudios employee, Mike Botticello, HiStudios’ head of content, allegedly physically abused Fussman and would “nut slap” him in front of other people. Botticello hasn’t replied to multiple &lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;requests to comment, but his lawyers responded to the complaint saying he denies “each and every allegation asserted in the complaint.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FZClVI"&gt;Strangely, Vincer corroborates this part of the lawsuit and says Fussman reported the “nut slapping” to him, causing Vincer to have to sit the two men down and talk about the situation and put a stop to it. Botticello’s lawyer declined to comment for this story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7lwulH"&gt;One of Fussman’s lawyers says this situation speaks to the “kind of environment” the plaintiffs worked in daily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GAfH9o"&gt;“Imagine at a normal company if an executive went up to an employee and slapped him in the genitals, and the CEO’s response was, ‘Let’s sit down and talk about it,’” the lawyer says. “Would that ever happen? No, he’d be fired immediately.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HFy7xI"&gt;Drennon Davis, another male employee, alleges Vincer offered to introduce him to a sex worker, but Davis turned the offer down, though he believed doing so could provoke retaliation. Vincer denies this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iMRQ1U"&gt;Meanwhile, Selah was fired prior to HiStudios’ public launch and the renting of the house. Selah says he began recording every conversation he had with Vincer and Himalaya CEO Wang before he was let go. About a year later, he says he took his old work laptop with all the recordings out during hunting season and “shot holes” in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yGylrd"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FY_XaPRV3l_pOYPdSBczynJHuhw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22650240/acastro_210609_4414_0003.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="umfsbt"&gt;When employees informed Himalaya of their experiences at the hype house, the company told Vincer to open an investigation with HiStudios’ own budget, Vincer says. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; attempted to reach the lawyer who conducted this investigation but received no response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N9e4OG"&gt;Vincer says he never saw the findings himself, as they were sent to Himalaya, but heard secondhand from two employees that the lawyer confirmed drug use in the house. Himalaya did not respond to multiple requests for comment on the lawsuit or investigation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OKnVhe"&gt;The whole situation ostensibly spooked Himalaya. In a rapid effort to get away from the mess that was HiStudios, Himalaya publicly &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/himalaya-media-announces-separation-from-spinoff-histudios-301018605.html"&gt;separated itself&lt;/a&gt; from the studio on March 5th, 2020, with seemingly no plan in place for what that might mean. Himalaya portrayed the split as a strategic move to “allow both businesses to grow,” in a press release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aJYtgP"&gt;Vincer also decided to give HiStudios a new name: Notorious&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gTfMoB"&gt;Himalaya’s intended clean break didn’t go as planned, however. The company wanted to keep HiStudios’ clients — it owned HiStudios, after all — but Vincer seemingly had other ideas. Once the companies separated, Vincer set Notorious up to essentially take over HiStudios’ roster of shows and creators, according to an email sent to creators by Wang and obtained by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. Per the email, Vincer allegedly locked the Himalaya and former HiStudios production team out of their emails, shared drive system, and Megaphone account, which hosted every podcast the team created and published. That gave Notorious nearly full control over the network. “This is not only illegal, but creates lots of difficulties to release new episodes for many shows,” the email from the CEO states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CrYtLH"&gt;The Notorious team also locked Himalaya’s accountant out of the shared drive that included documents she needed to pay creators, according to the email. At that point, Himalaya’s board began preparing a lawsuit to try to regain access to the emails and shared drive. (It seemingly never filed that lawsuit.) Both sides began reaching out to creators, per emails viewed by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, to win them over. Notorious emailed creators and declared its “full independence” from Himalaya, with a name that reflects the company’s “innovative spirit, culture, and dedication to delivering bold content.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JsNIvM"&gt;“The conversations I had were surreal, like, this is a bunch of suits and they’re talking to me like they’re arguing parents,” says one creator, who asked to remain anonymous because of their ongoing work with Notorious. “It really did feel like a divorce or something.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KMo8JJ"&gt;Vincer denies locking Himalaya’s team out of any accounts, although a source familiar with the situation, who has asked to remain anonymous over fears of retaliation, says Vincer instructed the HiStudios / Notorious team to change all the passwords. Because Vincer’s name was on the lease for the home, he stayed in the hype house and made it Notorious’ office, as well as his actual home. That’s when things got even messier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NnL02P"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ihSD27HbuXMZTcyuwsVWnnObgLk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22650241/acastro_210609_4414_0004.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="Wt3m8p"&gt;Following the Notorious transition, Steele says the house fell into disrepair. He and another member of his team say furniture was destroyed; dog poop sat on the floor inside the house; trash, including baby diapers, would linger in the driveway for weeks. Vincer, he says, would occasionally be passed out in the living room when podcast guests were coming over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mbX4oy"&gt;“[It went] from being a really pristine place to create that could have been something amazing, but it just got mismanaged to the point where it turned into a dump,” Steele says. “It turned into a personal haven for this middle-aged man to relive his childhood.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T9Jp7C"&gt;The source familiar with the split backs up these claims and says the state of the house got in the way of work. This person recalls a time when ice cream was smeared all over a screen the team used to give presentations, and Vincer, this person says, laughed when the team pointed it out instead of offering to get it cleaned up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xm05kz"&gt;At the same time, this person also says men in the house, including Vincer, would hang out without their shirts on, adding to the frat-like environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6NHr8f"&gt;“I had to walk up to a guy [Vincer] that I worked for to talk about something business-related, and he’s got no shirt on, and he’s got his gut hanging out, and he’s got a beer in his hand,” they say, adding that food also sat out for days, attracting flies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JqdWkl"&gt;This person also alleges the studio manager once had to hang up the phone after stepping in dog poop that sat in the studio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zsf79A"&gt;At this point, Vincer, his wife, three kids, four cats, and two dogs had moved into the home making it exactly that: a home. But the people who had been using the space as a workplace didn’t get the memo that this was now a place where a family lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="l5FdAu"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The hype house turned into a family home&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dlllzv"&gt;As Steele started spending more time with his team at the LA house during the spring and summer of 2020, he says things got less and less professional. For one, he says people in the house started out just smoking marijuana, which is legal in California, but later some moved on to doing lines of cocaine in the studios.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;He also says members of his team would get blamed for things in the house they didn’t do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mWetiK"&gt;“It was always assumed, like, let’s say all the liquor at the bar was drunk up, they assumed my guys were doing it,” he says. “I was just like, ‘My guys didn’t do that.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="byWN3p"&gt;He says his podcasters brought in their own drinks. “We got guys [on our podcasts] that are coming in with bottles of Clicquot and high-end stuff — Ace of Spades — they don’t even drink that crap that [the people at the house] drink.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ijtjG6"&gt;Vincer denies that the team would have been blamed for drinking all the booze. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NyDMGB"&gt;Bauer Feldman, who planned the cannabis event, started working on a podcast under an agreement with Steele, letting her record at the house. She says she enjoyed her time at the home until it started to unravel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X7JyDt"&gt;“I feel like I was in a smaller version of Studio 54,” she says, describing the vibe of the home. “It was exciting. It was creative. It was a whirlwind. But it was fake, none of it was real.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z2EBdM"&gt;Other people lived or crashed at the home last summer, including mostly young Instagram-famous people who seemingly have a lot of followers for no reason. These guests, Bauer Feldman says, would take over the house and leave drugs, like cocaine, lying around. She says Vincer attempted to keep the two worlds separate: one in which professionals used the house’s podcasting studios and another where twenty-somethings partied late into the night.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gyisHp6kQuOuigxv0vTCqOmZkCg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22650131/pcheung_210216_4414_0026.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Philip Cheung for &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Norm Steele alleges that Notorious still owes him and his team money.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="KuqSak"&gt;The source close to the situation also says that someone associated with an in-network podcaster moved into one of the studios and would leave dirty clothes out, particularly dirty socks, making the room smell terrible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rbywSd"&gt;Vincer confirms that other people lived in the home and stayed there, but he says there was no cocaine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vjWFgj"&gt;Still, a record request filed in Beverly Hills by &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;lists more than 40 calls to police about the home since Notorious took over, most of which relate to “disturbing the peace.” Nearly all of them came in during the COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GjSlNR"&gt;“[There were] young girls coming over and doing cocaine and drinking at this mansion in 90210 with what they thought were all these stars and famous people and Peter,” Bauer Feldman says. “And Peter’s like running the whole thing, and Peter tells everyone, ‘Oh, it’s my house.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8dwRXZ"&gt;Bauer Feldman also says women she believed to be sex workers would come over to the house and take men into one of the bedrooms. Steele corroborates this, too, saying women “pushed up on” a few of his team members. Vincer says there were “absolutely not” sex workers in the house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U0EiD8"&gt;Coupled with the “creep vibes” Bauer Feldman got from Vincer, she decided to step away from the home. “As a woman, that bothered me, and then also being a mother myself, and watching him with his wife there and his kids, and just get completely trashed in front of them and black out and act like an idiot. It was heartbreaking,” she says. Bauer Feldman cut ties with Notorious in July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BkdBC2"&gt;Even the creators who didn’t work with Vincer in LA, and in most cases haven’t even met him, say the company became a mess following the split with Himalaya. These collaborators say the company fell behind on payments or didn’t pay out at all. Five creators, including Steele, tell &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; they were owed money for their Notorious work. One podcaster says they were owed as much as $74,000 and that Notorious ended up paying them out once they got a lawyer involved. Notorious told this podcaster its ad buying company was to blame for the four-month delay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="HjEMFb"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Multiple creators say the Notorious team was late to pay or didn’t at all&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="E0NqIq"&gt;Meanwhile, &lt;em&gt;Crimelines &lt;/em&gt;host Worroll says she sent her bill to collections and hasn’t received any money. Steele says his team is owed $25,000 in back pay for advertisements they read for brands like Manscaped. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q76D5M"&gt;The anonymous source says Vincer also reduced each Notorious team member’s annual pay and was sometimes late issuing the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3bQ38Y"&gt;Vincer says Notorious struggled financially. “So yeah, I took a little longer to pay early partners than I probably should have or wanted to,” he says. But he isn’t aware of any current or former partners to whom he owes money, other than Steele who won’t “get a dime” from him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9zL3Ij"&gt;One of the final straws for Steele, and what pushed him to leave Notorious, was seeing what he believed to be a large amount of marijuanna delivered to the house, which he viewed as an indication that Vincer and Notorious were bringing in cash but weren’t paying him or his team. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cvDrQ6"&gt;“The dude [Vincer] was trying to give me weed, and it’s like, ‘Dude, I don’t give a fuck about weed,’” Steele says. “I don’t even smoke weed, what am I gonna do with that?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sILXyW"&gt;Eventually, Steele says he had to cut ties surreptitiously. “It’s almost like an abusive relationship, you kind of sneak out the house when your spouse is gone,” he says. “I went in and I made sure I took every last show that we had off the hosting platform. I snuck everybody off of there and snuck them back onto another platform.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w9QeXW"&gt;The team then stopped going to the house, and Steele changed his phone number, hoping to never hear from Vincer again. His podcast network ultimately &lt;a href="https://westcoaststyles.com/news/2020/09/charlamagne-the-god-the-gangster-chronicles-sign-huge-iheart-media-deal/"&gt;signed a deal&lt;/a&gt; with iHeartMedia and Charlamagne Tha God’s Black Effect Podcast Network, where the show is now produced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lKGExz"&gt;Vincer denies ever bringing in a large amount of weed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SomPbr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5exERu9SaVcuGweVMXRjWL-ZBVo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22650242/acastro_210609_4414_0005.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="xkP1ou"&gt;Since this entire saga began last year, Himalaya has mostly exited the podcasting business, apart from one show. It now focuses on subscription-based “audio courses,” or educational audio content offered by reputable names, similar to MasterClass. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uus4UM"&gt;Meanwhile, Vincer’s hype house continued to host parties throughout the summer and fall of 2020, and the Notorious Instagram account makes it look like a party place for TikTokers and hype beasts, with partygoers playing beer pong, people getting pushed into the backyard pool, and weed being smoked in the studios. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UQCLZG"&gt;Vincer tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; the company makes “a handful” of shows now but is mostly focused on marketing and making content for brands. It’s hard to tell how much content or money the company is making, although Vincer says it’s “self-sustaining.” Some shows on the brand’s various Apple Podcasts pages haven’t published a new episode in over a year, while a few do appear to be in active production. One of the network’s biggest releases, &lt;em&gt;Dumpster Fyre&lt;/em&gt;, which Fyre Festival founder Billy McFarland hosted from prison, ended after McFarland was put in solitary confinement for hosting it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gtLnlP"&gt;Vincer says his current 30-person team, most of whom are 20-something-year-olds, are more interested in video and broad creative work than solely looking to podcasts as a business. He says they make music videos and have a five-person sales team that helps sell various things for brands. Notorious is the exclusive sales partner of the Summer Smash music festival in Chicago this summer, for example, and he says podcast ads represent 40 to 50 percent of the company’s revenue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ufRkaM"&gt;The team has also listed a variety of jobs, mostly for junior positions or interns. A junior sales agent listing asks applicants to send in a video saying why they’re a good fit for the role and answering the question, “If you were an item in a gas station, what would you be?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RwZUgX"&gt;The post also advertises four benefits: “Only non-store in the US equipped with a fully-stocked Yerba Mate fridge; relaxed environment; pool on-site; and lunch provided.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="F3a8kR"&gt;&lt;q&gt;If you were an item in a gas station, what would you be?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1DE0u3"&gt;One big thing has changed in the months since the split-up. In February this year, the Notorious team moved into a new hype house, one that’s more like a compound than the Beverly Hills home. The home, according to its online listing, sits on 10 acres of land and features seven bedrooms. Vincer says it has a living room with “big TVs,” a dartboard, an editing room, and hiking trails that “go over an hour.” “It’s more of an events space,” he says, and they’ve hosted parties, like one for rapper 24kGoldn, and shot music videos for people like Tom Hanks’ son Chet Hanks. The Instagram account calls the house the “Notorious estate,” and Vincer says “three or four” of his “most consistent contributors” stay at the home full time with a woman, referred to as the “house mom,” on hand to clean and cook during the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PSFwIA"&gt;The beer pong and partying also continues, except this time with a bigger backyard that’s adorned with Greek statues and an interior that looks like an attempt at a French chateau vibe with sconces and ornate tapestries. Influencers post photos from the house, and drone footage shows off tanned guys with six packs hanging by the pool. Nothing seems different, apart from a bigger place to hang and make content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h76bgd"&gt;“We don’t turn up that much because we don’t really have that much time to do that, but I couldn’t tell you how pleased I’ve been since I founded Notorious with how well my team, and especially the team that I have now, has been able to manage a unique work environment,” Vincer says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wcPvR9"&gt;But on March 23rd, March 27th, and April 1st of this year, police visited the property because of a “disturbance,” according to an eviction notice filed in a Los Angeles court. And Vincer’s new neighbors continue to complain about “loud noise and traffic in the middle of the night,” the document says. Vincer’s new landlord gave him and the other people living in the house three days to vacate the premises, but because they haven’t, the landlord has since filed a civil case against Vincer asking for him to leave the property for good and pay damages of over $1,900 per day while he and his team continue living in the home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="mYLt6G"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Vincer’s newest house faces its own problems&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="A8TxQX"&gt;Vincer says he moved into the house thinking that he could host events there, not knowing the landlord and neighbors had a “longstanding feud,” which he says prompted the “aggressive actions.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ItEy50"&gt;At the same time, Vincer’s old landlord, from the HiStudios hype house, also filed a lawsuit against him for owed money, alleging he failed to pay for rent and damages to the property. The landlord alleges Vincer owes $71,967 in rent from May 2020 until he left the property in March 2021 and that damages to the home total up to $83,741.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8uc60L"&gt;Vincer says this is “being negotiated right now,” but that he only didn’t pay the last month’s rent because he wanted “negotiating leverage.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OIdqEB"&gt;For Steele and everyone else who’s been left in Notorious’ wake, they can’t help but simultaneously marvel and speculate about this new place that, from social media, looks like a hopping spot that’s carefree and fun. Multiple people have called or texted me to point it out, seemingly suggesting that for all that’s gone down between Vincer, HiStudios, Notorious, and Himalaya, the party still goes on. At least, per what they see on Instagram. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gq7CxZ"&gt;But behind the doors, Vincer faces three separate lawsuits and collaborators demanding to get paid. He might have changed venues, but business — however he defines it in his universe — goes on as usual. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="8OryXw"&gt;“I have nothing bad to say about Himalaya,” Steele says. “But that Notorious stuff, that’s the right name for it: Notorious.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22526502/himalaya-histudios-notorious-llc-podcast-audio-hype-house"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22526502/himalaya-histudios-notorious-llc-podcast-audio-hype-house</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-11T06:01:27-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T06:01:27-04:00</updated>
    <title>Elon Musk demos Cyberpunk 2077 on new Tesla infotainment system with ‘PS5-level performance’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/csMQtv3bmEp0pLecqSiFsaA5H7w=/47x0:554x338/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69438425/ezgif.com_gif_maker__1_.0.gif" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9fuyjF"&gt;Elon Musk teased that Tesla’s new Model S Plaid would be capable of running &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253258/tesla-model-s-ps5-xbox-series-x-next-gen-10-teraflop"&gt;earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;, and he’s now demonstrated the car’s “PS5-level performance.” The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22528963/tesla-model-s-plaid-ev-price-specs-range-speed"&gt;refreshed Model S&lt;/a&gt; includes a new Tesla infotainment system, powered by AMD’s Ryzen processor and a discrete AMD RDNA 2 GPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dp6EmB"&gt;“There’s never been a car that has state of the art computing technology, state of the art infotainment where this is literally at the level of a PlayStation 5,” said Tesla CEO Elon Musk during a demo event last night. “This is actual PlayStation 5-level performance… yes it can run Cyberpunk. It’s high frame rate, it will do 60fps with state of the art games.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="69lohi"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kUmkbzQ-BS0?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=1402&amp;amp;start=1402" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sge1cB"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22462660/amd-tesla-model-x-s-plaid-ryzen-radeon-rdna-2"&gt;AMD revealed last week&lt;/a&gt; that it’s powering this new infotainment system in both the new Model S and Model X, with 10 teraflops of compute power. That in itself is nearly identical to the 10.28 teraflops found on Sony’s PlayStation 5, although Tesla’s total compute includes both the integrated and discrete GPUs so it won’t be a full 10 teraflops for gaming alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mQIlk8"&gt;We only saw a brief demo of &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; running at high frame rates on the $130,000 Model S Plaid during Tesla’s event, alongside a closer look at the updated UI on the infotainment system. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7VNAQYotzytFK6UNjulBhOXdmwk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22652309/56vDKTW.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Paul Spivak (&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/user/skpl/" target="_blank"&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Tesla-branded controller.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="UlEpZm"&gt;In separate demonstrations after the event, some Tesla fans were able to get pictures of what appears to be a Tesla-branded game controller. It’s not clear if the controller, which mimics the shape of the car’s steering wheel, is a dummy unit or not. It appears alongside an Xbox controller in a photo published by &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/elonmusk/comments/nx7ccw/cyberpunk_2077_running_on_the_model_s_plaid/"&gt;Reddit users&lt;/a&gt; (above), and videos seem to show the Xbox controller being used to play Cyberpunk 2077.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ORNRf5"&gt;You might be wondering why you’d need PS5-level gaming performance in your car, which the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331315/elon-musk-tesla-technoking-title-ceo"&gt;Technoking&lt;/a&gt; is happy to answer. “If you think about the future of where the car is often in autopilot or full self-driving mode, then entertainment is going to become increasing important,” said Musk. Until that’s a reality, we’re hoping to see the folks at &lt;em&gt;Digital Foundry&lt;/em&gt; benchmark a car running the latest AAA games against powerful PCs, the PS5, and the Xbox Series X.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22529210/tesla-model-s-plaid-cyberpunk-demo-ps5-performance"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22529210/tesla-model-s-plaid-cyberpunk-demo-ps5-performance</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-11T05:42:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T05:42:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>The red PS5 controller is a different red to the red Xbox Series X controller</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZqL86okr8EMhPXuMmqHVBAPeIsQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69438344/DSCF7709.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="S4I2TZ"&gt;While the PS5’s divisive two-tone design has led some to swap out large pieces of plastic for a more unified look, this month did at least see Sony release some &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/13/22433966/sony-black-red-dualsense-controllers-playstation-5-ps5"&gt;official new color options&lt;/a&gt; for the excellent DualSense controller. There are now “cosmic red” and “midnight black” models that might appeal to you more than the black and white default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BuG4t5"&gt;The black controller doesn’t seem all that interesting, but as a fan of red objects I ordered the red one in to see how it looks in person. The color is actually quite unusual — Sony’s marketing info places the controller in front of a bright red nebula, in keeping with the “cosmic red” name, and it’s a pretty good match. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="geLs7i"&gt;Basically, it’s a little pinker than you might expect, falling somewhere between crimson, ruby, and raspberry. I think it looks good with the black trim and manages to feel appropriate for the PS5’s aesthetic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D6nkqh"&gt;And yes, the tiny PlayStation symbols microtexture is back, though it’s still pretty much impossible to see with the naked eye:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/F2QWKjpISx1Wjn5fBwP0DUWtvnM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22652298/IMG20210611164840.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A close-up of the new PS5 controller’s microtexture.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="K0u2eI"&gt;Sony is quite slow to release its first PS5 controller color variations. Microsoft had black, white, and blue options available at the launch of the Xbox Series X and Series S, and soon followed up with red, yellow, and camo options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EM1dRK"&gt;I have the red Series X controller too, and it’s a much more straightforward, primary-color shade than the PS5. The difference is clear when they’re next to each other. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oQVtruKBOj--ZMrveuNpVcsCLys=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22652295/DSCF7709.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The red PS5 controller next to its Xbox Series equivalent.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ppi3gH"&gt;The red and black PS5 controllers are out this week in Japan and should be available next week in North America, though like the PS5 itself it’ll probably be difficult to find stock. The black version costs $69.99, while the red version is for some inexplicable reason $5 more expensive at $74.99.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22529221/cosmic-red-ps5-controller-hands-on-series-x"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22529221/cosmic-red-ps5-controller-hands-on-series-x</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-11T04:34:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T04:34:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Cyberpunk 2077 developer says its hacked data is circulating online </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Cyberpunk 2077" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/B4POanqtWdnI9ZaoYb2jqClQUvQ=/63x0:738x450/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69438271/cyberpunk_2077_800.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: CD Projekt Red&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iwJqMy"&gt;Hacked data stolen from CD Projekt is circulating online, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CDPROJEKTRED/status/1403059158065295361"&gt;the company says&lt;/a&gt;. The studio behind &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Witcher 3&lt;/em&gt; says it can not confirm the exact contents of the data being circulated, but believes it relates to its games, contractors, and both current and former employees. It also warned that the data may have been manipulated or tampered with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ErOFdx"&gt;The disclosure comes four months after the studio first announced that it had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274035/cd-projekt-hack-source-code-cyberpunk-2077-witcher-3-encrypt-data-ransom"&gt;fallen victim to a ransomware attack&lt;/a&gt;. It initially said hackers had managed to access “certain data” from the company. CD Projekt posted the ransom note it received in which the hackers claimed to have access to source code from its games including &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Witcher 3&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Gwent&lt;/em&gt;. The note also said the hacked data included details relating to its HR, accounting, and other internal operations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0szLFs"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;IMPORTANT UPDATE&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Read more: &lt;a href="https://t.co/qd6sc5VF3I"&gt;https://t.co/qd6sc5VF3I&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/kKi1GkIaLO"&gt;pic.twitter.com/kKi1GkIaLO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— CD PROJEKT RED (@CDPROJEKTRED) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CDPROJEKTRED/status/1403059158065295361?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 10, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1hWTb9"&gt;The company said it would not give in to the hackers’ demands, and days later the attackers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278121/cd-projekt-red-ransomware-hack-cyberpunk-2077-the-witcher-3-auction-sale"&gt;claimed to have sold the data&lt;/a&gt; online. However the nature of the sale, in which the hackers claimed to have found a buyer outside of a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276664/cyberpunk-witcher-hackers-auction-source-code-ransomware-attack"&gt;hacking forum auction&lt;/a&gt;, raised questions about whether they were able to find a buyer at all. Writing in a &lt;a href="https://blog.emsisoft.com/en/37783/hellokitty-ransomware-group-likely-responsible-for-cd-projekt-attack-heres-why/#:~:text=There%20is,sold%20it"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, Emsisoft threat analyst Brett Callow said he thought it was “likely” that the hackers were just claiming to have found a buyer to “save face” after having failed to monetize the hack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jdkMkD"&gt;CD Projekt has &lt;a href="https://www.cdprojekt.com/en/media/news/information-regarding-data-security/"&gt;previously admitted&lt;/a&gt; that hackers were able to encrypt some of its employee data on its network. But the company said its investigation had found no evidence that the data had been transferred out of the company’s systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GF9w5K"&gt;The hack followed the troubled launch of the studio’s latest blockbuster title, &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;. Although it &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2020/12/11/22170468/cyberpunk-2077-sales-revenue-cd-projekt"&gt;sold well&lt;/a&gt; and was initially well-received by critics, players quickly discovered that the game was riddled with bugs, and almost unplayable on older consoles. The situation was so bad that the game was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22188007/sony-cyberpunk-2077-removed-playstation-store-full-refunds-policy"&gt;pulled from the PlayStation Store&lt;/a&gt;. As of this writing, it is &lt;a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-my/concept/234567"&gt;yet to return&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hukrxM"&gt;CD Projekt says it’s continuing to work with law enforcement and outside experts as it responds to the hack, and said it is “committed and prepared” to take action against anyone sharing the stolen data.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22529199/cyberpunk-hack-data-leaked-online-employee-game-data"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22529199/cyberpunk-hack-data-leaked-online-employee-game-data</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-11T01:05:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T01:05:29-04:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla delivers the first 25 Model S Plaid sedans</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tOByZZhkKDdhrCf6BX62Yj4rXQk=/451x72:2692x1566/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69437984/Screen_Shot_2021_06_10_at_10.47.28_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DxmNkb"&gt;A lucky 25 customers received Tesla’s redesigned Model S “Plaid” at an event hosted by CEO Elon Musk in Fremont, California on Thursday night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ZrJDH"&gt;The Silicon Valley automaker has billed this new $130,000 version of the Model S — first &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22252832/tesla-model-s-redesign-plaid-mile-range-interior-refresh"&gt;announced in January&lt;/a&gt; and originally slated to ship in March — as the “quickest production vehicle ever made,” with the ability to go from 0-60mph in under 2 seconds. Its name is a reference to the unthinkable speed beyond “Ludicrous” in the comedy classic &lt;em&gt;Spaceballs&lt;/em&gt;. It’s also expected to get around 390 miles of range. (Tesla is selling a less powerful version of the redesigned Model S with more range — 412 miles — that starts at just a hair under $80,000. Deliveries of those start later this year.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MyejPR"&gt;Why so fast?  “We’ve got to show that an electric car is the best car, hands down,” Musk said at Thursday night’s event. “It’s got to be clear [that] sustainable energy cars can be the fastest cars, the safest cars, [and] can be the most kick-ass cars in every way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wX59Ym"&gt;“This car crushes,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="5V1UGU"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We’ve got to show that an electric car is the best car, hands down.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="m9Vp9t"&gt;On June 6, Musk announced Tesla had canceled the most expensive version of the new Model S, which was called Plaid Plus. That version, which had a starting price of around $150,000, was supposed to go 520 miles on a full battery. It was also supposed to be powered by the new 4680 lithium-ion battery cells &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/6/22521769/elon-musk-tweets-tesla-plaid-plus-canceled"&gt;that Tesla is developing&lt;/a&gt;. A redesigned Model X was also announced in January, but deliveries of that new SUV have been pushed back months, and Musk didn’t mention the updated SUV Thursday night.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hShn2AyQriLR8iArroyFYXNP6JU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22652103/Screen_Shot_2021_06_10_at_8.51.33_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="nYTayf"&gt;Musk once shot down rumors of a Model S and Model X redesign in 2019, &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/08/tesla-will-not-refresh-its-model-s-or-model-x-electric-vehicles/"&gt;saying&lt;/a&gt; there was “no ‘refreshed’ Model X or Model S coming.” Instead, Musk said Tesla was always making minor improvements to both vehicles. But sales of both vehicles have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/26/22404198/tesla-q1-results-earnings-profit-model-s-x-y-3-bitcoin-delay"&gt;stagnated in recent years&lt;/a&gt; as Tesla focused on the more affordable Model 3 sedan and Model Y compact SUV. The redesigned versions are a chance to boost sales of these older cars. The company seems confident enough in the new Model S Plaid that it &lt;a href="https://electrek.co/2021/06/10/tesla-increases-model-s-plaid-price/"&gt;raised the starting price by $10,000 earlier today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aBuf3o"&gt;Musk got deep into the weeds about Tesla’s “practically alien” engineering, but he was also light on details about execution. Musk said that Tesla plans to deliver “several hundred [Model S Plaids] per week soon,” and will “probably” ramp up to around 1,000 per week next quarter. But he made almost no mention of the Model X Plaid, the dual-motor “long range” Model S, and he didn’t expand on his reasoning for canceling the 520-mile Plaid Plus. Earlier this week, he simply &lt;a href="https://electrek.co/2021/06/06/elon-musk-tesla-canceling-model-s-plaid-need-400-mile-range/"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Electrek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;that “more range doesn’t really matter.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7WNLtD"&gt;“There are essentially zero trips above 400 miles where the driver doesn’t need to stop for restroom, food, coffee, etc. anyway,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5u6MRHZMTBUZHbumrJ5KP6Z-DXc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22652101/Screen_Shot_2021_06_10_at_11.52.10_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="AuJc59"&gt;The new Model S is the first major overhaul for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22252832/tesla-model-s-redesign-plaid-mile-range-interior-refresh"&gt;sedan since it launched in 2012&lt;/a&gt; and set Tesla on its path to its current status as the world’s top electric vehicle company. The exterior design is largely unchanged (though it has a super low drag coefficient of 0.208) and the interior has received a big facelift. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="mb1s7n"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s the first major overhaul for the electric sedan, which launched in 2012&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yQ5EYQ"&gt;The Model S now has a horizontal touchscreen like the one found in the Model 3 and Model Y, but with a bigger 17-inch version with smaller bezels. Unlike the Model 3 and Model Y, there’s a digital instrument cluster behind the steering wheel. A third screen is found behind the center console for rear passengers. Tesla showed off a new UI for the screens on Thursday night, which features drag-and-drop elements and other refinements. Musk even capitulated to shouts from the crowd of fans at one point and agreed to finally add &lt;a href="https://www.teslarati.com/tesla-navigation-waypoints-spotted-elon-musk/"&gt;a waypoint feature to Tesla’s navigation system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3ES2xT"&gt;There are other upgrades, too, such as more room for rear passengers, as well as rear-seat wireless phone chargers. “The current Model S, the backseat is not amazing. But the new one — it’s actually a legit backseat,” Musk said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BWprv0"&gt;The Model S Plaid has extremely powerful processing that can run AAA games on the car’s screens at 60 frames per second, in addition to powering all of the other services Tesla allows, such as Netflix, Spotify. “Really, it’s like a home theater experience,” Musk said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4PM4nR"&gt;Tesla has also changed a lot under the proverbial hood. The Model S Plaid is powered by a new tri-motor drivetrain that Tesla originally started developing for the forthcoming second-generation Roadster. (The company tested the Plaid powertrain in a Model S sedan at famous racetracks: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/12/20862105/tesla-model-s-plaid-laguna-seca-nurburgring-porsche-taycan"&gt;Laguna Seca and the Nurburgring&lt;/a&gt;.) Those three motors collectively put down around 1,000 horsepower, and the car can reach a top speed of 200 miles per hour — though only when outfitted certain wheels and tires &lt;a href="https://electrek.co/2021/06/10/tesla-warns-new-model-s-plaid-advertised-200-mph-tire-wheel-upgrade/"&gt;that won’t be available until later this year&lt;/a&gt;. “It hits you right in the limbic system,” Musk said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="imnpcg"&gt;Earlier Model S sedans weren’t exactly slow, but the new one will be more capable of repeating that performance thanks to some new tech Tesla developed. The company has been working on new heat pumps starting with the Model Y, and in the Model S Plaid Tesla says the pump improves cold-weather range by 30 percent and reduces the energy consumption of running the HVAC system by 50 percent. The radiator is also much bigger in order to help cool the battery pack during demanding drives. Tesla even developed new carbon-wrapped rotors in the electric motors that power the Plaid system in order to keep them from breaking apart at high RPM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="esFten"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Similar exterior, but a radical new interior&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="I7PX53"&gt;Repeating high performance runs was a tricky prospect in older Model S sedans, so much so that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/10/20799221/porsche-taycan-fully-charged-mission-e-electric-car"&gt;Porsche made sure to market the Taycan’s ability&lt;/a&gt; to make lots of fast runs without losing performance when that EV launched. All of those changes should help Tesla  answer Porsche. Musk claims the new Model S will be safer than most other cars on the road based on Tesla’s internal data. The car has not yet been tested by safety regulators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tOwbLP"&gt;One possible hiccup in safety: the striking, U-shaped “yoke” steering wheel. It &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/roadshow/news/tesla-model-s-yoke-steering-wheel-regulations-nhtsa/"&gt;was reportedly a surprise to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration&lt;/a&gt;. When Musk was asked by Joe Rogan &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278792/elon-musk-joe-rogan-tesla-roadster-spacex-hover-thrusters"&gt;in February&lt;/a&gt; whether he thought the new steering wheel was legal, the CEO said “they use a yoke in Formula One.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ApqppD"&gt;“Yeah, but you’re not on the highway in a Formula One car,” Rogan responded. Musk answered that he believed Tesla’s Autopilot driver assistance system “is getting good enough that you won’t need to drive most of the time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6ja4im"&gt;Tesla not only changed up the steering wheel design, but it also got rid of all of the stalks on the steering column. There will be an option on the touchscreen to select drive modes, but Tesla sees that as a backup. Instead, the car will &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/29/22256504/teslas-model-s-x-redesign-automatic-shifting-prnd-gears"&gt;default to automatically shifting between park, reverse, and drive&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9E3osX"&gt;“I think, generally, all input is error,” Musk said Thursday night. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22528963/tesla-model-s-plaid-ev-price-specs-range-speed"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22528963/tesla-model-s-plaid-ev-price-specs-range-speed</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-10T21:06:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-10T21:06:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>Frontier Communications is getting sued by record labels for not disconnecting pirates</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-zu0Rw5dBUp_wW1wpnmc509MjdY=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69437241/VRG_ILLO_4341_American_Ethernet.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Grayson Blackmon / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4BqURN"&gt;Frontier Communications, an ISP that serves around 3 million subscribers, has been sued by Warner, Sony, and Universal’s record labels for allegedly not taking action against its users who pirate music (&lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/06/record-labels-sue-another-isp-demanding-mass-disconnections-of-internet-users/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vFUBGQ"&gt;The record labels &lt;a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.nysd.561609/gov.uscourts.nysd.561609.1.0.pdf"&gt;allege in their complaint&lt;/a&gt; (PDF) that not only did Frontier fail to disconnect people who repeatedly pirated, but it even encouraged them by advertising the ability to “download 10 songs in 3.5 seconds” and profited from the result. The labels also allege that Frontier ignored its subscribers’ piracy so it could keep collecting subscription fees, saying that the ISP valued profit over legal responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bSzyeQ"&gt;Frontier denies wrongdoing, telling &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that it has terminated customers when copyright holders complain. The ISP plans to “vigorously defend itself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nfKlMH"&gt;The suit, which was filed in the state of New York, seeks damages from Frontier for its subscribers who have infringed on almost 3,000 copyrighted works after the ISP was repeatedly told about their infringement. &lt;a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.nysd.561609/gov.uscourts.nysd.561609.1.1.pdf"&gt;A list of pirated songs&lt;/a&gt; (PDF) includes &lt;em&gt;Thank U, Next&lt;/em&gt; by Ariana Grande, &lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;(no relation to this publication) by Owl City, and &lt;em&gt;Rich as Fuck&lt;/em&gt; by Lil Wayne featuring 2 Chainz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M8kOko"&gt;The labels are seeking $300,000 per infringement, which would put the ISP on the hook for over $850 million. It’s worth noting that Frontier Communications &lt;a href="https://www.nhregister.com/business/article/As-it-emerges-from-bankruptcy-Frontier-16142938.php"&gt;emerged from chapter 11 bankruptcy&lt;/a&gt; last month — having to pay that much in damages wouldn’t be good for any company, but especially not one that’s just getting out of that situation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="f1lXJf"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s hard to foresee suing ISPs working to stopping music piracy&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LsMHZt"&gt;Warner, Sony, and Universal have also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/26/18282679/riaa-sony-universal-umg-lawsuit-charter-music-piracy-high-speed-internet"&gt;sued other ISPs like Charter&lt;/a&gt; and Cox on similar grounds, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/19/21030812/cox-communications-record-labels-lawsuit-appeal-1-billion-piracy-isp-charter"&gt;winning a $1 billion award&lt;/a&gt; from the latter (though that case is &lt;a href="https://www.law360.com/cases/5b622655a811114362b330b2/articles"&gt;still going through the appeals process&lt;/a&gt;). And over the past 20 years, the music industry has tried different approaches to curb online piracy, from &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/SB122966038836021137"&gt;suing individuals&lt;/a&gt; to working with ISPs to set up &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/2/25/4026194/infamous-six-strike-anti-piracy-program-barks-harder-than-it-bites"&gt;a strike system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N73VaS"&gt;The approaches haven’t been particularly effective and have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/1/30/14445596/six-strikes-piracy-system-failed-ending"&gt;largely been abandoned&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s hard to foresee the tactic of suing ISPs working to stop music piracy. And, &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/06/record-labels-sue-another-isp-demanding-mass-disconnections-of-internet-users/?comments=1"&gt;as &lt;em&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/em&gt; points out&lt;/a&gt;, ISPs being forced to cut off pirates could affect other people living with them as well, denying entire households access to a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22177154/us-internet-speed-maps-competition-availability-fcc"&gt;fundamental part of modern day life.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22528633/frontier-isp-lawsuit-record-labels-piracy-disconnection"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22528633/frontier-isp-lawsuit-record-labels-piracy-disconnection</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-10T20:49:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-10T20:49:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Trump administration forced Apple to secretly reveal at least two Democrats’ data</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WSVa_cXg4VFv_3-L4qCAJ-jDyNw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69437174/acastro_180130_1777_0005.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fXiNUu"&gt;By now, you may have heard that Trump’s Department of Justice &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/02/us/trump-administration-phone-records-times-reporters.html"&gt;secretly seized the phone records&lt;/a&gt; of journalists working for &lt;em&gt;The New York Time&lt;/em&gt;s, &lt;em&gt;CNN&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;, in the hopes of revealing their sources and stopping leaks to the press. But &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/10/us/politics/justice-department-leaks-trump-administration.html?referringSource=articleShare"&gt;the &lt;em&gt;NYT &lt;/em&gt;is now reporting&lt;/a&gt; that Trump didn’t stop at journalists — in 2017 and 2018, it forced Apple to cough up metadata on at least two Democratic members of the House Intelligence Committee, including &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RepAdamSchiff/status/1403151148786278403"&gt;current chairman Adam Schiff&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2021/06/10/politics/house-intelligence-committee-apple-data-trump-justice-department-doj/index.html"&gt;representative Eric Swalwell&lt;/a&gt;, and as many as a dozen people tied to that committee in total, including family members and at least one child. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2dDle2"&gt;Like the media outlets, Apple was under a gag order and unable to tell anyone until it expired this year — the only reason we’re learning about this now is because the new administration’s Justice Department decided to reveal the subpoenas and gag orders to the press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="L9gNMV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Metadata is powerful&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8SasHu"&gt;While one of the &lt;em&gt;NYT’s&lt;/em&gt; sources insist that Apple only provided metadata, not photos or the contents of emails, it’s been well-established for years that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/5/16/4336994/metadata-matters-how-phone-records-and-obsolete-laws-harm-privacy"&gt;metadata is data&lt;/a&gt;: you can learn a lot if you know where, when, and who a given person is talking to, particularly if you combine that with other insights. (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/19/21029992/smartphone-location-tracking-legal-technology-privacy-new-york-times"&gt;An earlier &lt;em&gt;NYT&lt;/em&gt; investigation&lt;/a&gt; showed that the amount of location data smartphones already reveal to data brokers is enough to identify someone personally.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n0XgPq"&gt;Apple didn’t immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wO9lQi"&gt;Last Saturday, the Justice Department &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/06/05/1003616525/doj-says-it-will-no-longer-seize-reporters-records-in-investigating-leaks"&gt;promised it would no longer secretly subpeona records from journalists&lt;/a&gt; to root out leaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FSZO70"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, June 10th, 11PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added confirmation that Swalwell was part of the probe.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22528853/trump-force-apple-democrat-house-intelligence-committee-data"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22528853/trump-force-apple-democrat-house-intelligence-committee-data</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-10T19:44:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-10T19:44:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>Here are the best Kindle deals right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VfQnBwLbLIeiZEVOPMuNUumuNok=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67715739/akrales_190723_3560_0016.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MyfWR7"&gt;When it comes to finding a device to use to read your ebooks, you have a few options to choose from. You can always buy a tablet or use your smartphone, but those devices are multipurpose and can be used for a ton of things, like surfing the web or doom-scrolling on Twitter. If you are looking for something to strictly read books, e-readers, while niche, are designed to store all of your books in a virtual library with limited functionality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pDKHVT"&gt;Amazon, having helped pioneer the e-reader, has dominated the space for years with its Kindle lineup, which consists of three unique models with their own pros and cons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JRHBaM"&gt;Below, we’ve listed each model currently available for purchase. Sometimes, there isn’t a deal for one, or any, of the products. In those instances, we’ve mentioned the most recent sale price so you know what a good Kindle deal looks like when you see one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KyFx7Z"&gt;Thankfully, there’s often a promotion going on, which will almost certainly be the case when &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22459166/amazon-prime-day-dates-2021-june-21-22"&gt;Amazon Prime Day arrives&lt;/a&gt; on June 21st. Until then, these are the best Kindle deals available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="LiuVH6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best iPad deals right now ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21280354/best-ipad-deals-apple"},{"title":"Here are the best Amazon Echo deals right now ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21546591/best-amazon-echo-deals"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="jqPttv"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/4/10/18302177/amazon-kindle-base-model-low-resolution-screen-backlight-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kindle (10th Generation)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="mXAcFi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10363966"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Hfprjz"&gt;This is Amazon’s most affordable e-reader, and as such, it usually retails for $90. Released in 2019, the base Kindle includes a front light, 8GB of storage, and comes with or without ad support. Despite including the same 167ppi resolution as its predecessors, this model has a slightly higher contrast than earlier models. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pIAlEv"&gt;Right now, you can buy &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07978J597?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a 10th-gen Kindle with lockscreen ads&lt;/a&gt; for $90, which is the usual price. If you want &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B085VZV5VB?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=1ccac7c6dd4bb605e9b24952e83a00de&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;one without ads&lt;/a&gt;, you can grab it for $110. If you buy either Kindle model, you’ll also receive three months of Kindle Unlimited at no additional cost. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XTnhuW"&gt;If you want to save some money on additional accessories for the e-reader, Amazon’s &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Essentials-including-Amazon-Printed-Adapter/dp/B08C6NDPFM?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kindle Essentials Bundle&lt;/a&gt; is $120 ($15 off its usual price); it includes one of three printed covers and a power adapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="RkX3DN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9552432"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ze80m8"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/10/7/20902588/kindle-kids-edition-amazon-bundle-young-e-reader-case-replacement-program-freetime"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kindle Kids Edition (2019)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="JypT34"&gt;The entry-level Kindle and Oasis models were not the only ones that received a refresh in 2019. Amazon also announced and released a Kindle Kids Edition Bundle, which provides age-appropriate content for younger readers who prefer digital books for $110 ($20 more than the base Kindle). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6LlYfl"&gt;The Kindle Kids Edition consists of five items: the device, a case, a two-year extended replacement guarantee (in the event the device breaks), and one year of Amazon’s FreeTime Unlimited service. The latter is the biggest selling point of the device aside from the kid-friendly patterns, as it allows parents to grant their kids access to a digital library of kid-friendly books like &lt;em&gt;Percy Jackson&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Hobbit &lt;/em&gt;at no additional cost. Right now, you can &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07NMY72SC?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;grab one for $110&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N7AYlh"&gt;Amazon is also currently offering the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/All-new-Essentials-including-Protector-Adapter/dp/B07XW24MVK?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Kindle Kids Edition Essentials Bundle for $128&lt;/a&gt;, which includes all of the things mentioned above, plus a screen protector and power adapter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3DEvBp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9552664"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="t6m9om"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/7/18065960/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-2018-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kindle Paperwhite (Fourth Generation)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="P1C5xu"&gt;The fourth-gen Kindle Paperwhite, released in 2018, starts at $130 and comes in three different configurations: an 8GB Wi-Fi model, a 32GB Wi-Fi model, and a second 32GB model that drops the ads from the lock screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qneu65"&gt;The Paperwhite features a six-inch, pin-sharp backlit display, which is the main reason to get the Paperwhite over the base Kindle. The 2018 model also added a few useful features normally found on Amazon’s flagship reader, the Oasis, such as water resistance and Audible audiobook support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UaH6Zy"&gt;No deals are currently available for the Paperwhite, but you can pick up the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PQ96B6B?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;8GB model with ad support&lt;/a&gt; for $130 or the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PTCW9G7?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ad-free edition for $150&lt;/a&gt;. If you need more space, Amazon is selling the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PP49ZDW?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;32GB Paperwhite with ads for $160&lt;/a&gt;; if you want the ad-free model, it’s &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PT96B3T?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available for $180&lt;/a&gt;. Just like the base Kindle, Amazon currently running a promotion where you can grab the e-reader plus three months of Kindle Unlimited at no additional cost. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Emeowb"&gt;Amazon has discounted its Kindle Paperwhite Essentials Bundle, which includes either an &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07HL49FCK/ref=mako_bundletwister_mt1?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;8GB e-reader bundle for $170&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07HKT4M5K/ref=mako_bundletwister_mt1?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$200 if you buy the 32GB&lt;/a&gt; (with ads). If you’re a fan of Suzanne Collins’ Hunger Games trilogy, Amazon also offers a bundle that includes a Kindle Paperwhite, a power adapter, and a Mockingjay-emblazoned cover. It’s currently available in two ad-supported configurations and colors: an &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kindle-Paperwhite-Bundle-including-Ad-Supported/dp/B087NMH2F7?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;8GB version for $160&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kindle-Paperwhite-Bundle-including-Ad-Supported/dp/B087NM77FC?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;32GB variant for $190&lt;/a&gt;, both of which save you $20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vOUHwk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9552401"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="X5jbTU"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/24/20707619/amazon-kindle-oasis-2019-e-reader-review-price-specs-features-display"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kindle Oasis (Third Generation)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;deals&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="IByP4u"&gt;The Kindle Oasis is the most expensive of the lineup, starting at $250. The device comes in two storage configurations, 8GB or 32GB, and like the other models, you can get it with or without ads on the lock screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1AvXZM"&gt;The 2019 Kindle Oasis looks very similar to the previous model. It retains its waterproof, seven-inch, 300ppi E Ink display and supports Audible audiobooks via Bluetooth. Unlike previous models, however, it can adjust the color temperature to a yellow-toned display, making it easier to read at night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oxP7sb"&gt;In the past, we have seen the 32GB Kindle Oasis drop to as low as $200, which is the lowest it has ever been for that configuration to date. While there are currently no deals on just the Oasis itself, configurations start at $250 and include three free months of Kindle Unlimited. The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07VHV8D7P?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;8GB, ad-supported Oasis&lt;/a&gt; is $250 and the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07VDMJJLG?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;one without ads is $270&lt;/a&gt;. If you need more storage, the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07VCMJSLB?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;32GB version is $280 with ads&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07VGTRMFS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$300 without&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XuGlPY"&gt;Amazon is currently offering an Essentials Bundle for $30 off its normal list price. You can get either the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07RNPKRKW/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;8GB, ad-supported configuration for as low as $280&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07RW2K1MD/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;32GB variant for $310&lt;/a&gt;, both of which come with a leather cover, a power adapter, and three months of Kindle Unlimited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="hPPu8s"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9552599"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="4mZNi9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21539047/best-amazon-kindle-deals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21539047/best-amazon-kindle-deals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-10T19:43:45-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-10T19:43:45-04:00</updated>
    <title>Disney and Starz are in a slap fight over the launch of Star+</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Disney logo" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eRHm8UO7J3bRudSBnLOolIuYOnQ=/0x0:1020x680/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69437050/Disney.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fzm7vK"&gt;Disney is set to launch its standalone Star+ streaming service in Latin America in August, but Starz has filed complaints in Mexico, Brazil, and Argentina alleging Disney is infringing on its brand identity and that the soon-to-launch service will only confuse consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y7gmVJ"&gt;In an English language translation of the complaints seen by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.thewrap.com/starz-disney-copyright-suit-star-streaming-service-name-latin-america/"&gt;previously reported by &lt;em&gt;The Wrap&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Starz argues that Disney’s “Star Plus” service — which will host content from Disney, FX, 20th Century Studios and National Geographic, as well as Star originals — sounds too phonetically similar to its own StarzPlay offering also available in the regions where it filed its complaints. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ohwAQu"&gt;Starz, a premium cable offering and streaming app, has been operating under the name since the mid-1990s and now has a presence in 58 countries. Its own service, StarzPlay, has been available in Latin America since 2019. Disney’s Star — a service offered in international markets and nested within Disney Plus — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22165950/disney-star-streaming-service-hotstar-international-movies-tv"&gt;officially launched&lt;/a&gt; in December. Star+, meanwhile, is &lt;a href="https://dmedmedia.disney.com/news/star-plus-arrives-in-latin-america-august-2021"&gt;set to launch&lt;/a&gt; as a single service offering in Latin America on August 31st. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="zf1RJA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Starz claims Disney’s “Star Plus” sounds too similar to its own StarzPlay service&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qwfw3b"&gt;“Both companies are currently direct competitors in the Mexican market, which causes an unfair competition to materialize, especially if it is considered that we are talking about the same services,” the complaint filed in Mexico states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EAa0QQ"&gt;Reached for comment, a spokesperson for Starz said the company “had no choice but to defend its rights and attempt to forestall any further customer confusion by filing trademark infringement suits” in Brazil, Mexico, and Argentina against Disney for its use of “Star” and various iterations of the service title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ePzdhD"&gt;Disney did not immediately respond to a request for comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fPeJDl"&gt;The company announced in May that its Star+ service would officially roll out to consumers at the end of August. At the time, Diego Lerner, president of The Walt Disney Company Latin America, said in a statement that the service would deliver “a never-before-seen customized experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7wy8Ry"&gt;“The strength of the content, that will include all of ESPN, makes Star+ a unique and relevant offering with its own identity that will become a recognized digital service, independent from Disney Plus,” Lerner said. “Having said that, its arrival will represent a service that is complementary to Disney Plus and it will consolidate The Walt Disney Company’s presence in Latin America’s streaming market.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22528736/disney-starz-star-plus-latin-america"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22528736/disney-starz-star-plus-latin-america</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
