<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-11-17T10:03:46-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-17T10:03:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-17T10:03:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>Nissan’s upcoming electric SUV, the 2023 Ariya, will start at $47,125</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7lfH1U_8ubtCQcQNgvTpkg1Y-lg=/58x0:5139x3387/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70154602/Nissan_Ariya_006a.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5dwgwE"&gt;The 2023 Nissan Ariya, the automaker’s upcoming electric crossover SUV, finally has a sticker price. The company announced that the EV will start at $47,125, and that reservations are now being accepted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o4gwcp"&gt;The Ariya, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/15/21324125/nissan-ariya-electric-suv-crossover-specs-price"&gt;which was first announced last summer&lt;/a&gt;, was expected to go on sale in Japan in the middle of 2021, followed by the US and Canada later in the year. But that’s been delayed, with North American customers not expected to receive deliveries until early fall 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="NB32MO"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Nissan also revealed a bunch of new information about the various trim levels&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FTohgd"&gt;In addition to pricing, Nissan also revealed a bunch of new information about the various trim levels. The least expensive Ariya will cost buyers $47,125 (after a $1,175 destination charge), but the costs can reach over $60,000 when optioning out a top-of-the-line model. Nissan had originally said it expected the Ariya to start at $40,000. (Nissan is still eligible for the full $7,500 federal tax credit and various state incentives.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gnfu1p"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10870616"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AYDSEA"&gt;Here’s a look at the various options: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="0cxrn6"&gt;Ariya Venture Plus with front-wheel drive, an 87kWh battery, 238-horsepower AC synchronous motor, 221lb-ft of torque, up to 300-mile estimated range: $47,125 (with delivery charge)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="r0uqWw"&gt;Ariya Evolve Plus FWD with 87kWh battery, 238-horsepower AC synchronous motor, 221lb-ft of torque, up to 285-mile estimated range: $50,125&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uI3R5I"&gt;Ariya Premiere FWD with 87kWh battery, 238-horsepower AC synchronous motor, 221lb-ft of torque, up to 285-mile estimated range: $54,625&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="G0TW1S"&gt;Ariya Platinum Plus with all-wheel drive, e-4ORCE dual motor all-wheel control, 87kWh battery, 389-horsepower AC synchronous motor, 442lb-ft of torque, up to 265-mile estimated range: $60,125&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="J8h6Au"&gt;Nissan is also offering discounts on charging at EVgo charging stations to the first 10,000 people who make reservations before January 31st, 2022. The discounts amount to a two-year free EVgo membership plus $500 in charging credits upon purchase. Deposits are $500, fully refundable, and can be placed at the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.nissanusa.com/ariya/reserve/premiere"&gt;new web portal&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5dGoEG"&gt;Like the majority of the auto industry, Nissan has promised to make and sell more electric vehicles. The company is targeting that more than 40 percent of its US vehicle sales by 2030 will be fully electric, with even more to be electrified (meaning hybrids and plug-in hybrids). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="YhGDQM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Nissan has long been a leader in electric vehicle sales&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="w1Nowb"&gt;Nissan has long been a leader in electric vehicle sales, despite really only having one EV — the functional-if-uninspiring &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/6/16258688/2018-nissan-leaf-photos-tokyo-launch-event"&gt;Nissan Leaf hatchback&lt;/a&gt; — on the market. The company unveiled the Ariya against the backdrop of &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-50964040"&gt;corporate turmoil&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/09/09/nissan-ceo-saikawa-to-step-down-on-september-16.html"&gt;executive turnover&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://europe.autonews.com/automakers/nissan-counts-suv-and-ev-product-offensive-spark-rebound-europe"&gt;plummeting sales&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-03-03/nissan-ready-for-deeper-cost-cuts-as-business-worsens-ceo-says"&gt;pandemic-related cost-cutting&lt;/a&gt; at Nissan. &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/03/business/carlos-ghosn-arrest.html"&gt;The arrest&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/06/business/carlos-ghosn-escape.html"&gt;subsequent escape&lt;/a&gt; of Carlos Ghosn, former chairman of the Nissan-Renault-Mitsubishi alliance, dominated the headlines for much of 2019, casting a spotlight on an automaker that appeared to be at war with itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w1rlhU"&gt;As such, the Ariya is the first major new product launch in the post-Ghosn era for the company — and a chance to turn over a new leaf (pun intended). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C6c4AW"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T9zSMj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787170/nissan-ariya-ev-price-specs-trim-reservations-deposit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787170/nissan-ariya-ev-price-specs-trim-reservations-deposit</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-17T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-17T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon’s Echo Show 15 goes up for preorder, shipping December 9th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GhNr2xqDUROskesk7VYkKAc7d2E=/625x0:7375x4500/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70154555/echo_show_15_media_lifestyle_6.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon’s Echo Show 15.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo: Amazon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eX2mSJ"&gt;Today, Amazon is opening up preorders for its largest Alexa-enabled smart display yet, the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/introducing-echo-show-15-smart-display-with-alexa/dp/B08MQLDFF6?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Echo Show 15&lt;/a&gt;. The $249.99 device has a 15.6-inch 1080p touchscreen that can be oriented in portrait or landscape, and can either be mounted on a wall or placed on a countertop. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dvSu4O"&gt;Announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/28/22693503/amazon-echo-show-15-smart-display-wall-price-specs-features"&gt;in late September&lt;/a&gt;, the Echo Show 15 is designed to act as a communal hub for families and show useful information like calendar appointments, reminders, and to-do lists. It shows these in permanent home screen widgets, which are displayed alongside a more typical assortment of news headlines like previous Echo Shows. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ceavvl5KxQQ-3UT2TXgIAqOg5lA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23021355/Echo_Show_15_8.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Amazon&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;It can also be oriented vertically.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bUVNUtAGKCSEvW3zrltyu2Y4CNA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23021356/echo_show_15_media_lifestyle_09_copy.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Amazon&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Or placed on a countertop.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MSVJan"&gt;As well as these communal features, the Echo Show 15 can also act as a standalone entertainment device. It’s Amazon’s first smart display that supports 1080p streams from the likes of Netflix and Amazon Prime Video and can also act as a photo frame, has a 5-megapixel camera for video calls, and can display a feed from a compatible security camera or video doorbell in a picture-in-picture view. There’s no mention of YouTube support, however, so expect to fire up the built-in web browser if you want to access it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22297810/amazon-echo-show-10-2021-review#:~:text=watching%20youtube%20videos%20also%20remains%20a%20laughably%20bad%20experience%20that%20involves%20accessing%20the%20youtube%20mobile%20site%20through%20the%20echo%20show%2010%E2%80%99s%20built-in%20web%20browser%2C%20though%20at%20least%20you%20can%20do%20it%20via%20a%20voice%20command."&gt;like with previous Echo Show devices&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FLZfKX"&gt;The Echo Show 15 is due to ship on December 9th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22786975/amazon-echo-show-15-release-date-preorder-smart-display-alexa"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22786975/amazon-echo-show-15-release-date-preorder-smart-display-alexa</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-17T09:35:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-17T09:35:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>Axiom Space reveals science that will be done on first crewed flight to the ISS</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7K9IkIEyDFFRai3duIPwPsbbTes=/0x0:6048x4032/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70154415/iss056e201174.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The International Space Station&lt;/em&gt; | Image: NASA&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kYhW40"&gt;Private space habitat company Axiom is &lt;a href="https://www.axiomspace.com/press-kit-ax1-research"&gt;revealing the science&lt;/a&gt; that the company’s first private astronauts will do when they travel to the International Space Station (ISS) next year. The research experiments include working with stem cells to gauge how space impacts aging as well as performing a two-way 3D hologram projection demonstration using a Microsoft HoloLens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pAxAAw"&gt;These and other experiments will be performed by four crew members whom Axiom plans to send to the ISS in February 2022, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/26/22250327/space-tourists-axiom-private-crew-iss-price"&gt;part of the company’s Ax-1 mission&lt;/a&gt;. The crew will fly to the space station inside a SpaceX Crew Dragon capsule that Axiom purchased in March 2020. It’s actually the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22465134/spacex-axiom-space-sign-bulk-deal-private-crew-dragon-missions"&gt;first of many SpaceX Crew Dragon flights&lt;/a&gt; that Axiom bought from SpaceX in order to send people back and forth to the ISS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MuZgWV"&gt;The four fliers on board Ax-1 include Michael López-Alegría, the mission’s commander and a former NASA astronaut who now works for Axiom, along with three paying customers. Larry Connor, an American nonprofit activist investor; Mark Pathy, a Canadian investor; and Eytan Stibbe, an Israeli investor and former Israeli fighter pilot, each paid $55 million to ride on board Ax-1. They are also the ones who helped to decide on the 25 research experiments they’ll be doing while on board the mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="R9aSZF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“These crew don’t really want a whole lot of spare time.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eMnbj2"&gt;“These crew don’t really want a whole lot of spare time,” Christian Maender, director of in-space manufacturing and research at Axiom Space, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “They’re planning on filling most of their time with science, believe it or not. For the little time that they are going to create for themselves, they just expressed an interest in taking opportunities to take in the views a little bit.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JZSkaF"&gt;Ax-1 is set to launch on top of one of SpaceX’s Falcon 9 rockets in February, spending two days in orbit while reaching the International Space Station. Once the crew has docked with the orbiting lab, they’ll spend eight days on board, conducting their research alongside the NASA astronauts, German astronaut, and Russian cosmonauts currently living on the ISS. The research should take up to 100 hours to complete.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/quDgRyt70KroCR3ybGdwwEddftk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22260805/Ax1_Crew.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Axiom Space&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Ax-1 crew (from L to R): Michael López-Alegría, Mark Pathy, Larry Connor, and Eytan Stibbe. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="O5XII8"&gt;Connor is the one who will be working with stem cells in coordination with the Mayo Clinic, studying how space travel affects heart health and senescent cells — aged cells that no longer divide and grow. Pathy, meanwhile, has up to 12 experiments on his plate, including a hologram demonstration. NASA has already demonstrated one-way “holoportation” bringing up the image of someone on the ground onto the space station, using a HoloLens. But Pathy will show that a two-way dialogue is possible, sending his image down to Earth while the image of the person he is talking to comes to him on the station. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="94kTar"&gt;“What it really plays into is opportunities for more longer duration spaceflight and more deep spaceflight,” Maender says, “where you are really talking about wanting to create a human connection between your crew — no matter where they’re traveling — and back to someone on the planet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s0x8rF"&gt;Stibbe will be taking part in his own mission called Rakia, named “after the dome (atmosphere) created by God on the second day after the firmament, which protects life on Earth,” according to Axiom. The goal of his research is to “connect the younger generation in Israel” by doing science and artistic endeavors, with experiments drawing on disciplines ranging from astrophysics to neuroscience. López-Alegría will help out with all of this research, as well as serve as a human subject for some of the experiments aimed at learning more about how space impacts the body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fCIAsq"&gt;Axiom considers Ax-1 the first of many missions. The company was founded in 2016 by Mike Suffredini, the former ISS program manager at NASA, and it has the ultimate goal of building private space stations that various customers can visit to do research. Axiom holds a contract with NASA to attach a module to the ISS as early as 2024, testing out the company’s habitat technology. That mission is part of a larger goal to expand to a free-flying space station called “Axiom Station.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="frYko2"&gt;With that larger target in mind, Ax-1 and the follow-up SpaceX Crew Dragon missions will all help Axiom better understand how to get people to space safely and what kinds of work they can do in orbit when they get there. “It’s a demonstration mission for us in a lot of ways,” says Maender. “Demonstrating how we can open up more opportunities for research in microgravity beyond what can be done on the on the ISS today.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jbB34X"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xKb58l"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M7WpNd"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22785888/axiom-space-ax-1-science-experiments-spacex-crew-dragon-iss"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22785888/axiom-space-ax-1-science-experiments-spacex-crew-dragon-iss</id>
    <author>
      <name>Loren Grush</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-17T09:24:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-17T09:24:30-05:00</updated>
    <title>NFT makers are trying to build the next Disney</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SdJKCnIaYFLvIUYjciNGX4LtYOs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70154365/acastro_211115_4866_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;There’s a long way to go&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="KlAjAk"&gt;In the online auction market OpenSea, you can pay around $600 to buy a portrait of a robot in streetwear — and, if you’re lucky, a stake in a new media empire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p-large-text" id="ibOJUG"&gt;The robot is called a TARS, and it’s part of the Voguverse, an elaborate 37th-century mythos involving space arcologies, a nuclear war, and interstellar travel. The portrait is one of countless digital assets being sold as non-fungible tokens, or NFTs. But by pairing its fictional universe with a blockchain-based ledger, the creators think they can tap into a new way to tell stories. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Be9QD4"&gt;As NFTs explode in popularity, entrepreneurs are imagining an entire media industry that’s built around them. At its most ambitious, the vision is sometimes dubbed a “decentralized Disney”: a world of fictional crossovers like the Marvel Cinematic Universe and its many spinoffs but where different characters and creative properties are owned by a panoply of fans, not a single company. Talent agencies, comics authors, and countless NFT enthusiasts are buying in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="avAx3f"&gt;What does &lt;em&gt;owned&lt;/em&gt; mean? Many are still figuring that out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Images of a hat, glasses, and jewelry in neon style." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/piSL7e5rZww3j9YrmuYVRjdlgf4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23021480/acastro_211115_4866_0003.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="aRLqDl"&gt;Over the past couple of years, NFTs — essentially &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22310188/nft-explainer-what-is-blockchain-crypto-art-faq"&gt;certificates of ownership inscribed on a cryptocurrency blockchain&lt;/a&gt; — have exploded into a lucrative and growing market. Some of the most sought-after NFTs are collectibles: typically limited edition runs of unique, automatically generated avatars or other items. The most popular tokens can sell for millions of dollars in sales that are more like an art auction than a bitcoin trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="keMuhY"&gt;NFTs have made the biggest waves in the fine art world, and some NFT collectibles series are united by an aesthetic rather than a concrete narrative. CryptoPunks, the best-known example, are a set of 10,000 mostly human pixelated portraits. But many are based in some kind of fictional setting. At its simplest, this might look like the city of “Arctopolis,” where Chill City NFT penguins live and work. At its most complex, it might involve something like the Voguverse. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A city street scene of penguins driving on ice roads with igloo houses on the corner." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Nlx73TQ8Fir6GMtYrunn6VmSe2Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23018440/60a1befaac554e547aaaf723_ChillCityTown.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Chill City&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Art depicting the home of Chill City NFT penguins&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KpIpyS"&gt;The Voguverse lore is laid out on a web page explaining the backstory of the TARS, a name that stands for “Tether Assisted Robotic Skeleton.” In the far future, Earth is uninhabitable, and humans live in space-bound “hives” ruled by a galactic government and mega-corporations that deal in cryptocurrency. (A lot of NFT lore involves crypto fans getting rich.) People use TARS telepresence bots to revisit their home planet, buying models that reflect their personalities and jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Esn61L"&gt;Vogu founder Andrew Trackzy sees TARS as a potential building block for the next big media intellectual property, or IP. “Our goals for Vogu and this IP is to grow it to a large-scale worldwide IP, just like Star Wars, just like Pokémon,” he tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. Even if Vogu doesn’t hit this bar, he thinks some other project will. “I do believe that — whether it’s us or another project that comes before or after us — that someone in the NFT space will create the next big worldwide IP.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="37ZkiS"&gt;He’s not alone. Some NFT series involve formal media tie-ins, like Stoner Cats, a collectible that’s funding an animated series featuring Mila Kunis and Seth MacFarlane. Other creators have struck open-ended deals to leverage their fame: CryptoPunks creator Larva Labs &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/digital/uta-cryptopunks-nft-film-tv-vieo-games-1235005392/"&gt;signed to Hollywood talent agency UTA&lt;/a&gt; in August, and the Bored Ape Yacht Club is represented by U2 and Madonna manager Guy Oseary. Trackzy says Vogu is currently talking with several potential media partners and working on a webtoon set in the Voguverse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8BxFbr"&gt;Trackzy’s plan mimics the strategy of building powerhouse media franchises from toy lines like &lt;em&gt;GI Joe&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Transformers&lt;/em&gt;. NFTs have some crucial differences from action figures, however, beyond being harder for kids to play with. For one thing, many buyers are seeking a fast-growing investment rather than an art piece or a toy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="53INwY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Most people probably aren’t calling up &lt;em&gt;Thundercats&lt;/em&gt; and being like, dude, Lion-O did not have the screen time in the last episode that I needed”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rIo2ou"&gt;“With an action figure, most people probably aren’t calling up &lt;em&gt;Thundercats&lt;/em&gt; and being like, dude, Lion-O did not have the screen time in the last episode that I needed,” says Trackzy, referencing the 1980s TV series. “As a project, you’re constantly under pressure from your community to increase the value of that collectible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AIl6wq"&gt;Because each NFT avatar is unique, buyers can also forge a connection with a genuinely (if only slightly) one-of-a-kind character. Some NFT buyers make fan art of their purchases, while others spin entire independent stories around them like Jenkins the Valet, a character built around a Bored Ape Yacht Club NFT. If one of these stories blows up, it can raise the profile of the entire lineup. The buyers can sell their NFT if they want to move on to another project, and unlike an action figure, the person who minted the NFT can collect a royalty every time a collectible changes hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="11VkoC"&gt;To NFT proponents like investor Drew Austin — who’s working on his own community NFT narrative project — that mix marks the birth of a new media model. “We are putting the foundation in place so that people can use their imagination and create stories and content and experiences with their own characters that they own through this because it’s an NFT,” says Austin. “The ability to be able to leverage the community, to be able to expand on IP and to create a universe, I think, is a really exciting concept.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O39Jd3"&gt;The dream might sound intuitive in the world of modern media franchises, where giant games and blockbuster movies are shaped by convoluted licensing deals for beloved figures like Spider-Man. Instead of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/16/17461884/marvel-fans-fox-comcast-deal-x-men-mcu"&gt;rooting for a giant corporate merger&lt;/a&gt; that might let the X-Men hang out with the Avengers, fans could directly collaborate to have their favorite characters share the same fictional world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="An image of an action figure in a package in neon style." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xCQ3JYRe9tCOERRrJd6nbVKRbmU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23021483/acastro_211115_4866_0002.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="bWmKnB"&gt;For believers, NFTs and entertainment IP rights seem like a perfect match — an emerging market with overwhelming possibilities and hype paired with a billion-dollar industry in dire need of disruption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3E1Cyu"&gt;But owning a fictional character and owning an NFT mean very different things, and the two forms of ownership don’t neatly overlap. It’s an often overlooked but incredibly important distinction that much of the NFT world is still grappling with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0zVMfr"&gt;To explain why, we have to dig into how NFTs and intellectual property work. NFTs are, at an incredibly oversimplified level, entries on a database called a blockchain. These entries represent (or sometimes directly encode) a file or even a physical object, and an entry is linked with a specific cryptocurrency wallet. “Owning” an NFT means having its entry associated with a digital wallet you control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="oTysKQ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;NFTs don’t confer any specific, universal set of legal rights&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="knQ7PY"&gt;“Owning” a media property, by contrast, typically means that you hold the copyrights and trademarks associated with it. A copyright — again, at an incredibly simplified level — is an exclusive, automatically granted legal right to sell copies of a creative work or produce other media based on it. A trademark stops other people from selling commercial goods with a name or mark that you’ve registered with an agency like the US Patent and Trademark Office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kRzCgF"&gt;NFTs don’t confer a specific set of legal rights. If anything, part of their appeal is supposed to be that you don’t need a government involved in enforcing their ownership. By contrast, copyright and trademark are complex legal frameworks enforced by individual countries and international bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tmH5Au"&gt;Some NFT collectibles, like &lt;a href="https://medium.com/veve-collectibles/disney-golden-moments-walt-disney-mickey-mouse-9821fb07fdd7"&gt;a new lineup sold by Disney&lt;/a&gt;, basically operate at the level of trading cards and confer no rights to the underlying art. But other NFT sellers do try to outline some kind of intellectual property framework. They draw up terms of service, laying out which legal rights they’re allowing buyers to exercise. Owning the NFT (in the “having a wallet linked to its entry” sense) signals that both parties have agreed to this contract. If one side breaks it, the two parties could go to court, the same way you could sue over any broken contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A pair of Vogu TARS robots in streetwear with the titles “Core” and “Kouwei” collection" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FG399A_UhFKZ8vBC2AX884GcJOQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23018449/Screen_Shot_2021_11_16_at_8.34.06_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Vogu Collective&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Voguverse robot NFTs are part of a complex fictional universe.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kX7GwX"&gt;But these contracts vary widely. Holding a &lt;a href="https://opensea.io/collection/chill-city-nft-collectibles"&gt;Chill City penguin&lt;/a&gt; NFT allows you to print non-commercial “one-off units” of T-shirts or other items depicting the penguin. A Bored Ape Yacht Club agreement lets you sell merchandise or derivative works depicting your ape, although you can only use the phrase “Bored Ape” to reference the NFT number. CryptoKitties uses the &lt;a href="https://www.nftlicense.org/"&gt;NFT License&lt;/a&gt;, an attempt at a standardized NFT intellectual property framework. Cool Cats offers a single sentence saying users are “free to do anything” with their digital cats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mMw8c5"&gt;Even a fairly generous NFT deal isn’t the equivalent of Disney owning the Avengers, as you’ll see if you look at lore-heavy collectibles like Vogu’s TARS. Vogu’s terms of service give TARS owners an exclusive copyright license to an image of a robot with the NFT’s specific combination of features. If Vogu wants to depict that exact robot in its media, the contractual deal it struck with the current owner says it needs to either get their permission or buy it back from them. The company apparently spent $16,000 reacquiring one besuited robot to use it as a fictitious in-universe CEO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="11CTJH"&gt;But buying the NFT doesn’t give you any intellectual property rights to the underlying details of the Voguverse, like the backstory of the robots or the term “TARS.” If you wanted to make a cartoon starring your TARS without Vogu’s active approval, you’d have to invent a whole new sci-fi world complete with new names for everything — as Trackzy puts it, &lt;em&gt;Robot Dude In A Kimono&lt;/em&gt; is acceptable,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;but &lt;em&gt;Vogu Kimono Guy&lt;/em&gt; is not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="FX28jC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“When you look at a CryptoPunk, it sort of served as inspiration to us”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YKeryI"&gt;NFT creators can also bypass buyers by designing a non-minted media character in the style of their collectibles. If Vogu had really wanted to avoid paying for a CEO that looked like a specific TARS, it could have made a nearly identical robot but added an extra accessory. For future projects, the Vogu Collective plans to hold virtual casting calls for cameo roles, but its major characters won’t be drawn from the TARS NFT lineup. Other creators take similar tacks: &lt;em&gt;Stoner Cats&lt;/em&gt; isn’t selling NFTs of its main characters, for example — it’s offering collectibles recombining their attributes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KRMlFw"&gt;“We wanted artists in the space to be able to exercise their creativity and use what they purchase. That’s part of the value of owning these assets,” says Trackzy. “At the end of the day, it’s a business decision that we had to make, to make sure that the community was happy with the rights that we gave them. But we also have to make sure that when I go and sit down with Universal Studios, they’re comfortable that they can make a movie.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="wlyuKj"&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="NX3I7x"&gt;Many NFT sellers still want people to play in their sandboxes. Unlike Disney, a company notorious for ruthless copyright crackdowns, plenty of them welcome fan works, including for-profit add-on NFT series. But that’s not unusual for small creative projects of any stripe, and a lot of collaborations involve handshake approval or one-off licensing deals, not an automatic blockchain contract. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wFFpwt"&gt;The team behind Jenkins the Valet says they’ve been collaborating with BAYC since the beginning of the project. “Our teams are working together to make sure that everyone is protected, and we will continue to exercise due care to make sure that their IP is expressed in a positive way that does not contradict what they are building,” they wrote in an email. (That said, they won’t be using the Bored Ape branding in their work.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="ssp7ZD"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We wanted artists in the space to be able to exercise their creativity and use what they purchase. That’s part of the value of owning these assets”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FpY4Du"&gt;The Vogu Collective also grants licensing permissions on a case-by-case basis, including to people who don’t own its NFT. One TARS-less fan is currently building a Voguverse-themed tabletop role-playing game based on the freely available &lt;em&gt;Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons&lt;/em&gt; ruleset, thanks to an informal agreement that gives Vogu final approval rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The cover of Punks #1 comic" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/db2CvPeM4qhxU7qC34Ogg5OQC9k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23021492/Screen_Shot_2021_11_17_at_8.20.17_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Pixel Vault&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The cover of Punks #1 comic&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hvSTqC"&gt;Some people are making NFT-based art without this kind of top-down approval, but they’re treading carefully around thorny ownership issues. &lt;em&gt;Punks&lt;/em&gt; comic — one of multiple comics and &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-11/the-world-s-largest-record-company-is-creating-an-nft-super-group?cmpid%3D=socialflow-twitter-tech&amp;amp;utm_content=tech&amp;amp;utm_campaign=socialflow-organic&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter"&gt;at least one band&lt;/a&gt; involving team-ups between different NFT avatars — is based on portraits from the CryptoPunks lineup. While Pixel Vault members own the avatars in question, Pixel Vault founder Sean Gearin says they haven’t been able to contact CryptoPunks creator Larva Labs for approval. Instead, the company enlisted three teams of lawyers to create a “100 percent unique” intellectual property inspired by the collectibles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EVQYub"&gt;Punk #8146 of CryptoPunks, for instance, is a tiny and nameless figure with a barely visible cigarette and a propeller beanie. &lt;em&gt;Punks&lt;/em&gt; protagonist Beanie has the same hat and cigarette, but he’s got a backstory as a former busboy who becomes a digital art kingpin, and he’s drawn in a far more detailed comic-book style. “When you look at a CryptoPunk, it sort of served as inspiration to us, but when you look at the comic itself, it bears no resemblance really to the original art of Larva Labs,” says Gearin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hJHRBM"&gt;Pixel Vault’s process resembles a fandom strategy called &lt;a href="https://fanlore.org/wiki/Filing_Off_The_Serial_Numbers"&gt;filing off the serial numbers&lt;/a&gt;, where authors change names and world details to make original stories out of fanfiction. This also happens in traditional comics: &lt;em&gt;Doom Patrol’s&lt;/em&gt; Willoughby Kipling was created as a direct stand-in for &lt;em&gt;Hellblazer’s&lt;/em&gt; John Constantine, and Marvel’s Wade Wilson (aka Deadpool) &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/comics/2016/1/28/10860668/deadpool-deathstroke-deadshot"&gt;began as a near-clone&lt;/a&gt; of DC’s Slade Wilson (aka Deathstroke.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4XivMn"&gt;NFTs play an important social role here. If Pixel Vault didn’t own the individual CryptoPunks it’s drawing inspiration from, &lt;em&gt;Punks&lt;/em&gt; would probably draw community censure and pressure from Larva Labs. But the blockchain isn’t replacing long-standing legal maneuvers — or changing the fact that you don’t need a license to get inspired by a work of art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Images of avatar faces in a neon style." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9GwJR89rvKD1YDGPDX3k-pM_ZO8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23021486/acastro_211115_4866_0004.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JPbAtC"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Punks&lt;/em&gt; is only a jumping-off point for Pixel Vault, which is trying its own ambitious approach to NFT storytelling. That’s the Metahero Universe: a nascent franchise built by a core creative team but run partly by fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JD63VO"&gt;Metahero started with a series of generative NFT avatars representing heroes and villains. Pixel Vault wants it to include a series of comic books and a big-budget massively multiplayer game. To manage this, it’s founded a series of planet-themed decentralized autonomous organizations, or DAOs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pmLL9V"&gt;DAOs are essentially groups of token holders who pool their resources and vote on decisions, similar to shareholders at a company. This system offers broad decentralized decision-making rather than ownership of a specific character. It could also add complications to the already difficult process of designing a video game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SL4Ap0"&gt;Building a Metahero game could be tough under any circumstances. When I spoke to Pixel Vault, the company had a 17-person staff whose background mostly wasn’t in game design. (It’s apparently considering partnering with a larger studio.) With the DAO structure, NFT holders are supposed to pick the game’s genre — like a battle royale title or a more traditional MMO — and then vote on numerous decisions throughout development, to the point of firing an entire creative team. It’s an intriguing experiment, but it also sounds a bit like running a Kickstarter campaign for a piece of video game concept art and promising to let backers run the studio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="lfxgxG"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I think self-preservation will ultimately rule the day”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7e70qO"&gt;If a game is open to non-DAO members, as Gearin says the Metahero MMO will be, the structure also seems to encourage a fandom crypto-aristocracy. Pixel Vault wants to balance the experience so players without an expensive NFT could join and have fun, even if more money offers visual flair or special abilities. But in theory, DAO holders could simply order the developer to let them steamroll every other player in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zjEzm9"&gt;Gearin thinks DAO members will avoid this because they’re invested in the overall long-term health of the game. “I think self-preservation will ultimately rule the day. So even if initially, they like the idea of ‘We want to be able to pay to win,’ ultimately that’s going to stunt the growth of the game, right?” he says. “The community can ultimately decide what they will, and it will be somewhat unpredictable. But at the end of the day, people typically act in what they believe their own best interest is.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FCVzHC"&gt;In case they don’t, Pixel Vault has an escape hatch: it controls 45 percent of the voting power in any decision. The planetary DAOs control another 45 percent, and 10 percent is tied up in a “founders DAO” that’s not associated with Pixel Vault but composed of early adopters who support its vision. “It’s kind of like the little security to help ensure that the best decision gets made if we indeed have the best decision,” Gearin says. But at least, in theory, all the DAOs could unite against their creator — taking the universe in any direction they want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="JAZA0Y"&gt;
&lt;p id="38yEcS"&gt;While Metahero is an organized attempt to create a decentralized media franchise, some NFT creators are taking the opposite tack: starting with a tantalizingly skeletal collectible, then encouraging NFT owners to build a fan-made world around it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HL8qj2"&gt;The best example of this is Loot, created by Vine co-founder Dom Hofmann. Loot bags are procedurally generated lists with a &lt;em&gt;Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons-&lt;/em&gt;like fantasy flavor: Loot Bag #980’s contents include “Crown” and “Demon Husk;” #2073 includes “Shoes,” “Necklace,” and “‘Rune Root’ Quarterstaff of Giants.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JXBgqg"&gt;Since launching in August, the text-based Loot bags have inspired a dedicated fandom. Buyers made art depicting their bag’s contents and formed guilds with people who own the same item, while other creators designed independent NFTs that pair with the bags. If you own a Loot Bag, you can do things like generate a custom Loot Character, a pixelated avatar wearing or holding items from the bag. The Loot Character is then minted as an NFT that’s permanently linked with the bag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="oKAx1i"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“As soon as you make it formal, it starts to feel much more like you’re engaging with a corporation”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DObPPe"&gt;A Loot Character team member who goes by Moniker says the group talks regularly with the core Loot team. But the whole enterprise is deliberately informal. There’s no hard answer to who holds the rights to Loot Characters’ art or even the name of the project since it’s derivative of the original Loot NFT lineup. “It’s sort of a bit of a handshake at this point,” Moniker says. “As soon as you make it formal, it starts to feel much more like you’re engaging with a corporation than you are a bunch of folks that are just really excited about a project.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A procedurally generated Loot Character" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L8MVBgD_iIJcH-LqKSOo-necL8A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23021495/Screen_Shot_2021_11_17_at_8.22.03_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Loot Character&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A procedurally generated Loot Character&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tXs2pU"&gt;Some other projects have followed Loot’s formula, like Adventure Cards, which generates the names of cards for a nonexistent &lt;em&gt;Magic: The Gathering&lt;/em&gt;-style game. Adventure Cards has inspired its own community-built augmentations, including a simple but playable digital game. “I want people to feel like they can own the cards and be inspired by the cards, as long as everyone is explicit about what their contribution is,” says Adventure Cards creator Paul McKellar, previously a member of Square’s founding team. “I’d like to do whatever, honestly, lets people do as much as possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nzNVKc"&gt;But NFT creators’ commitment to openness generally hasn’t extended to a formal system for sharing ownership of the world, at least not yet. “I think that it’s really yet to be determined what the best ways of leading the communities are,” McKellar says. One possibility is a DAO composed of people who have contributed to the Adventure Cards universe. If a company wanted to adapt the series for film or TV, they’d work with the DAO to sign a deal, and DAO members could split the profits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="GVCKn6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s really yet to be determined what the best ways of leading the communities are”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PGmfaT"&gt;That’s a starkly different model from some older web art. The &lt;a href="https://scp-wiki.wikidot.com/"&gt;SCP Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, for instance, is a wiki composed of thousands of fictitious paranormal incident reports written by a plethora of authors. The entries are licensed under Creative Commons, an alternative copyright model that lets anybody remix or build on a work. The Creative Commons system requires that all the original stories and any adaptations must be distributed freely, and the wiki itself warns creators that they won’t be getting rich. That guaranteed legal safety, however, has turned SCP into a far bigger decentralized media universe than any NFT project. On top of its reports’ collaborative interlocking narrative, it serves as the source material for spinoff novels, video games, and short films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RDczii"&gt;To some fandom veterans, NFT projects’ murky ownership questions mean collaborative blockchain storytelling doesn’t look like a revolutionary new medium, just the latest attempt to monetize fan labor. In late October, six young adult fiction authors &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/26/inside-realms-of-ruin-ya-novelists-failed-nft-project/"&gt;spurred a community backlash&lt;/a&gt; with a project called Realms of Ruin: a fantasy world where the authors would compose origin stories and fans would write tie-ins that they could mint as NFTs. It wasn’t clear who would control the copyright to these tie-in stories, and potential participants worried they were giving up legal ownership in exchange for blockchain tokens. The creators, apparently surprised by the negative response, shut down the project within hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="vNqN9T"&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="AXHlXR"&gt;It’s not clear that NFTs make it easier to craft new art from old art, nor that they would help settle common copyright conflicts. Countless copyright cases revolve around fair use, a situation where proving ownership is beside the point. Other cases, like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22691842/disney-marvel-sues-comic-artist-iron-man-avengers"&gt;Disney’s long feud with Marvel comics veterans&lt;/a&gt;, hinge on the precise terms of a contract. A blockchain &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; help prevent works from being “orphaned,” or dropped into a limbo where the rightsholder can’t be found, except that cryptocurrency owners &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/13/business/tens-of-billions-worth-of-bitcoin-have-been-locked-by-people-who-forgot-their-key.html"&gt;lose or forget keys all the time&lt;/a&gt; and many transactions are anonymous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NuVVo1"&gt;Meanwhile, trying to use NFTs as a proxy for copyright raises its own concerns. If you do something like buy a superhero avatar, write a comic book about the hero, and sell the underlying avatar, there’s no clear norm about whether the new buyer should expect the rights to your comic. If Netflix wants to make a TV series about that comic, it’s even less clear how many people it would need to sign a deal with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="eNHpLw"&gt;And ultimately, while NFT owners might love their digital characters, companies still own the names and stories that give them meaning. “Are these individually owned NFTs going to hit Main Street? If you can’t use the Bored Ape Yacht Club name — you’re just a cool picture of a monkey. If you can’t use the Vogu name — you are just a cool picture of a robot,” says Trackzy. “We still have a long way, I think, for that.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22785051/nft-collectibles-intellectual-property-decentralized-disney"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22785051/nft-collectibles-intellectual-property-decentralized-disney</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-17T09:21:35-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-17T09:21:35-05:00</updated>
    <title>YouTube co-founder predicts ‘decline’ of the platform following removal of dislikes</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Zd7ssraebRp6KAN8yAq-Avc5Ums=/0x20:480x340/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70154351/jawed_karim_at_the_zoo.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;YouTube co-founder Jawed Karim edited the description to YouTube’s first ever video (above) to make his opinion known. &lt;/em&gt; | Image: YouTube&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="AkSkPL"&gt;Jawed Karim, the third co-founder of YouTube, has condemned the platform’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/10/22773299/youtube-dislike-button-hide-public-count-numbers-small-creator-protection"&gt;removal of public dislike counts&lt;/a&gt; on videos, suggesting that the change will lead to YouTube’s decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bwFVri"&gt;“Why would YouTube make this universally disliked change? There is a reason, but it’s not a good one, and not one that will be publicly disclosed,” writes Karim. “The ability to easily and quickly identify bad content is an essential feature of a user-generated content platform. Why? Because not all user-generated content is good.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mulkmj"&gt;YouTube made the change to its UI last week, saying it removed public dislikes in order to counter harassment and promote “respectful interactions between viewers and creators.” But many YouTuber users and creators have criticized the decision, arguing that dislike counts give the community a way to express its preferences as well as quickly identify misleading and spam videos promoted by YouTube’s own algorithm. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="aQJyUJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Does YouTube want to become a place where everything is mediocre?”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VqE9cX"&gt;Karim has been getting his own message out in an unusual way: by editing the description to the first video ever uploaded to YouTube, a banal clip titled “&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/jNQXAC9IVRw"&gt;Me at the zoo”&lt;/a&gt; which stars the 25-year-old Karim himself. Karim originally edited the description of the video a &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/11/13/youtube-me-at-the-zoo-dislike-protest/amp/"&gt;few days ago&lt;/a&gt; to read: “When every YouTuber agrees that removing dislikes is a stupid idea, it probably is. Try again, YouTube [face palm emoji].” But this morning he changed this description once again to give a more detailed condemnation: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p2RxyQ"&gt;“The ability to easily and quickly identify bad content is an essential feature of a user-generated content platform,” writes Karim. “Why? Because not all user-generated content is good. It can’t be. In fact, most of it is not good. And that’s OK. [...] The process works, and there’s a name for it: the wisdom of the crowds. The process breaks when the platform interferes with it. Then, the platform invariably declines. Does YouTube want to become a place where everything is mediocre?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vySy4g"&gt;It’s not the first time Karim has used the “Me at the zoo” video as an informal billboard for his opinions on the platform. In 2013, when YouTube announced it would use Google Plus to power comments — a move which many saw as a way for the search giant to force increased engagement for its doomed social network — Karim &lt;a href="https://venturebeat.com/2013/11/08/youtube-cofounders-first-public-comment-in-8-years-why-the-f-do-i-need-a-google-account-to-comment-on-a-video/"&gt;changed the video’s description&lt;/a&gt; to read: “why the fuck do i need a google+ account to comment on a video?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uddM4j"&gt;In his statement today, Karim compares the video in which Matt Koval, YouTube’s “creator liason,” &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/kxOuG8jMIgI"&gt;announced the removal of dislikes&lt;/a&gt; to infamous footage of US soldier Jeremiah Denton, who was captured during the Vietnam War. In 1966, Denton was forced to give a television interview by his captors, during which he &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2014/03/29/296211985/j-denton-fo"&gt;blinked in Morse code&lt;/a&gt; to spell out the word “torture.”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7CHB4C"&gt;You can read Karim’s latest update in full below: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="description"&gt;The spoken words did not match the eyes. The video reminded me of an interview Admiral Jeremiah Denton gave in 1966. I have never seen a less enthusiastic, more reluctant announcement of something that is supposed to be great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z4enGm"&gt;Calling the removal of dislikes a good thing for creators cannot be done without conflict by someone holding the title of “YouTube’s Creator Liaison”. We know this because there exists not a single YouTube Creator who thinks removing dislikes is a good idea — for YouTube or for Creators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gg5Gmb"&gt;Why would YouTube make this universally disliked change? There is a reason, but it’s not a good one, and not one that will be publicly disclosed. Instead, there will be references to various studies. Studies that apparently contradict the common sense of every YouTuber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PDLu0l"&gt;The ability to easily and quickly identify bad content is an essential feature of a user-generated content platform. Why? Because not all user-generated content is good. It can’t be. In fact, most of it is not good. And that’s OK. The idea was never that all content is good. The idea WAS, however, that among the flood of content, there are great creations waiting to be exposed. And for that to happen, the stuff that’s not great has to fall by the side as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OrdchD"&gt;The process works, and there’s a name for it: the wisdom of the crowds. The process breaks when the platform interferes with it. Then, the platform invariably declines. Does YouTube want to become a place where everything is mediocre? Because nothing can be great if nothing is bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jV3HaD"&gt;In business, there’s only one thing more important than “Make it better”. And that’s “Don’t fuck it up”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787080/youtube-dislikes-criticism-cofounder-jawed-karim-first-video-description-zoo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787080/youtube-dislikes-criticism-cofounder-jawed-karim-first-video-description-zoo</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-17T09:20:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-17T09:20:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Uber’s latest subscription offers discounts on rides, food, and delivery for $10 a month</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7dOHCFcBQAYy4Hra0lreMfXzYNY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70154345/acastro_180927_1777_uber_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9LTTsu"&gt;Uber is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/18/21374105/uber-ride-pass-subscription-cities-us-price-food-delivery"&gt;no stranger to subscriptions&lt;/a&gt;, offering Amazon Prime-style benefits for a monthly fee since 2018. Today, the company is rolling out its latest, dubbed Uber One, which is aimed at highlighting the company’s post-pandemic shift to food and grocery delivery. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="116jZk"&gt;For $9.99 a month or $49.99 a year, Uber One members will get access to perks such as guaranteed pricing on rides and delivery, and discounts such as 5 percent off “eligible” rides, food, and grocery deliveries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="iC58tM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Uber One is targeted at the company’s most frequent — and loyal — customers&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hVOJ7y"&gt;Uber One members won’t have to pay a delivery fee for takeout and groceries, will have priority access to top rated drivers and couriers, and get $5 cash back on late deliveries. They’ll also get other “exclusive perks,” such as various promotions and “invite-only experiences.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nBwG8j"&gt;Uber One is targeted at the company’s most frequent — and loyal — customers, as most people will switch back and forth between Uber and Lyft in search of the right price. Uber wants to reward those customers who keep using its product, whether its for rides, food delivery, or both. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xo6Mf6"&gt;Uber One will replace Eats Pass, the food delivery version of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/30/18042120/uber-ride-pass-monthly-subscription-cheap-fare"&gt;the company’s first customer subscription product&lt;/a&gt; launched in 2018. For $24.99 a month, Uber Pass subscribers get 10 percent off rides and 5 percent off delivery orders. Now, Eats Pass members will be automatically upgraded to Uber One at the start of their next billing cycle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q9FMni"&gt;For Uber Pass members, there will be no changes to the plan, but if they wish to join Uber One, they would need to cancel Uber Pass and sign up for Uber One.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787130/uber-one-membership-subscription-discounts-ride-food-delivery"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787130/uber-one-membership-subscription-discounts-ride-food-delivery</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-17T09:10:07-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-17T09:10:07-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple will sell you iPhone parts to fix your own phone at home</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cG_qw6mF0FCWwz8VDwJ9he1CJkg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70154312/cgartenberg_210917_4762_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JyEEYp"&gt;Apple is opening up iPhones and Macs to DIY repairs. The company plans to &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/11/apple-announces-self-service-repair/"&gt;start selling parts and tools&lt;/a&gt; and offering instructions on how to repair Apple products at home, without having to bring them into a store or a third-party repair shop. Apple plans to start with the iPhone 12 and 13, followed by Macs with M1 chips. You’ll be able to replace the iPhone’s display, battery, and camera using parts from Apple at first, with other options coming later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ZtWhO"&gt;This is a huge shift from Apple, which has historically been resistant to the right-to-repair movement and from any repairs happening outside of its own stores. Even this week, Apple was walking back software that prevented Face ID from working if customers replaced their own screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TXbQYL"&gt;Apple is calling the program “Self Service Repair,” and it’ll launch “early next year” in the US and then expand to other countries. The company says the program is only meant for “individual technicians with the knowledge and experience to repair electronic devices,” and that most customers should still go to a professional. But Apple is at least now offering an option for the customers who do feel comfortable undertaking the repair on their own. Critically, making these repairs yourself won’t void a device’s warrant, &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/11/17/beginning-next-year-apple-will-mail-you-parts-and-tools-to-fix-your-iphone-and-mac-at-home/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, although damaging your device in the process still might.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UG1Bwd"&gt;The change also helps to further entrench Apple in the repair process. The company already has a program to sell “genuine” parts to third-party repair shops, and today’s announcement makes it all the more likely customers will buy full-priced parts from Apple — parts that won’t trip off iPhone systems that try to prevent unauthorized components — rather than looking for aftermarket options in the limited circumstances where that might be possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6iNdlv"&gt;Apple says it plans to sell “more than 200 individual parts and tools.” The company will also offer repair manuals that customers can review before buying the parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7DVwdV"&gt;Pricing for the parts and tools hasn’t been announced. Apple says customers can receive a recycling credit for returning their used part after completing a repair.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787144/apple-home-repair-iphone-mac-parts-tools-instructions"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787144/apple-home-repair-iphone-mac-parts-tools-instructions</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-17T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-17T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Nintendo’s latest Pokémon remakes are perfectly fine versions of great games</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/N4vstpPi_Pq0Vn3SRwe8DKIQQww=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70154231/BDSP_Screenshot_32.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bcIE68"&gt;The past week or so has shown just how challenging the concept of a remake or remaster can be, whether we’re talking about games or TV shows. The remastered &lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto&lt;/em&gt; trilogy, for instance, seemed like a slam dunk but has instead turned into a meme factory. Netflix’s take on &lt;em&gt;Cowboy Bebop&lt;/em&gt;, meanwhile, has had to thread a tricky needle of remaining true to the anime while also standing on its own. So, while it may seem like faint praise, it’s important to say this about Nintendo’s latest &lt;em&gt;Pokémon&lt;/em&gt; releases, which bring the classic &lt;em&gt;Diamond&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Pearl &lt;/em&gt;to the Switch: they’re perfectly acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EOIvTn"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pokémon Brilliant Diamond&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Shining Pearl&lt;/em&gt;, as they’re called, are slightly upgraded versions of the games that first graced the Nintendo DS in 2006. The new versions follow the same simple story — you’re a budding pokémon trainer who ends up having to thwart a mysterious organization known as Team Galactic — in the beautiful Sinnoh region. You once again start out by choosing between a penguin, fire monkey, and a turtle with a twig growing out of its head. When they first came out, &lt;em&gt;Diamond&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Pearl &lt;/em&gt;really tested just how far the &lt;em&gt;Pokémon&lt;/em&gt; formula could stretch. They didn’t add all that much, and the story wasn’t particularly memorable, and yet… I couldn’t stop playing. What they lacked in originality the games made up for with a rock-solid adventure and lots of cool creatures to collect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5oJQOy"&gt;This all remains true with the remakes. I’ve played through the first few hours of &lt;em&gt;Brilliant Diamond&lt;/em&gt;, and it feels a lot like what I remember from the DS days. The most notable difference, of course, is how the game looks. Things are fully 3D, but instead of following in the footsteps of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/13/20962722/pokemon-sword-shield-review-nintendo-switch-launch-date"&gt;the Switch games &lt;em&gt;Sword&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Shield&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, these remakes introduce a new chibi art style reminiscent of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/10/28/13457446/world-of-final-fantasy-game-rpg-ps4-vita"&gt;&lt;em&gt;World of Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZUfstLb8ME17yVs_uZsESKEQOwo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23020132/Pokemon_Brilliant_Diamond_and_Shining_Pearl___Screenshot_17.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="rpf3lZ"&gt;One the one hand, the graphics actually feel pretty true to the originals; characters have big heads and teeny tiny bodies while running around the field, and then inexplicably are perfectly proportioned once you hop into battle. But it’s also a bit of an acquired taste. Personally I’m not all that into the super-deformed character designs, and there are some other visual quirks, like flat textures and strangely shiny floors inside just about every building. It looks alright in handheld mode, though I found it pretty ugly blown up on a television set. I was also struck by how small the towns and routes felt compared to more recent entries. But hey, at least the pokémon look normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UDqH1x"&gt;If the visuals don’t bother you, the good news is that gameplay-wise this remake is great — and that’s because it changes very little from the original. If you’ve become bored by the &lt;em&gt;Pokémon&lt;/em&gt; formula over the years, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22698264/pokemon-legends-arceus-trailer-nintendo-switch"&gt;you should probably wait for next year’s &lt;em&gt;Arceus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which looks to introduce something of an open world to the series. But if the standard &lt;em&gt;Pokémon&lt;/em&gt; structure is still enough to excite you, there are few better options. The game even adds a few more modern quality-of-life improvements, most notably having EXP share — an item that lets all of the pokémon in your party, not just the one battling, earn experience — as a built-in feature from the get-go. This massively reduces the tedium of building a team and makes things like evolving a Magikarp into a less frustrating experience. There’s also an improved smartwatch that lets you use moves like Cut — necessary for bypassing certain obstacles — without having to teach them to a pokémon, which was always a pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="unAfcq"&gt;In a world where remakes, remasters, and reboots are both ubiquitous and often quite bad, it’s nice to have a game that doesn’t mess with things too much. Sure, I could’ve done with a different visual style. But there’s something really comforting about slipping back into a familiar experience and losing a few hours to the pleasant routine of catching them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7KlYN0"&gt;&lt;small&gt;Pokémon Brilliant Diamond &lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;Shining Pearl&lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt; launch on the Nintendo Switch on November 19th.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22786132/pokemon-brilliant-diamond-shining-pearl-nintendo-switch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22786132/pokemon-brilliant-diamond-shining-pearl-nintendo-switch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-17T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-17T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tidal launches free streaming and splits HiFi into two plans</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/G4_EgE-Rse6V8lBcVzt-nuFxGEM=/0x0:2200x1467/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70154162/tidal.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Tidal&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JYK8xi"&gt;Tidal is making some significant changes to its subscription plans and introducing a free, ad-sponsored tier for the first time. The new Tidal Free plan launches today, is exclusive to the US, and the company says it offers “access to our entire music catalog and playlists, with limited interruptions.” Streaming quality tops out at 160kbps, however, so it’s not much for Tidal’s paid options on that front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TGUnaR"&gt;As for those paid subscriptions, Tidal is upgrading its standard paid plan to include lossless and high-resolution audio. Now known as Tidal HiFi, the $9.99-per-month tier offers the improved music quality (up to 1411kbps) and also adds “offline capabilities, access to features like Tidal Connect and My Activity, which provides individualized daily listening insights.” With Apple Music and Amazon Music Unlimited now offering lossless at no extra cost, Tidal had little choice here but to match those services. The service, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/4/22313108/square-inc-tidal-majority-stake-jack-dorsey-jay-z"&gt;now owned by Square&lt;/a&gt;, was among the first to make a big lossless push. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t9J1tu"&gt;But the company is also adding a new, third plan called Tidal HiFi Plus. It costs $19.99 monthly and will be home to Tidal’s most premium audio content. You’ll need HiFi Plus for “best-in-class immersive sound formats” including Dolby Atmos and Sony 360 Audio tracks. Tidal’s Master Quality Authenticated (MQA) recordings are also reserved exclusively for the higher HiFi tier. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0lrxHv"&gt;Separate from its consumer-facing news, Tidal is announcing some new initiatives it hopes could provide artists with some additional revenue from the fractions of scraps they normally receive from music streaming services. Here’s what those will entail, according to the company:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="JQbhGG"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Direct-to-artist payments:&lt;/strong&gt; Beginning today, TIDAL will launch monthly direct-to-artist payments. This innovative program will give artists access to an additional payment stream, so they can benefit directly from their biggest fans on TIDAL. Each month, a percentage of HiFi Plus subscribers’ membership fees will be directed towards their top streamed artist, which they will see in their activity feed. This direct-to-artist payment is in addition to their streaming royalties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t8aabG"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fan-centered royalties:&lt;/strong&gt; Starting in 2022, TIDAL is taking a different approach on royalties. In this new model, royalties attributed to HiFi Plus subscribers will not be aggregated. Rather, royalties will be paid based on the actual streaming activity of individual HiFi Plus subscribers as opposed to the industry accepted method of aggregating streams, empowering fans to play a larger role in the success of their favorite artists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="PlqaYh"&gt;These new efforts sound promising in concept and definitely shake things up — particularly the fan-centered royalties — but keep in mind that Tidal is only pulling this extra money from subscribers on its top-tier HiFi Plus plan. The regular Premium / HiFi plan isn’t contributing to direct-to-artist payments or fan-centered royalties. In an unsurprising bit of corporate synergy, Tidal says it’ll be working with Square, Cash app, and also PayPal “to ensure quick and seamless payouts to artists globally.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ODbrdT"&gt;All of this comes as Spotify HiFi, announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295273/spotify-hifi-announced-lossless-streaming-hd-quality"&gt;nearly nine months ago&lt;/a&gt; at this point, has still yet to launch. Spotify has only said that its lossless tier is expected to be available “later this year.” The company has made no official comment on whether, like its competitors, it will also support Dolby Atmos and other new music formats.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787051/tidal-free-hifi-plus-announced-features-artist-payments"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787051/tidal-free-hifi-plus-announced-features-artist-payments</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-17T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-17T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Medical photography is failing patients with darker skin</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iaXVgduCMKFTJvFhte5O6QVUmSs=/0x0:4724x3149/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70154198/1041978360.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Universal Images Group via Getty&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Even medical stock photos only depict white people&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="GRYf5M"&gt;Doctors aren’t usually in the business of publishing photography guides. But Jenna Lester, a dermatologist at the University of California San Francisco, was growing frustrated with the poor quality images she’d receive of her dark-skinned patients. It wasn’t just a cosmetic issue — the bad photos meant darker-skinned people weren’t getting the same quality of care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0MWRk6"&gt;So in January, Lester co-authored a &lt;a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/bjd.19811"&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;British Journal of Dermatology&lt;/em&gt; that gives a step-by-step guide to photographing skin of color accurately in clinical settings. Lester, who herself is Black, said, “I feel like these issues and my life is constantly me saying, ‘Hey, what about us?’ ‘What about these patients?’” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cFWq9h"&gt;Medical photographs are vital to documenting disease in textbooks and journals and training medical students. If they’re not accurate — if, for example, they misidentify important characteristics like texture and color — doctors don’t get as clear a picture of what disease looks like on different people. It then becomes harder for medical professionals to spot potential conditions in their patients. This contributes to disparities in health outcomes for patients of color. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZeK3xz"&gt;“Across different aspects of medicine, patients with darker skin are getting lower access to screening, delayed diagnoses — and when they are diagnosed, it’s more often at a point where the disease is more severe or higher stage,” says Daniel Cho, a plastic surgery fellow at the Children’s Hospital for Philadelphia. For instance, the skin cancer known as melanoma, although comparatively rarer in Black people, is significantly more likely to kill them. The 5-year survival rates in Black and white individuals are 67 percent and 92 percent, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="INhzy9"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“when they are diagnosed, it’s more often at a point where the disease is more severe or higher stage”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="30cVBw"&gt;Bad photos of dark skin aren’t specific to medicine. Bias has plagued photography since the days of film cameras. Before the advent of commercial digital photography in the late 1990s, lab technicians in camera stores would color-calibrate film by comparing a customer’s photos to a standard called a “&lt;a href="https://cjc-online.ca/index.php/journal/article/view/2196/3069"&gt;Shirley Card&lt;/a&gt;.” Named after Shirley Page, the original model who was pictured, these cards were used to ensure the color, hue, and tone of a customer’s image remained consistent and balanced against the so-called default photo. That default was whiteness, as almost all the Shirley Card models were white. This made it harder for photographers to accurately depict details of darker hues. The chemical coatings on photos also weren’t designed to be sensitive to non-Caucasian flesh tones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eUYgNk"&gt;The result was that in photos with dark- and light-skinned people together, the darker-skinned person’s features were often erased, lacking the fine detailing afforded to the fair-skinned people. In the mid-1990s, Kodak began introducing multiracial Shirley Cards in an attempt to expand their global reach, which improved the issue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="izgUjo"&gt;Since then, digital photography technologies have evolved. For instance, cameras that can balance two different skin tones within the same image now exist and make it easier to represent a greater variety of skin tones at the same time. But the idea of whiteness as the standard in photography has prevailed — creating serious problems, especially in medical photography. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="YNVl32"&gt;&lt;q&gt;the idea of whiteness as the standard in photography has prevailed — creating serious problems, especially in medical photography&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TMgKMu"&gt;Within highly visual medical fields like dermatology and plastic surgery, physicians rely heavily on photographs of a patient’s skin to aid in diagnoses and treatment plans. But images of conditions on light skin are overrepresented in medical journals and textbooks. That’s problem number one, Lester says. “Problem number two is if you only see one tone of non-white skin. And problem number three is that if that tone of non-white skin looks nothing like it would in real life, how do we make a diagnosis?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SKoMPv"&gt;The issue of bad photos of dark-skinned patients is widespread. “I see terrible photos all the time of dark skin,” Lester says. “When I’m flipping through a patient’s chart, and I’m trying to monitor disease over time, the photos that other people have taken have not been great.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DopFBG"&gt;For instance, a bad photo of inflammation on dark skin may make the already subtle condition difficult to see. In a person of color, the use of a flash or&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;bad lighting can drown out the problem, and the inflammation may seem to blend into the skin. On the other hand, a well-captured image of the same taken near a window using natural light could allow a clear distinction between healthy and unhealthy skin.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Xcd60"&gt;Lester says the best photos come out of health systems with specialized photography departments, which are rare. Most clinical photos are taken by well-intentioned doctors who haven’t been trained in the nuances of photographing patients of different races. There are fundamental differences in the physics of how light interacts with different skin tones that can make documenting conditions on skin of color more difficult, says Chrystye Sisson, associate professor and chair of the photographic science program at Rochester Institute of Technology, the only such program in the nation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Yr8OS"&gt;Interactions between light, objects, and our eyes allow us to perceive color. For instance, a red object absorbs every wavelength of light except red, which it reflects back into our eyes. The more melanin there is in the skin, the more light it absorbs, and the less light it reflects back. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YmRofG"&gt;“If you wrote with a red pen on white paper, the white paper reflects all those wavelengths back at you to appear white, and the red pen stands out in comparison,” says Sisson. Darker paper, though, absorbs more light. If someone writes with the same pen on that darker paper, the red reflection doesn’t stand out as much. That’s why some red skin conditions like inflammation or rosacea can appear more subtle on darker skin.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="QHceRs"&gt;&lt;q&gt;some red skin conditions like inflammation or rosacea can appear more subtle on darker skin&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IkkI7n"&gt;But standard photographic setups don’t account for those differences. For instance, although many &lt;a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamadermatology/article-abstract/2758218"&gt;medical journals&lt;/a&gt; recommend using flash for photographing patients, it can compromise detail when done on dark skin. The contrast of the bright flash of the camera against dark subjects can make dark things appear darker than they are, reducing detail in dark skin. The reflection of the flash back from the skin can also obscure the skin tone underneath and leave a shine, an effect that is more pronounced on darker skin. “Whatever standard setup you come up with needs to take that into account,” Sisson says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BdiosR"&gt;These biases may also be increasingly cemented within new technologies, like artificial intelligence algorithms that are trained to detect conditions using clinical photographs. Google Health &lt;a href="https://blog.google/technology/health/ai-dermatology-preview-io-2021/"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; in May that it is hoping to pilot an AI-powered dermatology assistant tool to assess skin conditions and provide access to authoritative information on them. The company trained a deep learning algorithm on a set of over 16,000 pictures of various skin conditions. But &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41591-020-0842-3#MOESM1"&gt;only 3.5%&lt;/a&gt; of these cases depicted dark and deep brown skin. Out of these photos of dark skin, it’s impossible to tell how many of them were taken using techniques that make sure they’re truly representative. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i06dMx"&gt;Clinical images are also frequently used in teaching materials, meaning the next generation of medical professionals is being trained with a scarcity of representative photos. And as telehealth becomes increasingly important, patients will need to be taught how to take accurate images of their conditions — which becomes hard when even their doctors don’t know how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vwekeq"&gt;The consequences of these compounded issues are what motivated Lester to compile the set of tips for photographing skin of color in a medical context — instructing people to pay close attention to lighting and choosing the color of background drapes carefully, along with other techniques. Lester hopes that her guidelines will prompt others in the field to question what “standard” practice means and who it was built for and serve as a stepping stone in bridging health equity gaps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="NBxbp8"&gt;“Recognizing that there are nuances and differences is an important first step in making the necessary adjustments to having a photograph that looks representative,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22778114/medical-photography-racial-bias"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22778114/medical-photography-racial-bias</id>
    <author>
      <name>Georgina Gonzalez</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
