<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-15T02:57:18-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T02:57:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T02:57:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>Taiwanese horror game Devotion now back on sale after Steam and GOG controversies</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Devotion" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QsyBJ9WGPtKDbuh8-OWZ_IU1q8c=/0x0:1620x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68966407/Screenshot__756_.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fWMfAD"&gt;Red Candle Games, the Taiwanese studio whose first-person horror game &lt;em&gt;Devotion&lt;/em&gt; has been unavailable to buy following controversy over a reference to Chinese premier Xi Jinping, has put its games up for sale on its own online store. &lt;em&gt;Devotion&lt;/em&gt; and the studio’s first game &lt;em&gt;Detention&lt;/em&gt; are &lt;a href="https://shop.redcandlegames.com"&gt;available to buy now&lt;/a&gt; without DRM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dlCNgA"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Devotion&lt;/em&gt; was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/25/18239937/taiwanese-horror-game-devotion-gone-steam-removed-winnie-the-pooh-meme-china"&gt;pulled from Steam&lt;/a&gt; shortly after its launch in February 2019. The game was critically lauded for its atmosphere and originality, but drew controversy and negative user reviews after users noticed an in-game poster that read, roughly, “Xi Jinping Winnie-the-Pooh moron.” Xi is commonly compared to Winnie the Pooh in online memes, which often meet the ire of China’s online censors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="XpW9lL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How Devotion, Twitch’s hottest horror game, builds on the genre’s legacy","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/22/18236099/devotion-horror-game-steam-twitch-red-candle"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="wgnUij"&gt;At the time, Red Candle Games said it was removing &lt;em&gt;Devotion&lt;/em&gt; for technical and QA-related reasons, and would also “review our game material once again making sure no other unintended materials was inserted in.” The game never returned to Steam, and Red Candle Games later apologized for its “severe art material mistake.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="attwo8"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Devotion&lt;/em&gt; attracted new controversy in December 2020 when CD Projekt Red’s storefront GOG backed out from an agreement to sell the game &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22178453/gog-devotion-cancels-release-cd-projekt-red"&gt;hours after its announcement&lt;/a&gt;. “After receiving many messages from gamers, we have decided not to list the game in our store,” a statement from the store read. “This is a difficult predicament to overcome, but we won’t stop striving,” Red Candle Games said in response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M2Js3n"&gt;With the developer now selling &lt;em&gt;Devotion&lt;/em&gt; for PC and Mac on its own terms, the game’s availability should be assured for the time being. “We hope to provide a direct and simple purchasing channel for players who’re interested in our games,” the studio says in a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/redcandlegames/status/1371335941542060032"&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt;. It’s not immediately clear whether the Xi reference has been removed.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331243/devotion-back-on-sale-red-candle-games-drm-free"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331243/devotion-back-on-sale-red-candle-games-drm-free</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-15T00:15:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-15T00:15:44-04:00</updated>
    <title>Kia shows off first full images of new EV6 electric car</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XxOwdNclyWA9_3dlsEa6_R7fCDU=/0x0:2000x1333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68966167/580833.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vZ6aRl"&gt;Kia has given a first real look at its new EV6 electric car, following some shadowy &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323438/kia-ev6-electric-car-hyundai-apple-platform"&gt;teaser images&lt;/a&gt; that were released last week. Full details of the EV6 won’t be announced until an online event later this month, but the new images do at least reveal what it actually looks like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lxAmrV"&gt;The EV6 has a sporty crossover-inspired design and is the first vehicle to make use of a new design philosophy from Kia that the company calls “Opposites United,” which is comprised of no less than five pillars: “Bold for Nature,” “Joy for Reason,” “Power to Progress,” “Technology for Life,” and “Tension for Serenity.” Kia design chief Karim Habib explains what that means in this video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gMYdwo"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gqrfx2GzOYE?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5vk6lM"&gt;“EV6, as the first dedicated Kia EV, is a showcase of human-centered, progressive design and electrified power. We strongly believe EV6 is a compelling and relevant model for the new EV market,” Habib says in a &lt;a href="https://www.kianewscenter.com/news/kia-reveals-new-design-philosophy-and-full-images-of-ev6/s/ab39d812-3605-4288-99eb-cd3307ad7291"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt;. “With EV6 we aimed to create a distinctive, impactful design by using a combination of sophisticated, high-tech features on pure and rich volumes, while providing a unique space as a futuristic EV.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tz81BU"&gt;Here’s a shot from another angle:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zdeEW4UxkcyM6_vb16gJy2K8ofM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22371164/580834.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="DKk8g9"&gt;And here’s the interior:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/s_mfwbJ_OJTfFMRMF8ycjSNOHW8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22371165/580837.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="8LahwT"&gt;Kia describes the EV6 as its first “dedicated battery electric vehicle,” since its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/4/17320598/kia-niro-ev-production-form-reveal-ambitious-range-electric-crossover"&gt;Niro&lt;/a&gt; has gas/hybrid models as well as the newer version with an electric drivetrain. The EV6 is built around parent company Hyundai’s new E-GMP platform and is the second E-GMP vehicle to have been announced; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22296991/hyundai-ioniq-5-electric-suv-ev-battery-range-specs"&gt;Hyundai unveiled its own Ioniq 5 last month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fa3s9t"&gt;For more technical details, you’ll have to wait for the EV6 to be revealed in full. Kia hasn’t announced a date for the event just yet but says it’ll happen in March, so it won’t be too far off.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331130/kia-ev6-full-images-revealed-design-announcement-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22331130/kia-ev6-full-images-revealed-design-announcement-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-14T18:29:27-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T18:29:27-04:00</updated>
    <title>New Trailers: Infinity Train Book 4, The Serpent, Vanquish and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fUKNPD225HeJIy68Rj_HtLqLPts=/44x0:1481x958/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68964867/trailerz.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T_eiKWvQxZ8&amp;amp;ab_channel=HBOMax" target="_blank"&gt;HBO Max&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Dkqn0b"&gt;So I typically save my binge-watching for after dinner, and usually put something on to unwind before bed. Based on this routine, you can probably surmise that it was a very poor decision to try to get back into &lt;em&gt;Hannibal&lt;/em&gt;— an excellent show, truly, but not “just before bedtime” fare. Eek. But I can’t stop watching, and the chances I may get up earlier to watch before work— haha I couldn’t even finish that sentence. I just can’t do it. My other current show, &lt;em&gt;Servant&lt;/em&gt;, has its season 2 finale this week and honestly, I  have no idea what’s going to happen but Lauren Ambrose is absolutely doing work above and beyond what the show’s uneven writing gives her. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BrJ5Ko"&gt;This week’s trailers are kind of a mish-mash, or in more positive terms, there’s something for everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XvJ4lp"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tK5XoqD_q4g?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="noqKY3"&gt;The Falcon and The Winter Soldier&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="lWxzJ4"&gt;I thought I could not be more ready for &lt;em&gt;The Falcon and the Winter Soldier&lt;/em&gt; and then Marvel went ahead and dropped yet another teaser. Streaming this Friday (!!) March 19th on Disney Plus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xDWW0Z"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/T_eiKWvQxZ8?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="h8MVKE"&gt;Infinity Train Book 4&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="xJy0Uv"&gt;Alas, fans of &lt;em&gt;Infinity Train&lt;/em&gt;, the end is nigh. The first trailer for Book 4 of the animated series, which jumped from Cartoon Network to HBO Max, shows the season will follow two buddies (or &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; they?!) who want to be rock stars but find themselves on the Infinity Train, and have to figure out how to get back home (they both got on at the same time!). Entertainment Weekly has confirmed that this is, in fact, the final season for the quirky show. &lt;em&gt;Infinity Train Book 4&lt;/em&gt; comes to HBO Max April 15th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ON5qxn"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fUElfp3DJ5Y?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=1&amp;amp;start=1" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="SpRpdz"&gt;Vanquish&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="YzMDY7"&gt;Morgan Freeman plays an ex-cop who enlists a former drug courier whose daughter has been kidnapped to take out some serious bad guys. OK, I’m in, why not, it’s Morgan Freeman. &lt;em&gt;Vanquish&lt;/em&gt; will be on-demand and digital April 20th and Blu-ray and DVD on April 27th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Qt60Ft"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TgB7rMuxY-s?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="vvYgHq"&gt;The Serpent&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="wYfvBx"&gt;I watched this trailer about ten times partly because I was so intrigued by the French-language version of &lt;em&gt;House of the Rising Sun&lt;/em&gt; playing in the background (I think &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lCHqObhhMgA&amp;amp;ab_channel=PatrickBreizh"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; is it?). I had never heard of the main character in this movie based on a true story: Charles Sobrahj, a serial killer and con man who preyed on tourists who visited the “hippie trail” in Southeast Asia during the 1970s.  Tahar Rahim, Jenna Coleman, and Billy Howle star in &lt;em&gt;The Serpent&lt;/em&gt;, which hits Netflix April 2nd. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LpUJKr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22326012/new-trailers-serpent-infinity-train-vanquish-falcon-winter-soldier-netflix-marvel-disney-hbo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22326012/new-trailers-serpent-infinity-train-vanquish-falcon-winter-soldier-netflix-marvel-disney-hbo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-14T17:29:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T17:29:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook research reportedly finds small number of users responsible for spreading vaccine doubt</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YNBkiV2TO0vuTbZLZ_P0U34soWc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68964706/mdoying_180118_2249_facebook_0445stills_3.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Michele Doying / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lK5Krc"&gt;Facebook research into “vaccine-hesitant” beliefs has found that a small group of users is driving many of the discussions that may sow doubt or discouragement about taking a vaccine, &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/03/14/facebook-vaccine-hesistancy-qanon/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PC5ENE"&gt;Vaccine hesitancy predates both social media and COVID-19, as the &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/spotlight/ten-threats-to-global-health-in-2019"&gt;World Health Organization reports&lt;/a&gt;, and can derail progress in eradicating vaccine-preventable diseases. The WHO points out that vaccine hesitancy may not be wholly responsible for an the 30 percent increase in measles cases around the world over the past several years, but it played a role in measles’ resurgence. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZkDdsa"&gt;Facebook banned &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21514535/facebook-anti-vaxx-ad-ban-moderation-covid-19-vaccine"&gt;false and misleading ads about vaccines&lt;/a&gt; back in October, weeks before the first coronavirus vaccines were even available. In December, Facebook announced it would remove &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/3/22150425/facebook-covid-19-vaccine-coronavirus-misinformation-ban"&gt;false claims about COVID-19 vaccines&lt;/a&gt;, and began notifying users if they had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22177085/facebook-covid-19-misinformation-notifications"&gt;interacted with a post that had false information&lt;/a&gt;. It’s also taken steps to &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/02/reaching-billions-of-people-with-covid-19-vaccine-information/"&gt;promote authoritative information&lt;/a&gt; about COVID-19 vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YCdyt8"&gt;The research described by the &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt; appears to have information about more of a gray area, for example, if a user mentions on Facebook that their symptoms after receiving a vaccine dose are worse than they planned. Comments like that could be used to better understand the vaccine’s impact, but could also make other users wary, especially if they’re already nervous about the vaccine.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lPqUoW"&gt;The study appears to confirm what many Facebook users (and critics) have long known: that there’s an echo chamber effect that helps spread misinformation on the platform. Content that helps create this effect may not actually run afoul of any of Facebook’s rules, but can quickly metastasize among groups of susceptible users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cidb5v"&gt;Perhaps unsurprisingly, the Facebook researchers found there was significant overlap between users connected to QAnon conspiracy theories — which Facebook has banned from the platform —and the user communities who expressed skepticism about vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DNdpAG"&gt;Facebook spokesperson Dani Lever said in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the company has partnered with more than 60 global health experts, and has studied content related to COVID-19 vaccine and other information to inform its policies— adding that Facebook routinely studies trends that may be part of conversations on its platform, such as voting, bias, hate speech, and nudity so it can continued to refine its products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X8KPMV"&gt;“Public health experts have made it clear that tackling vaccine hesitancy is a top priority in the COVID response, which is why we’ve launched a global campaign that has already connected 2 billion people to reliable information from health experts and remove false claims about COVID and vaccines,” she said. “This ongoing work will help to inform our efforts.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330428/facebook-research-vaccine-hesitancy-doubt-coronavirus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330428/facebook-research-vaccine-hesitancy-doubt-coronavirus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-14T15:14:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T15:14:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>Marvel is going back to press for new print runs of WandaVision-related comics </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yvTLaDJStlsvktg2JhbxRwpRTPE=/0x0:920x613/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68964318/vision_cover.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3fI4Fc"&gt;After the success of its Disney Plus series &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;, Marvel has gone back to press for new print runs of several &lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;-related titles, &lt;a href="https://ew.com/books/wandavision-marvel-classic-scarlet-witch-comics-going-back-to-print/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Entertainment Weekly&lt;/em&gt; reported.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Scarlet Witch&lt;/em&gt; by James Robinson; Steve Englehart’s &lt;em&gt;Vision and Scarlet Witch,&lt;/em&gt; and&lt;em&gt; Vision&lt;/em&gt;, by Tom King and Gabriel Hernandez Walta are all on the list. Marvel also will be increasing its stock of print issues of &lt;em&gt;House of M&lt;/em&gt;, which EW says ran out “almost overnight” after the show debuted in January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vIp2nq"&gt;Fans of the show and comics will appreciate the connections; even though the show didn’t hew exclusively to the plot lines in the comics, there were numerous references in&lt;em&gt; WandaVision&lt;/em&gt; to themes in &lt;em&gt;House of M &lt;/em&gt;and the other comics listed above. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4NzzzX"&gt;As part of our series on getting into comics, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s Chaim Gartenberg wrote a quick synopsis of &lt;em&gt;Vision&lt;/em&gt;, a 12-issue run that looks at what happens if a superhero tries to step back and start a family. He writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="UtCC2k"&gt;The series is great for newcomers to Vision as a character, too: interspersed across the run is a reexamination of pivotal moments in the artificial hero’s career, including his relationship with Wanda, their desire for a family, his time as a familiar-looking White Vision that has lost all his memories, and more. For MCU fans that are more familiar with Vision’s on-screen origin, it’s a good look at the original version of the character.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="n9gSlo"&gt;You can read &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22315580/tom-king-vision-comics-marvel-wandavision-suburbs"&gt;the full review here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qWSbBi"&gt;If you absolutely can’t wait to read or re-read any of the Wanda or Vision comics, there are always the digital versions on Marvel Unlimited and sites like Comixology. There’s no word yet on when the new print issues of the comics will be available. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="hdeATV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"So you want to start reading comics?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22303444/comics-buying-guide-subscription-comixology-marvel-unlimited-dc-universe-infinite"},{"title":"WandaVision finale: where do we go from here? ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/5/22315094/wandavision-finale-marvel-mcu-scarlet-witch-doctor-strange-captain"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330333/marvel-new-print-versions-wandavision-comics-disney"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330333/marvel-new-print-versions-wandavision-comics-disney</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-14T14:34:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T14:34:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>Clubhouse announces accelerator program for creators on its platform</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="In this photo illustration, a Clubhouse app is displayed on a smartphone with the Clubhouse logo in the background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cEPl6xb2BU6dw8AncWKumUou_l0=/0x0:5000x3333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68964197/1231383719.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Thiago Prudêncio/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3S9jOF"&gt;During Clubhouse’s weekly town hall on Sunday, CEO Paul Davison announced the voice-chat app’s first creators program. Clubhouse Creator First will help aspiring hosts and creators on the platform build their audiences, connect with brands, and perhaps most importantly, monetize their shows. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2eolu0"&gt;The accelerator will accept 20 creators, and Clubhouse is taking applications through March 31st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dF2TxR"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Today’s Town Hall Updates:&lt;br&gt;We are launching our first creator accelerator program, Clubhouse Creator First. We are looking to support and equip 20 creators w/ resources they need to bring their ideas and creativity to life. Details and application here: &lt;a href="https://t.co/kmKjQvoUBK"&gt;https://t.co/kmKjQvoUBK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Clubhouse (@joinClubhouse) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/joinClubhouse/status/1371152823631577089?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 14, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="r92N7F"&gt;Clubhouse celebrates its first anniversary on March 17th, and has had quite the inaugural year. Its success particularly among the Silicon Valley VC crowd, has spawned several similar voice-based apps from bigger competitors, i&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22187490/twitter-spaces-test-voice-chat-rooms"&gt;ncluding Twitter Spaces&lt;/a&gt; which was announced late last year, and a similar forthcoming voice app &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276645/facebook-clubhouse-social-audio-app-develop"&gt;believed to be coming from Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IPZs9x"&gt;Davison also said during the Sunday town hall that Clubhouse is embarking on a “world tour,” hosting its first town hall in Italy on Monday. It’s also added some product features that users have been asking for, including link sharing and language filtering. The app also won’t require access to users’ phone contacts anymore, now, users can invite new people to the platform directly by using the person’s phone number. Davison said users can reach out to the company to delete previously-uploaded contacts, and that a tool to allow users to delete contacts from Clubhouse is coming soon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MPHmV5"&gt;Even though Clubhouse remains invite-only and is still not available on Android devices, during a recent funding round it was &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/clubhouse-gets-investment-interest-at-1-billion-valuation"&gt;valued at $1 billion&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RTMncy"&gt;You can sign up for the Clubhouse Creator Accelerator &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/joinClubhouse/status/1371152823631577089?s=20"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330281/clubhouse-accelerator-creators-davison-app"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330281/clubhouse-accelerator-creators-davison-app</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-14T12:58:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T12:58:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket launches for a record ninth time bringing 60 more Starlink satellites into orbit</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket " src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i2_Sr4NAfcWFZjTn2VDO-lXfjKw=/0x96:4200x2896/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68963903/1231200134.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Paul Hennessy/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rAe70S"&gt;A SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket launched the latest batch of 60 Starlink satellites into orbit Sunday, and returned to Earth successfully, landing on its Of Course I Still Love You drone ship in the Atlantic Ocean, &lt;a href="https://www.spacex.com/launches/"&gt;the company announced&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yMiSM3"&gt;Sunday’s mission marked a record ninth flight and landing for this Falcon 9 booster, SpaceX said, which was part of five earlier Starlink launches and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/8/18255060/spacex-crew-dragon-nasa-dm-1-international-space-station-landing-splashdown-atlantic-ocean"&gt;DM-1 mission for its Crew Dragon capsule&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Gkh8HM"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Deployment of 60 Starlink satellites confirmed &lt;a href="https://t.co/AMLK4R9dMn"&gt;pic.twitter.com/AMLK4R9dMn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— SpaceX (@SpaceX) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SpaceX/status/1371055836802387971?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 14, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kTXBo0"&gt;The satellites are part of growing Starlink constellation, which SpaceX is building to provide internet connectivity to rural areas on Earth. The company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/14/21043229/spacex-starlink-satellite-mega-constellation-concerns-astronomy-space-traffic"&gt;has permission to launch 12,000 satellites&lt;/a&gt; as part of the project, and has more than 1,000 in orbit so far. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aOJ4Lv"&gt;Starlink also has some 10,000 users in the beta program it launched last year. The Starlink kit, which comes with a router and antenna, costs $499, with a monthly subscription of $99 for internet speeds between 70 and 130 Mbps. The company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274385/musk-spacex-starlink-deposit-price-satellite-internet"&gt;opened pre-orders for Starlink&lt;/a&gt; in the US, Canada, and UK last month, with a $99 deposit fee. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9oRVzR"&gt;Sunday’s launch from NASA’s Kennedy Space Center was the second in the past few days for SpaceX, which sent another of its Falcon 9 rockets skyward from Cape Canaveral Space Force Station on Thursday. That launch also brought 60 satellites into orbit. The next Starlink launch is tentatively scheduled for March 21st, from Cape Canaveral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T1KBAj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZXwuwk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GE1rDf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330176/spacex-falcon-9-rocket-launch-starlink-satellites-internet"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330176/spacex-falcon-9-rocket-launch-starlink-satellites-internet</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-14T12:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T12:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Honda plans to sell two electric SUVs in the US in the 2024 model year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Honda moves toward more EVs" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/m22w-ZCsZ3P6Uwg1pn6L7U0pElM=/0x0:6000x4000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68963738/1230549990.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Artur Widak/NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1615731822.158600"&gt;Honda has announced it will sell two electric SUVs in the US in the 2024 model year, and plans to introduce hybrid gas-electric versions of its best-selling models. It’s the second Japanese automaker that has recently announced a future EV in the United States;  last month &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22187113/toyota-electric-vehicles-us-suv-debut-hybrids"&gt;Toyota said it plans&lt;/a&gt; its first mass-market electric vehicle by the end of 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wBMQsj"&gt;Dave Gardner, the head of sales for Honda of America, said last week one of the EVs will be an Acura, and the other will be a Honda brand, &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/technology-cd6e144889db43e45566186f92f60481"&gt;according to the &lt;em&gt;Associated Press&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. He said more details would be coming later in 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hkZ2fS"&gt;Japanese automakers— and Toyota in particular— once were the leaders in hybrid vehicles, but have lagged American companies in the all-electric vehicle market in recent years. But with California banning sales of new internal-combustion engine vehicles by 2035, and the Biden administration moving toward taking the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22249237/biden-electric-vehicle-government-fleet-ev"&gt;government vehicle fleet all-electric&lt;/a&gt; along with other plans to reduce emissions, automakers have their EV work cut out for them&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="07zhIC"&gt;Honda plans to make its vehicles in partnership with General Motors, Gardner said during the announcement last week. Honda has lately dominated passenger-car sales in the US, and makes many vehicles with internal combustion engines, Gardner noted, both of which put Honda a bit behind its competitors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c80yhv"&gt;“We’re really good at a couple of things that seem to be going out of vogue today, so there’s no doubt that we have work to start moving quickly in the zero-emission direction,” Gardner said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XXDGV4"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330086/honda-plans-electric-suv-2024-hybrid-toyota-emissions"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330086/honda-plans-electric-suv-2024-hybrid-toyota-emissions</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-14T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to watch the 2021 Grammys online</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Grammy Statue" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cGg9F4uRBDJC0jaZoBQKlwo9UO8=/18x0:5478x3640/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68963660/529168430.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Kurt Krieger/Corbis via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mscfxT"&gt;The 63rd Grammy Awards ceremony will be held Sunday March 14th, as awards show season continues apace despite the coronavirus pandemic. The show will honor the best music of 2020 and all the performers, producers, and behind-the-scenes people who made it happen. As with most of this year’s awards shows, the Grammys look a bit different this year, broadcasting from “in and around” the Los Angeles Convention Center, but without a live audience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Es6DgX"&gt;As is usually the case with awards ceremonies, there’s some controversy around this year’s Grammys. The Weeknd, whose song &lt;em&gt;Blinding Lights&lt;/em&gt; topped music charts around the world in 2020, received zero nominations — the consensus seems to be it had something to do with the anonymous expert committees who get final say in which artists make the cut. The Weeknd said he would boycott the Grammys going forward.  “Because of the secret committees,” he &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/11/arts/music/grammys-the-weeknd-beyonce.html"&gt;told the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, “I will no longer allow my label to submit my music to the Grammys.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SckAmh"&gt;What time do the Grammys start?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="w9pOmL"&gt;The Grammys  start at 8PM ET / 5PM PT on March 14th and will air live on CBS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="4xKR7T"&gt;Who’s Hosting the Grammys? &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="wRWJNE"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Daily Show’&lt;/em&gt;s Trevor Noah will be this year’s host, and awards presenters will include employees of independent music venues that have been hard-hit by the coronavirus pandemic, such as the Apollo Theater in New York, the Station Inn in Nashville, and The Troubador and Hotel Cafe in Los Angeles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="UsE6Av"&gt;How Do I watch the Grammys?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="62bZLw"&gt;In addition to airing live on CBS, the Grammys will stream live on Paramount Plus, CBS’ new streaming service, which has a free one-month trial if you want to check it out. You can also watch the Grammys on &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2FCBS.com&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F14%2F22329964%2Fgrammy-awards-2021-how-to-watch-online" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CBS.com&lt;/a&gt; or the CBS app but you need to sign in with a TV provider (such as Verizon). &lt;a href="http://Grammy.com"&gt;Grammy.com&lt;/a&gt; will air pre-show programming beginning at 3PM ET. And “Grammy Live,” which will have behind-the-scenes content will be on &lt;a href="http://Grammy.com"&gt;Grammy.com&lt;/a&gt; and on Facebook Live via the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/RecordingAcademy/videos/3850046275043092"&gt;Recording Academy’s Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="qGVmWq"&gt;Who’s Performing at this year’s Grammys?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="iFgcc7"&gt;So many people! In addition to Swift, this year’s show will include performances by Bad Bunny, Black Pumas, Cardi B, BTS, Brandi Carlile, DaBaby, Doja Cat, Billie Eilish, Mickey Guyton, Haim, Brittany Howard, Miranda Lambert, Lil Baby, Chris Martin, John Mayer, Megan Thee Stallion, Maren Morris, Post Malone, and Harry Styles. Bruno Mars and Anderson .Paak’s Silk Sonic will also perform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="GWrxrq"&gt;Who’s Nominated?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="SajRrz"&gt;Beyonce leads the pack of artists with nine nominations, followed by Taylor Swift, Dua Lipa, and Roddy Ricch, who have six nominations apiece. You can check out the full &lt;a href="https://www.grammy.com/grammys/awards/63rd-annual-grammy-awards-2020"&gt;list of nominees here.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22329964/grammy-awards-2021-how-to-watch-online"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22329964/grammy-awards-2021-how-to-watch-online</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-14T10:43:15-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T10:43:15-04:00</updated>
    <title>Pi Day is here and Google’s calculator will test how well you know the mathematical constant</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="pi, cc J.Gabás Esteban" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5XJ9u51IFUplRBd-P8QJ8JXote0=/80x0:944x576/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68963486/8476624791_ac7a5a8357_b.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CA2ThF"&gt;It’s Pi Day, the nerdiest of holidays because it’s all about a mathematical constant that represents the ratio of a circle’s circumference to its diameter (yes, sometimes writing majors do pay attention in geometry class). March 14th has become known as Pi Day because it’s written numerically as 3.14 and pi starts at 3.14 ... and goes on indefinitely. Irrational number, indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eOsRDR"&gt;In case you’ve forgotten the digits of pi, Google is celebrating (marking? observing? idk, choose the term that feels right to you) the day with an Easter egg game hidden in its calculator (also: TIL Google will bring up a calculator if you search for “calculator”). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2b6Q73"&gt;The pi symbol in the upper left corner of the calculator should have some twinkling stars around it, and when you click on it, the calculator will show you pi’s first three digits. Type those digits into the calculator in order and hit enter. Next you’ll see pi to four digits, which you repeat into the calculator, and it will show you pi to five digits, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TSi-OoMMxPeJEBSoTIn4yg9Mn_0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22369326/pi_4.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Pi to four digits, as computed by Google’s calculator&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="FWl5jQ"&gt;Is it possible the pi calculator game will go on forever like pi itself does? I mean, I’m working today so I don’t really have time to check (I don’t think I could get away with telling Nilay and Dieter I spent my day punching pi into a calculator in the name of “research” heh), but you should feel free to investigate and report back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="r2bLir"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"It’s Pi Day! Here are 3.14 facts about pi","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2016/3/14/11218914/pi-facts-pi-day-i-did-it-pi-way"},{"title":"Tau Day is here: celebrate tau, not pi, as the true circle constant","url":"https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2018/3/14/17119388/pi-day-pie-math-tau-circle-constant-mathematics-circumference-diameter-radius-holiday-truth"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Py16u3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B4nCqO"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330036/pi-day-google-calculator-math"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330036/pi-day-google-calculator-math</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
