<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-09-15T05:21:18-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-15T05:21:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-15T05:21:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>There’s a new bubbles emoji that’ll go just great with the peach</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DfD5EeSAW2Yi7XjidCkCbNSq420=/0x3:908x608/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69860402/image__3_.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;My editor put together this image disturbingly soon after I pitched this article.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Thomas Ricker&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IwU0Vi"&gt;If I were an emoji sommelier, there’s one pairing I’d definitely be recommending after looking at this year’s 37-strong selection of &lt;a href="http://blog.unicode.org/2021/09/announcing-unicode-standard-version-140.html"&gt;finalized emoji&lt;/a&gt;. And that’s a combination of the new “&lt;a href="https://emojipedia.org/bubbles/"&gt;bubbles&lt;/a&gt;” emoji with the existing “peach.” The former emoji has just been finalized with version 14.0 of the Unicode Standard, but the collection has been public &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578697/new-emoji-14-0-finalists-unicode-consortium"&gt;since earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lt8S7Y"&gt;The reason is simple. Peach has long pulled double duty as the internationally recognized symbol for the human butt, making “butt bubbles” an elegant euphemism for farts. Sure, you’ve long been able to tell a similar visual story by combining the peach with the gust of wind emoji (which I now see is technically called “&lt;a href="https://emojipedia.org/dashing-away/"&gt;dashing away&lt;/a&gt;”). But now you’ve got more options. Like if you wanted to symbolize the act of emitting gas in a bath, or swimming pool, you monster.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Emoji shown in the prior image, in addition to a melting face, face with hand over mouth, face with eye peeking through fingers, saluting face, face with dotted lines around it, face holding back tears, as well as heart hands, snapping fingers, pointing index finger, and handshakes, all with different skin tones." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CwRPFh-9t83V-nILuDkvUtE7wH0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22719624/emojipedia_14_draft_world_emoji_day_july_2021.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://blog.emojipedia.org/new-emojis-in-2021-2022/" target="_blank"&gt;Emojipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new emoji.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Yw6J0F"&gt;The list, which is &lt;a href="https://blog.emojipedia.org/whats-new-in-unicode-14-0/"&gt;nicely summarized by &lt;em&gt;Emojipedia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, also includes new faces like “biting lip” and “saluting face.” Unfortunately for &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.quora.com%2FWhy-do-English-people-salute-magpies&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F15%2F22675134%2Funicode-emoji-version-14-bubbles-saluting-face-biting-lip-2021" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;English people looking to ward off bad luck&lt;/a&gt;, there isn’t yet a magpie emoji to pair the latter with. New hand gestures include a pair of hands creating the shape of a heart, and a hand pointing towards the screen. As part of this release, handshakes between hands of different skin tones are now officially supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yo3Ufl"&gt;Finally, there are also new gender options for pregnancy, including emoji for “pregnant person” and “pregnant man.” A new “person with crown” joins the existing “prince” and “princess” emoji.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oUgHkc"&gt;Now that the list of emoji has been finalized, it’s up to the major platform holders to add the designs into their software, which for most is likely to happen next year between January and August, according to &lt;em&gt;Emojipedia&lt;/em&gt;. If you’re interested in learning about how emoji are made, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s own Jay Peters was involved in the creation of this year’s “bubbles” and “saluting face” emoji, and previously submitted proposals for “yawning face” and “waffle.” You can read all about the process he went through &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21327599/how-to-make-emoji-yawning-face-waffle-proposal-unicode"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BhinyE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6H3oko"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/15/22675134/unicode-emoji-version-14-bubbles-saluting-face-biting-lip-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/15/22675134/unicode-emoji-version-14-bubbles-saluting-face-biting-lip-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-14T21:09:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-14T21:09:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nintendo finally adds Bluetooth audio to the Switch in new software update</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QfbsuIF4qKyfEGGIezmG2oYo_YA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69859425/jbareham_180301_2346_nintendo_switch_0034_zelda.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="i8DIv7"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1437930124490457088?s=20"&gt;Nintendo has surprise-announced&lt;/a&gt; that Bluetooth audio support has come to the Switch through a software update. The ability to use Bluetooth headphones to listen to game audio has been a conspicuously missing feature &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/1/12/14237060/nintendo-switch-console-launch-date-price-announced"&gt;since the console launched in 2017&lt;/a&gt;, so it’s great to finally have it — though there are some limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GnRnpc"&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/55973"&gt;a Nintendo support article&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll be limited to using two wireless controllers if you’ve got a Bluetooth headset attached. The system also won’t support Bluetooth microphones, which isn’t necessarily surprising given that Nintendo’s own voice chat system relies on an app running on your phone. Still, it’s a bummer for people who play games with their own built-in voice chat abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="BPvUY0"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;The latest &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NintendoSwitch?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#NintendoSwitch&lt;/a&gt; update is now available, including the ability to pair Bluetooth devices for audio output.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;For more information, including restrictions on some features while using Bluetooth Audio, please visit the support page: &lt;a href="https://t.co/vzAB6lZTDu"&gt;https://t.co/vzAB6lZTDu&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/6J5xcDl5kU"&gt;pic.twitter.com/6J5xcDl5kU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Nintendo of America (@NintendoAmerica) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1437930124490457088?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DqJk5J"&gt;People have gone through great lengths to get wireless audio on their Switch (we even said that it’d be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/7/22315790/nintendo-switch-pro-4k-oled-upgraded-what-we-want"&gt;a great selling point for a Switch Pro&lt;/a&gt;): there &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/7/13/17570350/nintendo-switch-wireless-headphones-bluetooth-audio-support-adapter"&gt;have been accessories&lt;/a&gt; that acted as Bluetooth audio adapters, and some headsets like the SteelSeries Arctis 1 Wireless &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/3/20836987/steelseries-arctis-1-wireless-headset-usb-c-nintendo-switch-gaming"&gt;came with a dongle&lt;/a&gt; that took advantage of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2017/10/20/16507816/nintendo-wireless-usb-headphones-switch-update-firmware"&gt;Switch’s support for USB wireless headphones&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4Rl2m3"&gt;Having Bluetooth audio built-in is a big deal, then — especially considering that Nintendo’s Pro Controller, unlike many others, doesn’t include a headphone jack (though it’s worth noting that the &lt;a href="https://mashable.com/article/ps5-xbox-series-x-how-to-use-wireless-headphones"&gt;PS5 and Xbox Series don’t natively support Bluetooth audio&lt;/a&gt;). Even with the aforementioned limitations, the feature seems to be well-supported: Nintendo says that the Switch can save up to 10 connected devices, and says that it should work with both the regular Switch and the Switch Lite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VqRTYD"&gt;My colleague Jay Peters was able to connect his AirPods Pro to his base Switch and a Switch Lite without much trouble. In the settings menu, there’s a section for “Bluetooth Audio,” and you can pair your headphones from there by following the instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="zAvZt3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;My colleague’s AirPods Pro worked well with WarioWare: Get It Together&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HqUvIw"&gt;Jay’s AirPods Pro worked well in a few rounds of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/20/22632465/warioware-get-it-together-nintendo-switch-preview"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WarioWare: Get It Together&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, with no noticeable delay — something that’s particularly important for &lt;em&gt;WarioWare’s&lt;/em&gt; fast-paced, twitchy microgames. While using his base Switch, Jay also reports that after a cold boot, his AirPods Pro paired nearly instantly after selecting them again in the settings menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BcEzMT"&gt;However, Sean Hollister’s second-generation Switch (not a Lite) had trouble finding and connecting to any Bluetooth devices whatsoever. He got an Arctis Pro Wireless to connect after rebooting the Switch three times, but most attempts ended in failure, including with a set of first-gen Amazon Echo Buds and Wyze Buds Pro, a Bluetooth adapter for the Bose QC25 and an LG TV set. While some of them would&lt;em&gt; sometimes&lt;/em&gt; appear available for pairing, the gaming system spit out an “Unable to find Bluetooth audio devices” message even after repeated attempts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kYPVAs"&gt;&lt;a href="https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/22525/~/nintendo-switch-system-updates-and-change-history#current"&gt;According to the changelog&lt;/a&gt;, the update also adds some features to make wired internet more useful. The Switch will be able to stay connected to the internet even in sleep mode if it’s hardwired in, seemingly either through an adapter or the built-in LAN port on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/6/22456337/nintendo-switch-oled-model-specs-date-price"&gt;upcoming Nintendo Switch OLED dock&lt;/a&gt;. Nintendo says that this will help the console download content while it’s asleep, and that the feature will be on by default. Oh, and also you may have to do &lt;a href="https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/55980"&gt;firmware updates&lt;/a&gt; for the dock with the built-in LAN port. I wouldn’t expect those to be as exciting as this update though.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22674704/nintendo-switch-bluetooth-audio-software-update"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22674704/nintendo-switch-bluetooth-audio-software-update</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-14T20:21:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-14T20:21:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>Where are Apple’s new Macs? Here’s what we’re still expecting Apple to announce this year   </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="It uses TouchID for biometrics. Overall the hardware is identical to the last model" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b3eRLzXafQlJF-PIMmYt6XADG7I=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69859437/vpavic_4291_20201113_0429.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="W5nXzy"&gt;Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22663657/apple-iphone-13-pro-ipad-mini-watch-event-biggest-announcements"&gt;“California Streaming” event&lt;/a&gt; was packed with announcements, from the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22666802/iphone-13-specs-price-release-date-apple-camera"&gt;iPhone 13&lt;/a&gt; and forthcoming &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22667395/apple-watch-series-7-price-specs-redesign-announcement"&gt;Apple Watch Series 7&lt;/a&gt; to a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22667216/ipad-mini-6-price-specs-release-date-features-apple"&gt;sixth-gen iPad Mini&lt;/a&gt;. We expected much of this, yet, there were a number of things &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22663715/apple-iphone-13-event-rumors-announcements-california-streaming"&gt;we had anticipated&lt;/a&gt; that Apple might announce but didn’t, including new MacBook Pros and next-gen AirPods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gvt4P8"&gt;However, it looks like there’s still hope they may make an appearance soon, especially given that October is historically when Apple will showcase new Macs. According to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;’s reliable Apple-watcher, Mark Gurman, Apple will likely &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/markgurman/status/1437140403803672581"&gt;hold at least one more&lt;/a&gt; online event within the next “several weeks,” which means Apple may still reveal the no-shows from today before the end of 2021. Here are some of the more noteworthy omissions we expect to see in the months ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="cLH8qg"&gt;New MacBook Pros&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="jFiS2O"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22441805/apple-macbook-pro-2021-redesign-chip-magsafe-sd-card-slot-hdmi-port"&gt;redesigned 14-inch and 16-inch MacBook Pros&lt;/a&gt; powered by a new &lt;a href="https://www.tomsguide.com/news/apple-m1x-vs-m2-chip-what-we-know-so-far-and-what-it-means-for-new-macbooks"&gt;M1X chip&lt;/a&gt; — the rumored name for an enhanced variant of Apple’s M1 chip that made its debut last year — could make an appearance as early as next month, Gurman predicts. Rumor has it the new laptops will reportedly feature a flat-edged redesign and the return of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/22/22244011/apple-new-macbook-air-design-magsafe-charger-report"&gt;magnetic MagSafe charger&lt;/a&gt;, as well as the reintroduction of previously excised inputs like the HDMI port and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/22/22244398/apple-2021-macbook-pro-sd-card-slot-report-ports-refresh"&gt;SD card slot&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="7vfx8O"&gt;New Mac Minis, iMacs, and Mac Pro workstations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="NkHzJz"&gt;After Apple unveils the MacBook Pro, Gurman &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22441805/apple-macbook-pro-2021-redesign-chip-magsafe-sd-card-slot-hdmi-port"&gt;also speculates&lt;/a&gt; we may see an upgraded Mac Mini, a bigger iMac, an updated Mac Pro workstation, and even a “new low-end MacBook Pro.” Each machine will also be reportedly powered by the next generation of Apple’s in-house chips, which will “will greatly outpace the performance and capabilities of the current M1 chips,” according to Gurman’s anonymous sources. Still, there’s no guarantee Apple will unveil these before the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="blmZS4"&gt;Next-gen AirPods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="XYABES"&gt;It was &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/09/12/kuo-airpods-3-apple-event-tuesday/"&gt;heavily rumored&lt;/a&gt; that Apple would unveil the third generation of AirPods during its iPhone 13 event, so it was a huge surprise when the company didn’t. It’s possible, however, that we could still see these make their debut before the holiday season starts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MMWMyT"&gt;When they do arrive, the new AirPods will &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586507/apple-airpods-2021-refresh-rumor-iphone-se-2022-5g-15-details"&gt;reportedly boast&lt;/a&gt; some of the most significant changes in form since their 2016 debut. It’s likely the new pair will mirror the AirPods Pro in design, with a new case and shorter stems. However, that may be where the similarities between the two end — noise cancellation, for example, may remain exclusive to the Pro model. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2ZjAfT"&gt;The new AirPods are expected to retail anywhere between $150 and $200, and it’s not clear yet whether Apple will sell two different versions — one with and one without a wireless charging case — like it does with the current non-Pro AirPods. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="j7cEfE"&gt;macOS Monterey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="GyvvHU"&gt;During Tuesday’s keynote, Apple announced that the next iteration of its smartwatch operating system, watchOS 8, will launch alongside &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22666881/apple-ios-ipados-15-features-release-date-update"&gt;iOS 15 and iPadOS 15&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22667046/apple-watchos-8-feature-release-date"&gt;September 20th&lt;/a&gt;. macOS users, however, are still in the dark as to when, exactly, they might see the official release of macOS Monterey, the successor to macOS Big Sur. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wACDT6"&gt;macOS Monterey — which was first introduced as a free update during &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22461782/apple-wwdc-2021-recap-biggest-announcements-ios-15-macos-monterey-ipados"&gt;WWDC 2021&lt;/a&gt; and has been testing in public beta &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22557880/apple-macos-public-beta-facetime-safari-updates"&gt;since July&lt;/a&gt; — is still presumingly set to arrive in the fall, which what’s listed &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fmacos%2Fmonterey-preview%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F14%2F22674369%2Fapple-iphone-13-event-2021-announcements-missing-m1x-macbook-pros-airpods-3-macos-monterey" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on Apple’s website&lt;/a&gt;. The update brings improvements to FaceTime, Safari, and a slew of other apps. Monterey will also introduce features such as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/27/22596970/apple-macos-monterey-live-text-intel-processors"&gt;Live Text&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22523613/macos-monterey-wwdc-apple-ipad"&gt;Universal Control&lt;/a&gt;, a feature that allows you to control and quickly move files across multiple Apple devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YUncrx"&gt;Given the lack of Mac updates during Tuesday’s event, it seems possible that Apple could announce the release date of Monterey during the rumored event in October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="f0QJze"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to install the macOS Monterey public beta","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22558991/macos-monterey-how-to-install-public-beta"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22674369/apple-iphone-13-event-2021-announcements-missing-m1x-macbook-pros-airpods-3-macos-monterey"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22674369/apple-iphone-13-event-2021-announcements-missing-m1x-macbook-pros-airpods-3-macos-monterey</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
      <name>Brandon Widder</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-14T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-14T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Holmes trial gets into the Excel nitty-gritty</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Theranos Founder Elizabeth Holmes Attends Criminal Trial" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pYFWVJ_fUh8hNfAOON_3x81Y630=/0x0:4000x2667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69859367/1235132476.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;David Odisho / Getty&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;But will the technical jargon overwhelm the jurors?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="0hR02D"&gt;It was around the time that the defense counsel referred to “deferred revenue” that I began to feel genuinely bad for the members of the jury in the wire fraud trial of Elizabeth Holmes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0tIy8A"&gt;Tuesday’s testimony involved the nuances of accounting, how quality control works in labs, and way too many Excel spreadsheets. I get it — you have to show the financials to show that Theranos was in a tricky financial position. And you have to show how the labs were failing in order to establish that they were failing &lt;em&gt;and that Holmes knew it.&lt;/em&gt; But go through this too fast, and you risk confusing people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="cHqKlP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Every scam is, at bottom, about the same thing: getting money&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="D911L3"&gt;The case’s first witness, Theranos’s corporate controller, Danise Yam (she also goes by So Han Spivey), gave testimony that was crucial for making the government’s case. Every scam is, at bottom, about the same thing: getting money. If Elizabeth Holmes committed wire fraud, as the government alleges, it would have been with the goal of getting more cash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7FvvhM"&gt;To that end, prosecutor Robert Leach had Yam go through a series of Excel spreadsheets, often attached to emails. There were two major cash crunches, Yam testified: one in 2009, and another in 2013, when the cash position “started to get a bit tight, not to the extent of 2009,” but enough that Yam was sending updates to Holmes and Balwani on a weekly basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wECBIH"&gt;In 2013, Theranos was burning about $2 million a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tjRX5m"&gt;In the financial statements for 2012, there is no line for revenue — because there was none. There’s none in 2013 either. This is not, in and of itself, especially damning, but it does paint a picture of a money-losing company on the ropes; by 2012, Theranos had lost $161 million over its lifetime, and it lost another $92 million in 2013. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="qLhnGz"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Not only did Yam not provide numbers for this, she didn’t know where these other numbers came from&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="reoHeC"&gt;In the course of working at Theranos, Yam consulted with Aranca, an analytics firm, to price stock options for Holmes and other employees. To do this, she consulted with Holmes, because Holmes had “the best information” about what financial projections to give to Aranca. In one email from Yam to Holmes, Yam asks to use numbers she’s previously used. Holmes writes back, estimating that 2015 revenue will be about $100 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VpeD1K"&gt;This was all fine and sort of boring, until another document was introduced, one Yam hadn’t seen before. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b2qUdn"&gt;This document, Leach said, had been given to investors. It showed revenue projections of $140 million in revenue in 2015, and $990 million in 2016. Not only did Yam not provide numbers for this, she didn’t know where these other numbers came from. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RdDBIe"&gt;Look, &lt;em&gt;that’s weird.&lt;/em&gt; Let’s say you’re giving lower numbers to the people who price your stock options. That means that your options will be worth more if the higher numbers — the ones you gave to your investors — are right! On the other hand, let’s say those higher numbers you gave to your investors are wrong, and the lower numbers you used to price your shares are right. That, um, seems like maybe you lied to the investors in order to get their money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bf2rFI"&gt;The discrepancy here doesn’t establish intent — the government has to show that Holmes &lt;em&gt;knowingly lied&lt;/em&gt; — but it doesn’t look good. Which is probably why the defense counsel got up to talk about deferred revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="8IEOdP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Theranos’ situation wasn’t as bad as it looked, Wade argued&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QOcvgN"&gt;Lance Wade, Holmes’ lawyer, didn’t exactly &lt;em&gt;define&lt;/em&gt; deferred revenue, which is the accounting world term for advance payments for goods or services that aren’t yet delivered. (If the goods or services aren’t delivered, a company may have to give that money back; deferred revenue shows up as a liability on the balance sheet until the work gets done.) In response to Wade’s questioning, Yam says she provided Sunny Balwani — Holmes’ co-defendant, being tried separately — with Theranos’ annual deferred revenue estimate: $169 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kXWhuf"&gt;So Theranos’ situation wasn’t as bad as it looked, Wade argued: money was coming in from deals with Safeway and Walgreens and some other companies — Theranos just couldn’t mark it as revenue on its books. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SDr5DD"&gt;Okay, but what about the mismatched projections? Like, I’m not a math whiz, but $100 million, the 2015 projection given for stock option pricing, and $140 million, the 2015 projection given to investors, &lt;em&gt;are different numbers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VMczSE"&gt;I didn’t hear anything satisfying to explain that. Wade instead made the argument that different accounting practices can lead to different outcomes — pointing to another part of the document the Aranca consultants had prepared for Theranos as proof. See, one way of valuing Theranos meant it was worth $1.9 billion; another way meant it was worth $9.5 billion. This is not quite the same thing as using different numbers when you’re speaking to different audiences, though!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="qK0APW"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Theranos employees couldn’t list the company on their LinkedIn, or describe their responsibilities&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="33XbpR"&gt;After Yam stepped down, former Theranos lab associate Erika Cheung took the stand. She’d joined Theranos directly after UC Berkeley, and at first had been “starstruck” by Holmes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YNuiAk"&gt;The secrecy started immediately, in the job interviews where neither Holmes nor Balwani would say exactly what Theranos did. Cheung was presented with a non-disclosure agreement on her very first day. Then, Holmes’ brother, Christian, made it clear that Theranos employees couldn’t list the company on their LinkedIn, or describe their responsibilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gmQhRs"&gt;Cheung was only at Theranos six months before she quit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PS85Nh"&gt;Before that, though, Cheung did work on validation, a series of experiments that were run to make sure the results were accurate and precise. Samples of Cheung’s own blood were run as part of validation testing. Though traditional methods showed she was in the normal range for vitamin D, Theranos’ machines consistently showed that she was deficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sva3Aa"&gt;Cheung also discussed a similar kind of testing that is used to calibrate equipment on a daily basis, quality control. As part of the process, you take a sample with results you already know, and run it through the machine. If the machine’s results don’t match the sample, you troubleshoot to see where things went wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="LHfqBh"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It was a lot to throw at people all in one day&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rht8EP"&gt;But Cheung’s testimony called into question how good the quality control was. She’d emailed an internal helpline because, despite troubleshooting her machine, she couldn’t get it to work properly for the vitamin D test. This chain is escalated to Balwani and Holmes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s6mCCQ"&gt;The problem was resolved, but not in a way Cheung was comfortable with. See, the vitamin D reading came from six data points, and to get the machine to pass quality control, two “outlier values” had to be discarded. That was when we broke for the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wuXfbp"&gt;Cheung did a better job than either the defense or prosecution lawyers at clearly explaining technical concepts, but even so, it was a lot to throw at people all in one day, &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; after the bickering over accounting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="VCUrmO"&gt;Given the presumption of innocence and the standard of reasonable doubt, confusion works in Holmes’ favor. If the jurors get lost, it’s easier for Holmes to win — because if &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; can’t keep this all straight, then it might seem reasonable she wouldn’t have been able to, either. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22674657/elizabeth-holmes-theranos-trial-wire-fraud-financial-witness"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22674657/elizabeth-holmes-theranos-trial-wire-fraud-financial-witness</id>
    <author>
      <name>Elizabeth Lopatto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-14T19:51:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-14T19:51:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>Should you wait for the Apple Watch Series 7?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ILfKIWosxYvizGkz0Si0pY9KsZE=/141x0:1640x999/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69859316/lcimg_5ab83a83_d836_4e82_b8f5_f6ccdf0eee9f.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Apple Watch Series 7 has a larger display, and looks like an Apple Watch.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ajPTaI"&gt;One of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/29/22647766/apple-watch-series-7-rumors-screen-size-new-design-41mm-45mm"&gt;big rumors heating up&lt;/a&gt; before Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22663657/apple-iphone-13-pro-ipad-mini-watch-event-biggest-announcements"&gt;“California Streaming” iPhone announcement event&lt;/a&gt; about the Apple Watch Series 7 wound up fizzling out as soon as the new smartwatch was unveiled. The speculation was that Apple would perform the most significant overhaul of its smartwatch ever, aligning its design with that of the iPhone 12 and 13 — namely, flat sides and a more squared-off look with a larger display and smaller bezels. We got the larger display and slimmer bezels part, but the Apple Watch Series 7 still mostly looks like its predecessors at casual glance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sh7XXc"&gt;The biggest change to the Series 7 is indeed physically bigger: the display. Apple increased the screen sizes to 41mm and 45mm, and with a thicker glass top the display is stronger while stretching out further to the edges. The functional benefit is more room on the screen for larger icons, and Apple says you can do and see more with more info on screen and new watch faces. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wVz5af"&gt;Along with the screen changes, the Series 7 has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22667395/apple-watch-series-7-price-specs-redesign-announcement"&gt;a bevy of typical year-over-year improvements&lt;/a&gt;, such as faster charging, improved durability, new workouts, new colors, and even a full swipe keyboard for fidgeting with some tiny letters on these larger screens. But even with all of that, the design feels conservative, and not a radical departure from its immediate forebears. So should you wait until Apple’s estimated “later this fall” timeframe for the Apple Watch Series 7, or do the Apple Watches of today offer enough as-is for you? &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yWtSu4UACW7kFWvzFlbtzN6QQ84=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22850224/lcimg_d5b7c216_a765_44c8_94ea_3a59eb0563f3.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Apple Watch Series 7’s colors, including a green that seems vaguely black.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="alRuHC"&gt;The outgoing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496141/apple-watch-series-6-review-blood-oxygen-monitor-watchos-7"&gt;Apple Watch Series 6&lt;/a&gt; of 2020 is still an impressively capable smartwatch, and we’ve seen significant discounts on it for months now. The polarizing red colorway has at times plummeted as low as $249, even cheaper than the midrange $279 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496928/apple-watch-se-review-smartwatch-wearos-price-specs-features"&gt;Apple Watch SE&lt;/a&gt; that lacks an always-on display. Right at this moment you can buy a Series 6 from a variety of retailers in a color of your choice for &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-Series-6-GPS-40mm-PRODUCT-RED-Aluminum-Case-with-Sport-Band-Regular%2F478251261%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;amp;subid1=verge091421" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$319&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-Apple-Watch-GPS-40mm-Aluminum/dp/B08J5XF5SR?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$349&lt;/a&gt;, which is a considerable amount less than the $399 starting price of the Series 7 without having to wait. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cWFRQe"&gt;Spending less right now becomes even more appealing when you consider the Series 7 may still be using last year’s S6 processor — if so, it probably won’t have an added year of OS updates over the Series 6 like you’d normally expect. One of the benefits of a new processor isn’t just the speedy improvements of today, but also the sustainability and reassurance offered down the road by an increased performance ceiling. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="CvAQ2a"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best Apple Watch deals right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21289209/best-apple-watch-deals"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2zhG-_eAoGQRSxsbWZoY6BmO67w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22850995/applewatch_series7_typing.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please don’t lie and tell me you look forward to typing on this screen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5zlmpZ"&gt;The Series 7 certainly has its merits. If you prefer to have the most peace of mind, or you live a lifestyle that will really put a fitness-focused device to the test, then perhaps the new IP6X resistance rating for grittier environments and sandy beaches is enticing. If you value the fastest charging, the Series 7 comes with a USB-C magnetic fast charger, offering a 33 percent quicker charge, and even buying one of those separately will not juice up a prior generation watch any quicker. The larger displays are of course the biggest change, and if you always prefer what’s newer, bigger, and flashier then by all means keep an eye out for when preorders go up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yRniGK"&gt;But this new Apple Watch still pretty much just looks like any old Apple Watch, especially at the distances people usually see a watch on someone’s wrist. What will matter most to you here might be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22652375/samsung-galaxy-z-flip-3-phones-fashion"&gt;a very personal tech or fashion accessory decision&lt;/a&gt;, and if a slightly larger screen is all you need maybe that’s good enough. Though if you’re looking for the most sensible smartwatch from Apple, you may want to consider skipping the wait and choosing from the more cost-effective options available right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nyQVP6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22674258/apple-watch-series-7-upgrade-worth-waiting-for"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22674258/apple-watch-series-7-upgrade-worth-waiting-for</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-14T19:36:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-14T19:36:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>xCloud and Xbox Remote Play are officially available on Windows</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Mq8TmdOlEUQF3U6AKfBelq9_YCA=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69859247/Remote_Play_Key_Art.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="o9ZusI"&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2021/09/14/new-updates-to-xbox-app-on-windows-10/"&gt;Microsoft has announced&lt;/a&gt; that its xCloud service, officially known as Xbox Cloud Gaming, and Xbox Remote Play are now available to everyone with the Xbox app on Windows 10 (or 11). These features on PC rolled out to Xbox Insiders &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22616774/microsoft-xcloud-windows-xbox-app-xbox-cloud-gaming-beta"&gt;as a beta last month&lt;/a&gt;, and have been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/19/21524109/microsoft-xbox-app-iphone-ipad-game-streaming-xbox-app-microsoft-features"&gt;available on phones&lt;/a&gt; for a while, but them being officially available on PC is nice to see too. It’s giving you another option for how you want to play, whether the game is running on your personal console or Microsoft’s servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SDD0go"&gt;Xbox Cloud Gaming, which seems like a natural fit for PCs that don’t have the power to run the games themselves, has been available on Windows &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22391561/microsoft-xcloud-ios-pc-xbox-game-streaming-beta-features"&gt;for a few months through web browsers&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s a nice step forward that the service is now in a native app, rather than being confined to a web browser on PC. Using it still requires a Bluetooth or USB controller, and an Xbox Game Pass Ultimate subscription. It’s also worth noting that while Xbox Cloud Gaming’s availability on Windows is no longer exclusive to Insiders, Microsoft is still labeling the service itself as a beta, so your mileage may vary. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="qgAzuI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The feature may be out of beta, but the service isn’t&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wjwgvl"&gt;Remote Play is also a nice addition, allowing you to stream games from an Xbox Series S or X, or Xbox One, to your Windows machine. Microsoft says the feature is available either on your home network or remotely over the internet, though you’ll likely get better performance if the game is running locally on the same network. Microsoft has added some features to Remote Play too: the company says that you can now stream games in 1080p 60fps, and that you’ll be able to play “select” games from the original Xbox and 360. We’ve asked Microsoft for a list of the games that will be supported and will provide an update if we hear back. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22673798/xbox-cloud-gaming-remote-play-pc-windows-series-x-s-xcloud"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22673798/xbox-cloud-gaming-remote-play-pc-windows-series-x-s-xcloud</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-14T18:13:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-14T18:13:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>How the iPhone 13, Mini, Pro and Max compare to Android rivals — and vs. iPhone 12</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dIE1fKsyU-4YGO8QCzzk9vf437c=/136x0:1525x926/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69858872/Screen_Shot_2021_09_14_at_1.41.05_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OwYW5M"&gt;Apple has announced its new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22666802/iphone-13-specs-price-release-date-apple-camera"&gt;iPhone 13, iPhone 13 Mini,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22666884/iphone-13-pro-max-specs-price-release-date-cameras"&gt;iPhone 13 Pro and iPhone 13 Pro Max&lt;/a&gt;, which feature better cameras, 120Hz screens, new processors (which Apple claims are the fastest in a phone, period), better battery life, and smaller notches compared to their predecessors. But should you upgrade from the iPhone 12, and is Apple beating the Android competition? Here’s how Apple stacks up to Samsung, OnePlus, Google, and its own previous devices on paper. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zEx3AS"&gt;One thing to keep in mind before we dive in is that specs don’t tell the whole story. There’s the obvious difficult comparisons (how does an Apple A15 chip stack up against a Snapdragon 888, and how do you compare traditional phones to folding ones), as well as the small details that don’t fit cleanly on a spec sheet. For instance, one of Apple’s pro features is the ability to shoot 4K ProRes on its higher-end phones — except for the models with 128GB of storage, which will be limited to 1080p ProRes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="kLycRm"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Missing from this comparison: Google’s upcoming flagships&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZLNb0o"&gt;There’s also an obvious competitor missing: Google’s Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro. Google didn’t give us their full specifications &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605094/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-specs-ai-ml"&gt;in its partial announcement&lt;/a&gt;, which makes it hard to include them in a spec comparison. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tdkPRY"&gt;But let’s put all those caveats aside, because maybe you’re looking for a phone &lt;em&gt;right now. &lt;/em&gt;How do the iPhone 13 and 13 Mini stack up, spec-for-spec, against their Android competitors? Prices throughout this comparison, by the way, are for the unlocked iPhones, which are $30 more than the carrier versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CEaQyh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10752933"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="U16Rcu"&gt;Anyways, let’s stop talking about saving a few bucks, and blow the budget a bit: how does the iPhone 13 Pro stack up against the Android flagships, in a battle of the $1,000 plus phones?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Tbl3mx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10752940"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xtCxJu"&gt;As with past years, we see that Apple isn’t necessarily playing a spec-game, especially when it comes to cameras. Some of its higher-end Android competitors boast megapixel counts that are four or even almost 10 times as high as Apple’s cameras. Whether that’ll give them an edge or not will have to be seen when we test Apple’s “dramatically more powerful” cameras. Both Apple and Google have traditionally prioritized larger pixels for low-light performance rather than raw resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IKBjqe"&gt;Finally, let’s take a look at how Apple did year-over-year when it comes to upgrading its specs. It’s worth noting that, while we’ve included the 12 Pro, you actually can’t buy that phone  from Apple anymore, making the comparison more useful for upgraders than cross-shoppers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="eKc9TA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10753324"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WUkaL0"&gt;One interesting point is that the phones haven’t changed when it comes to width, height, or screen size, but they have gotten a bit thicker, and a bit heavier. They are packing a fair amount of new tech though, so perhaps that’s understandable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7HoaQL"&gt;What the specs don't show, though, is how unfavorably the iPhone 12 is priced — at first glance the it seems like a reasonable buy at $100 cheaper, but at that price you’re only getting half the storage. If you get a 128GB iPhone 12, you’ll only be saving $50 compared to the 128GB iPhone 13, which has all the upgrades to the screens, cameras, battery life, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22666802/iphone-13-specs-price-release-date-apple-camera"&gt;everything else Apple announced&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday. Sure, it’s technically less expensive, but you’d be giving up a lot for very little savings. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22674143/apple-iphone-13-pro-12-samsung-galaxy-pixel-android-comparison-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22674143/apple-iphone-13-pro-12-samsung-galaxy-pixel-android-comparison-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-14T17:49:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-14T17:49:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s updated leather MagSafe wallet supports Find My location tracking</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Z5Hcb5ftQ2C0iPfl-S_1-wyLOr8=/0x33:1468x1012/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69858738/Screen_Shot_2021_09_14_at_1.46.39_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HfglLg"&gt;Apple introduced an updated version of its &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MM0Q3ZM/A/iphone-leather-wallet-with-magsafe-golden-brown?fnode=39b68db69449c5a7ec6859579b5af320916609c170ab6488a4d76b5b025119f9e4646c0fcb99801d36758ddc3ecd4b1df121159a3759e017741796dbe5a58353744d6d28bbfdeeb02e47324b9e9820478c80412df67a05bd862cca30516def3b"&gt;MagSafe leather wallet&lt;/a&gt; today with new colors and support for an additional feature: tracking in the Find My app. Apple’s location tracking service recently expanded &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22396693/apple-airtag-location-tracker-hands-on-find-my-privacy-safety"&gt;with the addition of AirTags&lt;/a&gt;, and now the company is apparently working &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; version of the same functionality into its more low-tech accessories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ykzFme"&gt;That might seem like the continuous tracking AirTags offers, but Apple’s description points to something simpler. The company writes that the wallet “supports Find My, so you can be notified of your wallet’s last known location if it gets separated from your phone.” That’s helpful, but possibly not useful if someone moves your wallet after it’s separated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="sPE6m6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It seems like MagSafe is the key &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kNsRxF"&gt;Apple isn’t entirely clear why this is the case on its product page, but it’s possible what’s really happening is your iPhone is just noting when the MagSafe magnet is or isn’t attached to your phone. Your iPhone already plays a small animation when you attach a MagSafe product, it wouldn’t be too hard to imagine it marking a GPS location in Find My when a MagSafe accessory is disconnected. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UOweLsE59uRpvQ7chtkJ9-JPtNA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22850831/Screen_Shot_2021_09_14_at_1.37.20_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="eRG80f"&gt;There’s also an odd exception: in the fine print, Apple notes that the new Find My functionality isn’t supported on the Clear Case with MagSafe. The best guess here is that whatever unique ID your iPhone recognizes when you connect a MagSafe device might be blocked by a Clear Case. Why the Clear Case but not other MagSafe cases would keep Apple from knowing when a wallet is disconnected isn’t clear. That doesn’t make the new wallet less useful necessarily, but it does show it has limitations that a normal wallet with an AirTag or Tile shoved inside wouldn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pRoYru"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; has reached out to Apple for an explanation of how the new Find My functionality works, and what exactly is happening with the Clear Case. We’ll update if we learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Iv9hQc"&gt;The iPhone Leather Wallet with MagSafe is available now for $59.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="NhTNRN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple’s iPhone 13 event: the 8 biggest announcements ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22663657/apple-iphone-13-pro-ipad-mini-watch-event-biggest-announcements"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="SDYlRA"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tgSoWe"&gt;Related:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="2wH1jX"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="iPhone 13 event in 15 minutes|103694" data-volume-uuid="15e5aff54" data-volume-id="103694" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-677" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22674261/apple-iphone-leather-wallet-magsafe-find-my-tracking"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22674261/apple-iphone-leather-wallet-magsafe-find-my-tracking</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-14T17:45:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-14T17:45:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Apple Watch’s new sizes make shopping for bands more confusing</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Apple Watch" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8X-OzuKkyLOFNcVAUs7mkLrCiDY=/0x0:1653x1102/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69858714/applewatchsizes.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rOryBA"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22667395/apple-watch-series-7-price-specs-redesign-announcement"&gt;Apple Watch Series 7&lt;/a&gt; was one of the many announcements made during &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22663657/apple-iphone-13-pro-ipad-mini-watch-event-biggest-announcements"&gt;Apple’s “California Streaming” event&lt;/a&gt;, sharing the stage alongside the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22666802/iphone-13-specs-price-release-date-apple-camera"&gt;iPhone 13&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22666884/iphone-13-pro-max-specs-price-release-date-cameras"&gt;13 Pro&lt;/a&gt;, a new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22667216/ipad-mini-6-price-specs-release-date-features-apple"&gt;iPad Mini with USB-C charging&lt;/a&gt;, and more. The watch comes in new 41mm and 45mm case sizing, moving away from the 40mm and 44mm sizing that has been the standard for the last few generations of Apple Watch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z8STKV"&gt;As expected, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfAdlfb73UN" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple updated its online inventory of Watch bands&lt;/a&gt; accordingly for the new sizes. But many of them no longer list options for the 38, 40, 42, and 44mm sizing options for all of the bands. While it might appear at first that Apple has unceremoniously eradicated support for all previous models, don’t worry, it didn’t do that. However, the company did make it slightly more confusing to quickly find the accessory made for your watch size. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MYva4N"&gt;This breakdown should make it easier to choose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QjdNKJ"&gt;If you see a band you like that’s 41mm-sized, this implicitly indicates that they’ll work with 38mm and 40mm cases, too. The 45mm bands will work with Apple Watch models that have 42mm or 44mm cases. To make doubly sure that you’re getting a size that’s compatible with your watch, Apple’s site offers up compatibility details right beneath the sizing options, so be sure to click that if you’re skeptical. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Apple store" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Yt9bdtms4NzwG8dbeVNBGGSNvTA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22850741/bandcompatibility.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This window will appear if you click “See Compatibility Details” from Apple’s online store.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="OIsmNH"&gt;Shopping for solo loop bands is just a little more complicated, but nothing new there. In case you didn’t know, they’re compatible only with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496928/apple-watch-se-review-smartwatch-wearos-price-specs-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple Watch SE&lt;/a&gt;, the Series 4, and newer models. For 40mm and 41mm-sized Apple Watch models, you can get solo loop bands in the size range of one through nine, whereas the 44mm and 45mm models work with band sizes four through 12. If that sizing reads like gibberish to you, the solo loop requires you to take a measurement of your wrist size to find the size that lines up with Apple’s sizing guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J8cTGa"&gt;To reiterate, bands made for the smaller of the two new sizes work with the previous, smaller-sized Apple Watch models, and vice versa. Getting a bigger-sized Apple Watch band basically ensures it’ll work with previous wearables that were the biggest sizing option of their respective generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VxqHE7"&gt;I hope this tip helps you find a watch band that fits your watch. While it might be confusing at first, it’s fairly easy to commit to memory once you know about it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="UWHPsv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple is releasing watchOS 8 on September 20th","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22667046/apple-watchos-8-feature-release-date"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="BHY245"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="QbgNSM"&gt;Related:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="X84k3H"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="iPhone 13 event in 15 minutes|103694" data-volume-uuid="15e5aff54" data-volume-id="103694" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-458" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22674255/apple-watch-series-7-band-sizing-how-to-choose"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22674255/apple-watch-series-7-band-sizing-how-to-choose</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-09-14T17:31:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-09-14T17:31:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple drops the iPhone 12 Pro and iPhone XR from its lineup</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="iPhone XR" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/coGpCvtffTjdXwxzdnAhlZv0YlY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69858647/akrales_181019_3014_0770.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;iPhone XR | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iXrc0F"&gt;As &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22665413/apple-event-iphone-13-announcements-news-products"&gt;a slew of new iPhones come in&lt;/a&gt;, several models go out. This year, Apple pulled the plug on a couple of familiar standbys to make room for the iPhone 13, as &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/09/14/iphone-lineup-2021/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; points out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zGD6xK"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21524288/apple-iphone-12-pro-review"&gt;iPhone 12 Pro&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21555901/iphone-12-pro-max-review"&gt;12 Pro Max&lt;/a&gt; have disappeared from Apple’s online store outside of refurb models. This is customary for Pro models when the lineup is refreshed, even though they’ve been shipping for less than a year. If you absolutely must spend more than $1,000 on a brand-new iPhone that isn’t the iPhone 13 (or you love that dark blue colorway), your options today are carriers and third-party retail shops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BOGdkS"&gt;While the devices are likely to appear as cut-rate options at places like Woot from time to time, Apple’s retail option cuts out the option of buying last year's high-end model for a little less as opposed to choosing the latest and greatest — which, in the case of the iPhone 13 Pro, includes spec bumps all over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ThhI9u"&gt;The other model that no longer makes the cut is the iPhone XR. Introduced in 2018 as a cheaper LCD-equipped alternative to the iPhone XS, it hung on as a midrange-priced device with the Neural Engine, second-gen Face ID, and plenty of colors to choose from. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Tnec08"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple iPhone XR review: better than good enough ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/23/18011306/apple-iphone-xr-review-camera-screen-battery-price"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="f82eKR"&gt;The iPhone XR’s arrival coincided with the disappearance of the last iPhones to feature headphone jacks. While this year’s transition isn’t nearly so dramatic, it includes a shift in the cheaper options in the lineup. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="iPhone pricing - Fall 2021" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gRqhYSUEVT4qFcyLceDuhQlDZrw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22851009/iphone_pricing.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple.com&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;iPhone pricing - Fall 2021&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="4OQSfs"&gt;The iPhone XR was available for $499 unlocked, but the iPhone 11 &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-iphone%2Fiphone-11&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F14%2F22674308%2Fapple-iphone-xr-12-11-price-cut-discontinued" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;price has dropped by $100&lt;/a&gt; to cover the slot. At the iPhone 11 launch, Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/11/20847304/apple-iphone-11-pro-max-comparison-best-specs-features-price-size-camera"&gt;said the newer device offered up to an hour of extra battery life over its predecessor&lt;/a&gt;, the U1 ultrawideband chip for finding things, and a newer A13 Bionic CPU. The &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fiphone-12%2Fkey-features%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F9%2F14%2F22674308%2Fapple-iphone-xr-12-11-price-cut-discontinued" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;iPhone 12 and iPhone 12 Mini&lt;/a&gt; also received $100 price cuts from Apple, making their starting prices $699 and $599, respectively. The iPhone SE remains $399.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XuIrK9"&gt;As far as the new Pro devices go, they aren’t any cheaper, but once the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22666884/iphone-13-pro-max-specs-price-release-date-cameras"&gt;iPhone 13 Pro and 13 Pro Max&lt;/a&gt; start shipping on the 24th, they will offer high refresh rate displays, a new camera system, plus improvements to the CPU and GPU. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="e6eOSz"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="YfGfcI"&gt;Related:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="OOsfjT"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="iPhone 13 event in 15 minutes|103694" data-volume-uuid="15e5aff54" data-volume-id="103694" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-829" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22674308/apple-iphone-xr-12-11-price-cut-discontinued"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22674308/apple-iphone-xr-12-11-price-cut-discontinued</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
