<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-02T17:54:17-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-02T17:54:17-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-02T17:54:17-05:00</updated>
    <title>TikTok reduces India staff after long-standing countrywide ban</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="TikTok Banned In India" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pcO9_NPjD5NuV6g52bSKM1wjps0=/0x104:5035x3461/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68759734/1223851409.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A user browses TikTok in Tehatta, India. | Photo by Soumyabrata Roy/NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KWGo7c"&gt;More than seven months after India issued a countrywide ban on TikTok, the app is significantly reducing its staffing in the country. On Tuesday, &lt;a href="https://asia.nikkei.com/Business/China-tech/TikTok-gives-up-on-India-months-after-government-ban"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nikkei Asia&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; that TikTok was “essentially withdrawing” from India, citing sources familiar with the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="arbpl7"&gt;Reached for comment, a TikTok spokesperson confirmed that it was reducing its workforce in India but disputed the details of &lt;em&gt;Nikkei&lt;/em&gt;’s report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yzDLQ6"&gt;In a statement, a TikTok spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge: “&lt;/em&gt;Given the lack of feedback from the government about how to resolve this issue in the subsequent seven months, it is with deep sadness that we have decided to reduce our workforce in India... [We] hope to get the chance to relaunch TikTok in India to support the hundreds of millions of users, artists, story-tellers, educators and performers there.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vVevEC"&gt;It’s unclear how many employees TikTok will retain. &lt;em&gt;Nikkei&lt;/em&gt; reported that “most” local employees were set to be laid off. Pressed by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, the company did not clarify how many India-based employees will remain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ahfgGs"&gt;India was previously a large market for TikTok, which is owned by the Beijing-based firm ByteDance: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/29/21307014/india-ban-tiktok-wechat-china-apps"&gt;30 percent&lt;/a&gt; of TikTok’s downloads came from India as of April 2020. As of June, the app had about 167 million users in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="I21jbv"&gt;&lt;q&gt; “It is with deep sadness that we have decided to reduce our workforce in India”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eRDN0q"&gt;TikTok has been banned in India since June 29th. In its &lt;a href="https://pib.gov.in/PressReleseDetailm.aspx?PRID=1635206#"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt;, the country’s Ministry of Electronics and Information Technology stated that the apps were “engaged in activities which is prejudicial to sovereignty and integrity of India, defence of India, security of state and public order.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Htorks"&gt;ByteDance, at the time, did not indicate plans to pull out. Following the announcement, the head of TikTok India issued a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TikTok_IN/status/1277811841364668416?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1277811841364668416%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2020%2F6%2F29%2F21307014%2Findia-ban-tiktok-wechat-china-apps"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; claiming that the company had not shared Indian users’ information with the Chinese government and that its practices were in compliance with India’s data privacy and security requirements. “We have been invited to meet with concerned government stakeholders for an opportunity to respond and submit clarifications,” the statement read. “We place the highest importance on user privacy and integrity.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CmDoKm"&gt;That wasn’t TikTok’s first quarrel with the Indian government. Indian lawmakers, including the information technology minister of Tamil Nadu, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/13/18223590/tiktok-india-ban-legislation-government-teens"&gt;called for the app to be banned&lt;/a&gt; in early 2019, citing concerns about the behavior of teens and young adults on the service. Apple and Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/16/18411013/tiktok-india-google-play-block-apple-app-store-bytedance"&gt;pulled the app&lt;/a&gt; from their respective stores in India in mid-April, following a state court request. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JDDObX"&gt;That ban was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/24/18515035/tiktok-is-no-longer-banned-in-india"&gt;lifted&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/24/18515035/tiktok-is-no-longer-banned-in-india"&gt;j&lt;/a&gt;ust over a week later, and didn’t impact folks who were already using TikTok; it merely prevented new downloads. Even so, TikTok claimed that it suffered up to $500,000 in losses each day the ban was in effect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zsl3EM"&gt;“We are committed to continuously enhancing our safety features as a testament to our ongoing commitment to our users in India,” ByteDance said, following the lift of the ban. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YN5itf"&gt;Other countries have long-running security concerns with TikTok as well. The Trump administration &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/7/22160239/tiktok-ban-judge-trump-administration-us-commerce-department"&gt;attempted&lt;/a&gt; to block transactions between ByteDance and US companies last year but was blocked from doing so by the courts. Several &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/24/21150667/tsa-tiktok-employee-ban-bytedance-chuck-schumer-homeland-security"&gt;US government agencies&lt;/a&gt; have banned the use of the app on government-issued devices. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22262940/tiktok-leaves-india-ban-app-china-government-security-privacy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22262940/tiktok-leaves-india-ban-app-china-government-security-privacy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-02T17:41:34-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-02T17:41:34-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google Meet’s new ‘green room’ lets you do an audio / video pre-check</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zjBTZJXtkpf0gYvpC_GINLgTbEY=/0x178:934x801/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68759687/Screen_Shot_2021_02_02_at_10.15.30_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wVCcNH"&gt;It can be difficult to figure out how you’re coming across in a videoconference, especially if you want to make sure everything works before you start the meeting. How is your lighting? Are you sitting too close or too far from the camera? Is your audio okay, are you accidentally muted, or do you sound as if you’re in an echo chamber? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8826Jd"&gt;&lt;a href="https://workspaceupdates.googleblog.com/2021/02/check-video-and-peripheral-device-quality-with-google-meet-self-check.html"&gt;Google has now made it easier&lt;/a&gt; to check your appearance and your tech &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; a Meet conference with its new “green room” feature (&lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/02/02/google-meet-preview-video/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). When you start or prepare to join a meeting, in the usual “Ready to join?” window that first appears, you will now also see a small button below your video that says “Check your audio and video.” Just click on that button, and a pop-up window will not only show your video image, but allow you to see (and change) which microphone, speaker, and camera is currently live.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Google Meet’s “green room” lets you check your audio and video." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0QXn3yWmxmE4kLfrAp0HLZ4T6xw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22277054/Screen_Shot_2021_02_02_at_10.14.05_AM__1_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google Meet’s “green room” lets you check your audio and video.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="F35CO0"&gt;A “Next” button on that pop-up window then lets you record a short 6-second video sample, allowing you to see how you will look and sound to the others in your meeting. According to Google, the clip is private to you and will not be saved. Your mic, speaker, camera, and connection are also checked by the system and get green checkmarks if they seem to be working. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J1e35T"&gt;While previously you could see how you appeared in the initial “Ready to join?” window, Meet’s new “green room” can be even more helpful. For example, you can test various forms of lighting, test whether your laptop’s audio is better or worse than your headset’s, and make sure that you’re looking good before your meeting — with colleagues, friends, or family — starts.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vuve0j"&gt;Google Meet’s new “green room” feature is available now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pYrizG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22262973/google-meet-green-room-audio-video"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22262973/google-meet-green-room-audio-video</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-02T17:29:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-02T17:29:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apex Legends is finally coming to the Nintendo Switch on March 9th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p4zxOen3TvaYO7Ws3tOaXQC0eQE=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68759650/ss_8616ccdae08da0793a2f1d9b52997170eb0a1e25.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4cOIKF"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;/em&gt; is coming to the Nintendo Switch very soon. Today, &lt;a href="https://www.ea.com/games/apex-legends/news/switch-launch-march-2021"&gt;EA announced&lt;/a&gt; that the portable version of its sci-fi battle royale will debut on Nintendo’s tablet on March 9th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ped5Yk"&gt;Chad Grenier, &lt;em&gt;Apex&lt;/em&gt;’s game director, says the new version will include “cross-platform play, our latest seasonal content, and full feature parity with the other versions of the game.” &lt;em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;/em&gt; originally launched in early 2019, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/18/21296353/ea-apex-legends-switch-steam-crossplay-titanfall-2-sims-4-way-out"&gt;a Switch version was announced last June&lt;/a&gt;. It’s developed by Respawn, the studio behind games like &lt;em&gt;Titanfall&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/15/20965741/star-wars-jedi-fallen-order-review-xbox-ps4-pc-respawn"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Star Wars Jedi: Fallen Order&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eXOx5A"&gt;The Switch version launches not long after the game’s eighth season, which launches today. To make up for the difference, EA says that “since we’re launching a few weeks after the start of season eight, Switch players will be granted 30 free levels for their season eight battle pass. For the first two weeks after launch, playing on Switch will also earn you double XP.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zeTfvA"&gt;Nintendo’s device is steadily becoming a great portable option for some of the biggest free-to-play multiplayer games around, with &lt;em&gt;Apex&lt;/em&gt; joining titles like &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Spellbreak.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22233603/apex-legends-nintendo-switch-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22233603/apex-legends-nintendo-switch-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-02T17:13:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-02T17:13:16-05:00</updated>
    <title>The rise of the GOP Poster’s Caucus</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Opening Day Of The 117th Congress On Capitol Hill" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GIdb283-6eEn6LyN9l7JLks9eaU=/36x0:5877x3894/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68759553/1230412906.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7crxcI"&gt;It was September 2018, while Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey was testifying before Congress for the first time, when sitting lawmakers had their first confrontation with the wild nature of the online right. Nearly 90 minutes after the hearing began, Laura Loomer, a far-right internet celebrity, stood up from the committee audience. “Please help us Mr. President before it is too late,” Loomer yelled, selfie stick in hand. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8xALHs"&gt;She said something about “censoring” and then something about “shadowbanning,” although it was hard to make out the argument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X0WI06"&gt;“What is she trying to say?” Rep. Billy Long (R-MO) asked, before pretending to lead a live auction, imitating an auctioneer’s call to drown out Loomer’s voice and forcing her out the hearing room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bQWHFl"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Alt-Right conspiracy theory peddler Laura Loomer just crashed Jack Dorsey's Congressional testimony.&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/USRepLong?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@USRepLong&lt;/a&gt; began mocking her &lt;a href="https://t.co/aQiAwnmeoE"&gt;pic.twitter.com/aQiAwnmeoE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— jordan (@JordanUhl) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JordanUhl/status/1037414684994007040?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 5, 2018&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WMNZTz"&gt;It was a jarring moment, but as Republicans struggle with the rise of QAnon — and, more specifically, the bizarre conspiracies spread by Rep. Marjorie Taylor Greene (R-GA) — the moment may have had more to say about the party’s future than anyone realized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b8hU9o"&gt;Since 2016, the Republican Party has gone from nearly getting into fistfights &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/9/5/17823322/alex-jones-info-wars-senate-intelligence-committee"&gt;with conspiracy posters like Alex Jones&lt;/a&gt; to sharing offices next door to them on the Capitol grounds. Republicans have dipped in and out of the conservative internet ecosystem, one concentrated with misinformation and conspiracy, at times that were most politically expedient for them and their party. But Greene’s new spot in Congress is showing how powerful that ecosystem is and how difficult it will be for the party to shed. For a growing portion of the Republican Party, governance is now secondary to content, and the challenges of holding office aren’t so different from the hustle of a popular YouTube channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T4I5jm"&gt;While far-right conspiracy theorists trolled Congress in 2018, Greene was building her own facsimile of a following online. That same year, Greene posted to Facebook suggesting that the Parkland, Florida, school shooting, which left 17 people dead, was a “false flag” operation, a classic falsehood peddled by people like Jones online. It was this post, first reported &lt;a href="https://www.mediamatters.org/false-flag-conspiracy-theory/rep-marjorie-taylor-greene-facebook-2018-parkland-school-shooting-was"&gt;by &lt;em&gt;Media Matters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;paired with a new report &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/01/26/politics/marjorie-taylor-greene-democrats-violence/index.html"&gt;from CNN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;that uncovered messages from Greene supporting the execution of prominent Democrats that forced Republicans to finally address her online history, something broadly known for months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vGXlqh"&gt;Greene’s first few weeks in Congress have led to more content than compromise. She’s introduced dead-on-arrival articles of impeachment against President Joe Biden and was &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/01/17/politics/marjorie-taylor-greene-twitter/index.html"&gt;already suspended from Twitter&lt;/a&gt; for violating the platform’s rules on election misinformation after posting that &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/insurrection-at-the-capitol/2021/01/17/957891462/twitter-suspends-rep-marjorie-taylor-greene-s-account-temporarily"&gt;some races across the country&lt;/a&gt; were falsely called for Biden. Rep. Cori Bush (D-MO) announced last week that she would be moving her office farther away from Greene and described an altercation the two had in the hall over masks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0MESpR"&gt;Later that week, Greene put out a video of the incident where she wasn’t wearing a mask properly, mirroring the look and behavior of right-wing provocateurs like Loomer or disgraced former Staten Island congressional candidate and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/11/20689402/joey-salads-youtube-campaign-congress-trump-republican-political-bias"&gt;YouTube prankster Joey Salads&lt;/a&gt;; the camera was shaky, held vertically, and pointed at her face as she talked about her day in Congress. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="XoeqE2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;To Greene, this content and its consequences are their own kind of success&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5NHISu"&gt;To Greene, this content and its consequences are their own kind of success — something far more valuable than a co-sponsored bill or a spot on a powerful committee. After Democrats called to expel her last week, Greene said she raised &lt;a href="https://www.ajc.com/politics/marjorie-taylor-greene-says-she-raised-16-million-after-calls-for-her-expulsion/DOPUOGZ66FGV5CUGHATP2RXRFY/"&gt;over $1.6 million&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mtgreenee/status/1355263214020419586?s=20"&gt;In a statement Friday&lt;/a&gt;, Greene said, “I will never back down. I will never give up. Because I am one of you. And I will always represent you.” She continued, “I knew this day would come, it was only a question of when.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9iIIfM"&gt;If that sounds like the kind of non-apology you’d hear from a teenage YouTuber, it’s no coincidence. For Greene, governing &lt;em&gt;is &lt;/em&gt;posting. Her meteoric rise from Facebook influencer to congressperson is a symptom of the algorithm-based social media feeds of our time. In 2017, Greene first posted about QAnon. “Have you guys been following 4chan? Q? Any of that stuff?” Greene said &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2rtYok4fdbQ"&gt;in a video&lt;/a&gt;. “Q is a patriot, we know that for sure.” Greene makes increasingly more outlandish claims for the same reason prank YouTubers and their stunts become even more dangerous: the more controversy she generates, the larger her audience becomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2ArO1j"&gt;Greene has become the face of the Republican Party’s “Poster’s Caucus,” where messaging and content reigns supreme over policy. Rep. Madison Cawthorn (R-NC) said &lt;a href="https://www.msnbc.com/rachel-maddow-show/new-republican-congressman-prioritizes-punditry-over-policy-n1255967"&gt;in a letter to colleagues last week&lt;/a&gt; that he would be focusing on communications over legislation as well — and for good reason. Cawthorn’s biggest wins have been &lt;a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2020/11/03/madison-cawthorn-reacts-winning-seat-congress-cry-more-lib/6155257002/"&gt;tweets&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://madison-cawthorn.myshopify.com/"&gt;merch drops&lt;/a&gt;. That’s simply what his audience expects. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dNyrA1"&gt;If Republicans have largely remained silent over Greene’s bizarre approach to politics, it’s because they understand the value of Greene’s connection with her audience. It’s a more extreme version of a game conservative lawmakers have been playing with the online right for years. In an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;last year, conservative YouTuber Dave Rubin made a similar observation, saying that lawmakers needed him more than he needed them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r1bSwN"&gt;“It was Dan Crenshaw who reached out to me. It was the Ted Cruz people who reached out to me. It was Rand Paul people who reached out to me,” Rubin told &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21489979/biden-trump-presidential-dabate-election-youtube-ben-shapiro-dave-rubin"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “They clearly see the seas changing in terms of where people are getting their news, and that they need an opportunity to have their ideas heard.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DqN5hV"&gt;Political parties have long struggled with their base, and courting media figures has often been a part of it — from Walter Winchell to Rush Limbaugh. But the novel dynamics of the internet have made the base more extreme and alienated it from the conventional dynamics of government. While lawmakers focus on stimulus checks and a second Trump impeachment, online channels are talking about pedophilia rings and antifa super-soldiers, creating a bizarre alternate reality with no meaningful connection to the actual functions of Congress. Using open platforms and independent companies, the usual moderating forces — like corporate standards departments or advertiser boycotts — just aren’t a factor. For figures like Alex Jones or Laura Loomer, there’s simply no reason to reengage with reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2RKkd5"&gt;With Greene, that kind of logic is now part of the Republican House delegation, and it’s still hard to say how party leaders will respond to this new force. House Democrats are pushing hard to marginalize Greene, pointing to her unhinged and often anti-Semitic statements. While some Senate Republicans like Mitch McConnell (R-KY) condemned Greene, calling her embrace of conspiracy theories a “cancer for the Republican party,” others have been quiet. House Republican Leader Kevin McCarthy (R-CA) said he would talk to Greene about her social media posts last week, but it’s not clear when that meeting will take place, as of publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GxbRzw"&gt;It’s easy to see why McConnell is scared. This delay from Republicans and McCarthy is only providing Democrats &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2021/02/01/democrats-marjorie-taylor-greene-ultimatum-464382"&gt;with more ammo for future elections&lt;/a&gt;, tying the GOP with QAnon or any other conspiracy they grab on to before November 2022. That shell game might be good for subscriber numbers, but it’s bad for the GOP — and if leaders aren’t careful, they may end up the party of Alex Jones instead of the party of Marco Rubio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EjJNZP"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22262960/marjorie-taylor-greene-mccarthy-republican-gop-posters-caucus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22262960/marjorie-taylor-greene-mccarthy-republican-gop-posters-caucus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-02T17:10:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-02T17:10:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon’s latest earnings cap off a sterling 2020, despite the pandemic</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3BLtXg_W7dC_V4Bk2s0Zyowyyrg=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68759525/acastro_190920_1777_amazon_0001.0.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Dg1Jn6"&gt;Amazon founder and soon-to-be-former CEO Jeff Bezos &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22263039/amazon-new-ceo-jeff-bezos-andy-jassy-executive-chair-board-q3-2021"&gt;is stepping down from his role&lt;/a&gt;, making way for Amazon Web Services CEO Andy Jassy to take his place, and the company couldn’t be in better shape financially for the big transition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="spBgp0"&gt;Despite the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic, Amazon has kept growing bigger during times that have strained many other businesses. In its Q4 2020 earnings release this afternoon, the company reported net income more than doubling to $7.2 billion for the quarter, compared to $3.3 billion for the same period in 2019. Amazon’s full-year 2020 net sales were up 38 percent, to $386.1 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fYQ0pE"&gt;There’s a little more to unpack in these Q4 earnings than one might usually see. For 2020, Amazon shifted its Prime Day shopping event from the middle of summer to mid-October, which likely gave its numbers a big boost. And in doing so, it basically kicked off the holiday shopping season earlier than ever, with more people at home shopping exclusively online to avoid in-person gifting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2F7I0g"&gt;Amazon’s &lt;a href="https://ir.aboutamazon.com/files/doc_financials/2020/q4/Amazon-Q4-2020-Earnings-Release.pdf"&gt;latest earnings release&lt;/a&gt; doesn’t feature a lengthy statement from Bezos, who more recently had reserved this spot for announcing the company would commit huge amounts of money toward COVID-19 research and prevention. Instead, Bezos used it as a place to rattle off Amazon’s biggest inventions that have grown in popularity under his control, capping off his era as the CEO of the largest, most profitable company on the planet. He’ll remain CEO until Q3 2021, when Andy Jassy will take over.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22260133/amazon-q4-2020-quarterly-earnings-jeff-bezos-ceo-transition-andy-jassy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22260133/amazon-q4-2020-quarterly-earnings-jeff-bezos-ceo-transition-andy-jassy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-02T16:59:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-02T16:59:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla’s next car will seamlessly unlock with UWB, FCC leak suggests</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8I5GbKAWbEj6hTFDNNXzebGoDOQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68759439/acastro_180724_1777_tesla_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WD5Mi1"&gt;Apple and Samsung have been quietly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22230960/samsung-digital-car-key-audi-bmw-ford-genesis-uwb-bluetooth"&gt;contributing to a new technology to find and  seamlessly unlock your car with your phone&lt;/a&gt;, without even pulling it out of your pocket — and Tesla may be one of the first with the tech. Tesla is actively working on building UWB into its cars, according to documents filed with the Federal Communications Commission. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mXsVLw"&gt;On September 9th, the company submitted six new “products” for the FCC’s consideration, including two key fobs, a security controller, and a number of “endpoints” that would be installed inside the frame and cabin of a vehicle:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RnBE51dFq8WGJXV7QPurNnSscBA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22276933/image__14_.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pNrGoR"&gt;According to the FCC documents, at least three of those products explicitly support UWB communication. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R6NgDD"&gt;What’s more, Tesla’s FCC filing is unusual in that it includes &lt;a href="https://fccid.io/2AEIM-1614283/Operational-Description/Operation-Description-5073259"&gt;a complete operational description of the technology&lt;/a&gt;, something that’s usually redacted. The highlights: it’s a standards-based implementation of UWB, which means UWB phones from Apple and Samsung should theoretically be compatible, and it’s designed to let you know how far away you are from the car. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H3OjSC"&gt;That "ranging" is helpful to avoid &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/10/17842136/tesla-key-fob-hack-theft-spoofing-relay"&gt;replay attacks&lt;/a&gt; that try to trick your car into thinking its key fob is closer than it actually is. But it also theoretically unlocks the ability to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22230960/samsung-digital-car-key-audi-bmw-ford-genesis-uwb-bluetooth"&gt;find your car in a crowded parking lot&lt;/a&gt; using your phone, something Samsung is already planning to release an app for later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dazmgirpnE3YWn_I6mj0hynLw5U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22276974/tesla_uwb_description.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A selection from Tesla’s operational description of the tech.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="QV831p"&gt;When I spoke to UWB chip supplier NXP last year, company CTO Lars Reger told me that future cars would likely need several of these UWB endpoints inside the car, possibly at the door handles, to properly triangulate your location and know whether you’re inside or outside so, say, your kids won’t be able to turn on the engine if you’re not actually in the cabin. Apparently, Tesla thinks the B-pillars (located between the front and rear side windows of a car) and a piece of fascia might be good places to put those antennas, too.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xCoqL6T7PI462FpkkVk4Q20YJcs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22276944/tesla_keyfob.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A drawing of the inside of one of the UWB key fobs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pvNXFm"&gt;None of this means that Tesla will necessarily add the tech to its cars, but FCC documents are usually a pretty good sign that it’s not just an experiment. FCC filings are typically one of the last waypoints before a product comes to market, as they’re only required if you’re going to import, sell, or do widespread testing of a radio product in the US. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eivC6h"&gt;Last we checked, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/14/22230569/bmw-digital-key-plus-iphone-unlock-u1-chip-ultra-wideband"&gt;BMW was the only other automaker&lt;/a&gt; that’s committed to UWB. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22262996/tesla-uwb-fcc-car-key-ultrawideband-tech"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22262996/tesla-uwb-fcc-car-key-ultrawideband-tech</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-02T16:54:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-02T16:54:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s cloud business lost more than $5.5 billion last year, but it’s growing fast</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/295I17jeRHbOnMoF-qmIZsbbVrE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68759421/acastro_180427_1777_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration: Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="V6ocrJ"&gt;Google parent company Alphabet weathered the tail end of 2020 to &lt;a href="https://abc.xyz/investor/static/pdf/2020Q4_alphabet_earnings_release.pdf?cache=9e991fd"&gt;post better-than-expected earnings&lt;/a&gt; for the fourth quarter of the year. But the bigger story is that Alphabet broke out Google Cloud’s sales for the first time ever, revealing an eye-popping $5.6 billion annual loss last year, but a nearly 50 percent jump in revenue (to $13 billion) compared to 2019. And Google Cloud maintained that growth well into the fourth quarter, when the division generated $3.8 billion in sales. That’s a 46 percent jump from the fourth quarter of 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k72qbe"&gt;Those numbers are notable for a few reasons: Google Cloud lags behind the competition, in particular Microsoft’s Azure platform and Amazon’s dominant Amazon Web Services, the CEO of which was just promoted to run the entirety of Amazon now that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22263039/amazon-new-ceo-jeff-bezos-andy-jassy-executive-chair-board-q3-2021"&gt;co-founder Jeff Bezos is stepping back&lt;/a&gt; into an executive chairman role in a surprise announcement this afternoon. But the division’s fast-growing revenues, second only to the search giant’s core ad business, suggest Google could become a major cloud player and fiercer competitor to Azure and AWS in the years to come. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="GKupIo"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Google Cloud lags behind Azure and AWS, but it’s growing fast&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8xlY5q"&gt;The message is now clear: cloud computing is the dominant business for these major tech titans, and the execs who can excel in the cloud industry are stepping in to take the reins of  the entire business. Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella famously ran Azure before he took over for Steve Ballmer, and Google Cloud chief Thomas Kurian was a top exec at Oracle before replacing VMWare co-founder Diane Green in the top Google Cloud role. These are the people running the show at the most important divisions of the most important tech companies, until they get promoted to steer the entire ship apparently. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tzTHfl"&gt;In many ways, Google’s cloud business is going through the same growing pains its competitors once did; it took AWS nearly 10 years to become profitable for the first time, and it’s now a more than $45 billion annual business. But Google is facing an uphill battle, one that will take a considerable time and financial investment to come to fruition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z81Hfx"&gt;Thankfully, Alphabet is not dependent on Google’s cloud business, as Amazon relies on AWS, to make considerable profit every quarter, thanks to Google’s dominant ad business that brought in a staggering $52.9 billion in revenue last quarter alone and nearly $170 billion for the year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8HwX5g"&gt;The Google Services division’s profit margins there are immense — Google made more than $19 billion in net income for the fourth quarter of 2020, a 41 percent increase from the fourth quarter of 2019. YouTube also continues to grow at a steady clip. The video site posted more than $6.8 billion in revenue last quarter, a 47 percent increase from the fourth quarter of 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OKLndM"&gt;The always fluctuating Other Bets division — which includes Alphabet’s X lab, Waymo, and other non-Google companies — took in $196 million last quarter and $657 million in all of 2020, but it also posted an operating loss of $4.48 billion for the year. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22263048/google-cloud-loss-alphabet-q4-2020-earnings"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22263048/google-cloud-loss-alphabet-q4-2020-earnings</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-02T16:43:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-02T16:43:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>Wikipedia introduces new Universal Code of Conduct to fight harassment</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eC6j_wVvyGSQsIpyd-p5YSwhE7s=/131x0:1904x1182/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68759366/Screen_Shot_2021_02_02_at_3.55.15_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JrFvxD"&gt;Wikipedia has &lt;a href="https://wikimediafoundation.org/news/2021/02/02/wikipedia-embraces-first-of-its-kind-universal-code-of-conduct/"&gt;introduced&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;a href="https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/Universal_Code_of_Conduct/Policy_text"&gt;Universal Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt; that looks to create a global standard for the site and ensure a “diverse, inclusive, and accessible” community of contributors, continuing its efforts to fight harassment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uyUjKb"&gt;The formal code of conduct — like many Wikimedia projects — was a crowdsourced project, with over 1,500 volunteers from around the world contributing. It’s intentionally designed to be relatively short and easily comprehensible to users, measuring in at a brisk 1,600 words. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xzn6Ec"&gt;Broadly speaking, the new code of conduct is broken down into two categories: positive behavior that’s expected from users, editors, and Wikimedia employees, and unacceptable behavior that the company looks to discourage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aBrDUY"&gt;Expected behavior includes having mutual respect for others, engaging in constructive editing, and respecting things like personal pronouns for other contributors. The code of conduct also encourages users to help support each other on projects and to mentor new editors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ammhv4"&gt;On the flip side of things, the code of conduct explicitly calls out harassment — be it insults, sexual harassment, threatening language, doxxing, or bad faith arguments — along with “any behavior intended primarily to intimidate, outrage, or upset a person.” Abuse of power is similarly banned, as is content vandalism, hate speech, and “deliberately introducing biased, false, inaccurate, or inappropriate content” to Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ouR130"&gt;The code of conduct &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/25/21269482/wikimedia-foundation-anti-harassment-code-of-conduct-vote"&gt;follows the company’s announcement&lt;/a&gt; of plans to enact more formal policies against harassment and inappropriate behavior on Wikipedia and other Wikimedia sites last year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="GvWRro"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Wikimedia is writing new policies to fight Wikipedia harassment","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/25/21269482/wikimedia-foundation-anti-harassment-code-of-conduct-vote"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="J4wVzD"&gt;The new Universal Code of Conduct is just the first part of the company’s efforts to define encouraged and unacceptable behavior on Wikipedia. Defining bad conduct is a good place to start, but right now, Wikimedia has yet to codify any universal policies for what happens when bad actors &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; harass other users or spread misinformation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aSa8OA"&gt;Wikimedia is already working on that second phase of the Universal Code of Conduct, which will establish how both local and regional Wikipedia projects will enforce the new requirements and any consequences for those who break those rules. But the company is still in the early stages here — that part of the project &lt;a href="https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/Universal_Code_of_Conduct#Timeline"&gt;likely won’t be complete&lt;/a&gt; until late 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EhF6rP"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22262966/wikipedia-harassment-new-universal-code-of-conduct-policy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22262966/wikipedia-harassment-new-universal-code-of-conduct-policy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-02T16:11:59-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-02T16:11:59-05:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon will have a new CEO as Jeff Bezos transitions to executive chair later this year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/myObr0yaB2Nz7wXhl62wGk1FbY4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68759143/acastro_181114_1777_amazon_hq2_0006.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="NzQvvY"&gt;Amazon CEO Jeff Bezos &lt;a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/company-news/email-from-jeff-bezos-to-employees"&gt;will step down as CEO&lt;/a&gt; and transition to a new position at the company as executive chair of the Amazon board in Q3 2021. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?app=desktop&amp;amp;v=Dm1MOGqy6o4"&gt;Andy Jassy&lt;/a&gt;, who currently serves as CEO of Amazon Web Services (AWS), will replace Bezos as Amazon CEO. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BA4c8H"&gt;“Being the CEO of Amazon is a deep responsibility, and it’s consuming. When you have a responsibility like that, it’s hard to put attention on anything else,” &lt;a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/company-news/email-from-jeff-bezos-to-employees"&gt;commented Bezos in an email&lt;/a&gt; announcing the change. “As Exec Chair I will stay engaged in important Amazon initiatives but also have the time and energy I need to focus on the Day 1 Fund, the Bezos Earth Fund, Blue Origin, &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;, and my other passions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="YgOzz1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Bezos is stepping back to better focus on projects like the Bezos Earth Fund and Blue Origin&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Lw3beK"&gt;Bezos has served as Amazon’s CEO since he founded the company in 1994, and he has presided over the e-commerce giant as it grew from an online bookstore into one of the most dominant technology companies in the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V4YWwd"&gt;Under Bezos’ stewardship, Amazon has come to rule over internet commerce, established itself as a backbone of the infrastructure of the modern web through its Amazon Web Services products, built a subscription empire around its Amazon Prime services, launched popular technology products like the Echo and Kindle lines of devices, and even started dabbling in physical retail through grocery stores and an acquisition of Whole Foods. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="46vEDx"&gt;Bezos has also prospered as head of the company, with skyrocketing wealth that (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22163361/elon-musk-billionaire-richest-world-jeff-bezos-tesla-stock-spacex"&gt;until just a few weeks ago&lt;/a&gt;) made him the single richest human on Earth, with a net worth of nearly $180 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WaoVr4"&gt;Bezos’ transition to executive chairman of Amazon’s board will mean he’ll be slightly more removed from the day-to-day business of running the nearly $1.7 trillion company, allowing him to focus his “energies and attention on new products and early initiatives.” Those projects will include the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/16/21569902/jeff-bezos-first-recipients-10-billion-climate-change-fund"&gt;$10 billion Bezos Earth Fund&lt;/a&gt;, which Bezos established last year, and Blue Origins, his aerospace firm, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21509198/blue-origin-new-shepard-test-launch-nasa-payload-watch-live-time"&gt;recently resumed test flights&lt;/a&gt; at the end of 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eOC4VT"&gt;Jassy is a familiar face at the company, having joined back in 1997. He has led the Amazon Web Services team since it was founded in 2003 and was named the CEO of AWS in 2016. The choice of Jassy — who has headed Amazon’s cloud service business since the beginning — over a retail or hardware executive is a telling one for Amazon’s priorities as a company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a2p1y8"&gt;Amazon’s cloud business is a huge part of the company (and the internet at large, to the point where &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/25/21719396/amazon-web-services-aws-outage-down-internet"&gt;AWS outages&lt;/a&gt; can take down whole swaths of internet for hours), and its new leadership choice reflects that. It’s also a parallel to other major tech CEOs, like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/2/4/5169852/satya-nadella-microsoft-ceo"&gt;Microsoft’s Satya Nadella&lt;/a&gt;, who was similarly an instrumental part of the company’s cloud and server business before taking charge of Microsoft in 2014. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E1OlOh"&gt;It’ll still be some time before Jassy takes over, though — Bezos isn’t set to transition to his new role until Q3 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22263039/amazon-new-ceo-jeff-bezos-andy-jassy-executive-chair-board-q3-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22263039/amazon-new-ceo-jeff-bezos-andy-jassy-executive-chair-board-q3-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-02T15:37:54-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-02T15:37:54-05:00</updated>
    <title>Huawei’s HarmonyOS appears to just be a forked version of Android</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="huawei" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f5WlBTNUf0uld9UdFsx5duTpxpE=/0x0:1820x1213/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68758861/VRG_ILLO_1777_Huawei_004.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4bmwHs"&gt;HarmonyOS is Huawei’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/9/20798251/huawei-harmonyos-hongmengos-smartphones-internet-of-things-operating-system-android"&gt;alternative operating system&lt;/a&gt; that was created after the company was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/15/18216988/white-house-huawei-china-equipment-ban-trump-executive-order"&gt;banned in the US&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/19/18631558/google-huawei-android-suspension"&gt;lost its Android license&lt;/a&gt;. The reality is the operating system is less of a new alternative and more of a slapdash fork of Android 10, according to &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/02/harmonyos-hands-on-huaweis-android-killer-is-just-android/"&gt;a new report from Ron Amadeo at &lt;em&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yvu2dR"&gt;HarmonyOS was initially pitched as a wholly distinct OS from Android and iOS, something that would be just as at home on smart home appliances (like the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/19/20873710/huawei-vision-4k-tv-announced-features-mate-30-pro-event"&gt;Honor Vision TV&lt;/a&gt;) as it would on smartphones. The announcement was a hopeful promise that losing access to US businesses wouldn’t stop Huawei from innovating, but Amadeo’s experience with the beta highlights some disappointing discoveries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="eujOB3"&gt;Getting developer access requires a two-day background check that includes sending copies of your passport, personal ID, and credit card to Huawei&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yqieKq"&gt;You don’t actually run the beta OS in its emulator; it’s streamed to you, Google Stadia-style, from (presumably) a phone running the beta in China&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="iwqJcC"&gt;Most importantly, HarmonyOS seems to be a fork of Android 10 with the word “Android” find-and-replaced with “Harmony”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="Ow4yn5"&gt;HarmonyOS was likely always going to be most popular in China, but the fact that the new OS appears to be a continuation of Huawei’s EMUI skin with potentially slower access to Android updates through the Open Source Android Project is a major strike against it being used anywhere else. It might be good enough to not offend the US government and satisfy Chinese authorities, but quick text edits and an invasive application process do not an appetizing operating system make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IXXBHz"&gt;Read &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/02/harmonyos-hands-on-huaweis-android-killer-is-just-android/"&gt;Amadeo’s whole deep dive&lt;/a&gt; of detective work dissecting the beta, along with some jabs at Huawei’s fluff-filled developer documentation for a hypothetical “super virtual device,” over at&lt;em&gt; Ars Technica&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22262527/harmonyos-huawei-us-ban-android-google-ars-technica"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22262527/harmonyos-huawei-us-ban-android-google-ars-technica</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
