<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-15T03:49:50-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T03:49:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T03:49:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nintendo’s Metroid Dread has a bug: here’s how to avoid it</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="metroid dread" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/G7SUMxy5J4W8gZ0vwNgYEd54PUU=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69998140/Switch_MetroidDread_screen_02.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dread is the first all-new 2D Metroid in almost 20 years.&lt;/em&gt; | Screenshot: Metroid Dread&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BnzV3e"&gt;Nintendo is working to fix a bug in recently-released &lt;em&gt;Metroid Dread&lt;/em&gt; that could halt your progression if you’re unlucky enough to encounter it, the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1448816874423308288"&gt;company has announced&lt;/a&gt;. According to a &lt;a href="https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/p/989/a_id/56652"&gt;support page&lt;/a&gt; the bug causes the error message “The software was closed because an error occurred,” forcing it to close unexpectedly. Nintendo says the patch will be released before the end of the month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ajQTxC"&gt;Until this patch is released, however, players will need to avoid triggering the bug, which can apparently occur near the end of the game if the player “destroys a door while a map marker for that specific door is displayed on the map.” Thankfully, that means recovering from the crash when it occurs is fairly simple. Here’s what Nintendo says you should do if your game crashes: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="EfnWvb"&gt;“Restart the game and, before playing through this sequence, remove the door icon map marker to prevent this error from occurring.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="PHuuZj"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Metroid Dread&lt;/em&gt; was released last week on October 8th, and represents the first all-new 2D Metroid game in almost two decades (not including remakes like &lt;em&gt;Metroid: Samus Returns&lt;/em&gt;). It’s been broadly positively received, although &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/6/22710468/metroid-dread-review-nintendo-switch"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s own Andrew Webster&lt;/a&gt; notes that the game’s controls can struggle to keep up with its more hectic action sequences, of which there are far too many.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22727796/metroid-dread-bug-nintendo-patch-progression-door-marker-door-destroy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22727796/metroid-dread-bug-nintendo-patch-progression-door-marker-door-destroy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-14T20:41:18-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-14T20:41:18-04:00</updated>
    <title>Clubhouse has a new Music Mode that could make it the place to play</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Surveillance Fears After Clubhouse App Takes Saudi By Storm" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jnNetxPxfp1nMIl_ZOMId1NETDM=/0x2:8192x5463/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69997400/1231631262.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Jaap Arriens/NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="i9zjy8"&gt;Clubhouse has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22362980/clubhouse-social-audio-facebook-twitter-android"&gt;a tremendous amount of competition&lt;/a&gt; from big companies that want to own the live audio space, but it may be getting out ahead in one specific way. The company’s launching a new Music Mode that could make it a better place to play — and listen — to live music, ahead of &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/amazon-live-audio-clubhouse-competitor-ea0ead59-f6d3-49a0-a216-a4105e0338ba.html"&gt;Amazon’s reported entry&lt;/a&gt; into that space, and as Twitter &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/27/22644283/twitter-ticketed-spaces-live-audio-test"&gt;has begun rolling out “ticketed spaces”&lt;/a&gt; where musicians could host shows as well. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22535214/spotify-greenroom-locker-room-live-audio-app"&gt;Spotify has its own live audio app, too&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OBmBa8"&gt;If you’re a musician on Clubhouse, or you love listening to live music on the app, the new Music Mode “optimizes Clubhouse to broadcast your music with high quality and great stereo sound,” according to &lt;a href="https://blog.clubhouse.com/music-mode-hallway-search/"&gt;the company’s blog post&lt;/a&gt;. Clubhouse doesn’t say what it means by high quality, but it does also mention that you can now hook up professional equipment, like a USB mic or mixing board, and use it during your broadcast. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/30/22648050/clubhouse-spatial-audio-3d-360-sound"&gt;Clubhouse already added spatial audio in late August&lt;/a&gt;, which makes conversations sound more like a room full of people than a flat audio call.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Clubhouse Music Mode" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y-9FrQbbygiI7K2bVwOlHoxRgK8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22927960/clubhouse_music_mode.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF by Clubhouse&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="S8LLiV"&gt;You can easily turn on Music Mode by tapping the three dots in the top right corner of a room, selecting Audio Quality, and then choosing Music. If you just want to listen to the performance, however, you won’t have to do any of this — just sit back and enjoy stereo audio from your headphones, speakers, or your phone itself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1RLSae"&gt;Clubhouse also noted that its recently introduced Clips feature — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22702034/clubhouse-recording-in-app-clip-tool-update"&gt;which lets you capture a 30-second recording&lt;/a&gt; — will support stereo sound as well, so if you decide to save a snippet of a performance in Music Mode, the audio quality will stay the same. Music Mode will initially only be available on iOS, but Clubhouse says that the rollout to Android will follow shortly behind. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5g6c8V"&gt;Aside from Music Mode, Clubhouse has also updated its search feature. The platform will now display the search bar in a more convenient location at the top of your hallway. And as an added plus, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22690029/clubhouse-wave-invites-audio-chats"&gt;you’ll also be able to Wave to friends&lt;/a&gt; right from the search bar, a feature that lets you quickly invite friends to a live audio room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5q6xYJ"&gt;Amazon is far from Clubhouse’s only competition for live audio. Clubhouse likely learned its lesson this past year, when &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22362980/clubhouse-social-audio-facebook-twitter-android"&gt;Twitter, Facebook, LinkedIn, and even Spotify made their own versions of audio-only chatrooms&lt;/a&gt;. All of this came at a time when Clubhouse was still in an invite-only state, making it harder for the app to grow. But now that the app is thriving, Clubhouse wants keep as many advantages as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22727164/clubhouse-music-mode-compete-amazon-twitter"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22727164/clubhouse-music-mode-compete-amazon-twitter</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-14T19:50:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-14T19:50:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook execs tease VR prototype hardware with new photos</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/v7-l0N8nmrT1PU6wpZZFsnAuqqc=/0x178:843x740/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69990835/245329931_10113982963136581_574941966054337503_n.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Facebook&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="M9WeKB"&gt;Mark Zuckerberg and Facebook virtual reality lead and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22688510/facebook-cto-andrew-boz-bosworth-chief-technology-officer"&gt;soon-to-be CTO&lt;/a&gt; Andrew Bosworth (or “Boz”) are playing around with prototype VR (or AR) tech and want to show it off. Both executives have &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo/?fbid=10113982963161531&amp;amp;set=a.529237706231"&gt;posted pictures of themselves&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/boztank/status/1448336606360838145?s=21"&gt;wearing prototype headsets&lt;/a&gt; and linking the concepts to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22588022/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-ceo-metaverse-interview"&gt;Facebook’s work&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22701104/metaverse-explained-fortnite-roblox-facebook-horizon"&gt;the metaverse&lt;/a&gt;. While the headsets the two are wearing are in no way guaranteed to become actual retail products, it’s an interesting look at what’s going on in Facebook’s virtual reality lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QybSMc"&gt;The headset Zuckerberg is wearing looks similar to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21437674/oculus-quest-2-review-features-photos"&gt;the company’s Oculus headsets&lt;/a&gt;. However, he identifies it as “retina resolution,” borrowing Apple’s phrase for screens with such high pixel density that you can’t discern individual points at a normal operating distance. The headsets Boz shows off have more intriguing designs — one looks, to be frank, almost exactly like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266190/apple-vr-headset-ar-glasses-8k-displays-cameras-hand-tracking-details-report"&gt;drawings and descriptions of Apple’s rumored VR headset&lt;/a&gt;. The other one looks like it either has a very large strap or a cap that holds it onto his head, along with a wire sticking out of the contraption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="m2P08e"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Proud of the research Michael Abrash's team is working on at FRL-R Redmond—excited to get an early look at some of the technologies that will underpin the metaverse (we work on several prototype headsets to prove out concepts, this is one of them. Kind of. It's a long story.) &lt;a href="https://t.co/Yi9xjy5HmG"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Yi9xjy5HmG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Boz (@boztank) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/boztank/status/1448336606360838145?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 13, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="LSUhWN"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;So. Many. Prototypes. &lt;a href="https://t.co/xGESgGm7pH"&gt;pic.twitter.com/xGESgGm7pH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Boz (@boztank) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/boztank/status/1448401190379606021?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 13, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gKlzXd"&gt;Beyond Zuckerberg’s vague “retina” comment, there are basically no details on what kind of headsets they are, what they’re capable of, or even if they’re just nonfunctional design mock-ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bxxMxp"&gt;
&lt;div class="iframely-embed" style="max-width: 640px;"&gt;&lt;div class="iframely-responsive" style="padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo/?fbid=10113982963161531&amp;amp;set=a.529237706231" data-iframely-url="https://cdn.iframe.ly/api/iframe?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fphoto%2F%3Ffbid%3D10113982963161531%26set%3Da.529237706231&amp;amp;key=9ef4a209439e42bc59783ba959d50197"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://cdn.iframe.ly/embed.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ihcOXc"&gt;That’s perhaps to be expected, given that this isn’t a product announcement from Facebook. While the company has released a pair of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22662809/facebook-ray-ban-stories-camera-smart-glasses-hands-on"&gt;smart (and screen-less) Ray Bans&lt;/a&gt;, which it called a step in the path “towards full augmented reality glasses,” Facebook’s virtual reality lab also teases many prototypes that probably won’t make it to market. That includes things like its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609564/facebook-reality-lab-reverse-passthrough-vr-prototype-research-siggraph"&gt;horrifying eye-projection headset&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/25/22641894/facebook-project-aria-augmented-reality-ar-research-glasses-user-manual"&gt;research-focused Aria AR glasses&lt;/a&gt;, and a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/30/21308813/facebook-vr-sunglasses-research-proof-of-concept"&gt;proof-of-concept set of VR glasses&lt;/a&gt; (which show you a virtual world instead of augmenting the real one). Rather than hawking headsets, Boz and Zuckerberg seem to be selling their metaverse concept, which the company says is a virtual world that could be the next version of the internet. If you want to do a deep-dive into what that means exactly, check out &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22701104/metaverse-explained-fortnite-roblox-facebook-horizon"&gt;my colleagues’ great explainer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="SZy5EY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"What is the metaverse, and do I have to care?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22701104/metaverse-explained-fortnite-roblox-facebook-horizon"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="PeZlPM"&gt;Speaking of experimental headsets, HTC was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22713276/htc-vive-flow-vr-headset-launch-price-hands-on"&gt;getting ready to announce its Vive Flow headset&lt;/a&gt;, and one of its executives hilariously replied to Boz to ask if he’d be willing to trade the prototype headset for one hot off the factory line. Boz declined the offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CNIGbx"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="es" dir="ltr"&gt;no deal&lt;/p&gt;— Boz (@boztank) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/boztank/status/1448366889126686720?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 13, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="blJGLN"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update October 14th, 7:50PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added a second prototype post from Boz, and updated with information about the HTC Vive Flow.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22724876/facebook-zuckerberg-vr-prototype-photos-research-redmond-metaverse"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22724876/facebook-zuckerberg-vr-prototype-photos-research-redmond-metaverse</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-14T19:08:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-14T19:08:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple rehires former HomePod engineer to get its software back on track</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/erYLoVBkWHmT94b0ghPPceTy_wc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69997107/jbareham_180202_2266_0089.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="sheL58"&gt;Apple has hired a former HomePod engineer, Afrooz Family, to head up the team developing HomePod software, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-14/apple-hires-new-homepod-software-head-as-it-takes-on-amazon-echo?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which could signal a renewed effort from Apple to make the HomePod more competitive. The company released &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/17/22679870/new-apple-homekit-features-homepod-mini"&gt;HomePod software version 15&lt;/a&gt; in September, bringing some welcome features like the ability to use one or a pair of HomePod Mini speakers as the default with an Apple TV 4K. But Apple’s smart speaker line faces stiff competition, particularly from Amazon’s and Google’s speakers that are equipped with their smart assistants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HPl4RF"&gt;Family left Apple in 2016, where he was a senior audio engineer, to co-found audio company &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fsyngspace.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F14%2F22727249%2Fapple-homepod-software-chief-afrooz-family" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Syng&lt;/a&gt; with ex-Apple designer Christopher Stringer. (A &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt; article about Syng described Family as the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/b4a88a13-47c3-4bb4-a627-704fdf0c392b"&gt;“secret weapon.”&lt;/a&gt;) Syng’s claim to fame is its Cell Alpha connected speaker, which offers spatial audio in a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22439925/syng-cell-alpha-wi-fi-speaker-apple-designer-death-star-triphonic"&gt;Death Star-like design&lt;/a&gt;, but it comes with a steep $1,799 price tag. Family left Syng earlier this year, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AWEIYP"&gt;The first HomePod, which was released in 2018, was lauded for its sound quality but was criticized for its high price, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22328436/apple-discontinues-original-homepod-mini"&gt;Apple discontinued it in March&lt;/a&gt;. The company released the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21561589/apple-homepod-mini-review"&gt;cheaper and smaller HomePod Mini last year&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TJsjrv"&gt;Apple didn’t immediately reply to a request for comment. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22727249/apple-homepod-software-chief-afrooz-family"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22727249/apple-homepod-software-chief-afrooz-family</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-14T19:04:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-14T19:04:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>Block Party is out of beta and ready to block anyone who likes bad tweets</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ff7pgamXDpEKOIu-KlZIKMuUBjs=/0x43:1024x726/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69997092/blockpartyleadimage.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Block Party&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TVBZ7i"&gt;Block Party, &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/block-party-launch/"&gt;the anti-harassment service&lt;/a&gt; that specializes in making Twitter more tolerable to use, &lt;a href="https://blog.blockpartyapp.com/p/introducing-blocklists-paidplans"&gt;is out of beta and available now&lt;/a&gt;. Block Party automates the time-consuming process of moderating your Twitter feed, filtering out content from people you don’t want to see for later review and, starting today, blocking accounts that retweet or like a bad tweet of your choice with blocklists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HNQaOd"&gt;Block Party’s services are available in three different tiers. Free Basic accounts can use Block Party’s moderate filters to catch @mentions and place them in a “Lockout Folder” for later review. Premium accounts, which start at $12 per month, include stricter filters, block lists, a helper view to allow friends or family to review troubling tweets, bulk actions to block or mute multiple accounts in your Lockout Folder at once, and watchlists for tracking accounts after you mute them. The $13 per month Supporter tier includes all of those features and the opportunity to try new features before they’re released.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KfQIx19am9e3hjO1kDI_G9Bl6ok=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22927904/ezgif.com_gif_maker__2_.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="EsT7JY"&gt;Block Party offers a lot, but the two core ideas — filters and block lists — could make a big difference for anyone who has to use Twitter for their job or has a high-profile account that’s already a target of harassment. The company &lt;a href="https://blog.blockpartyapp.com/p/blocklists-design"&gt;has also tried to be mindful&lt;/a&gt; about how it implements both features. Block lists are capped at 100 accounts per list (you can have unlimited lists) in the hopes that it's a small enough amount you can review the list for anyone you might still want to see on your timeline. Meanwhile, filters can be set to remove spam accounts (new accounts without a profile photo, for example) or tuned even tighter to only show @mentions from people you follow or have replied to recently. Twitter offers both features in some capacity, but it lacks the flexibility, focusing on blocking and muting specific words or accounts, without all of the automation or customization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UPjlv7"&gt;Twitter’s made moves to offer more moderation and privacy tools, too, like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/11/22721218/twitter-soft-block-remove-follower-web"&gt;the built-in soft block tool&lt;/a&gt; released just this week or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22654061/twitter-features-archive-old-tweets-hide-likes-remove-followers-plans"&gt;concepts for ways to hide old tweets&lt;/a&gt; or limit who can see what you’ve liked. So far, though, Block Party has a head start and should make it much easier to make a difference in the quality of your timeline with just a few steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WEk2HU"&gt;You can sign up and read more examples of Block Party’s uses &lt;a href="https://www.blockpartyapp.com/landing/"&gt;at the company’s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="oPoiDh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Why social networks need better blocking tools ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22275568/blocking-clubhouse-block-party-social-networks"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22726988/block-party-availble-now-block-lists-subscription"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22726988/block-party-availble-now-block-lists-subscription</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-14T18:58:47-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-14T18:58:47-04:00</updated>
    <title>Boeing chief technical pilot couldn’t ‘Jedi mind trick’ his way out of a federal indictment</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iYWDIGaGDc0detNkO9O9YWVwRZE=/0x0:2700x1800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69997053/boeing_737_max.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Boeing&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TThO6T"&gt;Boeing’s former chief technical pilot, Mark Forkner, was indicted &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/former-boeing-737-max-chief-technical-pilot-indicted-fraud"&gt;on two counts of fraud and four counts of wire fraud&lt;/a&gt; for his role in the Boeing 737 Max debacle. He’s accused of withholding information from FAA evaluators about software on the Boeing 737 Max that was at the heart of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/22/18275736/boeing-737-max-plane-crashes-grounded-problems-info-details-explained-reasons"&gt;two crashes that killed 346 people&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="2wOeX4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Redline: The many human errors that brought down the Boeing 737 Max","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/2/18518176/boeing-737-max-crash-problems-human-error-mcas-faa"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="e9aiXN"&gt;That software, the Maneuvering Characteristics Augmentation System (MCAS), interpreted the plane as stalling when it wasn’t — causing crashes. Rushed development of the 737 Max required larger, heavier engines that could make it susceptible to stalling in certain takeoff situations. To prevent that from happening, Boeing set up MCAS to automatically pitch the nose down. When the system activated erroneously, pilots were unprepared — MCAS was not present on a previous version of the 737 — and unable to regain control of the planes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cMM9Gt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/18/20921067/boeing-737-max-messages-lie-mcas-faa"&gt;Emails uncovered during the investigation&lt;/a&gt; showed Forkner was aware that the MCAS could make the 737 Max difficult to fly. They also showed that he knew the system was active at lower speeds than Boeing reported to the FAA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iqCzSp"&gt;Forkner &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/18/20921067/boeing-737-max-messages-lie-mcas-faa"&gt;emailed coworkers&lt;/a&gt; admitting that the system was difficult and said, “I basically lied to the regulators (unknowingly),” according to the indictment. Eight months after sending those emails, he pushed for the FAA to remove any mention of the troubled MCAS from its reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CpuM7o"&gt;Forkner is also responsible for pushing against simulator training requirements for pilots before they flew the 737 Max, despite his experience in the simulator fighting the problems that eventually resulted in deaths. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pwc3Z0"&gt;Prosecutors explain that airlines could spend less money on training and more on each plane by lowering the requirements, increasing the 737 Max’s profitability. In another email, after convincing an airline to drop its training requirements, Forkner &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/9/21059420/boeing-employees-messages-737-max-investigation-simulator-crash"&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt;, “Looks like my jedi [sic] mind trick worked again! These are not the droids you’re looking for.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BxfUBx"&gt;Boeing was charged with conspiracy over the incident and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22219370/boeing-737-max-fraud-conspiracy-criminal-charges-fine-crashes"&gt;fined $2.5 billion&lt;/a&gt;. Forkner faces up to 20 years in prison for each count of wire fraud and up to 10 years in prison for each count of fraud.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Boeing 737 Max indictment" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hBFJMOZtV7rpeI3Q8ri-ub_4Loo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22928017/737_max.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: DOJ&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Boeing 737 Max indictment&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="2TFsmk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dkDBRX"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22727244/boeing-737-max-chief-technical-pilot-indictment"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22727244/boeing-737-max-chief-technical-pilot-indictment</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-14T18:13:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-14T18:13:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple Music might be coming to PS5</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PJd5IDl5xln_vvgQMbYd-9yMqaY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69996911/vpavic_4278_20201030_0150.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KPD4mi"&gt;Spotify has been a music streaming option on the PS5 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/22/21528372/ps5-streaming-apps-support-day-one-netflix-disney-plus-twitch"&gt;since it launched in November&lt;/a&gt;, giving you the option to listen to your favorite music when playing games. Soon, though, the console might get support for another service: Apple Music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6CNfL8"&gt;The first clue came earlier this week when a Reddit user &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AppleMusic/comments/q68jxg/since_when_was_this_a_thing_i_made_a_new_account/?ref=share&amp;amp;ref_source=link"&gt;posted a picture&lt;/a&gt; of Apple Music appearing in the PS5’s music menu. The option apparently showed up after they made a new account and tried to link it with Spotify. It seems the app didn’t work, though — the Reddit user also shared a photo of a message that said, “This app is playable only on PS4,” which &lt;em&gt;Eurogamer&lt;/em&gt; says is a standard error message when an app isn’t available.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7QIB-lyPsDb0MJy9raBtK9bB3kg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22927945/lji5211pmws71.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AppleMusic/comments/q68jxg/since_when_was_this_a_thing_i_made_a_new_account/?ref=share&amp;amp;ref_source=link" target="_blank"&gt;u/HOLYWARS1990&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Reddit user’s photo of Apple Music on PS5.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XvArdn"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eurogamer&lt;/em&gt; said it was also &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2021-10-14-it-looks-like-apple-music-may-be-coming-to-playstation-5"&gt;able to see the Apple Music option&lt;/a&gt; when making a new US account, though it wasn’t able to reproduce doing so. The Apple Music option didn’t appear when I tried making a new US account while writing this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ydz91X"&gt;The inconsistency of the Apple Music option suggests that the Reddit user and &lt;em&gt;Eurogamer&lt;/em&gt; may have gotten an early peek at something that Sony and Apple have in the works. The two companies worked together recently on an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22588577/ps5-sony-apple-tv-plus-six-month-trial-subscription"&gt;Apple TV Plus promotion for PS5 owners&lt;/a&gt;, so it seems there’s a relationship there. Apple brought Apple Music to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/23/21231790/samsung-smart-tv-apple-music-app-available"&gt;Samsung smart TVs&lt;/a&gt; last year, showing that it is willing to expand the app’s availability beyond Apple platforms. And the app is appearing just days before &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722112/apple-october-2021-event-rumors-macbook-mac-mini-airpods-m1x"&gt;Apple’s October 18th event&lt;/a&gt;, which would be a potential venue for Apple and Sony to announce that the app is coming to PS5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pdqOap"&gt;Sony and Apple didn’t immediately reply to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22727126/apple-music-app-ps5-playstation-5"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22727126/apple-music-app-ps5-playstation-5</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-14T17:19:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-14T17:19:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>Missouri governor threatens reporter who discovered state site spilling private info</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZxfuTvuN8Du1ZV3-nlM3nh5v4E0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69996666/acastro__171016_1777_0001_v1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustrator by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0tzqrf"&gt;Missouri Governor Mike Parson &lt;a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/10/missouri-governor-vows-to-prosecute-st-louis-post-dispatch-for-reporting-security-vulnerability/"&gt;is threatening legal action&lt;/a&gt; against a reporter and newspaper that found and responsibly disclosed a security vulnerability that left teacher and educational staffs’ social security numbers exposed and easily accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9ha8eD"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.stltoday.com/news/local/education/missouri-teachers-social-security-numbers-at-risk-on-state-agencys-website/article_f3339700-ece0-54a1-9a45-f300321b7c82.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;St. Louis Post-Dispatch &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; that it notified the Missouri Department of Elementary and Secondary Education (DESE) that one of its tools was returning HTML pages that contained employee SSNs, potentially putting the information of over 100,000 employees at risk. Despite the fact that the outlet waited until the tool was taken down by the state to publish its story, the reporter has been called a “hacker” by Governor Parson, who says he’ll be getting the county prosecutor and investigators involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hw6LQK"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.stltoday.com/news/local/govt-and-politics/parson-issues-legal-threat-against-post-dispatch-after-database-flaws-exposed/article_93f4d7d6-f792-5b1b-b556-00b5cac23af3.html"&gt;According to the &lt;em&gt;Post-Dispatch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the tool that contained the vulnerability was designed to let the public see teachers’ credentials. However, it reportedly also included the employee’s SSN in the page it returned — while it apparently didn’t appear as visible text on the screen, &lt;a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/10/missouri-governor-vows-to-prosecute-st-louis-post-dispatch-for-reporting-security-vulnerability/#comments"&gt;&lt;em&gt;KrebsOnSecurity&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that accessing it would be as easy as right-clicking on the page and clicking Inspect Element or View Source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="tpUPCc"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Seeing employee’s SSNs was reportedly as easy as clicking View Source&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LLmsXm"&gt;While the reporter followed standard protocols for disclosing and reporting on the vulnerability, the governor is treating him as if he attacked the site or was trying to access the teacher’s private information for nefarious purposes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EmLkW1"&gt;In a press conference, Governor Parson described the reporter’s actions as “decoding the HTML source code,” which makes it seem suspicious and clandestine. He is, however, literally describing how viewing a website works — it’s the server’s job to send an HTML file to your computer so you can view it, and anything included in that file isn’t secret (even if it’s not physically visible on your screen when viewing that webpage). Governor Parson says that &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GovParsonMO/status/1448697775068229635?s=20"&gt;nothing on DESE’s website gave users permission&lt;/a&gt; to access the SSN data, but it was being freely provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ERj8T9"&gt;You can view the governor’s full press conference below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="R0s8gG"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NxJjLWa9R2g?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=427&amp;amp;start=427" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ieirjt"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;has reached out to Missouri DESE to clarify whether the tool was publicly accessible or required logging in, and in response, the DESE says its only comment (due to the ongoing investigation) is that the data is now protected. Of course, it being accessible at all is an issue, regardless of whether it was behind a login.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xdisiL"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The governor’s response flies in the face of standard practice&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aAxDjO"&gt;Missouri’s response is, to put it lightly, the exact opposite of standard practice. Many organizations have bug or security bounties &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/20/21031350/apple-bug-bounty-rewards-open-program-macos-icloud-ios"&gt;worth hundreds of thousands of dollars&lt;/a&gt;, which they’ll pay to hackers who find and responsibly disclose flaws like these. The reason these exist is that they’ll make your systems safer — yes, people will look for and find vulnerabilities, but there was likely already somebody doing that anyways. With a bug bounty, they’re telling you so you can fix it rather than selling that info on the dark web or using it for personal gain. Obviously, those kinds of sums aren’t reasonable for school districts, which often have underfunded IT departments due to shrinking budgets, but there’re a lot of options between paying out large sums of money and threatening legal action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X05RIj"&gt;Governor Parson says that the incident could cost the state’s taxpayers $50 million. If a malicious hacker had found the treasure trove of SSNs, it likely would’ve been even more expensive: the state still would’ve had to fix the system, and it’d have teachers who would have solid claims against it if they needed identity protection services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="hKQPF1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;You still have to patch vulnerabilities even if you’re not publicly called out for them&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yLlrub"&gt;Governor Parson (along with &lt;a href="https://oa.mo.gov/commissioners-office/news/state-missouri-addresses-data-vulnerability"&gt;a press release by the Office of Administration&lt;/a&gt;) clarifies that the SSNs were only accessible one at a time — a list of all employees’ private info wasn’t included in the HTML files. But as anyone who’s &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/KdtPNRzuKrk?t=119"&gt;watched the opening scene of &lt;em&gt;The Social Network&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; knows, it can be trivial for hackers to download all the pages from an application and strip specific pieces of information out of them. Just because the reporter didn’t do it (it would’ve arguably been irresponsible if he had) doesn’t mean that it wasn’t possible and doesn’t speak to good security practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="KLiNup"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Prosecuting this disclosure will put people in Missouri at risk&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mBP2OQ"&gt;To be clear: prosecuting the reporter, news outlet, and anyone involved will only serve to put people in Missouri at risk because no one will want to report security flaws they’ve found in public systems if the state’s response will be sending law enforcement after them. Security flaws like this are extremely unfortunate, but they will inevitably happen (the &lt;em&gt;Post-Dispatch&lt;/em&gt; reports that the DESE was found to have been storing student SSNs by an audit in 2015). With public entities &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/31/22360409/ubiquiti-networking-data-breach-response-whistleblower-cybersecurity-incident"&gt;and companies alike&lt;/a&gt;, the real test isn’t whether it happens but how you respond to it. Unfortunately, it seems like Governor Parson is failing that test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GoJdnr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated October 14th, 5:52PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated to reflect comment from the DESE.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22726866/missouri-governor-department-elementary-secondary-education-ssn-vulnerability-disclosure"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22726866/missouri-governor-department-elementary-secondary-education-ssn-vulnerability-disclosure</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-14T17:01:27-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-14T17:01:27-04:00</updated>
    <title>IndiEV reveals electric car with a built-in gaming PC but not much else</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b0rCy1P2xWOxn5E_lfo9k4yWpB0=/0x0:5760x3840/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69996587/EV3A4269.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Nm04mj"&gt;There’s a new electric vehicle startup breaking cover in California, making bold claims and teasing pie-in-the-sky ideas while remaining guarded about its founder and origin story. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="afXIPa"&gt;If that sounds familiar, it’s because it’s a story that’s been playing out on repeat the last half-decade. This time, it’s a company called IndiEV, which emerged from stealth mode Thursday with a small prototype electric car called the Indi One that it says will start at just $45,000 — a car it boldly says will launch at the end of 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EM56Pb"&gt;Parts of the script are the same: IndiEV wants to power the Indi One with a scalable lithium-ion battery pack (that can be adapted to fit more affordable or expensive models or future vehicles); It wants to take advantage of the extra room afforded by the simpler architecture of electric vehicles to do interesting things in the cabin; it blends a futuristic exterior with a somewhat minimalist interior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="8oKdAV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Some funny ideas and a bold design&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="f90KB7"&gt;But IndiEV diverges from that script in a few places, most notably in that it’s promising the top tier Indi One will be the “first vehicle to have an integrated supercomputer” onboard, which it says will power all sorts of gaming and entertainment applications inside the car — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/1/22462660/amd-tesla-model-x-s-plaid-ryzen-radeon-rdna-2"&gt;like what Tesla is doing with the new Model S&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UtCVZ3"&gt;When pushed on the details, IndiEV shared that this “supercomputer” is merely a custom Windows PC with an i7 processor and an Nvidia RTX2080 graphics card. That’s not even top-of-the-line hardware, let alone a package that could in any seriousness be called a “supercomputer.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="unS1FI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10807882"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bjbQxG"&gt;One of IndiEV’s marketing reps said during a Zoom briefing that the hope is that the dedicated rig can power “any triple-A game, any virtual reality game, any augmented reality game.” The company showed off what they said was a working, hand-built prototype of the vehicle that had two 15-inch touchscreens on the dash — one for the separate Linux-based vehicle information system and one for the PC under the hood — and illustrations of people using VR headsets in the back seat while being driven around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eRhpAX"&gt;The company’s reps talked about other funny uses, too, like filming drives with the interior and exterior cameras and then editing the footage and uploading it over — you guessed it — the car’s built-in 5G modem. At the very least, IndiEV’s claimed team of about 65 people has created an interesting engineering challenge for themselves, as the “supercomputer” is mounted under the car’s front hood. It’s packaged in a cooler-sized housing that will have to somehow withstand the radical temperature shifts and vibrations that come with driving a car — no easy feat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="px47KG"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Yep, it’s got 5G&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AYSaKW"&gt;Not only did IndiEV claim the car I saw during the briefing was a working prototype, but it says a supplier in South Korea has already built 12 prototype bodies-in-white (the steel structure that sits on top of the chassis) for the Indi One. IndiEV didn’t name any of its suppliers, though data from ImportYeti shows that it had at least one body-in-white delivered to the US from a South Korean company called Merit Inc., an electric motor delivered from China’s &lt;a href="https://www.greencarcongress.com/2021/09/20210922-allison.html"&gt;Jing-Jin Electric&lt;/a&gt;, and battery cells from Chinese supplier Eve Energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sXKtTl"&gt;What, exactly, has been funding all these efforts for the last four years? IndiEV’s head of operations, John Kennedy, declined to say. But the startup was founded by a Chinese mobile game entrepreneur named Shi Hai, court documents and state filings show, who started a company called Snail Games a little more than a decade ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A4lRHF"&gt;There may be a reason why he’s not front and center: Shi and his ventures have been sued three times over claims of racist behavior, poor treatment of employees, and in one case, wrongful termination and wage theft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SXZPba"&gt;In 2014, one of the top executives at Snail Games’ US division David Runyan &lt;a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/articles/2014-11-14-former-snail-games-usa-exec-alleges-racism-and-unfair-dismissal"&gt;sued&lt;/a&gt; the company and Shi, claiming the founder discriminated against non-Chinese employees and made derogatory statements. He also said in his complaint that “working for Shi Hai was extraordinarily difficult as he was a volatile individual who would often make decisions based on raw emotions and snap judgments.” The suit was ultimately settled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="MG2OSi"&gt;&lt;q&gt;IndiEV didn’t want to talk about how it was funded&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kDxFA1"&gt;In 2019, IndiEV’s then-head of supply chain Shawn VanAmburg &lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22927695/1763263201_1_25_.pdf"&gt;sued the company&lt;/a&gt;, Shi, and a number of other founding executives over similar claims. In one alleged interaction, Shi told VanAmburg to fire her male subordinates and hire Chinese women because “Chinese women like to shop and are better negotiators,” according to the complaint. VanAmburg also alleged a number of safety code violations at IndiEV’s Los Angeles, CA facility. Her case wound up in arbitration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3IcLQN"&gt;Also in 2019, a woman named Meng Hua Lee &lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22927687/1780335640_1_41_.pdf"&gt;sued Snail Games&lt;/a&gt;, Shi, and other executives. She stated in her complaint that she worked as a “gopher” for Shi and his wife, Ying Zhou, who was also CFO of Snail Games. Meng was technically employed through the gaming company but said she worked much longer hours driving Shi and Ying around on “work and personal business,” picking up dry cleaning and “retrieving luxury items on their behalf,” caring for the couple’s children at their Beverly Hills mansion, shopping, making travel arrangements, conducting “internet research,” translating, making doctor appointments, cooking and cleaning, and more. Meng claimed she was “on call” for 24 hours a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8EwwyH"&gt;The company allegedly had Meng do many of these tasks for another executive for a telecommunications company affiliated with Snail Games, too, on top of her work for Shi and Ying. When Meng tried to get compensated for what she believed should be considered overtime work, Snail Games allegedly bucked. Meng also alleged that Shi often treated her in “a hostile and disparaging manner,” including telling her not to have children because she would end up “dedicating her life” to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="66k2SX"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The founder has been accused of bad behavior in lawsuits&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PsvPjH"&gt;Meng started submitting time cards for what she believed were unpaid wages in 2019. In June of that year, “shortly after” she dropped off Shi at Los Angeles International Airport, she was fired over email. The two sides are still apparently working out a settlement agreement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aBvhVm"&gt;A spokesperson for the company said these lawsuits are “all frivolous” and that they have been resolved. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NPPr95"&gt;As for how IndiEV originally came together, it’s still not totally clear. Beyond Shi, some of the earliest employees included a former human resources manager from Faraday Future, as well as Miles Bernal, the man who once claimed in his own lawsuit to have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/transportation/2017/12/12/16651026/faraday-future-investigation-money-debt-finances-yueting"&gt;run operations at the mansions Faraday Future founder Jia Yueting bought on the Pacific Ocean&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="03YzcB"&gt;For what it’s worth, IndiEV is at least now trying to engage with the public about what it’s doing, as opposed to something like fellow California EV startup Alpha Motors, which has &lt;a href="https://www.greencarreports.com/news/1133401_confusion-brews-as-retro-style-ev-startup-alpha-motor-turns-on-the-charm"&gt;done nothing to date to prove it’s not some kind of joke or scam&lt;/a&gt;. But like many other EV startups to emerge from California in recent years know well —  from Faraday Future to Fisker Inc. to Karma Automotive — IndiEV likely has an incredibly hard road ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22726631/indiev-indi-one-electric-car-founder-shi-hai-lawsuits"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22726631/indiev-indi-one-electric-car-founder-shi-hai-lawsuits</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-14T16:32:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-14T16:32:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>Deathloop’s huge new update brings DLSS, DualSense audio for PC, crash fixes, and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b0eoHjN-MZO-6aZ6i-HEU4jAQBY=/477x0:2637x1440/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69996388/deathloop.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="03Ljq9"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671207/deathloop-review-ps5-pc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deathloop&lt;/em&gt; is an incredible game&lt;/a&gt; but also one with its fair share of nasty issues, particularly on PC — where some have experienced seriously stuttery performance and a nasty crash just as &lt;em&gt;you’re&lt;/em&gt; supposed to crash the game’s penultimate party. Now, it appears Arkane Studios is coming fast and furious with the fixes and a little something extra as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="esTha6"&gt;&lt;a href="https://bethesda.net/en/article/5PwYCbups6Rw217NBm46gw/deathloops-game-update-1-now-available"&gt;A new 11GB update&lt;/a&gt; can add extra immersion to PC by letting you hear Julianna’s radio transmissions through a connected PS5 controller. Plus there’s brand-new support for Nvidia DLSS, letting you potentially eke out a substantial amount of extra performance if you’re willing to exchange your native resolution for a slickly AI-upscaled version. (The game supported &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/22/22545441/amd-dlss-fidelityfx-super-resolution-fsr-supersampling-tests-benchmarks"&gt;AMD’s rival FSR&lt;/a&gt; from the get-go.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KHIEz4"&gt;The patch (which is 5GB on PS5) also includes “improved NPC pathing and reactions to the player,” which would seem to address an issue the community’s had with how dumb the AI can sometimes seem, and an HDR calibration screen that you got on PC but was missing from the console release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cG64uU"&gt;For PC, I’m hoping “improved performance and stability, especially with ray tracing” means no more crashes at Aleksis’ party in the evening. “Fixed issues that were causing dropped frames and hitches in camera movement” is obviously an intended fix for the stuttering &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lu_XHyO-6zY"&gt;that &lt;em&gt;Digital Foundry&lt;/em&gt; uncovered&lt;/a&gt; last month, but keep in mind that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22684588/deathloop-stutter-pc-game-nvidia-amd-rtx-vrr-gsync-vsync-fps-framerate"&gt;there were several distinct issues&lt;/a&gt; and Bethesda already released a patch on September 21st that fixed some of them. I haven’t had the issue since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I8quHX"&gt;Here’s the full changelog: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="dUi5ix"&gt;PlayStation 5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="FVvdgY"&gt;Added HDR calibration screen to UI options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="R4j8eO"&gt;Improved performance and stability when ray tracing is turned on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="bc16QL"&gt;Improved NPC pathing and reactions to the player&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Z5I8Uh"&gt;Added an indicator of poor connection quality in the upper right of the screen (resembles a speedometer with an exclamation point)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NJVOyV"&gt;Improved the content of PS5 Activities &amp;amp; Game Help systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JKPxvw"&gt;Improved vibrations on DualSense controller&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="f1NZfx"&gt;Improved audio mix quality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vXSiCZ"&gt;Fixed laser mines, turrets, and fireworks behavior for both Colt and Julianna players&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DWMd4O"&gt;Fixed unlock issue with “Oops” and “Deathday Suit” trophies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="QpqWeL"&gt;Fixed issue that could cause Colt’s progression to be reset even if player chose “no” on confirmation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="yJvmI5"&gt;Fixed crash issue when a player unlocks a feat using Havoc while playing as Julianna&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PIrjL0"&gt;Fixed Aleksis Dorsey reactions, making him easier to identify among his party guests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="K0saPi"&gt;Fixed issue that was causing assassinations to glitch sometimes while playing as Julianna&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="VM7RjB"&gt;Julianna’s actions no longer directly unlock trophies for Colt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ckSOvL"&gt;Julianna players will no longer hear radio conversations meant for only Colt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="u67eSN"&gt;Fixed issue with leaning inconsistency (inputs will no longer be ignored sporadically)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Ci7xkn"&gt;PC&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="lZ7oFl"&gt;Fixed issues that were causing dropped frames and hitches in camera movement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="iBhI8D"&gt;Added support for Nvidia DLSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="IAFVtT"&gt;Added support for Sony DualSense controller audio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="iEXCcN"&gt;Added an indicator of poor connection quality in the upper right of the screen (resembles a speedometer with an exclamation point)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="t4nZez"&gt;Improved performance and stability, especially with ray tracing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DFuazr"&gt;Improved NPC pathing and reactions to the player&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="W8c8OA"&gt;Improved audio mix quality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="2xwwby"&gt;Fixed laser mines, turrets, and fireworks for both Colt and Julianna players&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="UFBVVl"&gt;Fixed issue with mouse wheel. Using the mouse wheel to switch between weapons will now work properly and will not cause weapons to be dropped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="f02ERC"&gt;Fixed unlock issue with “Oops” and “Deathday Suit” achievements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="25rkP3"&gt;Fixed issue that could cause Colt’s progression to be reset even if player chose “no” on confirmation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WgC9ED"&gt;Fixed crash issue when a player unlocks a feat using Havoc while playing as Julianna&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qhIKHX"&gt;Fixed Aleksis Dorsey reactions, making him easier to identify among his party guests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="s13prw"&gt;Fixed issue that was causing assassinations to glitch sometimes while playing as Julianna&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="CpP5SQ"&gt;Julianna’s actions will no longer directly unlock achievements for Colt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="O2WIp2"&gt;Julianna players will no longer hear radio conversations meant for only Colt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="gP6qHr"&gt;Fixed issue with leaning inconsistency (inputs will no longer be ignored sporadically)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="yB6x2A"&gt;It’s nice to see Nvidia’s DLSS come to games retroactively: &lt;em&gt;Rise of the Tomb Raider&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; Shadow of the Tomb Raider&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Chivalry 2&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-us%2Fgeforce%2Fnews%2Foctober-2021-rtx-dlss-game-updates%2F%3Fncid%3Dem-news-272931%26mkt_tok%3DNTYwLU5CUy03NTMAAAGAGZhjqL7_HVkTviPL6NdQx_YeH6KQshSplO4Y6hbqLOxbwtkvrRDCG29B_NvTHIe7hqP6Ao8QjuMs8BRp_oZ57PdOLVJElDWSoLXU0IgpZ30T%23cid%3D_em-news_en-us&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F14%2F22726925%2Fdeathloop-update-dlss-dualsense-npc-hdr-colt-julianna" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;are also adding it this month&lt;/a&gt;, among other games.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22726925/deathloop-update-dlss-dualsense-npc-hdr-colt-julianna"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22726925/deathloop-update-dlss-dualsense-npc-hdr-colt-julianna</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
