<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-13T14:33:31-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T14:33:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T14:33:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>Pinterest will now let workers blow the whistle on harassment and discrimination, despite NDAs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rbSBaUeZa0oOqO--xfRjXLBqF1c=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69120299/acastro_200902_1777_pinterest_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3lIChp"&gt;Pinterest has been battered with accusations of workplace discrimination for many months, and we’ve followed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/11/21429619/pinterest-workplace-discrimination-finance-team-unequal-culture-bias"&gt;a large portion&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/14/21369035/pinterest-virtual-walkout-protest-discrimination-slack-blind"&gt;of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21755406/pinterest-shareholders-lawsuit-sue-toxic-work-culture-discrimination"&gt;that&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/14/22175043/pinterest-gender-discrimination-lawsuit-settlement-coo-francoise-brougher"&gt;saga&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22178609/pinterest-wilmer-hale-workplace-culture-report-gender-discrimination-lawsuit"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;em&gt;The Verge. &lt;/em&gt;That includes,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;most recently, how Ifeoma Ozoma, a former Pinterest employee who accused the company of trying to silence her, helped draft California’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/8/22272779/silenced-no-more-act-california-nda-employees-workplace-harassment"&gt;new Silenced No More Act&lt;/a&gt;. Today, Ozoma is &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/13/opinion/nda-work-discrimination.html"&gt;speaking out in &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; about why she believes nondisclosure agreements (NDAs) should not be allowed to keep whistleblowers in check — but Pinterest now says, effective immediately, it will stop making workers sign NDAs that prevent them from talking about such things. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XjuF08"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.protocol.com/pinterest-silenced-no-more-act"&gt;That’s the news from &lt;em&gt;Protocol&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Pinterest will “not require employees to sign agreements that would prevent them from talking about their personal experiences at Pinterest after they leave,” according to the company’s global head of communications. It sounds like NDAs for other forms of company secrets will continue on, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bz82Ue"&gt;Pinterest CEO Ben Silbermann also reportedly issued a staff memo this morning about the Silenced No More Act, where he came out in support of the bill. “Regardless of what happens in the legislature, whether the bill moves forward or not, we’re going to adopt the policies behind the proposed law,” he reportedly wrote, according to &lt;em&gt;Protocol. &lt;/em&gt;Silbermann was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21755406/pinterest-shareholders-lawsuit-sue-toxic-work-culture-discrimination"&gt;one of the executives sued in December&lt;/a&gt; for allegedly creating a toxic work environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="UqkveN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Inside Pinterest, more tales of workplace discrimination","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/11/21429619/pinterest-workplace-discrimination-finance-team-unequal-culture-bias"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="c9Nell"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GYDePj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VKTO5y"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382148/pinterest-silenced-no-more-act-sb331-discrimination-harassment"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382148/pinterest-silenced-no-more-act-sb331-discrimination-harassment</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T14:18:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T14:18:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>How the Johnson &amp; Johnson pause could move the needle on vaccine fears</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DwX3XuymUoy4jd3NY6ubGNwIJx8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69120209/acastro_210309_1777_vaccine_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bVRBe9"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381469/covid-vaccine-pause-blood-clots-johnson-fda-cdc"&gt;Today’s announcement&lt;/a&gt; that federal officials have recommended pausing use of the Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson COVID-19 vaccine might hurt efforts to encourage people to get vaccinated. But — critically — that doesn’t mean the federal officials shouldn’t have made the recommendation, says Melanie Kornides, an assistant professor at the University of Pennsylvania School of Nursing who studies why some people are hesitant to take vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ajnh35"&gt;“Some people are missing the message — they’re so worried about hesitancy, that they’re not seeing how important it is to address the safety, in order to make people feel less hesitant,” she says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QSOrRd"&gt;The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) and Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) recommended the pause while they investigate six reports of rare blood clots in people who received the Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson vaccine. The specific illnesses were unusual: the patients had a rare type of blood clot in their brains &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; very low levels of platelets, a type of blood cell involved in clotting. Similar clotting disorders were seen in the AstraZeneca vaccine, which uses the same vaccine technology as Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson. This combination of clots and low platelets needs a different type of treatment than normal blood clots, and the federal agencies wanted time to look into the cases and tell doctors what symptoms to watch for. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YxYTe6"&gt;“I think that they did the right thing,” Kornides says. “The worst possible thing that they could do would be — if they had a legitimate concern, which it seems like they did — to investigate it without announcing, which would make it seem like they were covering something up.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="hCzFBY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I think that they did the right thing.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9adYov"&gt;Still, flagging a potential safety concern to the public could make some people more reluctant to get the vaccine, Kornides says. Even if it turns out the blood clots were not linked to the vaccine or that they were extremely rare, the pause might make people hold off on getting a vaccine. The biggest worry is for people who were already on the fence about the shots. Those people may now decide to wait longer to get their vaccine or be nudged toward turning one down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I7C3wV"&gt;The Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson vaccine was the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DrewAltman/status/1376921970072154112"&gt;shot of choice&lt;/a&gt; for the group of people that was on the fence — it’s only one shot and had fewer common side effects. “It’s going to introduce new fears for those people,” Kornides says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hahtQQ"&gt;It’s a bad time to lose ground with that group: in some states, supply of the COVID-19 vaccine has already &lt;a href="https://www.hawaiinewsnow.com/2021/04/11/with-vaccine-supply-exceeding-demand-maui-health-officials-urge-residents-get-their-shots/"&gt;started to&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.idahopress.com/eyeonboise/idaho-will-soon-have-more-covid-vaccine-supply-than-demand-official-says/article_e311f334-b555-5bd6-b321-ac4158f8a31f.html"&gt;exceed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.cbs17.com/community/health/coronavirus/covid-19-vaccine-supply-could-soon-exceed-demand-gov-cooper-says/"&gt;demand&lt;/a&gt;. In those areas, health officials and doctors are trying to encourage people to get vaccinated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="koHPsD"&gt;Luckily, there are two other vaccines available (the Pfizer / BioNTech and Moderna shots), and these safety issues have not been seen in the more than 100 million people who received them. People worried about the very rare blood clots could be convinced to get those instead. Anthony Fauci, director of the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, highlighted that point during a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8coTfdqYv6c"&gt;White House press briefing today&lt;/a&gt;. “There have been no red flag signals from those,” said Fauci.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kBUoiB"&gt;From a messaging perspective, the pause could be communicated as a positive sign and an indication that the FDA is taking safety seriously. “They’re not hiding anything,” Kornides says. It shows that people can be confident that the system watches out for any problems, even rare ones. Fauci stressed in the press briefing that the investigation should be left to the health officials. “You want to make sure that safety is the important issue here,” he said. “We are totally aware that this is a very rare event. We want to get this worked out as quickly as we possibly can.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="UoKcp8"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“You want to make sure that safety is the important issue here.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CfYUk7"&gt;It’s a good message, even if there’s a chance it might not win out in the back-and-forth around the COVID-19 vaccine. People may still be afraid of potential risks even if they know officials are monitoring them, Kornides says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZU8Ves"&gt;But ultimately, a personal touch may be more effective than public messaging. It’s now even more important for doctors and health officials to hear each person’s individual concerns about the shots and tailor their conversations accordingly, Kornides says. If someone is worried about the blood clots, for example, a doctor can explain the rarity of the reaction or encourage them to take one of the other vaccine types. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JF2t7r"&gt;The FDA and CDC should continue to be transparent about the investigation, Kornides says. The risk of increasing hesitancy can’t be a reason for the FDA and CDC not to explain vaccine-related concerns. “They had to do this because this is the way that we monitor safety of vaccines,” she says. “Without doing this, you can’t say that it’s a transparent system.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381875/covid-vaccine-johnson-pause-fda-cdc-coronavirus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381875/covid-vaccine-johnson-pause-fda-cdc-coronavirus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T13:47:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T13:47:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>AMD now offers Ryzen 5000 processors with integrated GPUs, but you can’t buy them yet</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fc-ceqkOieoBa2Q8hL2GY4jx7Q4=/401x0:4720x2879/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69119979/AMD_Ryzen_5000_Series_Lidded_5.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hta9A8"&gt;AMD has announced a new version of its Ryzen 5000 desktop processors — &lt;a href="https://www.amd.com/en/processors/ryzen-with-graphics"&gt;the Ryzen 5000 G-Series&lt;/a&gt;, which (like AMD’s previous G-Series offerings) adds an integrated GPU to the company’s existing Ryzen processors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="34zznH"&gt;The company is launching six new APUs today. There are three 65W chips for more powerful machines — an eight-core Ryzen 7 5700G model, a six-core Ryzen 5 5600G, and a quad-core Ryzen 3 5300G — along with a trio of 35W GE chips with slightly less power and thermal headroom. And like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/8/21506447/amd-zen-3-ryzen-5000-processors-gaming-cpu-price-release-date"&gt;their GPU-less counterparts&lt;/a&gt;, the new chips use AMD’s 7nm process and feature its Zen 3 architecture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="yPmJda"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10444349"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TlSP2o"&gt;The integrated GPUs here are nothing to write home about: they’re based on AMD’s legacy Vega platform instead of its newer RDNA / Navi process that’s used in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/3/17/22334662/amd-radeon-rx-6700-xt-review-gpu-graphics-card"&gt;its latest Radeon GPUs&lt;/a&gt;. But they do look capable enough for midrange gaming, particularly if you’re only interested in playing less demanding games like &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CkSfxh"&gt;To start, the new chips will only be available as part of pre-built OEM systems — similar to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/7/21/21331824/amd-7nm-ryzen-4000-desktop-chips-apu-processor-prebuilt-systems-intel"&gt;AMD’s Ryzen 4000 APUs&lt;/a&gt; — but the company promises that this time, it’ll be offering the chips directly to customers interested in using them in their own custom-made machines sometime later this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cMr8az"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382081/amd-ryzen-5000-processor-apu-gpu-cpu-chips-oem-prebuilt-graphics"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22382081/amd-ryzen-5000-processor-apu-gpu-cpu-chips-oem-prebuilt-graphics</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T12:59:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T12:59:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix redesigns kids’ profiles to be more kid-friendly</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iVCHIWLRY9UxuSSYzdhv0caYh1k=/53x0:628x383/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69119642/New_Kids_Homepage_1.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Netflix &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/netflix-gives-its-kids-profiles-a-visual-upgrade/" target="_blank"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oxMSq8"&gt;Netflix is redesigning its kids’ profiles to make them more visually appealing and more prominently display popular characters from kids’ shows. You can see the new look at the top of this post, which features a row of a kids’ most-watched shows right on the home screen with characters from the shows appearing on top of the title boxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TA3Bqj"&gt;The decision to include characters was to help kids better recognize their favorite shows, Netflix says. “We wanted to represent a title in the way that kids most recognize it — through the characters,” Michelle Parsons, product manager for kids and family at Netflix, &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/digital/news/netflix-kids-profiles-character-favorites-row-1234950107/"&gt;said to &lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “This is going to be like a kid walking into their own room, where they know where every Lego piece is.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5me7SX"&gt;For a show to appear in the favorites row, a kid must watch it at least once, &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/13/netflix-gives-its-kids-profiles-a-visual-upgrade/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;The shows that appear on the favorites row won’t just be Netflix-made — titles from Netflix’s full catalog can be featured. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="12h2LW"&gt;The revamped profiles are rolling out now to Netflix’s TV apps, and Netflix will test the new look on phones and tablets in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381917/netflix-kids-profile-design-favorites-row-on-screen-characters"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381917/netflix-kids-profile-design-favorites-row-on-screen-characters</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T12:37:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T12:37:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Five things to consider before you sign up for T-Mobile Home Internet</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1TZIzJqFNRIgNYCXWaFZO0zeUIU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69119429/acastro_191108_1777_t-mobile_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;T-Mobile’s 5G home internet may sound like a tempting alternative to Big Cable.&lt;/em&gt; | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0MLEl6"&gt;After a long early life in a pilot program, T-Mobile’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22312155/t-mobile-5g-home-internet-wireless-broadband"&gt;5G home internet service&lt;/a&gt; has finally arrived. The bar for decent, reasonably priced internet service in the US is embarrassingly low, so T-Mobile’s terms might sound like a dream: $60 per month, no contract, no installation appointment, no equipment rental fees, and no data caps. It’s a service that’s very much in its early days, and &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/home/internet/t-mobiles-60-home-internet-service-six-weeks-later/"&gt;reviews so far&lt;/a&gt; note some inconsistencies in performance among other quirks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zgbpDM"&gt;Even taking all this into consideration, it may still sound well worth the potential risks if you’re shelling out close to twice that to Big Cable every month. But before you drop-kick your Comcast router into the river, there are a few things to be aware of if you’re thinking about switching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="zaKGul"&gt;Eligibility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="MeoYKV"&gt;First, and most obviously, is that you may not be eligible for the service. Home Internet isn’t offered everywhere that has T-Mobile cellular phone service; the company is introducing it as local network capacity allows. And even where it’s offered, you might not necessarily be able to get it. To make sure that it can handle the added demands of home internet users, T-Mobile may limit the number of signups they’ll allow in your neighborhood or condo building, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wAxZwQ"&gt;Take a look at &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/news/where-can-you-get-t-mobiles-5g-home-internet-service-lets-go-to-the-map"&gt;&lt;em&gt;PCMag&lt;/em&gt;’s map&lt;/a&gt; for an easy visual of the areas where home internet is currently offered, but for the most precise information, you’ll of course want to &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.t-mobile.com%2Fisp%2Feligibility&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F4%2F13%2F22381885%2Ft-mobile-5g-home-internet-issues" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;check your home address with T-Mobile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3AK7cs"&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="IRBirI"&gt;Setting up wireless internet isn’t quite the plug-and-play experience you get with traditional wired service. You’ll be looking for the best spot in your home to place the Internet Gateway, as T-Mobile calls it. Signal strength may vary from room to room, and even within the same room you might find better signal near a particular window. An accompanying app takes you through the setup steps and lets you self-evaluate your tech comfort level at the beginning to provide an appropriate amount of guidance through the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="WC8zV0"&gt;&lt;q&gt;unlike traditional broadband, you might find a different spot in your home gives better service&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nepUqz"&gt;Reviewers and early testers have noticed that signal strength can also vary throughout the day, so keep an eye on your internet speeds. Be prepared to try moving the Gateway to other locations if you’re not getting performance you’re happy with when you need it — unlike traditional broadband, you might find that a different spot in your home gives you better service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hM81wx"&gt;Slowdowns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="XTCRst"&gt;Home internet service is subject to the same “data prioritization” policies as most of the company’s cellular data plans, meaning customers might see their speeds temporarily drop during busy times for the network. On some plans, this is applied only after a certain data threshold is met, but that’s not the case for Home Internet — users are always subject to this kind of slowdown. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="4uKY6j"&gt;&lt;q&gt;customers might see their speeds temporarily drop during busy times&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aFUL1R"&gt;That sounds like a dealbreaker, but T-Mobile executives that I spoke to said that customers are “unlikely” to experience this thanks to how the company is expanding the service. They say that Home Internet is only offered in places with adequate network capacity, and that signups in a particular area or building may be capped to avoid congestion. That’s reassuring but still something to take into account as a potential drawback if you need guaranteed speeds at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="kDuKlS"&gt;Hulu + Live TV isn’t supported right now&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="gDoDBy"&gt;Tucked away in Home Internet’s fine print is a statement that it’s “not compatible with some live TV streaming services.” T-Mobile clarified this for us, saying that while YouTube TV and Netflix will work, Hulu’s live TV service doesn’t work right now due to a technical requirement. The company says it’s working with Hulu to resolve the problem. If Hulu is your main source for live TV, then it’s a good idea to wait until that’s squared away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="imZe3x"&gt;You can’t take it with you&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="yWK4wZ"&gt;It might sound appealing to take your internet with you when you stay somewhere else, like a vacation home, but that’s not allowed according to the service’s terms. T-Mobile says that’s to make sure that the service is being used in areas with adequate network capacity. Similarly, you can’t take the SIM card out of your modem and pop it in your phone when you leave the house. T-Mobile’s not going to let you quit your cellphone plan that easily.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381885/t-mobile-5g-home-internet-issues"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381885/t-mobile-5g-home-internet-issues</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T12:08:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T12:08:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple officially announces Spring Loaded event for April 20th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iTL7G2zZyAsAExeV48EpMHNwwcE=/0x0:1770x1180/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69119219/appleinvite.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s April 20th event invite.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iSD9V1"&gt;Apple’s next event will take place on April 20th, the company announced today, with an invite teasing the upcoming event with a “Spring Loaded” tagline. The official confirmation came just hours after the company’s voice assistant &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381336/siri-apple-event-april-20th-ipad-pro-announcement-launch"&gt;revealed the date early&lt;/a&gt; when asked “When is the next Apple event?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G8jMEH"&gt;As is typical, there’s not much to go on from the invitation, although the squiggly Apple logo and “spring loaded” tagline could hint at a new Apple Pencil stylus — perhaps one with some sort of clickable button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nekj6J"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;So excited for this one! Only seven more days.   &lt;a href="https://t.co/PVJFcESqh8"&gt;pic.twitter.com/PVJFcESqh8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Greg Joswiak (@gregjoz) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gregjoz/status/1382004503155634179?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 13, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4gTnE7"&gt;The timing of the event does favor an announcement of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22336917/apple-new-ipad-pros-mini-base-april"&gt;new iPad Pros&lt;/a&gt;, too. Although the new 11- and 12.9-inch tablets are expected to have a similar design to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/24/21192146/apple-ipad-pro-review-2020-lidar-a12z-processor-speed-camera-trackpad-keyboard"&gt;last year’s models&lt;/a&gt;, the larger version will reportedly be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/23/21452182/ipad-pro-mini-led-display-oled-contrast-burn-in-screen-technology"&gt;Apple’s first with a Mini LED display&lt;/a&gt;. Other rumored improvements include a faster processor with performance in line with the M1 chip Apple used in its recent Macs, upgraded USB-C ports, and better cameras. A new iPad mini with a larger 8.5- to 9-inch screen (up from 7.9 inches &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/21/18274477/ipad-mini-2019-review-apple-ios-pencil-lightning-specs-price-tablet"&gt;last time around&lt;/a&gt;) is also reportedly coming &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/14/21259365/apple-10-8-9-inch-ipad-mini-ming-chi-kuo-ar-glasses-headset"&gt;in the first half of this year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LMBbA1"&gt;Another contender to appear at the event is Apple’s AirTags, Apple’s long-rumored Tile competitor. References to the trackers, which are thought to make use of the ultra-wideband technology that debuted in the iPhone 11, appeared in iOS &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/28/20936650/apple-airtag-tile-device-reference-ios-13-2-rumors"&gt;as early as 2019&lt;/a&gt;. But despite reportedly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/8/21427380/apple-airtags-tile-competitor-production"&gt;entering mass production last year&lt;/a&gt;, they’ve yet to be officially announced. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="W0QViF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple is reportedly working on new iMacs, MacBooks, and AirPods for this year&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LJpRnA"&gt;Beyond the devices Apple is rumored to be announcing imminently, there are a couple of others that are believed to be on the way for this year, which also have a chance of making an appearance next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SZJFj5"&gt;Apple is reportedly planning a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22233191/apple-silicon-redesigned-imac-mac-pro-rumor-features"&gt;revamp of its iMac lineup this year&lt;/a&gt;, as it transitions the Macs to its own Apple Silicon processors. Rumored changes include slimmer bezels and a design that resembles the Pro Display XDR. Last month, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/6/22316831/apple-store-imac-pro-base-model-while-supplies-last"&gt;Apple confirmed&lt;/a&gt; it would stop selling the current base model of the iMac Pro once supplies run out, suggesting Apple is poised to announce new models sooner rather than later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YLYSOA"&gt;There have also been reports that new MacBook Pros and a new MacBook Air are coming this year. The laptops are rumored to see a return of fan-favorite features like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/22/22244011/apple-new-macbook-air-design-magsafe-charger-report"&gt;MagSafe charging&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/22/22244398/apple-2021-macbook-pro-sd-card-slot-report-ports-refresh"&gt;SD card slots&lt;/a&gt;, while the MacBook Pro’s divisive Touch Bar could be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22232393/macbook-pro-2021-arm-intel-touch-bar-magsafe-kuo"&gt;on the way out&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1CUdJf"&gt;Then there’s Apple’s AirPods. A new version of the true wireless earbuds is reportedly on the way and could arrive as early as the first half of 2021. That’s according to a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/26/21534123/apple-airpods-3-pro-2-2021-chip-design-battery-life-true-wireless-earbuds-headphones-homepod"&gt;report from &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; last year&lt;/a&gt;, which said the new AirPods will come with AirPods Pro-style elements like shorter stems and replaceable ear tips. There are also new AirPods Pro earbuds on the way, which could ditch the stem entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PC2Xy5"&gt;Finally, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; also reported last year that Apple could release an &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2020-12-22/apple-tv-is-missing-the-moment?sref=9hGJlFio"&gt;upgraded Apple TV in 2021&lt;/a&gt;. Reportedly, this year’s model will be focused on gaming and will feature a new remote, updated processor, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/5/22369056/apple-tv-2021-120hz-refresh-rate-support-4k-gaming-arcade"&gt;and 120Hz support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22310826/apple-april-20th-event-date-rumors-ipad-pro-macbook-tv-airtags"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22310826/apple-april-20th-event-date-rumors-ipad-pro-macbook-tv-airtags</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T11:42:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T11:42:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>For many, COVID-19 vaccines come with a side of side effects</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="4 million vaccinations to under served communities" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/81B4nbr901lyfb4DMtzvcReQgdg=/0x1:3900x2601/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69106179/1232163164.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Dania Maxwell / Los Angeles Times via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dtkY1f"&gt;Getting a COVID-19 vaccine comes with a lot of benefits. There’s the protection against a world-altering virus, the ability to travel more safely, and hanging out in people’s houses again. There are &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/24/business/covid-19-vaccine-krispy-kreme-donuts.html"&gt;also doughnuts&lt;/a&gt;. But there’s also &lt;a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2778441"&gt;a pretty good chance&lt;/a&gt; that a vaccine will be accompanied by a few unwelcome side effects. Most of these are pretty benign — like a sore arm or fatigue. Some are more serious, but those are also extremely rare. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YfkShI"&gt;Here’s a cheat sheet&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;to help you figure out what to expect after your COVID-19 shot.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tMmkKj"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are some common side effects of the COVID-19 vaccines?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="tw5nkv"&gt;Your arm might feel sore after you get the shot, and there might be some redness or swelling near the injection site. There’s also a chance that you could develop a headache, fever, muscle pain, chills, fatigue, or nausea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wN4AMa"&gt;This is all according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) which &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/vaccines/expect/after.html"&gt;has a helpful &lt;/a&gt;page about side effects. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="Yxj1SY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9360449"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="NM2a9q"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What if I notice something else, not on that list of common vaccine side effects? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="NiM9Br"&gt;The CDC’s list is of the most common side effects — there may be others that occur less frequently, or that haven’t shown up in studies yet. Researchers are still gathering data on vaccines and their side effects. In fact, one brand-new study is looking for a possible &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/9/22374523/covid-vaccine-period-heavy-survey"&gt;connection between vaccines and irregular menstrual cycles&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oV0MZV"&gt;As with any medical treatment, take note of your symptoms and if any concern you, talk to your doctor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jhnU6o"&gt;If you’re in the US and you want to help researchers gather data about vaccine side effects, you can also enroll in the CDC’s v-safe program once you get your shot. It’s a smartphone-based system that &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/vaccines/safety/vsafe.html"&gt;asks you about your side effects&lt;/a&gt; after you get vaccinated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="FSDOZe"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’ve heard it’s the second shot that gets you — is that true? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ix3B7z"&gt;Yes, if you get a two-dose vaccine like Pfizer or Moderna, your symptoms may be more intense after your second shot than they were after your first. It’s not inherently a bad thing — it means that your body has learned its lesson from the first dose, and your immune system is now ready to fight off the coronavirus that causes COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PfbBqG"&gt;“Your body is primed by that first dose of vaccine.” said Melanie Swift, co-chair of the COVID-19 Vaccine Allocation and Distribution Work Group at Mayo Clinic &lt;a href="https://newsnetwork.mayoclinic.org/discussion/understanding-covid-19-vaccine-side-effects-why-second-dose-could-feel-worse/"&gt;in a Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/a&gt;. “The second vaccine dose goes into your body, starts to make that spike protein, and your antibodies jump on it and rev up your immune system response. It’s kind of like they’ve studied for the test. And it’s acing the test.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="L.A. Churches Act As COVID-19 Vaccination Sites To Reach Minority Communities" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uATeGeOXc2rRRfdk3-xiAEocDCg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22434463/1311704900.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Mario Tama/Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A person gets their first shot of a COVID-19 vaccine in Los Angeles on April 9.  &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="jtdWCn"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is more likely to get side effects from the vaccines? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="8mu22N"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/covid-vaccine-side-effects-women-younger-adults-2021-4"&gt;Younger people&lt;/a&gt; are more likely to see side effects. The immune system gradually weakens as you get older, this is called immunosenescence. Younger people’s immune systems are more likely to react strongly to a vaccine, making them more likely to feel side effects as their bodies go through a practice run of fighting off an infection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kTokuY"&gt;Women are also more likely to report side effects after getting a shot. Many women tend to have stronger immune responses to vaccines in general, and the COVID-19 vaccines are no different. But other factors, including gender bias in trial design, and inconsistent reporting &lt;a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/health/2021/04/10/covid-vaccine-women-report-more-side-effects-than-men-heres-why/7139366002/"&gt;might also play a role&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ez2odz"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;I &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;know &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m going to be sore — should I take something ahead of my vaccine appointment? &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="LoHuwP"&gt;No. “It is not recommended you take over-the-counter medicine – such as ibuprofen, aspirin, or acetaminophen – before vaccination for the purpose of trying to prevent vaccine-related side effects.” the CDC’s &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/vaccines/prepare-for-vaccination.html"&gt;page on preparing for your COVID-19 vaccination&lt;/a&gt; says. Researchers aren’t sure if those medications might change how well the vaccines work, so they ask that people hold off, and don’t take those pain relievers, or antihistamines ahead of your appointment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XnxsaZ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;After &lt;/em&gt;your appointment is a bit of a different story. While the CDC still recommends talking to your doctor before you decide to take medicine, &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/vaccines/expect/after.html"&gt;it also says&lt;/a&gt; that you can take over the counter medications “to relieve post-vaccination side effects if you have no other medical reasons that prevent you from taking these medications normally.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YD6gfo"&gt;If you are sore after your shot, the CDC recommends putting a cool washcloth over the site and moving your arm around. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="EOWjyn"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are some vaccines more likely to cause side effects than others? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="8Seqdv"&gt;Looks like it. A&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22371665/covid-vaccine-side-effects-moderna-pfizer"&gt; study published this week found&lt;/a&gt; that people who got Moderna’s vaccine were more likely to say they experienced side effects than people who got the Pfizer/BioNTech shot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7vWB3z"&gt;Both vaccines are still considered to be safe and effective. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Agriculture Workers In California Receive COVID-19 Vaccination" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bkhaqy_Jupi_A-TSCGqfWzWkTwA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22434470/1310980701.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Mario Tama/Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;People wait in a medical observation area after getting their shot. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bwHK9q"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What about more serious side effects? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="RvL1IS"&gt;There have been some instances of people having a severe allergic reaction to their shots — severe enough that they need to take epinephrine or go to a hospital. That’s one reason why people are asked to hang around for medical observation for about 15 minutes after they get their vaccine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YGYnTS"&gt;Other people might have what is still considered an ‘immediate’ allergic reaction (hives, wheezing, swelling) within four hours of their shot. In those rare cases, or if you are&lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/vaccines/recommendations/specific-groups/allergies.html"&gt; allergic to something in the shots&lt;/a&gt;, doctors may advise you to get a different vaccine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZKNBoA"&gt;An extremely small number of people who received the Johnson and Johnson vaccine developed a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381469/covid-vaccine-pause-blood-clots-johnson-fda-cdc"&gt;very rare blood clotting disorder&lt;/a&gt;. Out of an “abundance of caution” on Tuesday, April 13, the CDC and FDA recommended that the US temporarily pause use of this vaccine. The agencies want to learn more about the disorder, and give doctors time to learn how to recognize it and treat it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hGTiTk"&gt;Outside the US, some researchers have noticed that in very rare instances, some people who get AstraZeneca’s COVID-19 vaccine also develop serious blood clots. This &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/09/health/vaccine-blood-clots-astra-zeneca.html?partner=slack&amp;amp;smid=sl-share"&gt;may be because of an unusual antibody reaction&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s still not certain exactly what’s causing the clots, or who is at highest risk, though it &lt;a href="https://www.canada.ca/en/public-health/services/immunization/national-advisory-committee-on-immunization-naci/rapid-response-recommended-use-astrazeneca-covid-19-vaccine-younger-adults.html"&gt;does appear to be safer in older people&lt;/a&gt;. This particular vaccine is not authorized for use in the US. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vjBW7q"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When should I worry about vaccine side effects? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="pNDFbJ"&gt;The CDC recommends that you talk to a doctor if your side effects don’t go away after a few days, or they start worrying you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="nipVMO"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If I don’t have side effects, does that mean that the vaccine isn’t working? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="9cKpjT"&gt;While it is true that side effects are a sign that your body is building up its COVID-19 defenses, if you don’t have them, that doesn’t mean that the vaccine isn’t working. &lt;a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/if-you-dont-have-covid-vaccine-side-effects-are-you-still-protected/"&gt;You’re still protected&lt;/a&gt;, you just happen to be one of the lucky people whose immune system isn’t being a total jerk to you.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cYMHzc"&gt;Here’s what else happened this week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qaOuuy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Antivirus will be taking a break next week, April 17th. We’ll be back on April 24th.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3BJ7Rm"&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="FkQ8IF"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22370176/covid-19-vaccinated-people-cdc-guidance-herd-immunity"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are we waiting for?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;This week, my colleague Monica Chin asked a host of experts what kinds of measures we were looking for in order to resume activities like travel, theater, and other things that have been considered high risk for the past year. It’s well worth the read. (Monica Chin/&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wLvRdd"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/08/health/coronavirus-hygiene-cleaning-surfaces.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Has the Era of Overzealous Cleaning Finally Come to an End?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;This week the CDC updated its cleaning guidelines, emphasizing that the chance of catching the virus from a surface is just 1 in 10,000. That’s a big change from earlier in the pandemic, when we were all washing everything that came into our homes. Cleaning is still important — especially around someone with an active infection, but many experts now think the bigger risk of transmission is through the air. (Emily Anthes/&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3dDCkX"&gt;Development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="HUPavQ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/05/health/hexapro-mclellan-vaccine.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Researchers Are Hatching a Low-Cost Coronavirus Vaccine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Some scientists are starting trials of a low-cost vaccine that’s easier to make than alternatives. If it works, it could make a big difference in the push for global vaccination. (Carl Zimmer/&lt;em&gt;The New York Times)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O0ejMS"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.statnews.com/2021/04/09/scientists-work-toward-an-elusive-dream-a-simple-pill-to-treat-covid-19/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scientists work toward an elusive dream: a simple pill to treat Covid-19&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Antiviral drugs are incredibly difficult to develop, but some researchers are still hoping they can find “a Tamiflu for SARS-CoV-2.” It’s a highly complicated mission that is definitely easier said than done. (Damien Garde/&lt;em&gt;STAT)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="fHmTOY"&gt;Perspectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="RkevQk"&gt;She grew up in Hungary, daughter of a butcher. She decided she wanted to be a scientist, although she had never met one. She moved to the United States in her 20s, but for decades never found a permanent position, instead clinging to the fringes of academia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="vc64D6"&gt;— In a &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/08/health/coronavirus-mrna-kariko.html?smid=tw-nytimesscience&amp;amp;smtyp=cur"&gt;moving profile for &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, journalist Gina Kolata describes the extraordinary life of Katalin Kariko, an mRNA researcher whose work has been critical to the current push to develop COVID-19 vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vktsaX"&gt;More than Numbers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="flNjhy"&gt;To the people who have received the &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/covid-vaccine-tracker-global-distribution/?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;748 million vaccine doses&lt;/a&gt; distributed so far — thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NEgIM1"&gt;To the more than 134,719,328 people worldwide who have tested positive, may your road to recovery be smooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YQtW82"&gt;To the families and friends of the 2,915,972 people who have died worldwide — 561,074 of those in the US — your loved ones are not forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tZlBNf"&gt;Stay safe, everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u9T0lm"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 4/13 11:42AM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: This article has been updated with information about the CDC and FDA’s recommendation to pause use of the Johnson and Johnson vaccine after extremely rare reports of blood clots. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/10/22377030/side-effects-covid-19-vaccine-antivirus-newsletter"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/10/22377030/side-effects-covid-19-vaccine-antivirus-newsletter</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mary Beth Griggs</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T11:40:12-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T11:40:12-04:00</updated>
    <title>Tech workers at The New York Times have formed a union</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The New York Times HQ logo (1020)" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kEehgjXfmi00a26SS1C3zDZucb8=/3x0:1017x676/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69118961/nytimes-logo-headquarters-stock_1020.1419979248.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The New York Times HQ logo (1020)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mAQKVc"&gt;Tech workers at &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; have &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2021/04/13/business/stock-market-today/new-york-times-tech-workers-form-a-union"&gt;formed a union under the NewsGuild of New York&lt;/a&gt;, and they are demanding voluntary recognition from the paper’s management. The new union, called the Tech Times Guild, represents more than 650 workers from the digital side of the company, including software engineers, designers, and data analysts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uugKtk"&gt;Those employees are not included in the editorial union of &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, which represents more than 3,000 reporters and media professionals at the newspaper and is also organized under NewsGuild. The editorial union has historically excluded employees on the digital side of the paper, even as the company has expanded into more ambitious data and digital work. As a result, the Tech Times Guild is seeking a separate bargaining unit, which would negotiate separately with the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bBgg87"&gt;“As of now, we face a number of challenges,” the Tech Times Guild said &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NYTGuildTech/status/1381973488039256069"&gt;in a statement on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, “including sudden or unexplained termination, opaque promotion processes, unpaid overtime, and underinvestment in diverse representation. Without a union, we lack the data or bargaining rights to address these issues.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r4Q2NI"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; has not formally responded to the union’s request for recognition. Reached for comment, a &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; representative said the company was still considering the request. “Voluntary recognition is a significant decision,” The New York Times Company said in a statement. “We have heard questions from colleagues such as what a union would mean for staff, who might be included in the union, and how colleagues would have a say in who might represent them. We want to make sure all voices are heard.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LI4FaP"&gt;The new effort sits between the media industry, which has seen widespread labor organizing in recent years, and the tech world, where many organizing efforts have stalled. In March, an effort to unionize at Medium fell just one vote short, a defeat shortly followed by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/24/22349175/medium-layoffs-union-evan-williams-blogger-twitter-subscription"&gt;a painful restructuring at the company&lt;/a&gt;. A minority union formed at Google has avoided a vote but has seen &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/30/22256577/alphabet-workers-union-turmoil-global-alliance-announcement-google-cwa"&gt;growing friction&lt;/a&gt; between membership and union staff.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381774/tech-workers-union-nyt-new-york-times-newsguild-guild"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381774/tech-workers-union-nyt-new-york-times-newsguild-guild</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T11:35:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T11:35:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>Ingenuity’s flight on Mars is delayed again as NASA fixes a software bug</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6zc2wUEpjY0Fxkc5LO60RMpQTxE=/97x0:1479x921/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69118923/Mars_Perseverance_ZR0_0050_0671377559_653ECM_N0031950ZCAM05020_034085J.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ingenuity sits in the middle of a field at Mars’ Jezero Crater while NASA engineers on Earth scramble to fix its software.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: NASA / JPL&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZarA9f"&gt;The first flight of NASA’s Ingenuity Mars helicopter was delayed again after running into a glitch in the rotorcraft’s flight control software during tests last week. The mini helicopter remains grounded on the surface of Mars’ Jezero Crater while it waits for engineers to tweak, test, and reinstall the software. NASA said it will come up with a new date next week for the inaugural flight test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uTCjt5"&gt;Ingenuity, the four-pound helicopter that arrived on Mars on February 18th with its parent rover, Perseverance, is nine days into a monthlong test window that began when its four little legs &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/4/22366887/nasa-mars-rover-perseverance-ingenuity-helicopter-drops-off"&gt;touched the Martian surface&lt;/a&gt; for the first time on April 4th. The helicopter has been going through a series of tests and checkouts before flying, which includes &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/6/22368208/nasa-helicopter-mars-perseverance-ingenuity-pre-flight-test"&gt;surviving its first frigid night&lt;/a&gt; on Mars, unlocking its twin carbon fiber blades, and doing a few stationary rotor spin tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WUUhQ7"&gt;The first slow-speed rotor spin at 50 rpm went well early last week, while NASA was working toward a debut flight on Sunday night. But engineers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/10/22377299/nasa-ingenuity-mars-helicopter-flight-delayed-wednesday"&gt;ran into a problem on Friday night&lt;/a&gt; when they went for the high-speed rotor test: Ingenuity’s “watchdog” software detected a bug and prevented the craft from performing the test. Ingenuity was healthy, it just couldn’t do the high-speed rotor spin. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ecJlp6"&gt;Over the weekend, engineers at NASA’s Jet Propulsion Laboratory decided “that minor modification and reinstallation of Ingenuity’s flight control software is the most robust path forward,” NASA said in a Monday night &lt;a href="https://mars.nasa.gov/technology/helicopter/status/290/work-progresses-toward-ingenuity-s-first-flight-on-mars/"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;. Altering the software means independent engineers will have to review and test the changes before installing it back onto Ingenuity’s computer, a process that could take all week to complete.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uUTP99toDwuWuhup9Tbi8-nRfx0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22440783/Mars_Perseverance_ZL0_0050_0671377559_653ECM_N0031950ZCAM05020_110085J.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: NASA / JPL&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ingenuity is waiting on Mars for a software upgrade before it can fly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="kpE0Jp"&gt;NASA said “our best estimate of a targeted flight date is fluid right now, but we are working toward achieving these milestones and will set a flight date next week.” Engineers will come up with a new date for the high-speed test and its first flight after they send the new software through Perseverance’s communications hub and boot it to Ingenuity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zJpa0u"&gt;In the meantime, NASA said Perseverance will continue doing science and prepare for a test of MOXIE, an onboard instrument that will try to produce oxygen from Mars’ carbon dioxide atmosphere. The rover’s primary mission is to search for signs of ancient life and leave pods of soil samples on the surface for a future mission to retrieve and send back to Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BqOk21"&gt;For Ingenuity’s flight test, Perseverance will watch from a football field’s distance away using two onboard cameras. The rover also serves as a communications hub; its onboard Mars Base Station will relay signals from Ingenuity to satellites orbiting Mars, which will beam those signals back to Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="6beDRs"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The clock is ticking&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5GO5xy"&gt;Ingenuity is expected to carry out at least five flight tests within its 31-day test window (or 30 Mars days). For its debut flight test, the craft will ascend 10 feet above the surface and hover in place, pivot, then descend for a landing, lasting about 40 seconds altogether. Subsequent tests are expected to fly higher and travel short distances, but the exact flight details will be determined by how well the craft nails its first flight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T2sgKP"&gt;Ingenuity will need to exert immense power to achieve lift in Mars’ thin atmosphere. If it can do so, it’ll mark the first powered flight on another world, a historic achievement NASA is calling a “Wright brothers moment” that could expand interplanetary mobility to where traditional wheeled rovers can’t travel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u03Fuv"&gt;Ingenuity’s carbon fiber rotor blades will spin roughly 2,400 rpm during flight. For the high-speed spin test beforehand, the blades will spin at 2,537 rpm (while tilted in a certain position so it doesn’t accidentally lift off). As engineers tweak the craft’s software, the clock is ticking. NASA officials have said Ingenuity’s monthlong flight test window can’t be extended if the helicopter runs into more issues before flying. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PautOF"&gt;“The is primarily a science mission for the Perseverance rover, and it needs to get on with that primary mission,” Hårvard Grip, Ingenuity’s chief pilot, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;on Saturday night. “So that’s why there’s a time limit for the helicopter.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381554/ingenuity-mars-first-flight-delayed-nasa-fixes-software-bug"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381554/ingenuity-mars-first-flight-delayed-nasa-fixes-software-bug</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-13T11:25:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-13T11:25:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Discord will block NSFW servers on iOS</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uKg63rQeHQeCdq9q6mwyyfTQeHg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69118838/acastro_210129_1777_discord_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Uq9vCx"&gt;Discord is amping up its &lt;a href="https://support.discord.com/hc/en-us/articles/1500005389362-NSFW-Server-Designation"&gt;restrictions on adult content&lt;/a&gt;, with new age gates on NSFW servers and a ban on accessing these servers from iOS devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ecxUJS"&gt;Entire servers can now be marked as NSFW if their community “is organized around NSFW themes or if the majority of the server’s content is 18+.” This label will be a requirement going forward, and Discord will proactively mark servers as NSFW if they fail to self-identify. Discord previously allowed individual channels to be marked as NSFW and age-gated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gTNdGv"&gt;The NSFW marker does two things. First, it prevents anyone under the age of 18 from joining. But the bigger limitation is that it prevents NSFW servers from being accessed on iOS devices — a significant restriction that’s almost certainly meant to cater to Apple’s strict and often prudish rules around nudity in services distributed through the App Store. Tumblr infamously &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/3/18123752/tumblr-adult-content-porn-ban-date-explicit-changes-why-safe-mode"&gt;wiped porn from its entire platform&lt;/a&gt; in order to come into compliance with Apple’s rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vsOrc9"&gt;At least some Discord users seem to be frustrated by the changes, judging by the reaction on Twitter. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SugarRollArt/status/1381975250661998592"&gt;Several&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bergamot_latte/status/1381935558029545472"&gt;people&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Starwing_Wyvern/status/1381952577412141059"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; that this could make them switch to Android. One said the restriction &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PlexPuma/status/1381826522181435392"&gt;posed a problem for them&lt;/a&gt; since they needed to be able to monitor their server while mobile. The ban seems to be particularly concerning &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Aszabla/status/1381974218317905923"&gt;to art communities&lt;/a&gt; that include sexual illustrations.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381728/discord-nsfw-servers-blocked-ios-age-gate-restrictions"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/13/22381728/discord-nsfw-servers-blocked-ios-age-gate-restrictions</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
