<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-01-11T09:48:01-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T09:48:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T09:48:01-05:00</updated>
    <title>Finally, a doorbell for the pandemic era</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8glMC1_xLR9C6Qek38TxqvMh3Sc=/0x0:4500x3000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68649482/VDB770_doorbell_090220_touchless_cover_03.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Alarm.com&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RlATm2"&gt;Alarm.com has announced a new device for anyone worried about visitors catching COVID-19 from, of all things, their doorbell. Rather than using a button, the &lt;a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210111005239/en/Alarm.com-Develops-the-First-T%5B%E2%80%A6%5Dav1w-UkdSlG3miu0ZZ-LtXjCwD3Ec3ldN_zZCGORvG0LE20YOvo49uqw=="&gt;Touchless Video Doorbell&lt;/a&gt; is designed to chime when its camera detects visitors standing on your doormat. Alarm.com claims this is the “first commercially available video doorbell that rings without requiring any contact,” and that its aim is to “reduce public health risks and make home visits and deliveries safer for all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="taA5tb"&gt;In what seems to be an admission that this is &lt;em&gt;quite a confusing way&lt;/em&gt; to ring a doorbell, there are instructions on how to ring the device printed on its front. Alarm.com is also selling a doormat accessory for the doorbell, which instructs visitors on where to stand so the doorbell can see them properly. Given how perplexed we found most delivery drivers were by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21492740/yale-delivery-box-review-smart-lock-packages-price-specs-features#APBqXP:~:text=In%20the%20five%20days%20I%E2%80%99ve%20had,a%20particularly%20amusing%20thing%20to%20see."&gt;Yale’s Smart Delivery Box&lt;/a&gt;, there’s a chance this touchless doorbell could create similar confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-Ym_76uhFnv4mX6V46APr_L1lwA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22227215/VDB770_doorbell_090220_touchless_cover_03.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Alarm.com&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Instructions on how to ring can be found on the doorbell itself...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4-hVsEzIqHK-LBDszsRee0neFIU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22227217/Video_Doorbell_Product_Image2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Alarm.com&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;... as well as the doormat accessory, available separately.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AKc2xy"&gt;When Alarm.com’s doorbell detects a person, it plays a chime in the home, sends a notification to your phone, and starts recording a video clip. You can see and speak with visitors through the doorbell, and it also integrates with the rest of a home’s Alarm.com smart home security system, so it can trigger other devices like lights when a person is detected. Its camera is 1080p HDR, and it’s also equipped with infrared night vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M5Rr6w"&gt;It’s admirable that the main people to benefit from a touchless doorbell would be the delivery drivers who’ve become vital lifelines for people avoiding leaving their homes. But it’s not clear how much help a touchless doorbell could actually be. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AslAwE"&gt;The latest advice from the US’s &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/prevent-getting-sick/how-covid-spreads.html#share-nav:~:text=Respiratory%20droplets%20can%20also%20land%20on,a%20common%20way%20that%20COVID%2D19%20spreads"&gt;Centers for Disease Control and Prevention&lt;/a&gt; (CDC) is that surface transmission (like touching a doorbell contaminated with the virus and then touching your face) is “not thought to be a common way that COVID-19 spreads.” Instead, COVID-19 is thought to transmit from person to person most often when they’re in close contact with one another, which is something you don’t need a touchless smart doorbell to avoid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K4Vag8"&gt;Alarm.com’s Touchless Video Doorbell is available now via the company’s network of installation partners. When asked, the company wouldn’t comment on exactly how much the system costs, but said the doorbell itself is priced at “under $200.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224537/alarm-touchless-video-doorbell-doormat"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224537/alarm-touchless-video-doorbell-doormat</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T09:27:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T09:27:16-05:00</updated>
    <title>LG used a virtual influencer to announce new products during its CES keynote </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qYoVOMCFLRADUabmxlvrYYahgPw=/204x0:1350x764/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68649365/Screen_Shot_2021_01_11_at_8.40.39_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EnKqTZ"&gt;Reah Keem is just like you and I — she loves working on music, vacationing abroad, and is pretty bummed out about not being able to visit any cool places right now. The biggest difference, however, is that Reah Keem isn’t a real person. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d7kLjH"&gt;LG introduced Reah Keem as a virtual influencer who appeared during its live-streamed CES keynote to unveil the company’s new line of LG CLOi UV-C robots. The robot, which was &lt;a href="https://ces2021.lgusnewsroom.com/press-release/lg-announces-autonomous-robot-with-disinfecting-uv-light-for-various-b2b-applications/"&gt;announced by LG in December&lt;/a&gt;, is designed for areas with high traffic, like hotels, and roams around shining UV-C light that should reduce exposure to harmful germs. Keem’s job was talking about how important the CLOi UV-C was to her own life, using the chance to talk about how excited she was to start traveling again in the real world — a world in which she technically does not exist. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nSmEoX"&gt;She may not need oxygen to breathe, but Keem is definitely leaving her mark on the real world (including living in Seoul, apparently). She has around 6,000 &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/reahkeem/?hl=en"&gt;followers on Instagram&lt;/a&gt; and a SoundCloud page with exactly one song. For what it’s worth, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fsoundcloud.com%2Freahkeem%2Fcomino-drive&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F1%2F11%2F22224601%2Flg-ces-virtual-influencer-dj-reah-keem-uvc-robot#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;it’s pretty good&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xXo5MJ"&gt;&lt;iframe width="100%" height="400" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=true&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F866919088&amp;amp;show_artwork=true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bvOMjX"&gt;Virtual influencers aren’t new, but the appearance of a virtual creator at a highly virtualized and socially distant CES really hammered home how weird this event was. It’s nothing short of bizarre watching a creepily accurate virtual influencer say things like “I’m going to chill in my studio,” working on some sick beats, until the pandemic comes to an end and safe travel can happen again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FsUm8X"&gt;Although, paying an influencer to promote something they don’t really care about seems entirely accurate to the influencer ecosystem. It’s unclear if LG actually &lt;em&gt;created &lt;/em&gt;Reah Keem, or if LG paid her for her services at all; a press release only &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/lg-envisions-a-future-made-better-safer-and-easier-with-its-advanced-solutions-at-ces-2021-301205018.html"&gt;says that LG “introduced” Keem&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xqo0sJ"&gt;Will Keem have a future outside of this one LG live stream? Will she face competition from other big-time virtual influencers, including Miquela Sousa (better known as Lil Miquela) or Shudu? Right now, she’s working on her sick beats in her cool home studio, but the virtual influencer scene is heating up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r5eW44"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224601/lg-ces-virtual-influencer-dj-reah-keem-uvc-robot"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224601/lg-ces-virtual-influencer-dj-reah-keem-uvc-robot</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft’s new Surface Pro 7 Plus has a bigger battery, removable SSD, and LTE</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UEpf2J_noZZUMN5iqFdusniASss=/0x0:2640x1760/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68649235/surfacepro7plus.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft’s new Surface Pro 7 Plus.&lt;/em&gt; | Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bmCEdg"&gt;Microsoft is updating its Surface Pro line today with a refreshed Surface Pro 7 Plus model that is only available to businesses and schools. While the design and screen on the outside remain the same as the Surface Pro 7, Microsoft has overhauled the internals of the device to make way for Intel’s latest 11th Gen processors, a bigger battery, removable SSD, and LTE connectivity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o21kTG"&gt;This marks the return of LTE to the main Surface Pro line for the first time since 2015, but unfortunately there’s no 5G connectivity as Microsoft is using Qualcomm’s older Snapdragon X20 LTE modem inside the Surface Pro 7 Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0G-W1rUduteQFoYcWXv0ZHkBW4c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22219459/Surface_Pro_7__Image_10.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Surface Pro 7 Plus has no external design changes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CYhdpB"&gt;A variety of models will be available, starting with the Intel Core i3 (1115G4) and ending with the Intel Core i7 (1165G7). Only the Intel Core i5 (1135G7) model will have optional LTE starting at $1,149, and the base Core i3 model ships with 8GB of RAM and 128GB of storage for $899. The top Core i7 option ($2,799) can also be configured up to 32GB of RAM and up to 1TB of SSD storage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jSoKOG"&gt;Microsoft is now promising up to 15 hours of battery life on the Surface Pro 7 Plus, up from the 10.5 hours the company claims on the original Surface Pro 7. A small part of this battery life improvement will be thanks to the Intel 11th Gen chips, but it’s mostly down to a move from a battery capacity of 46.5Wh to 50.4Wh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qtFh94"&gt;The Surface Pro 7 Plus also ships with the same 12.3-inch (2736 x 1824) PixelSense display found on the original Surface Pro 7, with a single USB-C port, a USB-A port, 3.5mm headphone jack, and the Surface Connect port. The Wi-Fi-only models will include a MicroSDXC card reader, while the LTE models will replace this with a nano SIM. This does mean that the Surface Pro 7 Plus still doesn’t have Thunderbolt connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ivtYpXChd9ymk5EZuIDV5Tu83Hs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22219460/Surface_Pro_7__Image_4.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The removable SSD on the Surface Pro 7 Plus.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pOBkym"&gt;The Surface Pro 7 Plus has some bigger than normal internal changes overall, too. “We changed the inside quite substantially,” explains Robin Seiler, corporate vice president of program management for devices at Microsoft, in an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “It actually required us to flip the internals in order for us to put the SSD here, so when we did that we also updated the TDM (Thermal Design Model) to create more space for a larger battery size.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QvGh7o"&gt;The removable SSD works just like it does on the Surface Pro X or Surface Laptop 3, allowing businesses to swap drives out for reparability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PZZUlb"&gt;So why no major redesign with thinner display bezels? Microsoft says it’s mostly for consistency because businesses want to standardize on Surface Pro configurations and form factors. “When you look at the Surface Pro X, which has the thinner bezels, there are pretty substantial changes in terms of port locations which is driven by those bezels,” says Seiler. “Thinning the bezels does require significant change in terms of form factor and compatibility with previous [models].”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Qp6_zxJ6nud0F_5La7FP57fXKwI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22219462/Surface_Pro_7__Image_3.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Surface Pro 7 Plus starts at $899.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6WDoAQ"&gt;This focus on businesses and LTE connectivity, at a time when home internet connections might not hold up to working from home demands, also explains why Microsoft didn’t opt for the Surface Pro 8 moniker and make this device available to consumers. “This is simply an extension of a commercially-focused line,” explains Seiler. “It was important for us to signal that this is an extension of Pro 7, for all of the customers who have standardized on that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rZMyfu"&gt;Still, it’s disappointing that a refreshed model with Intel’s latest processors and LTE connectivity won’t be available directly to consumers. Microsoft won’t say if that will change any time soon, but it does feel like the company is trying to draw a line between the Surface Pro as business-focused and the Surface Go and Surface Pro X for consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A3JKBK"&gt;Microsoft is planning to start shipping the Surface Pro 7 Plus to customers on January 15th in the US, and it will also be available in Canada, Australia, New Zealand, the UK, and a large number of European countries.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22218445/microsoft-surface-pro-7-plus-features-price-specs-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22218445/microsoft-surface-pro-7-plus-features-price-specs-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Spotify Kids now supports shared playlists, letting parents control the music</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Sb5ecZ-SzcJhyQ7Bc2ZhVhWfmy4=/0x0:1920x1280/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68649199/spotifykidsplaylists.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Spotify&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mafrIp"&gt;Parents can now influence more of their kids’ music taste through Spotify. The audio streaming platform announced a new feature for Spotify Kids today called Shared Playlists, which allows parents to share playlists they’ve created with their kids. The Spotify Kids app gives kids access to child-approved audio content with the goal of gating them into a safe place to click around and access music and stories. This new feature allows kids to gain access to the content that lives outside those walls, however, with parents acting as the main gatekeeper. Spotify says the idea is to give parents a way to share the music they loved growing up or that they enjoy regularly as a family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p0jT7S"&gt;To share a playlist, parents have to access the PIN-protected area of the kids app. They can then select the music playlists they want to share, which have to have been created by the parent. Songs with potentially explicit tracks will be marked with an E, and if a parent wants to remove those tracks, they’ll have to do so from their Spotify app. The first time they share a playlist, a pop-up will appear asking the parent to confirm this decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ZCY9F"&gt;Spotify launched its Kids app &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/30/20938076/spotify-kids-app-announced-disney-taylor-swift-family-plan"&gt;in 2019&lt;/a&gt; and has continued to expand its reach, along with the introduction of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/12/21255107/spotify-kids-update-app-block-track-listening-history-parental-controls"&gt;new features&lt;/a&gt;. Parents can now view their kids’ listening history and block tracks. Shared playlists is another incremental feature but one that parents might appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22218697/spotify-kids-shared-playlists-adult-app"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22218697/spotify-kids-shared-playlists-adult-app</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>YSL’s lipstick pod gadget will create whatever shade you want</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ebjnuRG8b_WMX4FIatTw3kZHPy8=/0x0:4375x2917/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68649219/Perso1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;L’Oreal&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WA0oSw"&gt;L’Oreal debuted a gadget at CES &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/5/21051109/loreal-perso-ces-2020-gadget-lipstick-foundation-skincare-makeup-beauty-influencers"&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt; that promised to make lipstick shades in whatever color wearers wanted. This year, we’re learning what that device requires to work at home: lipstick pods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4ARHj3"&gt;The Yves Saint Laurent Beauté Rouge Sur Mesure Powered by Perso — yes, that really is the name — takes three different lipstick color pods and squirts their liquid out at the top of the device for wearers to mix. (The pods dispense the YSL Beauty Velvet Cream Matte Finish formula.) When combined, they create the desired shade. The top of the Bluetooth-enabled device doubles as a compact so people can take it on the go and touch up their color as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3UGEoa"&gt;The device costs $299 and is available for preorder today. Each preorder includes two sets of colors in either the red, nude, orange, or fuchsia family. Everything will ship in “early spring.” The device will then be more widely available in September. Custom skincare and foundation pods will also launch later this year. The device charges through USB-C and has a battery life of more than a week, according to L’Oreal, YSL’s parent company.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/c9hUxNdGsCl-ORY6i2rI5golGjo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22220819/VUE_04_white.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: L’Oreal&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="0loNDP"&gt;Wearers have three options to create a shade within the iOS or Android app. They can select from the “shade wheel,” which makes it easy to select a color from a wheel; the “shade match,” which creates a shade to complement an outfit or a favorite lipstick color through a photo; or “shade stylist,” which relies on a “smart algorithm” to choose between three shades that’ll best work with an outfit, again based on a photo. The app also includes a social component that showcases colors other users made and highlights “real-time trends” from “YSL experts” and other users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lp6GQy"&gt;The lipstick pod sets cost $100 on their own and cannot be swapped in for anything other than those pods. Each cartridge is verified through RFID, which allows the machine to detect the formula type inserted in each canal, track its consumption, and offer to automatically reorder the cartridge if needed. Although users can order individual cartridges, they cannot mix and match the pods from different sets. The machine won’t operate if they try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nnqCfn"&gt;Of course, relying on pods is often how hardware companies create recurring revenue. People buy the device once but then are required to keep buying more things to use it. In this case, it’s possible people might go through the cartridges faster than they would a typical lipstick, especially if they use it daily. I, for one, own lots of lipsticks that I rarely use. I get bored of one color and then look for a new one to start wearing — and not always from the same brand. YSL can bank on the fact that people will need to re-up these cartridges directly from its line, guaranteeing that customers stay loyal to its lipsticks and keep paying the company. Pods have finally found their place in makeup.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22218777/ysl-beaute-rouge-sur-mesure-perso-ces-gadget-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22218777/ysl-beaute-rouge-sur-mesure-perso-ces-gadget-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T08:56:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T08:56:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>LG teases its Rollable phone again</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="LG’s Rollable phone." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wW0c4C4hWnVMj6rqgLPTWQQknyI=/63x0:738x450/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68649195/lgrollable.0.gif" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tvwTzY"&gt;LG is once again teasing its rollable phone. While we’ve seen &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/14/21436954/lg-extendable-sliding-phone-teaser-explorer-project-wing-mobile"&gt;brief hints in the past&lt;/a&gt;, at CES today, LG provided the best look at the device so far. Named LG Rollable, the device has what the company calls a “unique resizable screen” that transforms from a phone into a small tablet. The screen slides in and out of place to extend its surface area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="seTZI8"&gt;It’s merely a concept right now, as part of LG’s “Explorer Project” experiments, and we still don’t know exactly what technology LG is using or the size of the expandable display. LG has previously used its Explorer Project to introduce its LG Wing smartphone, with a wild rotating design and two OLED displays. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="LG’s Rollable phone." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bVOdgojsRWxtCMpNnkxZin3zFqg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22227271/3NXKq5k.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: LG&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;LG Rollable is the name for the expandable device.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="H5vgLG"&gt;It’s still not clear whether LG’s Rollable phone will ever make it to market, but the company has now branded this experiment so it seems more likely we’ll see an LG Rollable in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rxazo2"&gt;Other companies are also investigating rollable phone displays. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/3/5/21165069/tcl-foldable-trifold-phone-hands-on-rollable-concept-prototype-display-tablet"&gt;TCL showed off&lt;/a&gt; a number of future phone concepts last year, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21571056/oppo-x-2021-rolling-phone-ar-glass-concept-inno-day-2020"&gt;Oppo also demonstrated&lt;/a&gt; a concept device with an expandable OLED display. Phone manufacturers have yet to move beyond the concept and experiment phase with their rollable phones, though.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224591/lg-rollable-phone-extending-display-teaser-ces-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224591/lg-rollable-phone-extending-display-teaser-ces-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T08:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T08:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>TP-Link’s first Wi-Fi 6E routers are coming this year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DSZn5KSnFBzmCtbS_YT-w5r_Zv8=/0x1:950x634/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68649112/Archer_AX206.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Archer AX206 router.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: TP-Link&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="etLe8B"&gt;TP-Link is announcing its first routers with support for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/23/21231623/6ghz-wifi-6e-explained-speed-availability-fcc-approval"&gt;Wi-Fi 6E&lt;/a&gt;, a huge new upgrade to Wi-Fi that quadruples the available airwaves for faster speeds and more reliable connections. The first four routers it’s announcing include a pair of mesh Wi-Fi systems and two high-end single-unit routers, including one that supports 10 Gbps speeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nbempf"&gt;Wi-Fi 6E routers add a third band of Wi-Fi — so in addition to 2.4GHz and 5GHz connections, there’ll now be a 6GHz network. That network will be significantly larger, too, which should mean less congestion and more potential for faster speeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="rcOeDl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Wi-Fi 6E explained: Wi-Fi is getting its biggest upgrade in 20 years","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/23/21231623/6ghz-wifi-6e-explained-speed-availability-fcc-approval"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="PEBXFM"&gt;TP-Link is planning to introduce two mesh Wi-Fi routers with support for Wi-Fi 6E this year. The Deco X96 and Deco X76 Plus are both tri-band systems, and they’ll use the new 6GHz network as a backhaul to communicate between router notes. That should make for a sturdier and quicker backhaul than traditional tri-band mesh networks, which rely on the smaller 5GHz band as both a backhaul and a way to communicate with devices.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/smmVrdt2q_Sy_TpCvV-uSnYkCio=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22215000/Deco_X96_1.0_01.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: TP-Link&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deco X96 mesh routers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="qSKtJ3"&gt;There is one downside, though: when you eventually buy phones, laptops, and other devices that support 6GHz Wi-Fi connections, these systems will only connect to them over traditional (and likely slower) 2.4GHz and 5GHz networks since the 6GHz network is being used by the routers themselves. The X96 promises speeds up to 7800 Mbps. The X76 goes up to 5400 Mbps and also includes a built-in Zigbee radio to support smart home gadgets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f68mnc"&gt;If you want to connect directly to devices over 6GHz Wi-Fi, that’s what TP-Link’s two other upcoming routers are for. The Archer AX96 and Archer AX206 are both tri-band routers, but because they aren’t mesh systems, that 6GHz band is free to connect with individual devices. The X96 tops out at 7800 Mbps, and the X206 is supposed to reach 10 Gbps, should your internet connection somehow be fast enough to support it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/63C8ATBmRjSDXS3CNn9428_qAAY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22214998/Archer_AX96_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: TP-Link&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Archer AX96 router.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="75iizM"&gt;Prices for the four routers haven’t been announced yet. The first units are expected to start shipping in the third quarter of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MYOU8d"&gt;TP-Link is also announcing a few other products today. The Deco Voice X20 is a Wi-Fi 6 (not 6E) mesh router that doubles as an Alexa-enabled smart speaker (a clever idea but one that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/15/20908082/nest-wifi-smart-speaker-router-assistant-hands-on-photos-video-price"&gt;other&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/8/30/17800146/orbi-voice-alexa-speaker-router-netgear"&gt;companies&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/8/31/17803516/huawei-ai-cube-alexa-speaker-4g-router-amazon-ifa-2018"&gt;have&lt;/a&gt; explored already) and is launching in the coming months. There’s also the Deco X80-5G, a gateway for using 5G as your home internet that doubles as a Wi-Fi 6 router. TP-Link is also announcing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/21979124"&gt;a number of new smart home gadgets&lt;/a&gt; under its Kasa brand, including a smart doorbell and a motion-activated switch.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22213115/tp-link-wifi-6e-first-routers-mesh-smart-speaker"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22213115/tp-link-wifi-6e-first-routers-mesh-smart-speaker</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T08:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T08:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>TP-Link’s new Kasa Smart Doorbell looks just like a Nest Doorbell</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b9GrmnwtyrQ2pEN7gpm6CJJdBrs=/0x0:1500x1000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68649111/KD110_Doorbell.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: TP-Link&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gVwxu2"&gt;TP-Link is announcing a bunch of new smart home gadgets as part of its Kasa line today, headlined by the brand’s first smart doorbell. The Kasa Smart Doorbell captures 1080p video, is able to distinguish between people and other moving objects, and can save footage to either a microSD card or the cloud. It’s paired with an indoor chime that’ll alert owners when someone is at the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yyALgC"&gt;The doorbell is pretty stylish as far as smart doorbells go. It appears to be a relatively compact gadget, with a camera at the top and a button to ring the bell at the bottom. It looks almost identical to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/3/17312166/nest-hello-yale-lock-smart-home-review"&gt;Nest’s Hello Doorbell&lt;/a&gt;, which has basically a sleeker take on the same lozenge-shaped, black-on-white design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G8uwZw"&gt;There’s no pricing or release date yet. TP-Link says it’ll be available sometime in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WaRDbV"&gt;TP-Link is also adding and updating a number of other smart home gadgets within its lineup this year. Among the standouts is a new outdoor camera that can do constant recording at 2K, includes a “starlight” sensor to capture “full-color” video at night, and can record to either microSD or cloud storage. The Kasa Spot Pan Tilt camera is also being updated with 2K video. TP-Link is adding two more light-dimming options, including a motion-activated dimmer and an updated three-way switch. There’s also a new outdoor smart plug with only a single outlet. Those devices are also expected later in the year, with pricing to be announced later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0ylDeV"&gt;Alongside the new Kasa products, TP-Link also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/21977156"&gt;announced some of its upcoming routers&lt;/a&gt;, including the first several to support &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/23/21231623/6ghz-wifi-6e-explained-speed-availability-fcc-approval"&gt;Wi-Fi 6E&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22215083/tplink-kasa-smart-doorbell-outdoor-camera-light-switches"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22215083/tplink-kasa-smart-doorbell-outdoor-camera-light-switches</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T08:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T08:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>LG is overhauling its webOS TV software — and maybe ruining it</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ScBZGJCrmXUnXoXsDok2RwR0nzM=/0x0:1722x1148/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68649116/NEW_HOME_WEBOS_6.0_NA.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: LG&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jh8Ihk"&gt;There’s really not much of a resemblance between the webOS software that runs on LG TVs and the Palm smartphones where the operating system had its beginnings many years ago. But LG’s TV interface has grown to be among my favorites for its efficiency at staying out of the way. When you hit the remote’s home button, a shortcuts bar with apps, HDMI inputs, and other destinations slides up at the bottom of the screen but doesn’t completely overtake whatever’s on-screen. Highlight a streaming app, and an additional row slides up to reveal recommended picks and what’s streaming. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RsxoOp"&gt;Well, so much for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CJ6C5u"&gt;LG is giving webOS a major overhaul for its 2021 TVs. Version 6.0 of the software gets rid of the slide-up bar altogether and now has a full home &lt;em&gt;screen&lt;/em&gt; that looks akin to what you’d find on, well, any other TV. The colorful webOS “blades” interface is completely gone. At least on the surface, everything looks more bland. It’s just a long list of &lt;em&gt;stuff&lt;/em&gt;. You’ve got a hero area at the top with large banners, then “top picks,” followed by apps, home dashboard / your inputs, and a bunch of other categories. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T2gZH0jO_MnSp4giKrI-w0q7GL0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22227074/LGwebos6.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: LG&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="iUDHZw"&gt;LG says “the new home screen provides faster access to the most frequently used apps and streamlines content discovery with the ability to receive recommendations based on the user’s preferences and viewing history.” You can see a big “sponsored” slot in the top left there, so yes, you can expect some ads and paid placement recommendations on the home screen of your future LG TV. (LG’s latest Magic Remote will also have shortcut buttons for select streaming apps including Netflix, Amazon Prime Video, and Disney Plus.) &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LbpTBNwQH-A0Y-vWDTllMsvEoeo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22227255/Screen_Shot_2021_01_11_at_8.37.33_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="VfjcU3"&gt;There will be individual rows for shopping, sports scores, and the ad-sponsored LG Channels — where you can stream free programming — on the home screen. These were all separate areas of webOS before, but now they’re being moved into the spotlight. Unfortunately, LG told me there’s no way to hide rows you don’t have any use for. I really hope that changes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="saqdXW"&gt;LG doesn’t usually bring each year’s new version of webOS to past TVs. So if you bought an LG OLED or LCD TV sometime in the last couple years, it’s &lt;em&gt;likely&lt;/em&gt; you’ll stay with the previous interface. But I’ve asked LG for confirmation on this since the annual changes aren’t typically this drastic.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2gxCqjBOP8fmPv5BsVGpp6I5hvM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22227059/Feature_WebOS_D.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: LG&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Earlier versions of webOS were colorful and less obtrusive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="UUXiJX"&gt;I don’t want to give a thumbs up or down on webOS 6.0 until I’ve seen it first hand, but my early feeling is that it seems like a regression. Maybe it’ll only take a few days with one of the new sets to get a hang of this refreshed layout, and this approach will probably be easier to navigate and more intuitive for non-techies. But I’ll miss the touch of whimsy that webOS on LG TVs had until now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ByIgrC"&gt;On the upside, LG says the new remote will have NFC capabilities, so you can tap a smartphone against it to share content to the TV screen. And the list of voice commands for Alexa and Google Assistant has been further expanded in webOS 6.0. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22223767/lg-webos-6-tv-software-oled-qned-lcd-redesign"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22223767/lg-webos-6-tv-software-oled-qned-lcd-redesign</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T08:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T08:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>LG’s 2021 TV lineup includes its brightest OLED ever</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BaB4HNDCZhuKGwl5KqGnIgUSfMo=/0x0:1872x1248/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68649118/Screen_Shot_2021_01_10_at_11.08.30_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: LG&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ochW0y"&gt;According to LG, 2021 represents a major leap for its OLED TVs thanks to a new “OLED Evo” panel that outputs a brighter picture. Brightness has remained a winning factor for LCD TVs over many years; despite perfect blacks and amazing viewing angles, sometimes an OLED set just won’t get the job done if you stick it in an ultra-bright room. But LG says the Evo panel found in its new G1 series — succeeding 2020’s GX lineup — can crank higher than any of its previous OLED TVs for improved luminosity and HDR. LG likens this achievement to past OLED milestones like 4K HDR and the introduction of 8K. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XuYY4H"&gt;The G1 series will come in 77-, 65-, and 55-inch sizes. It shares the same brains — the fourth generation of LG’s alpha9 processor — with the C1 series. Both lines feature improved image processing and can now “analyze the type of scene being shown and improve the picture accordingly.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aRrfjhj8pB1GwGvqFLAmZhWRLk0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22227238/Screen_Shot_2021_01_11_at_8.15.18_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: LG&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="rvbCaK"&gt;Last year, LG’s CX OLED was picked by many as the best TV for next-gen consoles like the Xbox Series X and PlayStation 5. LG is following up on the CX with the C1, and there’s a new supersized 83-inch model in the lineup. (This is a strong indicator that LG and Sony, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22218693/sony-tv-lineup-8k-4k-z9j-a90j-a80j-x95j-x90j-ces-2021"&gt;announced an 83-inch OLED last week&lt;/a&gt;, are using the same panel from LG Display.) The 2021 lineup still supports VRR, G-Sync, and FreeSync, and it gets a brand-new “Game Optimizer” area of settings that brings together all the options most important to gamers, like refresh rate / VRR, low latency, and more. You can pick the genre of game you’re playing to have presets applied or customize everything to your own liking. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/6/22215172/samsung-neo-qled-4k-8k-tv-announced-specs-ces-2021"&gt;Samsung is offering a similar concept&lt;/a&gt; on its 2021 TVs. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x3v5BHowtInc4_VzC5X3Gf5eZ6w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22226965/LG_OLED_TV_Lineup.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: LG&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5vDMQJ"&gt;But now LG is putting a superior, brighter panel in the G1 series to help distinguish it from the more affordable C series in more ways than design alone. (The G1 has the “gallery” design that helps it fit flush against a wall when mounted.) Both the G1 and C1 series support LG’s new Gallery Stand (seen above), which might appeal to people who don’t want to mount their OLED. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Kddt7R"&gt;On the audio front, these latest TVs are capable of virtual 5.1.2 surround sound, and LG says they’ll now level out volume levels to keep things consistent when you’re switching between inputs and streaming apps — and to prevent blaring ads on TV services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ExBpQW"&gt;At the bottom of the line, LG has the new A1 series, which can really be thought of as the next evolution of last year’s BX. It’s the cheapest way to get into OLED, and you still get all of the most important features — Dolby Vision, HDMI 2.1 (with VRR, ALLM, etc.) — if you can live with fewer HDMI ports and an older LG a7 processor inside. It sounds like a fair bargain, but we’ll need to wait for final pricing on the G1, C1, and A1 lineups closer to the spring to know which is the best buy for TV hunters this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WApNYu"&gt;As the company announced in December, it’s also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203910/lg-qned-mini-led-4k-8k-lcd-tv-announced-ces-2021"&gt;introducing a new “QNED” lineup of LCD TVs that use Mini LED backlighting&lt;/a&gt; for improved contrast and less blooming than past full-array local dimming sets. The QNED series slots in between OLED and LG’s standard NanoCell LCD sets. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224271/lg-2021-tvs-oled-qned-g1-c1-a1-announced-specs-ces"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224271/lg-2021-tvs-oled-qned-g1-c1-a1-announced-specs-ces</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
