<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-16T03:50:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T03:50:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T03:50:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Adidas is launching an NFT collection with exclusive access to streetwear drops</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A black hoodie with text and logos on the upper left chest. There’s a blockchain address followed by logos for GMoney, Bored Ape Yacht Club, Punks Comics, and Adidas." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_ch8IlvktsUWZAY5zEIi0nbwdWI=/0x0:3600x2400/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70280303/aO_metaverese_BlackHoodie_400_01_copy.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Adidas’ NFT-exclusive hoodie. | Image: Adidas&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UZRV2I"&gt;Adidas is getting into the NFT game. The apparel company is launching a line of NFTs on Friday, called &lt;em&gt;Into the Metaverse&lt;/em&gt;, which will offer buyers access to what’s essentially a very exclusive fan club. NFT holders will be able to purchase special merch drops, and Adidas says members will help to shape what kinds of products and experiences the company puts together for its NFT-owning community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="74zuXy"&gt;“Adidas is in the metaverse,” Tareq Nazlawy, Adidas’ senior director of digital growth, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “We want to figure out what would be the dopest thing to do in that space and start involving the communities we’re activating through this [NFT] in how we should manifest in the virtual world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dNy6gF"&gt;The launch comes after a couple weeks of crypto and metaverse hype from Adidas. The company launched digital tokens last month, which will offer holders early access to the NFT drop, and a couple weeks ago, it began tweeting vaguely about the metaverse. Adidas also bought a Bored Ape — the company named the ape Indigo Hertz — and outfitted it with a custom Adidas-branded tracksuit.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The hoodie lists the blockchain address: 0x676DBC8275D6164696461737f3Fd325741474D49 " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2iQm-nqEEggWDEEao4CstF2wZNI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23100694/aO_metaverse_BlackHoodie_420_01.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Adidas&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A close-up on the hoodie.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="iwC9ne"&gt;The NFTs will sell for 0.2 ETH, or about $800 USD, starting December 17th &lt;a href="https://adidas.njih.net/c/482924/264102/4270?u=http%3A%2F%2Fadidas.com%2Fmetaverse&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;through Adidas’ website&lt;/a&gt;. Adidas declined to share how many NFTs would be sold, citing “security protocols,” and declined to say whether the company would receive royalties on NFT resales. The company was also unable to share imagery or a description of what &lt;em&gt;Into the Metaverse &lt;/em&gt;NFTs will look like before this story was scheduled to publish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3vblLr"&gt;NFT buyers will get access to “digital and physical” Adidas products and experiences. At first, the physical goods will include the tracksuit worn by Indigo, a hoodie with a blockchain address on it, and an orange beanie. The merch is cobranded with a trio of collaborators: Bored Ape Yacht Club, the highly sought-after NFT collection; Punks Comics, which recently featured Indigo on an issue’s cover; and GMoney, a pseudonymous crypto enthusiast who’s been consulting with Adidas on how to enter the NFT space in a way that feels authentic. The beanie is supposed to be the one worn by GMoney’s CryptoPunks avatar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ALaHNL"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“You belong to a community, and we continue to add value to that over time.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FQ0NGG"&gt;“There will be other experiences we’re putting together,” Erika Wykes-Sneyd, VP of marketing for Adidas Originals, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “The intent is this thing, this NFT, you belong to a community, and we continue to add value to that over time, and it’s gonna also evolve with what we’re learning about the community how they’re changing and evolving.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GUlsqt"&gt;It’s a familiar formula for the NFT space. NFT project creators will tell you that the real value of their tokens comes from building a community around them and developing a roadmap to deliver new experiences. Adidas seems to be borrowing that approach, but it’s new to see a major company jump into the fray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6yhXr2"&gt;There’s a lot of opportunity here for Adidas. Streetwear enthusiasts are already used to competing to get limited-run product drops, and Adidas already has an app, called Confirmed, for selling special runs like Yeezys. The &lt;em&gt;Into the Metaverse&lt;/em&gt; NFT series just offers a new (and potentially &lt;em&gt;even more &lt;/em&gt;exclusive) way to offer those kinds of drops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="93sqtG"&gt;Plus, the NFT space already operates a bit like pricey, hyped streetwear brands like Supreme. One of the key privileges thus far of owning a Bored Ape Yacht Club NFT is access to exclusive merch drops, like a hat and hoodie, which resell on eBay for hundreds of dollars beyond their sale price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KBLktS"&gt;From that perspective, it was only a matter of time before an actual streetwear brand got in on the action. And it may not be long before others join them: just this week, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22833369/nike-rtfkt-nft-sneaker-shoe-metaverse-company"&gt;Nike bought a company that makes NFTs and virtual sneakers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22822143/adidas-nft-launch-into-the-metaverse-price-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22822143/adidas-nft-launch-into-the-metaverse-price-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T02:36:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T02:36:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>Cyberpunk 2077 developer CD Projekt will pay just $1.85 million in proposed class-action settlement</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Keanu Reeves as Johnny Silverhand in Cyberpunk 2077" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/J6jducDENZKdmuNu6JV7QzDPzGI=/600x0:3840x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70280253/Cyberpunk2077_No_Future_RGB.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: CD Projekt Red&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fMUBSy"&gt;Last week, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22824847/cd-projekt-red-settle-class-action-lawsuit-cyberpunk-2077-launch"&gt;we reported&lt;/a&gt; that game developer CD Projekt was negotiating to settle a class-action lawsuit over the infamously botched launch of &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;, a game that came riddled with bugs and poor enough performance on consoles that Sony pulled it from the PlayStation Store and many storefronts offered refunds. CD Projekt says those negotiations are now concluded, and here’s how much it’s agreed to pay: $1,850,000 USD. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zNVM2S"&gt;While the settlement will likely have to be approved by a court, it sounds like the lead plaintiffs and their lawyers negotiated for a fairly tiny sum here in exchange for “relinquish[ing] any and all claims against the Company and members of its Management Board.” That’s when you consider that the game had a development budget of over $316 million (&lt;a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/articles/2021-04-22-cd-projekt-refunded-around-30-000-cyberpunk-2077-copies"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;GamesIndustry.biz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), recouped that &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2020/12/11/22170468/cyberpunk-2077-sales-revenue-cd-projekt"&gt;entire development and marketing budget in digital pre-orders alone&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22195728/cyberpunk-2077-sales-copies-sold-launch-refunds"&gt;didn’t actually see a huge impact from refunds&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rkG3ev"&gt;Perhaps the plaintiffs didn’t have much of a case? It’s worth noting that this lawsuit (technically, four lawsuits that had been rolled into one) were brought by &lt;em&gt;shareholders&lt;/em&gt; who believed they were misled by the company about financial performance, not gamers who purchased the game. Despite the game’s seemingly &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; decent sales, the company’s reputation has slipped, &lt;a href="https://www.tweaktown.com/news/83350/analysts-reduce-cyberpunk-2077-sales-predictions-by-65/index.html"&gt;sales projections have lowered&lt;/a&gt;, and its stock price &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-12-10/a-year-on-from-cyberpunk-fiasco-cd-projekt-no-nearer-redemption"&gt;has fallen a reported 54 percent&lt;/a&gt; since last year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BgWoGL"&gt;CD Projekt has repeatedly promised to fix the game, and issued a series of patches, suggesting it might eventually become the game it promised. In late October, the company announced that next-gen updates for both Cyberpunk and &lt;em&gt;The Witcher 3&lt;/em&gt; would be delayed to 2022. “Apologies for the extended wait, but we want to make it right,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CDPROJEKTRED/status/1450845753996455944"&gt;the company wrote.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Hh8xzj"&gt;
&lt;div class="DC-embed" style="font-family: Source Sans Pro, Avenir Next, Avenir, Helvetica Neue, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif; max-width: 700px; background: rgb(244, 244, 244); padding: 18px 20px; box-sizing: border-box; border: solid 1px gainsboro; border-radius: 3px;"&gt;
  &lt;div style="font-size:14px;line-height:18px;"&gt;
    Page 1 of &lt;a class="DC-embed-resource" style="color:#5a76a0;text-decoration:underline;" href="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/21155163-cd-projekt-proposed-calss-action-settlement-cyberpunk-2077-terms/#document/p1" title="View entire cd-projekt-proposed-class-action-settlement-cyberpunk-2077-terms on DocumentCloud in new window or tab" target="_blank"&gt; cd-projekt-proposed-class-action-settlement-cyberpunk-2077-terms&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;img src="s3.documentcloud.org/documents/21155163/pages/cd-projekt-proposed-calss-action-settlement-cyberpunk-2077-terms-p1-xlarge.gif?ts=1639641217" alt="Page 1 of cd-projekt-proposed-class-action-settlement-cyberpunk-2077-terms" style="max-width:100%;height:auto;margin:0.5em 0;border:1px solid #ccc;-webkit-box-sizing:border-box;box-sizing:border-box;clear:both"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script src="https://www.documentcloud.org/embed/enhance.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="lcuqCf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Turns out Keanu Reeves never played Cyberpunk 2077","url":"https://www.polygon.com/22832740/did-keanu-reeves-play-cyberpunk-2077-interview-update-the-matrix"},{"title":"Keanu Reeves and Carrie-Anne Moss on making The Matrix Awakens with Epic Games","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22825102/keanu-reeves-carrie-anne-moss-interview-matrix-awakens-epic-games"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839181/cyberpunk-2077-cd-projekt-1-85-million-proposed-class-action-settlement"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839181/cyberpunk-2077-cd-projekt-1-85-million-proposed-class-action-settlement</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-15T21:59:59-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-15T21:59:59-05:00</updated>
    <title>Reddit files to take the company public</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/srDXLiXlZflCPQvc9c6BdR60IL4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70279871/acastro_180413_1777_reddit_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="do0YJk"&gt;Reddit &lt;a href="https://www.redditinc.com/blog/reddit-announces-confidential-submission-of-draft-registration-statement-related-to-proposed-public-offering"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; late Wednesday that it has started the process of taking the company public, by filing a confidential S-1 with the Securities and Exchange Commission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qMhXLH"&gt;The  number of shares to be offered, and the price range for the proposed offering haven’t been determined yet, the company said, adding that it was in a quiet period and could not provide further details for regulatory reasons, which is standard practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hq6mJf"&gt;The company has been &lt;a href="https://www.forex.com/en/market-analysis/latest-research/reddit-ipo/"&gt;rumored&lt;/a&gt; to be considering an IPO for some time, and in August announced it had &lt;a href="https://www.redditinc.com/blog/reddit-secures-funding-to-continue-growth-plans/"&gt;raised a $700 million round&lt;/a&gt; of funding at a valuation of more than $10 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="haPJrU"&gt;In the August announcement, Reddit said it had made $100 million in ad revenue for the second quarter of 2021, a nearly 200 percent increase from the previous year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k8r2VJ"&gt;The company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22621445/reddit-valuation-revenue-funding-round"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year that it planned to double its staff by the end of 2021 to around 1,400 employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mgCW7B"&gt;Reddit, founded in 2005, had grown to around 52 million daily users as of August, with more than 100,000 active sub-reddits. Huffman told the &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/12/technology/reddit-new-funding.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in August that Reddit was “still planning on going public” but didn’t have a firm timeline, adding, “All good companies should go public when they can.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22838901/reddit-going-public-sec-s-1-filing-confidential"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22838901/reddit-going-public-sec-s-1-filing-confidential</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-15T20:58:43-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-15T20:58:43-05:00</updated>
    <title>This ransomware may have stolen Christmas in cities, states, and companies across the US</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f3qzKAnArNg2s4KgqFhpEhaC7Jo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70279745/acastro_170621_1777_0008.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kupS3d"&gt;A ransomware attack is disrupting operations at many major companies, and some workers are concerned that it could affect their last paychecks before the holidays — because their payroll provider, Kronos, is the one that’s dealing with the ransom. The incident has left entire cities and states trying to come up with a plan to get paychecks out to their workers, and could affect HR operations at organizations like &lt;a href="https://nypost.com/2021/12/13/mta-timekeeping-system-goes-dark-after-ransomware-attack/"&gt;New York City’s Metro Transit Authority&lt;/a&gt;, Honda, GameStop, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q4Oe3d"&gt;One Whole Foods worker &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/security/ransomware-attack-threatens-paychecks-just-christmas-rcna8795"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;NBC News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that there’s “a real fear about our paychecks this upcoming Friday,” saying that employees had been to to use “a paper punch sheet to keep track of our hours.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="5h5jgl"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Ransomware has disrupted HR operations around the world&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TpOcBM"&gt;Kronos Private Cloud is a suite of human resources software operated by a company called Ultimate Kronos Group, or UKG. Initially, Kronos didn’t reveal how severe the issue might actually be: &lt;a href="https://www.ukg.com/KPCupdates"&gt;the company reported&lt;/a&gt; that its hosted versions of Workforce Central, TeleStaff, and other services were unavailable, and said that it didn’t have an estimate when they’d be back online. UKG recommended that its customers “evaluate alternative plans to process time and attendance data for payroll processing”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b4vilw"&gt;But early the next morning, UKG revealed that the issue was deeper than a service disruption: the company said it had been the victim of a ransomware attack, saying “it may take up to several weeks to fully restore system availability.” It also said its backups were “currently unavailable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XSRKAX"&gt;UKG’s list of clients includes some huge names including &lt;a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90706145/kronos-ransomware-attack-the-nightmare-that-could-hit-paychecks-right-before-christmas"&gt;Tesla&lt;/a&gt;, GameStop, Honda, &lt;a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/hr-platform-kronos-brought-down-by-ransomware-attack-ukg-warns-of-data-breach/"&gt;Sainsbury’s&lt;/a&gt;, Puma, the YMCA, MGM Resorts, the city of Denver, and &lt;a href="https://nypost.com/2021/12/13/mta-timekeeping-system-goes-dark-after-ransomware-attack/"&gt;New York City’s Metro Transit Authority&lt;/a&gt;. Medical facilities have also reportedly been affected — Honolulu’s &lt;a href="https://www.staradvertiser.com/2021/12/13/breaking-news/board-of-water-supply-employees-warned-to-check-credit-reports-after-cyberattack-strikes-contractor/"&gt;EMS and Board of Water Supply&lt;/a&gt; used Kronos, along with &lt;a href="https://www.gosanangelo.com/story/news/2021/12/13/shannon-hospital-impacted-ransomware-software-company-kronos/6502755001/"&gt;San Angelo, Texas’ Shannon Medical Center&lt;/a&gt; and more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PYt5Cv"&gt;Some companies have promised to get paychecks out, despite the disruption. According to &lt;em&gt;NBC News&lt;/em&gt;, Whole Foods has said that it’ll be able to pay its employees on Friday, and the state of West Virginia &lt;a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/21154976-release-from-erp-board-on-kronos"&gt;has said&lt;/a&gt; that it’d already processed paychecks for December 17th, and is coming up with a plan for paying workers on the 31st. The City of Cleveland has reportedly said that employees &lt;a href="https://www.wkyc.com/article/news/local/cleveland/cleveland-kronos-cybersecurity-incident/95-5cab1459-0779-4125-a74e-443bed04e90c"&gt;will keep getting their paychecks&lt;/a&gt;, though it did say that some of them may have had their names, addresses, and partial social security numbers compromised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="6pn0UV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Some companies have been able to promise payments, others have not&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fDNoQd"&gt;However, &lt;a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/hr-platform-kronos-brought-down-by-ransomware-attack-ukg-warns-of-data-breach/"&gt;anonymous sources told &lt;em&gt;ZDNet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that some companies will be missing payroll for the week. A post on the Sysadmin subreddit offers some insight as to why, as &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/sysadmin/comments/rga2sn/ukg_cyber_attack_what_is_your_current_payroll/"&gt;one person describes&lt;/a&gt; the Herculean efforts they’re taking to tally up employee hours and produce and mail checks without UKG’s services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eFnhqX"&gt;UKG hasn’t given details on the ransom, or talked about who’s behind it, according to &lt;em&gt;NBC News&lt;/em&gt;. Not all of its products have necessarily been affected, though — the company claims the self-hosted versions of the affected applications should keep working fine, and that it doesn’t have evidence any product outside Kronos Private Cloud was affected in any way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H5BmMX"&gt;There’s been speculation that the ransomware attack could be linked to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/10/22828303/log4j-library-vulnerability-log4shell-zero-day-exploit"&gt;massive log4j vulnerability that was recently discovered&lt;/a&gt;. But in an update to &lt;a href="https://www.ukg.com/KPCupdates"&gt;the site UKG set up to respond to this incident&lt;/a&gt;, the company said there’s currently “no indication” that the two events are linked, though it is still investigating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="g8fUtJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Winning the war on ransomware","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22822884/us-government-department-of-justice-ransomware-digital-extortion-task-force-report-2021"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22838737/kronos-ukg-ransomware-attack-payroll-tesla-whole-foods-cybercrime"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22838737/kronos-ukg-ransomware-attack-payroll-tesla-whole-foods-cybercrime</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-15T20:26:27-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-15T20:26:27-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here’s where you can buy a Nintendo Switch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6VMwDr75Sm_0F9dPNdugxlOlu6w=/0x0:1620x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66793958/switcholedmodel.11.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nintendo Switch OLED model boasts a vibrant, 7-inch display and slate of minor upgrades.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YIrWef"&gt;The Nintendo Switch was, like most consoles during the pandemic, once in short supply. Thankfully, retailers like Best Buy, Amazon, and Walmart now routinely stock the Nintendo Switch and Switch Lite in multiple color configurations and models, giving those who struck out ample opportunity to purchase Nintendo’s versatile console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DW6Flb"&gt;We’re keeping an eye across the web to find where you can buy a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/1/14772530/nintendo-switch-review-zelda-breath-of-the-wild"&gt;Nintendo Switch&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/19/20873717/nintendo-switch-lite-review-price-specs-features-games-launch-date"&gt;Nintendo Switch Lite&lt;/a&gt; (the portable-only version of the console), and the new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22569208/nintendo-switch-oled-model-hands-on-screen"&gt;Nintendo Switch OLED model&lt;/a&gt;, as well as any bundles that seem like good deals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ToUhxJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Nintendo Switch is back on top in the US after OLED launch","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/12/22776640/nintendo-switch-oled-sales-october-2021-doug-bowser-interview"},{"title":"If you haven’t gotten a Switch N64 controller yet, you’ll have to wait until next year","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22760049/nintendo-switch-64-n64-controller-in-stock-2022-next-year"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="lxqTuB"&gt;Where can I buy a Nintendo Switch or Switch Lite right now?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="qcOiY9"&gt;Over at Amazon, you can buy an updated Nintendo Switch model with gray Joy-Cons, plus a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nintendo-Switch-Neon-Blue-Joy%E2%80%91/dp/B07YMM3RHZ/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;64GB SanDisk MicroSD card for $313.79&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re looking to upgrade, Amazon is offering two additional bundles, one with a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nintendo-Switch-Neon-Blue-Joy%E2%80%91/dp/B07YBVJRD7?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;128GB SanDisk MicroSD card for $319.99&lt;/a&gt; and one with a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nintendo-Switch-Neon-Blue-Joy%E2%80%91/dp/B07YMJ4XBP/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;256GB SanDisk MicroSD card for $342.49&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Ueoxw3"&gt;You can purchase the updated Nintendo Switch model with gray Joy-Cons or red and blue Joy-Cons for either $299 or $299.99 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nintendo-Switch-Neon-Blue-Joy%E2%80%91/dp/B07VGRJDFY/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1746299173080046926#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy,&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fconsoles%2Fproducts%2Fnintendo-switch-with-neon-blue-and-neon-red-joy-con%2F11095819.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GameStop&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/768290/2092?subId1=VergeNintendoSwitch072321&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fnintendo-switch-with-neon-blue-and-neon-red-joy-con%2F-%2FA-77464001" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;Animal Crossing: New Horizons&lt;/em&gt; Edition is also &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nintendo-Switch-Animal-Crossing-New-Horizons/dp/B084DDDNRP?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available for purchase&lt;/a&gt; from Amazon for $299.99, as well as &lt;a href="http://goto.target.com/P0BVDj" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/1219877/9383?subId1=VergeWheretoGetNintendoSwitch121521&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FNintendo-Switch-Console-Animal-Crossing-New-Horizons-Edition%2F539083068%3F&amp;amp;veh=aff" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZaaYGt"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1732099797003183412#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://goto.target.com/GjEVNn" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt; are currently the only retailers carrying the Nintendo Switch Lite, which is available in the blue and pink colorways for its standard MSRP of $199.99.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fiSvia"&gt;If you’re not against buying a preowned or refurbished console, you’ll want to check out &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=vergeevergreen&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fswitch%2Fconsoles%2Fproducts%2Fnintendo-switch-with-gray-joy-con%2F206007.html%3Fgclid%3DCjwKCAiAt9z-BRBCEiwA_bWv-HzeKt4-dsaWdi9G9SGmxFTUUEAxrCA4NxZS0xEWCkIacwTZ_cUKPRoCEYUQAvD_BwE%26gclsrc%3Daw.ds" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GameStop&lt;/a&gt;, where you can currently pick up a &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fnintendo-switch%2Fconsoles%2Fproducts%2Fnintendo-switch-with-gray-joy-con%2F206007.html%3F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;first-gen Nintendo Switch with gray Joy-Cons for $280&lt;/a&gt;. Another good place to look is &lt;a href="https://store.nintendo.com/nintendo-switch/systems.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nintendo’s online store, where you can often find refurbished Switch consoles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Nintendo Switch with OLED screen" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YzjT6iua8IRxp8FH9VRp8hphoeg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22701274/newswitch_kickstand.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Nintendo&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tL1zU6"&gt;Where can I buy a Nintendo Switch OLED right now?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="FefR8R"&gt;The Nintendo Switch OLED &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/6/22456337/nintendo-switch-oled-model-specs-date-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;officially went on sale in October&lt;/a&gt; for $349.99, and offers a slew of improvements, most notably a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22566479/oled-nintendo-switch-vs-lite-screen-size" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;vibrant 7-inch OLED display&lt;/a&gt; and an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/6/22564942/nintendo-switch-oled-screen-new-kickstand" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;improved kickstand&lt;/a&gt; that offers far greater stability. The speakers get a bit louder and offer a touch more clarity, too, and there’s a wired ethernet port built directly into the dock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ThJrec"&gt;While it was initially extremely difficult to find, the supply of the OLED model seems to have finally caught up with demand. In fact, in some cases, the upgraded console is easier to find right now than certain colorways of the Nintendo Switch Lite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sxXvjE"&gt;At the time of this writing, the Nintendo Switch OLED model is available online at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B098RKWHHZ/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/9W2z64" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://store.nintendo.com/nintendo-switch-oled-model-neon-blue-neon-red-set.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nintendo&lt;/a&gt; for $349.99, the standard retail price. Best Buy also has the hybrid console in stock, however, it’s currently only &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cfKju4VpwZ5" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available for in-store pickup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="iPj5B1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Nintendo Switch OLED review: screentime","url":"https://www.theverge.com/games/22711889/nintendo-switch-oled-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="olD4z0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10738833"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="HHzLVA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10640111"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="8hV7z9"&gt;What accessories do I need to buy for the Nintendo Switch?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="hgAR00"&gt;Frankly, the Switch comes with everything that you need to get started and have fun. However, a few extra purchases can help you get a little more out of your console, and in some cases, help it weather the wear and tear that it’ll undoubtedly endure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jnXhNd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9556339"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9sHCpf"&gt;First off, a MicroSD card will help you extend your Switch’s default 32GB of storage. Amazon, Best Buy, and other retailers regularly sell cards with up to &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/SanDisk-512GB-microSDXC-Memory-Adapter/dp/B08GXXKY6P/ref=asc_df_B08GXXKY6P/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;512GB of storage for around $55.99&lt;/a&gt;. A &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/SanDisk-512GB-microSDXC-Memory-Adapter/dp/B08GYG5SVQ/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;400GB microSD card will cost you around $47.99&lt;/a&gt;, though, and with each game ranging in download size from 1GB to tens of gigabytes, the card has enough space to store several of them. Right now, the best deal available is probably at Costco, where members can get a &lt;a href="https://www.costco.com/sandisk-256gb-microsdxc-card-for-the-nintendo-switch-2-pack.product.100675941.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;two-pack of SanDisk’s 256GB MicroSD cards for $49.99&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Agp45r"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10397609"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QGdvLy"&gt;Let’s talk quickly about controllers. The Switch Joy-Cons have a somewhat unconventional look. Nevertheless, the Pro Controller is a great alternative to play most Switch games, though some Super Mario Party titles require the Joy-Cons to play. If you are looking for a Switch Pro Controller, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nintendo-Switch-Pro-Controller/dp/B01NAWKYZ0/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fnintendo-switch%2Faccessories%2Fcontrollers%2Fproducts%2Fnintendo-switch-black-wireless-pro-controller%2F141756.html%3Fgclid%3DCj0KCQjw0emHBhC1ARIsAL1QGNchiWTVbB56sBuEbLjc76K169WZpHUSFCnyWf2W_sbAwyKf3XbqzX0aAiS9EALw_wcB%26gclsrc%3Daw.ds" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GameStop&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cgdocaWxzJq" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; all currently have the controller available for $69.98, the full MSRP.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2BZPIqmUqpLcZoV5GVxdxMULT3I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/9537475/akrales_171025_2091_0010.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Switch doesn’t include a screen protector, so make that one of the first things you buy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="UODwlY"&gt;Next up, get a tempered glass screen cover. The display on the Switch and Switch Lite is covered in plastic, and it’s just asking to get scratched as soon as you take it out of the box. Save the heartbreak by getting an affordable, easy-to-apply glass cover at Amazon. &lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2YZPQpf" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;A&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07TCPVHTM?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt; three-pack of amFilm tempered glass protectors&lt;/a&gt; for the Switch Lite is currently $7.99.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cx5X9k"&gt;If you want to play online with friends, ensure that your saves are backed up in the cloud, and get access to a slate of on-demand games from the original Nintendo console and SNES console era, you’ll want to get a Nintendo Switch Online subscription. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07FV64QLX?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;It’s $19.99 per year for a single user&lt;/a&gt; on a console or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07KY69YFM/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$34.99 a year for up to eight users on different consoles&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="QMTTL1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10422489"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="STKJng"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="YFtcY7"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21257643/nintendo-switch-lite-oled-how-to-buy-in-stock"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21257643/nintendo-switch-lite-oled-how-to-buy-in-stock</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-15T18:28:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-15T18:28:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>DirecTV Stream and satellite TV are raising their prices next month</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="DirecTV Tops Profit Estimates as More Customers Sign Up" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JMLTqXXmmlX2-iHAHRnlnWXeRxs=/0x0:4000x2667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70279286/488453459.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Q67Ya2"&gt;DirecTV’s satellite and Stream services are getting price increases in January — hikes that the company attributed to rising programming costs as well as “higher-than-normal inflation across our suppliers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PQXGWq"&gt;Beginning January 23rd of next year, customers of both groups are likely to see their bills increase — though specifically by how much will depend on the service. Most of DirecTV’s satellite customers will see their monthly costs increase anywhere between $1 and 10, &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.directv.com/support/satellite/article/KM1442186/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;depending on which package&lt;/a&gt; they pay for. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8BxOHa"&gt;Additionally, regional sports network costs will be determined by ZIP code. While this means some customers could see a monthly increase of $2 more per month, others will see a decrease, and some customers will see no change at all when the new pricing goes into effect. (Customers can &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.directv.com/DTVAPP/content/rsn_fee" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;check their ZIP&lt;/a&gt; on the DirecTV site to see their monthly RSN fee.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CpIP70"&gt;Stream customers, meanwhile, will also see a price hike on many for the majority of Stream packages. Price increases per month will vary from &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.directv.com/support/stream/article/KM1466120/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$4 more to $10 more&lt;/a&gt;, depending on the plan. The changes will affect many DirecTV Stream users even if they were grandfathered into their plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sq2g5w"&gt;In notices to its DirecTV and Stream customers obtained by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, the company said the decision to hike prices would occur “despite our efforts to absorb some of these costs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K6pYZZ"&gt;“While competitors continue to shrink their offerings, your DirecTV team maintains a steadfast commitment to carrying the most robust channel line-up in the industry and unrivalled [&lt;em&gt;sic&lt;/em&gt;] leadership in premium sports and news content,” the company wrote. “In addition, we continue to invest in providing better customer service, releasing new technology upgrades that will enhance our signal reliability, and launching improved features. We are also delivering greater flexibility to watch what you want, when you want it, from virtually anywhere in the U.S.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tdnOkz"&gt;Anyone on promotional discounts will continue to be billed at their current rate until the promotional period ends, at which time the new price will be reflected on their bill. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22838593/directv-stream-satellite-price-increase-january-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22838593/directv-stream-satellite-price-increase-january-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-15T18:00:54-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-15T18:00:54-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Verge’s favorite holiday gifts under $50</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zThM19eW8UeFtTLtf7bAahfqzDM=/0x2:2048x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70116332/Budget_50.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Richard Parry&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Great gifts don’t always require you to splurge&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="grzXMI"&gt;Even though many of us are better off in some ways than we were in 2020, we’re still in the midst of a pandemic. And for a good number of people, that means this holiday season will, like last year, be about celebrating on a budget. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2Xuioi"&gt;Luckily, there are still plenty of great gifts you can pick up before the holidays are over if you have a little spending cash in your wallet. Our budget-conscious gift guide features a variety of ideas that cost under $50, all of which are either thoughtful, entertaining, or incredibly useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bPq2aB"&gt;Below, you’ll find personalized art prints illustrating what the Solar System looked like the day your loved one was born — or the minute you met your partner. Other suggestions, like Rocketbook’s reusable smart notebook, can help a friend or family member declutter their life and remain environmentally conscious while doing so. We even have a few literary staples on the list, as well as a smart garage door opener and a Bluetooth tracker that allows Apple users to keep better tabs on their belongings while on the move. Holiday travel is still a thing, after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="TMRZQi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Verge Holiday Gift Guide 2021","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22759813/holiday-gift-guide-best-tech-gadget-unique-ideas"},{"title":"The Verge’s 2021 Home Tech Holiday Gift Guide","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22752612/smart-home-tech-holiday-gift-guide-2021-kitchen-lighting-speakers"},{"title":"The Verge’s 2021 Gift Guide for Moms","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22759870/holiday-gift-ideas-mom-2021-unique-tech-gadgets"},{"title":"The Verge’s 2021 Gaming and Entertainment Gift Guide","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22747287/gaming-entertainment-gift-guide-2021-nintendo-playstation-xbox-gadgets-accessories"},{"title":"The Verge’s 2021 Gift Guide for Kids","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22759900/holiday-gift-ideas-kids-children-2021-unique-tech-gadgets"},{"title":"The Verge’s Favorite Holiday Gifts Under $50","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22748775/holiday-gift-guide-under-50-cheap-tech-gadgets-best-ideas"},{"title":"The Verge’s Favorite Holiday Gifts Under $25","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22745314/holiday-gift-guide-under-25-cheap-tech-2021-best-ideas"},{"title":"The Verge’s 2021 Holiday Gift Guide for Creators","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22746670/holiday-gift-ideas-2021-creators-content-artists-tech-gadgets-creative"},{"title":"The Verge’s 2021 Fitness and Wellness Guide","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22746889/fitness-wellness-holiday-gift-guide-2021-fitness-trackers-watches"},{"title":"The Verge’s 2021 Holiday Gift Guide for Working From Home","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22746680/work-from-home-remote-office-holiday-gift-guide-2021-supplies-tech-gadgets"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="BLWO2z"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10845632"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22748775/holiday-gift-guide-under-50-cheap-tech-gadgets-best-ideas"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22748775/holiday-gift-guide-under-50-cheap-tech-gadgets-best-ideas</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-15T17:56:35-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-15T17:56:35-05:00</updated>
    <title>We didn’t need an AR version of Snake, but AT&amp;T just gave us one anyway</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lyvzLeI-kJr3MWN6golqBER8L38=/0x50:2100x1450/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70279143/5g_snake_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warp Speed Worm is an AR filter for Instagram and Messenger and has tenuous connections to 5G at best.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VBq5av"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T has re-imagined the classic Snake game in a new, interactive, and wholly unnecessary way in an effort to promote the capabilities of its 5G network. Called &lt;a href="https://about.att.com/story/2021/facebook-warp-speed-worm.html"&gt;Warp Speed Worm&lt;/a&gt;, it’s an AR effect that can be used on Instagram and Facebook Messenger video calls.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ugd5HQ"&gt;Snake was, of course, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/2/27/14749896/nokia-3310-snake-gameplay-preview-mwc-2017"&gt;game of choice&lt;/a&gt; on your early Nokia phone. Or, depending on your age and general level of apathy toward high school mathematics, you may recognize it as the game you played on your TI-83 graphing calculator while you were supposed to be learning about coefficients. Not that I know anyone who would do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QuUZ0r"&gt;In any case, this newest contribution to the great Snake game &lt;em&gt;genre&lt;/em&gt; is an AR filter in which the titular worm is controlled by your head movements. You can play with friends, which AT&amp;amp;T would like you to do on their 5G network, or you can be a total doofus and play on your own using the camera in the Instagram app. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="upPDP3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;You can play with friends, which AT&amp;amp;T would like you to do on their 5G network&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mmjSwD"&gt;It’s sort of cute — you tilt your head left or right to direct the worm to pick up little game controller icons. As you’ll recall from AP Calculus, the more the worm eats, the longer it gets. When the worm inevitably eats itself, the game is over, and a sad little dead worm crown appears on your head. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9n6WIF"&gt;I gave the game a try by myself after struggling to understand how to save and use an AR group effect on an Instagram video call. I’ll admit that I missed the physical controls of my calculator and that my neck creaks alarmingly loud when I tilt it repeatedly. I also can’t comment on how AT&amp;amp;T 5G would have enhanced the experience — it worked just fine on my home Wi-Fi.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22837902/att-5g-ar-snake-warp-speed-worm-messenger-instagram"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22837902/att-5g-ar-snake-warp-speed-worm-messenger-instagram</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-15T17:37:43-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-15T17:37:43-05:00</updated>
    <title>Ted Lasso gets a cute claymation holiday short</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zeiJTVfbFLjvpnIAieWa-E0lRk0=/76x0:904x552/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70279055/121521_Ted_Lasso_Animated_Holiday_Short_Big_Image_01_big_image_post.jpg.large.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TOMZTH"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22590155/ted-lasso-apple-tv-plus-season-2-review"&gt;Season 2 of &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ended on something of a dark note, but everything is all nice and friendly again in a new holiday short. It’s called “The Missing Christmas Mustache,” and, like many classic holiday specials, it’s rendered in cute and charming claymation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wgBvsf"&gt;It features voices of the main cast — including Jason Sudeikis, Hannah Waddingham, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/9/1/22652236/ted-lasso-roy-kent-cgi-conspiracy-theory"&gt;definitely-not-CGI Brett Goldstein&lt;/a&gt; — as they search for a missing mustache. It’s only four minutes long, so I won’t spoil too much, only to say you should at least watch to learn a little more about Roy Kent’s eyebrows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="myJnzA"&gt;If nothing else, it makes up for the poorly-timed Christmas episode of &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt; that aired in August — and threw my sense of time and date even further out of whack. And it’s a nice little taste of the show’s wholesomeness while we all wait for season 3 to come to Apple TV Plus.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22838509/ted-lasso-claymation-holiday-short-apple-tv"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22838509/ted-lasso-claymation-holiday-short-apple-tv</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-15T17:35:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-15T17:35:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Matter’s plan to save the smart home </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HH3xc4NgYaMz_QI9ezoQSF9g1nQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70268903/acastro_211117_4887_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Matter is a new standard that promises to fix smart home interoperability — but can it deliver?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="t5qLmO"&gt;The smart home should be a natural evolution of our homes, bringing better appliances, better systems, better experiences. But to date, it’s been complicated, confusing, and expensive. Walled gardens have stifled innovation as developers focus on getting their devices to work with three or four or more different platforms rather than spending their time creating better products and new features. Consumers spend too much energy figuring out which product works with which and then troubleshooting those connections, before often giving up on the whole thing. This has led to a slower smart home adoption than many expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jCtd7u"&gt;What the smart home needs, and has needed for a long time, is a universal connectivity standard — a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/19/21028256/smart-home-standard-google-apple-amazon-alexa-siri-zigbee-choip"&gt;basic level of common plumbing in our homes&lt;/a&gt; for everything to flow through. Just as we chose VHS over Betamax in the ’80s (and Blu-ray over HD-DVD in the early 2000s) for a better home theater experience,  so we need to choose a smart home standard. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wyEbHC"&gt;
&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="200" scrolling="no" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm?e=VMP4578799766&amp;amp;light=true" width="100%"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="EsEraa"&gt;The problem is there aren’t two or three standards to choose from. There are many, and none of them work very well on their own. Zigbee, Z-Wave, Wi-Fi, and Bluetooth have all tried and failed to become the primary radio protocol of the smart home. But none have gained enough traction or offered enough flexibility to fit into all corners of the smart home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xn2P9z"&gt;That’s where Matter comes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-M-Z-nOK7Q7nT95Yzp7aVixVZfU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23079856/acastro_4887_0004.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vtaYcE"&gt;Buy a gadget, plug it in, and it will work with the rest of your smart home. Set up that new device with your favorite smart home app, and control it with your voice assistant of choice, no matter who made it. This may sound like some distant smart home nirvana, but this is the promise of Matter. The simple smart home could be just around the corner. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3ow3RE"&gt;An open-sourced connectivity standard created by over 200 companies, Matter is a communication protocol that leverages existing technologies — Thread, Wi-Fi, Bluetooth, and ethernet — to allow all of your devices to communicate with each other locally, without the need for a cloud. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="M2Fle3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Buy a gadget, plug it in, and it will work with the rest of your smart home&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qUilte"&gt;What makes Matter more than just another smart home standard is momentum; most of the industry is on board. Organized by the Connectivity Standards Alliance (or CSA, formerly the Zigbee Alliance), Matter is being developed by Amazon, Apple, Google / Nest, and Samsung, alongside many other smart home and smart home-adjacent companies, including Wyze, iRobot, Signify (Philips Hue), Ecobee, &lt;a href="https://buildwithmatter.com/"&gt;and more&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jVbU8O"&gt;Driven by a shared need to fix the problems of the smart home, these companies are working together to figure out how to make this standard be the one that sticks. Can Matter finally bring an end to the confusion perfectly encapsulated by Randall Munroe’s classic xkcd “&lt;a href="https://xkcd.com/927/"&gt;Standards&lt;/a&gt;” comic?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yeplUXpmj1adDXyyVOg8H8OzwcQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23084306/standards.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Comic by xkcd&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rNB9Yx"&gt;“This is a Renaissance [for the smart home]” says Tobin Richardson, president and CEO of the CSA. “Most of the industry, if not all the industry have agreed that [Matter] is going to be the way this will happen.” They are seemingly all on board with the fact that Matter is the solution to the smart home’s biggest problems — simplicity, interoperability, reliability, and security. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vhf5Ct"&gt;The final Matter specification, SDK, and certification program should be ready by mid-2022, and the goal is to have the first Matter-certified devices available by the end of 2022, says Richardson. That’s over a year later than promised when &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/18/21027890/apple-google-amazon-smart-home-standard-zigbee-connected-ip-project"&gt;Matter first launched in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, but better late than never.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="L8H9co"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How Amazon, Google, Apple, and Samsung will work with Matter, and which products you should buy.","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22832127/matter-smart-home-products-thread-wifi-explainer"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="ETdn7w"&gt;If you have already boned up on what Matter is and why it… matters, and you just want to know what devices you can buy and when, head over to our explainer piece “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22596168"&gt;What matters about Matter&lt;/a&gt;” article, where we look at what the different smart home platforms have committed to supporting around Matter and which devices are Matter-ready (a number of smart home makers have announced plans to update existing products as soon as Matter arrives). Otherwise, read on to learn about how Matter is going to fix the smart home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="up26W0"&gt;What is Matter, and why is it different?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="zL4HCM"&gt;Matter is a unified connectivity technology for the smart home. It is not a smart home platform like Apple HomeKit, Google Home, and Amazon’s Alexa. Matter doesn’t automate or control your home; it simply provides the pipes and language for devices to communicate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ow3IDq"&gt;Its unique feature is it’s an IP-based technology, meaning it uses the same mechanisms to communicate as the internet. So, there is no dependency on bridges or hubs, and yes, you will (eventually) be able to get rid of all those white boxes hooked up to your modem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IGjgMI"&gt;To simplify adoption, Matter will start as an application layer on top of existing IP technologies, including ethernet, Wi-Fi, Thread, and Bluetooth (for device provisioning). This means Matter is not reinventing the wheel; it’s adding better technology to the highways our smart homes are driving on.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Sr_XaQQMw4yPG4CCnnPWSA7QnDk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23084404/start_developing_with_matter_graphic.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Z-Wave Alliance&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Matter network map shows how devices will connect to each other, to the internet, and to other protocols using Wi-Fi, Thread, and Matter controllers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="x5QDBu"&gt;Once in your home, Matter devices can operate entirely locally, talking to each other over Thread and Wi-Fi and not going through the cloud. That means if your internet goes down, your smart home will still work. Devices will still need to communicate with the internet for out-of-home control and firmware and security upgrades, which will happen directly or through a Matter controller device (i.e., a smart speaker, smartphone, or bridge). Local control is a significant step in maintaining privacy in the smart home, a big concern for people when considering installing smart home devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="wACI89"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Smart home company Eve plans to use Matter to move beyond Apple’s HomeKit ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/10/22827727/eve-matter-thread-upgrade-smart-shades-release-date"},{"title":"Google commits to Matter, promises future interoperability between smart home platforms ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/21/22738584/google-smart-home-developer-summit-2021-matter-thread"},{"title":"Samsung promises Matter support for SmartThings hubs, Galaxy devices, TVs, and fridges ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/26/22745664/samsung-smartthings-matter-support-products-galaxy"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="eQBxti"&gt;Smart home company Eve built its entire business model on local control. “Our privacy platform is ‘what’s at home stays at home,’” Jerome Gackel, Eve Systems CEO, tells me. “With Matter, you do not need a cloud — you can have one, but it’s not a requirement.” Its commitment to avoiding cloud control is why Eve devices have been iPhone- and HomeKit-only thus far. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/10/22827727/eve-matter-thread-upgrade-smart-shades-release-date"&gt;But with Matter, Eve can move to the other platforms while remaining entirely local&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="Z8145w"&gt;What is Thread, and why is it better?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="xzuPtx"&gt;Thread is one of the key technologies of Matter. It promises to make the smart home more robust. Like Z-Wave and Zigbee, Thread is a low-power mesh networking protocol. “Networking is one of the biggest problems of the smart home; sensors and devices dropping offline,” says Tony Fadell, founder of Nest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4RYWAK"&gt;Thread and the precursor to Matter, Weave, was first developed in 2014 by Nest and six other companies, including Silicon Labs, ARM, Samsung Electronics, and Yale Security. Thread’s big selling points are speed and reliability. A motion sensor will turn your lights on in a millisecond compared to a second, and your network won’t go down because you accidentally unplugged the hub, as — with enough devices deployed — a Thread network can self-heal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1DXX7rddXUr9CI8ZEM-AOaIqdQc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23079855/acastro_4887_0003.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UidoTm"&gt;Unlike Bluetooth or Wi-Fi, Thread was specifically developed as a smart home protocol. Other protocols used in the smart home to date have been co-opted into that role, meaning they have practical and usability issues. Wi-Fi is too power-hungry for battery-powered devices. Bluetooth has range limitations. Zigbee and Z-Wave require dedicated hubs, which are cumbersome to set up and maintain and can be a single point of failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="rgpygN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Matter is not reinventing the wheel; it’s adding better technology to the highways our smart homes are driving on&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xOt5EO"&gt;Thread began in Nest’s earliest days. “Every single Nest thermostat since the beginning has shipped with a Zigbee radio inside, a connection for a long-distance, low-power protocol,” says Fadell. The idea was to future-proof a device likely to stay in the home for 10 to 20 years. “We wanted it to be able to talk to the future smart home,” he says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;div id="5W7LAL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10917556"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jGPb0G"&gt;But Zigbee wasn’t progressing fast enough for the Nest team, so they worked with Silicon Labs and others to develop Thread, which, in technical terms, is a Zigbee hardware stack with a software layer on top. “We knew what needed to happen — we needed a home IP-based mesh network with low-power range,” says Fadell. “The key is it’s IP native.” Low-power radios in the smart home have needed a hub or bridge to talk to the internet, but that problem went away by making Thread IP native. “That is what is so powerful about it,” says Fadell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bbCEvG"&gt;Eve was one of the first smart home companies &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/4/22310378/eve-smart-home-thread-plug-home-kit-weather-station-price-specs-features"&gt;to adopt Thread&lt;/a&gt;, and today, it is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/10/22827727/eve-matter-thread-upgrade-smart-shades-release-date"&gt;working toward&lt;/a&gt; running all of its relevant products on the protocol, having shifted over from Bluetooth. “Thread has really changed the reliability of our product, especially in terms of automation,” says Eve’s Gackel. “The difference between our Bluetooth product and Thread product experience has really increased customer satisfaction.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PzG3vv"&gt;Thread devices can be battery-powered or wall-powered, and the latter can be a Thread border router, a bridge between a Wi-Fi and Thread network. But a border router isn’t a typical white plastic box type of bridge that plugs into your router. The tech will be built into any device with an always-on power source and can be placed anywhere in your home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1HhyyS"&gt;A smart plug, smart speaker, fridge, TV, thermostat, and Wi-Fi access point can all be Thread border routers. “As you add more border routers in the home, you get better range and reliability,” explains Kevin Po, senior product manager at Google and a member of the CSA board. Case in point, the aesthetically pleasing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/3/22466594/nanoleaf-elements-light-panel-smart-home-price-release"&gt;Nanoleaf Shapes and Elements light panels are also Thread border routers&lt;/a&gt;, with a smidge more pizazz than a white plastic box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HPRjYl"&gt;A border router is like a mailman: it routes the different packets of information. Unlike a smart home hub, it doesn’t know what’s in those packets or control them. If a smart speaker wants to know the state of a lock, the border router can tell it without ever knowing the state itself. “From an end-to-end security perspective, that routing aspect provides a lot of benefits,” says Po.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7H15wWa4XdQiKA-u_uMYDtxrcm4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23084334/Thread_home_network.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Thread Group&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This image illustrates how Thread border routers connect a thread network to the internet.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="H2UoA3"&gt;While Z-Wave and Zigbee will continue to be part of the smart home — existing hubs can be upgraded to Thread or bridged to Matter — it seems possible these technologies will be phased out in the residential setting. “It would certainly seem, if everything is executed as promised, that it will make sense to move towards Matter products,” says Mitch Klein, executive director of the Z-Wave Alliance. “That’s a big ‘if,’ however, and there are other questions in terms of security still.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FH0cQK"&gt;Because Matter devices can speak straight to the internet, that potentially exposes them to hacking or malware, says Klein. &lt;a href="https://zigbeealliance.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Matter-Security-Privacy_one-pager.pdf"&gt;Matter’s security approach&lt;/a&gt; is “strong, agile (to address the evolution of things like encryption types over time), and proactive, with a community of members who do threat modeling and mitigation,” says Richardson of the CSA. IP control is central to the function of Matter, and Richardson argues that the approach is one of resilient security while still getting the benefits of an IP-connected world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="NAK1hc"&gt;How will devices work in a Matter smart home?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="AOEu7g"&gt;The Matter home will need a Wi-Fi access point and a Matter controller. This can be a smartphone or tablet, but it can also be a Thread border router that works with your preferred smart home ecosystem — such as an Amazon Echo speaker, an Apple HomePod Mini, a Google Nest Hub, or a Samsung SmartThings hub. While devices will work across platforms, automations and routines will not. “If you are using HomeKit, you will need a HomeKit hub,” explains Gackel. “A Google hub will not run HomeKit automations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="18wsbx"&gt;A Matter home will be able to incorporate any smart home device that is Matter certified. (The Matter logo on a product will indicate that it’s compatible.) You will also be able to set up any Matter device with your controller app, similar to how Apple’s HomeKit works today. All this means that when you buy a new product — such as a lightbulb or door lock — if it has a Matter logo, you won’t need to worry about what it works with; it will just work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EzZFQeRI68rbbFLbOOvkuQFJUvo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23079854/acastro_4887_0002.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="omRzdU"&gt;It will also be simpler to set up. Amazon’s Frustration-Free setup is the basis for Matter’s standard setup process, explains Chris DeCenzo, principal software development engineer at Amazon Lab126. It’s designed to enable a “zero-touch” experience, where you take the device out of the box, plug it in, and it connects to your home automatically. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IvYr8J"&gt;This doesn’t mean there won’t be manufacturer apps, just that you won’t have to use them for setup. Still, in some cases, you will need them to access device-specific features that aren’t available in Matter, and probably to update firmware, although this may happen through Matter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="07kogK"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Companies are committing to Matter, but some are still holding a few cards close to their chest.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ye0GAi"&gt;Despite the coming together of the big four smart home companies and the general excitement of the early Matter push, the reality is the smart home will still be a divided one. Matter may provide a basic standard of interoperability and portability, but companies will still seek competitive advantages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0hf077"&gt;For example, nothing in the Matter spec requires a Matter controller to support all device categories. If video doorbells become part of Matter in the future, Amazon could choose not to support doorbells in its controller. Amazon’s Ring doorbells already work in the Ring app and with its Echo devices, meaning the company may see no need to develop another doorbell camera controller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="14a8Uc"&gt;There’s also nothing compelling companies to upgrade products that they don’t want to. Google has said it will update its newest Nest Smart Thermostat to Matter but has not said if any of the three generations of the Nest Learning Thermostat or the Thermostat E will follow suit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y9K51y"&gt;Amazon has released a slew of new smart home products in 2021, including a thermostat, air quality monitor, and smart switches, with not a mention of Matter compatibility. DeCenzo tells me this doesn’t mean it won’t come, but that’s not exactly a guarantee that it will. “It’s hard for a device maker to make any absolute statements about something they’re going to support that isn’t here today,” he says. “Matter was just an idea when these devices were being developed.”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RSoSVS"&gt;Apple has committed to Matter but hasn’t commented on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/9/22824559/matter-tv-streaming-devices-smart-home-casting-protocol-support"&gt;whether it will adopt the Matter TV and Streaming Video player specification&lt;/a&gt; to allow Matter controllers to cast content from smartphones to televisions, similar to how AirPlay works. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qvRGFc"&gt;On the one hand, companies are committing to Matter, but with the other hand they’re still holding some cards close to their chest. While it’s legitimately tricky to say how you will develop your products for a specification that hasn’t been finalized yet, these companies are all deeply involved in the process, so they are hardly flying blind. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="9GBupl"&gt;How will companies differentiate themselves in Matter?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="1PALNF"&gt;Before Matter, compatibility was a huge selling point for devices. You bought a smart lock largely because it worked with your ecosystem of choice. With Matter, that reason should go away. Now, companies will need to innovate on top of the standard to create reasons for you to choose their devices over the competition. “What Matter does is change the game, so companies aren’t competing on connectivity and interoperability, and it’s just there,” says Michelle Mindala-Freeman, head of marketing at Connectivity Standards Alliance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zbAJeQ"&gt;This would appear to put the big four smart home platforms on an even playing field. If all devices talk to each other, you’re no longer locked into Google’s ecosystem because your preferred door lock only works with Google. While this would seem counter to Google, Amazon etc. selling more devices, what it does is make it easier for each company to innovate and move forward with their respective visions of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22719945/amazon-alexa-dave-limp-interview-ambient-computing-ring-eero-decoder"&gt;smart home&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KuEoO9"&gt;Ultimately, if the hardware is commoditized, the value becomes in the service layer your ecosystem of choice adds to your experience. Matter’s specifications are designed to be simple: that door lock will lock and unlock. “Above that, it’s up to the device makers, the platform companies and such to understand how to best innovate,” says Po.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZNHPu2ISjAQ9HIH0veWWCi2RLGo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23079853/acastro_4887_0005.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HQGuK0"&gt;If you want more advanced features — such as adaptive lighting or touch-to-unlock — you will go to a platform or manufacturer that supports those. “It will make for a more competitive environment,” says Kevin Kraus, of Yale Residential, part of Assa Abloy. “If you want a fully-featured door lock, you’re likely to buy a Yale lock. But let’s say you’ve got a shed, and you just need something that locks and unlocks, then you might go for something less sophisticated.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GQDR3K"&gt;Matter should push manufacturers to innovate, too. “We need to focus more on the added value of our products,” said Florian Deleuil of Netatmo in &lt;a href="https://matter-smarthome.de/en/interview-en/matter-is-pretty-changing-the-game/"&gt;a recent interview&lt;/a&gt;. “Otherwise, it could end up being difficult to distinguish our product from that of cheaper and less innovative suppliers.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LzVx9B"&gt;While it will be more competitive, the thinking is that the market will be much larger. Matter will help the smart home go from niche to mass. “If this is successful, everyone sells more,” says Z-Wave’s Klein. “Market penetration increases, the stagnation of the smart home in terms of growth is going to increase, and new product categories will open up.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UNKvkw"&gt;Today, you might choose a washing machine because it has an excellent design, a special cycle for athletic wear, and offers good energy and water efficiency. You don’t choose it because it works with Alexa or syncs with your fridge. Going forward, that’s probably how you’ll choose your next smart device. “Both industrial design, the overall physical user experience, and the feature sets that they virtually interact with will drive purchase decisions, not just who it works with,” says Klein. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1bs8hP"&gt;Matter will also provide wider choice. Today, you may be limited to devices that work with the platform you have set up. With Matter, that restriction should go away. The smart home future — where all devices communicate with each other to help your home run more efficiently, intelligently, and seamlessly — will finally emerge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Rj5xICvNyLceaIMRUUBHTfPr1fE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23084331/matter_lkup_rgb_night.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id="bNpJsc"&gt;But will it Matter?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="IdBNMP"&gt;In all of the interviews I did for this article, no one had anything negative to say about Matter (on the record). Right now, the industry is aligned on drinking the same Kool-Aid. But Matter is still an idea — albeit one with an unprecedented industry coalition behind it that makes it the most promising development in the smart home since Alexa arrived on the scene. It’s easy to love an idea; it can be harder to implement and stick to one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EBsr0h"&gt;Matter’s biggest roadblock is that it’s not here yet, and whether it will arrive as promised is still a large question mark. This is holding some companies back from committing to it or developing products for it today. “We totally believe in the vision and in all the benefits that will come from having a single protocol,” says Amazon’s DeCenzo. “But at the end of the day, we’ve got to get there. And that’s going to be a journey.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="Rns5ld"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Is Apple going to go out of its way to make sure Amazon’s products work well with its platform? &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Nt3pay"&gt;Fadell, who is as excited about the validation of his Thread gamble as a kid at Christmas, is also slightly skeptical. He worries that proprietary moves by companies looking to differentiate products could harm Matter’s overall promise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="niOU16"&gt;“Everything can talk to everything in Matter, but that doesn’t mean the experiences will be the same. I can speak French, but am I really French? No,” says Fadell. “It’s the same thing here. If you’re in the Apple ecosystem, sure you may work with other systems in certain ways — but inside Apple, with all the Apple tools, it will be a better experience, and it’s going to stay that way.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6x0NJ9"&gt;Yes, you will be able to use an Apple speaker to control an Amazon device, but is Apple going to go out of its way to make sure Amazon’s products work &lt;em&gt;well&lt;/em&gt; with its platform? “Unlikely,” says Fadell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZP75wL"&gt;Ultimately, Matter isn’t the solution we — as consumers — have been waiting for. On day one, it’s not going to produce the ambient, self-aware smart home that can respond to your every need without a lick of set-up on our part. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FQcQSu"&gt;What it is is the solution smart home developers need so that they can start building products and services for that smart home we’re waiting for. “If Matter only changes a couple of things, we will still have a fundamental new technology that works,” says Fadell. “And if it’s adopted — well, let’s see what happens then.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="xR0aPU"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uCXfRy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated Tuesday, December 14, 10:55AM: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clarified what Matter-ready devices are -- those products manufacturers have said will be updated to Matter as soon as the specification is released.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z3v7Xn"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated Wednesday, December 15, 5:35PM: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Included the names of the other companies involved in the initial development of Thread.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22787729/matter-smart-home-standard-apple-amazon-google"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22787729/matter-smart-home-standard-apple-amazon-google</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Pattison Tuohy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
