<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-12T11:15:36-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T11:15:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T11:15:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Verge is now on your smart TV</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mhU1cYgohM2i9Z5BafOT1eAgz0Y=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69963729/VergeApp_Roku_Splash_Screen_1080.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Stream Verge videos in 4K on Roku, Amazon Fire TV, and Android TV&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="CNRiWq"&gt;EDIT: We’ve identified an issue with the global release. Our app developer has made an update and the app should be available worldwide by Tuesday, October 12th.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; is now available on your TV — in 4K. You can now watch our product reviews, in-depth tech and science explainers, exclusive documentaries, and much more on your favorite streaming devices: Roku, Amazon Fire TV, and Android TV. The app will be on Apple TV later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1dYHPR"&gt;The app includes years of &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; videos, many available in 4K for the first time. You can binge your favorite videos from our team of journalists — including Dieter Bohn and Becca Farsace. The app will also be the first to stream our new documentary on the forgotten history of the Treo featuring The Verge’s Executive Editor, Dieter Bohn. Here’s a teaser: &lt;em&gt;Springboard: the secret history of the first real smartphone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JdNIKt"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Handspring Trailer|104173" data-volume-uuid="89d04bab1" data-volume-id="104173" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-8" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Ei64zL"&gt;You can also follow playlists of feature reporting and first looks or dive deep into topics like gaming and materials. And you can even use your TV to listen to your favorite podcast episodes from &lt;em&gt;The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Decoder with Nilay Patel,&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Why’d You Push That Button?&lt;/em&gt; hosted by Ashley Carman. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OYEYku"&gt;Download the app now to be part of our early adopter group. If you spot any bugs or have any feedback, please send a message to &lt;a href="mailto:support@theverge.com"&gt;support@theverge.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h2kqke"&gt;Here are instructions for each of the streaming devices you can use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="04PqSP"&gt;Amazon Fire&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Rc8UqQ"&gt;From the Amazon Fire Home screen, select “Find.”  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="5z2dwK"&gt;Select “Search.” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AbfUVy"&gt;In the search box, type “The Verge” and then select the search icon. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="K1sV3N"&gt;From the results feed, scroll down to “Apps &amp;amp; Games.” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6Qpbhz"&gt;Scroll through until you find “The Verge.” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nWkqHC"&gt;Select “The Verge” and then click on “Download.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="DvfILT"&gt;Android TV&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="7OxXej"&gt;From the Android TV Home screen, scroll to &lt;strong&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;Apps.”  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WyouCR"&gt;Select the Google Play store app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vj4EWo"&gt;Navigate to the search bar on the upper right hand side and then type “The Verge.” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LlzddJ"&gt;Scroll through search results until you find “The Verge.” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="pnnUnM"&gt;Select “The Verge” and click “Install.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="awMlon"&gt;Roku&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="xirMuR"&gt;From the Roku Home screen, scroll to “Streaming channels.” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3CZuo3"&gt;Scroll down to “Search Channels.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kp8u6R"&gt;In the search box, type “The Verge.” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="QfW0AV"&gt;Scroll through search results until you find “The Verge.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="aHFZni"&gt;Select “The Verge” and then select “Add Channel.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="vTHuWZ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="9APhkv"&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="2ofvt3"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="zaPGHQ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHERE TO WATCH&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="RiH54c"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;
&lt;div id="ZZKUY3"&gt;&lt;div class="section group"&gt;
	&lt;div class="col span_1_of_2"&gt;
	&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Vox-Media-The-Verge/dp/B091D7SV44/ref=sr_1_1?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=The+verge&amp;amp;qid=1633564648&amp;amp;s=mobile-apps&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22906778/VRG_OTT_LandingPage_AmazonFireTV.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;div class="col span_1_of_2"&gt;
	&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.theverge.androidtv"&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22906779/VRG_OTT_LandingPage_AndroidTV.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="2rMbJJ"&gt;&lt;div class="section group"&gt;
	&lt;div class="col span_1_of_2"&gt;
	&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22906780/VRG_OTT_LandingPage_AppleTV.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;div class="col span_1_of_2"&gt;
	&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href="https://channelstore.roku.com/details/6e328aea160203f7fb63e9614bd55c7c/the-verge"&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22906781/VRG_OTT_LandingPage_Roku.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JZ44fj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="14DBbu"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H7bBEq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22680029/the-verge-tv-app-android-tv-amazon-fire-tv-roku"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22680029/the-verge-tv-app-android-tv-amazon-fire-tv-roku</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mariya Abdulkaf</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T11:11:44-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T11:11:44-04:00</updated>
    <title>The next big thing in podcasts is talking back</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2_Pi7SWNLp4t_Bg-ABTFvOtH1hU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69984343/acastro_211012_4801_0001.7.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Poll, Q&amp;amp;As, and comment sections could turn podcasting interactive&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="LTh4KO"&gt;Vince Major and Michael Tucker, hosts of the podcast &lt;em&gt;Beyond the Screenplay&lt;/em&gt;, thought they knew what their audience wanted for their next episode: a deep-dive into &lt;em&gt;Back to the Future —&lt;/em&gt; a “no brainer,”&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;says Major. To be sure, though, they decided to poll their listeners. They didn’t go to Patreon, Instagram, Twitter, or the other places creators often chat with their audience. Instead, they went where their listeners already tune into their show, Spotify, and used its new polling tool to ask. The people spoke up — they wanted &lt;em&gt;The Godfather&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DH8IIy"&gt;“[The polls] kind of just let the podcasting technology catch up in some ways,” Tucker says. “The place where people are actually listening, they can now also participate.” Although the co-hosts only started using these polls within the past year, they say their listeners are taking advantage. They’re talking back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0zdFAZ"&gt;“Podcasting has always been this sort of one-way street,” says Mike Mignano, head of creation platform at Spotify. “A creator publishes content; the audience listens; that’s it.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="wlHeiJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The polls are coming into the podcast apps&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5aDipR"&gt;Now, however, interactive elements are making their way into the space. Spotify is giving all its Anchor creators the ability to make polls and Q&amp;amp;As and is testing interactive ads. Other apps, like Facebook, are trying things as simple as just allowing listeners to leave comments — a mainstay YouTube feature — while podcasting apps in China already allow listeners to build “listening circles” and “discussion groups.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zBVJIw"&gt;“When I first downloaded Chinese podcast apps, I was shocked at how interactive they were,” writes Helen Li in &lt;a href="https://restofworld.org/2021/what-spotify-and-apple-can-learn-from-chinese-podcasting-apps/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rest of World&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0rMWrT"&gt;Although interaction is big abroad, it’s unclear how popular it can be in the US in these traditionally audio-only zones. Do people want to touch their phone while they’re in listening mode? “It’s not really in the mindset of podcasts yet to give that instant feedback to engage,” Major says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="N0Jm0U"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Interactive elements are already popular abroad&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="O7c0Du"&gt;In the US, interaction fervor is nascent but bubbling up. On the just-launched &lt;a href="https://firesidechat.com/"&gt;Fireside&lt;/a&gt;, the live audio app co-founded by Mark Cuban, the first thing you see when you go to its website in big, bold, white font reading: “The future of entertainment is interactive.” Same thing with Twitch&lt;strong&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;which itself is reportedly working on a specific live audio integration: “We build communities around live content that’s interactive, diverse, and always next level.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PYeSa6"&gt;In Fireside’s case, viewers can react with emoji, ask a question, or leave a written comment. On Twitch, listeners can pay to have their name pop up in their favorite streamer’s video and join in the chorus of commenters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SdvMTY"&gt;Amazon, which entered the podcasting space last year with podcasts on Amazon Music and Audible (and also owns Twitch),&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;might be working on something podcast-specific, too. In a survey provided to podcaster attendees of a recent industry conference, the company mentioned the possibility of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashleyrcarman/status/1425202358175338511?s=20"&gt;a polling feature&lt;/a&gt;. Toys and games have also already relied on Alexa as a mediator and guide for interactive moments, so it’s easy to imagine the smart assistant taking on a bigger role in podcasting and ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;div id="xWig1a"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10776720"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2nBw4I"&gt;“We haven’t really seen anyone yet crack the code on true listener-to-creator interactivity on listening platforms,” Mignano says. “So I think it’s just the natural evolution of content and media on the internet, and I think, hopefully now, we can finally catch podcasting up with the rest of the mediums.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s0GV2M"&gt;There’s also the challenge of making interacting with audio feel natural. Backtracks, a podcast analytics and advertising platform, has developed an SDK that &lt;a href="https://backtracks.fm/blog/head-gestures-and-movement-for-airpod-pros-technology/"&gt;pairs with AirPods&lt;/a&gt; to detect head gestures. A podcast ad could say something like, “Nod your head to learn more,” and give you a chance to dive deeper into what you’re hearing. Backtracks CEO Jonathan Gill sees this as more palatable than asking someone who specifically is listening to something rather than watching it to look at their phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HXLJbV"&gt;“If you’re asking someone a question, and you expect them to answer on the phone by looking at the phone, after a certain amount of time, you miss the use case of your audience,” he says. “So one reason to do this as part of the listening experience is somebody could be walking, running, they could be in their house, outside, and then if you ask a question or interact with [the gestures], it actually fits into the context.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SIEqGr"&gt;One of the biggest reasons behind this push for interactivity is the hope that it’ll make podcasts stickier. If you can talk to your favorite podcaster in one specific place or build a community in one app, chances are you’ll return to that place. Then, of course, there’s the ads functionality, an especially critical function in audio, which has primarily relied on promo codes to attribute sales to listeners. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mbkHVy"&gt;The business use cases are clear, but as is always the question with innovation motivated by corporate interests, does anyone outside of these platforms want this? Moreover, would they use it even if they wanted it? Tap the poll below to let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2Ht3yd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="poll:10803231"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722468/spotify-amazon-facebook-audio-podcast-polls-interact"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722468/spotify-amazon-facebook-audio-podcast-polls-interact</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T11:02:37-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T11:02:37-04:00</updated>
    <title>FDA clears Withings’ EKG and blood oxygen features</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6jidNZebeY3jcm2vMrlgOb01kc8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69984261/akrales_200916_4186_0159.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="F9VEwe"&gt;After &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/5/21048522/withings-health-monitoring-scanwatch-ecg-afib-heart-sleep-apnea-blood-oxygen"&gt;over a year&lt;/a&gt; in limbo, Withings finally has Food and Drug Administration clearance for its ScanWatch, which monitors for abnormal heart rhythms through an EKG feature &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; flags nighttime breathing issues with its blood oxygen sensor. The watch has been available for sale in Europe, but not in the United States. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ok2NPs"&gt;This is the first smartwatch to get the FDA’s signoff on both types of health features. Apple, Fitbit, and Samsung all detect blood oxygen levels, but they don’t claim they can detect any medical conditions using that information, so they &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/7/21504023/apple-watch-ekg-blood-oxygen-fda-clearance"&gt;didn’t need to get the agency’s clearance&lt;/a&gt; in order to market the devices. Withings, on the other hand, is claiming that its device can flag nighttime breathing problems through a combination of blood oxygen levels, heart rate, and movement. Those breathing problems can be a sign of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and sleep apnea, the company said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="batkdg"&gt;Withings says its health features have been tested in clinical studies. One tested the EKG feature — the results from that study are not published, but &lt;a href="https://support.withings.com/hc/en-us/articles/360004508038-ScanWatch-Clinical-studies"&gt;the company said&lt;/a&gt; that it showed the feature was accurate and that it returned inconclusive readings one-fifth of the time. &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC8078374/"&gt;Its evaluation&lt;/a&gt; of the pulse oxygen feature, published in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Medical Internet Research&lt;/em&gt;, found that the readings from the ScanWatch matched up with the readings from a standard pulse oximeter. The study included 14 people with a variety of skin tones between the ages of 23 and 39 who didn’t have any medical problems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hLi5eA"&gt;The company also has an &lt;a href="https://support.withings.com/hc/en-us/articles/360004508038-ScanWatch-Clinical-studies"&gt;ongoing trial&lt;/a&gt; testing whether the ScanWatch can diagnose sleep apnea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lh5iHW"&gt;Other smartwatch companies are pursuing sleep apnea features, as well. Fitbit has been working on a similar feature &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/8/30/16227040/fitbit-sleep-apnea-tracking-ionic-smartwatch-sensors"&gt;for years&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/fitbit-really-wants-to-be-able-to-diagnose-your-sleep-a-1841027997"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in early 2020 that it was planning to file for FDA clearance “soon.” Apple is also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22652120/apple-watch-blood-pressure-temperature-sleep-diabetes"&gt;reportedly&lt;/a&gt; working on the Apple Watch’s sleep and blood oxygen features with the goal of detecting sleep apnea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I2MVeu"&gt;Sleep experts say that they’re excited about the potential for smartwatches to help detect conditions like sleep apnea, which often goes undiagnosed. But watches only track a few of the measurements doctors typically use to diagnose the condition, and for now, experts say they aren’t reliable enough to stand alone. They’re more useful as an initial screener, Seema Khosla, medical director of the North Dakota Center for Sleep, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21455863/withings-scanwatch-review-health-sleep-features-price"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PcQXtI"&gt;Withings says the ScanWatch will be available in the US starting in early November. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rb50VI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722333/withings-fda-clearance-blood-oxygen-heart-rhythm"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722333/withings-fda-clearance-blood-oxygen-heart-rhythm</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>8BitDo’s very good Pro 2 controller is getting an Xbox version soon</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="8BitDo Pro 2 for Xbox" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TNlGTwLudBvUjcRC2q8eXqnRCZo=/0x0:2331x1554/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69984199/pro2_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;8BitDo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="n1VpTk"&gt;8BitDo is releasing a wired version of its Pro 2 controller for Xbox consoles and PC on December 8th, 2021. It’s nearly identical in terms of features to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22364301/8bitdo-pro-2-controller-review-switch-back-buttons"&gt;the Bluetooth wireless model that my colleague Sam Byford reviewed&lt;/a&gt;, which supports Switch, mobile, and other platforms. Though, this new Xbox model’s wired-only connection means that it’s cheaper at $44.99. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07P5K93ZN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;You can preorder it now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e5Vlpa"&gt;This Pro 2 is clad in black, with an Xbox home button in its middle. Yet, in addition to all of the other Xbox-specific buttons you’re probably expecting (share, menu, view), it has 8BitDo’s other two buttons near the analog sticks, which can be remapped to your liking in its Ultimate Software app available on iOS and Android. Additionally, there are two buttons on the back of the Pro 2’s grips that can be mapped as you see fit. Through the app, you can also customize vibration, trigger, and stick sensitivity, as well as make a shortcut to adjust volume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jaXLrR"&gt;You might be wondering how this wired controller is able to communicate wirelessly with your phone. 8BitDo told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the Pro 2 for Xbox has a Bluetooth chip inside, which allows it to connect to your phone for the purposes of remapping the controls. However, the functionality ends there. The company said that it is not compatible with other systems wirelessly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="8BitDo Pro 2" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UO945l1CH3_sYU_F0QKG2CjKBYo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22903055/pro2_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: 8BitDo&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="P51VPv"&gt;This controller seems to be made for people who aren’t married to the analog stick arrangement of Microsoft’s Xbox controller. This one’s stick layout is more similar to a PlayStation controller, though all of the necessary Xbox buttons are here. There’s also a 3.5mm port for audio passthrough if you have headphones or a headset to connect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LWNTfC"&gt;It’d be ideal if the Xbox-flavored Pro 2 was wireless, but $45 for a customizable wired controller seems like a good value. Given that 8BitDo’s build quality is usually higher than many other third-party accessory makers, this might make for a nice companion to your official Xbox wireless controller or as a replacement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nb0aAi"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZpuwgC"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rItnzt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22710547/8bitdo-pro-2-xbox-wired-controller-preorder-features-series-x-s-windows-pc"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22710547/8bitdo-pro-2-xbox-wired-controller-preorder-features-series-x-s-windows-pc</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Hyper says its new USB-C docks can run two displays off an M1 MacBook out of the box</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-7O6146PqauJmCxuKJiwdefNd48=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69984220/HDM1H_desk_scene_Environment_4_3000x3000.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Two display from an M1 MacBook.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Hyper&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5VFjOh"&gt;Hyper claims its &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hypershop.com%2Fpages%2Fhyperdrive-dual-4k-hdmi-usb-hub-and-adapter-for-m1-macbooks&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F10%2F12%2F22722192%2Fhyperdrive-usb-c-docks-mackbook-m1-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;new USB-C hubs&lt;/a&gt; will address one of the key frustrations with Apple’s M1 MacBooks: their inability to natively power more than one external display at a time. Both Hyper’s $129.99 “HyperDrive Dual 4K HDMI 3-in-1 USB-C Adapter” and its $199.99 “HyperDrive Dual 4K HDMI 10-in-1 USB-C Hub” have two HDMI ports, which it says can output to two 4K monitors without the need for software drivers. They’re both launching today and are available to buy direct from Hyper. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EnwcdQ"&gt;Neither offers a perfect solution. Hyper notes that both hubs are only able to output a 60Hz signal to one 4K display, while the other will be limited to 30Hz. But it’s more convenient than the kinds of existing workarounds &lt;a href="https://www.macworld.co.uk/how-to/how-connect-two-or-more-external-displays-apple-silicon-m1-mac-3799794/"&gt;outlined in this guide from &lt;em&gt;MacWorld&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which require downloading a third-party driver to the Mac. Even then, some dock manufacturers like Plugable and Caldigit warn that this setup isn’t officially supported, and the latter even actively recommends using its products in this way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Mx_cV0k_RXMosqAe4ZBuUuFpGaA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22920250/HDM1H_Left_Side_Delivery_1_MAIN_3000x3000.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Hyper&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 10-in-1 USB-C hub.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/__tjTQzSHisqoPOlzQHURc3Us-w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22920249/HDM1_Right.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Hyper&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 3-in-1 USB-C adapter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4r4jqw"&gt;As well as running two 4K displays, both of Hyper’s accessories also support 100W USB-C Power Delivery pass through. The 10-in-1 hub also has a range of other ports, including a USB-C data port, two USB-A ports, gigabit Ethernet, SD card slots, and a 3.5mm headphone jack. In addition to M1 MacBooks, Hyper says the hubs also work with other compatible USB-C devices, like Intel-powered MacBooks, Windows PCs, and Chromebooks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zYTH5a"&gt;It’s unfortunate that such an expensive dock is needed to overcome the M1 MacBooks’ limitation in the first place. Here’s hoping &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22441805/apple-macbook-pro-2021-redesign-chip-magsafe-sd-card-slot-hdmi-port"&gt;Apple’s rumored 14- and 16-inch MacBook Pros&lt;/a&gt; won’t suffer from this same limitation.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722192/hyperdrive-usb-c-docks-mackbook-m1-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722192/hyperdrive-usb-c-docks-mackbook-m1-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>VanMoof’s new V e-bike is its fastest ever  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pSX1LkYcdPW0r5kV28rtJAQIkKk=/301x0:3540x2159/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69984203/VanMoof_V_02.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Rendering of the VanMoof V, the company’s first fast e-bike. | Image: VanMoof&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Fast and furious&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="iACxaI"&gt;VanMoof just &lt;a href="https://www.vanmoof.com/news/en-GB/203095-vanmoof-reveals-its-very-first-hyperbike"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href="https://www.vanmoof.com/en-GB/vanmoof-v"&gt;VanMoof V&lt;/a&gt;, the company’s first high-speed electric bike capable of hitting a top speed of 60km/h (37mph). That’s much faster than VanMoof’s current e-bikes, which are capped at 25km/h in Europe and 20mph in the US, and well beyond what local laws currently allow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p-large-text" id="y88cq9"&gt;Vanmoof is launching the pedal-assisted V today as a challenge to lawmakers and city planners to rethink outmoded regulations and start putting the needs of people ahead of cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KxfvEb"&gt;The V’s chiseled design still delivers the oft-imitated VanMoof aesthetic, only now it’s applied to a muscular e-bike fitted with motors in both the front and rear wheel hubs and powered by a hulking 700Wh battery. This allows for longer rides that are softened by oversized tires and a front and rear suspension attached to a “robust” aluminum frame. It also features signature VanMoof touches like a Turbo Boost button, automatic shifting, and a keyless kick lock among the anti-theft and recovery tech we’re used to seeing on the company’s e-bikes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="puZqFC"&gt;And just like VanMoof’s regular commuter e-bikes, there’s no throttle on the pedal-assisted V, and the battery can’t be removed for charging. It will, however, be offered with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22392495/vanmoof-powerbank-range-extender-2021-s3-x3-differences"&gt;PowerBank&lt;/a&gt; range extender option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gyjPC0"&gt;The VanMoof V will initially be sold in the Netherlands, Germany, France, the UK, the US, and Japan for $3,498/€3,498/£3,498. That’s not cheap until you compare it with the price of a car that these sturdy electric commuter bikes can replace. It also undercuts category darling &lt;a href="https://www.stromerbike.com/en/models/models"&gt;Stromer&lt;/a&gt;, whose fast European e-bikes start at about €4,500 and run over €10k, and offers a more sophisticated alternative to US brands like Super73, Juiced, and RadPower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m6eH5Y"&gt;We’re not seeing much in the way of detailed specs being announced today. That’s because the VanMoof V is still in development, with first deliveries not planned until “late 2022.” And in true VanMoof fashion, I’m told that all the new components are being developed in-house. Nevertheless, current VanMoof owners can get in line now by &lt;a href="https://www.vanmoof.com/en-GB/vanmoof-v/reservation"&gt;reserving their VanMoof V&lt;/a&gt; for $20/€20/£20 a pop. Reservation codes will be shared with the general public “periodically” via &lt;a href="https://www.vanmoof.com/en-GB/vanmoof-v#waitlist-signup"&gt;a waitlist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9cJUJ_G0t9KtFuqJeHiw6imxBjE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22920162/VanMoof_V_03.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rear suspension.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yy76IEsfI8759jOrMUkHD9Ck8SY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22920164/VanMoof_V_07.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Front suspension.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6I3gm68eI_Jayme-Y6_iH05yt1U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22920167/VanMoof_V_06.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Front light.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Vlrw3CnqVKOeI7lXl4evF9406BY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22920161/VanMoof_V_05.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tail light.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tvmZ6b"&gt;The VanMoof V is faster than both Europe’s 45km/h limit for so-called speed pedelecs and the 28mph limit for Class 3 e-bikes in the US. Although VanMoof says the bikes will include integrated speed settings tuned to each country’s regulations, it’s using the launch to plead with lawmakers, particularly in Europe, to “urgently update e-bike regulations” that are stifling the development and adoption of fast e-bikes as car replacements, and thus slowing progress towards a more sustainable future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eALSEw"&gt;“During the development of the VanMoof V, VanMoof intends to work with city governments to explore solutions from geofencing to revised speed regulations,” the company says in a press release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8UBN2p"&gt;As I said in my &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22385197/stromer-st2-review-electric-bike-speed-pedec-l1e-b"&gt;review of the Stromer ST2 speed pedelec&lt;/a&gt;, US cities have all of the fast e-bikes and no bicycle infrastructure, whereas European cities have all of the protective infrastructure and few fast e-bikes. Nevertheless, riding a Class 3 e-bike in the US typically requires nothing more than a helmet. European laws also require owners of s-pedelecs to obtain liability insurance and registration. They must also hold a moped-class driver’s license because current rules were implemented long before the advent of the modern e-bike. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C8JdeG"&gt;European rules also force fast e-bikes onto roads, where vulnerable cyclists must ride next to speeding taxis, dangerous trucks, and aggressive BMWs instead of alongside other bicyclists on protected bike lanes. Call me crazy, but if European lawmakers can let Ferraris drive on city roads before turning them loose on the autobahn, you’d think they could do the same for fast e-bikes on &lt;em&gt;speed-enforced &lt;/em&gt;bike lanes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9dD8Vx"&gt;Speed limits could be enforced through the same mechanisms that govern cars already, or via geofencing, as VanMoof suggests. Intelligent Speed Assistance (ISA) systems will be mandatory in new European cars starting in 2022, and several studies are underway to see how the speed limiting technology (which can be overridden by the operator) can be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/26/21154094/ebike-dutch-speed-limit-system-test-green-light-schiphol-s-pedelec-isa"&gt;applied to speed pedelecs&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vLnoVT"&gt;BMW already has a geofencing solution deployed in many European cities to automatically switch its newer plug-in hybrid cars to an all-electric driving mode when entering low emission zones. Last month, it proposed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/9/22664259/speed-pedelec-geofencing-speed-control-electric-bike"&gt;a series of high-speed e-bikes&lt;/a&gt; that would employ geofencing to allow them to act like motorcycles outside the city and bicycles within while noting that the legal framework to develop such e-bikes doesn’t exist. The message was clear: introduce modern legislation that reflects the realities of lightweight electric vehicle transportation, and BMW will make its e-bike concepts real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ESuLWQininGCyh5N8BAf1_kWUeQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22920168/VanMoof_V_01.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Profile.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7JJ8Oc"&gt;VanMoof is flipping the BMW script by announcing sales of its fast e-bike first. Such a move could result in a groundswell of support to prompt legislative action. VanMoof needs cities to change if it’s to make owning an e-bike compelling enough for the company to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22651860/vanmoof-128-million-funding-most-funded-ebike-company"&gt;sell 10 million electric bikes in the next five years&lt;/a&gt; — well above the roughly 200,000 it has shipped since the company was founded over a decade ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dYuETf"&gt;To achieve that goal while keeping its riders safe, VanMoof needs cities to take the rules and infrastructure designed for cars and holistically adapt them to the new realities of urban commutes done by electric skateboard, scooter, and e-bike. Else, they risk the &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/10/02/world/europe/paris-bicyles-france.html"&gt;chaos seen in Paris and other cities&lt;/a&gt; that have tried to adapt piecemeal to the electric bike boom accelerated by the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3RyO05"&gt;“We’re calling for policies designed around people, rethinking how public spaces can be used if not occupied by cars,” says VanMoof co-founder Ties Carlier in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="9exBGU"&gt;Changes of this magnitude would go a long way in helping &lt;a href="https://ec.europa.eu/info/strategy/priorities-2019-2024/european-green-deal_en"&gt;cities achieve their environmental goals&lt;/a&gt;, but they won’t happen overnight. VanMoof’s home of Amsterdam &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/cities/2015/may/05/amsterdam-bicycle-capital-world-transport-cycling-kindermoord"&gt;took decades&lt;/a&gt; to become the bicycle capital of the world. With the launch of the VanMoof V, VanMoof is trying to get the conversation started. If not now, when?&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22722099/vanmoof-v-electric-bike-price-specs-date-preorder"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22722099/vanmoof-v-electric-bike-price-specs-date-preorder</id>
    <author>
      <name>Thomas Ricker</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T10:50:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T10:50:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>Small satellite launcher Astra identifies cause behind strange sideways rocket launch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YWpX4A7w1aV-JbLdHf1X43GDdWk=/0x0:2048x1365/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69984140/50725072431_027173020e_o.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Astra’s 3.2 rocket taking off from Kodiak, Alaska&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Astra/John Kraus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LqijTn"&gt;Small satellite launcher Astra says it has &lt;a href="https://astra.com/news/lv0007-launch-window/"&gt;identified the culprit behind its bizarre launch failure&lt;/a&gt; in August, which caused the company’s rocket to hover sideways right after takeoff before briefly climbing into the sky. After implementing some design changes, Astra says it is ready to try again, with another launch attempt called LV0007 set as early as October 27th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yYy52J"&gt;This will be Astra’s fifth attempt to reach orbit with one of its rockets, which primarily take off from Kodiak, Alaska. The company first tried to send its vehicle to orbit for a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/3/21161727/darpa-launch-challenge-astra-space-competition-no-winner-prize"&gt;DARPA launch challenge&lt;/a&gt; in March 2020 but failed to get the rocket off the ground in time to meet the competition’s deadline. The vehicle then &lt;a href="https://kmxt.org/2020/03/explosion-during-astra-launch-rehearsal-results-in-damage-and-small-fire/"&gt;exploded on its launchpad&lt;/a&gt; a few weeks later. After that, Astra made three more tries throughout 2020 and 2021, where the rockets did actually take flight. The first launch lasted roughly 30 seconds &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/12/21433698/astra-rocket-launch-end-failure-orbit"&gt;before the rocket’s engines cut off and the vehicle fell back to Earth&lt;/a&gt;. Astra did actually reach space with the second flight, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22178110/astra-small-satellite-launcher-rocket-3-2-alaska-success-orbit"&gt;just barely missed reaching orbit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="YQ8GWL"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Reviewing flight data and video, two things are very clear - 1) An engine shut down right after launch 2) Everything that happened next made me incredibly proud of our team. Space may be hard, but like this rocket, we are not giving up.  &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AdAstra?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#AdAstra&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/2g3n812EaW"&gt;pic.twitter.com/2g3n812EaW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Chris Kemp (@Kemp) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Kemp/status/1431812555324854272?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 29, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="f1WfYT"&gt;Astra’s third attempt on August 28th, 2021 caught people’s attention with its strange maneuvering. Right after takeoff, the rocket briefly glided off the ground and then swept to the side after one of its five main engines shut down early. The vehicle then climbed into the sky after a few seconds and even managed to reach an altitude of 31 miles before the flight crews terminated the launch two minutes and 30 seconds into the launch. Astra says that there was a leakage of the rocket’s propellant that caused the engine to cut off early, which was “something we hadn’t seen before.” The company claims to have made some design changes to ensure that the same failure doesn’t happen again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l05EeN"&gt;“Data from the two-and-a-half minute flight provided valuable insights that we have incorporated into LV0007 and future launch vehicles,” said Chris Kemp, founder and CEO of Astra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="79spJk"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Data from the two-and-a-half minute flight provided valuable insights.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tX8HI5"&gt;Astra’s sideways failure came less than two months after the &lt;a href="https://spacenews.com/astra-completes-spac-merger-and-begins-trading-publicly/"&gt;company successfully went public through a SPAC merger&lt;/a&gt;. The company’s stocks &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/08/30/astra-stock-falls-25percent-after-companys-weekend-rocket-launch-failure.html"&gt;drastically fell the Monday following the botched launch attempt&lt;/a&gt;. In September, Astra inked &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/21/22670063/astra-firefly-reaver-rocket-engine-ip-agreement"&gt;a secret $30 million deal with rival launch company Firefly Aerospace&lt;/a&gt;, which would allow the company to manufacture Firefly’s Reaver rocket engine. Astra’s ultimate goal is to launch small satellites on its rockets, which stand at just 43 feet tall. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fsivr5"&gt;The company’s next launch out of Kodiak, Alaska will loft a test payload for the Space Test Program, which oversees experimental space launches for the US Department of Defense. Astra says its launch window for the mission first opens on October 27th and ends on October 31st. If for some reason the rocket doesn’t fly during that time, the company can try again during another window that runs from November 5th through November 12th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722331/astra-rocket-launch-failure-identified-lv0007"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722331/astra-rocket-launch-failure-identified-lv0007</id>
    <author>
      <name>Loren Grush</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T10:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T10:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Tech tools for teaching in a classroom during a pandemic</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fTILrJirYSE2TFFIPj6ypQdU4NY=/186x0:5747x3707/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69984062/GoogleChromecastRemoteandUI.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Chromecast with Google TV makes it easy to play content in front of a class without occupying your laptop.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Philip Berne for The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lNnLCG"&gt;The last year of lockdown and learning from home was undoubtedly the most challenging year for teachers in a generation. Now that students are returning to class, we face new challenges. Students hide behind their masks. Understaffing and last-minute changes require us to be more flexible. The transition from “going to school” in pajamas on the couch to physically going to school is exhausting, and engagement is low. Frankly, it’s quiet. Too quiet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RSxLLd"&gt;Here are some of my favorite tools that I’ve purchased this year to overcome the COVID doldrums. If you are a teacher with some classroom funds to spend, or if you know teachers who could use a tech boost, this is what I recommend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="832RT6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10801965" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yV34JJ"&gt;Every time a student gives an impassioned answer and I have to tell them I couldn’t hear it, I see their enthusiasm crushed. Karaoke gear, like the M37 microphone with Bluetooth from Miracle Karaoke, can be a fun solution — but be very sensitive introducing these to the class. Students haven’t been required to speak up in a classroom in front of their peers for more than a year, and there will be anxiety to overcome. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k1GHSN"&gt;These microphones have solid battery life and a built-in speaker, but they also pair via Bluetooth if you prefer. You might not bother with the karaoke sound effects, but there is a sweet little disco-ball light that attaches to the bottom if you want to make class more festive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jaGvYN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10801971" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3YppjL"&gt;When I need to project my voice through a mask to the back of the room, this amazing little HW Haoworks speaker box is the device I wear. The microphone comes paired via UHF, so it’s much clearer and more reliable than a Bluetooth headset, though you can also switch to Bluetooth if you desire. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BoBj2n"&gt;The speaker itself is water resistant, has a long-lasting battery, and is packed with useful features. My favorite: it can hold a microSD card to record instruction for students who are absent. I wear the boom microphone under my mask, and with the foam sock, it transmits my voice without too much breath noise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="mpKlSf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10801977" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cd28z0"&gt;Harman Kardon SoundSticks are special. There are better speakers you can buy for less, but I consider the premium a room decoration expense. When students come to class and see the SoundSticks positioned in the front, with the jellyfish subwoofer beneath the screen, they are immediately engaged. They want to hear what happens next, and that curiosity is worth the price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tY1DnW"&gt;I prefer the older version with a 3.5mm headphone plug to the newer Bluetooth model. Bluetooth and teaching do not mix well. Nothing kills the momentum of a class like a tech failure, and Bluetooth is the Viking king of tech failures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TLJKN8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10801982" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nlBKgP"&gt;Here is my splurge, the Nebula by Mars II projector, because I had an Amazon gift card and further justified when I decided to take on sponsorship of my school’s Anime Club. These COVID times call for flexibility, and not every classroom I use has a smart screen or all of the connections I need to show my lesson. I carry my projector to create a pop-up classroom wherever I am. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GIl67Q"&gt;The Nebula by Anker Mars II projector is just a bit bigger than the soda-can-sized Anker Nebula Capsule projectors, and it pumps out a ton more light. The speaker is good enough for impromptu classes in a hallway or an adjunct trailer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AFTJtT"&gt;There are some major caveats. It runs Android 7, though you can obviously just plug your source (likely a laptop, but a streaming stick works, too) directly into the HDMI port instead of using an app to show videos. Some video services like Netflix and Peacock will not let you stream using an external HDMI source. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="k37SNS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10801989" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3LQzHO"&gt;Get one of these Anker PowerPort Cubes and put it near your desk. When students need to charge, you get three power outlets for Chromebooks and three USB ports for phones. I find that often the students who frequently need to charge their equipment are the same students I want sitting closer to my desk for extra supervision. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="BHnBfN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10801992" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZFTGx5"&gt;It only took a couple of cuts with a colleague’s Cricut to know I wanted one. I picked up the Cricut Explore Air 2 because it’s available for a good price and it can make everything I would ever purchase to decorate my classroom. Decorations are a huge expense and a shopping hassle. Teacher stores never have exactly the message you need to convey, or you need to buy multiple packs of letters and stickers just to complete a thought. With the Cricut, you can cut only what you really need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EqZON6"&gt;I started by creating decorations and learning stations, cutting letters and shapes out of colored paper. Then I moved on to labeling and decorating my class with vinyl transfer. My next project will be to create customized T-shirts that I can wear on specific lesson days. I bought this Cricut at the start of the school year, and every day I look around and think of something new I want to cut that night. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XTZBR9"&gt;One important note, you don’t need to buy all Cricut-branded accessories, so if you shop for a Cricut don’t bother with the bundles. Every accessory tool Cricut offers is available from other manufacturers for half price or less. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="81liF8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9503888" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_layout"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oxZ5Ag"&gt;With a handy Google Chromecast with Google TV, I don’t need to connect my laptop to show content to students, and there are many reasons that’s a good thing. My laptop performs better when it isn’t mirroring. I don’t have to worry about notifications popping up at the wrong time. Plus, I can set up my Chromecast with all of my accounts in advance at home to save time and avoid sticky firewall problems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G4UbGd"&gt;Using my 5G phone as a hotspot, I get enough data throughput to show videos from YouTube or Netflix, or to play Crunchyroll when hosting my Anime Club. I have Roku devices at home and I love those as well, but for my school, I chose a Google device because our school accounts are Google-based.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1SpRHK"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Philip Berne is a technology writer and a high school English teacher near Washington, DC.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SRutZw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NQMPwi"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22721266/teacher-tech-gadgets-classroom-microphone-projector"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22721266/teacher-tech-gadgets-classroom-microphone-projector</id>
    <author>
      <name>Philip Berne</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T10:13:45-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T10:13:45-04:00</updated>
    <title>Chevy Bolt recall will be paid for by battery supplier LG Electronics, GM says</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8Zppv25Jxk3BtojPGU5LFKBfONM=/0x85:2040x1445/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69984005/aliptak_180919_2960_5234.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Andrew Liptak / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="k0nkFv"&gt;General Motors and LG Electronics have struck a deal in which the South Korean battery maker will pay for all the costs associated with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/30/22648922/gm-chevy-bolt-ev-production-halt-recall-fire-risk"&gt;the massive Chevy Bolt recall&lt;/a&gt;, the companies announced. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="19gUhr"&gt;Last August, GM announced that it was recalling all Chevy Bolts made after 2017, including the new versions released earlier this year, after multiple fires in the electric vehicle’s battery packs were found to have been caused by defects in the LG Chem cells found inside. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p31naC"&gt;As part of the agreement, LG will reimburse GM for the “costs and expenses” associated with the recall, which &lt;a href="https://investor.gm.com/news-releases/news-release-details/general-motors-lg-electronics-reach-agreement-bolt-ev-recall"&gt;the automaker estimates&lt;/a&gt; will “offset $1.9 billion of $2.0 billion in charges associated with the recalls.” It’s a better deal than originally expected, with &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/gm-says-it-will-seek-reimbursement-from-lg-chem-for-1b-chevy-bolt-recall-losses/"&gt;GM stating&lt;/a&gt; that it would seek $1 billion in reimbursement from LG. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="pQuIVC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Chevy Bolt recall is burning up what’s left of GM’s EV good will","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/19/22677539/chevy-bolt-recall-gm-electric-vehicles-fire-tesla-competition"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="kS8rrp"&gt;“LG is a valued and respected supplier to GM, and we are pleased to reach this agreement,” said Shilpan Amin, GM vice president for global purchasing and supply chain, in a statement. “Our engineering and manufacturing teams continue to collaborate to accelerate production of new battery modules, and we expect to begin repairing customer vehicles this month.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xFCgvS"&gt;As of last week, &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/11/gm-has-started-shipping-replacement-battery-modules-for-recalled-chevy-bolt-evs/"&gt;GM has begun shipping&lt;/a&gt; replacement battery cells to dealerships after initial delays that resulted from factory shutdowns caused by the global semiconductor chip shortage. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722317/chevy-bolt-recall-paid-lg-electronics-gm-costs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722317/chevy-bolt-recall-paid-lg-electronics-gm-costs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-12T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-12T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung’s new 980 Pro SSD for the PS5 brings its own heatsink</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Iuq86RISXEP3S64ZSWOI5d7AHPA=/0x0:4500x3000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69983895/980_PRO_with_Heatsink.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VHxb18"&gt;Samsung has created a new 980 Pro SSD model designed for Sony’s PlayStation 5. The SSD includes a heatsink specifically designed to fit inside the M.2 SSD storage expansion slot inside the PS5. Samsung is releasing this new 980 Pro SSD model on October 29th, priced at $249.99 for the 1TB version or $449.99 for the 2TB model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YNagmi"&gt;The built-in heatsink is designed to keep temperatures low enough to deliver sustained speeds, with sequential read speeds of up to 7,000MB/s and sequential write speeds up to 5,100MB/s. Not many games take advantage of such speeds on the PS5 just yet — Samsung’s 980 Pro specs are way above the 5,500MB/s read speeds that Sony recommends. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZPIMsC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;This new 980 Pro model will sit neatly inside the PS5’s M.2 SSD expansion slot&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yaUCZJ"&gt;Sony also recommends a heatsink on compatible SSDs. PS5 owners have been able to use the existing 980 Pro with a third-party heatsink, but this new model makes it a lot easier for people to simply slot this fast M.2 SSD into the PS5 without any modifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iwXZpB"&gt;If you’re planning to use this SSD elsewhere, Samsung lists the dimensions as 24mm (W), 80mm (L), and 8.6mm (H). Most modern motherboards come equipped with built-in heatsinks that should keep the 980 Pro cool enough for sustained speeds, so this new heatsink option is really targeting PS5 owners looking for one of the best SSD options available right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E51V2z"&gt;If you’re interested in other alternatives and cheaper options, we have a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22602046/best-ps5-playstation-5-m2-ssd-compatible-drives"&gt;PS5 SSD buying guide&lt;/a&gt; with a number of M.2 SSD models that will fit inside the PS5 with heatsinks attached.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722183/samsung-980-pro-ps5-ssd-heatsink-release-date-pricing"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22722183/samsung-980-pro-ps5-ssd-heatsink-release-date-pricing</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
