<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2022-01-19T15:04:55-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T15:04:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T15:04:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>Strava can help you avoid the runs on those long runs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EJDv95beNRvYM2hkVgFBU8e3ZvE=/505x0:3022x1678/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70409243/Screen_Shot_2022_01_19_at_12.13.16_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Points of Interest is Strava’s latest feature&lt;/em&gt; | Screenshot: Victoria Song / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rDy5zv"&gt;There’s nothing like being 45 minutes into a run on a new route, far from civilization, and feeling the tell-tale gurgle in your intestines signaling the dreaded &lt;a href="https://www.health.com/condition/digestive-health/runners-trots"&gt;runner’s trots&lt;/a&gt;. Sometimes, Google can come to your aid, but searching for a public restroom while trying not to publically poop your pants is, needless to say, incredibly stressful. So, it’s nice to see that Strava’s quietly added a new feature called Points of Interest that will help users find helpful locations on a given route. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x24qLh"&gt;According to a &lt;a href="https://support.strava.com/hc/en-us/articles/4420443741453-Points-of-Interest"&gt;Strava support post&lt;/a&gt;, Points of Interest is a feature that adds “community-powered local hotspots” to make outdoor activities like running, cycling, and hiking more enjoyable. These hot spots can include the obvious, like public restrooms and water fountains, as well as cafes, bike shops, photo spots, and other landmarks. The company says that the points are created from areas that are popular with Strava athletes from OpenStreetMap. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MQRleW"&gt;“Most maps have been optimized for cars, so we wanted to build a map oriented around athletes rather than vehicles,” Will Meyer, senior product manager for Strava’s Places team, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Dp-Lf16yI2uNkQTM-rnLJ7c7lQE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23179508/IMG_2486.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot: Victoria Song / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can also see Points of Interest in the mobile app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="L6iRWJ"&gt;The idea is to help athletes figure out the best part of an area to start an activity, as well as see where helpful areas might be located. Depending on whether you need a snack, bathroom break, or a place to refill a water bottle, you can now reroute yourself to a relevant area. While all Strava users will be able to see the Points of Interest map layer, subscribers can also create their own routes based around hotspots using the Routebuilder tool on the website or via the Maps tab in the app. There are also suggested Start Points, or popular areas where Strava users begin activities from. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D6Yt6r"&gt;Using Points of Interest is pretty straightforward — though, personally, it was most useful when planning out a route beforehand. (I try not to look at my phone while running, lest I run headfirst into a lamp post.) We’ll have to see how useful it ends up being when in a pinch. That said, it’s good to see fitness services adding handy navigational and safety tools for users. Aside from a case of runner’s trots, dehydration and “hitting the wall” are also major concerns that can leave runners, cyclists, or hikers in a lurch. This is particularly true for beginners, who may not have invested in a fitness watch with preloaded maps and primarily rely on smartphones. Aside from Strava, Garmin also recently announced its new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22883556/garmin-fenix-7-epix-gps-smartwatches-outdoors-fitness"&gt;Fenix 7 smartwatches&lt;/a&gt; would also include a similar feature dubbed Up Ahead that highlights aid stations, water, and elevation climbs on a given route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="INywSh"&gt;“Points of Interest has been in development for over five months, and more ways to interact with dynamic POI will be coming later this year, along with a suite of features that complement POI,” Meyer added. “We’re just getting started with how athletes can engage with points of interest and trailheads on Strava and working to build the best athlete-centric map.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891366/strava-routes-maps-points-of-interest-running"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891366/strava-routes-maps-points-of-interest-running</id>
    <author>
      <name>Victoria Song</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T14:45:08-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T14:45:08-05:00</updated>
    <title>Instagram is testing paid subscriptions with a small group of creators</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-kW_L_SKtAt_I9Q_JnQHOoKXBXc=/0x43:1024x726/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70409099/FJfCrvxVQAQkLQv.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Instagram&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FYPODQ"&gt;US Instagram users will soon be able to subscribe to a small number of creators and influencers to access exclusive content and features. In a blog post, the company says it’s launching &lt;a href="https://business.instagram.com/blog/subscriptions-creators-instagram-recurring-monthly-income/"&gt;a test of subscriptions&lt;/a&gt; today, with more creators being added in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="14uOl3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;10 creators are part of the early test, including basketball player Sedona Prince, Olympian Jordan Chiles, and astrologer Aliza Kelly&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rwQepO"&gt;Fans will pay a monthly fee to access subscriber-only content from creators they follow, like exclusive Lives and Stories. Subscribers will also get a purple badge by their username that signals their status to the creator. Price tiers will range from $0.99 to $99.99 per month, and creators can select the price point for their subscriptions. Co-head of product Ashley Yuki &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/19/instagram-launches-early-test-of-creator-subscriptions-in-the-u-s"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;that Instagram will not take a cut of creators’ subscription revenues “until at least 2023.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nq6ksp"&gt;Ten creators are part of the early test, including basketball player Sedona Prince, Olympian Jordan Chiles, and astrologer Aliza Kelly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mkNDEg"&gt;“I’m excited to keep building tools for creators to make a living doing creative work and to put these tools in more creators’ hands soon,” Mark Zuckerberg, CEO of Meta, which owns Instagram, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10114247293526361"&gt;wrote in a Facebook post&lt;/a&gt;. Facebook also has its own version of a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/creators/earn-money-with-subscriptions"&gt;subscription&lt;/a&gt; program for creators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JVA4lM"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mosseri/status/1483867380878958593"&gt;In a video today&lt;/a&gt;, Instagram head Adam Mosseri says subscriptions are “one of the best ways” for influencers and creators to have a predictable income. Some creators have already been monetizing Instagram features like Close Friends by &lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2019/09/close-friends-instagram-subscription-charge-influencers/598171/"&gt;charging fans a fee&lt;/a&gt; off-platform for access to Stories. Instagram and Facebook aren’t the only companies to roll out subscription models to compete with platforms like TikTok; in 2021, Twitter &lt;a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/product/2021/introducing-super-follows"&gt;introduced&lt;/a&gt; Super Follows, and some creators offer additional subscriber content off-platform on Patreon or Substack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nSHBKE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891722/instagram-paid-subscriptions-test"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891722/instagram-paid-subscriptions-test</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mia Sato</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T14:16:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T14:16:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>Belkin’s Boost Charge Pro is a $60 MagSafe puck with a kickstand and braided cable</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1ymzF4VRYu34a_agF_PV6_giTyo=/0x123:1000x790/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70408973/webdam.web.1000.1000.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The cable is also a meter longer than Apple’s version.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Belkin&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mbMu6O"&gt;Belkin’s new Boost Charge Pro wireless charging pad takes Apple’s MagSafe puck and ... well, makes it “pro” with a 2-meter-long braided cable and a kickstand for propping your phone up to make it easier to see while it’s charging (&lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2022/01/18/belkin-launches-magsafe-charger-with-kickstand/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). It also comes in black, a must for any accessory sporting the pro moniker. There is a bit of a catch, though — like many accessories with official MagSafe certification, it doesn’t come cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5BZjfn"&gt;At $60, which it’s listed at in both the &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/HPT72ZM/A/belkin-boost%E2%86%91charge%E2%84%A2-pro-portable-wireless-charger-pad-with-magsafe-special-edition"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.belkin.com%2Fus%2Fmagsafe-magnetic-accessories%2Fmagsafe%2Fboost-charge-pro-portable-wireless-charger-pad-with-magsafe-15w%2Fp%2Fp-wia004%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2022%2F1%2F19%2F22890567%2Fbelkin-boost-charge-pro-magsafe-puck-kickstand-braided-cable-expensive-chargers" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Belkin&lt;/a&gt; stores, the Boost Charge Pro costs significantly more than &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MHXH3AM/A/magsafe-charger?fnode=d76192b5c56e1c17af16d3c4b14699bc630d952cc4a5270eb57358c107d1627abb5684e394d566146208b03ae324c2aaaa5c81a50cc7b3e2458e016fb69760a3460ed0958f075e9ce2c4d0b285230d910e243d7c13efecd8d63a2f62b679a8140b7cb0349a986f62055ef44ac3ff3196"&gt;Apple’s $40 MagSafe charger&lt;/a&gt;, which was already seen as a bit on the pricy side. Yes, you do get that kickstand, and having a longer cable is definitely a plus. But is it really worth an extra $20, especially considering that you may need to budget for a USB-C charging brick, as it’s not included with either option?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ScN-V7xljU_DRjkbjNT6mJtOjDM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23178248/HPUC2_AV4.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Belkin&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ll admit it does look good in black.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="C0BeEF"&gt;This is a familiar story with MagSafe; despite the technology launching with the iPhone 12, MagSafe certified charging accessories aren’t particularly common. Amazon is full of MagSafe &lt;em&gt;compatible &lt;/em&gt;wireless chargers that’ll magnetically attach to your phone (some of them even have a kickstand!), but they’re almost certainly going to max out at 7.5W of charging instead of the 15W that MagSafe affords on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22691602/iphone-13-mini-slower-magsafe-charging-speeds-12w"&gt;non-Mini iPhones&lt;/a&gt;. (It’s also worth noting that some Amazon vendors still advertise their charging pucks as being capable of putting out 15W, but the listings usually&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;admit that number is only achievable on Samsung phones.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="jZ55d3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The handful of MagSafe accessories that are out have eye-popping prices&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JekqBu"&gt;When manufacturers do come out with MagSafe accessories, the prices are often eye-popping. Perhaps one of the most infamous instances is Belkin’s $40 Car Vent Mount Pro with MagSafe, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22387722/apple-magsafe-belkin-car-vent-mount-pro-review-no-charger"&gt;&lt;em&gt;is not capable of charging your phone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. But Belkin is far from the only company putting out pricy MagSafe accessories — &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2022/01/18/mophie-magsafe-travel-charger/"&gt;Mophie just announced&lt;/a&gt; a $150 three-in-one travel charging mat that has a MagSafe phone charger, an Apple Watch charging puck, and a (presumably Qi) charger for AirPods. Apple’s own MagSafe Duo Charger, which doesn’t include that extra AirPod pad, will set you back $130. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B0fdA8"&gt;Compared to those products, &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/HPP82ZM/A/mophie-3-in-1-stand-for-magsafe-charger?fnode=4e74707df6f53e9bea4a2730e6b91cc8e624a572af1b687dea4d8ba0f88f9a40a92e8c22b7be656ee1ca763cca646e95d9e1d17ce95265d37db2ba9c5e3b330a9dc2ef381460f0e183da6eae69971d7d1867d2eb196a2b5a5488fb315e9486761d4932a636f839dd87b6803cbb5dda19"&gt;Mophie’s $90 three-in-one stand&lt;/a&gt; that’s meant to stay at home almost seems reasonable — except for the fact that you have to bring your own MagSafe puck, putting its price in line with &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/HPU82ZM/A/belkin-boost%E2%86%91charge%E2%84%A2pro-3-in-1-wireless-charging-pad-with-magsafe?fnode=4e74707df6f53e9bea4a2730e6b91cc8e624a572af1b687dea4d8ba0f88f9a40a92e8c22b7be656ee1ca763cca646e95d9e1d17ce95265d37db2ba9c5e3b330a9dc2ef381460f0e183da6eae69971d7d1867d2eb196a2b5a5488fb315e9486761d4932a636f839dd87b6803cbb5dda19"&gt;Belkin’s similar $150 home charging mat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="SuTcSh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"A year later, Apple’s MagSafe continues to underwhelm","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728967/apple-magsafe-duo-wallet-cases-charging"},{"title":"Apple’s been playing it too MagSafe","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22629703/apple-magsafe-charging-mfi-standard-accessory"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="sVKV2e"&gt;This isn’t to say that MagSafe is bad or that these manufacturers should feel bad. It’s just that over a year since they were first introduced, MagSafe accessories are still quite expensive. And while Belkin’s latest puck doesn’t buck that trend, it is at least nice to have a MagSafe charger with a longer, braided cable that you won’t have to buy a separate stand for. It’s still &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22265910/belkin-magsafe-3-in-1-wireless-charger-hands-on-iphone-12-watch"&gt;not as cute as Belkin’s charging tree&lt;/a&gt;, though.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22890567/belkin-boost-charge-pro-magsafe-puck-kickstand-braided-cable-expensive-chargers"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22890567/belkin-boost-charge-pro-magsafe-puck-kickstand-braided-cable-expensive-chargers</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T14:15:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T14:15:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to file and pay your 2021 taxes online </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="irs (ray tsang flickr)" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2q0opZZPof55VL_p6_kem5Om2QQ=/0x3:1100x736/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70408963/irs.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QSUmXj"&gt;In 2020, the COVID-19 pandemic took everyone, including the IRS, by surprise, and the filing deadline for federal tax payments was moved from the usual mid-April date to July 15th. In 2021, the due date was pushed back to May 17th, 2021. Right now, however, it looks like we’ll be back to the traditional mid-April due dates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pThjvo"&gt;Actually, because the tax deadline can’t be the same day as an official holiday, most of us have until April 18th (April 15th is Emancipation Day in DC). If you live in Maine or Massachusetts, you actually have until April 19th because of Patriots’ Day. Need an extension? After you’ve &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21324583/taxes-2020-file-extension-deadline-irs-how-to"&gt;applied for that extension&lt;/a&gt;, you have until October 17th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T1IHJ6"&gt;However, the IRS has also made it known that the &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/newsroom/irs-operations-during-covid-19-mission-critical-functions-continue"&gt;pandemic is still slowing down some operations&lt;/a&gt;, such as processing returns filed on paper. As a result, it might not be a bad idea to start working on those taxes as soon as possible — and to submit them online. In fact, whether you’re a full-time worker dealing with a single 1040 or a freelancer / gig worker getting a series of 1099s, the fastest way to pay the piper these days is to do it online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="7RmRXX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10286635"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DtewJZ"&gt;The IRS offers a series of directions &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/"&gt;on its website&lt;/a&gt; to help US citizens figure out their taxes, report those taxes, and send in payments (or ask for refunds) using its e-file online method. Here’s a rundown of what’s available and where you can find it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Your first stop: IRS.gov" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bropDdmR6TVbcwzKTPMNEQt_4Js=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23179136/Screen_Shot_2022_01_19_at_10.40.37_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your first stop: IRS.gov&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="MrTZxI"&gt;How do I file online?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Wfouu8"&gt;There are several ways to file online, depending on your income and your comfort level in dealing with the whole income tax process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IAGjYo"&gt;If your &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/e-file-providers/definition-of-adjusted-gross-income"&gt;adjusted gross income&lt;/a&gt; was $73,000 or under, you can use the &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/filing/free-file-do-your-federal-taxes-for-free"&gt;IRS Free File option&lt;/a&gt;. The site offers a number of third-party services that can help you put together and file your taxes free of charge. Of course, that is assuming the third party doesn’t try to scam you into paying more than you have to; back in April of 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/turbotax-deliberately-hides-its-free-file-page-from-search-engines"&gt;&lt;em&gt;ProPublica&lt;/em&gt; revealed&lt;/a&gt; that TurboTax and other suppliers were deliberately hiding the pages for their free services in order to convince taxpayers to purchase additional features. As a result, in early 2020, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/1/21045779/irs-turbotax-free-file-h-r-block-tax-preparation-new-rules"&gt;IRS published rules&lt;/a&gt; prohibiting these practices. Still, it pays to be careful.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Free File is available for those whose income is $73,000 or less." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w7fFoMfWnTL-co_lcFIqLOtGLtQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23179142/Screen_Shot_2022_01_19_at_10.43.17_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Free File is available for those whose income is $73,000 or less.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fC7FEJ"&gt;If your income is above $73,000, you can still use fillable forms provided by IRS Free File, but you don’t get the support of the free software, and you can’t do your state taxes through this method. The forms will be available starting on January 24th. (If you’re really into doing your own taxes, you may want to check out the &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/newsroom/irs-tax-tips"&gt;IRS page on tax tips&lt;/a&gt;, which includes how to handle things like &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/newsroom/taxpayers-must-report-gig-economy-earnings-when-filing-taxes"&gt;gig economy earnings&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dlnklN"&gt;If you’re not a pro at filling out taxes, you’re going to either have to use e-file with one of the available software solutions or find a tax preparer who can do it for you. For those whose income is $58,000 or less, the IRS has a program called the Volunteer Income Tax Assistance (VITA) to help with tax preparation; there is also Tax Counseling for the Elderly (TCE) for people who are 60 or older. The &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/individuals/free-tax-return-preparation-for-qualifying-taxpayers"&gt;page describing these programs&lt;/a&gt; has a locator tool so you can find one of these sites near you; considering the current pandemic, it’s likely that much of the help will happen over the phone or via videoconferencing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yHhDuA"&gt;If you use a tax preparer, the person or company who does your taxes needs to be authorized to use e-file; if you don’t already have a tax professional, you can find one at &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/e-file-providers/authorized-irs-e-file-provider-locator-service-for-tax-professionals"&gt;the IRS site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="5JFGLd"&gt;How do I pay online?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="qQd1r5"&gt;The IRS lists a variety of ways you can &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/payments"&gt;pay your taxes online&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EmMzlE"&gt;If you use tax preparation software or have your taxes prepared by a tax professional, you can have the IRS pull the funds directly from your bank account via the &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/payments/eftps-the-electronic-federal-tax-payment-system"&gt;Electronic Federal Tax Payment System (EFTPS)&lt;/a&gt; at the same time you file. Be aware that, according to the IRS, it can take up to five business days to process a new enrollment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JwT6HE"&gt;You can also use &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/payments/direct-pay"&gt;IRS Direct Pay&lt;/a&gt; to pull funds from a savings or checking account. Finally, you can &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/payments/pay-your-taxes-by-debit-or-credit-card"&gt;use a credit or debit card&lt;/a&gt;; however, there is a fee involved (since the IRS isn’t going to absorb what your credit card company is charging for the service). In fact, if you use a credit card, you may have to add as much as 1.98 percent of your payment amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ugxyPN"&gt;How do I get my refund?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="o8jn9l"&gt;One of the ways the IRS tries to convince you to file online is to assure you that you will get your refund faster — &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/refunds/tax-season-refund-frequently-asked-questions"&gt;in less than 21 days&lt;/a&gt;, in most cases, although there are exceptions. Once you’ve filed, you can &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/refunds"&gt;check the status&lt;/a&gt; of your refund online. You can also &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/newsroom/irs2goapp"&gt;download the official IRS2Go&lt;/a&gt; mobile app, which allows you to check the status of your refund, pay your taxes, and get other information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l9GmZM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22889295/taxes-irs-file-pay-online-2021-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22889295/taxes-irs-file-pay-online-2021-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T14:05:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T14:05:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Fortnite’s latest virtual event is a simple — yet important — art gallery</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k090pn-DuuFm718qRbwRf7lZVh8=/330x0:3290x1973/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70408920/Fortnite_20220118172851.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1RRaaD"&gt;Yesterday on my lunch break, I spent about 15 minutes wandering the halls of the Serpentine gallery, looking at the “New Fiction” exhibition from pop artist Brian Donnelly, better known by his alias Kaws. There were all kinds of statues of his iconic “Companion” character — you may recognize its Mickey Mouse-like visage from copious vinyl figures or as an awards statue for the MTV VMAs — along with some huge, colorful paintings. It was a pleasant way to soak in some culture — and it all took place inside &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ei8ePZ"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; exhibition was essentially a virtual recreation of an IRL display at the real Serpentine in London, which is currently underway. Compared to other, similar virtual events, it’s pretty simple. It doesn’t have the surreal interactivity of “Your Progress Will Be Saved,” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/1/21308391/fortnite-creative-manchester-international-festival-art-exhibition-laturbo-avedon"&gt;a virtual &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; installation from 2020&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22788135/radiohead-kid-a-mnesia-exhibition-review"&gt;the Kid A Mnesia exhibition&lt;/a&gt; that was created as a collaboration between Radiohead and &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; developer Epic Games. Instead, it’s a fairly straightforward recreation of the gallery, where you can wander around and take in the exhibits at your own pace; aside from the building, there’s a big outdoor garden with some towering Kaws statues. (If you attend the show in-person, there’s also an AR element &lt;a href="https://acuteart.com/artist/kaws-new-fiction/"&gt;through the Acute mobile app&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MM4Jl3kbW7mzTkhaoVpNiacBgEM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23179273/Fortnite_20220118173010.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6XGcQQ"&gt;The most interesting thing about the &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; version of the show is how it’s being presented. It’s not tucked away in its own section of the Creative mode, where most players will probably miss it. Instead, for the next week, it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; the main hub. So if you want to hop in to see what the latest popular Creative mode games are, you’ll be dropped into the garden outside of the gallery. From there, you can wander around and pick games and experiences to try, but you also might be tempted by the giant red Companion statue lingering in the background, luring you to see what this “New Fiction” exhibit is all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sIMI9S"&gt;It’s basically a Trojan horse for pop art. Whatever you think of Kaws’ work, making it prominently available inside one of the most popular video games on the planet is a big deal. And it’s all part of an ongoing process of Epic sneaking culture into what is ostensibly a multiplayer shooter.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/D3nolbk5saRCb_UV-e7SvbcGNR0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23179507/Fortnite_20220118172805.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="NHtQBO"&gt;There are high-profile examples, of course, like the massive musical events from the likes of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/2/18208223/fortnite-epic-games-marshmello-concert-exciting-bizarre-future-music"&gt;Marshmello&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22616664/ariana-grande-fortnite-rift-tour-worldbuilding-storytelling"&gt;Ariana Grande&lt;/a&gt;. There have also been smaller-scale — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/25/22550240/fortnite-easy-life-concert-o2-arena"&gt;and much stranger&lt;/a&gt; — virtual performances, along with music everywhere from the dance club on the Party Royale island to radio stations while players drive around in battle royale. Meanwhile, prominent artists like &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cjwardart/status/1437347950343118852"&gt;Christian Ward&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FortniteGame/status/1425862696059158528"&gt;Yuko Shimizu&lt;/a&gt; have created loading screens and other in-game art, and last Halloween, players could buy a Kaws-designed in-game character. &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; is a big, messy mashup of pop culture, and increasingly that includes more than just big brands like Marvel and &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n4BShY"&gt;In an interview with &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2022/jan/18/kaws-fortnite-serpentine-street-art-augmented-reality"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Donnelly described these kinds of projects as a way “to throw bridges to a new generation.” It doesn’t replace the experience of attending a real gallery. But it is a way to get this work in front of people who would otherwise probably never see it. Love it or hate it, &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; commands a lot of attention — and it’s nice to see that being used to highlight something other than the latest blockbuster movie.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891305/fortnite-kaws-art-gallery"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891305/fortnite-kaws-art-gallery</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T14:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T14:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>GM announces plans to make mobile power generators using hydrogen fuel cells</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6_0II64Ot3jG_DKxEgZjV1O_w5w=/381x0:2715x1556/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70408877/EMPOWER_rapid_charger.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;GM’s EMPOWER rapid charger can help retail fuel stations add more affordable DC fast-charging capabilities  | GM&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KSLxE1"&gt;General Motors announced plans to manufacture mobile power generators using its Hydrotec-branded hydrogen fuel cells. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bQc1QD"&gt;The aim is to replace polluting gas- and diesel-powered generators with zero-emission hydrogen-powered ones. Hydrogen is the most abundant element in the universe, so its appeal to an industry that’s trying to pivot away from dirty internal combustion engines is obvious. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/4/13/15257576/hydrogen-fuel-cell-honda-clarity-self-driving-ny-auto-show-2017"&gt;Some automakers are developing hydrogen-powered cars&lt;/a&gt; as a possible alternative to EVs that use lithium-ion batteries. With today’s announcement, GM is staking out a position that looks beyond the car and power generation. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OZSbmeERvsN33xYeXetgVCk-g9s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23179673/GM_MPG.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GM&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;GM’s Mobile Power Generator can fast-charge EVs without having to expand the grid or install permanent charge points in places where there is only a temporary need for power&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ci946t"&gt;Hydrogen fuel cells — which use compressed hydrogen as their fuel and release only water vapor — have been in development for decades. GM has condensed its Hydrotec system into a “power cube” encompassing 300 individual hydrogen fuel cells. The cubes can then be deployed in a variety of applications, including mobile generators and temporary EV chargers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FTbnKG"&gt;The hydrogen-powered generators will only be sold to commercial and military customers to start out, but the automaker said it plans on offering versions for residential use in the future. GM said the ideal application would be at an outdoor concert venue, thanks to the hydrogen generator’s much lower noise profile as compared to gas-powered power sources. Another use case would involve temporary electric vehicle chargers installed at locations where demand for charging hasn’t yet resulted in a permanent charging station. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WXN9JMTI6XdoXo2i2w1YWOITcMI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23179678/Palletized_MPG.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GM&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;GM’s prototype palletized Mobile Power Generator converts offboard, bulk-stored hydrogen to electricity to quietly and efficiently power military camps and installations with no emissions in operation.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="EBQkhb"&gt;“Hydrotec power generators can quickly be deployed for disaster relief,” said Charlie Freese, executive director of GM’s Hydrotec division, in a call with reporters, “or it can provide backup for the electrical grid in areas that are experiencing rolling blackouts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u08u64"&gt;GM is planning on offering these generators in multiple sizes for a variety of uses. Each unit will put out power ranging from 60kW to 600kW, depending on size and use case. They also will use a different number of Hydrotec power cubes. The company’s Mobile Power Generator, for example, relies on one power cube, while the Empower rapid chargers will use eight cubes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RFzXuR"&gt;One of the biggest challenges, though, is the dearth of hydrogen charging and refueling infrastructure. Despite the technology having been in development for decades, there are only a little more than two dozen fueling stations in California, &lt;a href="http://cafcp.org/stationmap"&gt;mostly clustered&lt;/a&gt; around Los Angeles and the Bay Area. The East Coast is trying to get in on the action. A &lt;a href="http://chfcc.org/existing-and-planned-hydrogen-fueling-stations-northeast-us/"&gt;handful of stations&lt;/a&gt; are up and running, and more are in the works in New York, New Jersey, Massachusetts, Connecticut, and Rhode Island. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="d9iT9i"&gt;&lt;q&gt;One of the biggest challenges, though, is the dearth of hydrogen charging and refueling infrastructure&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gEncfQ"&gt;Hydrogen’s energy content by volume is low, which makes storing hydrogen a challenge because it requires high pressures, low temperatures, or chemical processes to be stored compactly. Overcoming this challenge is important for light-duty vehicles because they often have limited size and weight capacity for fuel storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aCnJef"&gt;However, Freese said he was confident that the infrastructure would improve as demand for hydrogen rises. “Hydrogen infrastructure is something that’s building out now,” he said. “There’s a lot of investment going on there.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yApDqr"&gt;In addition to producing hydrogen for mobile power generation, GM is also working on applying the technology to trucking, rail transportation, and even aerospace. The automaker is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22251582/gm-hydrogen-truck-navistar-oneh2-range-date"&gt;working with trucking firm Navistar and OneH2&lt;/a&gt;, a North Carolina-based hydrogen fuel cell company, to put more hydrogen-powered long-haul trucks on the road. It also has a deal with Liebherr-Aerospace to develop a hydrogen fuel cell power-generation demonstrator system for aircraft. And it’s working on fuel cell systems for Wabtec locomotives. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891368/gm-hydrotec-hydrogen-fuel-cell-mobile-power-generators"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891368/gm-hydrotec-hydrogen-fuel-cell-mobile-power-generators</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T13:10:48-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T13:10:48-05:00</updated>
    <title>Emirates, Air India, and others cancel flights due to AT&amp;T and Verizon’s 5G rollout</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Emirates Boeing 777 Cargo Plane Landing At Amsterdam" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eeFDieBmuMsA3jnPEEPij9jVees=/0x0:5000x3333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70405818/1237645376.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Nicolas Economou/NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gzsikH"&gt;On Tuesday, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.emirates.com%2Fus%2Fenglish%2Fhelp%2Ftravel-updates%2F%234842&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2022%2F1%2F18%2F22890080%2F5g-flight-cancel-att-verizon-c-band-emirates-air-india-ana-japan" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Emirates&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/airindiain/status/1483509249376329731"&gt;Air India&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ana.co.jp%2Ffs%2Fint%2Fen%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2022%2F1%2F18%2F22890080%2F5g-flight-cancel-att-verizon-c-band-emirates-air-india-ana-japan" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ANA&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.jal.co.jp%2Fjp%2Fen%2Finfo%2F2022%2Finter%2F20220118%2F%3Fm%3Dimportant_notice&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2022%2F1%2F18%2F22890080%2F5g-flight-cancel-att-verizon-c-band-emirates-air-india-ana-japan" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Japan Airlines&lt;/a&gt; all announced that they were canceling some flights to the US due to this week’s rollout of C-band 5G over concerns it could potentially interfere with some instruments, particularly on Boeing 777 aircraft. This comes as cell carriers, federal agencies, airlines, and airplane manufacturers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889664/att-5g-limits-c-band-expansion-airports-further-carrier-airline"&gt;struggle to reach an agreement&lt;/a&gt; on policies regarding how the rollout should be handled. The situation has continued to evolve as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891286/att-5g-rollout-select-metro-areas-faa-delay"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891284/verizon-c-band-5g-ultra-wideband-now-available"&gt;Verizon&lt;/a&gt; switch on their c-band, but it’s only gotten messier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xFj9dm"&gt;ANA cites specific guidance from Boeing, saying that “Boeing has announced flight restrictions on all airlines operating the Boeing 777 aircraft.” Japan Airlines also cites a notification from Boeing, saying that it was told that “5G signals for U.S. mobile phones, which will begin operating in the U.S. on January 19, 2022, may interfere with the radio wave altimeter installed on the Boeing 777.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zGaPah"&gt;However, Japan Airlines changed its guidance on Wednesday, saying it “received confirmation from the FAA (Federal Aviation Administration) that there is no longer a problem with the operation of the Boeing 777 and we will resume service to the U.S. mainland with Boeing 777 from January 20.” ANA has updated its advisory with similar language, saying that it’s returning to “the normal schedule based on FAA notification that there is no safety issue with the operation of Boeing 777 aircraft to the U.S. airports that we serve.” However, Emirates and Air India haven’t changed their guidance, and the FAA hasn’t publicly released an updated statement. The 777 isn’t currently on the regulator’s list of cleared aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="vRHiFa"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Emirates says it’s “working closely with aircraft manufacturers and the relevant authorities”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MlWmTF"&gt;Emirates’ announcement clearly outlines what’s being canceled. The airline, described as the world’s largest operator of the Boeing 777 &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/airlines-scramble-rejig-schedules-amid-us-5g-rollout-concerns-2022-01-18/"&gt;by &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, says that it’s “suspending flights to the following US destinations from 19 January 2022 until further notice,” listing Boston, Chicago, Dallas-Fort Worth, Houston, Miami, Newark, Orlando, San Francisco, and Seattle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="837OGu"&gt;The airline will continue to fly to New York JFK, Los Angeles (LAX), and Washington, DC (IAD). Emirates says it’s “working closely with aircraft manufacturers and the relevant authorities to alleviate operational concerns” and that it hopes to start flying to the US again as soon as it’s able.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SbuBmU"&gt;More airlines were affected as Tuesday progressed. &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/airlines-scramble-rejig-schedules-amid-us-5g-rollout-concerns-2022-01-18/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that Taiwan’s China Airlines will reschedule some flights, while South Korea’s Korean Air Lines switched away from Boeing’s 777 and 747-8 aircraft on six flights to the US, and Hong Kong’s Cathay Pacific says it’s prepared to use different planes if necessary. Lufthansa had canceled at least one US flight and was switching from the Boeing 747-8 to the 747-400 aircraft on some US routes. Air India, Singapore Airlines, and Austrian Airlines were also switching out 777 aircraft for US flights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uSGmYn"&gt;Airline operators in the US &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889141/us-airlines-united-american-delta-5g-c-band-disruption-radar-altimeter"&gt;warned earlier on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt; that the 5G rollout could cause “catastrophic disruption” to their flight schedules. &lt;a href="https://www.faa.gov/5g"&gt;According to the FAA&lt;/a&gt;, the concern is that the C-band 5G signals could interfere with the radar altimeters used in some planes, creating a safety issue. You can read &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22867221/att-verizon-5g-midband-spectrum-faa-air-safety-delay-cband"&gt;our full explainer on the whole situation here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="H1s6Mx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Why AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon are feuding with the US government over a last-minute delay to 5G","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22867221/att-verizon-5g-midband-spectrum-faa-air-safety-delay-cband"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="pBBjYr"&gt;Boeing didn’t respond immediately to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s request to confirm that it had sent out an advisory. Its competitor, Airbus, said that it will be working “as part of a wider industry coalition” to “study the issue further and work toward solutions.” For information on aircraft limitations, it referred to &lt;a href="https://www.faa.gov/newsroom/faa-statements-5g"&gt;the FAA’s statements on 5G page&lt;/a&gt;, where a statement from January 16th lists the airplane models that have been approved to land at some airports under low-visibility conditions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3837yY"&gt;On Tuesday morning, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889664/att-5g-limits-c-band-expansion-airports-further-carrier-airline"&gt;both AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon announced&lt;/a&gt; that they would voluntarily delay 5G antenna upgrades near certain airports. The chairwoman for the Federal Communications Commission issued a statement saying it’s “essential that the FAA now complete” the process of assessing altimeter performance and the effect C-band 5G communication can have on it with “both care and speed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cm6hVP"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, January 19th 1:10PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added information about Japan Airlines saying it’ll be allowed to fly 777s per the FAA.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h9vwZG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, January 19th, 5:27AM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added information on additional airlines that have been affected with emphasis on Boeing 777 aircraft.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22890080/5g-flight-cancel-att-verizon-c-band-emirates-air-india-ana-japan"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22890080/5g-flight-cancel-att-verizon-c-band-emirates-air-india-ana-japan</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T12:30:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T12:30:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>Is Microsoft building a gaming monopoly?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ECMUtIt4kpgAB9AFUdbaEXrL6Tc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70408428/acastro_210429_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7NzFjZ"&gt;Yesterday morning, Microsoft &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889258/microsoft-activision-blizzard-xbox-acquisition-call-of-duty-overwatch"&gt;announced plans to acquire&lt;/a&gt; Activision Blizzard, publisher of games ranging from the &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt; series to &lt;em&gt;Candy Crush Saga&lt;/em&gt;, for $68.7 billion. Microsoft says the move would make it the third-largest gaming company by revenue, following Tencent and Sony. The company, already a giant in the market, would gain even more leverage over how games are made and distributed. That’s assuming regulators approve it — something that’s not guaranteed amid a new push for scrutiny of potential tech monopolies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gQmt5C"&gt;After a damaging antitrust case in the 1990s, Microsoft has mostly escaped the more recent antitrust criticism directed at tech companies like Apple, Meta, and Amazon. But the company has been steadily building its power in the games world for the past few years. In 2021, it closed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/9/22319124/microsoft-bethesda-acquisition-complete-finalized"&gt;an acquisition of ZeniMax Media&lt;/a&gt;, giving it ownership of subsidiaries like &lt;em&gt;Fallout&lt;/em&gt; maker Bethesda Softworks for a total of 23 first-party game studios. Meanwhile, Microsoft has built its Xbox brand into a gaming service that spans both consoles and PCs. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22406059/xbox-game-pass-subscribers-25-million-microsoft-activision"&gt;The company recently revealed&lt;/a&gt; that its Xbox Game Pass subscription service had grown to 25 million subscribers after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/5/24/15684972/microsoft-xbox-game-pass-subscription-launch-date"&gt;launching in 2017&lt;/a&gt;. With the Activision Blizzard acquisition, it would integrate a massive game publisher into that system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Ob8dYn"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Microsoft has budgeted time for heavy scrutiny&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ov4d1c"&gt;That new market power could raise eyebrows at the US Justice Department and Federal Trade Commission, which will have to approve the merger. While neither agency has commented on the recent announcement, they’ve committed to more carefully examining tech industry consolidation — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889579/ftc-justice-department-lina-khan-kanter-google-facebook-amazon-antitrust"&gt;launching a joint process yesterday&lt;/a&gt; to start overhauling the approval process. Expecting resistance, Microsoft has budgeted an extended timeline for the process, planning for it to close by the fiscal year of 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0lJZ7Z"&gt;Microsoft acquiring Activision Blizzard fits the form of a vertical merger: where two companies that offer complementary services combine forces, like a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/22/17152518/att-time-warner-merger-trial-justice-department"&gt;major telecommunications company buying a media production company&lt;/a&gt;. In this case, it’s a major game studio joining a major game storefront and console company. (Since Microsoft already owns several first-party game studios, there’s also a level of horizontal merger, where directly competing companies combine.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7LOSYr"&gt;The new generation of antitrust activists has recently taken particular aim at vertical mergers. In September of last year, the FTC &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/ftc-moves-toward-stricter-antitrust-scrutiny-of-vertical-mergers-11631741589"&gt;withdrew Trump administration-era guidelines&lt;/a&gt; that agency chair Lina Khan said wrongly attributed helpful effects like increased efficiency to them — calling claims that they provided consumer benefits “misguided.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eUqgoy"&gt;A video game industry merger might not seem as immediately dangerous as something like a sprawling Amazon retail monopoly or a locked-up mobile app store. But Microsoft’s growing power in games could reduce its incentive to work fairly with third-party developers who rely on products like the Xbox and Game Pass to reach players. It could also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22890553/microsoft-activision-xbox-game-pass-competition-subscription"&gt;increase the dominance of Game Pass&lt;/a&gt; and its leverage to raise prices on subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZMwICJ"&gt;“It’s all about the Game Pass subscription model,” explains Matt Stoller of the American Economic Liberties Project. “Everyone who doesn’t own massive distribution is going to have an increasingly difficult time producing games and getting them distributed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sQm2uG"&gt;Stoller believes there’s a precedent for blocking Microsoft’s merger as anti-competitive. He cites &lt;em&gt;United States v. Paramount Pictures&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://constitutioncenter.org/blog/the-day-the-supreme-court-killed-hollywoods-studio-system"&gt;a landmark 1948 Supreme Court decision&lt;/a&gt; that took aim at Hollywood studios’ control over the distribution of movies &lt;em&gt;and &lt;/em&gt;the theaters where they were shown. The resulting consent decree barred studios from also owning theaters and imposed other restrictions like an end to “block booking,” which forced theaters to book slates of films in advance. (The decree was &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/business-news/judge-agrees-end-paramount-consent-decrees-1306387/"&gt;officially terminated in 2020&lt;/a&gt; after a judge determined it was “unlikely” the studios would wield the same monopoly power today.) The &lt;em&gt;Paramount&lt;/em&gt; decision “created an open market for creative content,” says Stoller — it’s credited with helping fuel the rise of television and freeing actors from restrictive contracts by reducing studios’ power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="veUfF9"&gt;Stoller sees Paramount-like consolidation today in games. “What you’re finding here is that it was an open market for gaming content, but it’s increasingly being closed off into walled gardens,” he says — although he acknowledges that companies like Nintendo have long maintained closed ecosystems. The recent rise of game streaming, a system where companies can exercise even more control over how content is distributed and played, could further consolidate the industry. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rOXmtr"&gt;“Game streaming giants will make it much harder for independent game producers to get into the market,” warns Stoller. And Microsoft is one of the biggest players in that space thanks to its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787396/xbox-cloud-gaming-consoles-series-x-s-one"&gt;cross-platform Xbox Cloud Gaming&lt;/a&gt; (formerly xCloud) service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Rd1INw"&gt;&lt;q&gt;One lawmaker has cited “encouraging” signs from Microsoft&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fbDheC"&gt;This doesn’t necessarily mean that regulators — or lawmakers who have expressed a broad interest in tightening the rules for mergers — will be hostile to Microsoft’s merger. The company’s acquisition of ZeniMax didn’t meet substantial resistance in either Europe or the US — although the latter was then still operating under Trump’s administration, which put less weight on antitrust. Rep. Ken Buck (R-CO), a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/6/22561157/ken-buck-antitrust-apple-amazon-facebook-google-cicilline-jim-jordan"&gt;prominent Republican supporter&lt;/a&gt; of antitrust reform, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RepKenBuck/status/1483564026919596032"&gt;tweeted yesterday&lt;/a&gt; that he’d received “encouraging” assurances from Microsoft that the deal wouldn’t decrease competition. “They’ve suggested that they’re going to emphasize access to titles and competition in the marketplace as well as the individual gaming experience,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RepKenBuck/status/1483564029293600776"&gt;Buck said&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rx3TY7"&gt;Buck’s comment hits on one of the key splits in recent antitrust debates: whether anti-monopoly efforts should focus narrowly on the direct effects on consumers or the market as a whole. As Khan has noted, combining two complementary services &lt;em&gt;doesn’t &lt;/em&gt;necessarily grant benefits to end users. But even if it does, it could have ripple effects that change the way games are made and played, putting more pressure on developers to play by Microsoft’s rules. And in an era of renewed suspicion of monopolies, that might raise more red flags than usual.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22889435/microsoft-activision-blizzard-game-pass-cloud-gaming-monopoly-ftc-questions"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22889435/microsoft-activision-blizzard-game-pass-cloud-gaming-monopoly-ftc-questions</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T12:25:17-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T12:25:17-05:00</updated>
    <title>Verizon’s faster C-band 5G is live and off to a promising start</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/klCou6FBnhd32v1B4r5jzh36x3U=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70408396/acastro_200109_1777_verizon_0004.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vXuyvi"&gt;Amid an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889664/att-5g-limits-c-band-expansion-airports-further-carrier-airline"&gt;ongoing tussle with the FAA&lt;/a&gt; and airline industry, Verizon today flipped the switch on its mid-band 5G deployment, which uses spectrum that the company spent tens of billions of dollars to acquire in the C-band auction. The new, faster level of 5G connectivity will significantly augment Verizon’s “5G Ultra Wideband” network, which, until now, has relied solely on extremely-fast-but-very-hard-to-find millimeter wave spectrum. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aZWFbT"&gt;Mid-band 5G overcomes many of the hurdles that have made mmW the brunt of jokes from competitors like T-Mobile: it’s actually available indoors, and coverage doesn’t vary as unpredictably from one street to the next. Customers with compatible phones should experience noticeably faster data speeds compared to Verizon’s “5G Nationwide” network that offers widespread signal but with download and upload performance that in many cases isn’t much better than LTE. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7KqM4F"&gt;In short, 5G is about to feel a lot more real for Verizon customers than it ever has before. Mid-band is a crucial element of Verizon’s long-term 5G ambitions and bridges the gap between the slow 5G Nationwide and barely existent, ultra-fast millimeter wave 5G.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SYFfnVodaBvNx-MyvG_yE1lnq38=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23179494/Screen_Shot_2022_01_19_at_10.56.22_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/verizon/comments/s7rmd2/cband_live_in_claremont_iphone_12_pro_max_and/" target="_blank"&gt;r/Verizon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;In many cases, C-band speeds are a substantial upgrade from Verizon’s slower “5G Nationwide” and a true leap over 4G LTE.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MpCLCi"&gt;Even on day one, the improvements are promising. Customers were quick to take to &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/verizon"&gt;the Verizon subreddit&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday to post a slew of Ookla Speedtest screenshots, with download rates regularly topping 500Mbps and even 800Mbps in some cases. Many are seeing an average downlink between 200 and 400Mbps, far exceeding the performance of 5G Nationwide. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="5dJeat"&gt;Which devices support Verizon’s new, faster C-band 5G?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ZiwHtD"&gt;At launch, the list of supported phones and tablets is fairly short. These are the devices that can already connect to Verizon’s C-band 5G:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="nyTl9H"&gt;Apple iPhone 13, iPhone 13 mini, iPhone 13 Pro, iPhone 13 Pro Max, iPhone 12, iPhone 12 mini, iPhone 12 Pro, iPhone 12 Pro Max&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="tgp345"&gt;Apple iPad Pro 12.9-inch (5th generation), iPad Pro 11-inch (3rd generation), or iPad mini (6th generation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dUkQZr"&gt;Google Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro &lt;em&gt;(coming soon)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="j7667Y"&gt;Samsung Galaxy S21, S21 Plus, S21 Ultra, Z Fold 3, Z Flip 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="lGwK67"&gt;Verizon has said that all phones it releases as of now will support C-band 5G, and the carrier expects to offer over 20 compatible phones by the end of 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="J0MtGT"&gt;Where can I get Verizon’s C-band 5G?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="eUWKR5"&gt;Verizon has said it will provide a C-band coverage map at launch, but so far, no such map is available on the carrier’s website — perhaps a consequence of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889664/att-5g-limits-c-band-expansion-airports-further-carrier-airline"&gt;eleventh-hour concessions to the FAA&lt;/a&gt;. You can expect just about every major metro market to have some degree of C-band coverage in January: the company has promised to reach “more than 100 million people in 1,700-plus cities around the nation” with the faster flavor of 5G this month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cv5XUO"&gt;But it’s a rolling process and won’t be instantly available everywhere. I’m located in downtown Brooklyn and am still riding on the slower 5G Nationwide network. On Wednesday afternoon, Verizon spokesperson Andrew Testa told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the initial rollout had been successfully completed, saying “today’s deployment is complete, but we’re continuing to expand so more and more people can experience 5G Ultra Wideband.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="uMjii0"&gt;How do I know if I’m on Verizon’s C-band 5G?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Q3cv4p"&gt;Verizon’s C-band 5G shares the same “5G Ultra Wideband” indicator in your phone’s status bar as millimeter wave 5G. That makes things a little confusing, but if you’re suddenly (and consistently) seeing “5G UW” appear in places where you never had it previously, that’s the best evidence that your device is taking advantage of the faster 5G.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Cb94xu"&gt;How fast is it really?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Cj8mhW"&gt;Based on many early tests, pretty fast — and on a different level altogether than 5G Nationwide. Upload speeds aren’t anything spectacular, but many Verizon customers on C-band are getting download rates that range &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/verizon/comments/s7pjbf/lake_county_il_north_of_chicago_is_live/"&gt;anywhere from 200&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/verizon/comments/s7p997/indiana_cband_result/"&gt;500Mbps&lt;/a&gt; and, in the very best cases, &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/verizon/comments/s7qe1h/cband_live_in_downtown_la/"&gt;over 800Mbps&lt;/a&gt;. And these are in regions where cellular data had previously often topped out around 60 or 80Mbps, so the upgrade is substantial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="y1txFg"&gt;
    &lt;blockquote class="reddit-card" data-card-created='"2022-01-19T16:01:56.193427+00:00"'&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/verizon/comments/s7os2i/cband_in_rochester_ny_is_live/?ref_source=embed&amp;amp;ref=share"&gt;C-Band in Rochester NY is live&lt;/a&gt; from
      &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/verizon/"&gt;verizon&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    &lt;script async="" src="https://embed.redditmedia.com/widgets/platform.js" charset="UTF-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="UTc47i"&gt;Do I need to change my plan to get C-band 5G on Verizon?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="HkNPVt"&gt;Not necessarily. According to Verizon, its Do More, Play More, and Get More Unlimited plans have access today, as well as the slightly tweaked and rebranded 5G Do More, 5G Play More, and 5G Get More plans that the carrier &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22867007/verizon-t-mobile-att-unlimited-plan-5g"&gt;announced in early January&lt;/a&gt;. Verizon’s previous Above and Beyond Unlimited plans also have 5G Ultra Wideband / C-band access. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EQO4A5"&gt;Verizon’s entry-level Start Unlimited plan does not include 5G Ultra Wideband whatsoever. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="0ztXEU"&gt;What about the whole airplane safety thing?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="YhstDY"&gt;Don’t expect to get C-band speeds at your local airport for some time. Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T have begrudgingly agreed to delay activating C-band 5G around many airports and are creating exclusion zones to address airplane-related safety concerns that continue to be raised by the FAA. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G05uF5"&gt;Both carriers have strongly criticized the FAA for being unprepared for this moment. “The Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) and our nation’s airlines have not been able to fully resolve navigating 5G around airports, despite it being safe and fully operational in more than 40 other countries,” Verizon said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8fESPh"&gt;If you’re a Verizon customer and are already using the faster mid-band 5G, feel free to share some of your impressions in the comments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="egfQPF"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 19th, 1:40PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Verizon has clarified to &lt;/em&gt;The Verge&lt;em&gt; that the Pixel 6 series is not yet fully certified for C-band access. Details around supported plans have also been updated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891284/verizon-c-band-5g-ultra-wideband-now-available"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891284/verizon-c-band-5g-ultra-wideband-now-available</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-19T12:18:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T12:18:26-05:00</updated>
    <title>AT&amp;T begins 5G C-band rollout in limited number of metro areas</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="5G Wireless Service To Launch In U.S. Despite Aviation Industry Concerns" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MM_JlKgcNCV4bS6JDyGdiFhbYIs=/53x0:2369x1544/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70408374/1365480215.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;AT&amp;amp;T is launching its expanded 5G service in eight metro areas. | Photo by Justin Sullivan / Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VvG9W7"&gt;&lt;a href="https://about.att.com/innovationblog/2022/connectivity.html"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T is lighting up its expanded 5G service&lt;/a&gt; in just eight metro areas in the US on Wednesday, including Austin, Dallas-Fort Worth, Houston, Chicago, Detroit, Jacksonville, Orlando, and South Florida (&lt;a href="https://about.att.com/ecms//dam/snrdocs/pdf/metro-areas-with-c-band.pdf"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;). This comes after both AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889664/att-5g-limits-c-band-expansion-airports-further-carrier-airline"&gt;voluntarily limited the activation of C-band spectrum around airports&lt;/a&gt; after facing mounting pressure from airlines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aRI818"&gt;“Today’s introduction begins in limited parts of 8 metro areas across the U.S. It will expand rapidly as our thoughtful and efficient deployment ramps up throughout the year,” Chris Sambar, AT&amp;amp;T’s executive vice president of technology operations, explains in the post announcing the expansion. “With 17 C-Band-capable devices already available online and in our stores, you can start seeing those speeds today.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="89AWZE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Meanwhile, Verizon plans on activating towers in 1,700 cities this month&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Ih1vQ0"&gt;Just one day before Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T’s scheduled 5G rollout on January 19th, major airlines &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889141/us-airlines-united-american-delta-5g-c-band-disruption-radar-altimeter"&gt;warned against activating 5G towers for fear of “catastrophic disruption”&lt;/a&gt; to flights operating across the country. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22890080/5g-flight-cancel-att-verizon-c-band-emirates-air-india-ana-japan"&gt;Air India, Emirates, Japan Airlines, and ANA&lt;/a&gt; canceled some of their flights in advance over concerns that the 5G expansion could &lt;a href="https://www.faa.gov/5g"&gt;interfere with radar altimeters&lt;/a&gt; that aircraft use to make low-visibility landings. Ahead of the rollout, the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) reached an agreement with both carriers to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/8/22873765/faa-verizon-att-airport-5g-carriers-buffer-zone"&gt;create 50 buffer zones where AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon will shut off transmitters for six months near airports&lt;/a&gt; with high traffic volume and frequent low-visibility conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wY1Hnk"&gt;In &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/18/22889664/att-5g-limits-c-band-expansion-airports-further-carrier-airline"&gt;a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, AT&amp;amp;T expressed frustration at the FAA’s failure to “utilize the two years they’ve had to responsibly plan for this deployment,” as well as its “inability to do what nearly 40 countries have done, which is to safely deploy 5G technology without disrupting aviation services.” AT&amp;amp;T and Verizon’s activation of the C-band spectrum has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22867221/att-verizon-5g-midband-spectrum-faa-air-safety-delay-cband"&gt;faced pushback by the FAA&lt;/a&gt;, resulting in two delays. And while AT&amp;amp;T is taking a more cautious approach to its rollout, &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.verizon.com/about/news/get-most-out-of-verizon-5g-ultra-wideband-network" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Verizon plans on activating its network in 1,700 cities&lt;/a&gt; — covering 100 million more people — this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="R7g4Dk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Verizon’s faster C-band 5G is live and off to a promising start","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891284/verizon-c-band-5g-ultra-wideband-now-available"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891286/att-5g-rollout-select-metro-areas-faa-delay"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/19/22891286/att-5g-rollout-select-metro-areas-faa-delay</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
