<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-05-06T17:37:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-06T17:37:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-06T17:37:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>IBM’s first 2nm chip previews the processors of tomorrow</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KAWsJFiAiOJWM17WxlZnSXDzkGY=/0x180:2700x1980/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69248769/IBM_Research_2_nm_Wafer.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;IBM&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EwTV4A"&gt;&lt;a href="https://newsroom.ibm.com/2021-05-06-IBM-Unveils-Worlds-First-2-Nanometer-Chip-Technology,-Opening-a-New-Frontier-for-Semiconductors#assets_all"&gt;IBM has revealed&lt;/a&gt; what it says are the world’s first 2nm process chips, giving a brief preview of the technology that might eventually power the smartphones, laptops, and gadgets of the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8PnCvr"&gt;The big jump here is in transistor count. Compared to today’s 7nm chips, the new IBM technology features dramatically more transistors, thanks to the more compact design. That means chips built using that process can potentially offer big gains in performance and battery life: IBM says its 2nm chips are “projected to achieve 45 percent higher performance, or 75 percent lower energy use, than today’s most advanced 7 nm node chips.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Wlm0ac"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’ll still be years before you can get one&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CM9iaI"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.anandtech.com/show/16656/ibm-creates-first-2nm-chip"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;AnandTech&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, IBM’s new 2nm chip features about 333 million transistors per square millimeter (MTr/mm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;). For comparison, TSMC’s most advanced chips, built using its 5nm process, feature about 173 million transistors per square millimeter (MTr/mm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;), while Samsung’s 5nm chips feature about 127 MTr/mm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UsFUva"&gt;While that all sounds great, it’s important to remember that IBM’s 2nm chip is largely just a proof of concept and that processors build on the 2nm node are still likely years away. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EOjriw"&gt;TSMC and Samsung, as mentioned before, produce 5nm chips right now. Intel is still &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/7/23/21336356/intel-7nm-chips-next-gen-delay-q2-2020-earnings-amd-10nm-tiger-lake-desktop-laptop-cpu"&gt;struggling to get its 7nm node&lt;/a&gt; out the door. And even TSMC doesn’t expect to get to 2nm for some time: it’s currently planning to start early production of its 4nm chip process by the end of the year, with mass production in 2022, &lt;a href="https://www.anandtech.com/show/16639/tsmc-update-2nm-in-development-3nm-4nm-on-track-for-2022"&gt;per &lt;em&gt;AnandTech&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Its 3nm node isn’t expected until the second half of 2022, with 2nm chips still in relatively early development. And all of that assumes that semiconductor companies don’t run into delays — just ask Intel, which has seen any number of manufacturing hiccups over the past decade or so. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GvMtHM"&gt;Still, it’s a tantalizing glimpse at the future of semiconductor technology, and even though it may take some time to achieve on a mass-production scale, IBM’s announcement shows that there’s still plenty to be excited about when it comes to new chips. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22422815/ibm-2nm-chip-processors-semiconductors-power-performance-technology"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22422815/ibm-2nm-chip-processors-semiconductors-power-performance-technology</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-06T17:36:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-06T17:36:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon delivery drivers were told to turn off safety apps to meet quotas</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An Amazon Prime delivery van is seen in Seattle. The..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vcLlN0OTR7GzqMd1Oe31NIjSwRM=/0x0:5000x3333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69248765/1232586538.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Toby Scott/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ml5kie"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/xgxx54/amazon-drivers-are-instructed-to-drive-recklessly-to-meet-delivery-quotas"&gt;According to a &lt;em&gt;Vice &lt;/em&gt;report&lt;/a&gt;, some Amazon delivery drivers are instructed by their employers to turn off Amazon’s safe driving monitoring app, so they can drive faster and get their deliveries done. The drivers don’t work for Amazon directly, but instead for companies known as Delivery Service Partners, and they report that their managers or dispatchers ask them to turn off Amazon’s Mentor app after leaving it running long enough to get a good score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SYvi5E"&gt;Mentor, the app made by a company called eDriving, gives delivery drivers a safe driving score based on variables like their braking, acceleration, speed, and distraction throughout the course of their 10-hour shift. Many drivers report that the score that the app gives them is factored into their bonuses (and the bonuses and incentives paid to the delivery companies contracted to Amazon).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="nRwWMo"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The app’s reviews have titles like “inaccurate and they don’t care”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Qqgqch"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt; reports that some of the delivery companies will have the drivers keep the app on for part of the day to try to trick Amazon and the Mentor app, with one company sending drivers messages like “everyone needs to be logged into Mentor for at least 2 hours no more no less.” A driver in Michigan said the company wanted the app turned off to improve delivery times. “They were harsh on drivers that weren’t going as fast as they wanted.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fwJHa3"&gt;An Amazon spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt; that the behavior is unacceptable and that it “does not adhere to the safety standards that [Amazon expects] of all Delivery Service Partners.” They also said that “more than 90% of all drivers are able to complete their deliveries before the scheduled time while following all safety procedures.” (Amazon didn’t immediately respond to a request for comment on how it collected and validated that statistic.) As &lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt; points out, it’s Amazon’s software that determines the delivery routes and Amazon that sets the productivity targets the drivers are incentivized to hit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zYCUZd"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Vice&lt;/em&gt;’s report, Mentor is also buggy when it’s on, with drivers reporting that it dings them for distracted driving when they haven’t touched the phone. The app’s reviews on the App Store have titles like “inaccurate and they don’t care,” “Frustration personified,” and “inaccurate data will cost us our jobs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="felU36"&gt;Delivery companies also reportedly ask employees not to report damage to vehicles to Amazon, instead electing to fix the vans themselves to avoid them being taken out of commission. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rDafVy"&gt;It’s unclear how Amazon’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/24/22347945/amazon-delivery-drivers-ai-surveillance-cameras-vans-consent-form"&gt;recent introduction of AI-powered monitoring cameras&lt;/a&gt; will change this dynamic between the Delivery Service Partners and their drivers. One could imagine that having a camera in the van would make it easy to determine if employees were turning off other monitoring devices. One could also imagine there are other ways to ensure safe and quick deliveries that don’t require an Orwellian work environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xkKPga"&gt;Amazon did not immediately respond to a request for comment on if it tracks which companies make these requests of drivers.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423560/amazon-delivery-drivers-unsafe-reckless-driving-monitoring-app"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423560/amazon-delivery-drivers-unsafe-reckless-driving-monitoring-app</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-06T16:53:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-06T16:53:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>The David After Dentist meme is now an NFT — and yes, this is real life</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NYllnBTe1b6vsmIGd4px1h2g1HE=/0x45:1331x932/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69248508/david_dentist.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;David After Dentist is now an NFT | &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=txqiwrbYGrs&amp;amp;ab_channel=booba1234" target="_blank"&gt;David Devore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="P5ZSWh"&gt;David DeVore was seven years old in 2008 when a trip to the dentist left him feeling “funny” afterward. His dad, David Sr., recorded his son’s post-anesthesia musings (“Is this real life?” “You have four eyes” “I feel funny”), and when he uploaded it to YouTube a few months later — intending to share it with friends and family — the video went viral within a few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GqvHPR"&gt;Now, 140 million views and 11 years later, David After Dentist is becoming the latest mid-2000s meme to go up for auction as an NFT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CydfH4"&gt;“It kind of feels like 2009 all over again,” the elder DeVore said in an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “NFTs are like the wild west right now, it’s like back when we went viral and social media was in its infancy.” &lt;a href="https://foundation.app/davidafterdentist"&gt;The auction for the David NFT&lt;/a&gt; goes live today, and DeVore said he expects it will conclude sometime on Friday afternoon. (It’s officially open for 24 hours but could be extended for late bids.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zp4x00"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 75%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/txqiwrbYGrs?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SELTRh"&gt;DeVore says while his family dealt with their share of trolls — some who questioned his parenting — the meme has been a positive thing for their family, helping pay for his kids’ tuition. He didn’t get into the latest amounts, but he &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/where-are-they-now-david-after-dentist-family-rolling-in-150000-2010-6"&gt;estimated in a 2010 interview&lt;/a&gt; that the family had made $150,000 in merchandise, licensing, and from YouTube revenue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0wugDn"&gt;Compared to other creators of that era like Disaster Girl and Nyan Cat, he said he felt lucky he was able to retain some control of the meme. “They had less control, if any at all,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5W3gRl"&gt;But those creators are seeing things come full circle now as well. Disaster Girl, whose real name is Zoe Roth, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22410070/disaster-girl-popular-meme-nft-500000-dollars"&gt;went for $500,000&lt;/a&gt;, and Nyan Cat’s creator Chris Torres sold &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/22/business/nft-nba-top-shot-crypto.html"&gt;it for nearly $600,000&lt;/a&gt;. A ton of classic memes from back in the day have been auctioned as NFTs, including &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/bad-luck-brian-meme-nft-crypto-art-blockchain-ethereum-foundation-2021-3"&gt;Bad Luck Brian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://foundation.app/grumpycat/grumpy-cat-5467"&gt;Grumpy Cat&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://foundation.app/keyboardcat/play-him-off-keyboard-cat-5553"&gt;Keyboard Cat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="L4sDdH"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"NFTs, explained","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22310188/nft-explainer-what-is-blockchain-crypto-art-faq"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="6iZwQe"&gt;David Jr. is 20 now and attending the University of Florida where he’s studying computer science (not dentistry, to this writer’s disappointment), and he has perfect teeth, his dad says. The response to the NFT has been mostly positive, DeVore Sr. added, in part because the creator economy has become more sophisticated since David After Dentist debuted more than a decade ago. “I think it plays into the strong empathy people have for creators,” he said. “People want to see them get rewarded.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yYRJHr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22422993/david-after-dentist-meme-nft-real-life"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22422993/david-after-dentist-meme-nft-real-life</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-06T16:48:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-06T16:48:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple made it harder to change Hulu subscriptions because of a tweet</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/U4i8GJHW4HFmmiW5RW2Fn9Hz8nY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69248464/acastro_170731_1777_0004_v2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Nf4Oba"&gt;Apple made it more difficult to upgrade your Hulu subscription plan — say, to add live TV — after it realized the company was offering a way to automatically cancel subscriptions made through the App Store. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HcwEra"&gt;According to new emails revealed as part of Apple’s lawsuit with Epic Games, the company had given Hulu access to its subscription API but didn’t realize Hulu was using it to help people switch to Hulu’s billing system (and avoid Apple’s in-app purchases) until 2018 when the feature was mentioned in a tweet that caught the eye of a higher-up at Apple. You can see the tweet embedded below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TARhnQ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I didn’t realize App Store subscriptions could be automatically cancelled through the StoreKit API. I’m surprised I haven’t seen more offers to switch billing away from the App Store. &lt;a href="https://t.co/DcXzM2CCrq"&gt;pic.twitter.com/DcXzM2CCrq&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— David Barnard (@drbarnard) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/drbarnard/status/1045733512140247042?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 28, 2018&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SjpnxD"&gt;Hulu’s motivation for providing automatic cancellations should be clear. Why let Apple take a slice of every subscription and upgrade when you can keep more of it by directing a subscriber to your site and billing system? And why not make it even easier to do so by automatically canceling that pesky old subscription?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zN9zqC28zg-hReGS855VyGS27xc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22496811/Screen_Shot_2021_05_06_at_12.02.13_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Matt Fischer’s email to Cindy Lin about a certain Phil noticing the Hulu tweet.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Ak0ojZ"&gt;Apple has a problem with that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NYcAWb"&gt;The first email in the thread from Matt Fischer, VP of the App Store, to Cindy Lin, EPM of iTunes, sets the scene. Phil saw &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/drbarnard/status/1045733512140247042"&gt;David Barnard’s tweet&lt;/a&gt; commenting on the unexpected feature and asked why Hulu would even be able to automatically cancel subscriptions in the first place. That Phil is likely Phil Schiller, the Apple fellow overseeing the App Store and someone both Fischer and Lin would want to have answers and results for quickly. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hGH4HtMMVE9OOR2qOEgnHxRiiVA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22496819/Screen_Shot_2021_05_06_at_12.09.55_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cindy Lin’s explanation of how Hulu may have been able to automatically cancel subscriptions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="67BniL"&gt;In the thread, Lin went on to explain that back in 2015, Hulu had access to the subscription cancellation and refund APIs that may have allowed it to enable the feature. Apple originally gave the streaming service access so it could support instant upgrades to a “[two] family set up” before Apple had developed its own upgrade and downgrade feature for in-app purchases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v4QH8F"&gt;Pete Distad, an executive in charge of Apple’s video business, and Carson Oliver, director of App Store Business Management, were aware of some issue with Hulu’s subscriptions. Interestingly, Distad was an SVP of marketing and communications at Hulu before he joined Apple. That relationship may not have helped, though. Oliver ends his email by writing, “I think we need to take immediate steps to protect against further misuse of the API.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vgqK0z"&gt;Hulu no longer has the ability to automatically cancel subscriptions and no longer offers in-app purchases. Upgrading your plan requires a trip to Hulu’s website or a phone call. Apple’s developer guidelines also now expressly forbid directing customers to subscribe in any way other than through in-app purchases.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OOxsqblhjqo9rLQ3TxcO55ILFRc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22496850/Screen_Shot_2021_05_06_at_12.32.21_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s developer policy for offering subscriptions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="WamfUi"&gt;It’s sort of funny that Apple seems to have found out about what Hulu was doing through a tweet, but also, here’s yet another example of how Apple’s hold over the App Store has tightened over the years, and how its relationship has changed with some of the biggest businesses selling their wares on its store. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xeJYw9"&gt;In 2015, Apple was willing to take &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/4/13/8406229/apple-tv-15-percent-streaming-services"&gt;a smaller cut of its commission&lt;/a&gt; on Netflix and Hulu subscriptions if they were made through an Apple TV. But by 2018, it was considering taking action against the company to protect its control of in-app purchases. Some employees at Apple also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421734/apple-epic-netflix-in-app-purchase-removal-emails"&gt;apparently considered other drastic measures&lt;/a&gt; to keep Netflix in line when it was kicking up dust about in-app purchases in that same year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ej4NJQ"&gt;Apple likely wants to keep video services using in-app purchases just as badly as the video services want to stop. Sometimes, they cut a deal — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/3/21206400/apple-tax-amazon-tv-prime-30-percent-developers"&gt;like the one Amazon received&lt;/a&gt;. Other times they use the available tools to their advantage... at least until Apple checks its Twitter feed.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423410/apple-hulu-subscription-in-app-purchase-tweet"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423410/apple-hulu-subscription-in-app-purchase-tweet</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-06T16:31:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-06T16:31:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter is testing a new Tip Jar feature for sending money to your favorite accounts</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ajljYICFX84AjiO6tkC0zcvnAvA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69248373/acastro_170726_1777_0010.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="j1g4b2"&gt;Twitter has started &lt;a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/product/2021/introducing-tip-jar.html"&gt;rolling out a new Tip Jar feature&lt;/a&gt; on its Android and iOS apps, which (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/23/22399984/twitter-tip-button-jar-great-tweets-profiles"&gt;as rumored&lt;/a&gt;) will allow users to send money directly to their favorite accounts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6WVUWS"&gt;To use the tip jar, simply tap on the freshly added dollar bill icon next to someone’s username when viewing their profile on one of Twitter’s mobile apps. Users will be able to toggle the tip jar feature, too (for those individuals or organizations that don’t want people just sending them cash out of the blue). Android users will also be able to send money in Twitter’s Clubhouse-like Spaces. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3uWH8v"&gt;Tip Jar supports a variety of payment options and links: Bandcamp, Cash App, Patreon, Paypal, and Venmo. Twitter is using those services’ external payment processors for transactions; it doesn’t take a cut. All English language Twitter users can send tips starting today, but only a select group (including “creators, journalists, experts, and nonprofits”) can turn on the feature to accept money for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3xme8z"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;show your love, leave a tip &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;now testing Tip Jar, a new way to give and receive money on Twitter   &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;more coming soon... &lt;a href="https://t.co/7vyCzlRIFc"&gt;pic.twitter.com/7vyCzlRIFc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Twitter (@Twitter) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Twitter/status/1390396166496522247?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 6, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cY25Va"&gt;Users have been using Twitter to solicit tips or Patreon follows for years — ending viral threads with a shoutout to a SoundCloud account is practically a meme at this point. So it makes sense that Twitter would be looking to streamline the feature as part of its own app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aMinK6"&gt;Notably, the only way to access Tip Jar right now is through navigating to a user’s profile. That means sending someone some money for a truly fantastic tweet will still take a bit more effort than, say, just liking or retweeting it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="13beBE"&gt;There are already some issues that Twitter will have to work out. As spotted by Rachel Tobac, sending tips through Paypal using Tip Jar currently allows whoever is sending the money to see the recipient’s address, which is a worrying security issue that Twitter and Paypal will hopefully resolve soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="p02t7P"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Huge heads up on PayPal Twitter Tip Jar. If you send a person a tip using PayPal, when the receiver opens up the receipt from the tip you sent, they get your *address*. Just tested to confirm by tipping &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/yashar?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@yashar&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter w/ PayPal and he did in fact get my address I tipped him. &lt;a href="https://t.co/R4NvaXRdlZ"&gt;https://t.co/R4NvaXRdlZ&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/r8UyJpNCxu"&gt;pic.twitter.com/r8UyJpNCxu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Rachel Tobac (@RachelTobac) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RachelTobac/status/1390409874006183936?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 6, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3gRtp1"&gt;The announcement tweet from Twitter also promises “more coming soon,” so it’s likely that we’ll continue to hear more about how Twitter is implementing tipping in the coming weeks and months. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aetg0L"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update May 6th, 5:30pm: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added information on Paypal address security issues using Tip Jar. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423583/twitter-tip-jar-feature-sending-money-venmo-cashapp"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423583/twitter-tip-jar-feature-sending-money-venmo-cashapp</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-06T16:12:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-06T16:12:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>The best free apps for video calling</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Italy Continues Nationwide Lockdown To Control Coronavirus Spread" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sBOloN_0dkwsgGMSI0vJ1f76A3Y=/0x1111:2667x2889/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66922524/1214094439.jpg.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Stefano Guidi/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Jz5xAw"&gt;Things may be starting to open up, but for now, the COVID-19 pandemic continues to limit face-to-face association and most of us are still relying on video calls to keep in touch with work colleagues, family, and friends. And for most of us — especially those who are facing financial difficulties — free is best. Zoom continues to top the list of videoconferencing apps, but there are a bunch of applications out there that will allow you to meet others online for free. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZBifoi"&gt;We’ve listed a few of the best known videoconferencing apps, along with a couple of popular text chat apps that include video calling features. While most of these already have free versions, some are offering access to additional features for those who are currently working from home or who want to check up on friends and relatives online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bCcs6d"&gt;There are a number of apps we have not included, such as Facebook, WhatsApp, and FaceTime, that allow you to do video chats. We’ve left them out because they require that all participants be members of a specific social network (Facebook, WhatsApp) or that you use a specific type of device (FaceTime, which is Apple-only). We’ve also tried to concentrate on applications that allow you to participate without having to download the app (unless you’re the host), and that allow at least ten or more participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F8yIwt"&gt;A good idea is to try one or two out for yourself to see how well they fit in with your style and those of your friends. This list is a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="6libON"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fzoom.us%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21286781%2Fbest-video-call-apps-free" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Zoom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="LQuFKh"&gt;The most popular video meeting app&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Zoom is one of the most widely used video meeting apps." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/t5zsGsMM_zzRUfccXF_2EdkoflI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22491368/Screen_Shot_2021_05_04_at_1.20.14_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zoom is one of the most widely used video meeting apps.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CYiJpA"&gt;Zoom has become one of the most well-known videoconferencing apps — in fact, its name is quickly becoming synonymous with video meetings. Before the pandemic hit, the company pushed Zoom mostly for corporate use, but it also provides a free basic version for individuals. At first, because Zoom didn’t expect its sudden popularity among non-business users, there were several missteps involving privacy and security; the company quickly instituted &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/22/21230962/zoom-update-security-privacy-features-improvements-download"&gt;a number of changes and updates&lt;/a&gt; to address these issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="66nndg"&gt;The free version of Zoom allows up to 100 users to meet, but there is a 40-minute limit on meetings of more than two people, which can be pretty limiting. As of this writing, Zoom was not offering any special deals for those now working at home, but it does have a page &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fzoom.us%2Fdocs%2Fen-us%2Fcovid19.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21286781%2Fbest-video-call-apps-free" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;offering help and advice&lt;/a&gt; to new users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="BYNFVw"&gt;Free version features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="RHNl6l"&gt;Maximum participants: 100&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="b91yn2"&gt;One-on-one meetings:  No time limit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JIlwSK"&gt;Group meetings: 40-minute limit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="XpI4G1"&gt;Screen sharing: Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kF9xF4"&gt;Record meetings: Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="81FqBb"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.skype.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21286781%2Fbest-video-call-apps-free" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Skype&lt;/a&gt; Meet Now&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id="StW6sf"&gt;A longtime go-to for online calls&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Skype’s Meet Now feature supports up to 50 people with a four-hour time limit. " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DjOAVSTCxLE9SAzc8jmS5cISMQQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22489407/Screen_Shot_2021_05_03_at_2.42.55_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Skype’s Meet Now feature supports up to 50 people with a four-hour time limit. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="WfOsT4"&gt;Skype has been the go-to platform for one-on-one conversations since the beta was released in 2003. Its Meet Now feature (which is accessed by choosing the “Meet Now” button on the left side of the app) allows for videoconferencing; up to 50 people can meet with a generous four-hour time limit on meetings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JB02lU"&gt;There is also a separate page that lets you &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.skype.com%2Fen%2Ffree-conference-call%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21286781%2Fbest-video-call-apps-free" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;create a free video meeting&lt;/a&gt; without having to actually sign up for the service. However, you get more features using the app, so if you’re okay with registering for a free account, you’re better off doing that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="FQrF4L"&gt;Free version features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="lgPZGp"&gt;Maximum participants: 50&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PS5plA"&gt;One-on-one meetings:  No time limit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3x7cKx"&gt;Group meetings: Four hours per call, 10 hours per day, 100 hours per month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="oFvVzA"&gt;Screen sharing: Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="sDu0pA"&gt;Record meetings: Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="5SlZUs"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.webex.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21286781%2Fbest-video-call-apps-free" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Cisco Webex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="4k2CRu"&gt;A corporate app with a solid freemium version&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Webex, a videoconferencing app that has been around since the ‘90s, has a useful free version." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ah3jKqqaHJRvvLdrj0b-aTaTz0U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22489405/Screen_Shot_2021_05_03_at_2.49.49_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Webex, a videoconferencing app that has been around since the ‘90s, has a useful free version.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XcIFOJ"&gt;Webex is a videoconferencing app that has been around since the ‘90s; it was acquired by Cisco in 2007. While it’s been mainly known as a business application and continues to focus on serving companies, it does have a &lt;a href="https://cart.webex.com/sign-up-webex?experienceType=Unified&amp;amp;ft=selfsignup"&gt;fairly generous free version&lt;/a&gt; that’s worth checking out. During the current pandemic, it has widened the features of the freemium version from 50 to 100 participants, and you can meet for up to 50 minutes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="iVgdLr"&gt;Free version features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="B6FO7y"&gt;Maximum participants: 100&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZhF2Xh"&gt;One-on-one meetings:  50-minute limit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="gTTnlh"&gt;Group meetings:  50-minute limit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ruv0bm"&gt;Screen sharing: Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3aAMO5"&gt;Record meetings: Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="7pIZFI"&gt;&lt;a href="https://meet.google.com/"&gt;Google Meet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="5QusdH"&gt;Now featured on your Gmail page&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/A7O1n6NkE0ge6ERXOwjV7S5TmVE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22489403/Screen_Shot_2021_05_03_at_2.52.53_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="msl2WU"&gt;Meet offers a very simple and efficient way to video chat with colleagues, friends, and family — assuming they all have Google accounts, which is a requirement for both hosts and participants. In fact, Google is not only pushing people to use &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/4/21265533/google-meet-gmail-hide-video-call-email-shortcut"&gt;its Meet videoconferencing app&lt;/a&gt; instead of Zoom but also instead of its own soon-to-be-sundowned Google Hangouts app. (We previously included Google Hangouts in this roundup, but Hangouts users are now being actively urged from within the app to use Google Meet for their video chats.) You can find a Meet link in the Gmail app and in every appointment you make using Google Calendar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="v1Sc5Q"&gt;Free version features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="ndFlQU"&gt;Maximum participants: 100&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9l2AqB"&gt;One-on-one meetings: 24-hour limit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="4Vykzc"&gt;Group meetings: 24-hour limit through June 28th, one-hour limit after&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="a6cOEo"&gt;Screen sharing: Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JUU1Sr"&gt;Record meetings: No&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="h4bFcC"&gt;&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fmicrosoft-365%2Fmicrosoft-teams%2Fteams-for-home" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft Teams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="0gleS7"&gt;Not just for business&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e6cKl0CUoE2ruyM1Bb3kGununBU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22489400/Screen_Shot_2021_05_03_at_2.58.33_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="celGBu"&gt;Microsoft Teams was built as a competitor to Slack and is an especially good idea if you’re part of the Office ecosystem. While the application is mainly focused on business use, Microsoft has stepped out of its three-piece suit and unveiled &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21349783/microsoft-teams-texting-calls-videoconferencing-how-to"&gt;a free personal version of Teams&lt;/a&gt;, which lets anyone chat, talk, or have video meetings — you just have to create an account with Microsoft in order to use it. Currently, due to the pandemic, Microsoft has extended the maximum number of participants from 100 to 300, and it has pushed the time limit from 60 minutes to 24 hours, which gives it an edge over most other free videoconferencing apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="z7fDpG"&gt;Free version features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="VPM1Xz"&gt;Maximum participants: Normally 100; extended to 300 during pandemic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3OY8iA"&gt;One-on-one meetings: Normally 60-minute limit; extended to 24 hours during pandemic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="MaDoxu"&gt;Group meetings: Normally 60-minute limit; extended to 24 hours during pandemic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="OU4H3U"&gt;Screen sharing: Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lqJ1wZ"&gt;Record meetings: No&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ZdqxTy"&gt;&lt;a href="https://duo.google.com/about/"&gt;Google Duo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="kdg4C0"&gt;A mobile app best suited to one-to-ones&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ycUHduEC2TCTGPyGnIbxdxIf4Ew=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22489396/Screen_Shot_2021_05_03_at_3.01.40_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="S0KN9x"&gt;You don’t really expect Google to only offer one simple videoconferencing app, do you? Besides Google Meet, Google also has its mobile app Duo, which was built as a consumer app (whereas Meet was originally designed as a business app). While Duo was first touted as the app to use for one-to-one conversations and could only be used on phones, it now allows you to create groups of up to 32 participants and includes a web app. All participants must have Google accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="hrdSff"&gt;Free version features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="aqu3zn"&gt;Maximum participants: 32&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="k4gNud"&gt;One-on-one meetings: No time limit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Rd9Yef"&gt;Group meetings: No time limit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3Tah4o"&gt;Screen sharing: Mobile only&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="bdHECg"&gt;Record meetings: No&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="dSGznj"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.starleaf.com/resources/remote-working-hub/"&gt;StarLeaf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="05W8yJ"&gt;A corporate meeting app with a free basic version&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_xVXExpwfdFlYEda9IYnq6kfTQM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22489394/Screen_Shot_2021_05_03_at_3.08.31_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XSzst4"&gt;If you’re not a company, you may not have heard of StarLeaf. It’s really a platform for companies rather than individuals; its lowest-cost paid plan starts with five licenses suitable for a small business. But it is now offering a basic video and messaging product free of charge for those trying to keep in touch during the pandemic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="PWyY2P"&gt;Free version features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="W5dlgk"&gt;Maximum participants: 20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0hGcJD"&gt;One-on-one meetings: No time limit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Gtv4JL"&gt;Group meetings: 45-minute time limit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uPfKjn"&gt;Screen sharing: Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="gxuvie"&gt;Record meetings: No&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="TzLjf1"&gt;&lt;a href="https://meet.jit.si/"&gt;Jitsi Meet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="4Zxxcw"&gt;Open source with plenty of features&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3MVwxTZMGAegmePx6edtBU9gdi0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22489390/Screen_Shot_2021_05_03_at_3.11.38_PM__1_.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="YYifcw"&gt;Another “you probably haven’t heard of it” videoconference app, Jitsi Meet is an open-source platform that lets you easily meet online by simply navigating to the site and clicking on “Start meeting.” If you’re a developer, you can build your own conferencing app via &lt;a href="https://jitsi.org/jitsi-videobridge/"&gt;Jitsi Videobridge&lt;/a&gt;, but most people will be happy with the quick web version, which offers many features found in more well-known apps, such as fake backgrounds, chat, session recording (to Dropbox), and the ability to “kick out” unruly participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="VhdHjO"&gt;Free version features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="JlbkKB"&gt;Maximum participants: 100&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="bN9uN0"&gt;One-on-one meetings: No time limit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3n0cX0"&gt;Group meetings: No time limit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="GpB4PM"&gt;Screen sharing: Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wCwVWj"&gt;Record meetings: Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="GEZRsM"&gt;&lt;a href="https://whereby.com/"&gt;Whereby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="0tRyD7"&gt;Single meeting rooms with up to 50 participants&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/47xmn6lLGej9EWf2brZ_EXrP7f0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22489313/Screen_Shot_2021_05_03_at_3.13.49_PM__1_.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Yb3ZHs"&gt;Whereby’s free version gives you the use of a single meeting room with up to 50 participants, along with the ability to lock rooms (participants have to “knock” to gain entrance). Each room has its own URL that you get to choose, which is great — assuming that nobody else has already taken that name. (For example, I first tried &lt;a href="http://whereby.com/testroom"&gt;whereby.com/testroom&lt;/a&gt; and found it was already taken.) But it also has a chat function, lets you share a screen, allows you to mute or eject users, and offers breakout groups. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="NQQ6g6"&gt;Free version features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="kgniVF"&gt;Maximum participants: 50	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rbf1TD"&gt;One-on-one meetings: No time limit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="bJgo7v"&gt;Group meetings: 45-minute limit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="MknVjh"&gt;Screen sharing: Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EXQvVY"&gt;Record meetings: No&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bZ2xUb"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.glip.com/"&gt;Glip Pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="YTpiKZ"&gt;A wide range of free features&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VsGToiLppKzDnrooRK78tgpe8E8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22489298/Screen_Shot_2021_05_03_at_3.18.20_PM__1_.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="AYVdrv"&gt;Glip Pro offers a nice range of features for a free video meeting app. It does insist that you have either a work email address or a Google account, and wants access to your contacts on that account. But if you’re good with that, you get 24 hours of meeting time (as long as you sign up by July), screen sharing, recording, chat, and virtual backgrounds, among others. It even offers closed captions (although, as with a lot of AI transcription software, some of the captions leave something to be desired).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="d0yA3C"&gt;Free version features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="u3cQbc"&gt;Maximum participants: 100 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Mm37EN"&gt;One-on-one meetings: 24-hour limit (for signups by July 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hVRYgE"&gt;Group meetings: 24-hour limit (for signups by July 2021)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="OxL6TK"&gt;Screen sharing: Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="PWP4sP"&gt;Record meetings: Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ZLto1d"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.spikenow.com/blog/team-collaboration/spike-a-free-video-conferencing-solution-for-everyone/"&gt;Spike&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="FU8i90"&gt;A simple web-based system&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Spike can be used without having to download anything." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e8slY15BZb4EfX-9Tc_mSoiiyuY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22496903/Screen_Shot_2021_05_06_at_3.49.27_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spike can be used without having to download anything.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="C5n46v"&gt;Spike, an expanding email service, offers videoconferencing to its subscribers, but it has also made a basic video meeting web app available to anyone who wants it. It’s quick and easy to use: just go to &lt;a href="https://video.spike.chat/"&gt;video.spike.chat&lt;/a&gt;, type in a name, and click on “Join Video Chat Meeting.” Spike generates a unique URL for the chat and even lets you share your screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="zCfIFs"&gt;Free version features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="3KJGq9"&gt;Maximum participants: 200 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Jw8spn"&gt;One-on-one meetings: No time limit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vZrJNH"&gt;Group meetings: No time limit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xHQSKV"&gt;Screen sharing: Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NNElO2"&gt;Record meetings: No&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="cL6ktK"&gt;More alternatives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="oQsh6Y"&gt;There is a wide range of other Zoom alternatives out there, including &lt;a href="https://www.remotehq.com/"&gt;RemoteHQ&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://talky.io/"&gt;Talky&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.8x8.com/"&gt;8x8&lt;/a&gt; (which acquired Jitsi in 2018). Some of these don’t have a free version or the number of participants who can use the free version is limited. For example, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bluejeans.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21286781%2Fbest-video-call-apps-free" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;BlueJeans&lt;/a&gt; starts at $9.99 per month for unlimited-time meetings with up to 100 participants, while the free version of &lt;a href="https://www.zoho.com/meeting/"&gt;Zoho Meeting&lt;/a&gt; only permits a maximum of three participants, and &lt;a href="https://www.intermedia.com/anymeeting-video-conferencing"&gt;Intermedia AnyMeeting&lt;/a&gt; allows four.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3nhBhm"&gt;Other apps offer some video meeting as an added feature. &lt;a href="https://slack.com/"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; is mainly set up for text chat, but it does give you the ability to make voice and video calls as well. If you’re on the free version of Slack, you can make a video call to an individual. But if you want to host a meeting between several people, as opposed to a one-on-one conversation, and want to do it for free, you’ll need to look for an alternative. The messaging app &lt;a href="https://signal.org/en/"&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt; offers group video calls with a maximum of eight participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QqAFyA"&gt;There are also apps like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/29/21229590/houseparty-how-to-video-chat-call-games-talk-friends-app-ios-android"&gt;Houseparty&lt;/a&gt;, which lets up to eight people use a virtual room to chat. In fact, anybody can drop into a friend’s online session without an invitation (although you can “lock” your room to prevent intruders). However, it does demand that all participants register in order to use it — and registration includes your name, email address, birthdate, and phone number. So we didn’t include it among our recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d0ADE9"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update May 4th, 2021, 2:40PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published on June 11th, 2020. Since then, all entries have been updated; in addition, two apps have been dropped (Hangouts and Spike) and Glip Pro has been added.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3fBE0Q"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update May 5th, 2021, 9:15AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated to reflect the fact that Whereby’s breakout groups feature is out of beta and to add Signal to the list of alternatives.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hd3p07"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update May 6th, 2021 4PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to add Spike back to the main list.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21286781/best-video-call-apps-free"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21286781/best-video-call-apps-free</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-06T15:50:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-06T15:50:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>Xbox games wouldn’t open for some in Europe for two hours</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/G4y0Sha7oFaNoZ-9xOtmS4PgL68=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69247454/acastro_180604_1777_xbox_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TOS0d2"&gt;Xbox games were refusing to open or launch for many across Europe today, with an error message being presented instead. “The person who bought this needs to sign in,” said the error. The issues started at around 1PM ET, and Microsoft posted the “All Clear” &lt;a href="https://support.xbox.com/en-GB/xbox-live-status"&gt;on its status page&lt;/a&gt; at 3:30PM ET.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QAwU6V"&gt;The problems appear to have been related to the Microsoft Store, which was also preventing some Xbox owners from purchasing games. The problems persisted for around two hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5baqwm"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;You should now be able to browse the Xbox Store on all platforms &amp;amp; any previously purchased games or apps should launch as expected. Thank you for the reports, we'll be here &amp;amp; listening.&lt;/p&gt;— Xbox Support (@XboxSupport) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/XboxSupport/status/1390374426764472320?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 6, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="blyZof"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;if you're having problems launching Xbox games in Europe right now, you're not alone &lt;a href="https://t.co/uFswmohMnT"&gt;pic.twitter.com/uFswmohMnT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Tom Warren (@tomwarren) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/1390360674224721922?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 6, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MinMOv"&gt;The rest of the Xbox Live, or Xbox network, service appeared to be functioning, with Party Chat, LFG, and other parts of Xbox still accessible while games were not. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/1/22362975/microsoft-teams-xbox-live-down-outage-issue"&gt;Xbox Live last went down last month&lt;/a&gt;, alongside an issue with Microsoft Teams. Microsoft blamed the previous issues on DNS problems, but Thursday’s error message suggested there was an authentication problem somewhere preventing some Xbox owners from accessing their digital games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YWuTBR"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update May 6th, 3:55PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to reflect that the service appears to be back up.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423339/xbox-live-down-games-not-opening-launching-error"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423339/xbox-live-down-games-not-opening-launching-error</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-06T15:42:42-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-06T15:42:42-04:00</updated>
    <title>The PS5 and Xbox Series X are available at Walmart again (Update: Sold Out)</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qJzvYoRXZGe0lnsA7LmCiK9WIb4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69248065/vpavic_4261_20201026_0181.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SB1zrc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Walmart’s restock of the PS5 and Xbox Series X seems to be over. If you’re looking for some accessories to go with a console, we have some picks below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aT866w"&gt; Due to the global electronic component shortage, getting your hands on a PS5 or Xbox Series X has been challenging. Fortunately, if you want another shot at getting either next-gen console, Walmart has done a surprise drop right now for both systems, while supplies last. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="czJSzo"&gt;As seen on Walmart’s website, the &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-PlayStation-5-Video-Game-Console%2F363472942&amp;amp;subid1=NextGenRestocks4152021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;PS5&lt;/a&gt; digital edition and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FXbox-Series-X%2F443574645&amp;amp;subid1=NextGenRestocks4152021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xbox Series X&lt;/a&gt; gaming consoles are available for purchase. We’re noticing that stock is coming in and out, so stick with the page for a few minutes and keep refreshing to see if you can add one to your cart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3IQHBv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10226833"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dtb19x"&gt;Once you get your PS5, if you are looking to buy some games, some of the hottest titles such as &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Returnal-PlayStation-5/dp/B08QFPS48J/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Returnal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Marvels-Spider-Man-Miles-Morales-Launch-PlayStation/dp/B08FC66ZV4?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: Miles Morales&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are available on the console. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08TYCWK3C/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Resident Evil Village&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is releasing tomorrow, May 7th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gzfCm6"&gt;If you are worried about not having a ton of storage available to store all of your games, the latest PS5 update allows you to store PS5 games on an external hard drive. Although you cannot play these games on &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Seagate-Playstation-Portable-External-STGD4000400/dp/B076826S5R?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;an external HDD&lt;/a&gt;, this is still good to help manage which games are currently stored on your SSD. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WTOXU4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9562978"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xeHgfY"&gt;Xbox fans, once you have secured Microsoft’s next-gen console, if you are unsure what type of games to buy, a subscription to &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Xbox-Game-Pass-Ultimate-Membership/dp/B07TGNFVWV?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xbox Game Pass Ultimate&lt;/a&gt; might be the best option for you. It includes a robust library of first- and third-party titles for you to download and play. And unlike the PS5, you can purchase a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08K3S6WJM?ots=1&amp;amp;slotNum=4&amp;amp;imprToken=b6bc6b7a-f849-2b43-7fa&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;ascsubtag=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22102198%5Bt%5Dw%5Bd%5DD" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;1TB SSD expansion&lt;/a&gt; to add to the Xbox’s base storage (512GB on the Series S, 1TB on the X), though it is not cheap. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="UU63rQ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9444130"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="WPSrBp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9444105"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="B4Kbmg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9532770"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="3NMCba"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The gaming industry keeps failing miserably at selling its most important products","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21451144/sony-ps5-preorder-microsoft-xbox-series-x-nvidia-rtx-3080-mess"},{"title":"The true price of a PlayStation 5","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/6/22155611/price-ps5-xbox-series-x-nvidia-rtx-3080-3070-3090-3060-amd-rx-6800-xt-scalpers-ebay"},{"title":"When will the global chip shortage end so you can finally buy a PS5?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22368552/global-chip-shortage-end-tsmc-samsung-ps5-supply-demand-intel"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id="OJ4FtK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22386165/ps5-xbox-series-x-restocks-walmart"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22386165/ps5-xbox-series-x-restocks-walmart</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-06T15:07:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-06T15:07:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Division is getting a free-to-play game and mobile version</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FW9EkLRwLaT98z0rHQ2IJiI5Exs=/0x0:810x540/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69247860/Division_update_header.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Ubisoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jPFnyY"&gt;Ubisoft &lt;a href="https://news.ubisoft.com/en-us/article/2MaVWnNfnfQ128qCKaUE3w/an-update-on-the-tom-clancys-the-division-universe?isSso=true&amp;amp;refreshStatus=noLoginData"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that it’s developing a free-to-play game set in &lt;em&gt;The Division&lt;/em&gt;’s universe, called &lt;em&gt;The Division Heartland&lt;/em&gt;. The company also announced that a &lt;em&gt;Division&lt;/em&gt; mobile game is in the works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sL5CYQ"&gt;The announcement is light on details, so it’s not clear yet whether the game will be a battle royale style like &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Warzone&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;, but Ubisoft has said it’ll be coming to PC, consoles, and cloud gaming platforms at some point in 2021 or 2022. There are also basically no details about the mobile game, but Ubisoft said in a news release that more will be revealed at a later date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZMVV1S"&gt;It’s understandable why Ubisoft would want to launch its own version of the free-to-play and mobile shooter games: &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22417447/fortnite-revenue-9-billion-epic-games-apple-antitrust-case"&gt;makes billions of dollars for Epic&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;CoD: Mobile&lt;/em&gt; alone &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/4/22367089/tencent-timi-studios-call-of-duty-mobile-10-billion-2020"&gt;reportedly made $10 billion&lt;/a&gt; in 2020. That’s not even mentioning the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/21/22396481/call-of-duty-warzone-100-million-players-apex-legends"&gt;100 million players&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;em&gt;Warzone, &lt;/em&gt;another lucrative title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bmjq91"&gt;Whether Ubisoft’s offerings in &lt;em&gt;The Division&lt;/em&gt; universe will be as popular as its competitors remains to be seen, but Ubisoft is certainly trying to keep the game’s world culturally relevant: it’s still developing content for &lt;em&gt;The Division 2&lt;/em&gt;, and is currently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/10/18660362/netflix-division-movie-jake-gyllenhaal-jessica-chastain-e3"&gt;working on a movie version with Netflix&lt;/a&gt; starring Jake Gyllenhaal.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423246/the-division-free-to-play-mobile-tv-show-ubisoft-cod"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423246/the-division-free-to-play-mobile-tv-show-ubisoft-cod</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-06T14:57:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-06T14:57:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s Night Shift is no match for the complexities of sleep</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="iPhone SE review" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4YsXlbTvH297UcURLpunyhACq40=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69247787/iphone-se-review-vpavic-verge-13.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kg7CIz"&gt;Apple’s Night Shift feature, which it says “may help you get a better night’s sleep,” doesn’t appear to live up to its claim, according to new research. Because exposure to blue light affects the regulation of sleep cycles, the hope is that Night Shift, which filters blue light from screens after sunset, will make falling asleep easier. But as a recent study shows, sleep is weird and complicated, and a single phone feature likely won’t do much to combat sleepless nights. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TcrQOk"&gt;The study, published in &lt;em&gt;Sleep Health&lt;/em&gt;, tracked the sleep of 167 young adults for one week. People were divided into three groups: one that used their phones for an hour before bed with Night Shift turned on, one that did the same with Night Shift turned off, and one that didn’t use their phones at all before bed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Dc3mqJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Night Shift is not superior to using your phone without Night Shift”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4l7NJN"&gt;“In the whole sample, there were no differences across the three groups,” said Chad Jensen, the lead researcher of the study, &lt;a href="https://news.byu.edu/intellect/is-night-shift-really-helping-you-sleep-better"&gt;in a press release&lt;/a&gt;. “Night Shift is not superior to using your phone without Night Shift or even using no phone at all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BbPulA"&gt;This is only one small study that will need to be replicated at a larger scale with different samplings of people before it can be generalized. Still, the results for the Night Shift feature fall in line with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/3/29/11326194/apple-night-shift-blue-light-sleep"&gt;early skepticism&lt;/a&gt; about how much it can help sleeplessness, especially because Apple doesn’t specify which wavelengths of light are blocked. And while blue light and phone use do likely contribute to difficulty sleeping, there are many other variables to consider within the complexities of sleep and sleep hygiene. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oycJ7Y"&gt;The researchers were mildly surprised that even the group of people who went phone-less before bed didn’t necessarily have better sleep on average. “Our hypothesis was that we would see better sleep without using the phone across the full sample,” Jensen tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, “so it was a bit surprising that we didn’t find that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BF9Hnl"&gt;Part of that result is likely due to the fact that most of the participants were college students who, according to the researchers, were already sleep-deprived. When people are already very sleepy, it doesn’t really matter if they’re on their phones before bed, says Jensen. “Because your need for sleep is so high at that stage that you fall asleep pretty readily no matter what you do before bed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JSyvGX"&gt;One of the few phone-related differences that the study did observe actually had to do with how much sleep participants got. Of the people in the study who slept more than the roughly seven-hour average sleep time, the people who went phone-less slept better and didn’t wake up as often during the night compared to those who used their phones. But the people who slept less than the average showed no difference in any measures of sleep quality, regardless of whether they used a phone at bedtime or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="WEECh2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“There’s not one thing that works for everyone”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="E4xLvL"&gt;If you are a generally well-rested person, Jensen lists myriad factors that could impact your sleep beyond your phone use: caffeine, exercise, the temperature of the room, the amount of light, the amount of noise, consistency of sleep schedules and bedtime routines, and using the bed for activities besides sleeping. And that’s all before we even consider various sleep disorders that can make people too sleepy or not sleepy enough, even if they strive for good sleep habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EsJP5e"&gt;“Sleep is so individualized, there’s not one thing that works for everyone,” says Raj Dasgupta, a sleep medicine specialist at the University of Southern California. Some people are more sensitive to light and might find blue light filtering helpful, but it won’t be the singular fix that leads to better sleep for everyone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C4023t"&gt;As far as phones go, there are things to consider besides just blue light exposure, says Jensen. “All those other forms of stimulation that are not related to light are equally important.” If you’re reading a depressing article or laughing at TikToks at bedtime, that level of alertness and engagement will likely hinder your ability to fall asleep, and filtering blue light won’t offset that effect.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423239/apple-iphone-night-shift-blue-light-sleep"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423239/apple-iphone-night-shift-blue-light-sleep</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kait Sanchez</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
