<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-01-11T11:22:58-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T11:22:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T11:22:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>Jabra’s best true wireless earbuds yet are now available in more colors</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IDNqv3MbnGh62pBQdixU85llcXE=/1215x705:7265x4738/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68650024/Elite_85t_Color_Range_Lineup_LB_1_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Four new colors will join the earbuds’ existing titanium and black model.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Jabra&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LORRGy"&gt;Jabra’s Elite 85T true wireless earbuds, which we called its “best earbuds yet” when we reviewed them last year, are getting four new color variants. Alongside the preexisting titanium / black color scheme, the earbuds will soon be available in gold / beige, copper / black, black, and gray. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vsPNSn"&gt;Outside of the new colors, the new Jabra Elite 85T earbuds are functionally identical to what we reviewed last year. That means they should offer a comfortable fit paired with good noise cancellation and excellent controls. They’re also able to connect to two sources at once, which is handy if you get a phone call while you’re listening to music on a laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xdZEwb"&gt;That’s not to say we didn’t have our reservations about the earbuds, which you can read about in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549587/jabra-elite-85t-review-features-specs-price"&gt;our full review&lt;/a&gt;. Otherwise, the new colors will be available starting today from Jabra’s website for $229 (£219.99 / €229).&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22220288/jabra-elite-85t-earbuds-price-four-new-colors"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22220288/jabra-elite-85t-earbuds-price-four-new-colors</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>TCL details the first of five 20-series phones: the affordable 20 5G and 20 SE</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/upGPDU7kuLGV-0Z94yO7KuCAVrw=/305x409:3811x2746/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68649898/TCL_20_5G_PR_Images_02.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The TCL 20 5G offers a 6.67-inch display with HDR10 video playback.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: TCL&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qm6qs3"&gt;The TCL 20 5G is one of many affordable 5G phones we’ll see this year, and at €299, it will launch a full €100 cheaper than &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/4/6/21207245/tcl-10-pro-5g-10l-price-release-date-budget-phones-specs-features"&gt;last year’s TCL 10 5G&lt;/a&gt;. Using a less expensive 5G-equipped 600-series Qualcomm processor likely enabled the price drop. Otherwise, it looks to be a modest iteration of the previous model. TCL isn’t providing information now about US availability or pricing, only that “some” of the five 20-series phones it will announce this year will come to the US. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YQveOJ"&gt;The 20 5G adopts the new Snapdragon 690 5G processor, dropping down from the 7-series chipset used by its predecessor. The 690 supports low- and midband 5G frequencies but not mmWave.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NsrzXJRB4_nZ7V0CTRx2jCoD4pk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22223117/TCL_20_5G_PR_Images_03.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: TCL&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The TCL 20 5G with a 6.67-inch screen and rear triple-camera array.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fBjaDQ"&gt;The phone also offers a slightly larger 6.67-inch, 1080 x 2400 LCD, while its triple-camera array (borrowed from the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21531096/tcl-10-5g-uw-ultrawideband-sub6ghz-5g-verizon-review-android-phone"&gt;UW variant that came to the US&lt;/a&gt;) now offers improved phase-detect autofocus in the main 48-megapixel camera. It gains a new Smart 5G feature that switches between 5G and 4G automatically depending on the application to preserve battery life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nkSJvh"&gt;The display hardware seems similar to the previous model. It offers the same 450-nit brightness as the 10 5G UW and can convert SDR content to HDR in real time. We didn’t love this feature &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21257398/tcl-10-pro-review-release-date-specs-features-camera-screen"&gt;in the 10 Pro&lt;/a&gt;, but TCL says the SDR to HDR conversion has been improved in this device. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="BBhI5j"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"TCL 10 Pro review: premium looks, budget performance","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21257398/tcl-10-pro-review-release-date-specs-features-camera-screen"},{"title":"TCL’s new phone has ultra-fast 5G for $399, but that’s not enough ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21531096/tcl-10-5g-uw-ultrawideband-sub6ghz-5g-verizon-review-android-phone"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="nT3atQ"&gt;The 20 5G continues to offer HDR10 video playback support, which isn’t too common at this price, and the device offers a display calibration mode for better color accuracy — not something that’s expected in this class, but TCL is obviously playing to its strengths. Other details include a 4,500mAh battery, fingerprint sensor, Android 10 (with an upgrade to 11 coming), and an 8-megapixel front camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5wDn9a"&gt;Also unveiled today was the 20 SE, which doesn’t support 5G but gets a bigger 5,000 mAh battery and dual speakers. It offers a 720 x 1640, 6.82-inch display, quad-camera array (main, wide, macro, and depth), reverse charging, and a rear fingerprint sensor. It ships with Android 11 installed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Uq8Dl8D6PPaejQHWPXQ2TDB7Zcg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22223061/TCL_20_se_PR_Images_b_22.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: TCL&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The TCL 20 SE is a cheaper, media consumption-oriented device.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="8rZHWQ"&gt;The 20 5G is currently on sale in Italy and will expand to other countries in February; it costs €299. The 20 SE will arrive in Europe this month for €149. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22219101/tcl-20-5g-20-se-android-phone-price-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22219101/tcl-20-5g-20-se-android-phone-price-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The TCL NXTPAPER is a cross between a tablet and an e-reader</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="TCL NXTPAPER tablet" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7vlBhPXnDyR2vJRU6u2HAxoOUoU=/199x227:2345x1658/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68649888/TCL_NXTPAPER.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The TCL NXTPAPER will in April to European customers.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: TCL&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XRnvMl"&gt;TCL has announced the NXTPAPER 8-inch tablet using technology it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/3/21419659/tcl-10-tab-max-mid-move-audio-s200-family-watch-announced"&gt;teased with its IFA 2020 announcements&lt;/a&gt;, which the company calls an “artistic combination of screen and paper.” The tablet features a full-color display without backlighting to reduce power consumption and provide a comfortable, E Ink-like viewing experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3z2w9t"&gt;The 1440 x 1080, 8.88-inch screen uses a reflective design to “reuse” natural light, and there’s no flicker or blue light to strain your eyes. TCL says it’s 65 percent more power efficient than a traditional tablet screen with better contrast than an E Ink device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="i3J6oR"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The tablet will ship with Android 10 and include support for Google Assistant&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mBuXuz"&gt;The TCL NXTPAPER includes 8-megapixel rear-facing and 5-megapixel front-facing cameras and is powered by a 5,500mAh battery that the company says provides over a full day of use. Both Wi-Fi and 4G connectivity are included, and the tablet will ship with Android 10 and include support for Google Assistant. A 3.5mm headphone jack is built in, and TCL will include a reading lamp accessory in the box. The device measures 7.4mm thick and weighs 316 grams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8882kR"&gt;TCL says its NXTPAPER tablet will ship in April 2021 for €349 and will first come to Europe, Africa, the Middle East, Latin America, and Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22219269/tcl-nxtpaper-tablet-color-display-ereader"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22219269/tcl-nxtpaper-tablet-color-display-ereader</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>TCL readies Wearable Display glasses for launch, plus new wireless buds and a pet tracker</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_hEjDwckwMMOmpD5cyKGtJKQSRY=/473x586:7162x5045/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68649924/TCL_Wearable_display_lg.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;TCL’s aptly named Wearable Display. | Image: TCL&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bL1rMB"&gt;For CES 2021, TCL is showing off a wearable display prototype that’s &lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/2019-09-07-tcl-personal-cinema-visor-prototype.html?"&gt;been in the works for years&lt;/a&gt; and is now close to reaching market. Simply enough, the company is calling it the TCL Wearable Display, and it’s a pair of glasses with two 1080p mini OLED screens on the inside. This isn’t a virtual reality headset — rather it’s a new take on the concept of a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/2/5/16966530/intel-vaunt-smart-glasses-announced-ar-video"&gt;wearable, personal display&lt;/a&gt; that gives the viewer the effect of looking at a very large screen. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wBTDmff9rJgjk0e7jXnaXzCpgMI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22223437/TCL_Wearable_display_02.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: TCL&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wearable Display is shaped like a pair of standard glasses.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="cqi0KK"&gt;The glasses require a wired connection to a device that’s equipped with USB-C video out. TCL says they produce the effect of viewing a 140-inch display from four meters away, with a density of 49 pixels per degree. They’re also capable of displaying 3D content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9wZWBH"&gt;TCL hasn’t given a price for the glasses yet, and it says the wearable will be available later this year in select markets. The company is working with an unnamed content subscription partner to bring it to the US as part of a bundle deal with a 5G-enabled phone.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JPUkIgoggpLgYKVbD_KWGuZpYXs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22223826/s600_4.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: TCL&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;TCL’s MoveAudio S600 wireless earbuds include active noise cancellation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="OlqXkC"&gt;TCL is also announcing new MoveAudio S600 wireless earbuds, which include active noise cancellation and transparency mode with three microphones built into each bud. They’re rated at IP54 to protect against dust, splashes, and sweat, and they provide eight hours of music playback on a single charge. TCL says they’ll be available to global markets (it’s not clear if that includes the US) in February for €149 (about $180). &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vPoWjcT8G2C-w31d8PaKD_z6T_0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22223828/tracker4.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: TCL&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;MoveTrack Pet Tracker keeps tabs on your pet.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MGFQIV"&gt;Finally, there’s the MoveTrack Pet Tracker. It’s a device that attaches to your pet’s collar and provides real-time location tracking. Users can receive a notification if their pet leaves a designated area, and they can monitor their activity levels. MoveTrack is IP67 rated and provides 14 days of battery life on standby. It will also sell in global markets — again, unclear if that includes the US — for €99 (about $120) in February.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22221389/tcl-wearable-display-glasses-moveaudio-s600-pet-tracker-ces"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22221389/tcl-wearable-display-glasses-moveaudio-s600-pet-tracker-ces</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>TCL announces XL Collection line of TVs, vows to take 8K mainstream this year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kyhI4pg_e8kBQIqLTJpHT935Hwo=/0x1:2084x1390/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68649884/TCL8K.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: TCL&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tvsstY"&gt;TCL makes some of the best under-$1,000 TVs you can buy, and it was also early to adopt the Mini LED technology that TV makers like Samsung and LG are only starting to use in their 2021 lineups. (TCL’s 8-Series and 6-Series both already include Mini LED backlighting.) For 2021, the company is hoping to combine its aggressive pricing strategy and technological head start on Mini LED for a new 6-Series that &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; goes all in on 8K resolution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mulcy5"&gt;“In the year ahead, all 2021 6-Series TCL Roku TV models being launched will feature 8K resolution,” TCL announced in a press release today, noting that last year’s models will remain available as well. TCL’s AiPQ engine will be able to upscale 4K content to higher clarity and sharpness on the new 6-Series. The main problem facing 8K is a dearth of native content at that resolution — and that situation isn’t going to change anytime soon. But it seems like TCL is intent on at least pushing 8K TV prices down. Now the question becomes how much more expensive &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; 6-Series will be over its predecessor. We don’t know yet.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wc0YpBeJsxo6SlqKOnM11Zq-2s8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22227439/TCLnew.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: TCL&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="z7WKTA"&gt;TCL thinks it’s well ahead of competitors in LCD TV technology, and that’s because of the company’s vertical integration and manufacturing expertise. This year, it’s introducing a new panel branded as “OD Zero” because the gap between the display and backlight system is zero millimeters. The result is what TCL describes as an “ultra-slim display with tens of thousands of Mini LEDs and thousands of contrast control zones.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8Tk46ZbHElrF81eIX6mINKmO3N8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22227405/CES_LP_21_Innov.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: TCL&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="nejeAn"&gt;After &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/28/22203910/lg-qned-mini-led-4k-8k-lcd-tv-announced-ces-2021"&gt;LG announced&lt;/a&gt; it would start making LCD TVs with Mini LED, &lt;a href="https://www.tcl.com/us/en/blog/article/mini-led-technology"&gt;TCL published a prickly blog post&lt;/a&gt; that criticized OLED’s low overall market share. “There are TVs with a display technology that hasn’t notably changed since it was first used in TVs in the early 2010s and still only accounts for less than 3 percent of global TV sales,” TCL’s Aaron Dew wrote before talking up the faster evolution of LCD sets and benefits of Mini LED. “To those brands excited to introduce Mini LED in 2021, my only question is ‘what took you so long?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="asTGNg"&gt;TCL’s most recent 6-Series received strong reviews and was also a great choice for gamers — though it couldn’t quite pull off 4K resolution at 120Hz. Presumably, that’s something TCL will look to resolve with this upcoming model. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8U8Mjq"&gt;In 2021, TCL will also debut The XL Collection, a lineup of 85-inch displays at different price points and resolutions. Here’s what the company says you can expect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="1dL8SB"&gt;Three different models will make up the XL Collection this year and each 85-inch TV will feature performance levels for every kind of home theater. From a simply smart 85-inch 4-Series TCL Roku TV that delivers the easiest way to enjoy 4K HDR streaming and an 85-inch 4K HDR TCL Roku TV with QLED picture quality to the ultimate 85-inch Mini LED powered 8K TCL TV with QLED wide color technology, the XL Collection will fit any budget and exceed the highest performance standards to deliver larger-than-life home entertainment. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pQPGH7t0oYSwUfYWxGaNlo24TTo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22227453/XLCollection.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: TCL&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;TCL’s XL Collection is a line of 85-inch TVs that start as low as $1,599.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="anirzI"&gt;The 4-Series will be first out of the gate among the XL Collection: it’s coming this quarter for $1,599. Not bad for a huge 4K display. The pricier XL sets with better QLED (quantum dot color) picture quality will come later in the year. Pricing on those is to be announced — and the same goes for the 8K 6-Series. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224277/tcl-tv-xl-collection-8k-6-series-od-zero-announced-ces-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224277/tcl-tv-xl-collection-8k-6-series-od-zero-announced-ces-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T10:01:45-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T10:01:45-05:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung is making a robot that can pour wine and bring you a drink</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Bot Handy" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TkVmdkGCFe88-PAG_j-e5rtf_bM=/0x1:1590x1061/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68649590/bot_handy.5.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Samsung&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9fW3HR"&gt;Samsung is working on a robot that can pick up laundry, load the dishwasher, set the table, pour wine, and even bring you a drink. The robot is called &lt;a href="https://news.samsung.com/global/samsung-introduces-latest-innovations-for-a-better-normal-at-ces-2021?utm_source=nr_twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=social"&gt;Bot Handy&lt;/a&gt;, and Samsung says it’ll be able to recognize objects using a camera and AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GMOGaF"&gt;The bot is meant to be “an extension of you in the kitchen, living room, and anywhere else you may need an extra hand in your home,” Sebastian Seung, president of Samsung Research, said during Samsung’s CES press conference today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o6ZOFG"&gt;For now, it’s not clear how close Bot Handy is to being a real, shipping product. Samsung didn’t announce a price or release window, and the company has previously used CES to show off futuristic-looking robots that are more of a concept than a real product. The robot is described as being “in development.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h0TghnK371BcPZ18gBqmzm34zkg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22227359/samsung_bot_handy_kitchen_full.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Video: Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="xt5qnL"&gt;In its current form, Bot Handy is a tall, thin, black-and-white robot with two large digital eyes that change expressions as it moves around. The robot has a single arm that can pivot at three points — essentially a shoulder, elbow, and wrist — with a clamp-like hand at the end of it. There are cameras mounted on top of the robot’s body and hand for recognizing objects. The robot can move around the room on what appears to be a rolling base, swivel from side to side, and raise itself up to reach higher objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0iYkFf"&gt;Samsung says the robot will be able to assess the material that different objects are made of so that it’ll grab them with the right amount of force. It’s also supposed to be able to handle objects of varying sizes, weights, and shapes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9LRdPz"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DqXsTtW5VEo?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=1033&amp;amp;start=1033" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="S31d4a"&gt;In addition to Bot Handy, Samsung also demonstrated an updated version of Bot Care, a “robotic assistant and companion” that the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/9/18175168/ces-2019-robots-best-worst-delivery-butler-tablet"&gt;first showed off in 2019&lt;/a&gt;. The robot is supposed to be something of a personal assistant, reminding you to take a break from work or that you have meetings coming up. In a demo, Samsung showed the robot automatically opening up a screen so that its owner could join a video call that was about to start. Like Bot Handy, there’s no indication of how far along in development this is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xToNmI"&gt;As far as actual products go, Samsung does have one robot that should ship this year. The &lt;a href="https://news.samsung.com/global/samsungs-new-ai-powered-robotic-vacuum-and-laundry-products-automate-home-cleaning?utm_source=feedly&amp;amp;utm_medium=direct"&gt;JetBot 90 AI+&lt;/a&gt; is a Roomba-esque vacuum robot equipped with LIDAR, a “3D sensor,” and AI to help it recognize objects so that it can better avoid obstacles. Samsung says the vacuum will be smart enough to get closer to objects that aren’t particularly fragile, like a kids toy, and to stay further away from something it could break, like a vase. The vacuum also has a traditional camera built in, which is meant to let you check up on pets while you’re away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZQNNjb"&gt;The JetBot 90 AI+ is supposed to ship in the US sometime in the first half of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224649/samsung-bot-handy-care-robots-ces-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224649/samsung-bot-handy-care-robots-ces-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T09:48:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T09:48:01-05:00</updated>
    <title>Finally, a doorbell for the pandemic era</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8glMC1_xLR9C6Qek38TxqvMh3Sc=/0x0:4500x3000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68649482/VDB770_doorbell_090220_touchless_cover_03.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Alarm.com&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RlATm2"&gt;Alarm.com has announced a new device for anyone worried about visitors catching COVID-19 from, of all things, their doorbell. Rather than using a button, the &lt;a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210111005239/en/Alarm.com-Develops-the-First-T%5B%E2%80%A6%5Dav1w-UkdSlG3miu0ZZ-LtXjCwD3Ec3ldN_zZCGORvG0LE20YOvo49uqw=="&gt;Touchless Video Doorbell&lt;/a&gt; is designed to chime when its camera detects visitors standing on your doormat. Alarm.com claims this is the “first commercially available video doorbell that rings without requiring any contact,” and that its aim is to “reduce public health risks and make home visits and deliveries safer for all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="taA5tb"&gt;In what seems to be an admission that this is &lt;em&gt;quite a confusing way&lt;/em&gt; to ring a doorbell, there are instructions on how to ring the device printed on its front. Alarm.com is also selling a doormat accessory for the doorbell, which instructs visitors on where to stand so the doorbell can see them properly. Given how perplexed we found most delivery drivers were by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21492740/yale-delivery-box-review-smart-lock-packages-price-specs-features#APBqXP:~:text=In%20the%20five%20days%20I%E2%80%99ve%20had,a%20particularly%20amusing%20thing%20to%20see."&gt;Yale’s Smart Delivery Box&lt;/a&gt;, there’s a chance this touchless doorbell could create similar confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-Ym_76uhFnv4mX6V46APr_L1lwA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22227215/VDB770_doorbell_090220_touchless_cover_03.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Alarm.com&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Instructions on how to ring can be found on the doorbell itself...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4-hVsEzIqHK-LBDszsRee0neFIU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22227217/Video_Doorbell_Product_Image2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Alarm.com&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;... as well as the doormat accessory, available separately.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AKc2xy"&gt;When Alarm.com’s doorbell detects a person, it plays a chime in the home, sends a notification to your phone, and starts recording a video clip. You can see and speak with visitors through the doorbell, and it also integrates with the rest of a home’s Alarm.com smart home security system, so it can trigger other devices like lights when a person is detected. Its camera is 1080p HDR, and it’s also equipped with infrared night vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M5Rr6w"&gt;It’s admirable that the main people to benefit from a touchless doorbell would be the delivery drivers who’ve become vital lifelines for people avoiding leaving their homes. But it’s not clear how much help a touchless doorbell could actually be. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AslAwE"&gt;The latest advice from the US’s &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/prevent-getting-sick/how-covid-spreads.html#share-nav:~:text=Respiratory%20droplets%20can%20also%20land%20on,a%20common%20way%20that%20COVID%2D19%20spreads"&gt;Centers for Disease Control and Prevention&lt;/a&gt; (CDC) is that surface transmission (like touching a doorbell contaminated with the virus and then touching your face) is “not thought to be a common way that COVID-19 spreads.” Instead, COVID-19 is thought to transmit from person to person most often when they’re in close contact with one another, which is something you don’t need a touchless smart doorbell to avoid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K4Vag8"&gt;Alarm.com’s Touchless Video Doorbell is available now via the company’s network of installation partners. When asked, the company wouldn’t comment on exactly how much the system costs, but said the doorbell itself is priced at “under $200.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224537/alarm-touchless-video-doorbell-doormat"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224537/alarm-touchless-video-doorbell-doormat</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T09:27:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T09:27:16-05:00</updated>
    <title>LG used a virtual influencer to announce new products during its CES keynote </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qYoVOMCFLRADUabmxlvrYYahgPw=/204x0:1350x764/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68649365/Screen_Shot_2021_01_11_at_8.40.39_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EnKqTZ"&gt;Reah Keem is just like you and I — she loves working on music, vacationing abroad, and is pretty bummed out about not being able to visit any cool places right now. The biggest difference, however, is that Reah Keem isn’t a real person. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d7kLjH"&gt;LG introduced Reah Keem as a virtual influencer who appeared during its live-streamed CES keynote to unveil the company’s new line of LG CLOi UV-C robots. The robot, which was &lt;a href="https://ces2021.lgusnewsroom.com/press-release/lg-announces-autonomous-robot-with-disinfecting-uv-light-for-various-b2b-applications/"&gt;announced by LG in December&lt;/a&gt;, is designed for areas with high traffic, like hotels, and roams around shining UV-C light that should reduce exposure to harmful germs. Keem’s job was talking about how important the CLOi UV-C was to her own life, using the chance to talk about how excited she was to start traveling again in the real world — a world in which she technically does not exist. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nSmEoX"&gt;She may not need oxygen to breathe, but Keem is definitely leaving her mark on the real world (including living in Seoul, apparently). She has around 6,000 &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/reahkeem/?hl=en"&gt;followers on Instagram&lt;/a&gt; and a SoundCloud page with exactly one song. For what it’s worth, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fsoundcloud.com%2Freahkeem%2Fcomino-drive&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F1%2F11%2F22224601%2Flg-ces-virtual-influencer-dj-reah-keem-uvc-robot#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;it’s pretty good&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xXo5MJ"&gt;&lt;iframe width="100%" height="400" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=true&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F866919088&amp;amp;show_artwork=true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bvOMjX"&gt;Virtual influencers aren’t new, but the appearance of a virtual creator at a highly virtualized and socially distant CES really hammered home how weird this event was. It’s nothing short of bizarre watching a creepily accurate virtual influencer say things like “I’m going to chill in my studio,” working on some sick beats, until the pandemic comes to an end and safe travel can happen again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FsUm8X"&gt;Although, paying an influencer to promote something they don’t really care about seems entirely accurate to the influencer ecosystem. It’s unclear if LG actually &lt;em&gt;created &lt;/em&gt;Reah Keem, or if LG paid her for her services at all; a press release only &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/lg-envisions-a-future-made-better-safer-and-easier-with-its-advanced-solutions-at-ces-2021-301205018.html"&gt;says that LG “introduced” Keem&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xqo0sJ"&gt;Will Keem have a future outside of this one LG live stream? Will she face competition from other big-time virtual influencers, including Miquela Sousa (better known as Lil Miquela) or Shudu? Right now, she’s working on her sick beats in her cool home studio, but the virtual influencer scene is heating up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r5eW44"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224601/lg-ces-virtual-influencer-dj-reah-keem-uvc-robot"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224601/lg-ces-virtual-influencer-dj-reah-keem-uvc-robot</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft’s new Surface Pro 7 Plus has a bigger battery, removable SSD, and LTE</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UEpf2J_noZZUMN5iqFdusniASss=/0x0:2640x1760/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68649235/surfacepro7plus.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft’s new Surface Pro 7 Plus.&lt;/em&gt; | Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bmCEdg"&gt;Microsoft is updating its Surface Pro line today with a refreshed Surface Pro 7 Plus model that is only available to businesses and schools. While the design and screen on the outside remain the same as the Surface Pro 7, Microsoft has overhauled the internals of the device to make way for Intel’s latest 11th Gen processors, a bigger battery, removable SSD, and LTE connectivity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o21kTG"&gt;This marks the return of LTE to the main Surface Pro line for the first time since 2015, but unfortunately there’s no 5G connectivity as Microsoft is using Qualcomm’s older Snapdragon X20 LTE modem inside the Surface Pro 7 Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0G-W1rUduteQFoYcWXv0ZHkBW4c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22219459/Surface_Pro_7__Image_10.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Surface Pro 7 Plus has no external design changes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CYhdpB"&gt;A variety of models will be available, starting with the Intel Core i3 (1115G4) and ending with the Intel Core i7 (1165G7). Only the Intel Core i5 (1135G7) model will have optional LTE starting at $1,149, and the base Core i3 model ships with 8GB of RAM and 128GB of storage for $899. The top Core i7 option ($2,799) can also be configured up to 32GB of RAM and up to 1TB of SSD storage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jSoKOG"&gt;Microsoft is now promising up to 15 hours of battery life on the Surface Pro 7 Plus, up from the 10.5 hours the company claims on the original Surface Pro 7. A small part of this battery life improvement will be thanks to the Intel 11th Gen chips, but it’s mostly down to a move from a battery capacity of 46.5Wh to 50.4Wh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qtFh94"&gt;The Surface Pro 7 Plus also ships with the same 12.3-inch (2736 x 1824) PixelSense display found on the original Surface Pro 7, with a single USB-C port, a USB-A port, 3.5mm headphone jack, and the Surface Connect port. The Wi-Fi-only models will include a MicroSDXC card reader, while the LTE models will replace this with a nano SIM. This does mean that the Surface Pro 7 Plus still doesn’t have Thunderbolt connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ivtYpXChd9ymk5EZuIDV5Tu83Hs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22219460/Surface_Pro_7__Image_4.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The removable SSD on the Surface Pro 7 Plus.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="pOBkym"&gt;The Surface Pro 7 Plus has some bigger than normal internal changes overall, too. “We changed the inside quite substantially,” explains Robin Seiler, corporate vice president of program management for devices at Microsoft, in an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “It actually required us to flip the internals in order for us to put the SSD here, so when we did that we also updated the TDM (Thermal Design Model) to create more space for a larger battery size.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QvGh7o"&gt;The removable SSD works just like it does on the Surface Pro X or Surface Laptop 3, allowing businesses to swap drives out for reparability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PZZUlb"&gt;So why no major redesign with thinner display bezels? Microsoft says it’s mostly for consistency because businesses want to standardize on Surface Pro configurations and form factors. “When you look at the Surface Pro X, which has the thinner bezels, there are pretty substantial changes in terms of port locations which is driven by those bezels,” says Seiler. “Thinning the bezels does require significant change in terms of form factor and compatibility with previous [models].”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Qp6_zxJ6nud0F_5La7FP57fXKwI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22219462/Surface_Pro_7__Image_3.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Surface Pro 7 Plus starts at $899.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6WDoAQ"&gt;This focus on businesses and LTE connectivity, at a time when home internet connections might not hold up to working from home demands, also explains why Microsoft didn’t opt for the Surface Pro 8 moniker and make this device available to consumers. “This is simply an extension of a commercially-focused line,” explains Seiler. “It was important for us to signal that this is an extension of Pro 7, for all of the customers who have standardized on that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rZMyfu"&gt;Still, it’s disappointing that a refreshed model with Intel’s latest processors and LTE connectivity won’t be available directly to consumers. Microsoft won’t say if that will change any time soon, but it does feel like the company is trying to draw a line between the Surface Pro as business-focused and the Surface Go and Surface Pro X for consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A3JKBK"&gt;Microsoft is planning to start shipping the Surface Pro 7 Plus to customers on January 15th in the US, and it will also be available in Canada, Australia, New Zealand, the UK, and a large number of European countries.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22218445/microsoft-surface-pro-7-plus-features-price-specs-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22218445/microsoft-surface-pro-7-plus-features-price-specs-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Spotify Kids now supports shared playlists, letting parents control the music</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Sb5ecZ-SzcJhyQ7Bc2ZhVhWfmy4=/0x0:1920x1280/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68649199/spotifykidsplaylists.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Spotify&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mafrIp"&gt;Parents can now influence more of their kids’ music taste through Spotify. The audio streaming platform announced a new feature for Spotify Kids today called Shared Playlists, which allows parents to share playlists they’ve created with their kids. The Spotify Kids app gives kids access to child-approved audio content with the goal of gating them into a safe place to click around and access music and stories. This new feature allows kids to gain access to the content that lives outside those walls, however, with parents acting as the main gatekeeper. Spotify says the idea is to give parents a way to share the music they loved growing up or that they enjoy regularly as a family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p0jT7S"&gt;To share a playlist, parents have to access the PIN-protected area of the kids app. They can then select the music playlists they want to share, which have to have been created by the parent. Songs with potentially explicit tracks will be marked with an E, and if a parent wants to remove those tracks, they’ll have to do so from their Spotify app. The first time they share a playlist, a pop-up will appear asking the parent to confirm this decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ZCY9F"&gt;Spotify launched its Kids app &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/30/20938076/spotify-kids-app-announced-disney-taylor-swift-family-plan"&gt;in 2019&lt;/a&gt; and has continued to expand its reach, along with the introduction of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/12/21255107/spotify-kids-update-app-block-track-listening-history-parental-controls"&gt;new features&lt;/a&gt;. Parents can now view their kids’ listening history and block tracks. Shared playlists is another incremental feature but one that parents might appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22218697/spotify-kids-shared-playlists-adult-app"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22218697/spotify-kids-shared-playlists-adult-app</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
