<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-28T18:08:34-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-28T18:08:34-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-28T18:08:34-05:00</updated>
    <title>Cybersecurity firm says social media bots hyped GameStop during trading frenzy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cauyjDHhe5MNV7eHWFEpxCcaWa0=/0x0:4015x2677/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68888800/gamestop_stock_sean_hollister.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="989dBd"&gt;A cybersecurity firm found that bots were promoting GameStop stock on social media before and after the stock’s frenzied rise last month, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-retail-trading-gamestop-robots-idUSKBN2AQ2BH"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; reported.&lt;/a&gt; Massachusetts-based PiiQ Media says social media bots promoted Dogecoin, GameStop, and other “meme” stocks in posts on Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, and YouTube. The firm estimated that tens of thousands of bots participated, but it’s still unclear how much influence they had or didn’t have on the rise and fall of GME and other stocks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ADCGcc"&gt;Shares in GME skyrocketed in January as Reddit users on r/wallstreetbets rallied around the stock in an attempt to squeeze hedge funds that had bet against the video game company. PiiQ told &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; it detected “patterns of artificial behavior” in GameStop-related posts just before the January 28th chaos through February 18th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lZgdGJ"&gt;PiiQ did not analyze Reddit traffic, and Reddit CEO Steve Huffman &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/02/18/reddit-ceo-steve-huffman-defends-platforms-role-in-gamestop-surge.html"&gt;said in a hearing&lt;/a&gt; before the House Financial Services in February that the platform had not detected any significant bot-driven activity or foreign actors on the subreddit as part of the GME trading hype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bTq44L"&gt;The Securities and Exchange Commission is investigating the GameStop saga, and the Senate Banking Committee plans to hold a hearing on “the current state of the stock market.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5C1KCB"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UVPCH7"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="naUesy"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8jeE2V"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H1Vlrf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/28/22306295/analyst-bots-hyped-gamestop-trading-reddit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/28/22306295/analyst-bots-hyped-gamestop-trading-reddit</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-28T17:11:23-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-28T17:11:23-05:00</updated>
    <title>Minneapolis hiring social media influencers for former police officers’ trials</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="MINNEAPOLIS, MN - OCTOBER 14: Flameless candles are illuminated" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4to7671hU4QeJLvoWn8eVEBvLNY=/0x0:5760x3840/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68888606/1229485925.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;George Floyd died in police custody in May 2020 | Getty&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="d0JiiN"&gt;Minneapolis is hiring social media influencers to share “city-generated and approved messages” during the trials of four former city police officers charged in the May 2020 killing of George Floyd, according to the &lt;a href="https://minnesotareformer.com/2021/02/26/amid-massive-security-presence-minneapolis-is-turning-to-grassroots-to-keep-the-peace/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Minnesota Reformer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The Minneapolis &lt;a href="https://lims.minneapolismn.gov/RCA/7568"&gt;city council approved the plan&lt;/a&gt; on Friday, which calls for six influencers to be paid about $2,000 each to spread the city’s messages with Black, Native American, Hmong, and Latino communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fr4XUX"&gt;The goal is to “address/dispel incorrect information” by using “trusted messengers,” part of a program the city refers to as its Joint Information System to share “timely and relevant information” with the public during the trials. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SNHycL"&gt;“Through the Communications and Neighborhood and Community Relations departments the City will ensure that communities and elected leaders have direct access to information in real time leading up to the trial, during the trial and when the verdict is announced,” according to the city. “We intend to offer enhanced community services during the trial to keep people informed and safe, especially non-English and Black, Indigenous People of Color (BIPOC) communities and small businesses that do not rely on traditional media.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="zTYbw2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Peace Reporters","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21355122/police-brutality-violence-video-effects-trauma-civil-rights-black-lives-matter"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="BDbzsa"&gt;Floyd died in police custody last May, after former officer Derek Chauvin pressed his knee to Floyd’s neck while he lay on the ground in handcuffs. The incident sparked protests in Minneapolis and across the country for much of last summer. &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/us-news-health-trials-coronavirus-pandemic-minneapolis-075d9b5f4a2a1f80d26cb33b77ca59b5"&gt;Chauvin faces second-degree murder&lt;/a&gt; and manslaughter charges. Jury selection for his trial begins March 8th. The other three ex-officers are due to go on trial in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gTdQyH"&gt;Even before Floyd’s death, there was widespread mistrust between Minneapolis’ Black residents and the police; according to the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, between 2015 and 2020, Minneapolis police used force against Black people &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2020/06/03/us/minneapolis-police-use-of-force.html?auth=login-email&amp;amp;login=email"&gt;least seven times more than they did white people&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/28/22306203/minneapolis-social-media-influencers-george-floyd-derek-chauvin-police"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/28/22306203/minneapolis-social-media-influencers-george-floyd-derek-chauvin-police</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-28T15:28:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-28T15:28:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>New AI ‘Deep Nostalgia’ brings old photos, including very old ones, to life</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xjrKwNiPRigKH1YKq5BTtmYHYHo=/161x0:869x472/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68888360/my_heritage_photo.0.gif" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;MyHeritage&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2c9DQO"&gt;An AI-powered service called Deep Nostalgia that animates still photos has become the main character on Twitter this fine Sunday, as people try to create the creepiest fake “video” possible, apparently. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HQHFum"&gt;The Deep Nostalgia service, offered by online genealogy company &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.myheritage.com%2Fdeep-nostalgia&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F28%2F22306097%2Fai-brings-still-photos-life-meme-twitter-geneaology-myheritage" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;MyHeritage&lt;/a&gt;, uses AI licensed from D-ID to create the effect that a still photo is moving. It’s kinda like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/9/9/9296829/apple-live-photos-feature-iphone-6s"&gt;iOS Live Photos feature&lt;/a&gt;, which adds a few seconds of video to help smartphone photographers find the best shot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BIprDM"&gt;But Deep Nostalgia can take photos from any camera and bring them to “life.” The program uses pre-recorded driver videos of facial movements and applies the one that works best for the still photo in question. Its intended purpose is to allow you to upload photos of deceased loved ones and see them in “action,” which seems like a lovely idea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9y2fYU"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;“It makes me so happy to see him smile again!" Try our new &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DeepNostalgia?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#DeepNostalgia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/PhotoAnimation?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#PhotoAnimation&lt;/a&gt; feature for yourself and prepare to be AMAZED!!! &lt;a href="https://t.co/p3h600G3MX"&gt;https://t.co/p3h600G3MX&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/YdAn9IxyW0"&gt;pic.twitter.com/YdAn9IxyW0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— MyHeritage (@MyHeritage) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MyHeritage/status/1366029972452827136?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 28, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FIGSMA"&gt;Users have to sign up for a free account on MyHeritage and then upload a photo. From there the process is automated; the site enhances the image before animating it and creating a gif. The site’s FAQ says it does not provide the photos to any third parties, and on its main page a message reads “photos uploaded without completing signup are automatically deleted to protect your privacy.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jS9knF"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;oh my! &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MyHeritage?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@MyHeritage&lt;/a&gt; has created such an extraordinary photo animation tool. Here is my grandmother! I have clients waiting for work today, how can I tear myself away from this and from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/RootsTechConnect?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#RootsTechConnect&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/op6cMjcXXH"&gt;pic.twitter.com/op6cMjcXXH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Nicole Lascelle (@pedigreetales) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/pedigreetales/status/1365042664664662018?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 25, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OmJEDj"&gt;Naturally, the program has become something of a meme-generator on Twitter, with users trying to push the AI to its limit. An archaeologist used photos of ancient statues, and yes they included some with the blank eyes. Sorry in advance for the nightmare fuel (but hiiii there Alexander the Great):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TXclpt"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Here's Alexander the Great &lt;a href="https://t.co/djbnzszFM0"&gt;pic.twitter.com/djbnzszFM0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Flint Dibble     (@FlintDibble) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FlintDibble/status/1365848793925750789?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 28, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aYexo6"&gt;Deep Nostalgia can only handle single headshots and can only animate faces, so you’re not going to be able to reanimate mummies to make it look like they’re walking (hey I wondered, OK?). You can upload five photos for free to the MyHeritage website for Deep Nostalgia treatment, after that you have to register for a paid account. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WRZ7U8"&gt;I wonder if perhaps there are some photos best left un-animated? I’m wary of uploading photos to any site, and I think the usual privacy cautions still apply. But if you’re going to try Deep Nostalgia brace yourself for a surreal experience. The AI is scarily good. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1me95r"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/28/22306097/ai-brings-still-photos-life-meme-twitter-geneaology-myheritage"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/28/22306097/ai-brings-still-photos-life-meme-twitter-geneaology-myheritage</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-28T13:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-28T13:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to watch the 2021 Golden Globes online</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-ENTERTAINMENT-VIRUS-GLOBES-AWARD" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_4LTlvORH9O50LRrPGs2g66mfNc=/0x133:4603x3202/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68887954/1231346745.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by VALERIE MACON/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FuzJDE"&gt;Awards season in Hollywood begins Sunday, February 28th, with the 78th Golden Globe Awards, hosted by the Hollywood Foreign Press Association. The Golden Globes, usually considered a harbinger of who may take home awards at other shows like the Oscars, will look a bit different this year thanks to the coronavirus pandemic. The hosts and presenters will be in different locations in the US and around the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wZ0iX5"&gt;Streaming services have finally come into their own at the Globes, with Netflix leading the pack of with 20 total nominations for its television shows; Hulu has six total nominations, Apple TV Plus has two, and Disney Plus has one. In the motion picture categories (the Globes honor films and TV shows), Netflix leads the way with 22 nominations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cbcqwx"&gt;And it seems the Golden Globes’ judges have heard the &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2018/film/awards/golden-globes-nominations-female-directors-shut-out-1203082355/"&gt;criticism from past years about excluding women&lt;/a&gt; from the best director category. This year three of the five nominees for best director are women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="AnvDs4"&gt;What time do the Golden Globes start?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="g6eeMm"&gt;The Golden Globes will start at 8PM ET / 5PM PT on Sunday, February 28th. As it has for the past several years, NBC is broadcasting the three-hour awards show. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="cBioKV"&gt;How do I watch the Golden Globes?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="8W3UN3"&gt;The Golden Globes will be available for live-streaming through &lt;a href="https://www.nbc.com/live"&gt;NBC’s website&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.nbc.com/apps"&gt;or app&lt;/a&gt;, but you’ll have to enter your TV provider information to watch. You can also watch on Hulu Plus Live TV and YouTubeTV, both of which have paid subscriptions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="z4SbPP"&gt;Where can I watch the pre-show?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="BCjX0R"&gt;As it does every year, &lt;a href="https://www.eonline.com/news/1241183/all-the-details-on-e-s-2021-golden-globes-red-carpet-and-award-show-coverage"&gt;E! is running its pre-show&lt;/a&gt; at starting at 6PM ET / 3PM PT.  The official pre-show will begin streaming at 6:30PM ET/3:30PM PT from the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/goldenglobes/"&gt;Golden Globes Twitter&lt;/a&gt; account and the official Hollywood Foreign Press Association &lt;a href="https://www.goldenglobes.com/winners-nominees"&gt;Golden Globes website&lt;/a&gt;. NBC will start its red-carpet coverage at 7PM ET / 4PM PT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="VPGMoh"&gt;Who’s hosting the Golden Globes?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="z1zU3S"&gt;Tina Fey and Amy Poehler are back as co-hosts, returning for the fourth time. The pair hosted back in 2013, 2013, and 2015. They’ll be bicoastal this year: Fey will be live in New York while Poehler will be in Beverly Hills. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KZuNjE"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/goldenglobes/status/1212720410841608194"&gt;list of presenters&lt;/a&gt; includes: Awkwafina, Cynthia Erivo, Annie Mumolo, Joaquin Phoenix, Kristen Wiig, Renee Zellweger, Bryce Dallas Howard, Christopher Meloni, Rosie Perez, Christian Slater, Anthony Anderson, Tiffany Haddish, Kate Hudson, Margot Robbie, and Kenan Thompson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nFP8Mq"&gt;Nominees are expected to appear from various locations around the world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ybqLcL"&gt;Who’s nominated?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ItLXFP"&gt;Here is the &lt;a href="https://www.goldenglobes.com/winners-nominees/2021"&gt;full list of nominees&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="U0z7gb"&gt;Film&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id="f6Idea"&gt;Best Motion Picture — Drama&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="7IjRJC"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Father&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mank&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nomadland&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Promising Young Woman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Trial of the Chicago 7&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="1GFjA8"&gt;Best Picture — Musical/Comedy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="pZPA7T"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Borat Subsequent Moviefilm &lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hamilton&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Music&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Palm Springs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Prom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="BJp9x1"&gt;Best Actress in a Motion Picture — Drama&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="0S8UCU"&gt;Viola Davis, &lt;em&gt;Ma Rainey’s Black Bottom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Andra Day, &lt;em&gt;The United States vs. Billie Holiday&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Vanessa Kirby, &lt;em&gt;Pieces of a Woman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Frances McDormand, &lt;em&gt;Nomadland&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Carey Mulligan, &lt;em&gt;Promising Young Woman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="VAXfIF"&gt;Best Actor in a Motion Picture — Drama&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="CzPnHK"&gt;Riz Ahmed, Sound of Metal&lt;br&gt;Chadwick Boseman, &lt;em&gt;Ma Rainey’s Black Bottom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Anthony Hopkins, &lt;em&gt;The Father&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Gary Oldman, &lt;em&gt;Mank&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Tahar Rahim, &lt;em&gt;The Mauritanian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Mdeo7V"&gt;Best Actress in a Motion Picture — Musical/Comedy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="2MB1Fv"&gt;Maria Bakalova, &lt;em&gt;Borat Subsequent Moviefilm&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Kate Hudson, &lt;em&gt;Music&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Michelle Pfeiffer, &lt;em&gt;French Exit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Rosamund Pike, &lt;em&gt;I Care A Lot&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Anya Taylor-Joy, &lt;em&gt;Emma&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Wwlqz1"&gt;Best Actor in a Motion Picture — Musical or Comedy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="bOApDj"&gt;Sacha Baron Cohen, &lt;em&gt;Borat Subsequent Moviefilm&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;James Corden, &lt;em&gt;The Prom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Lin-Manuel Miranda, &lt;em&gt;Hamilton&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Dev Patel, &lt;em&gt;The Personal History of David Copperfield&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Andy Samberg, &lt;em&gt;Palm Springs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="5CBW81"&gt;Best Supporting Actress — Motion Picture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="UtlTJc"&gt;Glenn Close, &lt;em&gt;Hillbilly Elegy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Olivia Colman, &lt;em&gt;The Father&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Jodie Foster, &lt;em&gt;The Mauritanian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Amanda Seyfried, &lt;em&gt;Mank&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Helena Zengel, &lt;em&gt;News of the World&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="k0uyLi"&gt;Best Supporting Actor — Motion Picture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="ogfeT9"&gt;Sacha Baron Cohen, &lt;em&gt;The Trial of the Chicago 7&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Daniel Kaluuya, &lt;em&gt;Judas and the Black Messiah&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Jared Leto, &lt;em&gt;The Little Things&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Bill Murray, &lt;em&gt;On the Rocks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Leslie Odom, Jr., &lt;em&gt;One Night in Miami&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="v3hut1"&gt;Best Director — Motion Picture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="X9bmEF"&gt;Emerald Fennell, &lt;em&gt;Promising Young Woman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;David Fincher, &lt;em&gt;Mank&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Regina King, &lt;em&gt;One Night in Miami&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Aaron Sorkin, &lt;em&gt;The Trial of the Chicago 7&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Chloe Zhao, &lt;em&gt;Nomadland&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="z1REOt"&gt;Best Screenplay — Motion Picture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="7Svmuv"&gt;Emerald Fennell, &lt;em&gt;Promising Young Woman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Jack Fincher, &lt;em&gt;Mank&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Aaron Sorkin, &lt;em&gt;The Trial of the Chicago 7&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Christopher Hampton and Florian Zeller, &lt;em&gt;The Father&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Chloe Zhao, &lt;em&gt;Nomadland&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="mQuVTq"&gt;Best Picture — Animated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="ovQZ8b"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Croods, A New Age&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Onward&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Over the Moon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Soul&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wolfwalkers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="IvIfXh"&gt;Best Picture — Foreign Language&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="WEfAyw"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Another Round &lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;La Llorona&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Life Ahead&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Minari&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Two of Us&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="liyr5E"&gt;Best Original Score — Motion Picture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="hFgiNJ"&gt;Alexandre Desplat,&lt;em&gt; The Midnight Sky&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ludwig Goransson, &lt;em&gt;Tenet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;James Newton Howard, &lt;em&gt;News of the World&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Atticus Ross and Trent Reznor, &lt;em&gt;Mank&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Jon Batiste, Atticus Ross, and Trent Reznor, &lt;em&gt;Soul&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="6p4Cro"&gt;Best Original Song — Motion Picture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="sAG5Z8"&gt;“Fight for You,” &lt;em&gt;Judas and the Black Messiah&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;“Hear My Voice,” &lt;em&gt;The Trial of the Chicago 7&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;“Io Si,”&lt;em&gt; The Life Ahead&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;“Speak Now,” &lt;em&gt;One Night in Miami&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;“Tigress and Tweed,” &lt;em&gt;The United States vs. Billie Holiday&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="NHN3Hk"&gt;Television&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id="eRh3F1"&gt;Best Television Series — Drama&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="FWWFxt"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Crown&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lovecraft Country&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ozark&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ratched&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="p5apPP"&gt;Best Television Series – Musical /Comedy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="KXMAx4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Emily in Paris&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Flight Attendant&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Great&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Schitt’s Creek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="t7irBf"&gt;Best Television Motion Picture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="EWUg5p"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Normal People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Queen’s Gambit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Small Axe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Undoing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unorthodox&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="HwX435"&gt;Best Actress - Television Motion Picture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="soad1F"&gt;Cate Blanchett, &lt;em&gt;Mrs. America&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Daisy Edgar-Jones, &lt;em&gt;Normal People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Shira Haas, &lt;em&gt;Unorthodox&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;br&gt;Nicole Kidman, &lt;em&gt;The Undoing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Anya Taylor-Joy, &lt;em&gt;The Queen’s Gambit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="uWSV67"&gt;Best Actor - Television Motion Picture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="sNVjV2"&gt;Bryan Cranston, Your Honor&lt;br&gt;Jeff Daniels, &lt;em&gt;The Comey Rule&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Hugh Grant, &lt;em&gt;The Undoing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ethan Hawke, &lt;em&gt;The Good Lord Bird&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mark Ruffalo, &lt;em&gt;I Know This Much is True&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="5mFiDe"&gt;Best Actress in a Drama Series&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="YJM818"&gt;Olivia Colman, &lt;em&gt;The Crown&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Jodie Comer, &lt;em&gt;Killing Eve&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Emma Corrin, &lt;em&gt;The Crown&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Laura Linney, &lt;em&gt;Ozark&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Sarah Paulson, &lt;em&gt;Ratched&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="v6Hnp3"&gt;Best Actor in a Drama Series&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="yuYLQ6"&gt;Jason Bateman, &lt;em&gt;Ozark&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Josh O’Connor, &lt;em&gt;The Crown&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Bob Odenkirk, &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Al Pacino, &lt;em&gt;Hunters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Matthew Rhys, &lt;em&gt;Perry Mason&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="AP7q5T"&gt;Best Actress in a Musical/Comedy Series&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="hWdjem"&gt;Lily Collins, Emily in Paris&lt;br&gt;Kaley Cuoco, &lt;em&gt;The Flight Attendant&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Elle Fanning, &lt;em&gt;The Great&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Jane Levy, &lt;em&gt;Zoey’s Extraordinary Playlist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Catherine O’Hara, &lt;em&gt;Schitt’s Creek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="rsI0qQ"&gt;Best Actor in a Comedy Series&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="xrH526"&gt;Don Cheadle, Black Monda&lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Nicholas Hoult, The Great&lt;br&gt;Eugene Levy, &lt;em&gt;Schitt’s Creek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Jason Sudeikis, &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ramy Youssef, &lt;em&gt;Ramy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="gfKoZ7"&gt;Best Supporting Actress -Television&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="LtXMAI"&gt;Gillian Anderson, &lt;em&gt;The Crown&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Helena Bonham Carter, &lt;em&gt;The Crown&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Julia Garner, Ozark&lt;br&gt;Annie Murphy, &lt;em&gt;Schitt’s Creek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Cynthia Nixon, &lt;em&gt;Ratched&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="hP0gRU"&gt;Best Supporting Actor - Television&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="R4b3Pt"&gt;John Boyega, &lt;em&gt;Small Axe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Brendan Gleeson, &lt;em&gt;The Comey Rule&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Daniel Levy, &lt;em&gt;Schitt’s Creek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;Jim Parsons, Hollywood&lt;br&gt;Donald Sutherland, &lt;em&gt;The Undoing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="2K8wXk"&gt;Cecil B. deMille Award&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="lv2coH"&gt;Jane Fonda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="DrO0eu"&gt;Carol Burnett Award&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="2xOBMK"&gt;Norman Lear&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9QVOlP"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vox Media has affiliate partnerships. These do not influence editorial content, though Vox Media may earn commissions for products purchased via affiliate links. For more information, see &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/ethics-statement"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;our ethics policy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fjg0oF"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/28/22305793/golden-globes-2021-live-stream-how-to-watch-start-time"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/28/22305793/golden-globes-2021-live-stream-how-to-watch-start-time</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-28T12:23:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-28T12:23:47-05:00</updated>
    <title>Verizon support says you should turn off 5G to save your phone’s battery</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="In this photo illustration the Verizon Communications logo seen displayed on a smartphone with the 5G inscription background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XYLHsvbhArPFRlGPayxGnme_6xc=/0x0:5000x3333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68887873/1227822210.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Rafael Henrique/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SwJAmv"&gt;Despite its relentless promotion of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22194419/5g-phone-plans-us-carriers-guide"&gt;5G phones&lt;/a&gt; and the fact that it spent more than &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299903/fcc-cband-auction-results-verizon-att-tmobile"&gt;$45 billion bidding&lt;/a&gt; on a new faster spectrum, Verizon support now is advising people on Twitter to turn off their phones’ 5G access to preserve battery life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P1vDDR"&gt;In a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/VZWSupport/status/1366055566347546635?s=20"&gt;Sunday morning tweet&lt;/a&gt;, Verizon support helpfully suggested that “one way to help conserve battery life is to turn on LTE” if users found their batteries were “draining faster than normal.” That step would, of course, turn off 5G in a phone that has it available. It’s also worth pointing out that you don’t actually “turn on LTE” when doing this step — LTE is always enabled as a fallback for the 5G network. But Verizon is obviously being cautious so as not to actually tell its customers to “turn off 5G”.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fAfQh69dqwsWSeWwmy_E0WegA_U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22334862/verizon_says_turn_off_5g.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="GIze4C"&gt;Twitter users naturally pointed out that switching to LTE-only would mean turning off 5G (which is available in some newer phones), but the helpful support person said it was important to troubleshoot “steps to find the root cause of any issues with speed,” adding that Verizon is “quickly launching more 5G areas, and making updates constantly to improve speeds.” Verizon’s nationwide 5G network uses a technology called DSS, which in many instances is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22292074/5g-nationwide-verizon-att-tmobile-c-band"&gt;actually slower than the LTE network&lt;/a&gt; it’s trying to replace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JXMAO1"&gt;Verizon announced its big 5G plans for 2021 last month, after formally launching its next-gen network in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21509364/verizon-5g-network-ultra-wideband-nationwide-apple-event"&gt;October 2020&lt;/a&gt;.  One of its top priorities is expanding coverage of its ultra-fast mmWave coverage, which is currently restricted to parts of some cities in the US. It’s also heavily dependent on how close you are to a Verizon 5G site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="jauZ6Q"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"5G in the US is disappointing right now, but it’s going to get better","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22292074/5g-nationwide-verizon-att-tmobile-c-band"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="oxXD2Q"&gt;Both Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T spent big bucks in the FCC’s Auction 107, bidding on the C-band spectrum. Verizon spent $45.4 billion— twice as much as AT&amp;amp;T’s $23.4 billion. AT&amp;amp;T’s current nationwide 5G network also relies on DSS with speeds close to or lower than 4G LTE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3ottI2"&gt;The new frequencies won’t become available until the end of the 2021 at the earliest, and will be available in limited locations first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LMmHq3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/28/22305899/verizon-support-turn-off-5g-save-phone-battery"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/28/22305899/verizon-support-turn-off-5g-save-phone-battery</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-28T09:28:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-28T09:28:38-05:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung’s shiny red Galaxy Chromebook 2 is now available at Best Buy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eX4Owb7wkhtBqCERNzOt03iUIrU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68887390/bfarsace190331_4355_0008.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Samsung Galaxy Chromebook 2 | Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OO3OOg"&gt;Samsung’s latest Chrome OS laptop, the Galaxy Chromebook 2, is &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1733322550682053658" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;now available for purchase at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. The Chromebook 2 was first announced at CES in January and features a new QLED display, 360-degree hinge, and a striking red paint job. It starts at $549.99 for a Celeron model and goes up to $699.99 for a Core i3 version, putting it at the higher end of Chromebooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xfKjrF"&gt;That price is the most significant thing about the Chromebook 2 because it’s considerably less than the Galaxy Chromebook that debuted a year ago. The older Chromebook had an 4K OLED screen and came with a stylus — neither of which you’ll fine with the new model — but it also cost just under $1,000 when it came out. In our review, we found despite the gorgeous screen and striking paint job, the original Galaxy Chromebook didn’t justify its cost, particularly thanks to abysmal battery life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ld3ze5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10366068"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="46EIGp"&gt;We’ve yet to put the new Chromebook 2 through its paces, but we did get to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22217002/samsung-galaxy-chromebook-2-price-release-date-hands-on-chrome-os-photos-video"&gt;see the machine in person&lt;/a&gt; back in January and it certainly seems like it will be competent. The QLED screen isn’t quite up to the marks of the OLED panel, but you’d be hard-pressed to notice without putting them side-by-side, and the rest of the Chromebook 2’s fit and finish are appropriate for the price Samsung is asking. Importantly, it still comes in that amazing red color, as well. You might notice the extra weight — the Chromebook 2 is about half a pound heavier — but it still falls under three pounds total and should be easily portable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Yom0rz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Samsung Galaxy Chromebook 2 hands-on: promisingly boring","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22217002/samsung-galaxy-chromebook-2-price-release-date-hands-on-chrome-os-photos-video"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="9ZFMuA"&gt;We will have a full review of the Chromebook 2 in the near future, but if you don’t want to wait and grab one yourself, you might be able to find one in stock at your local Best Buy right now. Let’s just hope Samsung improved the battery life over last time.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/28/22305763/samsung-galaxy-chromebook-2-now-available-best-buy-price-specs-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/28/22305763/samsung-galaxy-chromebook-2-now-available-best-buy-price-specs-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-28T09:05:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-28T09:05:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>Disinformation experts aren’t happy about the trailer for HBO’s QAnon series</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Supporters of former President Donald Trump flew a US flag with a QAnon symbol outside the Capitol on January 6th." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d9ovpbX3cv_4YKMvs-dwDU-i3yU=/0x2:8192x5463/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68887356/1294904312.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Supporters of former President Donald Trump flew a US flag with a QAnon symbol outside the Capitol on January 6th. | Photo by Win McNamee/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JFJCzT"&gt;The teaser video for Q: &lt;em&gt;Into the Storm&lt;/em&gt;, an upcoming documentary series from HBO about the QAnon conspiracy movement has a lot of deplatforming experts concerned; it looks more like a preview for a spy thriller than a careful examination of the umbrella group of conspiracy theories. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="11uYj7"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U2ftSMchz40?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sA756Y"&gt;The breathless tone might be effective at building hype, but it has many disinformation experts concerned. Ben Collins, one of the leading journalists covering online radicalization, tweeted that the trailer was “being marketed in a way that could recruit more people.” Promoted by HBO as a series that “charts a labyrinthine journey to unmask the mastermind behind QAnon,” critics pointed out that the trailer felt a lot like “&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/soundmigration/status/1365393034351943680"&gt;a recruitment video for Q.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="aY5EdJ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;disinfo community: *soberly* how do we balance coverage and inadvertent amplification of QAnon? How do we bring people back to reality in a smart, empathetic way? &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;HBO: *BRAAAAM (inception sounds)* watch our $30m documentary on how QAnon is HARDCORE and FUCKING CRAZY!!! &lt;a href="https://t.co/HXfoDPPzjr"&gt;https://t.co/HXfoDPPzjr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Emerson T. Brooking (@etbrooking) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/etbrooking/status/1365398029122080770?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 26, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2CFm3E"&gt;Joan Donovan, research director at the Shorenstein Center on Media, Politics and Public Policy at Harvard, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that, by portraying Q as edgy and exciting, the trailer risked attracting even more people to the cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qLFI7i"&gt;“The most concerning aspect to me is that the reuse of footage found online pieced together in 6 hours of conspiracist content will be validation for the contemporary movement and drive more content/interest,” Donovan said in a message to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “It’s not like we are 5 years from the insurrection. Q influencers will use the fact of their participation in the documentary to sap more people for donations and build a more loyal audience at a time when many are struggling to contain this anti-Semitic and racist networked conspiracy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zM7D9v"&gt;It’s hard to say how much of those concerns will carry over to the documentary itself. The trailer is less than a minute long, and the docuseries was the result of a three-year global investigation, according to HBO. So it’s possible the series strikes the right tone in how it presents QAnon and its origins, as well as its future. &lt;a href="https://pressroom.warnermedia.com/us/media-release/hbo-0/hbos-q-storm-six-part-documentary-series-exploring-origins-qanon-debuts-march-21"&gt;The press release announcing&lt;/a&gt; the series says it will “examine the influence of QAnon on American culture and question the consequences of unfettered free speech permeating the darkest corners of the Internet.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nhk3DS"&gt;Donovan said she hoped the trailer was a hoax, and that the actual film will show people speaking about how believing in QAnon ruined their relationships with their families and friends, but she wasn’t optimistic. “Somehow I doubt that will be the case,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pFth4k"&gt;QAnon began on 4chan in 2017, when an anonymous person posting as “Q Clearance Patriot” said they had access to classified information showing then-President Donald Trump was fighting a global cabal of pedophiles, whose ranks included celebrities and Democratic politicians. QAnon’s followers also strongly ascribed to the view —falsely pushed by Trump— that the 2020 presidential election was stolen, and many Q proponents have been linked to the January 6th attack on the US Capitol. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5LsJrX"&gt;Journalists have struggled with how to best cover QAnon; reporting on it without being adequately up to speed, news outlets ran the risk of amplifying and legitimizing some of the group’s more dangerous views. At the same time, ignoring QAnon’s followers or dismissing them as fringe could allow it to metastasize. One of HBO’s promotions for &lt;em&gt;Q: Into the Storm&lt;/em&gt; promised that the series will “pull back the curtain” on the group, but without the right context, could further muddy the public’s understanding of QAnon and its reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t4NNPG"&gt;During its heyday, there were thousands of Q-related Facebook groups and Q-related accounts on Twitter and Reddit. Most platforms have banned, or tried to ban, Q-related content and hashtags, but with mixed success.  “QAnon depends on centuries-old anti-Jewish tropes and anti-Black narratives about the modern civil rights movement,” Donovan says. “But it’s not that complicated.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pUFhHy"&gt;HBO declined to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XK5qo4"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qry8bW"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/28/22304518/hbo-trailer-upcoming-qanon-movie-disinformation-researchers"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/28/22304518/hbo-trailer-upcoming-qanon-movie-disinformation-researchers</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-27T18:20:51-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-27T18:20:51-05:00</updated>
    <title>FDA authorizes one-dose COVID-19 vaccine</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="In this photo illustration a Johnson &amp;amp;amp; Johnson logo is seen..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ugASOKRvzskno9r_I235MW3mqEA=/0x0:4896x3264/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68885973/1230992810.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Pavlo Gonchar/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fsMnHh"&gt;The Food and Drug Administration &lt;a href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/fda-issues-emergency-use-authorization-third-covid-19-vaccine"&gt;has authorized&lt;/a&gt; the Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson COVID-19 vaccine, which only needs one dose and can be stored in regular refrigerators. It’s the third COVID-19 vaccine to get sign-off from the agency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zatfYB"&gt;The vaccine can be administered to people 18 years and older. It &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22298855/covid-vaccine-johnson-effective-fda-south-africa-variant"&gt;protects against serious disease&lt;/a&gt;, and clinical trials did not flag any dangerous safety problems. In the United States, it was 72 percent effective against severe and milder COVID-19. It was slightly less effective in South Africa, where a variant form of the coronavirus is widespread. Early data also suggested that the shot might prevent asymptomatic infections, but researchers need more data before they can say that for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="CZgDDN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9360449"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5KObJb"&gt;The Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson vaccine is logistically easier to distribute than the Moderna and Pfizer / BioNTech vaccines, which take two doses and have to be stored in specialized freezers. Because it only takes one shot and doesn’t need to be frozen, the Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson vaccine would be easier to distribute to areas without that type of equipment. People also don’t have to come back for a second appointment. New York City officials hope to use this vaccine for &lt;a href="https://gothamist.com/news/de-blasio-hopes-johnson-johnson-covid-19-vaccine-will-supercharge-campaign-to-reach-more-seniors"&gt;homebound seniors&lt;/a&gt; because it can more be easily brought door to door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f74O2S"&gt;The Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson vaccine was built using a different technology than the Moderna and Pfizer / BioNTech vaccines. Those two are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21562309/pfizer-coronavirus-vaccine-gene-based"&gt;gene-based vaccines&lt;/a&gt;, a strategy that directly delivers the genetic material for a bit of the coronavirus into the body. The Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson vaccine, on the other hand, inserts a section of the coronavirus’ gene into &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/22/21266897/coronavirus-vaccine-development-strategies-pros-cons"&gt;another harmless virus&lt;/a&gt;. That virus, called an adenovirus, delivers the coronavirus gene to cells so that the body can learn to recognize it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j2BJVk"&gt;It’s &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nature.com%2Farticles%2Fd41586-021-00409-0&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F27%2F22301558%2Fcovid-vaccine-one-dose-johnson-fda-approval" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;hard to directly compare COVID-19 vaccines&lt;/a&gt; because no clinical trials have studied them head-to-head. The Moderna and Pfizer / BioNTech vaccines have higher efficacy on paper. Clinical trials found that they were around 95 percent protective against symptomatic COVID-19. But those vaccines were tested at different times and in different countries. The Moderna and Pfizer / BioNTech trials were tested in the US and other countries before variants appeared. The trials also use different definitions for what counts as mild, moderate, or severe disease. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cd1kYl"&gt;By one important measure, the vaccines are all pretty comparable: the Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson vaccine was just as good as the other two at protecting people from being hospitalized or dying from COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J10UQT"&gt;“What you care about is hospitalizations and deaths,” said Ashish Jha, dean of the Brown University School of Public Health, in &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/coronavirus-live-updates/2021/02/22/970235986/why-the-johnson-johnson-vaccine-has-gotten-a-bad-rap-and-why-thats-not-fair"&gt;an interview with &lt;em&gt;NPR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “And Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson appears to be just as good as Moderna and Pfizer at preventing those.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="37WCiT"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/covid-vaccine-johnson-and-johnson-short-doses/"&gt;Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson&lt;/a&gt; has around 4 million doses, enough for 4 million people, ready to ship in the US. That’s fewer than expected; the company originally said it could have 12 million ready by the end of February. &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/13/health/covid-vaccine-johnson-johnson.html"&gt;Manufacturing delays&lt;/a&gt; undercut that plan. The company says it will still be able to provide 20 million doses to the US by the end of March and 100 million by the end of June. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tFKabS"&gt;Over 48 million people in the United States have already received at least one dose of a COVID-19 vaccine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HDbDkB"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/27/22301558/covid-vaccine-one-dose-johnson-fda-approval"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/27/22301558/covid-vaccine-one-dose-johnson-fda-approval</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-27T13:31:54-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-27T13:31:54-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft’s Xbox Game Streaming app for Windows includes touch controls, gyro, and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/J24j0lghN4ZZJ9u6fmWtLDJhHpo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68885240/acastro_180604_1777_xbox_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nb0i3t"&gt;Microsoft is finalizing its Xbox Game Streaming app for Windows PCs, which includes access to streaming games from the company’s xCloud service. We’ve managed to get access to the latest version of the Xbox Game Streaming app for Windows, an unannounced and unreleased app. Once released, the app will let Windows users stream games from their Xbox Series S / X consoles, and from xCloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ebYKjL"&gt;Currently, you can’t stream games from the new Xbox consoles to Windows PCs, as this is unsupported in the existing Xbox Console Companion app. This new app will solve that, and also bring xCloud streaming to Windows PCs for the first time. We first got a look at this &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/15/22283739/microsoft-xcloud-web-screenshots-cloud-gaming-streaming-browser-features"&gt;xCloud app for Windows last year&lt;/a&gt;, and it has improved a lot since then. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="QIDTML"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;scoop: here's a look at Microsoft's unreleased xCloud app for Windows. This app lets you stream Xbox games from an Xbox Series X / S console, or from xCloud. Full details here: &lt;a href="https://t.co/ymyjQDmaeH"&gt;https://t.co/ymyjQDmaeH&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/V3U3PXe7LO"&gt;pic.twitter.com/V3U3PXe7LO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Tom Warren (@tomwarren) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/1365731532376317963?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 27, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7SaR93"&gt;The Xbox remote play feature, for connecting to Xbox consoles, works similarly to how the existing Console Companion does. You can remotely wake an Xbox console, sign in, and play games wherever you are. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="je8b5J"&gt;There is now full touch support, allowing Surface or other touchscreen devices to play Xbox games without a controller. Microsoft also appears to be readying some form of gyro support here, too. There’s an option to enable this, but it doesn’t appear to be fully functional yet. This is an internal beta application, so it’s still unfinished.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MGV3gpzp0ZuGNZyINt-ERTLYGkI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22333440/VlCW8k5.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft’s unreleased Xbox Game Streaming app.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="IWMHkx"&gt;Microsoft also appears to be readying 1080p streams for xCloud, instead of the 720p that exists today. This would obviously improve the experience on Windows PCs, ahead of higher resolutions once Microsoft has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/18/21295326/microsoft-project-xcloud-xbox-series-x-servers-hardware-2021"&gt;upgraded its xCloud servers to include Xbox Series X hardware&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hQaU3o"&gt;It’s still not clear exactly when this app will be made available more broadly. Microsoft is &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thurrott/status/1365308039725735936"&gt;rumored to be planning&lt;/a&gt; a “what’s new for gaming” event for next month, so it’s possible we’ll hear a lot more about the company’s xCloud plans (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/15/22283739/microsoft-xcloud-web-screenshots-cloud-gaming-streaming-browser-features"&gt;for the web and iOS&lt;/a&gt;, too) very soon.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/27/22304762/microsoft-xcloud-app-windows-xbox-touch-controls-gyro-support"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/27/22304762/microsoft-xcloud-app-windows-xbox-touch-controls-gyro-support</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-27T12:09:41-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-27T12:09:41-05:00</updated>
    <title>Judge approves $650 million Facebook privacy settlement over facial recognition feature</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zLev8oIHMvhfAzsoUQnqRWiptS8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68885045/acastro_180522_facebook_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IFxSiV"&gt;A federal judge on Friday &lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22333300/In_re_Facebook_Biometric_Information_Privacy_Litigation_final_order.pdf"&gt;gave final approval&lt;/a&gt; to a $650 million Facebook class action privacy settlement and ordered the 1.6 million members of the class in Illinois who submitted claims to be paid “as expeditiously as possible.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tsrAsC"&gt;Chicago attorney Jay Edelson sued Facebook in Cook County Circuit Court back in 2015, alleging that the platform’s use of facial recognition tagging was not allowed under the Illinois Biometric Information Privacy Act. The lawsuit claimed that Facebook’s Tag Suggestions tool, which scanned faces in users’ photos and offered suggestions about who the person might be, stored biometric data without users’ consent in violation of the Illinois law. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FxNNey"&gt;The case became &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/17/17246222/facebook-bipa-fines-penalty-tag-suggestions-facial-recognition"&gt;a class action lawsuit in 2018&lt;/a&gt;. In 2019, Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/3/20847650/facebook-facial-recognition-setting-default-opt-in"&gt;made facial recognition on the platform opt-in only&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lcCjtS"&gt;The three named plaintiffs in the suit will each receive $5,000 and others in the class will get at least $345 each, according to the order by Judge James Donato of the Northern District of California. Donato said the settlement was a “landmark result” and a “major win for consumers in the hotly contested area of digital privacy.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q9xWev"&gt;“We are pleased to have reached a settlement so we can move past this matter, which is in the best interest of our community and our shareholders,” Facebook &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/technology-business-san-francisco-chicago-lawsuits-af6b42212e43be1b63b5c290eb5bfd85"&gt;said in a statement&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RG2jKs"&gt;“It’s a big deal,” Edelson told &lt;a href="https://www.chicagotribune.com/business/ct-biz-facebook-privacy-settlement-approval-20210227-okljqhsiargl7ijvzzfcotpyby-story.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Chicago Tribune&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “It sends a pretty clear message that in Illinois, biometric privacy rights are here to stay.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/27/22304618/judge-approves-facebook-privacy-settlement-illinois-facial-recognition"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/27/22304618/judge-approves-facebook-privacy-settlement-illinois-facial-recognition</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
