<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-06-12T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-12T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-12T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>You can get some great tech and game deals ahead of Prime Day</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IWuEmoeuuKdtMwXlI2LJ0lCq_fc=/0x1:1137x759/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69443721/samsungq70ahero.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="J9ZKiV"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22459166/amazon-prime-day-dates-2021-june-21-22"&gt;Prime Day 2021&lt;/a&gt; is happening in just a little over a week, kicking off on Monday, June 21st, and lasting through Tuesday, June 22nd. In addition to keeping up with our regular deals cadence each day, we’ve been working hard behind the curtain to ensure that we’ll be able to bring you the best Prime Day coverage out there once it starts. To that end, we’re updating each of our useful deal guides, so you’ll be able to tell more easily when something that we recommend is discounted. We recently updated our guide to helping you find the best deals on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22307388/wireless-earbuds-deals-airpods-galaxy-buds-powerbeats"&gt;wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt;, for instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wnRd2b"&gt;It’s going to be a busy but great week ahead for deals. If you’re looking for savings, you’ll definitely want to see what’s coming on Prime Day, whether it’s at Amazon or at other retailers like Best Buy, Walmart, and Target. Until then, I’m going to give you what you came for: the best deals of the week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="OoZJsH"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="5zuwAe"&gt;Get $700 in gifts cards when you buy Samsung’s 85-inch Q70A QLED TV&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="OSxPt4"&gt;At Best Buy, you can get $700 in gift cards when you purchase Samsung’s 85-inch Q70A QLED TV. Originally $3,300, recent price cuts have reduced it to $2,800. Best Buy gifts cards obviously aren’t as good as a cash discount, but once factored in, it’s like getting this gargantuan, but very thin TV for $2,100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UK1DOn"&gt;This model has a 4K 120Hz refresh rate panel and it supports FreeSync, variable refresh rate and auto low-latency mode. It features an HDMI 2.1 port to allow PC and Xbox Series X to display games at up to 4K resolution at 120 frames per second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xXqHgU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10603517"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="F36KX5"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="WnBs98"&gt;Amazon’s Echo Show 5 is just $50 right now&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="hysBf5"&gt;You can stretch $50 pretty far these days, especially on tech. One way to spend your $50 is on Amazon’s first-generation Echo Show 5 smart display. It can display the time, weather, video content, and more. You can also hop on a video chat with its built-in camera and microphones. These originally sold for $90, but you can get one for nearly half the cost right now at one of the retailers below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="fNcjDa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513095"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="dwKocr"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="4Ta92i"&gt;Roku’s capable Ultra streaming box is $30 off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="MPyBss"&gt;If you’re in the market for a new streaming device that supports 4K output with Dolby Vision and HDR 10 as well as Atmos compatibility, Roku’s Ultra at $69 is a great value right now. I can’t forget to mention that the Ultra has an ethernet port, so you can get full speeds for streaming 4K content if your wireless network isn’t up to snuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="rfhAb8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10518754"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="f3sGc9"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Control" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/08uR2eJiVXuOSxa81QyzIZzNVxs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/20062302/control.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="8l1nEJ"&gt;Remedy’s &lt;em&gt;Control &lt;/em&gt;for PC is free at the Epic Game Store&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="3JKmPS"&gt;There’s a new free game at the Epic Games Store nearly every week, &lt;a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/p/control"&gt;and this week’s title is &lt;em&gt;Control&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. That info alone is enough for some people to just go ahead and click the link to grab the game. If you need a little more convincing, it’s a third-person action game in which  you investigate an otherworldly presence that has taken over a fictional version of the FBI. In addition to being a fun game to play, it’s got some dollops of &lt;em&gt;X-Files&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Twin Peaks&lt;/em&gt; inspiration in there, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GrfV4K"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/6/12/22529879/samsung-qled-q70a-amazon-echo-show-control-roku-ultra-streaming-gaming-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/6/12/22529879/samsung-qled-q70a-amazon-echo-show-control-roku-ultra-streaming-gaming-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-12T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-12T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon Echo Show 5 (second gen) review: small screen, small updates</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Amazon’s smallest smart display has gotten the tiniest of refreshes&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="wL02c4"&gt;Amazon recently updated a couple of its Alexa-based Echo Show smart displays. The new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22521948/amazon-echo-show-8-2nd-gen-2021-review"&gt;Echo Show 8 (second gen)&lt;/a&gt; saw a couple of enhancements over its predecessor, but the smaller Echo Show 5 has received an even smaller refresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Dg4dV"&gt;There are only three basic changes in the new &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/All-new-Echo-Show-5-2nd-Gen-2021-release-dp-B08KJN3333/dp/B08J8H8L5T?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$84.99 Echo Show 5 (2nd Gen)&lt;/a&gt;: it has a 2-megapixel camera instead of the 1-megapixel sensor of the first model; it comes in blue as well as the black and white color options; and the 3.5mm output jack on the back is gone. Unlike the larger Echo Show 8, the new 5 didn’t get a new processor, and its camera doesn’t feature the automatic panning and cropping that the Echo Show 8 and 10 offer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ofY0wY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10602714"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nancLy"&gt;That means that this new model provides effectively the same experience as the prior generation. It’s a compact smart display that’s best used as a smart alarm clock or a desk companion in a home office. The 5.5-inch 960 x 480-pixel touchscreen is bright and colorful, but not as easy to read from across the room as Amazon’s larger smart displays. It works as a monitor for a security camera or video doorbell, but I wouldn’t want to watch much video on it — your phone is a better device for that. If you insist, the Echo Show 5 supports Amazon Prime Video, Netflix, and YouTube via its browser, but not as many video services as the larger models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FxFoJKj27YiCmyTnBs4oIqch3Mo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653348/dseifert_4630_amazon_echo_show_5_2nd_gen_10.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new Echo Show 5 is available in blue, in addition to white or black.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T7Wpy12qv80d3zHEjK2SaCcazbE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653351/dseifert_4630_amazon_echo_show_5_2nd_gen_9.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 5’s camera has been upgraded to 2 megapixels, but it’s still not great. Fortunately, you can block it with the built-in privacy shutter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fRXXzK"&gt;The single speaker inside the wedge design gets surprisingly loud and puts out more bass than expected for its size, but it won’t as easily fill a room with sound. It works great for a morning alarm or listening to a podcast at a desk. The Echo Show 5 also has a handy feature that lets you tap the top of the device to snooze an alarm, which is easier than trying to say “Alexa snooze” when you’re half awake. (The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22357214/google-nest-hub-2nd-gen-2021-assistant-smart-display-review"&gt;Google Nest Hub’s&lt;/a&gt; ability to just stop the alarm with a single word, or to snooze when you wave your hand in front of it, is still better, though.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XzBMOL"&gt;Though the camera in the new model is 2 megapixels instead of 1, that’s not a huge upgrade. The Echo Show 5 doesn’t support Zoom, so you can’t use it for work calls, but it’s fine for calling from one Alexa smart display to another or to the Alexa app on a phone. Perhaps a more useful feature is the ability to view the camera’s feed through the Alexa app, so you can see what’s going on at home when you’re gone. If you don’t want to use the camera at all, you can block its view with the built-in privacy shutter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="10Lar9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Amazon’s new Echo Show 8 is a little faster and has a better camera","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22521948/amazon-echo-show-8-2nd-gen-2021-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="uabtP8"&gt;Since the second-gen Echo Show 5 has the same processor as the last model, it’s not any faster. Of Amazon’s smart display lineup, it’s certainly the pokiest, taking the most time to load a video feed from a security camera and taking an extra beat or two to pull up different screens or menus when you interact with it. Most people will probably not find that to be a problem, but if you were hoping for a speed increase this time around, sadly there isn’t one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R2fK2WiPef33PFDkDrBiJ-vjWz8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653346/dseifert_4630_amazon_echo_show_5_2nd_gen_12.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Kids Edition Echo Show 5 comes in a unique chameleon color.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ha2tClCh-INTLP5M4gjzLCgY84s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653342/dseifert_4630_amazon_echo_show_5_2nd_gen_16.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Kids Plus service that comes with the Kids Edition limits what can be played on the device.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TluHbV"&gt;Along with the standard Echo Show 5, Amazon is also now selling a Kids Edition model for $10 more. That gets you a custom blue-green-yellow chameleon color, a year’s subscription to the Kids Plus service, and a two-year warranty against accidental breakage. (A two-year damage warranty for a device that is supposed to stay put on a shelf or dresser doesn’t seem very valuable to me, but I’m sure some kid out there will find a way to break the thing.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wCq8tg"&gt;The Kids Plus service on the Echo Show is similar to what’s available on Amazon’s Fire HD Kids Edition tablets. It allows parents to customize which content and features are available on the devices and tailor them to their child’s age. It will play music from Amazon Music and won’t allow explicit tracks. It also removes certain features like smart home controls from the Show’s touch interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JYTjMT"&gt;On the tablets, it’s possible to have multiple profiles that can be switched between different kids, but the Echo Show doesn’t support that. If you’re planning to have more than one kid share it, you have to set the limitations to the age range of just one.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RmegLe4QIwWgtm5qQ8hwoprOd5g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22653355/dseifert_4630_amazon_echo_show_5_2nd_gen_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new Echo Show 5 is effectively the same as the prior model﻿.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="DRFe2N"&gt;In all, the new Echo Show 5 (and its Kids Edition derivative) is basically the same as the prior model. It’s still a handy, compact smart display for a nightstand or desk, but it’s not as capable or fast as the larger Echo models in Amazon’s lineup. Given the limitations with the camera, I would be more interested in a model without a camera at all, similar to Google’s Nest Hub, as the bedroom alarm clock is the ideal use case here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V9atOn"&gt;At $84.99, the new model is $5 less expensive than its predecessor at launch, but Amazon frequently discounts its Echo devices and you’ll likely be able to find it for less than its retail price quite often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MDcCdl"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="TkRQZ9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10602736"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22529891/amazon-echo-show-5-2nd-gen-alexa-smart-display-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22529891/amazon-echo-show-5-2nd-gen-alexa-smart-display-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-12T08:21:21-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-12T08:21:21-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nintendo leaks new Mario + Rabbids game on its own website</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/shPwgPWpxQp2rx4UrOUa9o-nOZ8=/0x0:920x613/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69443648/mr.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="d2Iv7P"&gt;Ubisoft’s Mario and Rabbids crossover turn-based strategy game is getting a sequel, according to Nintendo’s website. The unannounced game is currently &lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/mario-plus-rabbids-sparks-of-hope-switch/"&gt;listed on its own page&lt;/a&gt; as “&lt;em&gt;Mario + Rabbids: Sparks of Hope&lt;/em&gt;” together with some key art, three screenshots, and a release date of 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BExQR9"&gt;Ubisoft’s E3 press conference is happening at 3PM ET today, Saturday June 12th, and the new game was presumably set to be announced there. The first &lt;em&gt;Mario + Rabbids&lt;/em&gt; title, &lt;em&gt;Kingdom Battle&lt;/em&gt;, was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/6/12/15749998/nintendo-ubisoft-e3-2017-mario-rabbids-kingdom-battle-trailer"&gt;originally revealed&lt;/a&gt; by Nintendo’s Shigeru Miyamoto at Ubisoft’s press conference at E3 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="zjTt5J"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Mario + Rabbids is a shockingly good Nintendo Switch strategy game","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2017/8/28/16214482/mario-rabbids-kingdom-battle-nintendo-switch-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="6xhFle"&gt;Despite the bizarre nature of its IP mashup, &lt;em&gt;Kingdom Battle&lt;/em&gt; was one of the best early Switch games, mixing elements of the Mario and Rabbids characters with solid yet accessible &lt;em&gt;X-COM&lt;/em&gt;-style tactical action. We called it “a shockingly good Nintendo Switch strategy game” in our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/8/28/16214482/mario-rabbids-kingdom-battle-nintendo-switch-review"&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rBEv1f"&gt;It’s not necessarily surprising that a well-received game would get a sequel a few years later, but this is an uncharacteristic mistake from Nintendo. Here’s how the &lt;em&gt;Sparks of Hope&lt;/em&gt; page appears on Nintendo’s website right now:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UaNgv9uJ1ZpZvEOkr_iD7U4QXbM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22654487/Screenshot_2021_06_12_at_21.00.50.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="oQsYgP"&gt;And here are the three screenshots:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wNLrZUWf2LnDHKYjAWA5vcNYGoQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22654490/screenshot01.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5I5MA28k6ct7_DG1n6I3AsKB6J4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22654491/screenshot02.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KTdSK_t2z1ZBTFOn3EwkjXL6Z8w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22654492/screenshot03.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="BUtx8Y"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mario + Rabbids: Sparks of Hope &lt;/em&gt;could, of course, also be officially announced at Nintendo’s own E3 event. That one’s happening at 12PM ET on Tuesday, June 15th — and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22465864/e3-schedule-time-date-live-stream-how-to-watch"&gt;here’s our guide to everything else going on at E3 2021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22530737/mario-rabbids-sparks-of-hope-nintendo-leak-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22530737/mario-rabbids-sparks-of-hope-nintendo-leak-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-12T08:13:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-12T08:13:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nvidia to drop Windows 7 and Windows 8 driver support in October</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="nvidia, nvidiastock" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bSf7kGgz2Vr1q8ieR-nSvLzHQ2s=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69443642/DSC00697.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Sam Byford / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Q4IUA7"&gt;Nvidia is planning to drop support for Windows 7, Windows 8, and Windows 8.1 later this year. Nvidia drivers will be exclusively available for Windows 10 in October, with only critical security updates available on Windows 7, Windows 8, and Windows 8.1 through September 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AtKTuL"&gt;Microsoft has already dropped support  for Windows 7 and Windows 8, and even the extended support for Windows 8.1 will end in January 2023. “The vast majority of our GeForce customers have migrated to Windows 10 OS,” reads a &lt;a href="https://nvidia.custhelp.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/5201/related/1"&gt;support note from Nvidia&lt;/a&gt;. “In order to ensure GeForce owners experience the best possible security, support, and functionality, Nvidia will now focus on Windows 10 operating system.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RzqS8k"&gt;There are now 1.3 billion active Windows 10 devices, but Windows 7 is still in use in many parts of the world. &lt;a href="https://gs.statcounter.com/os-version-market-share/windows/desktop/worldwide"&gt;Statcounter estimates&lt;/a&gt; that Windows 7 still accounts for 15 percent of all Windows versions. Windows 10 dominates &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/hwsurvey/Steam-Hardware-Software-Survey-Welcome-to-Steam"&gt;Steam usage&lt;/a&gt; though, making up nearly 93 percent with Windows 7 at just under 2 percent. Microsoft is also expected to launch a new version of Windows, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/3/22466394/microsoft-windows-11-launch-teaser-rumors"&gt;likely to be named Windows 11&lt;/a&gt;, in October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ipdbv3"&gt;Nvidia’s last driver to officially support these old versions of Windows will be made available on August 31st, with an October 4th release being the first to only support Windows 10.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22530738/nvidia-windows-7-windows-8-driver-support-end-october-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/12/22530738/nvidia-windows-7-windows-8-driver-support-end-october-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-11T20:18:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T20:18:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple rubberstamped Trump’s request to secretly scoop up data on two members of Congress</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wxb5CmJPhMnhWOoqpeb-NdvtPNk=/0x336:4032x3024/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69442683/B2E53F34_14F4_4895_AECA_E72D86070E7C.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Steve Jobs Theater at Apple’s Apple Park headquarters.&lt;/em&gt; | Dieter Bohn / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FBbcJ8"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/11/technology/apple-google-leak-investigation-data-requests.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times &lt;/em&gt;is reporting&lt;/a&gt; on a new wrinkle in the story of how the Trump administration’s Department of Justice used Big Tech &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22528853/trump-force-apple-democrat-house-intelligence-committee-data"&gt;to spy on two members of the House Intelligence Committee&lt;/a&gt; in an attempt to track down leaks to the press — namely, that Apple didn’t fight it, perhaps never had a chance to fight it, because the company rubberstamped the request. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="rGvdjG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Trump administration forced Apple to secretly reveal at least two Democrats’ data","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22528853/trump-force-apple-democrat-house-intelligence-committee-data"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="13T3Uy"&gt;Apple didn’t even know it was handing over the records of Congressman Adam Schiff (D-CA), then the ranking member of the House Intelligence Committee, it told the publication. In a statement, Apple said it didn’t know what the investigation was about, and couldn’t have known unless it dug through user accounts itself. So it was handled like the vast majority of the 250 requests the company received from the government each week: approved. “An Apple paralegal complied and provided the information,” reports the &lt;em&gt;NYT&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nWJTaa"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Apple did not realize that data on two Democratic lawmakers was part of a request by the Trump Justice Department. It was handled by a paralegal like a routine request.&lt;a href="https://t.co/kS51EUmnCp"&gt;https://t.co/kS51EUmnCp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Jack Nicas (@jacknicas) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jacknicas/status/1403471132435623936?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="myl4ao"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;More details: The grand jury subpoena sought metadata for 109 identifiers, specifically 73 phone numbers and 36 email addresses. Apple said it assumes ISPs and other tech companies were also sent similar requests. Apple now limits identifiers to 25 or less.&lt;/p&gt;— Zack Whittaker (@zackwhittaker) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/zackwhittaker/status/1403476908789178375?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9KULPB"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Times’ &lt;/em&gt;piece paints a picture of a US government whose requests have been increasing in volume, and perhaps a general willingness by Big Tech to comply (not that these companies often have a choice). Apple challenged only 4 percent of this sort of request in the first six months of 2020, according to the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;. And while Google fought a gag order when the Trump administration seized the phone records of &lt;em&gt;NYT &lt;/em&gt;reporters, the story suggests it was easier to challenge because Google counted the NYT as a corporate customer, not an individual user. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sLMN3L"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/legal/transparency/us.html"&gt;Both Apple&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://transparencyreport.google.com/user-data/overview?hl=en&amp;amp;user_requests_report_period=series:requests,accounts;authority:US;time:&amp;amp;lu=user_requests_report_period"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; have transparency report pages where you can see how many government requests they received, and how often they comply. Apple didn’t reply to our request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="If2jF8"&gt;Microsoft was also swept up in Trump’s leak hunt. It told the &lt;em&gt;NYT&lt;/em&gt; that it, too, only learned that it had provided information to the government about a congressional staff member after a gag order expired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hzJtqP"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RPiZb9"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YkxpTv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22530359/trump-leak-hunt-apple-google-microsoft-subpoena"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22530359/trump-leak-hunt-apple-google-microsoft-subpoena</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-11T19:30:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T19:30:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to watch E3 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oa1-khhYmtqlpCAP5VnzRqPRboc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69386792/acastro_180604_1777_E3_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VC1JN5"&gt;E3 2021 is finally here. After being canceled last year due to the COVID-19 pandemic, E3 is back for 2021 in an all-digital format, &lt;a href="https://e3expo.com/news/e3-news/e3-2021-schedule-and-fan-registration"&gt;kicking off on June 12th&lt;/a&gt;. Some big reveals have already hit — although technically not a part of E3, Thursday’s Summer Game Fest’s Kickoff Live event was packed with news, including a trailer and release date for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22307059/elden-ring-george-rr-martin-fromsoftware-e3-2021-trailer-gameplay"&gt;highly-anticipated &lt;em&gt;Elden Ring&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and the announcement of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22528209/death-stranding-directors-cut-ps5-hideo-kojima"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Death Stranding: Director’s Cut &lt;/em&gt;for PS5&lt;/a&gt;. (You can catch &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/MqXeohrnoaY"&gt;a full replay of that show here&lt;/a&gt;.) And over the next few days there still are big conferences from Ubisoft, Microsoft and Bethesda, and Nintendo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Y8NWN"&gt;If you want to attend the virtual E3 as a fan, you can register to attend &lt;a href="https://e3expo.com/"&gt;on E3’s website&lt;/a&gt;. (I will warn you from personal experience that the E3 portal and website are pretty bad.) But if you just want to follow along with the press conferences and announcements, we’ve put together a timeline of some of the biggest events to look forward to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="949NMw"&gt;When is E3?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="45kdc1"&gt;E3 takes place from Saturday, June 12th, to Tuesday, June 15th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="rY9aIQ"&gt;Saturday, June 12th&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="KVyvuM"&gt;11AM ET: &lt;a href="https://www.guerrillacollective.com/"&gt;Guerrilla Collective&lt;/a&gt; (note that this is the second Guerrilla Collective show — the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H_wuLg5gE3w"&gt;first took place on June 5th&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="E6goBz"&gt;1PM ET: &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/e3"&gt;E3 broadcast&lt;/a&gt; pre-show&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hKXkuc"&gt;3PM ET: &lt;a href="https://ubisoft.pxf.io/c/482924/864200/12050?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ubisoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fforward&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ubisoft Forward&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kej1Gv"&gt;4:30PM ET: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/devolverdigital/status/1403166347392061442"&gt;Devolver Digital MaxPass Plus show&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/devolverdigital/status/1402044786174054407"&gt;case&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="aScn2x"&gt;5PM ET: &lt;a href="https://mobile.twitter.com/GearboxOfficial/status/1401932046801514499"&gt;Gearbox E3 Showcase&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DKOhSC"&gt;6PM ET: &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=43993&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oculus.com%2Fblog%2Ftune-in-to-the-upload-vr-showcase-for-a-sneak-peek-at-upcoming-oculus-quest-games%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The Upload VR Showcase&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="jNrFW7"&gt;Sunday, June 13th&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="VM2L1E"&gt;11:45AM ET: &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/e3"&gt;E3 broadcast&lt;/a&gt; pre-show&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nARhlQ"&gt;1PM ET: &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-US%2Fxbox-bethesda-games-showcase&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22465864%2Fe3-schedule-time-date-live-stream-how-to-watch" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft’s Xbox &amp;amp; Bethesda Games Showcase&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LIrB0q"&gt;3:15PM ET: &lt;a href="https://square-enix-games.com/en_US/news/e3?utm_campaign=sepe321_blog_SQEXSOCIAL"&gt;Square Enix Presents&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="CYRDhQ"&gt;5PM ET: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/back4blood/status/1403396658176487441"&gt;Warner Bros. Games’ &lt;em&gt;Back4Blood&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="f1igwM"&gt;5:30PM ET: &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/pc-gaming-show-2021-preview/"&gt;PC Gaming Show&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Xl4JQN"&gt;7PM ET: &lt;a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/amp/laura-bailey-and-troy-baker-set-to-host-the-future-game-show-powered-by-wd_black/?__twitter_impression=true"&gt;Future Games Show&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="CMx47m"&gt;Monday, June 14th&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="9up1Hi"&gt;11AM ET: &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/e3"&gt;E3 broadcast&lt;/a&gt; pre-show&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LXDo8K"&gt;5:30PM ET: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CapcomUSA_/status/1402249050532024321"&gt;Capcom showcase&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="KdCIaj"&gt;6PM ET: &lt;a href="https://razer.a9yw.net/c/482924/642901/10229?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.razer.com%2Fevents%2Frazer-e3-keynote&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Razer E3 keynote&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="31WHku"&gt;Tuesday, June 15th&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="UaMpX1"&gt;11AM ET: &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/e3"&gt;E3 broadcast&lt;/a&gt; pre-show&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ykEMnl"&gt;12PM ET: Nintendo’s &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1400089827501092867"&gt;Nintendo Direct&lt;/a&gt;, which will have “roughly” 40 minutes of information about upcoming games, followed by a Treehouse Live with about three hours of gameplay demoed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="akTXH2"&gt;5:25PM ET: Bandai Namco’s E3 presentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="HLrqOc"&gt;6:35PM ET: &lt;a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gamespot-presents-the-play-for-all-showcase/1100-6492375/"&gt;GameSpot’s Play for All Showcase&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jBubgu"&gt;7:45PM ET: &lt;a href="https://e3expo.com/news/e3-news/e3-2021-awards-show"&gt;Official E3 2021 Awards Show&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="eK22Ej"&gt;How can I watch E3?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="wDH2zQ"&gt;E3 will be airing its broadcast on &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/e3"&gt;Twitch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/e3"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/E3"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/E3Expo/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. For the presentations hosted by individual companies, you may be able to find official streams on their social platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6aE5bQ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update June 11th, 7:30PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Made updates to the scheduled and added details about what was announced at Summer Game Fest Kickoff Live.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22465864/e3-schedule-time-date-live-stream-how-to-watch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22465864/e3-schedule-time-date-live-stream-how-to-watch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-11T17:16:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T17:16:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook just bought the Fortnite of VR</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WgFD2vAcIxiT0BA8U_uokN3WEkU=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69442042/Screen_Shot_2021_06_11_at_1.34.40_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A character in &lt;/em&gt;Population: One&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: BigBox VR&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tboSmC"&gt;Facebook has acquired yet another developer of a popular virtual reality game, announcing on Friday that BigBox VR, makers of the battle royale VR title &lt;em&gt;Population: One, &lt;/em&gt;will be joining Oculus Studios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DYHcwL"&gt;“&lt;em&gt;POP: ONE&lt;/em&gt; stormed onto the VR scene just nine months ago and has consistently ranked as one the top-performing titles on the Oculus platform, bringing together up to 24 people at a time to connect, play, and compete in a virtual world,” Mike Verdu, the VP of content at Facebook Reality Labs, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=43993&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oculus.com%2Fblog%2Fwelcoming-bigbox-vr-to-facebook%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;wrote in a blog post&lt;/a&gt;. “And while social is bringing players into &lt;em&gt;POP: ONE&lt;/em&gt;, the quirky humor, continual updates, and pure fun of the environment keeps them coming back time and time again — we’ve even seen players scheduling time to meet in-game for a synchronous social experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="aQt53Z"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Population: One has been a big hit&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dUzI29"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Population: One&lt;/em&gt; has been a hit, earning more than $10 million on the Oculus Store “after just a few months,” &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=43993&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oculus.com%2Fblog%2Ffrom-bear-to-bull-how-oculus-quest-2-is-changing-the-game-for-vr%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Verdu said in a February blog post&lt;/a&gt;. The game, which is available on both the &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=43993&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oculus.com%2Fexperiences%2Fquest%2F2564158073609422%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Oculus Store&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/691260/POPULATION_ONE/"&gt;on Steam&lt;/a&gt;, will “continue to be supported on all its current platforms,” according to Verdu. And the game will continue to receive regular updates, &lt;a href="https://www.bigboxvr.com/"&gt;BigBox VR says on its website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Kv9flQ"&gt;But it’s not clear just yet what bigger changes might be in the works because of the acquisition. “BigBox VR has big plans for the future of &lt;em&gt;POP: ONE&lt;/em&gt; and for other projects, but we’re not ready to share details at this time,” Verdu says, vaguely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R0DJvw"&gt;BigBox VR joins a slew of other VR studios that Facebook has snapped up over the past couple years. The company acquired &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22412882/facebook-oculus-studios-onward-developer-downpour-interactive-acqusition"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Onward&lt;/em&gt; developer Downpour Interactive in April&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=43993&amp;amp;u1=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22176923%5Bt%5Dw%5Bd%5DD&amp;amp;murl=https://www.oculus.com/blog/welcoming-ready-at-dawn-to-facebook/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lone Echo&lt;/em&gt; creator Ready at Dawn last June&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=43993&amp;amp;u1=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22176923%5Bt%5Dw%5Bd%5DD&amp;amp;murl=https://www.oculus.com/blog/welcoming-sanzaru-games-to-facebook/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Asgard’s Wrath&lt;/em&gt; maker Sanzaru Games in February 2020&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/26/20984468/facebook-acquisition-beat-games-beat-saber-vr-studio"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Beat Saber&lt;/em&gt; developer Beat Games in November 2019&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22530144/facebook-oculus-studios-acquires-bigbox-vr-population-one"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22530144/facebook-oculus-studios-acquires-bigbox-vr-population-one</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-11T17:14:34-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T17:14:34-04:00</updated>
    <title>New Yorkers needing affordable internet will have to wait   </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2d9Q7OBqOzEFTUZ_1C5jcQeJ6Ds=/237x0:2754x1678/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69442024/1170796244.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Jaap Arriens/NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OOODye"&gt;Internet access is, according to New York’s Eastern District Judge Dennis R. Hurley, a “modern necessity.” Unfortunately, Judge Hurley wrote those words in an injunction, filed today, to stall a piece of progressive legislation which would have mandated affordable internet availability to all living in New York State — and which would have come into effect early next week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hQPq9B"&gt;The bill, known as the Affordable Broadband Act, would have required ISPs serving more than 20,000 households to offer two low-cost plans: one offering speeds of 25 Mbps down for no more than $15 per month, and another offering 200 Mbps down at no more than $20 monthly. It was passed by the state legislature and signed by Governor Cuomo &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22388184/new-york-affordable-internet-cost-low-income-price-cap-bill"&gt;back in April&lt;/a&gt;, and would have gone into effect on June 16th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xD9kqk"&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-04-16/n-y-to-require-all-internet-providers-offer-low-cost-broadband?sref=P6Q0mxvj"&gt;state Assembly member Amy Paulin&lt;/a&gt;, the average monthly cost of internet access for New Yorkers is $50; in general, Americans can pay &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22177154/us-internet-speed-maps-competition-availability-fcc"&gt;about double&lt;/a&gt; what Europeans do for broadband access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1REfl6"&gt;Of course, no sooner was the bill signed then telecom lobbies &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/att-verizon-new-york-broadband-law-41448df8-370c-403a-8826-60159daf1877.html"&gt;sued to stop it&lt;/a&gt; from being enacted. &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/att-verizon-new-york-broadband-law-41448df8-370c-403a-8826-60159daf1877.html"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Axios&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, NY Governor Cuomo was quoted as saying the lawsuit was “nothing more than a transparent attempt by billion-dollar corporations putting profit ahead of creating a more fair and just society.” And, love or hate the guy, he has a point there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0cCR4W"&gt;The ABA isn’t dead in the water, but Judge Hurley’s eleventh-hour injunction doesn’t bode well. In his determination, he found its enactment is likely to cause “irreparable harm” to telecom companies — either because they’re hit with civil penalties for failing to meet the requirements of the ABA, or loss of revenue by charging less for services — among other, base-level findings that allowed the injunction to be found valid. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VngP7N"&gt;One particularly interesting arrow in Judge Hurley’s quiver, however, was to weaponize other existing programs that help make internet access affordable, specifically the FCC’s Emergency Broadband Benefit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="QDnrzU"&gt;While the stated purpose of the ABA is to expand access to broadband internet, that is not to say it is the sole legislative effort doing so. Plaintiffs discuss several federal programs allocating billions of dollars to achieve that same end [...] While Defendant argues that the New York Legislature determined these federal benefits were insufficient, that determination was made prior to the FCC’s April 29, 2021 announcement that the Emergency Broadband Benefit would become on effective May 12, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="KHWSwT"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/26/22302807/fcc-internet-subsidies-authorized-low-income-broadband"&gt;The Emergency Broadband Benefit&lt;/a&gt; is critically different from the ABA in several ways. It does not cap the cost of internet access in any way, and unlike the ABA it’s means-tested: applicants need to qualify by showing they meet specific economic criteria. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22430529/emergency-broadband-benefit-program-how-to-get"&gt;Those who do can receive $50 off their monthly bill.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e2BK25"&gt;So: for now, like the ABA itself, New Yorkers who were hoping for reliable broadband at a reasonable price point are stuck in limbo. While the injunction casts a large shadow over the future of the law, it is, at the end of the day, essentially just a judge saying “look, I need more time to sort all this out.” Hopefully, with some careful consideration, New York can still put a dent in the almost comically consolidated telecommunications sector. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22530128/new-york-affordable-internet-15-injunction"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22530128/new-york-affordable-internet-15-injunction</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bryan Menegus</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-11T16:42:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T16:42:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Larry Page’s air taxi startup is buying former DJI rival 3D Robotics</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="3dr solo images" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6wsAB_lL0i4AvoeVawzSuQdGzgo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69441855/3dr-solo-_-_2.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: 3D Robotics&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6yVU9B"&gt;Kitty Hawk, the air taxi company backed by Google co-founder Larry Page, is buying what’s left of one-time DJI competitor 3D Robotics. As part of the acquisition, 3D Robotics co-founder Chris Anderson will become Kitty Hawk’s chief operating officer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dqo115"&gt;The acquisition &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jeremybogaisky/2021/06/11/larry-page-kitty-hawk-air-taxi-sebastian-thrun/?sh=51b27bff738c"&gt;was first reported by &lt;em&gt;Forbes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which published a detailed look at the current state of Kitty Hawk and its new focus on developing a remote-piloted electric vertical takeoff and landing (eVTOL) aircraft on Friday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ctnvG9"&gt;Anderson will serve under CEO Sebastian Thrun, a former Google executive who founded the company’s self-driving car project (before it became standalone company Waymo) and launched its famous “X” moonshot division. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="77X8rm"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Kitty Hawk is shifting its focus after recent turmoil&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VdFdIG"&gt;3D Robotics was, for a short while, the lone American company trying to carve out space in the budding consumer drone market against early entrants like France’s Parrot and China’s DJI. But as DJI began to dominate the market, 3D Robotics abandoned its consumer product (which had autonomous capabilities and was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/4/13/8394359/3d-robotics-solo-drone-quadcopter-gopro"&gt;called Solo&lt;/a&gt;), laid off some employees, and spent the years since developing software for commercial drones. Late last year, though, the company asked the Federal Aviation Administration to certify a drone for government use that “may” rely heavily on automation, signaling a lingering interest in hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZQWbeU"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Some personal/professional news: I'll be joining &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kittyhawkcorp?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@kittyhawkcorp&lt;/a&gt; (Larry Page &amp;amp; Sebastian Thrun's eVTOL company) as COO as part of a 3DR acquisition. The path from drones to remotely-piloted passenger aircraft is becoming increasingly clear, especially from a FAA cert basis...&lt;/p&gt;— Chris Anderson (@chr1sa) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/chr1sa/status/1403434049977212928?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 11, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1oT8yW"&gt;“The path from drones to remotely-piloted passenger aircraft is becoming increasingly clear, especially from a FAA [certification] basis,” Anderson &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/chr1sa/status/1403434049977212928"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; Friday. “The two share many similar technologies, from power systems to autopilots, so it will be interesting to see where scaled-up drones &amp;amp; scaled-down traditional aviation meet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iS5pGW"&gt;3D Robotics is not the only drone company to work on autonomous technology. Fellow startup Skydio released two versions of its own self-flying camera drone before recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/13/21322832/skydio-x2-commercial-drone-enterprise-military-announce-100-million-funding"&gt;shifting focus&lt;/a&gt; to include enterprise and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/1/22306876/skydio-1-billion-valuation-enterprise-military-customers-chinese-drones-grounded"&gt;military customers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ByqDpw"&gt;Page founded Kitty Hawk in 2015, though the company didn’t break cover until 2017. The startup’s initial focus was around a small personal electric aircraft called the Flyer, which Kitty Hawk said would be so simple to fly that a pilot’s license wouldn’t be required. It even said at the time that a commercial version &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/4/24/15406208/larry-page-flying-car-kitty-hawk-flyer-prototype"&gt;would be available in late 2017&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rHMuio"&gt;Kitty Hawk developed a working prototype of the Flyer and even showed off a much sleeker version the following year. The startup also revealed &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LeFxjRMv5U8"&gt;a second aircraft called Cora&lt;/a&gt; in 2018 that it handed off to a joint venture with Boeing. But Kitty Hawk abandoned the Flyer in 2020, laid off dozens of employees, and turned its attention toward a third electric aircraft in development. That aircraft, called Heaviside, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/3/20897336/kitty-hawk-electric-aircraft-heaviside-mile-range-flight-time-google-larry-page"&gt;looks more like a traditional plane&lt;/a&gt; and more closely resembles the vehicles being built by numerous other eVTOL startups like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22529534/archer-maker-air-taxi-evtol-reveal-specs"&gt;Archer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22298957/joby-aviation-public-evtol-electric-aircraft-spac-hoffman"&gt;Joby&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358027/lilium-flying-taxi-evtol-spac-electric-aviation-gm-engle"&gt;Lilium&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cwS6E6"&gt;While the plan with Heaviside was originally for it to be piloted, the company is now working toward making it fully autonomous, according to the &lt;em&gt;Forbes&lt;/em&gt; report. Thrun reportedly pushed so hard for this change in direction that Kitty Hawk fired the engineer behind the aircraft, Damon Vander Lind, in May after he fought for the original vision. The report also details a number of recent employee departures, including a few engineers who left Kitty Hawk after they believed Vander Lind retaliated against them for raising safety concerns about Heaviside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jsLG4H"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4dg2jw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22530073/larry-page-kitty-hawk-3d-robotics-drone-air-taxi"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22530073/larry-page-kitty-hawk-3d-robotics-drone-air-taxi</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-11T15:30:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T15:30:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>Darnella Frazier, who documented George Floyd’s murder, receives Pulitzer Prize citation</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="PALESTINIAN-ISRAEL-US-RACISM-POLICE-TRIAL-FLOYD" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NbLvckNtwUW6Ch1g0WEN03ZnZdo=/0x2:8192x5463/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69441477/1232039092.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by EMMANUEL DUNAND/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JvbyYF"&gt;Darnella Frazier — the teen who used her smartphone to film the video of George Floyd’s murder in May 2020 that sparked a wave of Black Lives Matter protests worldwide, which culminated in the murder conviction of former police officer Derek Chauvin — &lt;a href="https://www.pulitzer.org/article/2021-pulitzer-prize-announcement"&gt;will receive a special citation from the Pulitzer Board&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XonCKN"&gt;Frazier was given the citation for “courageously recording the murder of George Floyd, a video that spurred protests against police brutality around the world, highlighting the crucial role of citizens in journalists’ quest for truth and justice,” the Pulitzer Board said (&lt;a href="https://www.pulitzer.org/cms/sites/default/files/content/2021longlist130611.pdf"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lHWZtG"&gt;Frazier’s video, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/20/us/darnella-frazier-video.html"&gt;which was viewed by millions&lt;/a&gt;, ignited one of the biggest protest movements in American history and demonstrated how a smartphone with a camera can be a powerful tool &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21355121/new-civil-rights-movement-police-brutality-protests-film-videos-black-lives-matter"&gt;to document police brutality and racial injustices&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="21u42N"&gt;Frazier was 17 when she filmed the video and uploaded it to Facebook. She also testified at Chauvin’s trial, a trial that eventually resulted in a historic conviction: “the first time in Minnesota history that a white police officer was convicted of killing a Black civilian on the job,” &lt;a href="https://www.startribune.com/derek-chauvin-convicted-of-murdering-george-floyd-in-minneapolis-is-led-away-in-handcuffs/600048324/"&gt;according to the &lt;em&gt;Star Tribune&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. (The &lt;em&gt;Star Tribune&lt;/em&gt; was awarded a Pulitzer Prize on Friday for its coverage of Floyd’s death and what followed.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cU20iB"&gt;“Even though this was a traumatic life-changing experience for me, I’m proud of myself,” Frazier said &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/25/us/darnella-frazier.html"&gt;in a statement on the anniversary of Floyd’s death&lt;/a&gt;. “If it weren’t for my video, the world wouldn’t have known the truth. I own that. My video didn’t save George Floyd, but it put his murderer away and off the streets.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="SKWJlH"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Capturing the Police","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21355121/new-civil-rights-movement-police-brutality-protests-film-videos-black-lives-matter"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22529934/darnella-frazier-filmed-george-floyd-murder-phone-pulitzer-prize-citation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/11/22529934/darnella-frazier-filmed-george-floyd-murder-phone-pulitzer-prize-citation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
