<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-05-20T16:21:43-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-20T16:21:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-20T16:21:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s new privacy ad imagines Thanos-snapping your stalkers out of existence</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VRQCgvfwt6mkNNe6ISXkydwj5Ak=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69319196/vlcsnap_2021_05_20_12h43m26s445.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Xs6JLW"&gt;Apple’s new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22405474/apple-app-tracking-transparency-ios-14-5-privacy-update-facebook-data"&gt;App Tracking Transparency&lt;/a&gt; feature in iOS 14.5 doesn’t seem to be a difficult concept to grasp; initial estimates suggest &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/05/96-of-us-users-opt-out-of-app-tracking-in-ios-14-5-analytics-find/"&gt;as many as 96 percent of US users&lt;/a&gt; are leaping at the chance to tell their apps “No, you can’t track me across the internet.” Now, Apple is taking a victory lap with a full ad campaign, too, one that turns the feature into a selling point for the iPhone and furthers the attempt to pitch itself &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/26/18282158/apple-services-privacy-credit-card-tv-data-sharing"&gt;as the only tech company you can trust&lt;/a&gt;. And, if you ask me, its new ad spot “Tracked” is just about perfect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4jjBXj"&gt;Just give it a watch, above: Who wouldn’t want to Thanos-snap ad trackers into dust? It’s no wonder Google is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266823/google-anti-tracking-feature-android-privacy-apple-ios-app-tracking-transparency"&gt;thinking long and hard about following Apple’s lead&lt;/a&gt; with an anti-tracking feature of its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="1qIbzV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to&amp;amp;nbsp;use iOS 14.5’s new app tracking blocker","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22403523/ios-14-5-tracking-consent-app-transparency-how-to"},{"title":"Why Apple’s new privacy feature is such a big deal","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22405474/apple-app-tracking-transparency-ios-14-5-privacy-update-facebook-data"},{"title":"Google is weighing an anti-tracking feature for Android, following Apple’s lead","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266823/google-anti-tracking-feature-android-privacy-apple-ios-app-tracking-transparency"},{"title":"Can Apple live up to Apple’s privacy ads?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/tech/2020/1/22/21076245/apple-icloud-backup-encryption-loophole-privacy-ads-fbi"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="dmdztJ"&gt;Critics claim these moves &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22180102/facebook-new-newspaper-ad-apple-ios-14-privacy-prompt"&gt;will make the internet more expensive&lt;/a&gt; and potentially harm small businesses, and are updating their apps to warn you about that — as well as the idea &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/14/22436944/twitter-ad-tracking-ios-14-5-app-transparency"&gt;that ads might be less relevant&lt;/a&gt; if you opt out. But that’s a tough sell compared to the privacy fears that exist these days, and it’s hard to argue with Apple’s idea that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22179721/apple-defends-upcoming-privacy-changes-standing-up-for-users-facebook-data"&gt;users should get to choose for themselves&lt;/a&gt;. The company also launched &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/14/22174017/apple-app-store-new-privacy-labels-ios-apps-public"&gt;privacy “nutrition labels”&lt;/a&gt; late last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tXl5OL"&gt;Apple tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;that its own ad platform and apps don’t track users, and that the Ad Tracking Transparency prompt applies to its own apps as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8dqqJR"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ihw_Al4RNno?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=1&amp;amp;start=1" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446220/apple-privacy-ad-video-ad-tracking-transparency"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446220/apple-privacy-ad-video-ad-tracking-transparency</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-20T16:16:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-20T16:16:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>MagSafe PopSockets are here: we tested to see if they stick</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bqlNFFCpe7-xJ9TASP5mQEOavfE=/13x0:4887x3249/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69319172/DSCF2173.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The PopGrip for MagSafe is bulkier than the regular PopGrips, but is easy to take off.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pxHvXB"&gt;MagSafe PopSockets are finally here, after the famous phone handle company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225701/popsockets-magsafe-accessory"&gt;announced  they would be coming in January&lt;/a&gt;. The PopGrip for MagSafe sells for $30, which is two to three times more expensive than the adhesive versions, but the bigger question that people have been asking since the announcement is whether they’ll be as trustworthy. I decided it was time to find out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3NcqiV"&gt;The PopGrip for MagSafe is a retractable grip for your phone (as the name implies) that can also work as a stand for watching video or a hands-free video call. PopSockets has made versions of the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/PopSockets-PopGrip-Swappable-Phones-Tablets/dp/B07P29XQR4?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;PopGrip&lt;/a&gt; for years now (and if you’ve got a collection of fun design tops, this will still work with those), but they’ve traditionally used an adhesive to attach to your device. The MagSafe version uses Apple’s system of magnets that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21509659/apple-iphone-12-magsafe-charging-magnetic-charger-return"&gt;it introduced on the iPhone 12 models&lt;/a&gt; and is compatible with everything from the iPhone 12 Mini to the gargantuan iPhone 12 Pro Max.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6swZQw"&gt;There have also been &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/METISINNO-MagSafe-Socket-Compatible-iPhone/dp/B08RDBZH6D?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;some attempts by third parties&lt;/a&gt; to make MagSafe mounts that you can stick to your iPhone, then stick a PopSocket to, but the PopGrip for MagSafe is an integrated, first-party version. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Vb2ojW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10510706"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1UrbXV"&gt;PopSockets makes it clear on the box that this shouldn’t be used with bare iPhones, and it’s easy to see why: the iPhone’s glass back doesn’t provide a lot of grip. But sometimes the question with accessories isn’t “what do the directions say” but “can I get away with using it like this?”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/obBI70G9XJXgJXiM6dfR0iUhAXQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22528842/raw_phone_couch.gif"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Goodbye!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hYY5rb"&gt;Looks like the answer is no! Listen to PopSockets, and do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; use this thing with a bare phone. If you put it on and shake it around a few times you may get lucky and think that it’s fine, but I promise it will come off very easily at some point. Probably while you’re on some sort of perilous precipice.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9NaThJHHHBX8_5IWRvlmlZTpFHM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22528854/DSCF2160.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pictured: a terrible idea.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Yks3rD"&gt;That did make me wonder, though, what would happen if I had a plastic case that wasn’t MagSafe compatible. Would the magnets still reach through, and would the plastic be less slippery than the iPhone’s glass? I can’t answer the second question, because the answer to the first one is absolutely not. It basically just falls off, even with a reasonably thin MagSafe-less case.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ct2pov0pujZLr7ES3PnUTOHAiSY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22528889/Non_Magcase.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hGIc9Z"&gt;Okay, well let’s give the PopSocket the best-case scenario: how well will it stick to Apple’s silicone MagSafe case, which has both magnets and a reasonably grippy texture?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5lgZc9xYyZ9T5MwzGn4UqB0oDUM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22528870/Silicone_Case_Couch.gif"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’d call that a pass!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="47Zj35"&gt;As you can see, it’s not coming off — at least not until you want to pop it of to, say, wirelessly charge, in which case it’s actually very easy to remove. But maybe it’s just the specific way I was shaking it that let it perform so well. I will admit that I haven’t historically been a heavy PopSocket user, but I’ve been told that people put a &lt;em&gt;lot &lt;/em&gt;of faith in the PopSocket adhesive. So that made me wonder what was the silliest thing I could do to &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; put the MagSafe case / PopGrip connection to the test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wW5Siz"&gt;And obviously the answer &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JJchhTeDZhM"&gt;was karate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K33n3i4e3YpvbTKRvU-DWpYQZeY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22528824/karate_test.gif"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unlike my form after years of not practicing, my phone is still intact.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="EhAYRD"&gt;Make no mistake, if you &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to dislodge the PopSocket from the phone, you can. If I’m holding the phone at a perfect parallel angle to the floor and shaking with all my might, it will eventually come off, but that doesn’t seem like a terribly realistic scenario and it’s been rock-solid in all my other tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ut0Jkv"&gt;It’s also worth noting that I wasn’t able to test the MagSafe PopSocket with other case materials, like &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Leather-Case-MagSafe-iPhone/dp/B08L5NRTFJ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple’s leather&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-Clear-Case-iPhone-Pro/dp/B08L5NRTRR?ref_=ast_sto_dp&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;clear plastic cases&lt;/a&gt;, so it’s hard to say if it would do as well. But it does seem that, with at least one of Apple’s cases, the MagSafe PopSocket can hang with the adhesive version. And if you use your phone with a non-MagSafe case, or no case at all? Well, you may have to stick with the sticky PopSockets, or buy a MagSafe case if you really want that sweet magnetic removability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1BO7UM"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22445808/magsafe-popsocket-iphone-review-test-stick-adhesive"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22445808/magsafe-popsocket-iphone-review-test-stick-adhesive</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-20T16:00:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-20T16:00:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Pixel 6 Pro could have a curved screen and a triple rear camera, new leak suggests</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9E-SsriP6IB3EtdUWxmBEjxESQ8=/400x0:4720x2880/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69319100/PIXEL_6_PRO_5K3.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Newly leaked renders suggest that Google isn’t playing it safe anymore with its next generation of Pixel devices.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: OnLeaks and digit.in&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="aYaYqP"&gt;New images from reputable leaker &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/onleaks"&gt;OnLeaks&lt;/a&gt; (via &lt;a href="https://www.digit.in/news/mobile-phones/exclusive-google-pixel-6-pro-rednders-leak-display-design-camera-59483.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;digit.in&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) show what may be a bold step forward for Google’s Pixel series. The Pixel 6 Pro, as pictured in the alleged renders, could offer a 6.67-inch curved display and a rear triple-camera array — a Pixel first — including a periscope-style telephoto lens. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l0Zh5G"&gt;This report also says that the 6 Pro will use an OLED screen, though there’s no confirmation of refresh rate, and will measure around 163.9 x 75.8 x 8.9mm. It’s expected to offer dual speakers and support wireless charging — features that are both available on the Pixel 5. There are some obvious differences in design, too, with the camera array moved to a raised, horizontal stripe across the back of the device and a bright accent color on the panel above it. There’s no confirmation with this leak whether the 6 Pro will include the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/2/22364543/google-pixel-6-custom-in-house-processor-gs101-whitechapel-arm-report"&gt;rumored, Google-designed “Whitechapel” SoC&lt;/a&gt; (system on a chip).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UC-GcKR-HRuFxfKOQmvNX-DYtno=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22528954/PIXEL_6_PRO_5K1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: OnLeaks and digit.in&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Renders show a rear triple-camera array including a periscope telephoto lens.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MhZnlx"&gt;The naming shift from “XL” to “Pro” could also indicate a new relationship between the standard and big-screen models. In previous generations (the Pixel 5 never got an XL counterpart), the XL model was a “same phone, bigger screen” affair. Ditching that moniker for “Pro” could indicate that it’s both a bigger and higher-end device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kTkQGB"&gt;Google has taken a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21514312/google-pixel-5-review-camera-speed-processor-fingerprint"&gt;conservative approach recently&lt;/a&gt; to its Pixel hardware and design. This hasn’t been an entirely bad thing, and it’s earned Google’s handsets a reputation for simple, affordable design with great cameras and software. But if these renders are the real deal, then the company appears to be making a move to challenge other flagships with higher-end hardware. For now, there’s no confirmed release date for the Pixel 6 or Pixel 6 Pro, but we’d expect Google to stick with its typical fall timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UoiiaR"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446078/google-pixel-6-pro-leak-specs-camera-screen"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446078/google-pixel-6-pro-leak-specs-camera-screen</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-20T15:45:47-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-20T15:45:47-04:00</updated>
    <title>The PlayStation 5 is available at Walmart (UPDATE: Sold Out)</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ig94_fqNQBXgc2SfQyCwz6Qs2P8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69318686/acastro_210511_1777_psRestock_0005.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5ikMud"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update May 20th, 2021, 3:44PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: The PS5 seems to be out of stock at Walmart, as the retailer hasn’t refreshed its pages in a little more than 10 minutes. We’ll be on the lookout for more opportunities.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DQIMvb"&gt;Sony’s elusive PlayStation 5 console is in stock at &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPlayStation-5-Console%2F363472942&amp;amp;subid1=VergePS5Restocks03102021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re one of the many people who has struggled to get one for yourself, today is looking good for you, and it’ll look better if more retailers jump in with stock later today. As usual, Walmart might not immediately appear to be selling consoles today, but you might be able to get one added to your cart if you refresh frequently. (&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: make sure your payment method and shipping address are entered ahead of time on each site before you try to buy a console. The faster you can checkout, the more likely your chance of success. Also, Walmart tends to release more consoles in 10-minute waves, so try again if 3:00PM ET doesn’t work, try again at 3:10PM ET.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LpQGVG"&gt;The PS5 with a UHD Blu-ray disc drive and 1TB of built-in SSD storage costs $499.99 and is available from Walmart. Due to the disc drive, this model is slightly thicker and heavier than the digital edition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="AN08xm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10384391"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SQnMrc"&gt;If you want to save a little money (and a little space in your entertainment center), the PlayStation 5 digital edition without a disc drive is available for $399.99. Other than lacking the ability to play discs, this model is exactly the same as the more costly version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZVc8fy"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9563999"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jmX6UO"&gt;I wish you the best of luck in getting a console today. Whether you get one today, or plan to get one when the next restocking happens, there are a few must-have accessories to accompany your purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9pnh2z"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10420564"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="z6YELL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10499033"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="OlxFkn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10510093"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="utPhLC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="ceREf8"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22445559/playstation-5-ps5-restock-walmart"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22445559/playstation-5-ps5-restock-walmart</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-20T15:31:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-20T15:31:19-04:00</updated>
    <title>Numbers won’t tell us when the pandemic is over</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Mural Hope Easter" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mgUfvJPt6x9l-DC3J_iKH10up_I=/4x0:4624x3080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69318903/1311049166.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A mural in Rome celebrates the arrival of COVID-19 vaccines. | Photo by Marilla Sicilia/Archivio Marilla Sicilia/Mondadori Portfolio via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Our emotional relationship to COVID-19 will drive our transition out of the pandemic&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="zcimDu"&gt;Courtney Gidengil has a roadmap for how the COVID-19 pandemic might end. It was sketched out the last time the United States transitioned out of a pandemic — the “swine flu” outbreaks in 2009. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cEH2Sn"&gt;Gidengil, a senior physician policy researcher at the RAND Corporation, spent that pandemic asking a group of adults how worried they were about the virus. Their answers changed through the course of her &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3297965/pdf/AJPH.2011.300407.pdf"&gt;eight-month study&lt;/a&gt;. Early on, people were worried that they’d get sick, and that if they got sick, they’d die. Then, as we learned more about the virus, a flu strain called H1N1, they felt like they were less at risk. The virus was still around, but people weren’t as scared of it. Eventually, it just became one of the normal flu strains that circulate each year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5tWpPV"&gt;“We understand more about it, but people also just become attuned to the risk,” Gidengil says. ”It just becomes more like background noise in everyday life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="i96CGB"&gt;&lt;q&gt;”It just becomes more like background noise in everyday life”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="odOB5S"&gt;That emotional transition — from fear and uncertainty to gradual acclimatization — is likely to happen again with COVID-19. H1N1 is a very different disease than COVID-19; it was far less deadly and barely disrupted most people’s day-to-day lives. But it’s one way to picture what the social trajectory out of a pandemic can look like. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xGOGtO"&gt;Right now, COVID-19 is still killing people all over the world — the pandemic is still viscerally real. But in the US, it doesn’t have the same sharp bite as it did six months ago. The end feels close: case rates have been falling for weeks, and tens of thousands of people get vaccinated each day. The virus is being beaten back unevenly all over the world, but populations will each adjust to living with the new disease as the risk of it becomes more and more tolerable — it won’t feel like it’s an emergency anymore. It’ll just be another virus that sometimes makes people sick. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cq3Ymm"&gt;That gradual adjustment is partly why the end of the pandemic feels so slippery: there’s no one number of cases to reach or switch that will flip to mark the end. We’re not waiting for a group like the World Health Organization to say it’s over, and even if it did, that announcement wouldn’t be essential — after all, &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/03/09/health/coronavirus-pandemic-gupta/index.html"&gt;some people started&lt;/a&gt; calling the outbreak a pandemic before the WHO did. In many ways, COVID-19 will stop being a pandemic disease and start being a regular disease when we feel like it has. The end will be based on people’s tolerance for risk, personal values, &lt;a href="https://www.newyorker.com/culture/cultural-comment/tiktok-and-the-vibes-revival"&gt;and straight vibes&lt;/a&gt; — not a hard-and-fast data point. And that transition will be different for everyone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ndLPvw"&gt;“We will be very attentive to the coronavirus for a while, and then it will enter the kind of background welter of things that kill us,” says Nicholas Christakis, a sociologist and director of the Human Nature Lab at Yale University. “Slowly, we will stop paying attention to it — that will define the social end of the pandemic.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="e8NHmd"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A regular threat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="uGhIYZ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/03/health/covid-herd-immunity-vaccine.html"&gt;We probably won’t be able to get rid&lt;/a&gt; of COVID-19 entirely. Vaccination, improved treatments, and familiarity with the virus will defang the threat. Already, it looks like vaccinating the people at the highest risk from dying of COVID-19 has &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/trvrb/status/1390681942463447048"&gt;brought down its overall fatality rate&lt;/a&gt; in the United States. But the virus will continue to circulate through the population, and eventually, the peaks and valleys of the pandemic will settle at some sort of consistent height. At that point, it will have transitioned from a &lt;em&gt;pandemic&lt;/em&gt; disease — an illness that spreads rapidly and affects the entire world — to an &lt;em&gt;endemic&lt;/em&gt; disease. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s98c8w"&gt;Those are specific, technical terms, but in many ways, their definitions are based on experience and emotion. Pandemic diseases are unpredictable and cause unexpected, scary amounts of death and sickness. Endemic diseases, on the other hand, are predictable. They’re a threat but a threat the population is used to. Think: seasonal flu, chicken pox, some sexually transmitted diseases, malaria in parts of Africa. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="aaJeCj"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“When you shift from pandemic to endemic, it means that there’s a collective acceptance that we are now living with this disease”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yDCvXF"&gt;“When you shift from pandemic to endemic, it means that there’s a collective acceptance that we are now living with this disease,” Gidengil says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vu1Zm7"&gt;Personally, I’ve spent a lot of time lately wondering what that acceptance will look like for me. I’m fully vaccinated, and so are most of my friends and family. I’ve started to ease back into “normal” activities like visiting my parents, browsing clothing stores, and making dinner with friends. But it still feels weird to take off my mask inside if there are strangers around. I still jump when someone coughs nearby. Hearing someone I know has COVID-19 would still be scary. Logically, I know my risk from COVID-19 is many times lower than it was a month ago — but that’s hard to internalize after &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/93yye8/pandemic-safety-mask-lockdown-cant-quit-grief-trauma-anxiety"&gt;over a year of fear&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gENEF1"&gt;The adjustment to living with COVID-19 as a background threat will be different for everyone, says Steven Taylor, clinical psychologist and author of &lt;em&gt;The Psychology of Pandemics&lt;/em&gt;. People who had higher baseline levels of anxiety may take longer to adjust to a new relationship with the virus. “It’s going to be tough for some people to wrap their heads around the idea that the pandemic is over, but people are still getting sick and dying from COVID-19,” he says. On the other hand, people who normally cope well with stress will navigate the transition to having an endemic virus more easily. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8cCpZ6"&gt;It’s worth taking a second to talk about another slippery, complex part of this discussion. Some people &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; believed that COVID-19 posed much of a threat and went about their normal lives over the past year. At that point in time, deciding to tune out COVID-19 and think of it as just a background threat wasn’t reasonable. COVID-19 was still clearly and objectively a pandemic, with soaring cases, hospitalizations, and deaths. Decisions that just ignored reality were dangerous for individuals’ health, the health of others, and health systems overall. In some places in the world, COVID-19 is still a clear and present danger, and the end of the pandemic is still far away. But over 2021 and 2022, as vaccination rates go up and the levels of COVID-19 fall, the pandemic can start to become more subjective. Personal risk tolerance will play a &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2021/05/05/americans-will-have-answer-remaining-questions-about-pandemic-themselves/"&gt;bigger and bigger role&lt;/a&gt; in how people manage their relationship with the virus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="New York Opens Pop-Up Vaccination Sites At MTA Stations, Offering Free Metro Cards" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EcJkD8d14uVOMIh_CfI0pXSTbhw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22528432/1317682227.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Spencer Platt / Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WFVCnA"&gt;“When we get to a point where we have very low levels of hospitalizations and deaths, it’s less of a public health issue,” says Jennifer Nuzzo, an epidemiologist and senior scholar at the Johns Hopkins Center for Health Security. Then, we could start to see reasonable differences in how people navigate their changing relationship with COVID-19. Some people might still want to avoid any situations where they could be exposed to the coronavirus. Others might be willing to risk it for the chance to go to an indoor concert, for example. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7ivhyG"&gt;Making that choice might feel similar to the choice to get into a car, even though there’s a high risk of an accident. “We look at the risk of getting into a car accident as worth it because of the value that transportation by motor vehicles brings to our lives,” Nuzzo says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ua58cH"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An uncertain timeline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="TLVjG2"&gt;There’s no playbook for how the adjustment period from pandemic to background, endemic threat will go or for how long it could take. Gidengil’s research showed that H1N1 stopped feeling like a pandemic over the course of a few months, but that virus was never as scary as COVID-19. HIV offers another example, Taylor says — it still circulates and is still dangerous, but when effective treatments were developed, the anxiety around it started to fade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gNAQus"&gt;Even with treatments, though, that adjustment to HIV took years, says Yale sociologist Christakis. “People stopped thinking about it as much, but there wasn’t a rapid decline in the public consciousness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="edli2t"&gt;&lt;q&gt;the emergence of viral variants might make the adjustment process bumpier than the arc of H1N1&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="b7Gcm0"&gt;It’s still unclear how that will play out with COVID-19. The emergence of viral variants might make the adjustment process bumpier than the arc of H1N1 —  while H1N1 faded quickly, new variants of the coronavirus might raise public concerns at uneven intervals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Oiw2Qj"&gt;As cases fall and vaccinations increase, policy changes may influence how people feel about the virus. Local and federal health agencies could decide to only report new COVID-19 hospitalizations and deaths, rather than every single new case, Nuzzo says. That could signal to people that each individual case isn’t as much of a threat. Changes in mask mandates also give people cues. We’ve seen that recently with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention’s mask guidelines for people who are fully vaccinated. Telling people that they can stop wearing masks in certain situations indicates that they can start to let their guard down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SB2ARV"&gt;Still, policy doesn’t always dictate people’s relationships with COVID-19. In some areas, vaccinated people may be &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/17/nyregion/vaccinated-masks-cdc.html?smtyp=cur&amp;amp;smid=tw-nytimes"&gt;sticking to masks&lt;/a&gt;, even where the CDC and local regulations say they’re no longer necessary. “I think it’s ultimately going to matter how comfortable people feel,” Nuzzo says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="CgiJvT"&gt;&lt;q&gt;That comfort will come with time — and with familiarity&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2ylGol"&gt;That comfort will come with time — and with familiarity. My brother had COVID-19 this spring. He recovered just fine, but he was undeniably sick for around a week — no appetite, a high fever, a horrible sore throat, unable to get out of bed. He’s young, and he was never in any serious danger, but it was still scary. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OjntVh"&gt;If a family member got sick a year from now, Taylor thinks I probably wouldn’t be as worried. That hypothetical family member would probably be vaccinated, and we’d have another year of information about the virus. I’d also have a year of stories about people who caught COVID-19 and didn’t become seriously ill, because the vaccines are so good at preventing bad cases of the disease. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aMxWFq"&gt;Calm “comes from experience,” Taylor says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="kvQlsR"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blind spots&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="bhsk9X"&gt;Calm can also be dangerous. The trouble with marking the end of pandemics by how they feel instead of by a concrete metric is that we might set the bar for what feels like normal in an uncomfortable place. “At a certain point, there’s a concern that people might underestimate the risk,” Gidengil says. “Diseases come under control, so there is less risk, but we want to attune it so we’re at the sweet spot of understanding what the risk is so that we can make well-informed decisions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fVCUXD"&gt;She saw that with H1N1. Toward the end of that pandemic, as people’s fear of the virus started to let up, Gidengil’s research showed that the number of people who wanted to get the H1N1 vaccine started to drop. The virus seemed like less of a threat, and people felt like it was less urgent to take steps that would protect them from it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="SDMC Launch Campaign Against Mosquito Borne Diseases" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PH6BqiHey24RioWvcyhkoOLRpeY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22528449/1228200153.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Sonu Mehta / Hindustan Times via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fumigation machines are part of campaigns against malaria in India. Endemic diseases like malaria are extremely dangerous.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CgOhXV"&gt;But endemic diseases, even though they seem less acutely scary, are still dangerous. Seasonal flu kills thousands of people a year in the United States. Malaria is a leading cause of death in countries where it’s endemic. Our collective anxiety might fade, but the virus will still be a clear risk. The level of regularly circulating coronavirus will layer on top of the other circulating diseases. It’ll &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21378046/covid-19-long-term-hospital-survellience-adjustments"&gt;raise the baseline number&lt;/a&gt; of people who get sick and die each year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aa9bL5"&gt;“Another killer has been added to the list of things that kill us,” Christakis says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="gW8jr0"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Another killer has been added to the list of things that kill us”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QBNK8y"&gt;Right now, around 600 people a day are dying from COVID-19 in the United States. If that was the average background level of disease, it’d mean something like an additional 200,000 deaths from infectious diseases each year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cDh156"&gt;Feeling our way toward the social end of the pandemic in the US also risks turning on blinders to the way COVID-19 could continue to burn through the rest of the world. The vaccine rollout is devastatingly unequal — high-income countries locked down &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/interactive/2021/coronavirus-vaccine-inequality-global/"&gt;over half&lt;/a&gt; of the world’s doses, and poorer countries likely won’t be able to immunize their populations for years. Low rates of COVID-19 in the US could create an illusion of security, but outbreaks around the world mean persistent risk. “I don’t think it’s fully safe for the US while the rest of the world suffers,” Nuzzo says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VURyhV"&gt;Luckily, we have a stake and some control over how the transition toward the end of the pandemic happens. Communities and their public health leadership can decide that they don’t want to normalize tens of thousands of additional deaths. They can invest money and effort and time into smothering the virus as much as possible. They can decide to say that the pandemic isn’t over in one country until it’s over everywhere. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="CraWqq"&gt;COVID-19 isn’t going anywhere, Christakis says. “The virus is just going to keep searching for victims.” Pandemics can’t last forever, and danger doesn’t always feel like an emergency. But the number of people we’re willing to lose to the virus without alarm bells ringing is up to us.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Xnudd"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1gcyBW"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22445906/social-end-pandemic-covid-adjustment-death-vibes"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22445906/social-end-pandemic-covid-adjustment-death-vibes</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-20T14:46:27-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-20T14:46:27-04:00</updated>
    <title>Slack had some problems on Thursday for more than an hour</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pueWRGSomJe0poqIhJ3iBDk2g2c=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69318276/acastro_190412_1777_slack_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3VQ0J5"&gt;Slack experienced frustrating issues for many on Thursday, including for some of us here at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. For me, some messages just wouldn’t send. But a little more than an hour after Slack first reported the outage, the company said that the issues were resolved. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nSRGX4"&gt;“We’ve released a fix for this issue, and Slack is up and running once again,” &lt;a href="https://status.slack.com/2021-05/33aed870657e30a0"&gt;Slack said in a post on its status site&lt;/a&gt; at 2:36PM ET. “If you are still experiencing any trouble, please fully quit your Slack app or browser using Command + Q (Mac) or Ctrl + Q (Windows/Linux), and then reopen it.” Slack first posted about the outage at 1:17PM ET.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HtTWIW"&gt;The next time there’s a Slack outage, I highly recommend you &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=slack%20down&amp;amp;src=typed_query&amp;amp;f=live"&gt;cruise Twitter&lt;/a&gt; to see the ridiculous &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NyloAndry/status/1395436475815243782"&gt;memes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Swainsch/status/1395436446337703939"&gt;GIFs&lt;/a&gt; that people post. You might not be able to work anyway, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0KMvFK"&gt;Slack also went down &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/4/22213105/slack-outage-down-2021-server-error"&gt;in January&lt;/a&gt; on the first full work day of the year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yBEvZn"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update May 20th, 2:46PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Slack confirmed that the outage has been fixed. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446007/slack-down-outage-messages-trouble-loading"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446007/slack-down-outage-messages-trouble-loading</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-20T14:42:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-20T14:42:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>How Ford’s F-150 Lightning stacks up against the Tesla Cybertruck and Hummer EV</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tACxlwQTQ5Ry_1-L1BmGFleEIZQ=/188x0:2213x1350/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69318558/3_16x9.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Ford&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Z71ovA"&gt;Ford has revealed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/19/22442777/ford-f-150-lightning-electric-truck-specs-price"&gt;its first all-electric F-150&lt;/a&gt;, the Lightning, and on paper it looks like a really compelling truck. It’s priced aggressively for an electric vehicle, has plenty of power, and looks to be more capable at towing and hauling than the cheapest gas-powered F-150s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F9YmLm"&gt;But Ford’s not alone in developing an electric pickup truck — far from it, in fact. There is a slew of electric pickups set to hit the market in the next year and a half or so. Tesla’s polarizing Cybertruck should start rolling off the line at the company’s new Texas factory at the end of 2021 or in early 2022. Rivian — a startup that has raised billions of dollars and is backed by Amazon and Ford — has an electric pickup called the R1T due out this June. And General Motors’ first electric pickup will be the gaudy Hummer, which the company has revived after a decade. That’s due out in late 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="1PrEgC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Ford F-150 Lightning revealed: an electric truck for the masses","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/19/22442777/ford-f-150-lightning-electric-truck-specs-price"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="9srBm3"&gt;The most interesting thing about these pickup trucks is perhaps not just that they’re electric. It’s that they’re all quite different from each other. Tesla’s Cybertruck is a radical rethink of a truck’s exterior design and body structure. The R1T is one of the most refined pickups ever made for off-roading. The Hummer is... well there’s not much the Hummer pickup &lt;em&gt;isn’t&lt;/em&gt;. The F-150 Lightning is about as straightforward as it gets — which is unsurprising for an electric version of the most popular vehicle in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SsTItf"&gt;Despite the diverse designs, all four of these electric trucks are going to court buyers who want to do Truck Stuff with them, meaning stats like power, torque, towing and hauling capacity, and of course, range will be crucial considerations (along with price). Here’s how they stack up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gZWJ0s"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10510162"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YXJi46"&gt;Ford’s electric pickup is really price competitive with the Cybertruck, though Tesla promises much more range and performance at the higher ends. The two designs could not be more different, but they track the closest, spec-wise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LrXiTl"&gt;The electric Hummer pickup truck outclasses both of those in a lot of ways (like max horsepower and torque), but it costs as much as a house, so it better. Rivian’s premium pickup is right in the middle, with some really good performance promised at a more digestible price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NKbgw8"&gt;There are others on the horizon, to be sure, but they’re either too far away to consider right now or there’s just not enough detail about them to properly stack them up. General Motors has committed to making &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/6/22370058/gm-chevy-electric-silverado-pickup-truck"&gt;an electric Chevy Silverado&lt;/a&gt;, though it doesn’t have a release date yet. Michigan startup Bollinger has spent years teasing a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/24/20930252/bollinger-motors-electric-trucks-b1-b2-trucks-price-specs"&gt;boxy electric work truck&lt;/a&gt; (plus a few variants) but still does not have a clear path to production. Lordstown Motors has a pickup truck slated for production at the end of this year, but it’s exclusively for fleets (and the company still has to finish a &lt;em&gt;lot &lt;/em&gt;of real-world testing). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BnntS4"&gt;Meanwhile, one of the most compelling things about the F-150 Lightning is that it stacks up really well against its gas-powered siblings — especially because Ford is only selling it in a four-door SuperCrew configuration to start, which is its most expensive cab layout. Here’s a snapshot of the Lightning up against the cheapest gas-powered SuperCrew F-150 and the hybrid F-150.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="g2sksC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10510467"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wkROD1"&gt;The base Lightning obviously can’t compete with the ability to go nearly 500 miles on a tank of gas or nearly 800 miles in the hybrid. But Ford has packed the electric F-150 with a lot of really compelling features — like a gigantic front trunk, tons of onboard power for running tools or even your home in a pinch — and has made its all-wheel drive standard. How many buyers will those features sway? We’ll have to wait until 2022 to find out. But Ford has already &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/05/20/ford-already-has-20000-reservations-for-new-electric-f-150-lightning-pickup-.html"&gt;taken more than 20,000 $100 deposits&lt;/a&gt; for the electric F-150, so it’s off to a pretty good start. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uLbD3Z"&gt;Related: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="EWSRJA"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Ford F150 Electric|102099" data-volume-uuid="0fa4f5fdb" data-volume-id="102099" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-851" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22445725/ford-f150-lightning-ev-truck-specs-cybertruck-hummer-rivian"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22445725/ford-f150-lightning-ev-truck-specs-cybertruck-hummer-rivian</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-20T14:03:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-20T14:03:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>Snap’s new Spectacles let you see the world in augmented reality</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A photo of a woman wearing the fourth-gen Spectacles, which are black with angular frames." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-TRdQFrgKF_-Q6eS-tXq0cVd9L0=/120x0:1740x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69318328/Spectacles_KatVHarris_Portrait.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Snap’s fourth-generation Spectacles. | Photo: Snap&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bdAtUx"&gt;Snap’s new Spectacles glasses are its most ambitious yet. But there’s a big catch: you can’t buy them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5KyxKs"&gt;On Thursday, Snap CEO Evan Spiegel unveiled the company’s first true augmented reality glasses, technology that he and rivals like Facebook think will one day be as ubiquitous as mobile phones. A demo showed virtual butterflies fluttering over colorful plants and landing in Spiegel’s extended hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ye9Tqb"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The next generation of Spectacles can help unlock a new way to use AR hands-free”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="a6OcHH"&gt;The new Spectacles have dual waveguide displays capable of superimposing AR effects made with Snapchat’s software tools. The frame features four built-in microphones, two stereo speakers, and a built-in touchpad. Front-facing cameras help the glasses detect objects and surfaces you’re looking at so that graphics more naturally interact with the world around you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8nghss"&gt;These Spectacles, however, aren’t ready for the mass market. Unlike past models, Snap isn’t selling them. Instead, it’s giving them directly to an undisclosed number of AR effects creators through an application program online. (Another indication they aren’t ready for everyday use: the battery only lasts 30 minutes.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;div id="OBlzSP"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Tapping the vast potential of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Snap?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Snap&lt;/a&gt;’s AR platform, the next generation of Spectacles allow you to overlay Lenses directly onto the world in front of you, for an immersive AR experience. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SnapPartnerSummit?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#SnapPartnerSummit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://t.co/r4XnSC886z"&gt;https://t.co/r4XnSC886z&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/UTDDoxwBOO"&gt;pic.twitter.com/UTDDoxwBOO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Spectacles (@Spectacles) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Spectacles/status/1395439601590833156?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 20, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hbMbFD"&gt;The idea is to encourage a small portion of the 200,000 people who already make AR effects in Snapchat to experiment with creating experiences for the new Spectacles, according to Spiegel. Like the bright yellow vending machines Snap used to sell the first version of Spectacles several years ago, the approach could end up being a clever way to build buzz for the glasses ahead of their wide release. Spiegel has said that AR glasses will take roughly a decade to reach mainstream adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cAteAd"&gt;“I don’t believe the phone is going away,” he told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; in an interview this week. “I just think that the next generation of Spectacles can help unlock a new way to use AR hands-free, and the ability to really roam around with your eyes looking up at the horizon, out at the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LSRl6D"&gt;The first two generations of Spectacles, released &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/11/21/13671164/snapchat-spectacles-glasses-review-camera-sunglasses"&gt;in 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/26/17279434/snapchat-spectacles-pricing-availability-snap-wearable-camera"&gt; and 2018&lt;/a&gt;, looked like sunglasses with a single camera in the corner of the frame. They let you snap videos (and later photos) in a unique, spherical format that could then be transferred to your phone and posted to Snapchat or another social network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid c-image-grid__odd c-image-grid__odd-first-wide"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Snap’s fourth generation Spectacles are black, with thick areas at the hinges to house components. They feature angular lenses and cameras beside each hinge." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TtxSBUgI8D7eDom5DfyuubyZ44Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22528614/Spectacles_Product_1.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The glasses fold up and fit inside a black charging case." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XWSM0_JTFMPYQn7JKPMbKsUXMGc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22528642/Spectacles_Product_4.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A side view showing the right temple of the glasses. A touchpad beside the lens lets you control the Spectacles." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QWQLAYxxr1mErUksYy91IEeT3wk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22528643/Spectacles_Product_3.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Above: Snap’s new fourth-generation Spectacles. Lower: the Spectacles in their case, and a side-view showing their touch panel. Images: Snap&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="533QIv"&gt;Snap, which calls itself a camera company, started moving more toward AR in 2019 with the launch of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/12/20951783/snap-spectacles-3-review-snapchat-glasses-price-specs-features"&gt;its third-generation Spectacles&lt;/a&gt;. That model added a second camera to detect depth in videos, allowing for more advanced effects to be applied afterward. But they lacked displays. You had to shoot a video, import it to Snapchat, and then apply AR effects — which Snap calls Lenses — later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MJNBhW"&gt;The new fourth generation of Spectacles come from a secretive hardware division of the company called Snap Lab, which is &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/snap-plans-hardware-push-with-ar-spectacles-drone"&gt;also working on a camera drone&lt;/a&gt;. They weigh 134 grams, more than double the weight of the previous version but far less than Microsoft’s Hololens AR headset. They’re designed to be worn indoors or outdoors with up to 2,000 nits of display brightness, a tradeoff the company clearly made to favor display richness at the expense of battery life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="20lfrb"&gt;Two front-facing cameras use the software Snap built for its mobile phone Lenses to automatically detect physical surfaces and place effects in a way that doesn’t obstruct the real world. Two stereo speakers capture audio and allow for the wearer to control them by voice. A touchpad on the side of the frame operates an interface in the displays that Snap calls the Lens Carousel, allowing the wearer to switch AR effects they’re seeing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid c-image-grid__odd"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="An image showing artworks appearing in AR on a basketball court. It’s a first person view through the new Spectacles." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iuLSIO5Fq6DQ-vC9h4YVDxbaMb0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22528666/Spectacles_LeightonMcDonald_1.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="An image showing sea creatures like jelly fish floating through the air above the beach at sunset. It’s a first person view through the new Spectacles." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WtXjvYv5W622Iar7ibUUTaX12WQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22528665/Spectacles_ClayWeishaar_Lens_1.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A first person shot through the glasses showing a series of bubbles representing different AR filters." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x0WuriXyeXvk5iJiK5Dtn8wF--Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22528664/lens_carousel.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Above: two images show AR effects as seen through the new glasses. Lower: the lens carousel interface lets you select different AR effects. Images: Snap&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5bLrnr"&gt;The new Spectacles were announced Thursday at Snap’s virtual Partner Summit for developers, where the company previewed a number of new augmented reality features for Snapchat. Its AR clothing try-on tech can now handle watches and glasses, and businesses will be able to more easily add AR versions of their online catalogs for Snapchat’s 500 million monthly users to try and purchase. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="xEuxm5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“You have to invent a whole new way of interacting with computing”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hqFAym"&gt;A new feature, called Connected Lenses, allows multiple people to see and interact with the same scene in AR. Snap is also launching an AR “innovation lab” called Ghost and is committing $3.5 million to support creators making effects, with another $1 million in funding with Verizon to fund AR experiences used over 5G.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9CtqbE"&gt;While Snap is known primarily for the Snapchat app now, these Spectacles indicate how the company’s ambition is to be a major player in the race to build AR glasses. Facebook, Apple, and other tech giants are currently working on their competing devices. Facebook plans to debut its own pair of smart glasses in partnership with RayBan later this year, though they won’t feature AR displays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZpUuqQ"&gt;According to Spiegel, head-worn devices like these new Spectacles will create a big shift in how we interact with computers. While Snap is betting that millions of people will eventually want to wear Spectacles, the company is content for now to build in public alongside its creators. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C9FQrE"&gt;“You have to invent a whole new way of interacting with computing when it’s volumetric and integrated with the space around you,” Spiegel said. “So I don’t see Snapchat transitioning to wearables that directly, but one of the things that’s really fun is to think about what the new interaction paradigms can look like.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22445481/snap-spectacles-ar-augmented-reality-announced"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22445481/snap-spectacles-ar-augmented-reality-announced</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Heath</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-20T13:55:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-20T13:55:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Snapchat gets augmented reality Legos you can build with a friend</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7zpLTPTWVk2iK-lUo9DrRKuKWo8=/158x0:1781x1082/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69318239/Screen_Shot_2021_05_20_at_9.31.31_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zQhWLk"&gt;Snapchat is introducing a new type of augmented reality lens, called “Connected Lenses,” which allows Snapchat users to connect and enjoy an AR experience or game together — even if they’re not in the same physical space. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ehdjnl"&gt;The company is partnering with Lego for its first Connected Lens, which allows users to build a Lego model in augmented reality together, whether that’s in the same room or through the internet from around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3eWUwt4SZjBng6BSaAyQ-CWQhwA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22528419/Screen_Shot_2021_05_20_at_9.30.58_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="WMo2N9"&gt;In the demo video that Snap showed off, both users see the same floating Lego model on a table in their respective homes and can add parts, effects, and animations to the model, which are reflected for both users in real time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ST47nH"&gt;The move marks Snap’s latest expansion of augmented reality lenses, which include the popular photo filter lenses, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/4/18294062/snapchat-landmarkers-ar-lenses-filters-eiffel-tower-rainbows"&gt;company’s “Landmarker” lenses&lt;/a&gt; for interacting with famous landmarks in AR, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/10/17551428/snapchat-lens-explorer-community-filters"&gt;the community-sourced Lens Explorer&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bHMRSH"&gt;Creators will also be able to build new Connected Lenses using Snap’s Lens Studio. The new multiperson Lego Lens should be available soon on Lego’s Snapchat profile. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="49LZid"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22445495/snapchat-connected-lenses-ar-friends-lego"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22445495/snapchat-connected-lenses-ar-friends-lego</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-20T13:35:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-20T13:35:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Snap will launch a standalone iOS video editing app called Story Studio later this year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ECWt6q7FFJPf0d1Z0j43WzVMX5c=/63x0:738x450/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69318136/Story_Studio_GIF.0.gif" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Snap’s forthcoming iOS app Story Studio will allow people to handle more complicated videos edits from their mobile device. | Snap&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CENQ6T"&gt;Snap wants to be the company people think of when they go to edit videos on mobile, so during its annual partnership summit today, the company announced a new iOS app that’ll help it achieve that goal: Story Studio. It’ll give people editing tools specifically designed for mobile, or vertical, videos. The app will pull data from Snapchat and its new Spotlight feature, more familiarly recognized as its TikTok competitor, to help people figure out how and what to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Afq8Kr"&gt;They can look through Snapchat insights, like what’s trending on the app across sounds, hashtags, and lenses. Lenses will be built directly into Story Studio, as well as Snapchat Sounds and stickers, so editors can add those. Of course, like most other video editing apps, users can trim their videos and edit frame by frame. They can then share directly to Snapchat through a built-in button, or download their work to publish in other apps. Notably, content made in Story Studio won’t include a watermark, meaning if it’s published on other platforms, like Instagram’s Reels, it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274332/instagram-algorithm-tiktok-watermark-recommendation-software-best-practices"&gt;won’t be demoted&lt;/a&gt; by the algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9l0wnH"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_YDx3zJ-3-I?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="saNyuM"&gt;The app will roll out later this year, and the company didn’t share any other details about a possible Android version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wn2pNs"&gt;Additionally today, Snap provided updates on Spotlight. For one, it’s making it easier for video editors to upload content they made in more advanced desktop apps, like Final Cut Pro. Spotlight content can now be uploaded, and watched, through the web at &lt;a href="http://snapchat.com/spotlight"&gt;snapchat.com/spotlight&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FHFZDnRdgaXqUH7lX1T8BemNPog=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22527733/Spotlight_Web_Upload.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF: Snap&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Snapchat is making it easier for people to upload Spotlight content. Now they can do so through their desktop computer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="4EJ0ke"&gt;Finally, Snap also added that it would no longer be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/23/21585513/snapchat-snap-spotlight-creators-app-update-tiktok"&gt;distributing $1 million per day&lt;/a&gt; to its top Spotlight creators. Instead, starting June 1st, it’ll distribute millions per month and didn’t specify exactly how much. The amount creators receive will be based on the engagement their posts receive, as it is now, and there’s no set limit on the number of people who can get paid. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OzlmSC"&gt;This could be a potentially big deal for the company as it heralds Spotlight as a major success. Some teens &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/15/style/snapchat-spotlight.html"&gt;became nearly overnight millionaires&lt;/a&gt;, and Snap &lt;a href="https://s25.q4cdn.com/442043304/files/doc_financials/2021/q1/Snap-Inc.-Q1-2021-Transcript.pdf"&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; over 125 million used the feature in March. At the same time, Snap also says more than 500 million people are now monthly active users, which it announced today. It’s possible Spotlight had a hand in this growth, but the number of people logging on might decrease when the promise of a million distributed dollars per day disappears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="14s1qv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22445373/snap-ios-story-studio-app-video-edit-app-spotlight"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22445373/snap-ios-story-studio-app-video-edit-app-spotlight</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
