<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-15T19:36:08-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T19:36:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T19:36:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>After seeing new leaked photos of the Pixel 6, I think I finally get the phone’s unusual design</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tQPglv-t6irHT0jFmscKCsBsPpQ=/8x0:4096x2725/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70002129/FBxXgMvWUAUanqP.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Pixel 6’s distinctive look is easy to spot at a distance.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1449129719782326274" target="_blank"&gt;Evan Blass on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yqjx77"&gt;We’re just a few days away from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22691850/google-pixel-6-event-2021-fall-announcement"&gt;Google’s October 19th launch event&lt;/a&gt; for the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro, but if you want an early look at what to expect, you might want to check out this &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1449129643542519811"&gt;big thread of leaked images&lt;/a&gt; from prolific leaker Evan Blass. The thread includes what appear to be official renders of both phones, images of cases, and some photos of people using the phones — and it’s that last category of images that were the most interesting to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KptRwm"&gt;Ever since early rumored renders of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446078/google-pixel-6-pro-leak-specs-camera-screen"&gt;Pixel 6 lineup&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447011/google-pixel-6-leaks-renders-pics-specs"&gt;hit the web&lt;/a&gt;, I wondered exactly why Google decided to make the massive camera bar across the back of both phones. It never really appealed to me, and since the bar isn’t flush with the back of the phones, I’ve been worried it’s going to make them wobble when laid on a desk.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Google’s new Pixel 6 phones, regular and Pro" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4ckQnWc66L7bV9d2osK3PMYdxPE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22755089/Google_Pixel_6__Portfolio_Shot.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out those camera bars.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MnM2al"&gt;Blass’ photo dump includes twelve photos of people &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1449129710722629643"&gt;actually&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1449129719782326274"&gt;using&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1449129727051042816"&gt;the phones&lt;/a&gt;, and seeing these photos clicked something about the Pixel 6’s design in place for me: the camera bar and two-tone color choices give the Pixel 6 lineup a unique look that you won’t be able to mistake for any other phone. Even if somebody doesn’t know what the Pixel 6 is, they definitely won’t get it mixed up with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22684421/apple-iphone-13-mini-review"&gt;an iPhone&lt;/a&gt;, and that distinctive appearance could be enough for people who haven’t tried a Pixel before to pick up a Pixel 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="LdKhxg"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="und" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://t.co/v1jdMmlkHc"&gt;pic.twitter.com/v1jdMmlkHc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— E (@evleaks) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1449129727051042816?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8tNh6D"&gt;Another set of photos answered a question I had about the Pixel 6: what it would look like in a case. Based on the images Blass shared, Google’s &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1449129685552672777"&gt;official&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1449129697208684544"&gt;cases&lt;/a&gt; will fit around the camera bump, but edges around the bump appear to have a ridge, so the phone won’t sit flat on its back even with the cases on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="E9wMyH"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="und" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://t.co/y7ip43FVen"&gt;pic.twitter.com/y7ip43FVen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— E (@evleaks) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1449129697208684544?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="niwxzX"&gt;Blass also shared renders of the Pixel 6 in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1449129643542519811"&gt;green&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1449129651062853633"&gt;black&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1449129658537193478"&gt;orange&lt;/a&gt; and the Pixel 6 Pro in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1449129665612943364"&gt;silver / gray&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1449129672390885376"&gt;black&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1449129679202443264"&gt;gold&lt;/a&gt;. These renders don’t have many surprises, since Google already revealed the designs and colors of the phones &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605094/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-specs-ai-ml"&gt;in August&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="H7xBnx"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="es" dir="ltr"&gt;Pixel 6 Pro &lt;a href="https://t.co/CdXMDezk57"&gt;pic.twitter.com/CdXMDezk57&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— E (@evleaks) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/1449129665612943364?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BqRCI6"&gt;Last week, Blass leaked some other photos of the upcoming phones as well, including images of a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/7/22714141/google-pixel-6-pro-marketing-images-leak-evleaks-wireless-charger-face-unlock"&gt;new Pixel Stand wireless charger&lt;/a&gt; (which, according to an entirely different leak, is rumored to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22651097/google-pixel-6-pro-stand-23w-wireless-charging"&gt;support 23W wireless charging&lt;/a&gt;). We won’t have long to wait until we learn more about the Pixel 6, though, so you should keep it locked to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; for our coverage of the phone’s October 19th launch event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="1Ngjrf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"This is the Pixel 6","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22605094/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-specs-ai-ml"},{"title":"Retailer leak suggests Google’s Pixel 6 will have 23W wireless charging","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22651097/google-pixel-6-pro-stand-23w-wireless-charging"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22729135/google-pixel-6-pro-leaked-photos-images-renders-evan-blass"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22729135/google-pixel-6-pro-leaked-photos-images-renders-evan-blass</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T19:02:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T19:02:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>A year later, Apple’s MagSafe continues to underwhelm </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The watch charger flips up so you can use the Apple Watch in nightstand mode." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P6OOA5yf8u1He-TS4NYA6S22rRU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70002069/dbohn_201109_4283_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dieter Bohn / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="QxPh0J"&gt;One year ago yesterday, I wrote &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/10/14/21515490/apple-iphone-12-magsafe-accessories-ecosystem"&gt;how MagSafe could be the biggest reason to buy an iPhone 12&lt;/a&gt;. I believed it, too. It looked like Apple had cracked the code to effortlessly accessorize the iPhone and even add modular new capabilities. The company showed its pricey new MagSafe cases and wallets seemingly snapping into place, plus faster wireless charging. The future looked bright. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IzRPOV"&gt;But if you became an early adopter like me, you might have wound up disappointed. As &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;’s Mark Gurman &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/markgurman/status/1449111887388549126"&gt;points out&lt;/a&gt;, two of Apple’s first overpriced MagSafe accessories are already out of date. First, &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/10/15/magsafe-duo-apple-watch-series-7-no-fast-charge/"&gt;we just learned Friday&lt;/a&gt; that Apple’s $129 MagSafe Duo Charger can’t fast-charge an Apple Watch Series 7. Second, Apple has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22674261/apple-iphone-leather-wallet-magsafe-find-my-tracking"&gt;already replaced the $59 MagSafe Leather Wallet with a better version&lt;/a&gt; that you supports Find My so your phone can remember where it was when it got removed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ODYxiT"&gt;I think Gurman might actually be undercounting, though. The new Leather Wallet with MagSafe &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t support Apple’s $49 Clear Case with MagSafe, so hope you didn’t buy one of those thinking it’d be futureproof — apparently, it blocks the NFC tags that MagSafe accessories like the Wallet use to passively ID themselves to the phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aieFb5"&gt;And while we’re on the subject of cases, &lt;em&gt;every official iPhone 12&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;case&lt;/em&gt; (and likely the vast majority of third-party ones) are incompatible with the iPhone 13 lineup, because the camera bump got wider this time around. I took advantage of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22684911/iphone-13-true-cost-of-free-phone-iphone-13-pro"&gt;those “free” iPhone offers &lt;/a&gt;to upgrade to an iPhone 13 Mini (loving &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22709829/iphone-13-mini-pro-max-battery-tests"&gt;the improved battery life&lt;/a&gt;, by the way), and now I have an expensive but useless Clear Case with MagSafe that I’m not sure what to do with. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/veSIf7yagsYNfzHMXo1A66G1tO4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21958778/iphone_magsafe_gif.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5lxINl"&gt;Those are just the latest disappointments, though. It didn’t take long before iPhone 12 buyers like me discovered that no, Apple’s new cases don’t actually snap into place like they do in the Apple’s animations I showed you last year (see above and below). They still rely on a rim that grasps the edges of your phone and requires pressure to insert and remove. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FoW1bR2d1LZ27Mtsv47mblNFWzE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21958810/iphone_magsafe_4_gif.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dhjfvk"&gt;Several &lt;em&gt;Verge &lt;/em&gt;editors have also complained that the $39 MagSafe charging cable doesn’t have a long enough cord to use on the couch or in bed where its quick-detach feature might actually help — but Apple’s still selling the same 1-meter cable a year later. My MagSafe pad now sits unused on a shelf, while I begrudgingly plug in a Lightning cable instead. Meanwhile, both it and the $129 MagSafe Duo still don’t come with charging bricks, even though the previous Apple USB-C chargers you might own (18W and 29W) &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22169285/apple-29w-usb-c-power-adapter-brick-magsafe-duo-incompatible"&gt;aren’t good enough to drive them at full speed&lt;/a&gt;. They require 20W and 30W chargers, respectively, which Apple sells for $19 or $49 each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qWq5PO"&gt;And though it took most of a year for Apple to release &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22588777/apple-magsafe-battery-review-size-iphone-12-mini"&gt;its own MagSafe Battery Pack&lt;/a&gt;, we were underwhelmed by its capacity in our review. I bought and returned one myself, though not for any of the reasons Dieter laid out. I just couldn’t stand how weak the vertical magnet was even with Apple’s own Clear Case, the pack always twisting in my hand. (Without the case, it made my iPhone 12 Mini uncomfortably warm to hold.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qry9ui"&gt;Every one of these examples speaks to a lack of foresight around MagSafe, and that’s unusual. Foresight is generally one of Apple’s strengths, bringing out new products and technologies only when their time has come. But to me, the real tragedy of MagSafe’s first year is the lack of a larger ecosystem. The entire time we’ve been waiting for Apple to show us what MagSafe is truly capable of, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22629703/apple-magsafe-charging-mfi-standard-accessory"&gt;it’s been keeping the rest of the world from getting out ahead&lt;/a&gt; — using its MFi program and artificial charging restrictions built into the iPhone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dc0B0S"&gt;Combining the Qi wireless charging standard with non-patentable magnets, MagSafe should have been a lightning rod to customization and modularity. So far, Apple has insulated itself — and us — from the possibilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="dryAbs"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple’s been playing it too MagSafe","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22629703/apple-magsafe-charging-mfi-standard-accessory"},{"title":"The Lightning port isn’t about convenience; it’s about control","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/24/22690338/apple-iphone-lightning-ports-convenience-control-usb-c-eu-wireless-charging-mfi-magsafe"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728967/apple-magsafe-duo-wallet-cases-charging"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728967/apple-magsafe-duo-wallet-cases-charging</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T18:46:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T18:46:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>US Treasury says ransomware payouts in 2021 could top entire past decade</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VY5KvL-tDj5ek3mNZdkCAASbQ60=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70002018/acastro_170726_1777_0008.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7nJRIU"&gt;The ransomware business is booming this year and could be bringing in billions for some of its top players, according to &lt;a href="https://www.fincen.gov/news/news-releases/ransomware-trends-bank-secrecy-act-data-between-january-2021-and-june-2021"&gt;a report released&lt;/a&gt; by the US Treasury’s Financial Crimes Enforcement Network, or FinCEN (&lt;a href="https://therecord.media/treasury-said-it-tied-5-2-billion-in-btc-transactions-to-ransomware-payments/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;The Record&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The report analyzed the massive growth in ransomware payments in the first half of 2021 by looking at suspicious activity reports from financial institutions and was even able to estimate how much some hacking groups were making by analyzing blockchain transactions linked to their wallets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BI3REj"&gt;The report found that reports of suspicious ransomware-related transactions totaled around $590 million from January 2021 to June 2021. One of the most shocking numbers in the report is that the top 10 hacking groups have trafficked around $5.2 billion worth of Bitcoin over the past three years.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_df_n0LoOtbecwkHBtkwIE3EDZ8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22930534/Screen_Shot_2021_10_15_at_1.46.33_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Chart: US Treasury&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The oldest variant on this chart started in 2018, but the data FinCEN analyzed goes back to 2011.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="IJDkx8"&gt;It’s a mind-boggling figure, but it’s likely an incomplete one. FinCEN came to it by finding wallets linked to payments to the top 10 ransomware programs, then analyzing their outgoing transactions (with the money likely headed off to be laundered, though it’s worth noting that it’s almost impossible to know whether it came from ransomware activities). The hacking groups could have more crypto squirreled away in wallets they haven’t touched yet. Or they could have it in other currencies — the analysis only covered Bitcoin, and the report indicates there’s been an increase in hackers asking for alternative coins like Monero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KkdhXY"&gt;In June, Chainalysis’ research director told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the blockchain data company had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/24/22545675/ransomware-cryptocurrency-regulation-hacks"&gt;labeled 2020 “the year of ransomware”&lt;/a&gt; and wondered if 2021 wouldn’t get the same title. It seems that the answer is yes, though maybe it needs an upgrade — FinCEN estimates that there was $200 million more paid out in the first half of 2021 than in the entirety of 2020. It says that if the trends keep up, hackers could make more from ransomware this year than they did in the past decade. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GHdzZUAD8-ZqCi1T3Gb9dAZ-YSk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22930536/Screen_Shot_2021_10_15_at_1.47.59_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Graph: US Treasury&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ransomware has been on the rise.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="o7nkwK"&gt;It’s not a surprise that the ransomware business is booming in 2021 — we’ve seen hackers hit and extort &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22616882/gigabyte-technologies-ransomware-attack-data-leak-112-gb-ransomexx"&gt;major tech companies&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/10/22428996/colonial-pipeline-ransomware-attack-apology-investigation"&gt;pipelines&lt;/a&gt;, hospitals, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446388/cna-insurance-ransomware-attack-40-million-dollar-ransom"&gt;insurance companies&lt;/a&gt;, and more. But this report shows how paying ransoms can help fund hackers’ attempts to get at new targets, with the massive success of just a few groups. The government has been working to clamp down on this vicious cycle, though. The Department of Justice &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/7/22714241/us-justice-department-cryptocurrency-enforcement-unit"&gt;is setting up a team&lt;/a&gt; to go after the exchanges that facilitate crime-related transactions, like ransomware demands. But with billions on the line, it’s going to have to overcome huge incentives if it wants to stay ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="qNJbkY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Ransom notes: how ransomware funds more ransomware","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/24/22545675/ransomware-cryptocurrency-regulation-hacks"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728765/us-treasury-ransomware-payout-numbers-reports-2021-first-half-cybercrime"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728765/us-treasury-ransomware-payout-numbers-reports-2021-first-half-cybercrime</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T18:20:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T18:20:52-04:00</updated>
    <title>Valve bans blockchain games and NFTs on Steam, Epic will try to make it work</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eQwrFGXtUrMP0sAp8zX80GVAeBc=/0x0:1820x1213/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70000611/acastro_180509_1777_steam_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IVcxLA"&gt;Games that use blockchain technology or let users exchange NFTs or cryptocurrencies won’t be allowed on Steam, according to a rule added to &lt;a href="https://partner.steamgames.com/doc/gettingstarted/onboarding"&gt;Valve’s “What you shouldn’t publish on Steam” list&lt;/a&gt;. The change &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SpacePirate_io/status/1448713803680473089"&gt;was pointed out by SpacePirate&lt;/a&gt;, a developer working on an NFT-based game, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SpacePirate_io/status/1448713807312801796?s=20"&gt;who said&lt;/a&gt; that the change was because the company doesn’t allow game items that could have real-world value. But Steam could also be avoiding controversy with the move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l2VLSl"&gt;Steam is one of the most well-known PC game stores, but it’s not the only one. While Epic’s CEO Tim Sweeney has said that the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696978/epic-tim-sweeney-nft-scam-concerns-web-3"&gt;isn’t interested in touching NFTs&lt;/a&gt;, that policy doesn’t seem to apply to games in its store: &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/e/22493091"&gt;Epic told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that it’s “open” to the idea of games that use NFTs or cryptocurrencies in an email on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zkI3KB"&gt;Looking at &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20210826165938/https://partner.steamgames.com/doc/gettingstarted/onboarding"&gt;a Wayback Machine capture of Steam’s rule page from late August&lt;/a&gt;, there are only 12 rules and no mention of cryptocurrencies or NFTs. The new rule is also missing from other documents — it currently doesn’t show up on the &lt;a href="https://partner.steamgames.com/steamdirect/"&gt;Joining the Steamworks Distribution Program page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="RMxaqo"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Steam's point of view is that items have value and they don't allow items that can have real-world value on their platform. While I respect their choice, I fundamentally believe that NFTs and blockchain games are the future. It's why I started this journey with all of you.&lt;br&gt;3/4&lt;/p&gt;— Age of Rust (@SpacePirate_io) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SpacePirate_io/status/1448713807312801796?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 14, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6AOvwC"&gt;Steam has a history of making controversial moderation decisions, especially &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/1/17417790/steam-pornography-rules-guidelines-porn-visual-novels"&gt;when it comes to games with sexual content&lt;/a&gt;. In this case, though, it doesn’t seem like people are pressing F to pay respects to NFT games — a majority of the replies and quote tweets to SpacePirate’s tweets are praising Valve for the move (or mocking those that are upset about it). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="52ry6n"&gt;Valve didn’t immediately respond to a request for comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="m9r447"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10374749"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="U2XNch"&gt;It’s perhaps understandable why Steam would want to avoid having NFTs on its platform. Besides the justification cited by SpacePirate that they could have real-world value (which seems a bit weak, given the massive commercial communities around things like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/7/14/12186584/valve-gambling-statement-counter-strike"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CS:GO&lt;/em&gt; skins&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Team Fortress 2&lt;/em&gt; hats), NFT and crypto-based games don’t have the best reputations. There’s the infamous Evolved Apes saga where a developer sold NFTs with the promise that they’d be included in a fighting game but then &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/y3dyem/investors-spent-millions-on-evolved-apes-nfts-then-they-got-scammed"&gt;seemingly took the money and ran&lt;/a&gt;. There are some &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22632765/vine-creator-dom-hofmann-blockchain-video-game-nft-supdrive"&gt;potentially interesting game concepts that use NFTs&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s hard to say how many of them would’ve been a good fit for Steam even if they were allowed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="E7tPBT"&gt;&lt;q&gt;NFTs may become a big question in platform moderation&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xmrBVc"&gt;Steam and Epic’s different approaches highlight the fact that any platform or store that moderates content will likely have to make a decision about whether it wants to allow apps or games to sell NFTs — one of the biggest question marks right now &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/reckless/status/1448054684128878592"&gt;may be Apple&lt;/a&gt; and how it handles apps like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/20/22684372/opensea-app-nft-ios-android-apple-google"&gt;OpenSea&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723131/coinbase-nfts-crypto-marketplace"&gt;Coinbase&lt;/a&gt; should they decide to start letting users buy the digital tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ntLlHb"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated October 15th, 6:20PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated with information from Epic that it’s open to blockchain-based games on its store.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728425/valve-steam-blockchain-nft-crypto-ban-games-age-of-rust"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728425/valve-steam-blockchain-nft-crypto-ban-games-age-of-rust</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T18:17:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T18:17:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>Epic says it’s ‘open’ to blockchain games after Steam bans them</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nEgoi9-vLVEEZckDBQtq5tGv4Ak=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70001923/acastro_20200818_1777_epicApple_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="i37MNz"&gt;Epic tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that it’s “open to games that support cryptocurrency or blockchain-based assets” on its game store, unlike its competitor Valve which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728425/valve-steam-blockchain-nft-crypto-ban-games-age-of-rust"&gt;has banned games that feature blockchain technology or NFTs from Steam&lt;/a&gt;. When we asked about allowing games that featured NFTs, Epic told us there’d be some limitations, but that it’s willing to work with “early developers” in the “new field.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wydB5N"&gt;Epic says that the games would have to comply with financial laws, make it clear how the blockchain is used, and have appropriate age ratings. It also says that developers won’t be able to use Epic’s payment service to accept crypto; they would have to use their own payment systems instead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZUyCOD"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Epic will clarify its rules in the future&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="D684tz"&gt;Epic’s CEO Tim Sweeney has said that the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22696978/epic-tim-sweeney-nft-scam-concerns-web-3"&gt;isn’t interested in touching NFTs&lt;/a&gt;, but that statement now appears to only apply to its own games. Epic tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that it will clarify the rules as it works with developers to understand how they plan to use blockchain tech in their games. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1449146317129895938"&gt;Sweeney also tweeted&lt;/a&gt; some additional thoughts after we published this story: he says Epic welcomes “innovation in the areas of technology and finance,” and suggests that blockchain isn’t inherently good or bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="i5HPPV"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;As a technology, the blockchain is just a distributed transactional database with a decentralized business model that incentivize investment in hardware to expand the database's capacity. This has utility whether or not a particular use of it succeeds or fails.&lt;/p&gt;— Tim Sweeney (@TimSweeneyEpic) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1449147941407571974?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="z1GANJ"&gt;None of this means that developers spurned by Steam can rush out and throw their game up on the Epic Game Store. Currently, Epic’s self-publishing program &lt;a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/publish"&gt;is in closed beta&lt;/a&gt;, and Epic’s FAQ says it chooses who can join on a “case-by-case basis.” Epic, however, has shown itself to be a fairly permissive platform owner — something that became a point of contention in its trial with Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22425759/epic-apple-trial-app-store-itch-io-offensive-sexualized-unspeakable-games-day-5"&gt;when lawyers brought up&lt;/a&gt; the “offensive and sexualized” games that were available on Itch.io, a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/22/22395997/epic-games-store-pc-apps-windows-store-brave-discord-itch"&gt;game store accessible on Epic’s game store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TFO99b"&gt;Allowing games that Steam bans is another way that Epic could compete with Valve. Epic has already shown that it’s willing to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22418782/epic-games-store-free-games-cost-apple-trial-arkham-subnautica-mutant-year-zero"&gt;make big bets&lt;/a&gt; trying to make its store a major player in the PC gaming space, and this could be another play to get some gamers or developers on its side. Some NFT fans immediately looked to Epic after the news about Steam broke. Enjin, a company that helps developers integrate NFTs into their products (&lt;a href="https://www.ageofrustgame.com/enjin"&gt;including SpacePirate&lt;/a&gt;, who &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SpacePirate_io/status/1448713803680473089?s=20"&gt;tweeted about their game being taken off of Steam&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/enjin/status/1449113287291981826"&gt;retweeted our Steam article&lt;/a&gt;, and tagged Epic CEO Tim Sweeney, asking to talk. It seems now they have at least one question answered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="QCCPCd"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Disappointed to see short-sighted decisions that are directly impacting our adopters like &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SpacePirate_io?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@SpacePirate_io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@TimSweeneyEpic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/EpicGames?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@EpicGames&lt;/a&gt; let's chat? &lt;a href="https://t.co/oQ8Y9OScS8"&gt;https://t.co/oQ8Y9OScS8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Enjin (@enjin) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/enjin/status/1449113287291981826?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UnT3wJ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update October 15th, 9:10PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added tweet from Tim Sweeney. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22729050/epic-game-store-open-to-blockchain-cryptocurrency-nft-games"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22729050/epic-game-store-open-to-blockchain-cryptocurrency-nft-games</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T17:49:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T17:49:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>McDonald’s is testing the McPlant, a Beyond Meat meatless burger</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="New McPlant McDonald’s burger" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Tuq7ehbHiF_WK7FksiM5Rbu7VdQ=/113x0:1328x810/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70001802/mcplant_mcdonalds_beyond_meat.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by McDonald’s&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mG8wnh"&gt;McDonald’s new plant-based burger, aptly named the McPlant, is coming to eight restaurants across the US (via &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/11/09/mcdonalds-to-test-mcplant-which-includes-its-own-meat-free-burger-next-year-beyond-meat-shares-fall.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The fast-food chain teamed up with Beyond Meat to make the meatless option. This comes about a year after McDonald’s ended its P.L.T. pilot, another Beyond Meat branded burger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q9VN7a"&gt;It’s still unclear what the differences are between the McPlant and the P.L.T., other than the name. A &lt;a href="https://corporate.mcdonalds.com/corpmcd/en-us/our-stories/article/ourstories.mcplant-usrestaurant.html"&gt;post on McDonald’s website&lt;/a&gt; says that the McPlant patty will contain peas, rice, and potatoes and will also be topped with tomatoes, lettuce, onions, pickles, mayonnaise, ketchup, mustard, and American cheese. That sounds a lot like the P.L.T., but we won’t really know until the start of its test on November 3rd. It’s also important to note that the McPlant will be cooked on the same grill as beef burgers, so it might not be classified as purely vegan or vegetarian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t0reOM"&gt;McDonald’s briefly ran the P.L.T. in Canada from 2019 to 2020. And as &lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt; noted, at the time, McDonald’s said that it had no plans to resurrect the burger. Something must’ve changed McDonald’s thinking — maybe it was the results from the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22262481/mcdonalds-mcplant-burger-denmark-sweden-test-markets"&gt;McPlant test that it’s been running in Sweden, Denmark&lt;/a&gt;, the Netherlands, Austria, and the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mhGGC9"&gt;Meatless options have been growing in popularity at fast-food restaurants, with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/1/18290336/burger-king-impossible-burger-st-louis-meat-free-meatless"&gt;Burger King kicking off the trend with the Impossible Whopper&lt;/a&gt; in 2019. Other chains also hopped on the bandwagon that same year, with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/7/20758429/subway-beyond-meatball-marinara-sub-meatless-restaurant-testing-us-canada"&gt;Subway introducing the Beyond Meatball Marinara&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/26/20833145/beyond-meat-kfc-fried-chicken-test-plant-based-sample-date"&gt;KFC piloting plant-based fried chicken&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z5KODX"&gt;If your mouth waters just thinking of the McPlant, you’ll soon be able to find it at McDonald’s in Irving, TX; Carrollton, TX; Cedar Falls, IA; Jennings, LA; Lake Charles, LA; El Segundo, CA; and Manhattan Beach, CA while supplies last. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728805/mcdonalds-mcplant-beyond-meat-burger-test"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728805/mcdonalds-mcplant-beyond-meat-burger-test</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T17:21:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T17:21:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>Human rights activist suing Twitter for allegedly giving Saudi spies access to his info</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Twitter’s blue bird silhouette logo on a black background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mKlF-nu8K5Hvn5dRwaiBQeha_1I=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70001707/acastro_180827_1777_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qMSOOT"&gt;A Saudi human rights activist has filed a lawsuit against Twitter, alleging that the company hired two people who spied on behalf of the government of Saudi Arabia and accessed his personal information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1xBjAG"&gt;Ali Al-Ahmed, head of the human rights advocacy organization Institute for Gulf Affairs, has frequently been critical of the Saudi government. Twitter, Al-Ahmed claims, did not have the right to disclose or share his private information under its own privacy policy and should have done more to protect his information. He names two men in the suit &lt;a href="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22930394/indictment.pdf"&gt;who were indicted last year&lt;/a&gt; (.pdf) by federal prosecutors for working as agents of the Saudi government while working for Twitter several years ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wG8xQF"&gt;Al-Ahmed also claims in the lawsuit that his Twitter account was suspended in 2018 without explanation and has yet to be reinstated despite repeated appeals. The lawsuit alleges that the company has kept Al-Ahmed’s Arabic-language account inaccessible so as not to displease the Saudi government. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oYC2rQ"&gt;“While Twitter may wish to play the victim of state-sponsored espionage, Twitter’s conduct in punishing the victims of this intrigue, including Mr. Al-Ahmed, tells a far different story: one of ratification, complicity, and/or adoption tailored to appease a neigh beneficial owner and preserve access to a key market, the [Kingdom of Saudi Arabia],” the complaint states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J7IaPc"&gt;Al-Ahmed is seeking reinstatement of his Arabic-language Twitter account and unspecified damages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7hHHVF"&gt;Twitter declined to comment Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="68gruE"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/21085701-twitter-spy-complaint/?embed=1&amp;amp;responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="twitter-spy-complaint (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="905" style="border: 1px solid #aaa; width: 100%; height: 800px; height: calc(100vh - 100px);" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728121/human-rights-activist-suing-twitter-saudi-spies"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728121/human-rights-activist-suing-twitter-saudi-spies</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T16:56:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T16:56:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Moscow adds facial recognition payment system to more than 240 metro stations</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Face Pay launched at all Moscow Underground stations" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/X3GUG-zSzh5ttgZyd6qs6hC0MNk=/0x0:5472x3648/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70001561/1235893124.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by TASS\TASS via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="l9dT0o"&gt;&lt;a href="https://mosmetro.ru/news/detail/?news=802"&gt;Moscow launched “Face Pay” on Friday&lt;/a&gt;, a facial recognition payment system implemented in more than 240 Mosmetro stations, “the largest use of facial recognition technology in the world,” officials claim (&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/oct/15/privacy-fears-moscow-metro-rolls-out-facial-recognition-pay-system"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The service relies on stored photographs to validate metro payments, an obvious privacy concern given the previous uses of facial recognition technology by the Russian capital’s law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MCs3tj"&gt;Face Pay requires metro riders to upload a photo and connect their bank and metro cards to the Mosmetro mobile app. With everything uploaded, all you need to do is look at the camera posted above the turnstiles to make it in time for your next train. Moscow authorities expect 10 to 15 percent of riders to use Face Pay “regularly” in the next two to three years, the hope being less time swiping and paying for rides will translate to shorter lines and waits, and less close contact during the ongoing pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Face Pay launched at all Moscow Underground stations" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/s3J5IFYQVF9jL1IoI0QVS62zkQQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22930357/1235892999.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by TASS\TASS via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moscow’s head of city transport and road infrastructure Maxim Liksutov with a Face Pay camera. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="1mdtRa"&gt;That’s all fine and good, at least conceptually. The relative convenience biometric recognition can add to payment systems is a concept that’s currently being floated in the US through Amazon One, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/29/21493094/amazon-one-palm-recognition-hand-payments-amazon-go-store"&gt;the shipping giant’s palm recognition tech&lt;/a&gt;. As &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; notes, Moscow’s Department of Information Technology claims &lt;a href="https://www.kommersant.ru/doc/5030021"&gt;photographs collected through official channels won’t be turned over to the police&lt;/a&gt; and are instead securely encrypted in the GIS ETSHD system (Moscow’s Unified Data Storage and Processing Center).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ktyfCw"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s not hard to imagine the metro system turning into a valuable surveillance tool&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4bZyTC"&gt;That hasn’t convinced Russian privacy advocates, though. “This is a dangerous new step in Russia’s push for control over its population. We need to have full transparency on how this application will work in practice,” Stanislav Shakirov, the founder of digital rights group Roskomsvoboda, told &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;. “The Moscow metro is a government institution and all the data can end up in the hands of the security services.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tm2Z9Q"&gt;Shakirov has good reason to be concerned. Moscow’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/28/16378164/moscow-facial-recognition-cctv-arrests-crime-surveillance"&gt;implementation of facial recognition across its vast network of more than 10,000 CCTV cameras&lt;/a&gt; is more than a little scary. Worse than the possibility of abuse by local Moscow law enforcement, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/11/21561018/moscows-facial-recognition-system-crime-bribe-stalking"&gt;the system can apparently be hijacked&lt;/a&gt; for as little as $200 by enterprising hackers. That’s the real risk of applying facial recognition across even more of daily life in the city, not just that the government could have an easier time tracking the movements of citizens, but that the system itself is a vulnerable target for even worse abuses.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728667/russia-face-pay-system-moscow-metro-privacy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728667/russia-face-pay-system-moscow-metro-privacy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T16:54:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T16:54:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>Busta Rhymes has questions about NFTs, and he has NFTs for sale</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Nas Performs At City Harvest Benefit" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3iavKzjhlkOPfPnEsM_mqI6sY_w=/0x0:2592x1728/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70001553/1342270247.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Johnny Nunez/WireImage&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="T0nBah"&gt;You can’t always take Busta Rhymes &lt;a href="http://www.mtv.com/news/1699317/mayan-apocalypse-busta-rhymes/"&gt;literally&lt;/a&gt;, and sometimes &lt;a href="https://pagesix.com/2021/08/24/busta-rhymes-goes-on-anti-mask-rant/"&gt;you shouldn’t take his questions seriously at all&lt;/a&gt;, but a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BustaRhymes/status/1448979255807946755"&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt; from this morning about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22310188/nft-explainer-what-is-blockchain-crypto-art-faq"&gt;NFTs&lt;/a&gt; is solidly in line with the disturbing reality of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Hz6zAQ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;SHOULD I BUY A HOUSE… or.. A LINK TO A PICTURE OF A PIXELATED MONKEY&lt;/p&gt;— Busta Rhymes (@BustaRhymes) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BustaRhymes/status/1448979255807946755?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cmvUjv"&gt;I won’t give you, or Busta, any help with your investment or trading decisions. However, understanding that some NFTs are a link to a picture on a server &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/14/22726556/signal-founder-moxie-marlinspike-nft-whim-change-platform-shit-emoji-fragility"&gt;that could change or disappear&lt;/a&gt; is information worth knowing before you spend your hard-earned cryptocurrency on a digital collectible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bs0KLv"&gt;And yes, Busta Rhymes is talking about crypto and NFTs for the same reason almost anyone else is. Just like every &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/13/22725019/fox-maskverse-masked-singer-nft-community-blockchain-collectables"&gt;TV network&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22348858/nba-nft-top-shot-dapper-labs"&gt;sports league&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/2/22705818/dc-free-superhero-nfts-register-fandome-event"&gt;comic book publisher&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BustaRhymes/status/1443714943086366721"&gt;he has a few of them for sale&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ZzLaDK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The NFT scammers are here","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22683766/nft-scams-theft-social-engineering-opensea-community-recovery"},{"title":"NFTs, explained: what they are, and why they’re suddenly worth millions","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22310188/nft-explainer-what-is-blockchain-crypto-art-faq"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22727956/busta-rhymes-nft-tweet-crypto-bored-evolved-ape"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22727956/busta-rhymes-nft-tweet-crypto-bored-evolved-ape</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-15T14:41:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-15T14:41:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix just fired the organizer of the trans employee walkout</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jj54EgP9dAwP8AGQkM1a1fcVMmg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70000779/acastro_181101_1777_netflix_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5lfxHM"&gt;Netflix has fired a leader of the trans employee resource group who was organizing the upcoming October 20th walkout. The employee, who is Black and currently pregnant, asked not to be named for fear of online harassment. They have been encouraging trans employees and allies to walk out of work in protest of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/11/22720724/netflix-suspends-trans-employee-tweeted-dave-chappelle-the-closer"&gt;Netflix’s handling of the Dave Chappelle special &lt;em&gt;The Closer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The employee declined to speak to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; for this story. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B41xJf"&gt;“All these white people are going around talking to the press and speaking publicly on Twitter and the only person who gets fired is the Black person who was quiet the entire time,” says a former employee in an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “That’s absurd, and just further shows that Black trans people are the ones being targeted in this conversation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZgBrDn"&gt;The employee was terminated on suspicion of leaking metrics to the press related to the Dave Chappelle special. Those metrics — about how much Netflix paid for &lt;em&gt;The Closer &lt;/em&gt;and how many people it reached — &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-13/netflix-staff-raised-concerns-about-dave-chappelle-special-before-release?srnd=equality&amp;amp;sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;subsequently ended up in a report on &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. While the employee had shared the metrics internally, they spoke out against the leaks to colleagues, worried they might hurt the walkout movement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SzbWk7"&gt;The leaking of internal data is highly unusual at Netflix. While the company prides itself on transparency, employees are told that the culture can only thrive when Netflix data remains internal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yvHqbQ"&gt;A Netflix spokesperson confirmed the employees’ dismissal. “We have let go of an employee for sharing confidential, commercially sensitive information outside the company,” they said. “We understand this employee may have been motivated by disappointment and hurt with Netflix, but maintaining a culture of trust and transparency is core to our company.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xZv8uc"&gt;Controversy surrounding &lt;em&gt;The Closer&lt;/em&gt;, which was widely criticized by trans activists for being transphobic, has roiled Netflix in recent weeks. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/11/22720724/netflix-suspends-trans-employee-tweeted-dave-chappelle-the-closer"&gt;The company suspended Terra Field&lt;/a&gt;, a trans software engineer who posted a viral tweet thread about the controversy, for attending a director-level meeting to which she wasn’t invited. Field has since been reinstated. The company is now sending employees details about what meetings they’re allowed to attend. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6lhxtB"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728337/netflix-fires-organizer-trans-employee-walkout-dave-chappelle"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22728337/netflix-fires-organizer-trans-employee-walkout-dave-chappelle</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
