<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-08T18:15:50-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T18:15:50-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T18:15:50-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Switch-style Aya Neo handheld gaming PC is now on Indiegogo, starting at $789</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PQyAAlEP2N3V7M0adON7g5y5UV8=/0x87:1386x1011/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/assets.sbnation.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68932681/Screen_Shot_2021_03_08_at_5.59.47_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OZpFIy"&gt;The Aya Neo —  a Nintendo Switch-style handheld gaming PC that promises to offer a full-fledged PC gaming experience in the palm of your hands — &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.indiegogo.com%2Fprojects%2Faya-neo-world-s-first-7nm-handheld-gaming-device--2%2F%23%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F8%2F22320306%2Faya-neo-handheld-gaming-pc-indiegogo-price-release-date-nintendo-switch" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;is now available to back on Indiegogo&lt;/a&gt;, starting at $6,120 HKD (~$789 USD) for the 500GB model. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="lmnlQU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"We’re getting closer to a Nintendo Switch-sized gaming PC","url":"https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/1/18/22237379/aya-neo-gpd-win-3-nintendo-switch-gaming-pc-handheld-specs-comparison"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="7Tflop"&gt;This version of the Neo is technically the second, following the limited, sold-out run of the “Founder’s Edition” that Aya offered back in January. The new, broader release promises several improvements over that initial version, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="2BVmVN"&gt;An improved operating system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RXZXYr"&gt;Reduced weight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uF2saG"&gt;The option to toggle rumble&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nUqNTd"&gt;Better buttons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AARz2f"&gt;Better power consumption and performance presets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="F4Kvv0"&gt;Improvements to issues that caused resolution scaling problems or blurry screens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JgMUwFMdd04ohgZS4doRzTrm3ac=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/assets.sbnation.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22355227/Screen_Shot_2021_03_08_at_6.00.04_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="UPGG4G"&gt;The company also showed off a new optional $47 dock that adds two USB 3.2 Gen 1 type-A ports, one HDMI port, one SD card slot, one MicroSD card slot, and an ethernet jack — another similar concept to the Switch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cnEkmJ"&gt;The rest of the specs for the Aya Neo are still the same: a 7-inch 1280x800 IPS display, a 10-25W AMD Ryzen 4500U CPU, 16GB of LPDDR4x RAM, three USB-C ports, and up to 6 hours of estimated battery life. Don’t expect to play triple-A games at high settings, but we were able to competently run &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496153/star-wars-squadrons-review-single-player-campaign-x-wing-tie-fighter-space-simulator-vr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Star Wars: Squadrons&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;at 60fps with the Founder’s Edition, and it had nearly enough power to play the unfinished &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22286507/valheim-steam-pc-game-2-million-sales"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Valheim&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the go. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uULZTt"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JkCIILzfhmA?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KZc3kH"&gt;All that said, the Aya Neo is still a crowdfunded product from a first time company. And while it’s certainly encouraging that Aya has managed to ship its initial Founder’s Edition run of Neos, there’s still the usual elements of risk when it comes to crowdfunded products — even ones that are technically second-generation models. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G2UCdm"&gt;But if you are willing to roll the dice, you can back the Aya Neo on Indiegogo for $6,120 HKD (roughly $789 USD) for the 500GB model or $6,750 HKD (approximately $869 USD) for the 1TB model, which is about 10 percent off of what the products are planned to sell for after the crowdfunding campaign. Shipping is planned for May. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="Kw4hEy"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:1523637"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5NfHJa"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KLWbia"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sEsW5W"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5BymjQ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22320306/aya-neo-handheld-gaming-pc-indiegogo-price-release-date-nintendo-switch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22320306/aya-neo-handheld-gaming-pc-indiegogo-price-release-date-nintendo-switch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T17:58:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T17:58:37-05:00</updated>
    <title>Verizon is once again giving you a reason to turn 5G off</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Pseg15ozbBJ1ekOK1tx7GNjk29k=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/assets.sbnation.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68932592/acastro_200109_1777_verizon_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Despite years of promotion, Verizon’s 5G network still lags behind 4G. | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="m9ufjc"&gt;Verizon 4G appears to be getting even better than its nationwide 5G network, according to &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/news/tested-verizons-new-4g-beats-5g-big-time"&gt;new tests conducted by &lt;em&gt;PCMag’s&lt;/em&gt; Sascha Segan&lt;/a&gt;. After &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/28/22305899/verizon-support-turn-off-5g-save-phone-battery"&gt;last week’s tweet&lt;/a&gt; suggesting that users turn off their phone’s 5G to conserve battery life, there seems to be a multitude of reasons for Verizon customers to stick with 4G right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9Ihm2K"&gt;Additional spectrum is making the difference for Verizon 4G right now, and not the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299903/fcc-cband-auction-results-verizon-att-tmobile"&gt;C-band spectrum&lt;/a&gt; that’s been in the news recently. This is CBRS, a set of frequencies that sits near C-band. Verizon &lt;a href="https://www.fiercewireless.com/operators/verizon-dish-cable-top-list-cbrs-auction-winners"&gt;bid $1.89 billion on CBRS&lt;/a&gt; licenses last year and has been putting the newly acquired spectrum to work for its 4G service in certain locations (there are likely technical reasons, which Segan explains in his post, why Verizon isn’t using this spectrum for 5G just yet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="bAjyeB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"5G in the US is disappointing right now, but it’s going to get better","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22292074/5g-nationwide-verizon-att-tmobile-c-band"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="DbCy0Z"&gt;Segan found a couple of these spots and tested CBRS-assisted 4G speeds versus 5G. With the exception of range-limited, super-fast Ultra Wideband 5G, 4G won by a landslide. In one location, 4G download speeds reached 815 Mbps, while 5G based on Dynamic Spectrum Sharing (that’s the widespread but slower variety known as DSS) only hit 358 Mbps. This was a test of just a couple of locations of course, but Segan points out that it bodes well for the kinds of improvements we can expect when C-band becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7g2IS4"&gt;So is there any reason for someone on Verizon to keep 5G active rather than switching to 4G? Maybe, Segan tells us. “If you’re in a spot with Verizon’s ‘UWB’ millimeter-wave 5G, it’s absolutely terrific. UWB is the fastest form of 5G available today. But the DSS ‘nationwide’ 5G just isn’t providing any advantage right now. I’d say, turn it off if you can and check back in a few months to see if they’ve improved the situation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Yyj77b"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’ll be the C-band spectrum that will likely make the difference for Verizon 5G&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LrUdv7"&gt;The silver lining, of course, is that Verizon 4G is actually good — and getting even better for some. In the long term, it’ll be the C-band spectrum that will likely make the difference for Verizon 5G. “If you’re buying a Verizon phone soon and you’re interested in future performance, make sure it has C-band,” Segan says. In the meantime, unless you live next door to an Ultra Wideband cell site, you can probably turn off 5G and rest assured that you’re getting the best network performance possible for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pQYJq6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22320170/verizon-4g-cbrs-spectrum-nationwide-5g"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22320170/verizon-4g-cbrs-spectrum-nationwide-5g</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T17:05:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T17:05:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to block ad tracking on your iPhone</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HxrfWjIoYEDUhdCbULmSlmpoNP8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/assets.sbnation.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68932275/akrales_180620_1777_0259.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Jwd5Mq"&gt;In 2019, an &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/05/28/its-middle-night-do-you-know-who-your-iphone-is-talking/?utm_term=.f643c2a83a4c"&gt;article in &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Geoffrey Fowler described the author’s shock when he discovered just how many of his iPhone apps were collecting and uploading information about his usage while he slept. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VqUHGx"&gt;As we all know by now, data is a huge commodity these days. If you use a phone, laptop, or any type of computing device (unless you’re a security expert or a high-end hacker with access to sophisticated blocking tools), you’re paying for your apps by contributing marketing and other info to the companies that supply them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rdXttf"&gt;As Fowler’s article demonstrated, iPhone users are not immune to this. Since his article was published, Apple has made some &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/14/22174017/apple-app-store-new-privacy-labels-ios-apps-public"&gt;laudable changes to its privacy policies&lt;/a&gt;. But it’s still a good idea to take charge of your own data. There are some simple ways to minimize the amount of tracking that app vendors can do and the amount of data they can access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="exJEUb"&gt;Turn off personalized and location-based ads&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="WBCofK"&gt;According to Apple’s &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT205223"&gt;Advertising &amp;amp; Privacy&lt;/a&gt; page: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="q8RHB4"&gt;Apple’s advertising platform does not track you, meaning that it does not link user or device data collected from our apps with user or device data collected from third parties for targeted advertising or advertising measurement purposes, and does not share user or device data with data brokers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="wLQYsb"&gt;However, the page goes on to say that contextual data, such as info about your device, its location, your App Store searches, and what you read on Apple News could be collected. You can get around this somewhat by &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT202074"&gt;turning off personalized and location-based ads&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="qhWD8Y"&gt;To turn off personalized ads&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="WdWeaM"&gt;Select your “Settings” app, tap on “Privacy,” and scroll down to and select “Apple Advertising” (it will be near the bottom of the list).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7xqUx9"&gt;Toggle “Personalized Ads” off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT202074" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-13TMuhA1KUgUKSGpDPAiCkMTWU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/assets.sbnation.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22354741/IMG_DBA61BE67C50_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can toggle off personalized ads from Apple.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can also toggle off Location Services" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zRIXFHciFirbr26IjadMqQNZ8IM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/assets.sbnation.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22354742/IMG_B32453FF7846_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can also toggle off Location Services.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="tFThlr"&gt;To turn off location-based ads&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="exNzsg"&gt;Select “Settings” &amp;gt; “Privacy” &amp;gt; “Location Services” (at the top of the display).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RGKWdi"&gt;Toggle off “Location Services.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="IuI4ot"&gt;On this page, you can also change several of your apps, such as the App Store or Maps, to allow location access never, ask next time, or while using the app. Also, note that you can still use the “Find My Phone” feature; it will temporarily enable Location Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bGtgw9"&gt;If you want to see how effectively your phone is protected, you could try taking the &lt;a href="https://panopticlick.eff.org/"&gt;Panopticlick test&lt;/a&gt;, which is offered by the Electronic Frontier Foundation. It monitors device fingerprinting, among other things. I ran it on an Apple iPhone 11 after following the above instructions, and I got a “partial protection” result for blocking tracking ads, blocking invisible trackers, and protecting from fingerprinting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1wLgon"&gt;Lock down Safari&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="2syYGD"&gt;If you use the Safari browser on your iPhone, there are several things you can do to make it safer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="In your iPhone’s Settings, select “Safari”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rNe8EpVqCnaJX1_zwU2FGFXDYEg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/assets.sbnation.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22354806/IMG_6A5B7FC23344_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;In your iPhone’s Settings, select “Safari.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Enabling “Block All Cookies” is more secure, but can also be inconvenient" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fgFFNGBuWMM1KsGcpzCqqNEhxEQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/assets.sbnation.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22354812/IMG_06711E4C44E2_1.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enabling “Block All Cookies” is more secure but can also be inconvenient.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="9Lo0v1"&gt;Go to “Settings.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="zdMkKN"&gt;Select “Safari,” and scroll down to the “Privacy &amp;amp; Security” section.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="or38q5"&gt;Turn on “Prevent Cross-Site Tracking” (which means advertisers and other third-party content providers can’t track you from one site to another).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="oX8nX2"&gt;Turn on “Block All Cookies.” The cookies collected by various websites can contain a great deal of information about how you use the site, what info you put into it, etc. By blocking cookies, you prevent that data from being collected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="8bM4Zf"&gt;However, you will probably make things very inconvenient for yourself. Your visits to sites will not be recorded, so, for example, you may not be able to revisit a playlist or repurchase the same T-shirt you bought last year. Some sites will even refuse entry if you don’t allow them to collect cookies. It’s your choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Fv7b88"&gt;Turn off Background App Refresh&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="0XgVrk"&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT202070"&gt;According to Apple&lt;/a&gt;, the reason to have Background App Refresh turned on is to allow suspended apps (apps that aren’t currently active) to “check for updates and new content.” According to Disconnect, the privacy app company that Geoffrey Fowler cites in his article, it also allows apps to collect marketable tracking data and transmit that data even when you’re not using the app. Interestingly, iPhones ship with Background App Refresh turned on, but it’s not terribly hard to turn off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="eAlq90"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:6359379"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="2sishI"&gt;Go to “Settings.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EKg5tY"&gt;Select “General.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NxM8Zy"&gt;Select “Background App Refresh.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="UX9E4h"&gt;You’ll see a list of all the apps that use this feature, and they’re all going to be turned on. Find “Background App Refresh” at the top of the page, and tap on it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ITsFC2"&gt;You’ll be brought to a page that lets you enable it for Wi-Fi and cellular data, for Wi-Fi only, or you can turn it off altogether. Select “Off.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="XNsYpK"&gt;If you go back to the previous page, you’ll see that all of the toggles for the various apps are completely gone. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="ahdHe2"&gt;You may want to be selective about which apps can work in the background. Some apps might not work well otherwise. For example, Google Photos won’t automatically back up your camera roll unless this feature is enabled. So you can, if you wish, leave “Background App Refresh” on, and then choose which specific apps you want to toggle off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3YLMFr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 8th, 2021, 5:00PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This article was originally published on May 30th, 2018; several portions have been updated to reflect changes in iOS. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22309965/block-ad-iphone-data-how-to-tracking"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22309965/block-ad-iphone-data-how-to-tracking</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T16:06:14-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T16:06:14-05:00</updated>
    <title>Spice up your daily pandemic walk with these apps</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7JTL09TXMNTLmfl06h24EoUsf-k=/0x0:2000x1333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68931867/final.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Keep the routine fresh&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="vfp7Lm"&gt;As you may have heard one or two times, we’re now roughly a year into COVID and pandemic lockdown life. To fill the void in our lives that was once occupied by social gatherings, visiting family, and breathing indoor air freely, many of us have turned to new hobbies and habits. Some of them are even healthy! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vEv0XJ"&gt;Taking a daily or, if I’m being honest, &lt;em&gt;semi&lt;/em&gt;-daily walk is a lockdown habit that has seen me through These Unprecedented Times. I’m &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/roobeekeane/status/1347644813320073220?s=20"&gt;not alone, either&lt;/a&gt; — without gyms or really anywhere else to go at all, lots of us have embraced (or at times, endured) a daily walk around the neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m5qr1L"&gt;To be sure, it’s not always easy. I got tired of walking by the same houses and the same pieces of fossilized trash about six months in. It rains a lot where I live and that can turn an otherwise pleasant walk into a real bummer. Other days, the motivation just isn’t there and the mailbox is as far as I get. But a few tricks along the way have helped me and fellow &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; staffers stay committed to the walk ritual. Here are some techniques to keep your pandemic walk routine fresh and the apps that can help you put them into practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="BIctUh"&gt;Find a new route&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Vw0WdGgH1BgVp5TrwbEgDrqQfgc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22354699/footpath.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Footpath helps you map out new routes and gives you key information like elevation change along the way.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bEBgeP"&gt;This year I’ve embraced the life-changing magic of hauling myself out of my own neighborhood and going on a walk somewhere else. It feels counterproductive driving somewhere to take a walk, but it really does help shake things up when I’m burned out on my usual route. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4zvSG2"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.alltrails.com/"&gt;AllTrails&lt;/a&gt; is an app popular with hikers, but it’s also great for finding nearby parks and trails you may not know about, whether you’re in an urban spot or farther from the city. There’s also an active community who leave helpful tips, like whether the restrooms are a horror show or if the parking lot is a hotspot for break-ins. All of its basic features are available in the free version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZygxB3"&gt;&lt;a href="https://footpathapp.com/"&gt;Footpath&lt;/a&gt; is another good tool to help identify a new route, whether it’s close to home or somewhere unfamiliar. Use the app’s detailed street map to draw roughly where you’d like to go; the app will snap your route to the nearest streets and pathways. Footpath gives you important details about the route like mileage, elevation gain / loss along the way, and even a time estimate that factors in hills so you know what you’re getting into. You can trace out the full route or draw a path to a destination you’d like to reach and the app can create a loop route back to your starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pEtefm"&gt;The free version will help you brainstorm some new walks, but more advanced features like turn-by-turn navigation — iPhone only for now but coming to Android soon — require an Elite subscription ($23.49 annually). Alternatively, you can add Elite features to individual saved routes for a one-time fee of $1.99 each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Rmyp3f"&gt;Make it mindful&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="khOWzU"&gt;Any therapist or Silicon Valley CEO will tell you about the benefits of meditation. My brain is too noisy for a traditional sitting-and-breathing meditation, but I find walking meditations a lot easier to get into. &lt;a href="https://app.www.calm.com/program/wAzjO76/mindful-walking"&gt;Calm&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.headspace.com/meditation/walking-meditation"&gt;Headspace&lt;/a&gt; (each is $69 for an annual subscription) offer walking meditations of various lengths; the ones offered by Headspace are tailored to more specific circumstances, like walking in a city or just back and forth at home. There are also plenty of free options if you search YouTube or your streaming music service of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="aES93I"&gt;Find something to tune into&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/05OGacEC6uRchhIWbp9WT1AFXww=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22354708/apple_time_to_walk_apple_watch_airpods_01252021_inline.jpg.large_2x.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Time to Walk is an Apple Fitness Plus feature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Vhm8rP"&gt;Finding a bite-sized podcast to listen to during walk time is a nice bonus incentive to take a break and head out the door. &lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/2rTT1klKUoQNuaW2Ah19Pa?si=b5snZO3iT66QKGQPD24Yqw"&gt;NPR’s &lt;em&gt;Short Wave&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a quick ten-ish minutes with episodes every weekday. One of my &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; colleagues uses her walk to catch up on &lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/06iGnWl5EnkJktsKhSNeAQ?si=brnULdIcRHi2RbOUrfm4lQ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gamertag Radio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Or check out an audio book from your local library with the &lt;a href="https://www.overdrive.com/apps/libby/"&gt;Libby app&lt;/a&gt; to make walk time double up as your reading time. And for something a little more freeform, use the time to listen in on a conversation on &lt;a href="https://www.joinclubhouse.com/"&gt;Clubhouse&lt;/a&gt; or Twitter Spaces. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ONIgIv"&gt;If you’re an &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fapple-fitness-plus%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22320002%2Fwalking-apps-pandemic-strava-footpath-alltrails-seek" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple Fitness Plus&lt;/a&gt; subscriber, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22248678/apple-time-to-walk-celebrity-guided-audio-dolly-parton-shawn-mendes"&gt;Time to Walk&lt;/a&gt; is a great option. Featured celebrities like Dolly Parton share stories, recorded as they walk in places that are meaningful to them. It’s a nice, reflective experience with a diverse range of hosts. You will need a subscription to Apple’s $79 / year fitness service and an Apple Watch, so it’s more likely to be an option if you’re already invested in those things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="LOz6NS"&gt;Gamify it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f12e8YMF5OIjGprB0TbULvPTCmw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22354714/seek.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seek helps you identify local animals and plant life, rewarding you with badges as you observe more species.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WFthGB"&gt;It works on kids and it works on adults: when all else fails, turn it into a game. Tracking walks on &lt;a href="https://www.mapmyrun.com/app"&gt;MapMyRun&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.strava.com/mobile"&gt;Strava&lt;/a&gt; can give you that extra sense of accountability and accomplishment when you get back home and tap the “finish” button. It’s a neat little trick that works on my lizard brain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LJypyF"&gt;Or, do as another of my &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; colleagues does and take note of local critters and plant life with the &lt;a href="https://www.inaturalist.org/pages/seek_app"&gt;Seek app&lt;/a&gt;. It uses your phone’s camera to identify plants, birds, and other kinds of fauna. Best of all, it will keep track of species you’ve indentified and award badges as you identify more. Badges!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="asxYQT"&gt;Of course, that’s just the real-life version of the classic catch ‘em all game. Another &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; staffer uses that oldie but goodie &lt;a href="https://pokemongolive.com/en/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to keep her neighborhood walks interesting. If you missed its rise in popularity the first time around, here’s the gist: several years ago, &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt; tricked a bunch of us into going outside to look for AR characters in real-life locations. Once you find them, you can capture them by flinging virtual pokéballs at them on your phone screen. Keep it casual and just see how many different pokémon you encounter and capture on your walk route, or seek out rarer pokémon more aggressively. It’s your world.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22320002/walking-apps-pandemic-strava-footpath-alltrails-seek"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22320002/walking-apps-pandemic-strava-footpath-alltrails-seek</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T16:01:09-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T16:01:09-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft Surface Laptop 4 will reportedly include both AMD and Intel configurations</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Surface Laptop Go on the corner of a table half open, seen from the back." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UV-K45UCM_yioAPE127R42H-1Ns=/16x0:2640x1749/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68931825/twarren-surfacelaptopgo-10.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Tom Warren / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3qfrI2"&gt;For a while, Microsoft’s Surface Laptop 3 was one of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21250695/best-laptops"&gt;best laptops&lt;/a&gt; you could buy. Microsoft is now planning its successor, the Surface Laptop 4, and it appears &lt;a href="https://winfuture.de/news,121617.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WinFuture&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has obtained details about this upcoming device. Per this report, the laptop is coming sometime in April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kUDqvj"&gt;The biggest news is that the new Surface Laptop will come with both Intel and AMD options. The AMD models will include chips from the Ryzen 4000 mobile series, including the Ryzen 5 4680U and the Ryzen 7 4980U. These aren’t AMD’s top guns; the current-gen &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22225474/amd-ryzen-5000-series-mobile-processors-ces-2021"&gt;Ryzen 5000 mobile series&lt;/a&gt; was announced earlier this year. The Intel models will have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/2/21408718/intel-11th-gen-tiger-lake-cpu-processor-announcement-laptops-fall"&gt;Intel’s latest 11th Gen CPUs&lt;/a&gt;, though, including the Core 15-1145G7 and the Core i7-1185G7. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I5jzn8"&gt;Apart from the chips, it seems like very little is changing between the Laptop 3 and the Laptop 4. Here are some other tidbits we’ve learned from &lt;em&gt;WinFuture&lt;/em&gt;’s report: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="T8zV5B"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;There will be 13.5- and 15-inch models available. &lt;/strong&gt;These are also the models that the Surface Laptop 3 offered. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WB1VRc"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;All models have a 3:2 aspect ratio. &lt;/strong&gt;The resolution of the 13.5-inch device will be 2256 x 1504, and the 15-inch will be 2496 x 1664. These are the same resolutions that the Surface Laptop 3 offered. The 3:2 aspect ratio has been a staple of Microsoft’s Surface products for a few years now. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZnzTV9"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;RAM maxes out at 32GB.&lt;/strong&gt; But it looks like if you want that much memory, you’ll need to get an Intel model. The AMD configurations only go up to 16GB. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RWPhut"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Storage maxes out at 1TB&lt;/strong&gt;. Similarly, it looks like only the Intel models offer that much storage. AMD laptops will max out at 512GB. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="jhVnT7"&gt;If these leaks are true, I’m expecting Microsoft will take a similar approach to the Surface Laptop 4 as it did to the Surface Book 3 last spring — that is, bump up the chips with minimal changes to the chassis. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best Laptops 2020: Microsoft Surface Laptop 3" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/83hkaLkGBV2kvydYC0SbSU9JY10=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19250347/akrales_190930_3689_0135.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the Surface Laptop 3, to give you an idea of what the Surface Laptop 4 will look like.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="y1FgHG"&gt;That doesn’t mean there’s nothing to be excited about, of course. Chip upgrades are still a big deal. One of our primary complaints about both the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/28/20932406/microsoft-surface-laptop-3-13-5-inch-review-test-price-specs-features"&gt;13.5-inch&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/21/20923620/microsoft-surface-laptop-3-15-inch-review-windows-test-price-specs-features"&gt;15-inch Surface Book 3&lt;/a&gt; models was that their battery life wasn’t great compared to the competition. The 15-inch model also ran into some performance issues in our testing. It had significant trouble running 4K 60fps videos and completing media exports. It will be great if the new chips are able to address some of these drawbacks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uIj0Gx"&gt;I wouldn’t blame Microsoft for not overhauling the design; people like it, and why fix what’s not broken? But as I noted in my &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21271796/microsoft-surface-book-3-review-price-specs-features-13-5-screen"&gt;review of the Surface Book 3&lt;/a&gt;, there’s only so long the Surface line’s look can stay relevant. Across the market, laptop bezels are shrinking, chassis are getting lighter, and customers are expecting a sleeker and more modern vibe from both high-end and midrange products. The Surface Laptop’s design was never ugly, but as the likes of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21546784/dell-xps-13-late-2020-review-design-specs-price-features"&gt;Dell XPS&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22264792/hp-spectre-x360-14-laptop-stylus-oled-review-price-specs-features"&gt;HP Spectre&lt;/a&gt; continue to evolve, I worry that it won’t be too long before the Surface line’s look is left behind. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dl49XV"&gt;All that’s being said: these are still rumors at this stage, so treat them with a grain of salt. I’ll be sure to update you when we’ve gotten more concrete information about this upcoming device, hopefully sooner rather than later. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iYVG7m"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bzOSqU"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cH3hVj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319854/microsoft-surface-laptop-4-specs-features-release-price-leak"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319854/microsoft-surface-laptop-4-specs-features-release-price-leak</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T15:50:53-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T15:50:53-05:00</updated>
    <title>SpaceX moves to beam Starlink internet into trucks, boats, and aircraft</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="TOPSHOT-URUGUAY-SPACE-SPACEX-SATELLITE-STARLINK" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/o-eo1kyrO9nEkI26DF6g3vT8u3g=/0x0:4500x3000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/assets.sbnation.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68931738/1231167449.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A train of Starlink satellites in low-Earth orbit passes over Uruguay. SpaceX is asking the FCC for approval to beam Starlink internet into moving vehicles.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Mariana Suarez / AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iBkAeU"&gt;SpaceX is seeking regulatory approval to connect its rapidly growing network of internet-beaming Starlink satellites to cars, trucks, shipping boats, and aircraft. The request, filed last Friday with the Federal Communications Commission, marks SpaceX’s biggest step yet toward connecting Starlink to the automotive sector, a potentially lucrative line of business that would expand the company’s current stationary offerings from rural homes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fl4yaV"&gt;The March 5th FCC filing asked for “a blanket license authorizing operation” of Starlink terminals on so-called Earth Stations in Motion — an umbrella term for cars, trucks, maritime vessels, and aircraft. “No longer are users willing to forego connectivity while on the move, whether driving a truck across the country, moving a freighter from Europe to a U.S. port, or while on a domestic or international flight,” the filing read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wMCZQF"&gt;Smaller passenger vehicles may have to wait. “Not connecting Tesla cars to Starlink, as our terminal is much too big,” SpaceX CEO Elon Musk tweeted on Monday, responding to an article on the FCC filing. “This is for aircraft, ships, large trucks &amp;amp; RVs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XxAbMc"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Not connecting Tesla cars to Starlink, as our terminal is much too big. This is for aircraft, ships, large trucks &amp;amp; RVs.&lt;/p&gt;— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1369051431903268865?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 8, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6sGgIw"&gt;With over 1,000 satellites in space, SpaceX’s Starlink has at least 10,000 users through an invite-only beta program it started last year. The beta program is currently aimed at rural parts of the US that have little to no internet connectivity. A Starlink kit with an antenna and router costs $499, plus $99 per month for speeds around 70 to 130 Mbps. Last month, SpaceX &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274385/musk-spacex-starlink-deposit-price-satellite-internet"&gt;started accepting refundable $99 Starlink preorders&lt;/a&gt; for “a limited number of users per coverage area,” which so far includes parts of the United States, Canada, and United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ipw2iL"&gt;SpaceX’s request to link Starlink with vehicles didn’t give any details on any new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/15/21325413/spacex-starlink-user-terminals-antennas-internet-satellite-constellation-beta-testing"&gt;antenna designs&lt;/a&gt;, but it said they “are electrically identical to its previously authorized consumer user terminals but have mountings that allow them to be installed on vehicles, vessels and aircraft.” The mobile antennas would fit on the “masts of ships or the tops of semi- trucks” — or, in consumer cases, on “passenger cars or pleasure boats,” another SpaceX filing said. Unlike Starlink’s current terminals, which come with mounts and are installed by the customer, the vehicle antennas will be set up by “qualified installers.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UUIR8T"&gt;Throwing a Starlink terminal on a moving vehicle isn’t a surprising move for SpaceX, which last year asked for an experimental FCC permit to operate Starlink terminals on Gulfstream jets. And though Musk played down the prospect of equipping Teslas with Starlink terminals today, he said in &lt;a href="https://seekingalpha.com/article/4320044-tesla-inc-tsla-ceo-elon-musk-on-q4-2019-results-earnings-call-transcript"&gt;an earnings call&lt;/a&gt; in January 2020 that “it’s certainly something that could happen in coming years.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DI1PER"&gt;With the new filing, SpaceX now appears to be more focused on their mobile connectivity efforts, hinting that they plan to target their service at “drivers, ship operators, and air travelers in the United States and abroad.” Offering Starlink internet to those customers will “allow operators and passengers to access services that enable increased productivity,” SpaceX said. The filing also mentioned that it would “enhance the security of mobile platforms” but provided no further insights into those plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZRbUQY"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 8th, 5:52PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This story was updated to include new details from a tweet by SpaceX CEO Elon Musk, commenting on the SpaceX FCC filing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319761/spacex-starlink-fcc-internet-cars-boats-aircraft"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319761/spacex-starlink-fcc-internet-cars-boats-aircraft</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Roulette</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T15:45:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T15:45:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>The brands are at it again — Taco Bell is hopping on the NFT train</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yyt7vBEBALJqJiOB8Jwxqs7vjjM=/0x86:512x427/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68931678/unnamed.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This piece is called Transformative Tacos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="r5cvPb"&gt;On Sunday evening, Taco Bell was serving up more than just tacos — it was also delivering NFTs: the fast-food chain &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tacobell/status/1368807880434982912"&gt;tweeted that it was selling taco-themed GIFs and images&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://rarible.com/tacobell?tab=created"&gt;NFT marketplace Rarible&lt;/a&gt;. Of course, everyone saw that it was a brand hopping on a bandwagon (one that could &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/nfts-hot-effect-earth-climate/"&gt;potentially be detrimental to the environment&lt;/a&gt;), and promptly ignored it. No one bought them, and no articles were written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="56lqqu"&gt;Just kidding! Taco Bell said that the demand for the NFTs was hot, and that the 25 tokens apparently sold out in 30 minutes. The NFTs are, of course, taco-themed, with four out of the five designs being animated GIFs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tK12KARJmU1WOjk0cPmH-Vr7yZ4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22354670/unnamed.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF: Taco Bell&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Taco cradle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div id="6SxHrd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10374749"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FIsNqf"&gt;Taco Bell does say that all the proceeds will go to the Live Más Scholarship through the Taco Bell Foundation. Taco Bell also told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the NFTs included a real-world perk in the form of a $500 electronic Taco Bell gift card. That perk, however, is reserved for the original owner of the NFT, a PR spokesperson confirmed. Not a bad deal for the people who paid a buck or two for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PIKc1s"&gt;Taco Bell has hinted that it’s planning on doing another run of the tokens, but I wouldn’t rush to buy them in hopes of getting a gift card — there are no promises that future Taco Bell NFTs will include them. Also, you’d have to spend the rest of your life knowing that you gave your money to Taco Bell and got back a GIF, instead of a taco. Taco Bell says that NFTs are forever, but can they really be as satisfying as the crunch of a hard tortilla shell with some water-flavored lettuce? Or if you want a better tasting taco, the warm feeling you get from supporting a local taco place instead?&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319868/taco-bell-nfts-gif-tacos-sell"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319868/taco-bell-nfts-gif-tacos-sell</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T15:40:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T15:40:16-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft was warned months ago — now, the Hafnium hack has grown to gigantic proportions</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cJxHCLnJkXm5zZ__lHjOU6wJg8k=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68931642/acastro_170621_1777_0007_v2_0001_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UWSWR9"&gt;On Friday, cybersecurity journalists Brian Krebs and Andy Greenberg reported that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/5/22316189/microsoft-exchange-server-security-exploit-china-attack-30000-organizations"&gt;as many as 30,000 organizations had been compromised&lt;/a&gt; in an unprecedented email server hack, believed to have originated from a state-sponsored Chinese hacking group known as Hafnium. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VCiEhB"&gt;Over the weekend, that estimate &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-07/hackers-breach-thousands-of-microsoft-customers-around-the-world"&gt;has &lt;em&gt;doubled&lt;/em&gt; to 60,000 Microsoft Exchange Server customers hacked around the world&lt;/a&gt;, with &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-56321567"&gt;the European Banking Authority now admitting&lt;/a&gt; that it’s one of the victims — and it looks like Microsoft may have taken a little too long to realize the severity and patch it. Krebs has now put together &lt;a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/03/a-basic-timeline-of-the-exchange-mass-hack/"&gt;a basic timeline&lt;/a&gt; of the massive Exchange Server hack, and he says Microsoft has confirmed it was made aware of the vulnerabilities in early January. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZMFzRU"&gt;That’s nearly two months before Microsoft issued its first set of patches, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fsecurity%2Fblog%2F2021%2F03%2F02%2Fhafnium-targeting-exchange-servers%2F%3FranMID%3D24542%26ranEAID%3DTnL5HPStwNw%26ranSiteID%3DTnL5HPStwNw-L0oJAsS_1sBt.74BPIZPQg%26epi%3DTnL5HPStwNw-L0oJAsS_1sBt.74BPIZPQg%26irgwc%3D1%26OCID%3DAID2000142_aff_7593_1243925%26tduid%3D%2528ir__yyl6lwa6xgkftidukk0sohzibe2xprw31xxe2pxb00%2529%25287593%2529%25281243925%2529%2528TnL5HPStwNw-L0oJAsS_1sBt.74BPIZPQg%2529%2528%2529%26irclickid%3D_yyl6lwa6xgkftidukk0sohzibe2xprw31xxe2pxb00&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F8%2F22319934%2Fmicrosoft-hafnium-hack-exchange-server-email-flaw-white-house" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;alongside a blog post&lt;/a&gt; that didn’t explain the scope or scale of the attack. Originally, it was even planning to wait for one of its standard Patch Tuesdays but relented and pushed it out a week early. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jKASwR"&gt;Now, &lt;a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2021/03/06/1020442/four-new-hacking-groups-microsoft-email-servers/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MIT Technology Review&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; Hafnium may not be the only threat, citing a cybersecurity analyst who claims there appear to be at least five hacking groups actively exploiting the Exchange Server flaws as of Saturday. Government officials are reportedly scrambling to do something, with one state official &lt;a href="https://www.cyberscoop.com/exchange-server-microsoft-hacks-china-biden/"&gt;telling &lt;em&gt;Cyberscoop&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that it’s “a big F’ing deal.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cTGaMh"&gt;More diplomatically, White House press secretary Jen Psaki &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/03/05/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-march-5-2021/"&gt;called it&lt;/a&gt; “an active threat,” drawing more attention to &lt;a href="https://cyber.dhs.gov/ed/21-02/"&gt;the emergency directive&lt;/a&gt; that the Department of Homeland Security’s cybersecurity agency sent out March 3rd. White House national security adviser Jake Sullivan has warned about it as well, as has former Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency director Christopher Krebs and the White House National Security Council.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="RPMgiD"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This is the real deal. If your organization runs an OWA server exposed to the internet, assume compromise between 02/26-03/03. Check for 8 character aspx files in C:\\inetpub\wwwroot\aspnet_client\system_web\. If you get a hit on that search, you’re now in incident response mode. &lt;a href="https://t.co/865Q8cc1Rm"&gt;https://t.co/865Q8cc1Rm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Chris Krebs (@C_C_Krebs) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/C_C_Krebs/status/1367673471669526528?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 5, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="yg1f8S"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Patching and mitigation is not remediation if the servers have already been compromised. It is essential that any organization with a vulnerable server take immediate measures to determine if they were already targeted. &lt;a href="https://t.co/HYKF2lA7sn"&gt;https://t.co/HYKF2lA7sn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— National Security Council (@WHNSC) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WHNSC/status/1368275202883411975?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 6, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lk5iTt"&gt;At this point, the message should be clear that anyone who installed a local Microsoft Exchange Server (2010, 2013, 2016, or 2019) needs to patch and scan, but we’re only beginning to understand the scope of the damage. Hackers reportedly installed malware that can let them right back into those servers again, and we don’t yet know what they might have already taken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6UCmcC"&gt;“We are undertaking a whole of government response to assess and address the impact,” reads part of an email from a White House official, according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vxExPv"&gt;Microsoft declined to comment about the timing of its patches and disclosures, pointing us to a previous statement instead: “We are working closely with the CISA, other government agencies, and security companies, to ensure we are providing the best possible guidance and mitigation for our customers. The best protection is to apply updates as soon as possible across all impacted systems. We continue to help customers by providing additional investigation and mitigation guidance. Impacted customers should contact our support teams for additional help and resources.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pY8ft5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, 4:27PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added Microsoft’s decline to comment, and earlier statement.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319934/microsoft-hafnium-hack-exchange-server-email-flaw-white-house"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319934/microsoft-hafnium-hack-exchange-server-email-flaw-white-house</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T15:28:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T15:28:24-05:00</updated>
    <title>Oprah’s Meghan and Harry interview exemplifies Paramount Plus’ streaming challenges</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tpjYxbQc45qYGJl0CG1u9tJT4CA=/72x0:857x523/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68931575/oprah_harrrymeghan.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TP9PxQ"&gt;Two of the biggest entertainment events of the weekend &lt;em&gt;could &lt;/em&gt;have been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22315338/paramount-plus-hands-on-nickleodeon-mtv-streaming-tv-movies"&gt;Paramount Plus&lt;/a&gt; exclusives: Oprah’s highly anticipated interview with Meghan Markle and Prince Harry, and Eddie Murphy’s eagerly awaited &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/22314289/coming-2-america-review"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Coming 2 America&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Instead, the former is now only &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cbs.com%2Fshows%2Foprah-with-meghan-and-harry-a-cbs-primetime-special%2Fvideo%2Fi6UW_WTQjLrEeOoObMmlwrFLTTypvuZm%2Fcbs-presents-oprah-with-meghan-and-harry-a-primetime-special%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F8%2F22319711%2Foprah-meghan-harry-interview-paramount-plus-coming-america" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available on CBS’s website (free)&lt;/a&gt; and the latter is streaming exclusively on Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5V0fyQ"&gt;For a company whose executives just touted the vital importance of leaning into streaming, having launched Paramount Plus within days of the interview and film being released, not finding a way to have one or the other — or both, ideally — available on demand is head-scratch worthy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FlEXfr"&gt;One absence is more understandable than the other. Harpo (Oprah’s production company) did not make the streaming video on-demand rights available to ViacomCBS, &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;has learned. The interview was available on Paramount Plus as live programming, but there’s no replay available for subscribers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wbilif"&gt;Their interview became the most streamed event outside of NFL games and the Super Bowl, according to ViacomCBS, but without any context, that statement doesn’t provide any accurate measurement. The interview also garnered an average of 17.1 million linear viewers on Sunday (a truly impressive number considering appointment television becomes more and more of a relic with each new streaming service). Based on that figure, and conversation on social media, it was a pretty big deal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Oi6AuP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s a short-term sacrifice play&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oV5w22"&gt;ViacomCBS actually made out quite well even without the interview being on Paramount Plus. The special brought in roughly $325,000 for a 30-second ad, &lt;a href="https://www.latimes.com/entertainment-arts/business/story/2021-03-08/oprah-winfreys-interview-with-meghan-and-harry-draws-17-million-viewers-on-cbs"&gt;according to the &lt;em&gt;Los Angeles Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; and is now playing ad-supported on CBS’s website and app. (The rights for something airing as a digital video on a free site and the rights to have it as an exclusive title for a longer period of time on a streaming service are different.) This means the interview could wind up on a different streaming service, but CBS’s digital website will have the interview for 30 days. All of which is great for CBS’s traditional television business, but not great for a company that has spent the last year touting the importance of its brand-new streaming platform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hqbjFc"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;Vulture&lt;/em&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kvanaren/status/1368927262159106051"&gt;Kathryn VanArendonk tweeted&lt;/a&gt;, “Imagine launching a streaming service, having a wildly popular interview that same week available only through your streaming service, and then having the interview disappear from your platform entirely the second it’s done airing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tXBBS9"&gt;It’s a short-term sacrifice play. Obviously, ViacomCBS would have liked to own the streaming rights to drive subscribers to Paramount Plus. But ViacomCBS did not have the upper hand. If CBS passed, Harpo could have gone to ABC (Disney) or NBC (Comcast) instead. Plus, based on a quick Google Trends search and scrolling through Twitter, people did sign up for Paramount Plus through the free trial for the interview. The question is whether or not people will stick around after those initial seven days. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CEZ31m"&gt;Remember, the key to understanding most companies’ streaming philosophies is exciting new content brings subscribers in, but it’s fan-favorite TV series and films that keep people paying month after month. That’s what makes the decision to not carry &lt;em&gt;Coming 2 America&lt;/em&gt;, the sequel to Eddie Murphy’s &lt;em&gt;Coming to America&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;even more confounding. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nZOBDS"&gt;Some important context to consider: ViacomCBS sold the film to Amazon in October during a period when the company was selling off a number of its films while theaters were closed or operating at limited capacity. &lt;em&gt;Trial of the Chicago 7 &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Lovebirds&lt;/em&gt; both went to Netflix, netting Paramount &lt;a href="https://www.thewrap.com/inside-paramounts-2020-survival-strategy-earn-more-selling-off-films-than-releasing-them/"&gt;between $75 and $85 million for both&lt;/a&gt;. Paramount also sold &lt;em&gt;Without Remorse &lt;/em&gt;to Amazon, alongside &lt;em&gt;Coming 2 America&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Yv3QZA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Paramount has been dysfunctional for 15 years, but...I’m speechless at how inept and stupid Paramount has been”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="w1lF4F"&gt;For several of the films, it made sense. CBS All Access wasn’t a major investment for ViacomCBS compared to Paramount Plus, and the company needed to generate revenue for movies just sitting on a shelf. The majority of these movies also came out prior to Paramount Plus’ launch. If the original intention was to release &lt;em&gt;Coming 2 America &lt;/em&gt;between mid-December and January, why not just push it back to March and make it a debut title?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wbu580"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Coming 2 America &lt;/em&gt;was released the same weekend as Paramount Plus. It could have been used to bring in subscribers, like &lt;em&gt;A Quiet Place II &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Mission Impossible 7&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;which&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;are leaving movie theaters early and landing on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299995/mission-impossible-7-quiet-place-2-paramount-plus-45-days-after-theaters"&gt;Paramount Plus just 45 days after release&lt;/a&gt;. Instead of leveraging the film, ViacomCBS wound up competing with Amazon for attention. Not having the movie is one less reason for people to sign up for Paramount Plus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gz07UR"&gt;As one former executive at a rival studio told &lt;em&gt;The Verge, &lt;/em&gt;“Paramount has been dysfunctional for 15 years, but ... I’m speechless at how inept and stupid Paramount has been.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="keOIAF"&gt;Oh, and in terms of where Oprah’s interview with Meghan and Harry might end up after all is said and done? Keep an eye &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/1/22307034/discovery-plus-ambient-tv-hgtv-food-tlc-house-hunters-90-day-fiance-diners-driveins-dives"&gt;on Discovery Plus&lt;/a&gt;. Oprah has a stake in the company, and OWN is part of the Discovery family. It’s just the thing Discovery Plus would love to have. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319711/oprah-meghan-harry-interview-paramount-plus-coming-america"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319711/oprah-meghan-harry-interview-paramount-plus-coming-america</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-08T15:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T15:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Waymo simulated real-world crashes to prove its self-driving cars can prevent deaths</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Self-propelled car from Google sister company Waymo" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NVwx5nXD54BFAwB3wzKXG82EOlE=/53x0:3568x2343/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68931331/1142125645.jpg.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Andrej Sokolow / picture alliance via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HLNS4K"&gt;In a bid to prove that its robot drivers are safer than humans, Waymo simulated dozens of real-world fatal crashes that took place in Arizona over nearly a decade. The Google spinoff discovered that replacing either vehicle in a two-car crash with its robot-guided minivans would nearly eliminate all deaths, &lt;a href="https://blog.waymo.com/2021/03/replaying-real-life.html"&gt;according to data it publicized today&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0hikKa"&gt;The results are meant to bolster Waymo’s case that autonomous vehicles operate more safely than human-driven ones. With millions of people dying in auto crashes globally every year, AV operators are increasingly leaning on this safety case to spur regulators to pass legislation allowing more fully autonomous vehicles on the road. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="0kpbb8"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Waymo has turned to counterfactuals, or “what if?” scenarios&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Lp6Gn9"&gt;But that case has been difficult to prove out, thanks to the very limited number of autonomous vehicles operating on public roads today. To provide more statistical support for its argument, Waymo has turned to counterfactuals, or “what if?” scenarios, meant to showcase how its robot vehicles would react in real-world situations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1U9ouX"&gt;Last year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/30/21538999/waymo-self-driving-car-data-miles-crashes-phoenix-google"&gt;the company published 6.1 million miles of driving data&lt;/a&gt; in 2019 and 2020, including 18 crashes and 29 near-miss collisions. In those incidents where its safety operators took control of the vehicle to avoid a crash, Waymo’s engineers simulated what would have happened had the driver not disengaged the vehicle’s self-driving system to generate a counterfactual. The company has also made &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/21/20822755/waymo-self-driving-car-data-set-free-research"&gt;some of its data available to academic researchers&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="tq0Cfa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Waymo’s driverless car: ghost-riding in the back seat of a robot taxi","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/9/21000085/waymo-fully-driverless-car-self-driving-ride-hail-service-phoenix-arizona"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="rAd8lP"&gt;That work in counterfactuals continues in this most recent data release. Through a third party, Waymo collected information on every fatal crash that took place in Chandler, Arizona, a suburban community outside Phoenix, between 2008 and 2017. Focusing just on the crashes that took place within its operational design domain, or the approximately 100-square-mile area in which the company permits its cars to drive, Waymo identified 72 crashes to reconstruct in simulation in order to determine how its autonomous system would respond in similar situations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qHiKCb"&gt;
&lt;iframe class="scribd_iframe_embed" title="Waymo Simulated Driving Behavior in Reconstructed Collisions" src="https://www.scribd.com/embeds/497900366/content?start_page=1&amp;amp;view_mode=scroll&amp;amp;access_key=key-tnzKLmhnZfzquBqFRKcp" tabindex="0" data-auto-height="true" data-aspect-ratio="0.7729220222793488" scrolling="no" width="100%" height="600" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p style="   margin: 12px auto 6px auto;   font-family: Helvetica,Arial,Sans-serif;   font-style: normal;   font-variant: normal;   font-weight: normal;   font-size: 14px;   line-height: normal;   font-size-adjust: none;   font-stretch: normal;   -x-system-font: none;   display: block;"&gt;&lt;a title="View Waymo Simulated Driving Behavior in Reconstructed Collisions on Scribd" href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.scribd.com%2Fdocument%2F497900366%2FWaymo-Simulated-Driving-Behavior-in-Reconstructed-Collisions%23from_embed&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F8%2F22315361%2Fwaymo-autonomous-vehicle-simulation-car-crash-deaths" style="text-decoration: underline;" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Waymo Simulated Driving Beh...&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a title="View ahawkins8223's profile on Scribd" href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.scribd.com%2Fuser%2F112638498%2Fahawkins8223%23from_embed&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F8%2F22315361%2Fwaymo-autonomous-vehicle-simulation-car-crash-deaths" style="text-decoration: underline;" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ahawkins8223&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VNA8a6"&gt;Some of these crashes involved one vehicle, while most involved two. For crashes with two vehicles, Waymo ran separate experiments simulating its autonomous vehicles in the role of each vehicle — first replacing the vehicle that initiated the crash and then replacing the vehicle that responded to the other vehicle’s actions. For crashes with one vehicle, Waymo only simulated the single vehicle. That left it with 91 simulations in total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fgYq7o"&gt;The company reconstructed these crashes, systematically aligning the vehicle’s trajectory to make sure its Waymo vehicles are exposed to a similar situation than in the actual fatal crash. Waymo used the same simulation platform it uses to train and evaluate its autonomous vehicles on virtual roads in ordinary operations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="UU2PG4"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Waymo’s AVs “avoided or mitigated” 88 out of 91 total simulations&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aFwmwg"&gt;The results show that Waymo’s autonomous vehicles would have “avoided or mitigated” 88 out of 91 total simulations, said Trent Victor, director of safety research and best practices at Waymo. Moreover, for the crashes that were mitigated, Waymo’s vehicles would have reduced the likelihood of serious injury by a factor of 1.3 to 15 times, Victor said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tLXYdt"&gt;“That means that even if it didn’t avoid the crash completely, it took action to reduce the severity of the impact,” Victor said. “If the severity was reduced, it made it less likely that the driver would have died.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hr12D2"&gt;When Waymo replaced the vehicle responding to the instigator of the crash, it found that it “completely avoided” 82 percent of simulated crashes — the vast majority of which without the need for hard braking or evasive action. In another 10 percent as a responder, the Waymo vehicle’s urgent maneuvers helped mitigate the severity of the crash. Those crashes all took place at an intersection where the other vehicle either turned left across or cut straight across the Waymo vehicle’s path, leaving little time to react, the company said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PUpin5"&gt;“We’re not saying that we will eliminate all fatalities, but we are saying that the best way to reduce the chances of a serious injury would be to take an evasive maneuver when that’s possible,” Victor said. “And in all of these crash simulations, the Waymo driver took evasive maneuvers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="CBEwbp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The Waymo driver took evasive maneuvers”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rvhI5J"&gt;There were three incidents of a person dying after being rear-ended by another vehicle. In simulation, Waymo was not able to avoid these crashes when its vehicle was the one being rear-ended. “In rear crashes specifically, there’s not a lot that the responder role can do,” said Matthew Schwall, head of field safety at Waymo. “So the Waymo driver really suffers from the same challenge that humans do in those situations, that it’s hard to make the prediction soon enough to be able to make an evasive maneuver.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n0KMlQ"&gt;Twenty simulated crashes involved a pedestrian or cyclist being struck by a driver. Waymo’s autonomous vehicles avoided 100 percent of those crashes in simulation, the company said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3QpdpF"&gt;There’s no standard approach for evaluating AV safety. &lt;a href="https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_reports/RRA569-1.html"&gt;A recent study by RAND&lt;/a&gt; concluded that, in the absence of a framework, customers are most likely to trust the government — even though US &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/15/21292014/dot-nhtsa-self-driving-car-test-data-voluntary"&gt;regulators appear content to let the private sector dictate what’s safe&lt;/a&gt;. In this vacuum, Waymo hopes that by publicizing this data, policymakers, researchers, and even other companies may begin to take on the task of developing a universal framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w3pTce"&gt;To be sure, Waymo did not make its findings subject to a peer-reviewed analysis for publication in an academic or scientific journal, though it would be open to publishing it in the future, a spokesperson said. The simulations were not conducted independently of the company, nor were they reviewed by any third-party for verification prior to the company making them public. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j8FRH0"&gt;The company did share its findings with a select group of academic experts to get their reactions. Daniel McGehee, director of the National Advanced Driving Simulator Laboratories at the University of Iowa, said Waymo is pushing safety analyses and transparency “to a new level.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZugPly"&gt;Jonas Bargman, associate professor for vehicle safety at Chalmers University of Technology in Sweden, said that Waymo’s use of simulation-based assessment is at “the scientific forefront” but only one of the components needed to assess the safety of automated vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TpRWgw"&gt;After reviewing the report, Bargman concluded that the “Waymo simulation platform is highly sophisticated,” citing the company’s 3D sensor-level perception models. He singled out the use of counterfactual what-if scenarios as “highly relevant for the introduction of Waymo self-driving vehicles to the public.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22315361/waymo-autonomous-vehicle-simulation-car-crash-deaths"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22315361/waymo-autonomous-vehicle-simulation-car-crash-deaths</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
