<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2020-12-14T03:23:41-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-14T03:23:41-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-14T03:23:41-05:00</updated>
    <title>EA is buying Codemasters for $1.2 billion to take lead in racing game market</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_XFbajObSeg7gAjJsZeLI0ltLjA=/150x0:1850x1133/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68508136/XlPL0pXmRyiUcwac_SxURA.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nBQXPk"&gt;Electronic Arts has agreed to buy out UK developer Codemasters in a move that could see the US publishing giant wrest control of the racing video game genre. The deal is expected to close in the first quarter of next year for £6.04 (~$7.98) a share, valuing Codemasters at around $1.2 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YNZFJ6"&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.sky.com/story/games-giant-electronic-arts-gatecrashes-725m-codemasters-takeover-12160582?awc=11005_1607932504_f635c04741f6c3ae9f7e6abbb5b5e4b8&amp;amp;dcmp=afc-103504-na-na-longtail&amp;amp;dclid=CIrGyq7_zO0CFQwEvAodKHoGoQ"&gt;Sky News first reported&lt;/a&gt; EA’s interest in Codemasters over the weekend, saying that the British company had previously agreed a $970 million deal with Rockstar Games and 2K Sports owner Take-Two Interactive. EA &lt;a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20201213005036/en/Electronic-Arts-Reaches-Agreement-for-Recommended-Acquisition-of-Codemasters-Group-Holdings-PLC"&gt;confirmed&lt;/a&gt; the agreement early Monday morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cvXU3g"&gt;Codemasters is one of the oldest British game developers, having been founded in the ‘80s and producing early hits like &lt;em&gt;Dizzy &lt;/em&gt;for systems that were popular in the UK like the ZX Spectrum and the Commodore 64. In recent decades it’s been best known for creating racing games like the &lt;em&gt;Dirt&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Grid&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Formula 1&lt;/em&gt; series, and last year acquired the developer behind &lt;em&gt;Project Cars&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ezZtca"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Dirt 5 reminded me how much I needed MotorStorm back in my life","url":"https://www.polygon.com/2020/11/17/21571850/dirt-5-motorstorm-impressions-tracks-courses"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="vu70I7"&gt;EA, of course, owns the &lt;em&gt;Need for Speed&lt;/em&gt; franchise, so the Codemasters addition would give it further control over a huge chunk of the racing game market. The main competitors would be Sony’s &lt;em&gt;Gran Turismo&lt;/em&gt; and Microsoft’s &lt;em&gt;Forza&lt;/em&gt; series, both of which are exclusive to their publisher’s respective consoles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4KPtNM"&gt;“We believe there is a deeply compelling opportunity in bringing together Codemasters and Electronic Arts to create amazing and innovative new racing games for fans,” EA CEO Andrew Wilson says in a statement. “Our industry is growing, the racing category is growing, and together we will be positioned to lead in a new era of racing entertainment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ePYZV3"&gt;“Electronic Arts and Codemasters have a shared ambition to lead the video game racing category,” says Codemasters chairman Gerhard Florin. “The Board of Codemasters firmly believes the company would benefit from EA’s knowledge, resources and extensive global scale — both overall and specifically within the racing sector. We feel this union would provide an exciting and prosperous future for Codemasters, allowing our teams to create, launch and service bigger and better games to an extremely passionate audience.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/14/22173732/ea-codemasters-buyout-agreed-price-need-for-speed-dirt"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/14/22173732/ea-codemasters-buyout-agreed-price-need-for-speed-dirt</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-13T17:02:53-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-13T17:02:53-05:00</updated>
    <title>Hackers backed by Russian government reportedly breached US government agencies</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6H9bf1FQ7mwx4qExq8JM7LSCxAA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68506684/acastro_170629_1777_0008.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2vGgQG"&gt;The same Russian government hacking group responsible for a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22165027/fireeye-cybersecurity-attack-red-team-tools"&gt;security breach at FireEye&lt;/a&gt; compromised the Treasury and Commerce departments and other US government agencies, &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/russian-government-spies-are-behind-a-broad-hacking-campaign-that-has-breached-us-agencies-and-a-top-cyber-firm/2020/12/13/d5a53b88-3d7d-11eb-9453-fc36ba051781_story.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;reported. The group, known as APT29, or Cozy Bear, was responsible for hacking the US State Department and the White House during the Obama administration, according to the &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt;, and is the group that officials believe &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/16/21327021/russia-hackers-covid19-coronavirus-vaccine-attacks-uk-us-canada"&gt;targeted COVID-19 vaccine research&lt;/a&gt; over the summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OmnJLU"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-cyber-amazon-com-exclsuive-idUSKBN28N0PG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters &lt;/em&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; that in addition to hacking Treasury and the Commerce Department’s National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA), the hackers may have breached other US government entities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OyqO0t"&gt;Government officials considered the hack dire enough that the National Security Council held an emergency meeting at the White House on Saturday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vrQVzM"&gt;An NSC spokesman told &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; that the government was “aware” of the reports, adding “we are taking all necessary steps” to remedy the situation. It’s not yet clear exactly what information may have been stolen or which foreign government was involved. But the “highly sophisticated” hackers were able to break into NTIA’s Microsoft Office software, tricking authentication controls in order to monitor staff emails for months, according to &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l9eD4V"&gt;Several federal law enforcement agencies, including the FBI, are investigating the breach. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gFeJau"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/13/22173035/hackers-russia-breached-us-government-agencies-email-cozy-bear"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/13/22173035/hackers-russia-breached-us-government-agencies-email-cozy-bear</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-13T15:45:42-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-13T15:45:42-05:00</updated>
    <title>New video of Samsung Galaxy S21 Plus shows thin bezels around a flat display </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mO2Ijmjo7XNWNK_NEI3QZOZVlqQ=/0x202:804x738/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68506381/random_stuff_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_Lf3p_1m4NE&amp;amp;feature=emb_logo&amp;amp;ab_channel=RandomStuff2" target="_blank"&gt;Random Stuff 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Dvjok6"&gt;Plenty of details about the Samsung Galaxy S21 have already leaked ahead of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167208/samsung-galaxy-s21-january-14th-launch-india-plus-ultra-s-pen"&gt;expected January release&lt;/a&gt; date. But a new video gives a glimpse of the Galaxy S21 Plus model, showing a flat display with thin bezels around it, and a punch hole selfie camera. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zcZkfw"&gt;The quality of the video from user Random Stuff 2 isn’t the greatest, and it has some sort of distracting music playing under the user’s commentary. It also doesn’t provide a lot of detail about the back of the phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="G4nOBU"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_Lf3p_1m4NE?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="F9QMXn"&gt;Three Galaxy S21 models are expected: a standard, a Plus and an Ultra. A &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/12/8/22163632/samsung-galaxy-s21-plus-ultra-5g-teaser-video-leak"&gt;series of leaked teaser trailers&lt;/a&gt;, showed off redesigned camera bumps, showing what appears to be five cameras on the S21 Ultra and three each on the S21 and S21 Plus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ijk7mf"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2020/11/14/exclusive-specs-and-features-of-samsungs-galaxy-s21-smartphones/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt; reported last month&lt;/a&gt; that the S21 will have a 6.2-inch display, the Plus will be 6.7 inches and the Ultra will have a 6.8-inch display. The phones will all have batteries ranging in size from 4,000 mAh to 5,000 mAh, and all three are expected to have either a Snapdragon 875 or Exynos 2100 processor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qGFdvd"&gt;The phones are all expected to have 5G, with the S21 and Plus both with Wi-Fi 6 and Bluetooth 5.1, and Wi-Fi 6E in the Ultra. The S21 Ultra is also expected to be compatible with Samsung’s S-Pen, but rumor has it the S-Pen won’t be sold with the device. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b8VmCs"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fXAShG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q4yA2e"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/13/22172817/new-video-samsung-galaxy-s21-plus-slim-bezels-flat-display"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/13/22172817/new-video-samsung-galaxy-s21-plus-slim-bezels-flat-display</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-13T13:47:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-13T13:47:26-05:00</updated>
    <title>Oracle moves its HQ from California to Texas</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Oracle stock" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fgj8J5DRODVG-zBBBWQI2mY-LK0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68505909/acastro_201002_1777_googleVsOracle_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Alex Castro&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vy8b8W"&gt;Software giant Oracle moved the company headquarters from Redwood City, California to Austin, Texas, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-12-11/oracle-moves-headquarters-to-texas-joins-exodus-from-california"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;, the latest tech firm to depart Silicon Valley for the Lone Star State.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xqcuIu"&gt;Oracle did not immediately reply to a request for comment Sunday, but &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/12/11/oracle-is-moving-its-headquarters-from-silicon-valley-to-austin-texas.html"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that it was putting into place “a more flexible employee work location policy,” and that the move to Austin would “best position Oracle for growth and provide our personnel with more flexibility about where and how they work.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ujBwyf"&gt;Oracle, founded in 1977, is one of the older Valley tech firms, and is a staple of the area; the San Francisco Giants play at Oracle Park, and the company’s Redwood City campus features its well-known cylindrical buildings. It already has a campus in Austin, which it opened in 2018. Texas Gov. Greg Abbott heralded the news in a tweet, saying “Texas is truly the land of business, jobs, and opportunity.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4geq5K"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;BREAKING: Oracle just announced they have moved their Headquarters to Austin. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Texas is truly the land of business, jobs, and opportunity. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We will continue to attract the very best.&lt;/p&gt;— Greg Abbott (@GregAbbott_TX) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GregAbbott_TX/status/1337518818013405190?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 11, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HrUs5k"&gt;Several other firms have announced plans to leave California in recent months, with some company leaders blaming the state’s political climate as unfriendly to business. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/22/21334860/tesla-cybertruck-factory-austin-texas-location-model-y"&gt;Tesla is building a new plant&lt;/a&gt; near Austin and CEO Elon Musk has threatened to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/9/21253127/elon-musk-lawsuit-alameda-coronavirus-tesla-fremont-lockdown"&gt;move the company out of California&lt;/a&gt; altogether after tussling with local officials over coronavirus lockdowns, but Tesla still has a plant in Fremont. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163805/elon-musk-texas-moved-california-tesla-spacex"&gt;Musk said he moved his personal residence&lt;/a&gt; to Texas, as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="akkROG"&gt;And another Silicon Valley company, &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/houston-california-greg-abbott-texas-1ce5ef41c6e20e84b5954de11fa3c8a7"&gt;Hewlett Packard Enterprise, announced plans&lt;/a&gt; earlier this month to build a 440,000-square-foot campus in a Houston suburb for its new headquarters. HPE already has Texas locations in Austin and Plano, near Dallas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eMQMIo"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IeQExg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eDHqb6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/13/22172610/oracle-moves-headquarters-california-texas-hewlett-packard-tesla"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/13/22172610/oracle-moves-headquarters-california-texas-hewlett-packard-tesla</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-13T11:44:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-13T11:44:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>Workers reportedly protest at Wistron iPhone plant in India over pay issues</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="INDIA-LABOUR-UNREST" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RO-wBIEA5V57I49aBxDi57FLZMY=/0x0:4600x3067/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68505471/1230098491.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by MANJUNATH KIRAN/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KP7G9F"&gt;Workers at an iPhone production plant in India reportedly smashed windows and set fire to vehicles to protest reductions in pay, the &lt;a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/bengaluru/violence-breaks-out-at-wistron-corps-iphone-manufacturing-plant-near-bengaluru/articleshow/79691511.cms"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Times of India &lt;/em&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;. The incidents began Saturday at a facility run by Taiwan manufacturing company Wistron Corporation, where the &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2020/08/24/iphone-se-assembled-in-india/"&gt; iPhone SE is assembled.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kIUGQr"&gt;According to the &lt;a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/bangalore/angry-at-delayed-payments-employees-ransack-narsapura-plant-where-iphones-are-made-7102392/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Indian Express&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; during a shift change workers who said they had seen their pay reduced damaged the offices, some furniture, and factory equipment before things escalated outside. A local official told the &lt;em&gt;Express &lt;/em&gt;that police were investigating the incident. About 2,000 workers were involved in the protest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zyjtyZ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Karnataka: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Violence?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Violence&lt;/a&gt; at iPhone production plant run by Taiwan-based &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Wistron?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Wistron&lt;/a&gt; Corp at Narasapura (in Kolar district) near &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Bengaluru?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Bengaluru&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Employees allege they have not been paid properly. &lt;a href="https://t.co/GKbeFeyRKc"&gt;pic.twitter.com/GKbeFeyRKc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— TOI Bengaluru (@TOIBengaluru) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TOIBengaluru/status/1337615298761912321?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 12, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5ncnBF"&gt;Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/5/17/15651842/apple-iphone-india-assembling-begun"&gt;began assembling iPhones in India &lt;/a&gt;in 2017, where it &lt;a href="https://www.techradar.com/news/apple-tops-indias-premium-smartphone-market-with-a-756-share"&gt;tops the premium smartphone&lt;/a&gt; market. However, it only has about a 1 percent share of the total smartphone market in the country, since the &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-india-apple-wistron/apple-supplier-wistron-to-assemble-key-iphone-component-in-new-india-plant-sources-idUSKBN1ZX0F6"&gt;iPhone’s price tag puts it out of reach&lt;/a&gt; for many Indian consumers. &lt;a href="https://www.counterpointresearch.com/india-surpassed-usa-become-second-largest-smartphone-market-world-reaching-158-million-shipments-2019/"&gt;India was the second-biggest smartphone market&lt;/a&gt; in the world in 2019, ahead of the US and second only to China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="POOpJN"&gt;Wistron opened the plant near Bengaluru earlier this year, &lt;a href="https://www.deccanherald.com/business/technology/wistron-to-assemble-key-apple-iphone-component-in-india-sources-801036.html"&gt;part of a multimillion dollar investment&lt;/a&gt; by the company in India. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F9nGBJ"&gt;Apple and Wistron did not immediately reply to requests for comment Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I05vaV"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/13/22172383/workers-protest-wistron-iphone-se-plant-india-pay"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/13/22172383/workers-protest-wistron-iphone-se-plant-india-pay</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-13T09:44:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-13T09:44:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla will reportedly suspend production of its Model S and Model X for 18 days</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8WtiJA4gtFAQRsPaLCt417MWXqA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68505062/acastro_180524_1777_tesla_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="engadget-post-contents"&gt;Tesla will shut down production for its Model S and Model X for 18 days beginning December 24th according to an internal memo, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/12/12/tesla-model-s-and-x-production-will-shut-down-for-18-days-email.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt; reported.&lt;/a&gt; Why and what the company will do with the two lines during the shutdown wasn’t immediately clear, but workers on those production lines will apparently get a week’s pay, some paid holidays, and will have opportunities to work on other teams within the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g9TmJd"&gt;The memo also says the workers can volunteer to help with delivery of vehicles to customers while production is on hold. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F2SQx7"&gt;Auto industry analyst &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tweetermeyer/status/1337904510551773187?s=21"&gt;Edward Niedermeyer noted&lt;/a&gt; that Tesla asked California for tax exemptions in 2015 for equipment it needed to build 195,000 Model S and Model X vehicles by 2021. &lt;a href="https://dailykanban.com/2016/09/08/tesla-plans-long-term-expansion-model-s-model-x-capacity/"&gt;The company told the state of California&lt;/a&gt; at the time it would expand its production capabilities in anticipation of producing “approximately 118,000 additional Model S and X vehicles per year,” in addition to its projected annual rate of approximately 77,000 Model S and X vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lchfKL"&gt;&lt;a href="https://ir.tesla.com/press-release/tesla-q3-2020-vehicle-production-deliveries"&gt;In the third quarter of 2020&lt;/a&gt;, Tesla produced 145,000 vehicles and delivered 139,300. Of that number, Tesla produced just under 17,000 Model S and X vehicles, delivering 15,200 of them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WKgKJ3"&gt;Tesla is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/22/21334860/tesla-cybertruck-factory-austin-texas-location-model-y"&gt;building its next factory in Austin&lt;/a&gt;, Texas, and CEO Elon Musk has threatened to move all &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/9/21253127/elon-musk-lawsuit-alameda-coronavirus-tesla-fremont-lockdown"&gt;Tesla production out of California&lt;/a&gt;. He confirmed he has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163805/elon-musk-texas-moved-california-tesla-spacex"&gt;relocated his personal residence&lt;/a&gt; from California to Texas, a move predicted to save him millions in taxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nGRkTW"&gt;In a separate email to employees Friday, Musk said demand for Tesla vehicles has been “quite a bit higher than production this quarter,” and urged employees to increase production as much as possible, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-12-12/musk-calls-on-tesla-workers-to-boost-output-through-end-of-year?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;. “Please send me a note directly if you see ways to improve output, but feel that your voice is not being heard,” he wrote in the email. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1SqOea"&gt;During Tesla’s October battery day event, the company said it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/2/21498558/tesla-q3-2020-vehicle-delivery-numbers-record-breaking"&gt;expected to deliver 500,000 vehicles in 2020&lt;/a&gt;. But by that point, the company had sent 318,350 cars to customers, so it will need to deliver more than 181,000 vehicles before the end of the year to hit its target. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gunokV"&gt;Tesla did not respond to a request for comment Sunday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EaY4F7"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wzd919"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XMw5hp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/13/22172375/tesla-suspend-production-model-s-model-x-18-days-elon-musk"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/13/22172375/tesla-suspend-production-model-s-model-x-18-days-elon-musk</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-13T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-13T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Which celebrity should be the face of the COVID-19 vaccine?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Elvis Presley receiving a polio vaccination from Dr. Leona B" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TSLQL8IPgSaK98Sbt_1HgmdPZjE=/0x290:4862x3531/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68504889/585208158.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Seymour Wally/NY Daily News Archive via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WUd4mW"&gt;In 1956, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2016/apr/24/elvis-presley-polio-vaccine-world-immunisation-week"&gt;Elvis Presley&lt;/a&gt; got a polio vaccination on the&lt;em&gt; Ed Sullivan Show&lt;/em&gt;. The shot was newly available and highly effective — but too few teenagers and young adults were getting vaccinated, so the devastating disease was still circulating. Officials turned to Presley to set an example and encourage people to get their shots. Along with other campaigns, the celebrity endorsement helped vaccination rates go up, and eventually, the disease was eliminated from the country. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aC3DrC"&gt;That bit of history raises a very important question: who will be the Elvis Presley of the COVID-19 vaccine? The vaccine won’t help slow the pandemic if people don’t take it, and many people still say they &lt;a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/science/2020/12/03/intent-to-get-a-covid-19-vaccine-rises-to-60-as-confidence-in-research-and-development-process-increases/"&gt;aren’t sure&lt;/a&gt; if they will. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Z4oki"&gt;Presidents Barack Obama, George W. Bush, and Bill Clinton &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/12/02/politics/obama-vaccine/index.html"&gt;already said&lt;/a&gt; they’ll take the vaccine in public, as did &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2020/12/11/world/covid-19-coronavirus#to-build-confidence-fauci-says-hell-get-vaccinated-publicly"&gt;Anthony Fauci&lt;/a&gt;, director of the National Institute for Allergy and Infectious Diseases. That’s a great start — but for an unprecedented vaccination campaign, we probably need more famous people on board. Celebrities can’t be the only way officials encourage people to roll up their sleeves (vaccine communication is complicated!), but it might help. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tjntui"&gt;Here’s who &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; staffers think should get vaccinated in public.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Queen, Duke Of Edinburgh, Prince Of Wales &amp;amp;amp; Duchess Of Cornwall Visit Poundbury" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BIguhYxhTlRYSDBhcROkOmYp-To=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22163428/618569182.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Samir Hussein / WireImage&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="CAsjz0"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II&lt;/strong&gt; - She is literally the queen. This won’t mean much to anyone with even the smallest anti-authoritarian leaning, but for many from a certain generation, Queen Elizabeth represents an uncomplicated bygone era where a stiff upper lip was all you needed to get through the toughest of hardships. Broadcasting her vaccination would send a powerful message, not least about the safety of the vaccine. Broadcast it anywhere where viewership trends older, like traditional broadcast channels. — &lt;em&gt;Jon Porter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K7Zg5q"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Donald Fagen of Steely Dan&lt;/strong&gt; - I’ll start with the obvious: Donald Fagen is not a beloved or even particularly famous pop star. But at 72, Fagen is at the forefront of the generation most at risk for COVID-19, and he still holds a powerful sway over his age cohort. He’s also a known conservative and a longstanding skeptic of grand paternalist schemes — exactly the kind of person vaccine developers need to win over. If inoculating Fagen can get the vast silent majority of Steely Dan aficionados on board, it could be a huge service to public health. — &lt;em&gt;Russell Brandom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="iHpCPK"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Donald Fagen is not a beloved or even particularly famous pop star&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1pNA88"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gwyneth Paltrow&lt;/strong&gt; — There’s no one group that defines the anti-vaxxer. But rich, white people are &lt;a href="https://well.blogs.nytimes.com/2015/12/24/rich-white-and-refusing-vaccinations/"&gt;more likely&lt;/a&gt; than most to decline vaccines for their children. A few years back, they made headlines for &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2015/jan/17/too-rich-sick-disneyland-measles-outbreak-reflects-anti-vaccination-trend"&gt;skipping measles vaccinations&lt;/a&gt;, which came to light after an outbreak of the highly contagious disease at Disneyland. They might be inclined to trust Paltrow, patron saint of wellness and &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2020/jan/13/why-is-gwyneth-paltrow-selling-a-candle-that-smells-like-her-vagina-goop"&gt;vagina candles&lt;/a&gt;. If she throws Goop’s support behind COVID-19 vaccinations, she might be able to get this group on board. — &lt;em&gt;Nicole Wetsman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bvr8tq"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oprah Winfrey - &lt;/strong&gt;The “wine moms” our pop culture mostly ignores are &lt;em&gt;hugely important&lt;/em&gt;: they tend to be influential in their families and communities. Oprah has made an entire career out of cultivating these women — it’s part of the reason why she’s such an icon. You want everyone vaccinated? Have Oprah do it live, on television, as part of a special. The opportunities here are endless: you can bring on musical guests, who play a song or two and then &lt;em&gt;also &lt;/em&gt;get vaccinated. You can have an interview with a major cultural icon who talks about how they have personally been affected by the pandemic (Tom Hanks, anyone?). And maybe, since Oprah is famous for her giveaways, there’s a segment where Oprah gives either an in-studio audience the vaccine or where she travels around the country vaccinating fans. It would be must-watch television — and if the adoption rates of the books and consumer products Oprah champions are any indication, we’ll have the vaccinations done in no time. —&lt;em&gt; Liz Lopatto&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5mqDVp"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dolly Parton — &lt;/strong&gt;Dolly is having a major 2020. She was introduced to a new audience of fans thanks to the Twins the New Trend &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_pEPFYiJOXU&amp;amp;ab_channel=TwinsthenewTrend"&gt;review of her 1973 hit “Jolene,”&lt;/a&gt; and her $1 million donation to Vanderbilt University &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/nation/2020/11/18/dolly-parton-moderna-vaccine-abumrad-covid/"&gt;helped fund Moderna’s coronavirus vaccine&lt;/a&gt;. She’s a longtime supporter of philanthropic causes: she’s raised money for wildfire relief, HIV-AIDS research, and a cancer hospital. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/colbertlateshow/status/1333645538328076288"&gt;President Obama recently admitted&lt;/a&gt; he screwed up by not giving Dolly a Medal of Freedom while he was in office. Despite her fame and business acumen, Dolly’s unpretentious, homey image and humble beginnings make her the perfect person to reassure people across many demographics about taking a vaccine; after all, Dolly’s already on board with it. — &lt;em&gt;Kim Lyons &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Billboard Women In Music 2020" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aNwx3IXjbBSyROL7hK6tlmLt1jc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22163217/1290609708.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by 2020 Billboard Women In Music / Getty Images for Billboard&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="eicRAH"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taylor Swift &lt;/strong&gt;— Prior to the 2018 midterm elections, Taylor Swift made an Instagram post urging her fans to vote for Tennessee Democratic candidates. At that time, the singer rarely discussed politics publicly and hadn’t waded into the 2016 election (it was the same summer as her Snapchat scandal). But she chose the right moment to break her silence: the post appeared to lead to a &lt;a href="https://time.com/5419276/taylor-swift-instagram-post-voter-registration-spike/"&gt;sharp rise in voter registrations&lt;/a&gt; among young people. As a celebrity with such a massive, young, and ardent following, you can probably only make so many public statements like this before your more apolitical fans start tuning it out. But Swift’s base still seems to be listening to her, and a vaccination over Instagram live could be what we need to send young people out in droves. She could even write a song about it! — &lt;em&gt;Monica Chin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G1vF03"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kim Kardashian / the Kardashian family —&lt;/strong&gt; Encourage people to keep up with the Kardashians by getting vaccinated. Then, everyone can go to Kim’s 41st birthday party on a private island! — &lt;em&gt;Jay Peters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="FGbkEs"&gt;&lt;q&gt;keep up with the Kardashians by getting vaccinated&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="H2RCsM"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Desus and Mero&lt;/strong&gt; — Hosts of late-night talk shows appeal to a large audience of America. Of the many entertainers of the genre, Desus and Mero are the most down-to-earth of the bunch. They know how to talk to an audience and they understand the internet and pop culture more than any other on television. Their strength in communicating would easily illustrate how relieved you should feel that a vaccine is here. — &lt;em&gt;Andru Marino&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kyt76S"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jeff Foxworthy, Bill Engvall, Ron White, and Larry the Cable Guy — &lt;/strong&gt;If this is going to be a televised event, a reunion is what drives numbers on TV today. The cast of &lt;em&gt;Blue Collar Comedy Tour&lt;/em&gt; was marketed as four guys speaking from an everyday American perspective. They may appeal to a crowd that may be skeptical of a vaccine, and bringing lighthearted comedy into the situation can ease over some tensions. Also, they could reunite on Desus and Mero’s show. — &lt;em&gt;Andru Marino&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Tonight Show Starring Jimmy Fallon - Season 8" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AKxaADzKHkgDFgKVM4PCgcQOZKQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22163431/1228811202.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by: Andrew Lipovsky / NBC / NBCU Photo Bank via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jimmy Fallon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="gLz8HU"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Late-night TV hosts — &lt;/strong&gt;Whether you watch the likes of Jimmy Fallon, Stephen Colbert, Lilly Singh, Jimmy Kimmel, or Conan O’Brien regularly — or at all — it’s tough to deny their influence in pop culture. Having each of them volunteer to get a vaccine during a show, perhaps looping in celebrity guests to also take part, would be a great way to boost trust in the vaccine, cast over public access TV channels that anyone can freely view in the US online or with an antenna. — &lt;em&gt;Cameron Faulkner&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="37uJ6j"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rob Lowe — &lt;/strong&gt;Rob Lowe is one of our generation’s most lovable pop culture icons; and thanks to his ever presence on primetime television, we’ve all had dinner with him at one point or another. He is like a national comfort blanket. Plus, those in their 50s and 60s begin to be at a higher risk of COVID-19 and will need to get vaccinated early on in this process. Although seemingly ageless, Rob Lowe is actually 56 and a perfect example of how right things can go for someone if they take their health seriously. Plus, whose mom doesn’t love Rob Lowe? — &lt;em&gt;Esther Cohen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1h3J33"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7XtWBU"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ajHKgj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22170016/coronavirus-vaccine-celebrity-public-elvis-oprah-dolly-parton"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22170016/coronavirus-vaccine-celebrity-public-elvis-oprah-dolly-parton</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-12T16:54:12-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-12T16:54:12-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google adds more AR animals to mobile Search and most of them are pretty cute</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bFhYKvSkm3UZzH1AxSJTCrsZ5SE=/0x149:1061x856/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68503089/scary_giant_ar_cat.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Giant AR cat is giant&lt;/em&gt; | Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dTGiNQ"&gt;Google has added 50 new augmented reality animals to Search which can be either cute, or in the case of the giant cat in the photo above, a bit disconcerting. Of course it’s possible that I find the giant kitty menacing because I hate fun (or so I have been told), but I do not think I want that creature to greet me, anywhere, ever, in AR or any other reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zIcvMh"&gt;I do, however, want this red panda to play with a pumpkin in my dining room as long as she wants to. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P6cOo3WAytDE6Us4n7Uj92FGhOo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22165276/red_panda.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Kim Lyons/The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Look how cute she is with her little pumpkin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="2avxY8"&gt;In addition to the red panda and cat, there’s a giraffe, cow, zebra, pig, and hippo among the new creatures you can welcome virtually into your home (or other space, but we’re all homebound right now). Just search for an animal on Google’s mobile app and tap “view in 3D” among the results. &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2020/12/11/google-opens-the-door-for-50-new-ar-animals-to-jump-into-your-living-room/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Police &lt;/em&gt;has a pretty good list&lt;/a&gt; of all the AR animals they’ve discovered so far. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9e43Xi"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Hip(po), hip(po), hooray!   There are 50 new AR animals to discover on Search. Search for your favorite animal on your Google mobile app, tap "View in 3D" to see them in your space and don’t forget to share your best creations with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Google3D?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Google3D&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://t.co/u80Mn7wi1z"&gt;pic.twitter.com/u80Mn7wi1z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Google (@Google) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Google/status/1337506620612485120?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 11, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Rtqe0A"&gt;When Google started putting 3D animals in Search last year it only had a few standard animals available like a tiger, a lion, a wolf, and a dog. It &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/2/18649312/google-ar-search-results-animals-3d-model-augmented-reality-lions-tigers-bears-oh-my"&gt;added more creatures in March&lt;/a&gt;, including alligators, ducks, and hedgehogs. In August, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/25/21400577/google-arts-and-culture-augmented-reality-prehistoric-creatures-museum-exhibits"&gt;Google made prehistoric creatures&lt;/a&gt; and historical artifacts available in AR via its Arts and Culture app— and who among us wouldn’t love to check out the ancient crustacean &lt;a href="https://artsandculture.google.com/asset/QwGIdPc45fzOug"&gt;Cambropachycope&lt;/a&gt; up close and personal? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="901gAX"&gt;I have to admit after playing with the AR animals in Search for a bit (in the name of research, obviously), it’s a pretty fun feature, and is likely to be very fun for kids stuck inside during — everything. Now, off to watch my new pet red panda wrestle with her pumpkin. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/12/22171601/google-adds-augmented-reality-ar-animals-search-3d"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/12/22171601/google-adds-augmented-reality-ar-animals-search-3d</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-12T15:31:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-12T15:31:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>The RestoMod is a limited-edition retro-looking PC with a fake floppy drive</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yEc2DXwnadAMNo_Mt0iHi9BeGcY=/0x0:1405x937/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68502825/restomod.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Origin made its RestoMod PC to look like a throwback&lt;/em&gt; | Origin&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FUqw44"&gt;Origin has made a new, limited edition PC that has the guts of a new model but the face of an ancient 1990s machine, complete with a fake floppy drive. In case you want some nostalgia while you wait for &lt;em&gt;Red Dead Redemption&lt;/em&gt; to load, perhaps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KuV4UQ"&gt;The RestoMod has a custom Corsair 4000D case, and the &lt;a href="https://www.originpc.com/configurator/neuron-resto-mod/"&gt;standard build&lt;/a&gt; has 16GB of memory, a 2.9 GHz Core i5 processor, 250GB of storage, and a 6GB NVIDIA GeForce GTX 1660 Ti graphics card, for $2,080. The RetroMod can be customized as desired, Origin says, but they’ve only made 50 of them, so supplies are limited. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QP6-FGhpPm5fZiyIL7nrx5FjU9I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22165119/restomod2.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Origin&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;RestoMod: New but with an old look&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="yg38Ix"&gt;The front face of the machine is where you’ll get the old-school feel, Origin says: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="WR3MWc"&gt;By using a custom HD UV print on the steel front panel, the RestoMod PC features a custom design inspired by PCs from the 1990s. The buttons and drives are just for looks, but you can always pretend that the Turbo button gives you that extra boost in performance. To complete the look, the RestoMod PC chassis has been painted in a matching beige color to accentuate how cases back in the day preferred simplicity over color.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Jrkk1D"&gt;It’s a little disappointing that the Turbo button isn’t functional somehow, but this PC is all about its image: old and sorta dingy. Of course, for a limited run of only 50 machines it seems like Origin could have sourced some actual retro parts, like old disc drives, rather than what’s essentially a fun, but cosmetic paint job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KlPbXL"&gt;If you find the beige faux face of the RetroMod comforting, head over to &lt;a href="https://www.originpc.com/configurator/neuron-resto-mod/"&gt;Origin’s website &lt;/a&gt;to configure your new, but old, PC. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/12/22171472/origin-limited-edition-pc-floppy-drive-restomod"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/12/22171472/origin-limited-edition-pc-floppy-drive-restomod</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-12T12:42:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-12T12:42:01-05:00</updated>
    <title>Verge Weekender: Disney’s big day, Cyberpunk 2077, latest at Google, and our favorite gadgets</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CBaRdCSUO5UiwA8jPrh6u3wm-co=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68502313/acastro_190228_1777_vpn_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="94r8lj"&gt;Happy Saturday and welcome to the inaugural edition of the Verge Weekender, a short recap of some of the stories we covered this week on &lt;em&gt;The Verge. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s6c7QJ"&gt;The big event of the week was Disney’s investor day, where the company announced new Disney Plus series &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22168373/wandavision-trailer-disney-plus-marvel-studios-elizabeth-olsen-paul-bettany"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WandaVision&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, showed trailers for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/21591343/falcon-winter-soldier-premiere-date-disney-plus-sebastian-stan-anthony-mackie-august"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Falcon and the Winter Soldier&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22168459/loki-trailer-marvel-studios-disney-plus-tom-hiddleston-release-date"&gt;much-anticipated series&lt;em&gt; Loki&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; as well as slew of new &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; series on Disney Plus, including &lt;em&gt;Rangers of the New Republic, Ahsoka, Obi-Wan Kenobi, &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Star Wars: Lando. &lt;/em&gt;There’s also a new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22168623/alien-tv-show-noah-hawley-legion-fargo-fx-disney"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alien &lt;/em&gt;TV&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;series&lt;/a&gt; in the works. Check out the full roundup of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167976/disney-investor-day-2020-biggest-announcements-plus-marvel-star-wars-pixar-animation"&gt;everything Disney announced at its 2020 Investor Day&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QUC2bT"&gt;Perhaps the biggest news of the week/year/pandemic hit late Friday, as the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22158608/fda-coronavirus-covid-19-vaccine-authorized-emergency-use"&gt;FDA approved the Pfizer COVID-19 vaccine&lt;/a&gt; for emergency use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="yVpeQ9"&gt;The vaccine is authorized in the US for people over the age of 16. It was found to be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/18/21573072/pfizer-vaccine-effective-authorization-fda-safe"&gt;95 percent effective&lt;/a&gt; at preventing symptomatic COVID-19 in clinical trials. “That is extraordinary,” Anthony Fauci, director of the National Institute for Allergy and Infectious Diseases, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nowthisnews/status/1333146966985908224"&gt;said in a press conference&lt;/a&gt; at the end of November. It’s far better than experts had dared hope for. The FDA was prepared to authorize a vaccine as long as it was at least 50 percent effective. “We were shocked,” Pfizer’s chief executive officer, Albert Bourla, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/21/us/politics/coronavirus-vaccine.html?smid=tw-share"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “We couldn’t believe it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Ekcfgy"&gt;Here’s what else went down over the past week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="9hW6Vv"&gt;Google CEO Sundar Pichai addressed how the company handled the departure of AI ethics researcher Timnit Gebru&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="TScRsd"&gt;“We need to accept responsibility for the fact that a prominent Black, female leader with immense talent left Google unhappily,” Pichai wrote in an email to staff. He added that the company would consider “de-escalation strategies” in the future. In response, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/timnitGebru/status/1336758639785365506"&gt;Gebru tweeted&lt;/a&gt; that Pichai’s email wasn’t an apology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8szGFs"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The backstory:&lt;/strong&gt; Gebru tweeted that Google had abruptly fired her after she voiced her frustration over how the company had handled a &lt;a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2020/12/04/1013294/google-ai-ethics-research-paper-forced-out-timnit-gebru/"&gt;research paper on the risks of large language processing models&lt;/a&gt;, and Google’s head of AI, Jeff Dean, &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1f2kYWDXwhzYnq8ebVtuk9CqQqz7ScqxhSIxeYGrWjK0/edit"&gt;published a note&lt;/a&gt; explaining that Gebru’s paper hadn’t met company standards. Her own team &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/7/22158501/timnit-gebru-team-google-public-statement-fired"&gt;pushed back, writing that Google&lt;/a&gt; had applied its publication review policy “unevenly and discriminatorily.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="AWK4lS"&gt;Cyberpunk 2077 finally debuts after nearly a decade in development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="JPWb0U"&gt;The long-awaited game from CD Projekt Red &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22157995/cyberpunk-2077-cd-projekt-red-review-xbox-ps4-ps5-pc-stadia"&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt; to generally favorable reviews. But reports of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167303/cyberpunk-2077-ps5-console-google-stadia"&gt;bugs from users on older consoles&lt;/a&gt; put into doubt whether developers who helped make the game would earn their performance bonuses. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22157995/cyberpunk-2077-cd-projekt-red-review-xbox-ps4-ps5-pc-stadia"&gt;company announced Friday&lt;/a&gt; it would pay devs full bonuses regardless of the game’s &lt;a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/pc/cyberpunk-2077"&gt;critical reception&lt;/a&gt;. It also said it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22170547/cyberpunk-2077-update-hotfix-cd-projekt-red-epilepsy-risk-braindance"&gt;removing some flashing-light sequences&lt;/a&gt; in the game to reduce the potential for inducing seizures for some users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="kU3wV5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Cyberpunk 2077 is huge, ambitious, and safe","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22157995/cyberpunk-2077-cd-projekt-red-review-xbox-ps4-ps5-pc-stadia"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h3 id="QTkOlt"&gt;Visa and Mastercard crack down on Pornhub after report of unlawful videos&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="LAxd9G"&gt;After &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/04/opinion/sunday/pornhub-rape-trafficking.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times &lt;/em&gt;reported &lt;/a&gt;the porn portal had videos of underage girls and assaults on its site, Pornhub &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22164031/pornhub-upload-limit-blocked-download-nyt-kristof-child-abuse"&gt;banned uploads&lt;/a&gt; by unidentified users and blocked the downloading of videos. It disputed the &lt;em&gt;Times &lt;/em&gt;story, calling the allegations it hosted child sex abuse material “irresponsible and flagrantly untrue.” But on Thursday, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22168240/mastercard-ending-pornhub-payment-processing-unlawful-videos"&gt;Visa and Mastercard both said they would stop processing payments&lt;/a&gt; on the site as they conducted their own separate investigations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PCjTAg"&gt;In other news... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="oGr3QT"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163104/spacex-starship-prototype-test-flight-boca-chica-altitude"&gt;SpaceX aborts test flight of Starship prototype at one second to liftoff&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="faOcMP"&gt;The test of SpaceX’s next-generation Starship rocket had to abort before taking off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="F30Jiq"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22163820/best-gadgets-2020-tech-samsung-apple-ps5-iphone"&gt;The Verge’s Favorite Gadgets of 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="CAf8BL"&gt;The Galaxy Buds Live (aka Galaxy Beans), Oculus Quest 2, and PlayStation 5 all made our list this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="gfWP9i"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22166888/apple-airpods-max-design-comfort-price-features"&gt;Apple Airpods Max First Look&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="6PVjLr"&gt;Nilay Patel got a pair of Apple’s new $549 Airpods Max. First impressions: the case leaves a lot to be desired, but the sound quality matches competing— but less expensive— headphones. “Whether Apple has actually done enough here to justify the staggering premium over the competition is an open question that it’ll take us a little more time reviewing to answer,” he writes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="KAbKzA"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163225/google-fuchsia-os-call-contributors-mailing-list-governance"&gt;Google is still making its mysterious Fuchsia OS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="gdQbtI"&gt;The OS Google announced more than four years ago is still in the works, Dieter Bohn reports, and while the company says it’s not ready for general product development yet, it’s seeking more public contributors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="WFkTH7"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22168243/among-us-innersloth-new-map-airship-early-2021"&gt;Among Us developers reveal an all-new map, The Airship, coming early 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="8eNQr2"&gt;After winning best multiplayer game of the year at the Game Awards, Innersloth announced a new, more elaborate map for Among Us. Not sus at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="TOzGPM"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The 14 biggest trailers and announcements from The Game Awards 2020","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22166109/the-game-awards-2020-announcements-trailers-fortnite-smash-bros-among-us-mass-effect"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="oDCQKc"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/12/22169555/verge-weekender-disney-cyberpunk-2077-google-gadgets-spacex-vaccine-airpods"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/12/22169555/verge-weekender-disney-cyberpunk-2077-google-gadgets-spacex-vaccine-airpods</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
