<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-05-29T10:45:55-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-29T10:45:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-29T10:45:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>Fitbit may soon be adding snoring detection to its devices</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r5U_zkxBZ2q0e6aF7cL2MWmJqi8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69360799/akrales_190903_3635_0025.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4YAWwp"&gt;Fitbit may soon add snoring and noise detection to its devices, a move that will likely please the spouses and partners of the snoring population and be of interest to people for whom snoring is a sign of a &lt;a href="https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/snoring/symptoms-causes/syc-20377694"&gt;possible health condition&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gZuhZE"&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/05/27/fitbit-snore-and-noise-detection-your-sleep-animal/"&gt;a report in &lt;em&gt;9to5 Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which decompiled the latest version of the Fitbit app in Google’s Play Store, the feature allows a Fitbit’s microphone (in devices that have one) to listen to “ambient noise including your potential snoring,” after you’ve fallen asleep. Not only would the feature be a major drain on the device’s battery, the idea of a sleep tracker monitoring noise “throughout the night,” as the release notes state, is a little creepy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sb8LB7"&gt;The&lt;em&gt; 9to5 Google&lt;/em&gt; report says the feature is called Snore &amp;amp; Noise Detect, and it monitors “noise including snores from you or someone next to you.” It analyzes noise level, and tries to find “snore specific” sounds. When the Fitbit detects a noise event louder than the baseline noise level, it tries to determine whether it’s picking up snoring or something else. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rIgxE-E9eHlsWpk8_TcD7PQ0LHw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22547737/snore_detect_screen_shots.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2021/05/27/fitbit-snore-and-noise-detection-your-sleep-animal/" target="_blank"&gt;9to5 Google/Fitbit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A preview of what Fitbit’s snore detection could look like&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="1ElNzn"&gt;The snore tracker can’t distinguish who is snoring, of course; the Fitbit wearer or someone else in the bedroom. The release notes recommend users not play white noise or other ambient sounds in the bedroom which can interfere with the snore detection, and suggests users charge their Fitbit to at least 40 percent before they go to bed because “this feature requires more frequent charging.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vGZPRf"&gt;The notes don’t indicate what users are supposed to do with the information about snoring, but since snoring and the conditions that can lead to it can be seriously disruptive to sleeping, it may be a useful metric to be aware of. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GEN1uO"&gt;Fitbit also will be introducing “sleep animals” as part of a separate upcoming feature, according to &lt;em&gt;9to5 Google&lt;/em&gt;, although it appears to be in much earlier stages of development than the snore detector. It looks like each different style of sleeping will correlate with an animal— and again, it’s not totally clear what users do with the information, or how the animal images would be displayed in the app. But according to the report, a restless sleeper would be a bear, a short sleeper would be a hummingbird, a solid sleeper would be a tortoise, and so on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XcbZYBZ_TxG6o2Nu30LAHgo4L_E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22547731/fitbit_9to5_bear.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://9to5google.com/2021/05/27/fitbit-snore-and-noise-detection-your-sleep-animal/" target="_blank"&gt;9to5 Google&lt;/a&gt;/Fitbit&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m more of a bear when I first wake up tbh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QMQ18t"&gt;Snore &amp;amp; Noise Detect isn’t available to all users yet, and while &lt;em&gt;9to5 Google&lt;/em&gt; enabled the feature long enough to set it up, it wasn’t able to fully test it. Fitbit didn’t immediately reply to a request for comment on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="zhQozX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to pick the right Fitbit for you","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/24/21078627/how-to-pick-fitbit-guide-versa-2-ionic-charge-3-inspire-ace-smartwatch-price"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/29/22459675/fitbit-snoring-detection-fitness-trackers-smartwatch-sleep-animal"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/29/22459675/fitbit-snoring-detection-fitness-trackers-smartwatch-sleep-animal</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-29T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-29T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The future of COVID-19 immunity looks good  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Larry Flynt’s Hustler Club Hosts Pop-Up Vaccination Site In Las Vegas" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k-RY7D_Hkd5C_NVOOC-igm8ZZYk=/67x0:3355x2192/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69360695/1319347246.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Ethan Miller/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="z8lIaF"&gt;Our COVID-19 vaccines have passed their first tests with flying colors. They work unbelievably well, and they’re helping to slow the spread of disease in countries where they’re widely available. Now, scientists are turning to the next key question: how long will they work that well?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aWq4ZW"&gt;In people who were sick with COVID-19 and then got vaccinated, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/26/health/coronavirus-immunity-vaccines.html"&gt;new research&lt;/a&gt; shows that they probably work for years. That group has powerful memory cells in their bone marrow that produce new antibodies when they’re needed. And they work so well that they can even block variants of the virus, studies show. These people may not even need vaccine boosters to stay protected long term. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="Ecr9rP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9360449"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vdpmvE"&gt;Protection may be different for people who got vaccinated but never had COVID-19, Michel Nussenzweig, an immunologist at Rockefeller University in New York, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/26/health/coronavirus-immunity-vaccines.html"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The immune system responds differently to vaccines than it does to natural infection, so they might need boosters against variants — even if they have strong and long-lasting protection against the original coronavirus strain. “That’s the kind of thing that we will know very, very soon,” Nussenzweig said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w84gJz"&gt;Luckily, other research is charging ahead to figure out exactly what those potential boosters might look like. Scientists are &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41591-021-01377-8"&gt;honing in&lt;/a&gt; on the levels of antibodies someone needs to be protected against COVID-19. That benchmark, known as the immune correlate of protection, will give them an idea of the safety threshold — if someone’s antibodies drop below it, they might be more vulnerable to infection again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pfMXFq"&gt;Zeroing in on that threshold does two things. First, it gives scientists a way to monitor protection in people who have already been vaccinated. They can watch to see how long it takes for antibodies to decline below it, and get an idea of when people might need that booster shot. Antibodies naturally decline over time, and they’re not the only measure of protection (those long-lasting memory cells in bone marrow are another, for example). But they’re an early look at how immunity might be changing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="pKSLYs"&gt;&lt;q&gt;having a threshold for protection opens up a shortcut to creating any needed booster shots against COVID-19 variants&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rzO9ix"&gt;Second, having a threshold for protection opens up a shortcut to creating any needed booster shots against COVID-19 variants. COVID-19 vaccine trials included tens of thousands of people. They took months to run, because researchers needed to watch how frequently people with and without the shots got sick. Once we have a good idea of the immune response that stops infections, though, they can test boosters — which are functionally the same vaccine, with small tweaks — in smaller groups of people. We already know the shots are safe, so &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/29/22255198/covid-vaccine-variant-update-mutation-south-africa-moderna"&gt;all they may need to do&lt;/a&gt; is check if the new version also pushes people’s immune system above the cutoff. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wVIvTy"&gt;Together, this research outlines a way to keep people safe from COVID-19 going forward. It starts to ease fears that protection against the coronavirus would start to fade over time, putting communities at risk for outbreaks down the road. The virus is tricky, and variants are a curveball, but — luckily — the human immune system has ammunition as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6G96lf"&gt;Here’s what else happened this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="kjFvjM"&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ksBVPd"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2021/05/tracking-breakthrough-infections/619027/"&gt;What Breakthrough Infections Can Tell Us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CiL3lp"&gt;Finding and analyzing the rare cases of COVID-19 in people who have been vaccinated can give us crucial information about variants. But testing vaccinated people too often can have drawbacks, as well. (Katherine Wu / &lt;em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P0zvcp"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22452761/moderna-covid-vaccine-teens-fda"&gt;Moderna says its COVID-19 vaccine is effective in teens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qg1kyP"&gt;The shot could be the second vaccine available for people under 18 and key toward safely reopening schools in the fall. (Nicole Wetsman / &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="KwSuh3"&gt;Development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="pxmsZO"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/coronavirus-live-updates/2021/05/25/1000171685/half-of-all-u-s-adults-will-be-fully-vaccinated-against-covid-19-as-of-tuesday"&gt;Half of all US adults are now fully vaccinated against COVID-19 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hPSCDe"&gt;The country hit this huge milestone in less than six months. (Bill Chappell / &lt;em&gt;NPR&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ueQpFU"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/28/opinion/herd-immunity-covid-us.html"&gt;The U.S. may never hit the herd immunity threshold. That’s OK.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LyZUj6"&gt;In places like the United States, where half of the population has been vaccinated, the pandemic will slow and stop being a threat even without reaching the level needed for herd immunity. (Erin Mordecai, Mallory Harris and Marc Lipsitch / &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ytPsYh"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22458230/covid-origins-lab-leak-biden-vaccines-pandemic"&gt;We have bigger problems than COVID-19’s origins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Glk1YS"&gt;Spending too much time arguing over the lab leak speculation is a distraction from the important steps governments need to take to end this pandemic and prepare for the next one. (Nicole Wetsman / &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="16POVD"&gt;Perspectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="1uCWOB"&gt;During a brainstorming session at the end of April, we discussed a number of ideas, including gift cards, direct payments and free tickets to sporting events. My chief adviser, Ann O’Donnell, who has been with me since my time in Congress, hesitantly suggested the idea of a lottery. She almost didn’t mention it because of its seeming absurdity. “This is kind of a wacky idea but ….”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="XQwDv0"&gt;—Ohio Governor Mike DeWine wrote &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/26/opinion/ohio-vaccine-lottery-mike-dewine.html"&gt;in &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; about the decision to give $1 million to five vaccinated adults through a lottery. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="TCzxef"&gt;More than numbers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="MilWBe"&gt;To the people who have received the &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/covid-vaccine-tracker-global-distribution/"&gt;1.8 billion vaccine doses&lt;/a&gt; distributed so far: thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1AoQoH"&gt;To the more than 168,927,298 people worldwide who have tested positive, may your road to recovery be smooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5wV5TE"&gt;To the families and friends of the 3,509,402 people who have died worldwide — 592,938 of those in the US — your loved ones are not forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uKgofl"&gt;Stay safe, everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XAYi1O"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/29/22458912/covid-immunity-vaccine-protection-lab-leak-antivirus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/29/22458912/covid-immunity-vaccine-protection-lab-leak-antivirus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-29T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-29T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Memorial Day has brought about some fantastic tech deals</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The iPhone 12 Pro Max is huge, but it has the best camera system on a smartphone" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zRkWPvx-QieAEmasEeRkIRezugI=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69360519/bfarsace_201106_4269_002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you have an iPhone, you owe it to yourself to get accessories that allow for fast charging.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ruUBlP"&gt;Memorial Day is Monday, May 31st, but many of the best deals in commemoration of the holiday are already live ahead of the weekend. We’ll always give you the most essential deals you need to know about in this column. But if you’re hungry for more (like, way more), my colleague Brandon Widder compiled the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/5/28/22453053/best-memorial-day-sales-2021-tech-deals-tvs-headphones"&gt;best Memorial Day deals&lt;/a&gt; on video games, headphones, TVs, and other odds and ends you might find interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x4oHtQ"&gt;Here are a few of the highlights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="oOtu7l"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="w5HO3v"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dailysteals.com%2Fproducts%2Fapple-20w-usb-c-power-adapter-usb-c-to-lightning-cable-bundle%3Fvariant%3D39311427207255&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F5%2F29%2F22458509%2Fmemorial-day-deals-tech-apple-usb-c-charger-beats-headphones-among-us-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Load up on fast charging accessories for your iPhone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="oImSzs"&gt;If you own an iPhone 8 or a more recent iPhone model, it supports fast charging. But to obtain fast charging speeds, you’ll need the right hardware. Conveniently, we’ve worked with Daily Steals to secure a deal on a bundle that includes Apple’s 20W USB-C charger and a Lightning to USB-C cable. Normally $40, it costs a mere $15 when you use the code &lt;strong&gt;VERGEUSBC &lt;/strong&gt;at checkout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="HbMKbP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10523257"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="4DNr3y"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ll8K2T"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/p/among-us"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Among Us&lt;/em&gt; is free for PC until June 3rd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="UnL2n0"&gt;The multiplayer whodunnit game &lt;em&gt;Among Us&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/en-US/p/among-us"&gt;is free to download&lt;/a&gt; for Windows on the Epic Games Store until June 3rd. It normally costs $5, so it isn’t a tremendous savings, but it’s a fantastic game with a healthy player base. To pick it up, however, you’ll need an account for Epic Games Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Uk1zWU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10521776"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="L1W0In"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="A7lPDY"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FBeats-Solo-Pro-Wireless-Noise-Cancelling-On-Ear-Headphones-with-Apple-H1-Headphone-Chip-Black%2F350931600&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Pick up a set of Beats Solo Pro for $150&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="rIWip6"&gt;Amazon has the best price yet on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/25/20931329/beats-solo-pro-review-noise-canceling-on-ear-wireless-headphones-features-price"&gt;Beats Solo Pro&lt;/a&gt; on-ear wireless headphones. Normally $300, they’re down to $150 in the gray colorway. The Solo Pro headphones feature active noise cancellation and Apple’s H1 wireless chip, which allows for hands-free voice commands and a fast, easy connection to an iPhone, Apple Watch, iPad, or Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3dpeN4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10436511"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="H2zAQx"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Marvel’s Spider-Man: Miles Morales Ultimate Edition" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qKOq3Eec2fMutHoT3_acry3TnjE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22174858/MilesMorales_PS5_Combat_Legal_scaled.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Sony / Insomniac Games&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Q4B2AQ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.eneba.com%2Fus%2Fpsn-playstation-network-card-psn-50-usa-psn-key-united-states%2Fjetpak%3Faf_id%3Dawinus%26utm_source%3Dawinus%26utm_medium%3Daw_173843_voxmedia.stories.usechorus.com%26utm_campaign%3Daw_Editorial%2BContent%26currency%3DUSD%26awc%3D20387_1622225328_8eed663ef7492fe34c3e69faa61e4447&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F5%2F29%2F22458509%2Fmemorial-day-deals-tech-apple-usb-c-charger-beats-headphones-among-us-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Get a $50 PlayStation gift card for $43&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="NzqVAl"&gt;Through Monday, May 31st, &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; readers can receive a few dollars off the cost of a $50 PlayStation Store gift card, which can be used on either the PlayStation 4 or PlayStation 5. To claim the deal, &lt;a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=20387&amp;amp;awinaffid=173843&amp;amp;clickref=%5B%5Dvg%5Bp%5D22220764%5Bt%5Dw%5Br%5Dtheverge.com/authors%5Bd%5DD&amp;amp;ued=https://www.eneba.com/us/psn-playstation-network-card-psn-50-usa-psn-key-united-states/jetpak" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;visit Eneba, click “Buy Now,”&lt;/a&gt; and type in the offer code &lt;strong&gt;50USDVERGE&lt;/strong&gt;. As for what you use the gift card on, check out &lt;a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/category/518b9425-a874-447f-b286-002ceca36cbf/"&gt;Sony’s Days of Play sale&lt;/a&gt; that’s bringing down the cost of several PS4 and PS5 games, including &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: Miles Morales&lt;/em&gt;, seen above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="cOKEMy"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/g0G1TdUpUKo8OR-tVu5TLt8My5E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21813011/cgartenberg_200824_4157_0006.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="D3U5uz"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pjtra.com/t/8-10090-88849-119386?sid=VergeDealExclusiveApril2021&amp;amp;website=309942&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fnomadgoods.com%2Fproducts%2Fbase-station-pro" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nomad’s Base Station Pro wireless charging pad is half off&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="PIH2B7"&gt;If you have oodles of Qi-ready devices, like a phone, AirPods, and a smartwatch, you can charge them all at the same time with Nomad’s Base Station Pro. This charging pad usually costs $200, &lt;a href="https://www.pjtra.com/t/8-10090-88849-119386?sid=VergeDealExclusiveApril2021&amp;amp;website=309942&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fnomadgoods.com%2Fproducts%2Fbase-station-pro" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;but you can get it for $100 through Saturday&lt;/a&gt;. Just use the offer code &lt;strong&gt;VERGE &lt;/strong&gt;at checkout. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j0bw81"&gt;Nomad’s high-end model is compatible with several devices from Apple, Samsung, and Google, with a few exceptions, including the Pixel 5 and Pixel Buds. Nomad also recently improved support for iPhone 12 devices that feature the MagSafe charging system. Long story short, the iPhone 12’s built-in magnet made recharging slower with the Base Station Pro, but it has recently been improved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GCy5fx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10425642"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="ieVd00"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/29/22458509/memorial-day-deals-tech-apple-usb-c-charger-beats-headphones-among-us-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/29/22458509/memorial-day-deals-tech-apple-usb-c-charger-beats-headphones-among-us-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-29T08:49:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-29T08:49:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Elon Musk tweets Tesla Model S Plaid delivery to be delayed until June 10th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wCGT1ChmvVZnH8ZZska8Wg107aM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69360493/twarren_08202017_1939_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="X3AgWQ"&gt;Tesla CEO Elon Musk &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1398504702988390400?s=20"&gt;tweeted Saturday&lt;/a&gt; that deliveries of the automaker’s Model S Plaid would be delayed until June 10th because the car needs “one more week of tweak.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o7iV0M"&gt;“This car feels like a spaceship,” tweeted Musk, who is also CEO of SpaceX. “Words cannot describe the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Limbic_resonance"&gt;limbic resonance&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4wj6Kp"&gt;The company has been teasing the Plaid since 2019, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1395286896842985479?"&gt;Musk tweeted on May 20th&lt;/a&gt; that Tesla would hold a delivery event June 3rd at its factory in Fremont, California. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="V32nLq"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Model S Plaid delivery pushed to June 10. Needs one more week of tweak.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This car feels like a spaceship. Words cannot describe the limbic resonance.&lt;/p&gt;— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1398504702988390400?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 29, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5R3jxJ"&gt;Tesla &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/22/21451723/tesla-plaid-model-s-available-2021-specs-price-battery-day"&gt;showed off the Model S Plaid as part of its Battery Day presentation&lt;/a&gt; last September. It’s a step up from Tesla’s Ludicrous trim level, and can reach 0-60 mph in less than two seconds, reaching top speeds up to 200 mph, according to Musk. &lt;a href="https://www.tesla.com/models/design#overview"&gt;The current specs on Tesla’s website&lt;/a&gt; show the Plaid will have range between 390 and 412 miles, with the forthcoming Plaid Plus at a range of more than 520 miles. Prices on Tesla’s website as of Saturday show the Model S Plaid purchase price starting at $119,990, and the Plaid Plus at $149,990. The Plaid Plus is listed as “available in mid-2022.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pVneKY"&gt;The Plaid debuted in September 2019 at the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/12/20862105/tesla-model-s-plaid-laguna-seca-nurburgring-porsche-taycan"&gt;Laguna Seca raceway,&lt;/a&gt; where it ran the course in 1 minute and 36 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/29/22459617/musk-tweets-model-s-tesla-plaid-delivery-delayed-again-june-10th"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/29/22459617/musk-tweets-model-s-tesla-plaid-delivery-delayed-again-june-10th</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-28T18:47:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-28T18:47:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>Venmo leaked Joe Biden’s friends, but you can now keep yours a secret</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Venmo stock" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W46wb25jB5GMIgQLdPkUgUiWs1g=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69359211/venmo1_2040.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Venmo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0ZfrMK"&gt;Venmo has added new privacy controls for friend lists following a jaw-dropping incident where &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/em&gt; was able to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/14/22436847/venmo-contact-friends-list-not-private-president-joe-biden"&gt;track down President Joe Biden’s Venmo account&lt;/a&gt; because of the app’s leaky privacy protocols. App researcher Jane Manchun Wong discovered &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/wongmjane/status/1398383802146168833"&gt;earlier on Friday&lt;/a&gt; that Venmo was working on the new controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NJeRiD"&gt;“We’re consistently evolving and strengthening the Venmo platform for all of our customers. As part of these ongoing efforts, we are enhancing our in-app controls providing customers an option to select a public, friends-only, or private setting for their friends list,” a Venmo spokesperson said in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UlIHno"&gt;To find the new controls, tap the hamburger icon while on the main feed, then tap “Settings,” “Privacy,” and then “Friends List.” The Friends List menu appeared for me and another &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; staffer while I was writing this article, so if it hasn’t rolled out to you just yet, sit tight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QI6yrB"&gt;In the new menu, you can pick if you want your friends list to be public, visible to friends, or private. You can also toggle whether or not you want to appear in others users’ friends list.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/buKJForJKGv1Vlo__xMkhgmM8x8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22547066/IMG_0591.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ZqMdsB"&gt;The new toggles fix a major privacy hole in Venmo that has been known for years: there previously was no way to keep your list of Venmo contacts private, meaning that you could see the contact list of any other user on the platform. The hole was bad enough that following a brief mention of Biden using Venmo in a recent &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/14/us/politics/joe-biden-policy-decisions.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; profile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/we-found-joe-bidens-secret-venmo"&gt;&lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was able to track down the president’s account in less than 10 minutes. The publication also found the accounts for many in his inner circle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7kHpuC"&gt;While you’re in your privacy settings, I’d also recommend &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/4/8/22374698/venmo-feed-matt-gaetz-public"&gt;setting your Venmo feed to private&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="2rB0PM"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"PSA for US Congresspeople: here’s how to set your Venmo feed to private","url":"https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/4/8/22374698/venmo-feed-matt-gaetz-public"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="cgcYj4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction: Clarified that Venmo’s previous friend settings included a privacy flaw, not a security flaw.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22459163/venmo-privacy-controls-friends-list-joe-biden"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22459163/venmo-privacy-controls-friends-list-joe-biden</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-28T18:19:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-28T18:19:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple delays Podcasts subscriptions to June</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4N2LqGV-Go2B5YClyIs2R8yGGgs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69359138/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="n0NyLH"&gt;Apple is delaying the launch of its upcoming Podcasts subscriptions until June, the company announced in an email sent to creators Friday (&lt;a href="https://9to5mac.com/2021/05/28/apple-delaying-podcasts-subscriptions-launch-until-june-promises-improvements-to-podcasts-app/amp/?__twitter_impression=true"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The service was previously set to launch this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mjbNaY"&gt;Apple’s Podcasts subscriptions &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22381980/apple-podcasts-app-subscriptions-new-design"&gt;will allow people&lt;/a&gt; to subscribe to participating podcasts to get extra perks like ad-free listening or early access to episodes. In April, Apple said the subscriptions would launch in 170 countries, and that initial partners include Pushkin Industries and NPR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bq5QCY"&gt;The shifted launch comes as some creators using Apple Podcasts &lt;a href="https://podnews.net/article/apple-podcasts-lemon-bugs?utm_source=podnews.net&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=podnews.net:2021-05-28"&gt;have recently run into some issues&lt;/a&gt;, such as being unable to log in to Apple’s Podcast Connect portal or seeing a delay in the availability of new episodes. In its email sent Friday, Apple said it has fixed the “disruptions” that presented problems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E7UXzb"&gt;You can read Apple’s full email to creators below, which the company shared with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="ka4avf"&gt;We’re writing to provide an update on the availability of Apple Podcasts Subscriptions and channels. We’ve been delighted by the response to last month’s &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fnewsroom%2F2021%2F04%2Fapple-leads-the-next-chapter-of-podcasting-with-apple-podcasts-subscriptions%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F5%2F28%2F22459129%2Fapple-delays-podcasts-subscriptions-june" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;announcement&lt;/a&gt; and it’s exciting to see the hundreds of new subscriptions and channels submitted from creators across the globe every day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hvdhoL"&gt;To ensure we are delivering the best experience for creators and listeners, Apple Podcasts Subscriptions and channels will now launch in June. We will communicate further updates on availability, and best practices to help you prepare your subscriptions and channels, through this newsletter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nna6d5"&gt;Over the last few weeks, some creators have experienced delays in the availability of their content and access to Apple Podcasts Connect. We’ve addressed these disruptions and encourage creators experiencing any issues to &lt;a href="https://podcastsconnect.apple.com/contactus"&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LY27Uc"&gt;We’ve also heard from listeners and made adjustments based on their feedback with iOS 14.6, which was released on Monday. We will introduce additional enhancements to Library in the coming weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NCvcwF"&gt;Thank you for your understanding. We can’t wait to see your new subscriptions and channels and we are looking forward to launching them to listeners around the world soon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22459129/apple-delays-podcasts-subscriptions-june"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22459129/apple-delays-podcasts-subscriptions-june</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-28T17:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-28T17:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Ladies and gentlemen, the weekendgelion</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Saturday Night Live - Season 45" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ETQOELhxD2F1BoNLiu5xDYuy5jE=/1x0:3000x1999/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69358844/1205774770.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by: Will Heath/NBC/NBCU Photo Bank via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hlu54k"&gt;You have reached a significant moment, perhaps not in history, or even in the grand scheme of your life’s long arc toward love and fulfillment, but a significant moment nonetheless. Do I need to spell it out for you? It’s 5PM. On a Friday. Heading into a long weekend. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uTZJpa"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;...Ladies and Gentlemen...&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Neon Genesis Weekendgelion &lt;a href="https://t.co/n5oB1Vneml"&gt;pic.twitter.com/n5oB1Vneml&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— andy (@andymoney69) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/andymoney69/status/1398308089540104197?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 28, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uKSJsV"&gt;What is a “weekendgelion,” you may be asking? Obviously it’s the portmanteau of “weekend” and “Neon Genesis Evangelion.” You could have just Googled that, but I understand — it’s your time off! I respect your commitment to doing the bare minimum for the next three days. What does a beloved ‘90s anime series have to do with, as the above video’s creator puts it, the pursuit of &lt;strong&gt;COLD BEER&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;GOOD FRIENDS&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;FREEDOM&lt;/strong&gt;? On its face, absolutely nothing, other than that its theme song — “A Cruel Angel’s Thesis”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="lYHqmS"&gt;has been memetic fodder since it was technologically feasible for unpaid internet goons to insert it into unrelated situations or media properties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9bGC7I"&gt;was briefly Twitter’s main character this week, after &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/22456627/olympics-documentary-anime-olympics-neon-genesis-evangelion"&gt;a very real, official, Olympic hockey documentary&lt;/a&gt; was rediscovered entirely because of the song’s straight-faced inclusion in its opening montage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WItSJO"&gt;should be the anthem to all summer and pre-summer cookouts going forward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="RnNc9l"&gt;Perhaps you’re not in my timezone (Eastern Standard, the ideal timezone, &lt;em&gt;New York numbah one babyyy&lt;/em&gt;), in which case this post either isn’t for you yet or has hopefully failed to reach your screen because you are already slung across a hammock, covered in snack crumbs and lightly doused in the hedonistically dribbled leavings of your beverage of choice. Good job! Everyone else, please delete Slack from your phone, toss said phone into the nearest ocean or freshwater body, and get on hammock guy’s level. Not that it’s a contest. The last thing anyone should be doing right now is expending effort of any kind. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SNF9KZ"&gt;You made it to the weekendgelion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="94pNhG"&gt;Congratulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K7MBIt"&gt;Congratulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3jDaFM"&gt;Congratulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J5Tfwq"&gt;Congratulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K2WY23"&gt;Congratulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i9t9B0"&gt;Congratulations.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22458706/memorial-day-weekend-evangelion-olympics-log-off-please"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22458706/memorial-day-weekend-evangelion-olympics-log-off-please</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bryan Menegus</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-28T16:59:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-28T16:59:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter could be working on Facebook-style reactions</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cMNP5fXFG_weU-bb7qXXL-sl-lU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69358829/acastro_200715_1777_twitter_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8KgMGk"&gt;Twitter could be adding some new emojis to augment its formerly star-shaped, currently heart-shaped Like button, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/wongmjane/status/1398359547731841024"&gt;according to app researcher&lt;/a&gt; Jane Manchun Wong. The assets Wong found — which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423583/twitter-tip-jar-feature-sending-money-venmo-cashapp"&gt;have been&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/8/21284406/twitter-verified-back-badges-blue-check"&gt;reliable predictions&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/4/21500687/twitter-birdwatch-misinfo-tool-propaganda"&gt;of future features&lt;/a&gt; in the past — show “cheer,” “hmm,” “sad,” and “haha” emoji reactions, though some currently only have a placeholder emoji.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l0FaAq"&gt;Facebook has had a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/2/24/11094374/facebook-reactions-like-button"&gt;similar set of reactions since 2016&lt;/a&gt;. But Wong’s leak shows that Twitter could be taking a slightly different path when it comes to which moods it wants users to express: while it has laughing and sad expressions in common with Facebook, Twitter may also include a makes-you-think and cheer option. Twitter doesn’t seem to have the “angry” expression that Facebook does, but that may be because anger on Twitter is already handled by the reply and quote tweet functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0yhNaE"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Twitter is working on Tweet Reactions view:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“Likes”, “Cheer”, “Hmm”, “Sad”, “Haha”&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The icons for the Cheer and Sad reactions are WIP and shown as the generic heart one at the moment &lt;a href="https://t.co/ZCBhH8z7JR"&gt;https://t.co/ZCBhH8z7JR&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/dGqq1CzIis"&gt;pic.twitter.com/dGqq1CzIis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Jane Manchun Wong (@wongmjane) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/wongmjane/status/1398359547731841024?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 28, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GEJq8Z"&gt;We’ve seen another glance at this feature when Twitter asked users about the addition of emoji reactions &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/24/22348952/twitter-emoji-reactions-downvotes-tweets-testing-features"&gt;in a survey a few months ago&lt;/a&gt;. In response to a request for comment, Twitter told us the same thing it did last time: that it is “always exploring additional ways for people to express themselves in conversations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XOx8Cp"&gt;Twitter seems to be busy with new features recently: we’ve heard rumors of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/15/22437690/twitter-blue-subscription-service-299-undo-tweets"&gt;a premium subscription service&lt;/a&gt;, and we’ve seen the rollout of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22421574/twitter-crop-issue-bigger-images-rollout"&gt;larger pictures&lt;/a&gt;, its audio-based &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455799/twitter-spaces-web-browser-clubhouse-social-audio-room"&gt;Spaces feature&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22423583/twitter-tip-jar-feature-sending-money-venmo-cashapp"&gt;tests of a tip jar feature&lt;/a&gt;. The company even started back up its verification program (before &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22458914/twitter-verification-pause-applications-relaunch"&gt;pausing it again just over a week later&lt;/a&gt;). Perhaps the only thing Twitter isn’t working on is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22458555/florida-deplatforming-law-twitter-facebook-snap-pinterest-tiktok-youtube-google"&gt;a theme park to deal with Florida’s deplatforming law&lt;/a&gt;, but considering the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/11/22169773/twitter-acquires-squad-screen-sharing-video-chat"&gt;disparate&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22417852/twitter-buying-scroll-subscription-service-news-revue-newsletter"&gt;acquisitions&lt;/a&gt; it’s been making of late, it’s too early to ignore the possibility. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22458959/twitter-reactions-feature-facebook-sad-cheer"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22458959/twitter-reactions-feature-facebook-sad-cheer</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-28T16:27:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-28T16:27:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>WhatsApp reverses course, now won’t limit functionality if you don’t accept its new privacy policy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Tk32lbpAQav_fGor-avVbnLoPgw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69358713/acastro_210119_1777_whatsapp_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3at86H"&gt;Earlier this month, Facebook-owned WhatsApp said that users &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/7/22424769/whatsapp-privacy-policy-deadline-controversy-functionality"&gt;would lose functionality over time&lt;/a&gt; if they didn’t accept its new privacy policy by May 15th. In a reversal, Facebook now says that plan has changed, and users who don’t accept the updated policy actually &lt;em&gt;won’t&lt;/em&gt; see limited functionality (&lt;a href="https://thenextweb.com/news/whatsapp-says-it-wont-limit-functionality-if-you-refuse-its-privacy-policy-for-now"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;TNW&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C6Z45W"&gt;“Given recent discussions with various authorities and privacy experts, we want to make clear that we will not limit the functionality of how WhatsApp works for those who have not yet accepted the update,” a WhatsApp spokesperson said in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. WhatsApp tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that this is the plan moving forward indefinitely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="dToMmq"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The new policy has been a source of controversy for months&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XCz95w"&gt;The rollout of the policy &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22233257/whatsapp-privacy-policy-update-delayed-three-months"&gt;has been a confusing mess&lt;/a&gt;, and raised concerns that WhatsApp would begin sharing more of users’ personal data with Facebook. (Some WhatsApp user data, such as users’ phone numbers, is already shared with Facebook, a policy that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/8/25/12638698/whatsapp-to-start-sharing-user-data-with-facebook"&gt;went into place in 2016&lt;/a&gt;.) WhatsApp has stressed this is not the case, though — the policy update is regarding messages sent to businesses via WhatsApp, which may be stored on Facebook’s servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vmw6uy"&gt;The majority of users who have seen the new policy have accepted, &lt;a href="https://faq.whatsapp.com/general/security-and-privacy/what-happens-when-our-terms-and-privacy-policy-updates-take-effect/?lang=en"&gt;the company says in a support article&lt;/a&gt;. This article also notes that you’ll get reminded about the new policy if you haven’t accepted it, and that’s still the case now, WhatsApp said in its statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a8GVly"&gt;“We will continue to remind users from time to time and let them accept the update, including when they choose to use relevant optional features like communicating with a business that is receiving support from Facebook,” WhatsApp said. “We hope this approach reinforces the choice that all users have whether or not they want to interact with a business.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22458805/whatsapp-privacy-policy-no-plans-limit-functionality"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22458805/whatsapp-privacy-policy-no-plans-limit-functionality</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-28T16:17:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-28T16:17:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>UK police surprised to learn energy-intensive weed farm is actually a Bitcoin mine</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Uv9x7DTS_aUmKQVimQOGNCHf9C0=/0x117:1401x1051/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69358663/Crypto_mine_WM.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: West Midlands Police&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hi6PFZ"&gt;Police in the United Kingdom raided an industrial unit outside Birmingham under suspicion it was housing an indoor marijuana growing operation, CNBC &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/05/28/bitcoin-mine-discovered-by-uk-police-on-cannabis-farm-raid-.html"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;. They &lt;a href="https://www.west-midlands.police.uk/news/bitcoin-mine-uncovered-during-industrial-unit-raid"&gt;were surprised to discover&lt;/a&gt; instead an extensive Bitcoin mining setup which was illegally siphoning electricity from a mains supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LKLY7K"&gt;Prior to the raid, police observed multiple people going in and out of the building throughout the day, and spotted extensive ventilation and wiring. They also claim a drone was able to detect high amounts of heat coming off the building. Because indoor cannabis farms use systems of grow lights, heating, and ventilation to cultivate plants where they might not usually flourish, police believed they were looking at “classic signs” of a clandestine weed operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TkDYSk"&gt;What they were actually looking at, as they soon learned, was about approximately a hundred or so &lt;a href="https://99bitcoins.com/antminer-s9-review/"&gt;Antminer S9 machines&lt;/a&gt;, generating enormous amounts of heat while they minted new coins. Easy mistake to make, and incidentally, not illegal in cases where cryptocurrency miners pay their electrical bills. This particular operation, however, was siphoning “thousands of pounds” worth of mains electricity, and as a result was shut down by the same police who thought they were gearing up for a drug raid. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FI0lVO"&gt;The mining equipment, which we can estimate as being worth &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ebay.com%2Fp%2F10023346379&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F5%2F28%2F22458632%2Fbitcoin-mine-mistaken-cannabis-growing-operation-police" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;upward of $5,000&lt;/a&gt;, was seized, though no arrests have been made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IyznXF"&gt;Police may not have caught a drug ring, but they likely did more good by shutting down this illicit mining setup — for the environment anyway. In 2016, weed was found to account for &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2016/feb/27/marijuana-industry-huge-energy-footprint"&gt;1 percent of the electricity consumption&lt;/a&gt; in the US, an equivalent of 15 million tons of greenhouse gas emissions, at the time. For comparison, Bitcoin was estimated to be responsible for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/4/20682109/bitcoin-energy-consumption-annual-calculation-cambridge-index-cbeci-country-comparison"&gt;almost 0.25 percent&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;em&gt;the entire world’s&lt;/em&gt; electricity consumption in 2019. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22458632/bitcoin-mine-mistaken-cannabis-growing-operation-police"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22458632/bitcoin-mine-mistaken-cannabis-growing-operation-police</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
