<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-04-29T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-29T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-29T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Returnal is dark, challenging, and the perfect PS5 showcase</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_QzNXMKVimGJeLegukbrN1aIdnM=/160x0:1888x1152/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69204052/50700424253_e8d902ea3e_k.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PRQG8S"&gt;We’re nearly six months into the life of the current generation of game consoles, but there are still vanishingly few high-profile exclusives that show off what the PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X can do. After getting through the initial wave of launch titles, I’ve spent most of 2021 using my PS5 to play &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;. But this week sees the launch of &lt;em&gt;Returnal&lt;/em&gt;, a PS5 exclusive that comes with some caveats. It’s challenging and complex, making it the kind of game you’ll die in repeatedly. But it also might be the best showcase for Sony’s new console yet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HvRiUG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Returnal&lt;/em&gt; puts you in the spaceboots of an astronaut experiencing the worst case of deja vu imaginable. After crash landing on a mysterious alien planet, she soon realizes she’s stuck in a loop; every time she dies, she heads back to the crash site to start all over again. Each time you explore, you learn just a little bit more about the planet and the astronaut, as well as the rules of the game. With more information and practice, you’ll (hopefully) be able to progress slightly farther each loop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aPQ9M6"&gt;The game plays out as a third person shooter, but it’s also a mish-mash of many different inspirations and genres. Despite the perspective, &lt;em&gt;Returnal&lt;/em&gt; often feels like a bullet hell shooter, with alien creatures spitting countless energy orbs for you to avoid. You even get bonuses for avoiding getting hit. (This aspect of the game shouldn’t be too surprising, as &lt;em&gt;Returnal&lt;/em&gt; was developed by Housemarque, a studio best-known for games like &lt;em&gt;Super Stardust&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Resogun&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="oz9cGY"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lL2Qa0MQyuE?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gmqxuV"&gt;The loop structure also means that the game plays out like a roguelike (think &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/1/21496904/hades-supergiant-games-review-nintendo-switch"&gt;games like &lt;em&gt;Hades&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Each “run” is different; the planet remixes itself each time you play, and you’ll pick up different weapons and fight different enemies along the way. There are also elements of &lt;em&gt;Metroid&lt;/em&gt;, where you’ll come across roadblocks that you can’t get around until you unlock the right item or ability. Early on, for instance, there are electrified webs that block your way, and you can’t cut them down until you get a massive laser sword.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VoE8kY"&gt;It should also be noted that &lt;em&gt;Returnal&lt;/em&gt; is extremely hard, combining two notoriously challenging genres — roguelikes and bullet hell shooters — into a game that does little to make itself accessible. In fact, there aren’t even any difficulty options, aside from the ability to turn up the aim assist. The result is an experience where you’ll have to get used to death and failure, and learn from your mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="JFS8I6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;What stands out is its use of sound and the DualSense controller&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JvvdGG"&gt;It can be frustrating, but it’s worth pushing through for a few reasons. For one, the action feels incredible; zipping around while shooting octopus birds and slicing at evil tree-creatures with a huge sword is a blast. But &lt;em&gt;Returnal&lt;/em&gt; is also a game that’s just dripping with atmosphere — and it’s only enhanced by some of the PS5’s unique features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1z1JVm"&gt;The dark world you’ll explore feels ripped out of an &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; movie, complete with towering, crumbling ancient ruins, and lots of disturbing bio-engineered technology. This is all rendered in incredible detail, and &lt;em&gt;Returnal&lt;/em&gt; particularly shines when it comes to special effects; there are all kinds of hypnotically beautiful explosions of light and color, and I especially love the fast travel effect, which sees your character melt away into nothingness.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/N0ANd9yFrnUghuOUiVjpzZK2Inw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22476658/50826660412_71c9837773_k.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="USTWoR"&gt;But there are lots of great-looking PS5 games already. Even last-gen titles look good on the new hardware. What makes &lt;em&gt;Returnal&lt;/em&gt; stand out in particular is its use of sound and the DualSense controller. I’ve spent most of my time with the game so far wearing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549510/best-gaming-headset-wired-wireless-features-specs-price-sound-microphone-test-buy"&gt;Sony’s Pulse 3D headphones&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s the first game where I’ve really noticed the 3D audio that the company has touted so much. I could pinpoint monsters by the sounds of their screams and growls, which was extremely helpful, as there’s often so much happening on screen that it can be hard to follow. The sound design also makes the game that much creepier; the alien monsters make unsettling noises as they approach, and it always made me wary when stepping into a new, unknown space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KNBuNd"&gt;Meanwhile, I’d go so far as to say it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549072/astros-playroom-ps5-review-dualsense-controller"&gt;the best DualSense game since &lt;em&gt;Astro’s Playroom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which comes bundled with the console in order to show off the gamepad’s unique capabilities. The subtle vibrations mean you can feel the patter of raindrops in your palms, and the burst of each weapon has its own distinct sensation. There are also some really creepy noises that come out of the speaker (though you may miss them with headphones on). My favorite feature, though, is the way &lt;em&gt;Returnal&lt;/em&gt; utilizes the controller’s adaptive triggers. The left trigger has two phases: push halfway and you can zoom in to aim your main weapon, but click it all the way down and you’ll unleash a special attack. It basically gives the controller an extra button in a way that feels very natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yf86u7"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Returnal&lt;/em&gt; is definitely an acquired taste. Its looping structure and unforgiving nature means many players will end up frustrated as they struggle through nearly identical scenarios repeatedly. Death isn’t always fun. But it also blends together so many cool things, from the vibe of &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; to the thrill of a great arcade shooter, in a way that’s seamless and deliberate. And if you’re someone who actually managed to pick up a PS5, it’s the kind of game you’ll want to take out to show off what the console can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9L7Wg4"&gt;&lt;small&gt;Returnal &lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;launches on April 30th on the PS5.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22408468/returnal-ps5-dualsense-3d-audio"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22408468/returnal-ps5-dualsense-3d-audio</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-29T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-29T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Motorola Moto G Play (2021) review: a fairly good phone for a very good price</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;A good phone for the price, but if you can spend a bit more you’ll get some worthwhile upgrades&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="jijWOE"&gt;The Moto G Play is the least expensive of four phones that Motorola introduced for the US market earlier this year. Introduced at $169, it’s already enjoying an apparently permanent $10 mark down, placing it firmly in budget territory. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BLqMWm"&gt;Most of what you’ll find on the G Play’s spec list makes a lot of sense given that price point: a 6.5-inch 720p LCD with standard refresh rate, Snapdragon 460 processor with 3GB of RAM, and a generous 5,000mAh battery. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QQGEiE"&gt;There’s another factor that might sway some shoppers toward the G Play, too: as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/4/22346084/lg-exits-smartphone-business"&gt;LG leaves the budget phone space&lt;/a&gt; and its remaining stock disappears from retailers’ shelves, Motorola’s budget-friendly phone will be one of a smaller number of options. In the US. we haven’t seen the kind of sub-$150 devices from Motorola that the company has introduced in other markets this year, so for now, the G Play is a likely candidate for the budget-oriented phone shopper’s consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="yq02wW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10470952"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="abrA10"&gt;There are a couple of aspects of the phone’s feature set that feel underwhelming even considering the price: namely, a paltry 32GB of storage (though it can be expanded after the fact) and a 13-megapixel main camera when more advanced, high-resolution pixel-binning sensors are becoming the norm at every price point, for example. But in short, the G Play performs just fine for its price. Just know that you’ll need to bring patience and acceptance of a few shortcomings, and that spending an extra $50 to $100 if your budget allows would get you some meaningful upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6Fj8ocXqWgKds7jM22tLsrhGO1c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22446427/ajohnson_20210412_4525_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The G Play’s 6.5-inch display is a bit low-res for its size and hard to see in bright outdoor light.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="4NdOM4"&gt;Moto G Play performance and screen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="TsNIGy"&gt;The G Play uses a Snapdragon 460 chipset which was introduced over a year ago and is an entry-level Qualcomm processor. Coupled with 3GB of RAM, it manages to keep up with routine tasks like jumping between apps and scrolling social media, albeit with subtle-but-noticeable stuttering along the way. Heavier tasks like starting and stopping Google Maps navigation take an extra couple of beats. It’s not as frustrating as my experience with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22301223/lg-stylo-6-review"&gt;LG Stylo 6&lt;/a&gt; was, but it’s a step down from the kind of performance you can expect from a phone that’s $50-100 more expensive, including those in Motorola’s own G-series lineup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="STHUPi"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The G Play includes a 5,000mAh battery, which is significantly bigger than the typical 4,000 or 4,500mAh&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AVK5Qk"&gt;The screen, likewise, gets the job done but doesn’t particularly shine. Its 720p resolution is stretched thin across the 6.5-inch display and images are noticeably pixelated. Colors are on the cooler side and the screen is a bit dim unless you max out the brightness. Even with the brightness cranked all the way up I had a hard time seeing it outdoors. We spend so many hours looking at our devices that this is one area where it might be worth upgrading. That said, there isn’t exactly anything wrong with the display — it’s just not very nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jJxSkW"&gt;There’s better news on the battery front. The G Play includes a 5,000mAh battery, which is significantly bigger than the typical 4,000 or 4,500mAh found in other comparably sized Android phones. Motorola claims it will get three days of battery life, which is probably true if you’re a light user and conservative with your screen brightness. I had no problem getting two days on a charge with a couple of hours each day of screen-on time. A full day and then some of heavy use is definitely reasonable to expect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="eUodGD"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Storage is expandable via microSD card, so plan on that extra $10-15 as a necessary part of the purchase&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dXVVyI"&gt;The Moto G Play includes just 32GB of storage — about as low as it gets in 2021. Considering roughly half of that will be taken up with operating system files, it’s just not enough. Storage is expandable via microSD card, so plan on that extra $10-15 as a necessary part of the purchase if you don’t already have one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NBBRcS"&gt;The G Play ships with Android 10 installed. While it’s on Motorola’s list to receive an Android 11 update, the timing is unclear and, given the company’s track record, could be many months away. The phone will receive security updates until January 2023. That’s an unfortunately short life span, so you might want to count on trading it in or cashing in your upgrade with your carrier after a couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-0xKl-_nv-5ScC8ZHGcoPWpzV6o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22446426/ajohnson_20210412_4525_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s just one camera on the Moto G Play’s rear panel — plus a depth sensor and a flash.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="9xrLwx"&gt;Moto G Play camera&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="la0jKI"&gt;The G Play has just one 13-megapixel rear-facing camera (accompanied by a 2-megapixel depth sensor) and a 5-megapixel selfie camera. That’s it. Even in the budget class, that’s not many cameras in 2021. I don’t think anyone (myself included) will miss having the low-quality macro camera that manufacturers keep putting on their devices these days, but not having an ultrawide is a bummer considering it’s not hard to find a phone that offers one at this price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZrSppU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10470933"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lWH6dz"&gt;If nothing else, the G Play’s camera offerings are very straightforward. There are just two main shooting modes in the native camera app: photo and video. Portrait mode and a few other extras are available in the shooting menu, but there’s no night mode here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vICTq7"&gt;Outside in good lighting, this 13-megapixel camera does okay. Overall exposures are balanced and the camera doesn’t try to do too much HDR-ing, which I appreciate, but you don’t have to look too close to notice that details in grass and leaves are smoothed over. Things go downhill quickly in less good light — the G Play just isn’t up to low-light photography. The selfie camera is also guilty of aggressive over-smoothing at its default “Face Beauty Auto” setting that made my face look like a glazed donut. Thankfully, you can turn this off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zPOT-4NqzEVGAxuJIn-F4NNXgcc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22446423/ajohnson_20210412_4525_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The G Play is well-priced for what it offers, but spending a bit more would mean some valuable upgrades.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZzJkNf"&gt;Clearly the G Play has its share of shortcomings — at $160, it has to. The question is whether these are trade-offs you can live with for a couple of years. If you enjoy a very casual relationship with your phone, the G Play will do all of the things you need it to do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="APEtVk"&gt;&lt;q&gt;If you enjoy a very casual relationship with your phone, the G Play will do all of the things you need it to do&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="C9Vhl0"&gt;Everyday performance for the basics — light web browsing, social media, email, music — is sufficient. If you just use your phone camera for quick snapshots out and about and don’t expect too much from it, the G Play will do fine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E238ck"&gt;If you suspect that you need a little more from your phone, or that you want the experience of using your phone to be a little more enjoyable, then I’d strongly encourage spending a bit more on something like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22268805/motorola-moto-g-power-2021-review"&gt;Motorola’s own Moto G Power&lt;/a&gt; for a better camera. Samsung and OnePlus have recent entries in the sub-$200 class that are worth looking at, too; I haven’t tested them, but they’re specced competitively. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="GJynXC"&gt;If your relationship with technology is less complicated than those of us who spend hours each day of our precious time on this Earth staring at the little glowing screen in our hands, jumping between social media apps, and pushing our phone cameras to their limits, then you’ll get along fine with the Moto G Play. Just spare a thought for the rest of us, please?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rzGcFy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="h3LWLv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10470831"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22408041/motorola-moto-g-play-2021-review-price-screen-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22408041/motorola-moto-g-play-2021-review-price-screen-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-29T07:19:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-29T07:19:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>EU adopts controversial law forcing one-hour takedowns of terrorist content</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/biyYtaBIG5tM4lVFY3c2uAg2-kc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69203961/acastro_1800724_1777_EU_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vfxNvE"&gt;The European Parliament has &lt;a href="https://www.europarl.europa.eu/news/en/press-room/20210422IPR02621/new-rules-adopted-for-quick-and-smooth-removal-of-terrorist-content-online"&gt;formally adopted&lt;/a&gt; a law requiring internet companies to “remove or disable access to flagged terrorist content” within one hour after being notified by national authorities. Once issued, such takedown notices will apply across the EU, with countries able to levy financial penalties against firms that refuse to comply. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9sKwlT"&gt;The legislation will come into force 12 months after it is published in the EU’s &lt;a href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/oj/direct-access.html"&gt;official journal&lt;/a&gt;, a standard step for all EU law. It will then have to be adopted by each member state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k4RpZo"&gt;The legislation has been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/21/18274201/european-terrorist-content-regulation-extremist-terreg-upload-filter-one-hour-takedown-eu"&gt;under discussion&lt;/a&gt; in the EU for years. It was first proposed in &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2018/sep/13/social-media-firms-could-face-huge-fines-over-terrorist-content"&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt; at a time when terrorist attacks by groups like ISIS were peaking across the &lt;a href="https://www.europarl.europa.eu/news/en/headlines/security/20180703STO07125/terrorism-in-the-eu-terror-attacks-deaths-and-arrests-in-2019"&gt;continent&lt;/a&gt; and lawmakers were worried about online radicalization. Since then the proposals have been making their way through the EU’s legislative bodies, with several major amendments.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SwKHtJ"&gt;Notably, the legislation now explicitly excludes takedowns targeting terrorist content that’s part of any educational, artistic, journalistic, or academic material. It also includes no obligation for internet companies to preemptively monitor or filter their content. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="oxB7Dq"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The law could encourage the use of faulty algorithmic content filters&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OGWlfv"&gt;However, many MEPs and rights groups are still worried the legislation will have unintended effects. Although companies are under no obligation to filter content, say critics, they might choose to do so in order to avoid having to respond quickly to takedown notices. Such algorithmic filters could be over-zealous, worry experts, blocking legitimate content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="imMde8"&gt;“To say that [using automated filters] is not an obligation is to allow it,” Gwendoline Delbos-Corfield, a Green MEP from France, told &lt;a href="https://www.euractiv.com/section/cybersecurity/news/eu-adopts-law-giving-tech-giants-one-hour-to-remove-terrorist-content/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;EURACTIV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Such technology might look particularly attractive in a “context where the algorithm is going to be cheaper than human means.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WCQhXy"&gt;Another concern is that the one-hour takedown limit is too short a time frame for smaller platforms with fewer resources. Such platforms are often used by terrorist groups to host content precisely because they can’t moderate content. This would make business harder for these companies, stifling competition in a market already dominated by US tech giants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="roiPii"&gt;It’s also possible that EU member states could interpret what constitutes “terrorist” content in harmful ways. “This could open the way for authoritarian regimes, like those in Poland and Hungary, to silence their critics abroad by issuing removal orders beyond their borders,” writes &lt;a href="https://www.liberties.eu/en/stories/terrorist-content-regulation-open-letter-to-meps/43410"&gt;one civil rights group&lt;/a&gt;. “Because this must happen within the hour, online platforms will have no option but to comply with these orders to avoid fines or legal problems.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22409306/eu-law-one-hour-terrorist-content-takedowns-passes-parliament"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22409306/eu-law-one-hour-terrorist-content-takedowns-passes-parliament</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-29T07:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-29T07:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>EV charging network ChargePoint now supports Android Auto  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-Q4crVHGD5kpCNXPN0D7ZvbmWmU=/162x0:1356x796/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69203865/Android_Auto_Screens_Nearby_Stations.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The integration lets you view charging stations directly from your car’s infotainment screen.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: ChargePoint&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qdPP52"&gt;ChargePoint, operator of one of the largest EV charging networks across Europe and North America, is adding support for Android Auto to its app. The functionality means Android phone users will be able to find, navigate to, and start charging from a ChargePoint charging station from their car’s infotainment screen, without having to pick up their phone. Support for Android Auto follows the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21571093/chargepoint-carplay-app-find-stations-start-charging-electric-cars-ev"&gt;addition of CarPlay support&lt;/a&gt; in November last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gmRTb5"&gt;According to ChargePoint, the Android Auto experience lets you view a map with nearby charging stations, check status, filter by metrics like availability and cost, and then start a charging session once you arrive. The in-vehicle app can also be set to notify the driver once a busy charging station becomes available. ChargePoint says its network includes over one hundred thousand charging locations.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6xLSMCUX-Nq3_bP97XfP6xsMJ9Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22477688/Android_Auto_Screens_Station_Details.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: ChargePoint&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Details about available charging spots can be viewed from the screen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="zadkv0"&gt;The app’s Android Auto support will be available from today in the USA, Canada, Austria, Belgium, Denmark, France, Germany, Ireland, Italy, Netherlands, Norway, Spain, Sweden, Switzerland, and the UK. To use it, you’ll need ChargePoint’s app running on a device with Android 6.0 or above, and a car that supports Android Auto. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22409310/chargepoint-android-auto-electric-vehicle-charging-network"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22409310/chargepoint-android-auto-electric-vehicle-charging-network</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-29T05:52:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-29T05:52:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung loses over $270M from Texas plant shutdown as quarterly profits boom</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AHjlqNP9zskqnOU3qbEefZHi4io=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69203726/acastro_190503_1777_samsung_0004.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rjroCK"&gt;Shutting down its semiconductor plant in Austin, Texas lost Samsung over 300 billion won (around $270 million), &lt;a href="https://en.yna.co.kr/view/AEN20210429007100320"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yonhap News &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;. Speaking during a conference call, a senior vice president at Samsung’s foundry business Han Seung-hoon said that the shutdown affected around 71,000 wafers, corresponding to “around 300 to 400 billion won in damage.” The statement coincided with Samsung’s &lt;a href="https://news.samsung.com/global/samsung-electronics-announces-first-quarter-2021-results?utm_source=feedly&amp;amp;utm_medium=direct"&gt;latest earnings release&lt;/a&gt;, in which it reported strong sales of its smartphones and other consumer electronics. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hUpzfR"&gt;The South Korean electronics giant was forced to shut down its Austin plant — which produces microprocessors like radio frequency integrated circuits and solid state drive controllers — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22287054/samsung-chip-production-halted-austin-winter-storm-uri-power-blackouts"&gt;back in February&lt;/a&gt; after a storm left some 200,000 Austin homes without power. The shutdown lasted a month in total, the longest Samsung has ever had to halt production at a factory. However, the company says that the plant was back up to 90 percent production at the end of March, and is now back up to normal levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="GHRsrA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Around 71,000 wafers were affected by the Austin plant shutdown&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="E1SnbY"&gt;Overall, however, &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/4b7b284a-a280-4252-bcc7-0fb6a4ef5d92"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Financial Times&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that Samsung profits exceeded expectations. Net profit for the quarter was up 46 percent to 7.1 trillion won (around $6.4 billion) compared to the same quarter the previous year, resulting in its highest first quarter profit since 2018.  The increase was driven by a 66 percent surge in profits at its mobile division, according to &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/04/29/samsung-earnings-q1-2021.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Samsung says that sales of its “well received” flagship Galaxy S21 series have increased alongside its more price competitive midrange models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="thBH4R"&gt;Samsung’s own manufacturing issues have coincided with a global chip shortage that’s affected everything from graphics cards to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266483/ford-f150-production-slowdown-semiconductor-chip-shortage"&gt;cars&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/9a497f21-e3e4-4c74-8737-07cd13209475"&gt;even toasters&lt;/a&gt;. Samsung says the supply issues have had knock-on effects on its business, contributing to a drop in sales for mobile displays in the first quarter. The company says it’s possible that supply issues will continue into the second half of the year (echoing similar predictions from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/15/22385240/tsmc-chip-shortage-2022-intel-ceo-earnings-graphics-cards-cpus-gpus"&gt;TSMC and Intel&lt;/a&gt;), but that it’s “strengthening cooperation with the in-house foundry and expanding the use of outsourced foundries” to compensate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z9Acn7"&gt;Otherwise, Samsung thinks its business will benefit from economic recoveries and stimulus programs around the world. It expects strong demand for everything from servers, to storage, smartphones, and PCs in the second half of the year. However, it specifically says that demand for TVs could drop in the same period, as people start venturing outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0kd9se"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iSheaR"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22409273/samsung-austin-texas-plant-month-shut-down-losses-smartphone-sales-chip-shortage"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22409273/samsung-austin-texas-plant-month-shut-down-losses-smartphone-sales-chip-shortage</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-29T05:05:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-29T05:05:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon lawsuit alleging Trump bias in $10 billion military contract clears another hurdle</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aqnP71Iezoxz1ysOg1aOo6r6_8Q=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69203696/acastro_180329_1777_amazon_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0LeMrI"&gt;An ongoing lawsuit pursued by Amazon against the US government and Microsoft will continue after a federal judge rejected a motion to dismiss the case. The suit concerns Microsoft’s success in securing the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/25/20700698/microsoft-pentagon-contract-jedi-cloud-amazon-details"&gt;$10 billion JEDI cloud computing contract&lt;/a&gt; with the Defense Department — a decision that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/9/21002725/amazon-trump-jedi-contract-rules-court-documents-microsoft-pentagon"&gt;Amazon says&lt;/a&gt; was influenced by President Donald Trump’s dislike of the company and its CEO Jeff Bezos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5gtKOz"&gt;The decision, as reported by &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2021/04/28/pentagon-cloud-contract-depositions/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-04-28/judge-declines-to-toss-amazon-suit-claiming-trump-cost-jedi-bid"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;means Amazon can now argue in front of a court that Trump himself and former defense secretary Jim Mattis should testify. A motion to dismiss the case was rejected by Judge Patricia Campbell-Smith on Wednesday April 28, though her full opinion was filed under seal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JiZYRN"&gt;Amazon and Microsoft are both industry leaders in the cloud computing market, but Amazon was seen as having the edge over its rival in securing the JEDI contract. When Microsoft was announced as the winner in October 2019, Amazon quickly objected, accusing President Trump of putting pressure on the government to pick Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WDjvacxzRnNcogXH8k6irT4XK-E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22477655/Screen_Shot_2021_04_29_at_9.58.17_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;President Trump shakes hands with Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella in 2017 as Amazon CEO Jeff Bezos looks on. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ibV0v7"&gt;There’s ample evidence of Trump’s dislike of both Amazon and Bezos, especially after Bezos’ purchase of &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;, which Trump claimed pursued a political agenda against him in its reporting. Evidence of Trump’s influence includes &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/10/26/trump-mattis-screw-amazon-10-billion-pentagon-cloud-contract-jedi.html"&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; that he directly told Mattis to “screw Amazon” out of the $10 billion contract. (Mattis reportedly responded: “We’re not going to do that. This will be done by the book, both legally and ethically.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="3VR0LT"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“This procedural ruling changes little.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PZm4uj"&gt;Responding to the news, Microsoft said it would make no difference. “This procedural ruling changes little. Not once, but twice, professional procurement staff at the DoD chose Microsoft after a thorough review,” said Microsoft’s communications head Frank Shaw in a statement. “Many other large and sophisticated customers make the same choice every week.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KGwx3Z"&gt;Amazon applauded the decision, with Drew Herdener, vice president of communications, noting that there was a “disturbing” record of Trump improperly wielding his influence. “We continue to look forward to the Court’s review of the many material flaws in the DoD’s evaluation, and we remain absolutely committed to ensuring that the Department has access to the best technology at the best price,” wrote Herdener.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DrQ33S"&gt;Although the case is a long way from being settled, it’s possible that the mere threat of a drawn-out court battle will change the outcome. In a &lt;a href="https://www.nextgov.com/it-modernization/2021/01/pentagon-hints-it-could-abandon-jedi-cloud-effort/171753/"&gt;memo from January&lt;/a&gt;, the Defense Department hinted as much. “The prospect of such a lengthy litigation process might bring the future of the JEDI Cloud procurement into question,” said the department. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I46LvD"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22409245/amazon-microsoft-jedi-contract-reject-motion-dismiss-trump-influence"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22409245/amazon-microsoft-jedi-contract-reject-motion-dismiss-trump-influence</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-29T03:59:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-29T03:59:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>PS5 preorders begin in China, almost six months after US launch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KnhaWK6qxoYpECskCxyWXOgVl_I=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69203624/vpavic_4278_20201030_0247.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KNi2lA"&gt;The PS5 will be available to buy in China on May 15th, a little over six months after its original release in the US last year, &lt;a href="https://weibo.com/2833736934/Kd7K32XBZ?from=page_1006062833736934_profile&amp;amp;wvr=6&amp;amp;mod=weibotime&amp;amp;type=comment#_rnd1619682582948"&gt;Sony announced today&lt;/a&gt;. The disc version of the console will retail for 3,899 yuan (around $600), while the cheaper disc-free model will cost 3,099 yuan (around $479). Preorders open today. The launch means Sony’s next-gen console will beat Microsoft’s to release in the country, although &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/04/29/sony-playstation-5-launch-china-ahead-of-microsofts-xbox.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CBNC&lt;/em&gt; notes&lt;/a&gt; that Microsoft received safety approvals to release the Xbox Series X and Series S there at the end of last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Kjo3zc"&gt;Relative to its size and population, China isn’t considered a huge market for console gaming. Game consoles were technically illegal in the country &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/jan/07/china-lifts-13-year-ban-video-games-consoles"&gt;until 2014&lt;/a&gt;, which meant PC and mobile gaming has become dominant. Even now, strict laws make it hard to release consoles in China simultaneously with other countries. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/12/11/7376315/Sony-ps4-joins-microsoft-xbox-one-in-china"&gt;PS4, Xbox One&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/3/20994756/nintendo-switch-china-launch-release-date-price-tencent"&gt;Switch&lt;/a&gt; have all released in China, with Nintendo’s console reportedly being the most successful. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nNe3IX"&gt;The PS5’s Chinese launch comes as the console faces stock issues around the world. A combination of unexpectedly high demand as well as supply chain issues including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22368552/global-chip-shortage-end-tsmc-samsung-ps5-supply-demand-intel"&gt;a global chip shortage&lt;/a&gt;, have been blamed for the problems. However, Sony Interactive Entertainment president and CEO Jim Ryan recently said he &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297039/playstation-ceo-ps5-supply-2021-stock-consoles-jim-ryan"&gt;expects the stock situation to improve&lt;/a&gt; in the second half of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22409232/ps5-sony-china-launch-may-15th-release-date-price"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22409232/ps5-sony-china-launch-may-15th-release-date-price</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-29T03:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-29T03:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Vivaldi is updating its browsers to block annoying cookie pop-ups</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i60nfBJtsFfk2phO_qZj3fvHdpc=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69203592/vivaldi_browser_cookie_blocker_setting.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Vivaldi&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5WTD3D"&gt;Vivaldi announced today that it’s updating the &lt;a href="https://vivaldi.com/press/embargoed/vivaldi-browser-blocks-cookie-dialogs-improves-privacy-design/"&gt;desktop&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://vivaldi.com/press/embargoed/new-vivaldi-on-android-language-switcher-cookie-crumbler/"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; versions of its Vivaldi browser with the ability to block annoying cookie preference pop-ups. Thanks to the passage of the European Union’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/28/17172548/gdpr-compliance-requirements-privacy-notice"&gt;General Data Protection Regulation&lt;/a&gt; (GDPR), you’ve probably had to click through at least one dialog box asking if you’d like to manage how a site tracks you. Vivaldi’s new update lets you avoid those notifications — with some major caveats — while theoretically still keeping you safe from tracking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6EJa8q"&gt;Vivaldi’s logic for the new feature, affectionately called “Cookie Crumbler,” is that while giving users control over how they’re tracked is good, doing so through a pop-up “leads to clicking ‘allow’ or ‘accept’ without realizing that unwittingly users just gave permission for trackers to create behavioral profiles about them,” Vivaldi writes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-v1z0djtC6kORkl4FMj0ezKL-UY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22476438/Screen_Shot_2021_04_28_at_1.05.47_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A cookie dialog box from &lt;/em&gt;The Guardian.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MYhPRA"&gt;Vivaldi’s &lt;a href="https://vivaldi.com/features/ad-blocker/"&gt;built-in Ad Blocker&lt;/a&gt; can theoretically already handle hiding users from the various tracking methods deployed by sites, so Cookie Crumbler is about removing the annoying hangers-on — the pop-up notifications that direct users to customize how they’re tracked, if at all. Users with an updated version of Vivaldi (version 3.8 as of today) can enable Cookie Crumbler by going to Settings &amp;gt; Privacy &amp;gt; Tracker and ad blocking &amp;gt; Manage sources &amp;gt; Remove cookie warnings lists. The same feature can be enabled on the Android version of Vivaldi under the same menus.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4CzAkfZA18MElQRuM7398cB-mTI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22476434/vivaldi_browser_cookie_blocker_setting_1.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Vivaldi&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Cookie Crumbler” can be enabled on Android in the same menu you manage Vivaldi’s ad and tracker blocker.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LoBREU"&gt;Cookie Crumbler pulls from two separate third-party block lists to work, but “this is not a perfect solution, as there will be a few websites that use other tactics to obtain cookie consent,” Vivaldi says. Enabling Cookie Crumbler may also make some sites completely inaccessible on desktop and mobile, depending on if the site locks some functionality behind interacting with the cookie dialog. Losing access to some websites is a major inconvenience for a web browser that’s designed to visit websites, and that may be why Cookie Crumbler isn’t enabled by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kzHsYa"&gt;Vivaldi is also taking an even stronger stance on Google’s cookie alternative, FLoC, or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22358287/privacy-ads-google-chrome-floc-cookies-cookiepocalypse-finger-printing"&gt;Federated Learning of Cohorts&lt;/a&gt;. FLoC builds cohorts from users’ browsing history to sort them semi-anonymously by interests or qualities for websites looking to sell ads. It seems less directly invasive than a traditional cookie, but also hugely dependent on browser makers implementing it correctly for it to be safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yyVYpP"&gt;Vivaldi is &lt;a href="https://vivaldi.com/blog/no-google-vivaldi-users-will-not-get-floced/"&gt;decidedly not okay&lt;/a&gt; with Google’s implementation of FLoC and is not enabling it in its browser, despite relying on Google’s Chromium codebase. With today’s updated version of Vivaldi, it’s also blacklisting the FLoC component required for Google’s current test of the ad technology, removing it from browsers that might already have it downloaded and preventing it from being downloaded going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EXff93"&gt;Vivaldi 3.8 also adds new customization options for the browser’s Panels feature (think SlideOver in iPadOS but for websites) and a new keyboard command for adding bookmarks. The Android version of the app can also now switch between the 41 languages Vivaldi supports rather than relying on Android’s built-in language settings.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22408098/vivaldi-cookie-crumbler-blocks-pop-ups-floc-gdpr"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22408098/vivaldi-cookie-crumbler-blocks-pop-ups-floc-gdpr</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-29T00:55:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-29T00:55:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>Would you pay $30 a month for a faster web browser that eats less battery?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LENmsQirMZcz7iocpzQn4960BIg=/0x0:1376x917/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69203413/mighty_browser.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ao3iRA"&gt;No matter how much web browsers improve, it feels like they can’t keep pace with everything we want to do. Open one too many tabs on a few-year-old laptop, and your fan starts spinning, your battery life dips, your system starts to slow. A faster or cleaner PC might fix it, but &lt;a href="https://www.mightyapp.com/"&gt;a startup called Mighty has a different idea&lt;/a&gt;: a $30-a-month web browser that lives in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ievKTm"&gt;Instead of your own physical computer interacting with each website, you stream a&lt;em&gt; remote &lt;/em&gt;web browser instead, one that lives on a powerful computer many miles away with its own 1,000Mbps connection to the internet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pAtGyB"&gt;Suddenly, your decent internet connection would feel like one of the fastest internet connections in the world, with websites loading nigh-instantly and intensive web apps running smoothly without monopolizing your RAM, CPU, GPU and battery, no matter how many tabs you’ve got open — because the only thing &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; computer is doing is effectively streaming a video of that remote computer (much like Netflix, YouTube, Google Stadia, etc.)  while sending your keyboard and mouse commands to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Z2VD1m"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dWPdDgSZ5yU?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gMeA3R"&gt;Skeptical? I definitely am, but perhaps not for the reason you’d think — because I tried this exact idea nearly a decade ago, and it absolutely works in practice. In 2012, cloud gaming pioneer OnLive introduced a virtual desktop web browser that would let you load full websites on an iPad in the blink of an eye &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; stream 4K video from YouTube. (Quite the feat in 2012!) &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/2/22/2817646/onlive-desktop-plus-has-the-fastest-virtual-web-browser-youve-ever"&gt;I called it the fastest web browser you’ve ever used&lt;/a&gt;, and OnLive’s asking price was just $5 a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="E6HE8w"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s a proven idea&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="E2fXRx"&gt;Cloud desktop providers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/12/21176310/shadow-cloud-gaming-service-price-lower-google-stadia-nvidia-geforce-now"&gt;like Shadow&lt;/a&gt; have also offered similar capabilities; when you rent their gaming-PCs-in-the-cloud ($12-15 a month), you can use those virtual PCs’ built-in web browsers to get similar speeds, thanks to the fact they typically live in data centers with very few hops to (and possibly direct peering arrangements with) major content delivery networks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="76CLaI"&gt;Mighty argues that by focusing on the browser (rather than recreating a whole Windows PC), it can give more people what they actually want. “Most people want an experience where the underlying OS and the application (the browser) interoperate seamlessly versus having to tame two desktop experiences,” &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26962818"&gt;founder Suhail Doshi commented at&lt;em&gt; Hacker News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Mighty claims it’ll eliminate distracting cookies and ads, automatically notify you about Zoom meetings, quick search Google Docs and presumably other integrations to come. Mighty also says it encrypts your data and keystrokes, &lt;a href="https://www.mightyapp.com/security"&gt;among other security promises.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F9nNZv"&gt;But it’s not entirely clear why it costs so much more, or who would be willing to pay $30 a month for such a subscription — you’d think the kinds of people who can afford a monthly browser bill on top of their monthly internet bill would be the same kinds of people who can afford a faster PC and faster internet to begin with. Gigabit fiber is already a reality for some homes, and it’s not like Mighty will turn &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/21/22242635/fcc-ajit-pai-internet-speed-advanced-telecommunications-3mbps"&gt;your iffy 25/3 connection&lt;/a&gt; into a gigabit one; while Doshi tells me it’ll technically work with a 20Mbps connection, he says he’s targeting 80+Mbps households right now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="If2683"&gt;Then again, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22177154/us-internet-speed-maps-competition-availability-fcc"&gt;it’s not like everyone has a real choice of internet service provider&lt;/a&gt;, no matter how much money they make. As Jürgen Geuter (aka tante) points out below, this feels more like an indictment than innovation. It’s been a decade, and we still haven’t solved these problems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qKjRkW"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;"Streaming your browser to you because rendering the HTML is too slow on your machine" is not innovation but a mark of shame on everyone building websites and browsers.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Tech failed as an industry. &lt;a href="https://t.co/JJC0WomArb"&gt;https://t.co/JJC0WomArb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— tante (@tante) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tante/status/1387390816595947522?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 28, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YIMvM9"&gt;I agree &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/1387499682759380995"&gt;with my colleague Tom&lt;/a&gt;: I genuinely want to know who’d actually pay for this and why. Would you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="HQzqfI"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I want to meet whoever is going to spend $30 a month to stream a Chromium browser from the cloud just to avoid RAM hungry Chrome &lt;a href="https://t.co/4pl6jL2zUV"&gt;https://t.co/4pl6jL2zUV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Tom Warren (@tomwarren) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/1387499682759380995?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 28, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vrhrAc"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22408818/mighty-browser-chrome-cloud-streaming-web"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22408818/mighty-browser-chrome-cloud-streaming-web</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-04-28T21:04:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-28T21:04:10-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook claims it mistakenly hid posts calling for India’s prime minister to resign</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NejP3qeOZaAQUaLrvkqiS_3MN7c=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69201908/acastro_180828_1777_facebook_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kLTZoh"&gt;When Facebook users tried to view a hashtag calling for the resignation of Indian prime minister Narendra Modi on Wednesday, they &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/srinivasaiims/status/1387472195316711426"&gt;instead saw a message&lt;/a&gt; saying that Facebook was temporarily hiding the posts in order to keep the community safe. &lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/facebook-blocking-posts-hashtag-resign-modi"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Buzzfeed News &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; that the posts were hidden for about three hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T3qohU"&gt;Facebook has now restored the posts. The company tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the hashtag was blocked “by mistake” and claims it wasn’t because the Indian government asked Facebook to remove it. It also says the block was the result of some of the content that used the hashtag, but did not specify what kind of content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QeLMIH"&gt;The temporary suspension of the hashtag is likely to fuel concerns about the influence that Modi’s BJP party wields over Facebook operations and social media in general. Last weekend, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/24/22400976/twitter-removed-tweets-critical-india-censor-coronavirus"&gt;Twitter hid tweets critical of various officials&lt;/a&gt; after receiving an emergency order from the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="foSR7N"&gt;India is currently currently seeing another wave in COVID-19 cases, which has lead to critical medical supplies being in short supply. Many of the Facebook posts with the ResignModi hashtag include references to the coronavirus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2MMbby"&gt;Facebook has blocked hashtags in the past — during the 2020 US election &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/5/21551717/facebook-tiktok-block-election-conspiracy-theory-hashtags-twitter-monitoring"&gt;it blocked the  “StopTheSteal” tag&lt;/a&gt;, showing users a similar message to the one seen in India today. The hashtag for “Qanon” is also blocked, as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/6/21504887/facebook-qanon-ban-all-apps-pages-groups-instagram-accounts"&gt;part of Facebook’s fight&lt;/a&gt; against the conspiracy-based social movement. Unlike the ResignModi hashtag, the StopTheSteal and Qanon tags are still blocked, with the message citing content that goes against community standards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eqaH8A"&gt;Facebook India has been a sore point for the company in recent months, with its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/27/21536149/ankhi-das-facebook-india-resigned-quit-bjp-hindu-muslim-conflict"&gt;controversial policy chief resigning&lt;/a&gt; last October. Critics pressured her to leave, claiming that, under her guidance, Facebook India had failed to moderate hate speech that led to anti-Muslim pogroms in Delhi. More broadly, there were concerns that her public alignment with the ruling BJP party had led to unfair application of Facebook policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="162nQO"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update April 28th, 9:04PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated with statement from Facebook.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22408334/facebook-hides-modi-resign-posts-restore-investigation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22408334/facebook-hides-modi-resign-posts-restore-investigation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
