<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-07-21T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix’s Masters of the Universe erases the past to chart a new future</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HabPKxMLWg-ct_Als1Nb4srET_w=/282x0:3318x2024/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69611738/MastersoftheUniverse_Revelation_Part1_Episode5_00_19_39_05.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Atxnj3"&gt;Part of what made &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/15/18097423/she-ra-netflix-interview-reboot-noelle-stevenson-showrunner-nimona-lumberjanes"&gt;&lt;em&gt;She-Ra and the Princesses of Power&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;so good was the way it completely reimagined the classic cartoon. It was still set in a magical realm with talking horses and evil robot armies, but it took an old show — which, if we’re being honest, was created for the express purpose of selling toys — and gave its characters and world some real depth and meaning. It was funny and exciting, heartbreaking and beautiful, without a toy commercial in sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gu7p0e"&gt;On the surface, &lt;em&gt;Masters of the Universe: Revelation&lt;/em&gt;, which stars She-Ra’s long-lost twin brother He-Man, isn’t quite so exciting. It’s not a reboot but a direct sequel, one that’s meant to pick up right after the original cartoon ended in 1985. It has the same cast of characters, some of which are pretty goofy, like a wimpy battle cat and an alien sorcerer with self-esteem problems. Skeletor (now played by Mark Hamill) remains a gigantic dork. Yet, thanks to a bold decision early on, the show manages to become something that almost feels new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hln5Bw"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big spoilers for &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Masters of the Universe: Revelation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; ahead.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T3njnr"&gt;Because it’s a direct sequel, &lt;em&gt;Revelation&lt;/em&gt; wastes no time in setting things up. Immediately Skeletor is in the midst of a plan to destroy Castle Grayskull in order to reveal its true power so that he can harness it for himself. Unfortunately, his attack has the side effect of not only destroying the planet of Eternia, but also all of existence. In order to prevent this, He-Man sacrifices himself and his magical sword, taking Skeletor with him in the process. After just one episode, the show’s two most iconic faces are killed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Js1lTH"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iXdEeRBh9Zk?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SvCjtP"&gt;It’s a dramatic shift, and from there &lt;em&gt;Revelation&lt;/em&gt; resembles something of a post-apocalyptic fantasy wasteland. The story fast-forwards a few years when Teela (Sarah Michelle Gellar), a former royal guard, is now a scavenger, making a living by scrounging for old bits of tech and items imbued with magic. There’s a strange cult that worships technology, and, without Skeletor to lead them, Eternia’s many villains have scattered. Eventually, Teela learns that the planet is slowly dying as its magic leaks away, so she reluctantly sets about finding the two halves of He-Man’s sword of power in order to set things right. It’s one of those epic quests that involves traveling to both heaven and hell, and pulling together a group of misfits to help you do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0IzWE3"&gt;This premise lets the show mostly get away from the Saturday morning cartoon vibe of the original, while still keeping the same characters and world. Eternia remains an interesting mix of sci-fi, swords, and sorcery, as if Frank Frazetta and Ralph McQuarrie had a jam session. Killer robots fight alongside beast men, and sword-wielding warriors ride mechanical horses and armored cats into battle. Things have a bit more of a &lt;em&gt;Mad Max&lt;/em&gt; vibe this time around, with villages fighting over the last drops of magic while the techno-cult terrorizes them. In addition, Teela has a new job as a mercenary, Man-at-Arms (Liam Cunningham) has become an Obi-Wan-style hermit, and Evil-Lyn (Lena Headey) is left confused without a dictator to support. They all end up joining forces in the quest.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-DQaDgFV6v9PQYlFVR7TLfTtNbs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22728252/MastersoftheUniverse_Revelation_Part1_Episode3_00_01_36_01.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="DGot4P"&gt;It can feel like a reboot, but the show does retain some of the inherent silliness of its predecessor. &lt;em&gt;Revelation&lt;/em&gt;’s writers never met a terrible pun they didn’t like, and characters like the dopey villain Mer-Man and the perpetually terrified Cringer feel out of place in this grittier world. The acting is also uneven. There are some good individual performances — Cunningham adds a welcome gravitas, Headey channels her inner Cersei, and Hamill hams it up as always — but it often sounds like a video game where everyone recorded their lines separately. (There are also a few bizarre jokes, like a “no glove, no love” quip that doesn’t seem appropriate in a PG cartoon.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="taXQ2s"&gt;Because of all of these elements, the show doesn’t feel quite as refreshing or daring as &lt;em&gt;She-Ra&lt;/em&gt;. But for a direct sequel to the original cartoon made to sell toys, its surprisingly modern; the dramatic opening paves the way for a new path even if &lt;em&gt;Revelation&lt;/em&gt; never fully breaks away from its source. What’s available now on Netflix is also only a beginning: the first part of &lt;em&gt;Revelation&lt;/em&gt; is five episodes long, and the final episode suggests there might be even bigger changes in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OXYN4U"&gt;&lt;small&gt;Masters of the Universe: Revelations &lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;will be on Netflix on July 23rd.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22585095/masters-of-the-universe-revelation-netflix-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22585095/masters-of-the-universe-revelation-netflix-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T10:30:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T10:30:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google gives Pixel 4 XL an extra year of free repairs for power issues</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-adPzqMK7Q5i3AAb7EwEi3NHccw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69611569/vpavic_191016_3730_0029.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verg&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ENwDJK"&gt;If your out-of-warranty Pixel 4 XL has been exhibiting some problems, you might be able to get a free repair. Google recently &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/answer/10169830?hl=en"&gt;posted a support page&lt;/a&gt; outlining a “one-year extended repair program” for the larger of its two 2019 flagships. Those who are eligible can receive a free repair for up to a year after their original warranty expires. As for who’s covered by this program, Google points to “certain power-related issues.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EuqPLc"&gt;More specifically, the company says these are the problems that “may” get a free repair:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="wAVXaX"&gt;A Pixel 4 XL that can’t be powered on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NPYIhX"&gt;The Pixel 4 XL restarts or shuts down randomly without any user action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rGk1L3"&gt;Charging problems with the power adapter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="smPuWr"&gt;Wireless charging issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7lmSNv"&gt;The battery on a Pixel 4 XL is draining “significantly faster than earlier in its use”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="TM5eKI"&gt;That’s a pretty wide spread of potential ways to qualify for the repair program. But Google cautions that if there are other major problems with your phone (like a damaged screen) that “prevent” the complimentary repair, those will have to be fixed first — and for a fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZpK70V"&gt;Pixel 4 XL owners can bring their device to &lt;a href="https://www.ubreakifix.com/locations"&gt;a uBreakiFix store&lt;/a&gt; to see if it qualifies for a free fix. According to &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/07/20/google-might-be-extending-your-pixel-4-xls-warranty-for-an-extra-year/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, repair staff at those locations are very familiar with the situation. You can also start the repair process directly with Google to see if your issue is covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JFv7Xm"&gt;The extended repair program is available in the US, Canada, Singapore, Japan, and Taiwan. Google specifies that it does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; apply in Australia, France, Germany, Ireland, Italy, Spain, or the UK. That’s because Pixel 4 XLs purchased in those countries already came with a longer two-year manufacturer’s warranty.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586833/google-pixel-4-xl-extended-repair-program-announced"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586833/google-pixel-4-xl-extended-repair-program-announced</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T10:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T10:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Adam Neumann’s WeWork debacle wasn’t possible without VC help</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="WeWork Presents Second Annual Creator Global Finals At Microsoft Theater" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dsUpSAV4BHCajnXPnwzM4ksJh2w=/0x0:5406x3604/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69611557/1079941752.jpg.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Michael Kovac/Getty Images for WeWork&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;A new book explains how the failed IPO truly took a village&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="Sk2BUd"&gt;For the better part of two years now, I’ve been wondering how the 2019 WeWork debacle happened. Whatever, sure, Adam Neumann is a &lt;em&gt;wild and crazy guy&lt;/em&gt; — but without commitments from a number of sophisticated investors (Benchmark! T Rowe Price! Fidelity! Harvard University!), his tequila-soaked dreams never would have become a reality. I’ve been waiting for &lt;em&gt;someone&lt;/em&gt; to explain what these people were doing, handing Neumann all that cash, and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Cult-We-Neumann-Startup-Delusion-ebook/dp/B08FHC77MT/ref=sr_1_1?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cult of We&lt;/em&gt; by Eliot Brown and Maureen Farrell&lt;/a&gt; finally gets there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="izrNRr"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Adam had a meeting with SpaceX CEO Elon Musk, where he told Musk that getting people to Mars would be the &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt; part&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2XOPTa"&gt;Take the fateful S-1, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/15/20806366/we-company-wework-ipo-adam-neumann"&gt;document required for its IPO&lt;/a&gt;. At the time, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/24/20882491/wework-adam-neumann-softbank-ceo"&gt;I wondered&lt;/a&gt; how so many people had read the document and decided it was fine. Helpfully, Brown and Farrell explain this: turns out bidding for the IPO was very intense between Goldman and JP Morgan. And all those weird provisions? Well, JP Morgan pointed out that the public might not like them! Mary Callahan Erdoes, the CEO of JP Morgan’s wealth management division, was dispatched to tell Adam that all the provisions in the S-1 that benefited him were likely to cause a major hit to WeWork’s valuation. He shrugged. And that was that — WeWork was the client and JP Morgan was getting paid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MbcUEj"&gt;I don’t mean to suggest the book is short on details about the Neumanns, who seem delusional. Rebekah Paltrow Neumann, for instance, saw six different iterations of her office, which featured a pink and yellow couch and a white sheepskin rug — but nonetheless complained when it was finished because it was smaller than Adam’s. (“My soul can’t breathe,” she said.) And Adam had a meeting with SpaceX CEO Elon Musk, where he told Musk that getting people to Mars would be the &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt; part; building community would be hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qrLUWd"&gt;But, the book explains, WeWork was a functional business in 2012, when it made a profit. That was, incidentally, before it retooled itself to be appealing to venture capitalists. After reading Brown and Farrell’s reporting, it seems to me that after 2012, WeWork’s primary function wasn’t office space — it was raising its valuation. And the sky-high valuation wasn’t on the Neumanns alone; it was also on everyone who gave Adam money, but especially Masayoshi Son, who encouraged him to think &lt;em&gt;even bigger&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s8CtFK"&gt;Another thing working in Adam Neumann’s favor was the tech industry’s cult of the founder, which had become part of the venture capital pitch; the phrase “founder friendly” appears in the book’s index. Founders were to be worshipped, adherents of this sect believed, and should have full, unfettered control over their companies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="dnxfk1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“How did they all get played?” &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2Y66An"&gt;Brown, who began covering WeWork as a real estate reporter at &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;, watched in surprise as the WeWork brand took off as a “tech company.” Ferrell, whose specialty at the &lt;em&gt;WSJ &lt;/em&gt;is IPOs, was writing madly as the IPO began to unravel. The two realized they had a book on their hands pretty quickly — “WeWork was the apotheosis of like, &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; concerning trend,” Brown says — and they wanted to know how the whole debacle had happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oSdTOj"&gt;I talked with Brown and Farrell about their book, the venture capital industry, and the spineless cast of characters — the board of directors, for instance, who simply thought it would be easier to let Adam Neumann have his way. “It still is kind of wild to me how Adam Neumann had the ultimate power to make all of this happen and do all the things he did when you have some of the most sophisticated financiers in the world behind him,” Ferrell tells me. “How did they all get played?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6R0m6X"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This interview has been edited and condensed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EB7aLu"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some of the things that freaked people out in the S-1 had actually been reported earlier, by you and others. So why didn’t someone press pause sooner?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nBNEV7"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eliot Brown:&lt;/strong&gt; I don’t know! We would write stories and then the valuation kept going up. We’d write stories on conflicts of interest and, you know, people would sort of just glide past that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="GMidBh"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It was grand delusion internally.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="A0oL83"&gt;There were a couple things going on. People started coming to the reality in mid-2019 [after the IPOs of money-losing ride-share companies Uber and Lyft], that like, wow, companies that lose billions of dollars — that might not be a cool business model long term. There was this talk of “Oh, now companies need to show a path to profitability.” A path to profitability? That’s what a company is! Like, of course they show that! That’s the point! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w8tyDj"&gt;And then the S-1 itself was just... It had so many things that were totally insane that it would have been just impossible to ignore all this stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DcATE8"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maureen Farrell:&lt;/strong&gt; It was grand delusion internally. Adam ran the company in the most chaotic way. And it worked up until a point. But I mean, when you’re just getting into the weeds on what was happening day to day, with the S-1 ramp up, it was just — everything was so crazy. People are living in this world of chaos, and so certain things didn’t become clear, like the $5.9 million payment for the word “We,” they kind of missed that. Because there’s so many other insane things in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eKARYS"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But WeWork didn’t start as something crazy. In fact, renting people office space is not a terrible idea. Is there a specific point when things changed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RnkrhD"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EB:&lt;/strong&gt; Maybe broadly what WeWork shows is that not every business is a venture capital business. There’s this meme in Silicon Valley, and entrepreneurship today, that if you have an ice cream company, it’s not gonna be a good ice cream company unless you raise VC money. And so everything has to be tech and everything has to be, you know, rapid growth. And it turns out that some businesses do not need to do that and are not built for that. So I think the turning point is when WeWork first took venture capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="jINwD1"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Adam Neumann was fixated on making the company as big as it could possibly be.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hW4KsB"&gt;They literally were profitable for one year in their history. And that was 2012, by their own numbers. After that, it was just nothing but losses, right? They originally hit this gold mine, where real estate was cheap and demand for this kind of cool, hipster-y, millennial chic space was high, and so they could make enough money. And so then a normal, rational human might say, “Okay, well, let’s just grow kind of at whatever pace that allows and not try to take over the planet in the next five years.” But that wasn’t the sort of venture capital mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xZAaqf"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did venture capital get involved?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oNZZYh"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MF:&lt;/strong&gt; Adam Neumann was fixated on making the company as big as it could possibly be and, you know, getting the valuation high as it could possibly be. So he kind of morphed the company into... like the venture capitals were almost his clients, you know? He focused the business and sort of changed it and explained it in such a way that it would appeal to them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L6DNGm"&gt;It was a leap of faith, believing that the business model was something it wasn’t. It didn’t make sense. It was a real estate company. And he convinced some of the most sophisticated and successful venture capitalists in the world that it was something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="q6pSsd"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Maybe this mattress company &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a tech company!”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2lp6bA"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EB:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s just a product of simply there being too much money, right? There’s only so many good ideas out there. Money could go into other things, but everyone was trying to get into Silicon Valley. So there’s this waterfall going into a small spigot because it really can’t absorb that much money. And so in bubbles, that’s what happens — people cast aside critical thinking. Instead, they’re like, “Maybe this mattress company &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a tech company!” Because if you don’t say that, then you can’t spend your money. And if you don’t spend money, you can’t make money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iNwfGP"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much did the Silicon Valley focus on the founder play into this mindset?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uBJvBA"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MF:&lt;/strong&gt; The whole cult of the founder was so central to this narrative in general and how this all played out. It really gave Adam Neumann this really long leash, because founders are geniuses and they are eccentric. So who’s the next Mark Zuckerberg that can create this Goliath of a company and make us gigantic returns?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xgWySu"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Throughout the book, I kept wondering, &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is going on with this board?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Over and over again, they rubber-stamp Neumann’s decisions. In fact, there’s this excuse that shows up over and over: Oh, the public markets will create discipline. Why is that the public markets’ job?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;aside id="IEZad7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Toward the end, he just stopped going to board meetings. He just didn’t show up.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Y0qBpC"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MF:&lt;/strong&gt; In the book, we spell that out, that the directors are saying that to each other, which is just so crazy. They handed him super voting control, they let him get that. And then it seemed like they absolved themselves of having any clear role in pushing back on him, when that’s the role they’re supposed to take. That floored us so much each step of the way. And the board&lt;em&gt; finally&lt;/em&gt; stepped up and flipped out at him just as the IPO is about to completely blow up. That was the first time you see them really pushing back in a big way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F2lhF1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EB:&lt;/strong&gt; Toward the end, he just stopped going to board meetings. He just didn’t show up. They finally just flip out, and say, “Adam, you have to come to these things.” One of the directors goes up to meet him in his office like, “Adam, it’s a board meeting.” That’s September 2019, which is when it was falling apart. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5bomiY"&gt;The other thing with the board is, we asked people, “Why wouldn’t you stand up?” And the answer was, “Well, he controls the board. So what’s the point of voting no? Because he’ll just be mad and he’s gonna win anyhow.” Okay, but if a majority of you voted no, then he would have to actually blow up the board — that’s a really big action. But they would never vote no, it was unanimous. It’s like “You want this jet?” Everyone would be like, “No, I don’t want the jet.” And then, you look at the minutes — oh, unanimously approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="3K9WyM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The easy answer was, ‘Well, my job as a board director is to have the share price go up.’”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eFos62"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MF:&lt;/strong&gt; You know, the easy answer was, “Well, my job as a board director is to have the share price go up.” The share price kept going up and up and up, and they were getting extremely wealthy. They were killing it on their investments. So from that perspective, it was working. It would be easier to argue with Adam if the company were declining in value. So then the first time that they stand up to him is when the company is running out of money and, you know, its valuation has plunged. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y1hUE8"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If the same thing had happened now — &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22251427/reddit-gamestop-stock-short-wallstreetbets-robinhood-wall-street"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;after GameStonk stuff in January&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; — would there have been the same kind of rebellion on the part of the public markets? Or would people have been like, yeah, sure, we’ve got a bunch of weird shit out here?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yK1Phg"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MF:&lt;/strong&gt; One of the things we saw on Palantir, even, there are some very extreme steps that the founders had taken — they could have no economic stake in the company and keep voting control. So there’s been a lot of crazy stuff that’s come out into the public markets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9ExrOP"&gt;Someone I talked to right after the S-1 came out said there’s a menu of things that founders can pick from to kind of push the envelope. And in that menu, maybe people pick a few of them. Adam Neumann picked every single one on that menu, and it was just so egregious. Even in this market, it was a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0fcCg8"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EB:&lt;/strong&gt; The super loss-heavy startups, where you can have, literally, one, two, three, four billion-dollar losses in a year — that has fallen a bit out of vogue. Who knows if it comes back! Most of the super-highly-valued unicorns going public are slightly better in terms of, you know, not hemorrhaging cash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Iqo4tB"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did we learn any lessons from WeWork?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="od2xZC"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EB:&lt;/strong&gt; No.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="zK46xI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“WeWork and Adam Neumann were the manifestation of the financial system that was structured this way.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="acb5yd"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MF:&lt;/strong&gt; For a minute, it really seemed like they did. In 2019, for a while, Masayoshi Son was telling everyone, “Oh, you suddenly have to be profitable.” And then the pendulum has swung back faster than we ever could have anticipated. And it almost feels more extreme in some ways than it was then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DKvPFu"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EB:&lt;/strong&gt; When we started the book, we thought it was the punctuation of an era of, you know, Silicon Valley unicorn insanity. And then the pandemic happened, and the Fed printed money and cash rolled even more into Silicon Valley. And, yeah, it seems to have gone the other way. So WeWork was more of a blip than the end of an era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ApUtYZ"&gt;These things go in cycles. If you were to be a super charismatic founder out there trying to raise money for a co-working company right now at a $47 billion valuation, it would be extremely difficult. People still do mention WeWork in VC circles. But one of the things that the pendulum has swung so the public markets are kind of where the crazy is right now. So this is a long way of saying we have learned nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3OGqb0"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MF:&lt;/strong&gt; We hope people take some lessons from the book. Maybe there are lessons to be learned or — even just a wake-up call. The reckoning that seemed to happen immediately, we hope can happen again, when you just put every piece of the story out there. What does it mean to be a director? What does it mean to be a banker to these companies? Should you stand up to someone like him?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="CHvnlj"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EB:&lt;/strong&gt; One of the things we really feel strongly about is this isn’t a story about Adam Neumann and WeWork being special. WeWork and Adam Neumann were the manifestation of the financial system that was structured this way. And if it wasn’t Adam Neumann, who, you know, bought a plane and a jet wave pool company and started an elementary school with his VC money, it would have been someone else doing something maybe slightly less crazy. But this is what happens when you have these forces where there’s just so much money in Silicon Valley, there’s this meme that founders are immortal beings and special, and we should give them control. Like, this is the obvious manifestation.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22585805/adam-neumann-cult-of-we-wework-book-vc"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22585805/adam-neumann-cult-of-we-wework-book-vc</id>
    <author>
      <name>Elizabeth Lopatto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T09:56:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T09:56:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>Tumblr starts letting bloggers charge a subscription</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Screenshots show Tumblr on an iPhone. There’s a “Support” button at the top of the blog, which leads to a pop-up explaining the subscription price and perks." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V4J893tXJJOZ-wctGzubhE7f23Q=/625x0:7377x4501/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69611270/01_Artistv2.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Tumblr’s Post Plus feature lets blogs offer a subscription for exclusive posts. | Image: Tumblr&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="C2Qbgq"&gt;Tumblr is finally offering its writers a way to make money off their work: charging a subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1cNVk0"&gt;The 14-year-old blogging platform is starting to add the ability for writers to put their posts behind a paywall. The feature, called Post Plus, lets creators offer a $3.99, $5.99, or $9.99 per month subscription, which will give readers access to any posts they decide to designate as for subscribers only. For now, the feature is available in a “limited beta” for select creators only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="X7F4z9"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Like Substack, without the whole email thing&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Icb1tL"&gt;The formula sounds a lot like what Substack offers — a blog and an easy way for writers to charge for it — minus the whole emailed newsletter component. Facebook is also starting to test the waters in this area and is starting a subscription newsletter product called Bulletin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IMtybV"&gt;While Tumblr is still a big network, the platform has been shrinking. It now gets 11.3 million daily posts, according to Tumblr’s press information page, down from 14.8 million this time last year, and 67.7 million this time in 2012, according to archives of the page. Tumblr struggled during the shift to mobile, and it later stalled after being purchased by Yahoo in 2013 and Verizon in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gmrj9X"&gt;Automattic, which runs WordPress.com, bought Tumblr in 2019, but it hasn’t done much with the service since. It’s hard to imagine a paywall feature, for a site that is often used for pseudonymous fan blogging, will be what brings people back. But it’s a step toward making the platform a more flexible option for writers and gives existing ones another reason to stick around. The network is now highlighting its continued adoption by younger users, saying that just about half of its users are part of Gen Z.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mn7HFN"&gt;A wide launch of the feature is planned for this fall, a Tumblr spokesperson tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. Tumblr will take a 5 percent fee from subscriptions, which is competitive compared to Substack’s 10 percent cut. If readers subscribe on iOS or Android, though, those platforms’ 30 percent app store fees will come out of what a creator gets to keep.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586765/tumblr-subscription-blogs-post-plus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586765/tumblr-subscription-blogs-post-plus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T09:54:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T09:54:52-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to change your name on TikTok</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Tessellated TikTok logos against a dark background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DFTBC6u3D8EwYbS5JeVsEkDl8Jc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69611264/acastro_190723_1777_tiktok_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lxcf8x"&gt;When you start using TikTok, you’re asked for a profile name and a username. If you’ve been using TikTok for a while, though, it wouldn’t be unusual to decide that you want to change one or both. Perhaps you used your real name and weren’t aware at first that your name would be made public. Or perhaps the name you originally chose is no longer quite right for the type of content you’re going to post. Or perhaps you simply decided that you want to be known by something more exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IDGE5j"&gt;Either way, it’s simple to change either your profile name or your username. (In TikTok, the username is the one preceded by an @ sign.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S9ILSk"&gt;Go to your profile page (by tapping the “Me” icon in the lower-right corner).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="4olhQg"&gt;Select “Edit profile.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="MrK9QW"&gt;Select “Name” (to change your profile name) or “Username.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="GX3Aah"&gt;Type in your new name. (In the case of your username, remember that will have to be unique.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can change names on the “Edit profile” page." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MAQYtGOeyYC9trgBkt8ec1OhuZI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22730561/Screenshot_20210720_162536.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can change names on the “Edit profile” page.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="You can only change your username once every 30 days." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Lpekqag83vmDpvKMRRsDEQ2SOxE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22730562/Screenshot_20210720_162749.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can only change your username once every 30 days.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2Epixf"&gt;There are several other things you need to be aware of before you change your username. First, your username can only be changed once every 30 days, so make sure it’s one you can live with, at least for that period. In addition, if you change your username, that means you’ll be also changing your personal TikTok URL (which is usually in the form of something like &lt;em&gt;tiktok.com/@username&lt;/em&gt;). As a result, anyone who tries to use the older address will no longer see your videos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="3oEzU4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"The Verge on TikTok","description":"Join us for TikToks about the future of technology and science","label":"Follow us!","url":"https://bit.ly/3ho6J5U"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="BCgAbx"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22585579/tiktok-name-username-change-how-to"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22585579/tiktok-name-username-change-how-to</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T09:48:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T09:48:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>The latest iPad Pro and iPad Air tablets are each $100 off today</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The iPad Pro with the Liquid Retina XDR display" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tbH08hPuy0cqCxZ1dtQA8Pi3T5Q=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69611199/vpavic_210512_4592_0192.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="H6EnL5"&gt;If you’ve been waiting for a sizable deal on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22442084/ipad-pro-2021-review-features-screen-mini-led-m1-processor"&gt;new M1 processor-equipped 12.9-inch iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt; or the 10.9-inch iPad Air released last year, you can save $100 on either model now at Amazon. Starting with the iPad Pro, the base model in space gray that comes with &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0932D45W8/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;128GB of storage costs $999 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. That’s $100 off the usual cost, which is great considering this iteration includes a brilliant Mini LED Liquid Retina XDR display with more contrast and color depth than in previous models. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="VTELt4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10474637"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6e3oK9"&gt;It’s understandable if you might be after something a little less pricey instead. At &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1746838897268969922#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08J6FD94H/ref=fs_a_ipadt2_us2?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, you can save $100 on the base model of the 2020 iPad Air that has a 10.9-inch screen and — like the iPad Pro — a USB-C port for charging. Normally $599 for the 64GB version, it’s $499 now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MukiV2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9546269"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iw2jVV"&gt;These are both good deals, but it’s tough to recommend purchasing through these retailers if you’re a student or educator &lt;a href="https://apple.sjv.io/c/482924/435031/7613?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fus-hed%2Fshop%2Fback-to-school&amp;amp;subid1=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;because Apple’s back-to-school promotion is a smarter way to buy&lt;/a&gt;. The price for the same iPad Air is $549, but you’ll get a set of AirPods at no extra charge. In the case of the iPad Pro mentioned above, you can get it for the same price through Apple and get AirPods at no extra charge.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Eero 6" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ULhFUiPZOoJ20AyiMlZrf4rkjW8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22284101/eero6.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Eero&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="frTEve"&gt;Best Buy has a fantastic deal on a three-pack Eero 6 mesh Wi-Fi 6 system. Normally $279, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1746840315027404150#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;it’s $181 today&lt;/a&gt;. This bundle includes one Eero 6 router that has two ethernet ports, one for your modem and another that can go to a preferred device or an ethernet switch. You’ll also get two Eero 6 wireless extenders that don’t have ethernet but can extend the signal to more parts of your home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="eo8lco"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9603441"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wmb7nB"&gt;If you own a PS4 or PS5, I suggest picking up &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21558093/yakuza-like-a-dragon-review-xbox-series-x" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yakuza: Like a Dragon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; at Best Buy today. The &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1746840908635950785#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;limited edition release that includes a steelbook case costs $25&lt;/a&gt; (usually $60), and with this game disc inserted into your PS5, you can get the PS5 update for no extra cost. This game is available on Xbox Game Pass Ultimate, but for PlayStation gamers, this is a tough deal to pass up. Unlike previous &lt;em&gt;Yakuza &lt;/em&gt;games, this one’s a turn-based RPG, but it still has the franchise’s signature humor and drama.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="M9DgoB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10367357"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="LjDGvo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="6XyZSh"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/7/21/22586665/apple-ipad-pro-air-m1-eero-6-mesh-wifi-router-deal-sale-amazon-best-buy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/7/21/22586665/apple-ipad-pro-air-m1-eero-6-mesh-wifi-router-deal-sale-amazon-best-buy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T09:29:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T09:29:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nobuo Uematsu’s beautiful Fantasian soundtrack is now on Apple Music</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="fantasian" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-Mz7Ag417bBX1L7mAX_6kFXM5so=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69611089/1_4k.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7GvpnB"&gt;One of the most exciting things about &lt;em&gt;Fantasian&lt;/em&gt; — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22383403/fantasian-review-apple-arcade-rpg-iphone-ipad"&gt;a &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt;-style roleplaying game that debuted on Apple Arcade earlier this year&lt;/a&gt; — was how it reunited two industry legends. Hironobu Sakaguchi served as the creative director of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/2021/3/2/22309074/fantasian-diorama-rpg-apple-arcade-hironobu-sakaguchi"&gt;the handcrafted adventure&lt;/a&gt;, while longtime &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; composer Nobuo Uematsu returned for the soundtrack. Now, all of that beautiful music is finally available to stream on &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmusic.apple.com%2Falbum%2F1576490134&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F7%2F21%2F22586744%2Ffantasian-soundtrack-apple-music-nobuo-uematsu" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple Music&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I6Fl7x"&gt;It’s a hefty album, too, with 58 songs spanning more than two and half hours of music and a wide range of genres. Prior to &lt;em&gt;Fantasian&lt;/em&gt;’s release, Uematsu said that he was worried this might be his last soundtrack. “Will I get another chance to work on an entire game?” &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BJR1wua8OJs"&gt;he said&lt;/a&gt;. “I didn’t want to have any regrets.” Sakaguchi expressed similar concerns, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/2021/3/2/22309074/fantasian-diorama-rpg-apple-arcade-hironobu-sakaguchi"&gt;telling &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: “Let’s be honest, I’m in the latter chapters of my game development career, and each game can take years to go from conception to release.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="SzzlFt"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Nobuo Uematsu × Hironobu Sakaguchi Works ~ Music from FANTASIAN&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Leading up to the 7/28 album release, the soundtrack will be available on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AppleMusic?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#AppleMusic&lt;/a&gt; starting today! Nobuo Uematsu returns to his roots of music composition in this unforgettable experience.&lt;a href="https://t.co/kv91dXK025"&gt;https://t.co/kv91dXK025&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/wtQ4BrbJA4"&gt;pic.twitter.com/wtQ4BrbJA4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— MISTWALKER Corp. (@mistwalker) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mistwalker/status/1417826667045613574?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 21, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rbibm7"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fantasian&lt;/em&gt; is currently available to Apple Arcade subscribers, and a second part, which completes the story, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/auuo/status/1416542005274890245"&gt;is also in development&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586744/fantasian-soundtrack-apple-music-nobuo-uematsu"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586744/fantasian-soundtrack-apple-music-nobuo-uematsu</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T09:17:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T09:17:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Biden administration should take the First Amendment as seriously as Facebook misinformation</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="President Joe Biden speaks in front of a banner promoting Vaccines.gov with the slogan “WE CAN DO THIS”" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PagTtoPHJ32eL_Z2cRaCR4sRBEE=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69611033/51269419295_91e28ca1df_o.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;White House / Adam Schultz&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bgjSWb"&gt;Last week, the White House declared war on anti-vaccine misinformation and Facebook’s moderation system. President Joe Biden &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580620/biden-facebook-vaccine-misinformation-platforms"&gt;said that Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and other social networks were “killing people” by hosting false information about vaccines, although he later &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583809/joe-biden-facebook-covid19-coronavirus-vaccine-misinformation-killing-people"&gt;softened the attack&lt;/a&gt;. Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/17/22581683/facebook-biden-remarks-covid-19-vaccine-misinformation"&gt;disputed the accusation sharply&lt;/a&gt;, promoting its vaccine efforts. And yesterday, the Biden administration &lt;a href="https://www.protocol.com/bulletins/biden-sec-230-review-covid"&gt;hit back&lt;/a&gt; with a troubling — and unnecessary — promise that it was “reviewing” internet law in response to misinformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i1nwFj"&gt;I want to be clear: the White House’s vaccine push is a good thing. American COVID-19 cases are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22579247/covid-vaccine-misinformation-delta-antivirus"&gt;abruptly rising&lt;/a&gt; as the virus’s Delta strain spreads, fewer than half of all Americans are fully vaccinated, and &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/coronavirus-pandemic-health-941fcf43d9731c76c16e7354f5d5e187"&gt;nearly all recent US COVID-19 deaths&lt;/a&gt; have been among unvaccinated people. A significant number of Americans &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Ftoday.yougov.com%2Ftopics%2Fpolitics%2Farticles-reports%2F2021%2F07%2F15%2Fwhy-wont-americans-get-vaccinated-poll-data&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22585152%2Fbiden-white-house-facebook-vaccine-misinformation-section-230-first-amendment" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;report believing theories&lt;/a&gt; like “the US government is using the COVID-19 vaccine to microchip the population,” an idea that’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22516823/covid-vaccine-microchip-conspiracy-theory-explained-reddit"&gt;literally made up&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2021/06/microchipped-vaccines-15-minute-investigation/619081/"&gt;wouldn’t even work&lt;/a&gt;. Companies like Facebook help &lt;a href="https://www.mediamatters.org/facebook/despite-facebooks-covid-19-promises-anti-vaccine-groups-are-thriving"&gt;spread these theories&lt;/a&gt; even if they’re also promoting trustworthy content. And elected officials can urge companies to stop doing something that’s harmful even if it’s legal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="tLFlIk"&gt;&lt;q&gt;To emphasize: promoting vaccination is a good thing&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2s4xCd"&gt;But the White House hasn’t spelled out the last part of that equation. Instead, it’s offering blurred lines between reasonable guidance and an unreasonable government crackdown by condoning the idea that Facebook should be legally “accountable” for false claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="257k6W"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.msnbc.com/morning-joe/watch/biden-will-make-every-effort-to-convince-americans-to-get-vaccinated-wh-117059141549"&gt;In an interview&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/07/20/white-house-social-networks-should-be-held-accountable-for-spreading-misinfo.html"&gt;with MSNBC&lt;/a&gt; about anti-vaccine misinformation, White House communications director Kate Bedingfield responded to a question asking if Biden would change Section 230 to make companies “liable for publishing that information, and then open to lawsuits.” Bedingfield responded that “we’re reviewing that, and certainly they should be held accountable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7y6IYm"&gt;The idea that Section 230 is holding back a crackdown on misinformation is... well, misinformation. (And it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/17/21070403/joe-biden-president-election-section-230-communications-decency-act-revoke"&gt;not the first time Biden’s suggested it&lt;/a&gt;, either.) Section 230 protects against lawsuits involving illegal content. With limited exceptions, the First Amendment allows people to lie and be wrong online. There’s nothing for the Biden administration to “review” unless they believe one of three things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="HDCKtt"&gt;Vaccine misinformation falls under existing First Amendment exceptions like defamation or fraud, and Section 230 should no longer shield companies that host it. (Posts doing things like selling non-vaccine COVID-19 “cures” might fit that bill, but probably not &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/17/covid-misinformation-conspiracy-theories-ccdh-report"&gt;general false messaging about vaccines&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="u9Kfaq"&gt;Vaccine misinformation is so harmful that it should be made illegal and Facebook should then be held liable for letting users spread it. (Congress could theoretically define and ban “misinformation,” but it would be an uphill battle against the First Amendment’s protections.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qbA2Eg"&gt;People should be encouraged to punish Facebook for hosting bad but legal content by making it fight frivolous lawsuits that it will almost certainly win.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="Ise6ot"&gt;The White House can encourage removing false medical information without supporting the idea of taking Facebook to court over it. As attorney and writer Ken White (also known as Popehat) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Popehat/status/1416132396034846720"&gt;pointed out on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, Biden could have emphasized from the start that Facebook has a First Amendment right to allow much false information, even if he thinks the site has a moral duty to remove it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Grp9U1"&gt;Bedingfield could easily have made a similar point in her interview, even leaving the door open to changing Section 230 in other ways — something like “we believe in holding Big Tech accountable and are reviewing laws including Section 230, but we also respect platforms’ right to moderate legal content as they see fit and hope they’ll use that power responsibly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="dhghz8"&gt;&lt;q&gt;‘Section 230 is holding back a misinformation crackdown’ is misinformation&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="MUvRJc"&gt;And when it comes to most false information online — especially information involving the coronavirus pandemic, where even good-faith medical advice and scientific consensus changes continuously — the US government should continue to respect the right to host that content. As Bedingfield later pointed out in the interview, it’s not like Facebook is creating anti-vaccination posts from scratch; major outlets like Fox News have &lt;a href="https://www.mediamatters.org/fox-news/fox-has-undermined-vaccination-efforts-nearly-60-all-vaccination-segments-2-week-period"&gt;pushed against vaccination efforts&lt;/a&gt;. Letting people sue Facebook for platforming them would be an indirect crackdown on the press and individuals, not simply “Big Tech” regulation. At least one group has directly sued Fox News for its coronavirus coverage, and the case &lt;a href="https://www.rcfp.org/fox-news-washlite-lawsuit-analysis/"&gt;was thrown out&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BC7Inj"&gt;While the First Amendment’s protections aren’t limitless, trying to ban scientific misinformation would almost certainly backfire. Encouraging lawsuits over it would let companies pressure Facebook to take down stories about alleged pollution, dangerous products, or other unflattering but contested incidents. And “fake news” laws in other countries have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/interface/2019/12/3/20991422/singapore-fake-news-law-censorship-politics-usa"&gt;become tools to silence&lt;/a&gt; legitimate protest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZiBK5B"&gt;The Biden administration making this clear wouldn’t silence every critic who believes all social media moderation is censorship. (After all, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22566729/trump-lawsuit-facebook-twitter-google-social-media-censorship"&gt;former president Donald Trump sued Facebook&lt;/a&gt; for voluntarily seeking policy guidance from &lt;em&gt;his own administration&lt;/em&gt;.) But it’s the right way to handle a complicated problem — one that preserves the White House’s commitment to protecting the First Amendment along with Americans’ health.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22585152/biden-white-house-facebook-vaccine-misinformation-section-230-first-amendment"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22585152/biden-white-house-facebook-vaccine-misinformation-section-230-first-amendment</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T09:02:56-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T09:02:56-04:00</updated>
    <title>Watch the latest teaser trailer for Netflix’s upcoming animated Witcher film</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PTnu7fpxOim7lGBmuYdGy-d9ZEw=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69610939/Vesemir_Character.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="I8sqWI"&gt;Netflix has dropped the latest teaser trailer for its animated &lt;em&gt;Witcher&lt;/em&gt; prequel, giving us a better look at the film’s characters and allowing us to hear its English-language voice actors for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o6gh63"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Witcher: Nightmare of the Wolf &lt;/em&gt;focuses on the early life of Geralt’s mentor, Vesemir, “a cocky young witcher who delights in slaying monsters for coin,” as per Netflix’s synopsis. Available plot details are thin, but the film involves Vesemir confronting “a strange new monster” and “demons of his past” in a politically-fraught kingdom. (So far, so &lt;em&gt;Witcher&lt;/em&gt;.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yuHzkO"&gt;The film is being made by Korean animation house Studio Mir, which has previously tackled a number of Netflix animations, including &lt;em&gt;Dota: Dragon’s Blood&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Voltron: Legendary Defender&lt;/em&gt;, as well as shows like &lt;em&gt;The Legend of Korra. &lt;/em&gt;The trailer includes a fun nod to &lt;em&gt;The Witcher&lt;/em&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://www.vulture.com/2019/12/the-witcher-bathtub-geralt-meme.html"&gt;infamous bathtub meme&lt;/a&gt;, with Vesemir, instead of Geralt, enjoying a nice soak.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kc1-8y2fQM86zDf03Gq7ZnMlqUw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22708735/E54CqchWQAc5I42.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hv30Rz"&gt;The voice cast features Theo James as Vesemir, Lara Pulver as Tetra, Graham McTavish as Deglan, and Mary McDonnell as Lady Zerbst. The film has been written and produced by Beau DeMayo and co-produced by &lt;em&gt;The Witcher s&lt;/em&gt;howrunner and executive producer Lauren Schmidt Hissrich, with Studio Mir’s Kwang Il Han directing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pfq6YL"&gt;Expect to see even more &lt;em&gt;Witcher&lt;/em&gt; content from Netflix in future, with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/27/21340050/netflix-the-witcher-blood-origin-live-action-prequel-announced"&gt;live-action spinoff in the works&lt;/a&gt; and a second season of the main show, starring Henry Cavill as Geralt of Rivia, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/9/22566778/the-witcher-season-2-release-trailer-netflix-henry-cavill"&gt;arriving on December 17th&lt;/a&gt;. It’s no surprise given that &lt;em&gt;The Witcher&lt;/em&gt; was Netflix’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/21/21075927/netflix-the-witcher-viewer-numbers-length-metrics-q4-2019-earnings"&gt;most popular first season ever when it debuted&lt;/a&gt; (though &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22252580/bridgerton-netflix-82-million-households-biggest-show-ever-caveats"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bridgerton&lt;/em&gt; has since stolen that record&lt;/a&gt;). You tossed a coin to your witcher, and Netflix is happy to deliver.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586549/witcher-anime-film-teaser-trailer-nightmare-of-the-world-premiere-date-august-23"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586549/witcher-anime-film-teaser-trailer-nightmare-of-the-world-premiere-date-august-23</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to jump on TikTok trends</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lgnVzfdO-uR7tYg7kIaYq0xhGZ0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69610844/acastro_200803_1777_tikTok_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tJzH59"&gt;So you’ve started &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22567211/tiktok-video-how-to-beginners"&gt;posting videos on Tiktok&lt;/a&gt;, and now you’re ready to up your game. One of the easiest ways to make your videos more entertaining and to potentially get more views is to jump on trends. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EfdI43"&gt;The way the TikTok algorithm is designed, it rewards videos that use certain trending sounds, effects, or hashtags. These videos are more likely to receive views because they’re pushed to other people who also enjoy that trend, and they’re easier to find &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22574404/tiktok-videos-for-you-page-curate-algorithm-discover-how-to"&gt;when browsing in the Discover tab&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s how to improve your TikTok strategy by using trends to your advantage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bZyaOb"&gt;Identify trends&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ltAdLA"&gt;Trends can originate from a variety of features on the app: sounds, dances, transitions, or hashtags. One of the easiest ways to identify trends is to browse via the Discover tab, which will feature a variety of trending sounds or topics. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3aPkd9"&gt;In fact, there’s a hashtag that you can follow that does the work for you. &lt;a href="https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMdG2L2uM/"&gt;#trendalert&lt;/a&gt; is a popular hashtag that some TikTokers use to identify trending features that others can follow. They take it upon themselves to scour TikTok and identify what is gaining in popularity, usually by watching the ratio of sounds to the videos made using those sounds, and looking for quick growth. The appeal of following this hashtag is that all you have to do is jump on whatever trend they’ve identified. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0Qla3w9WktxL7ouWmwEYbi_3PAg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22729034/IMG_8195.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;TikTok’s Discover tab is useful for trending features.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LggQfM4b1KWVAY8dQ9TFaVVGl4w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22729036/IMG_8196.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;#trendalert is a popular tag for TikTokers that identify trends for you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="52qcAm"&gt;Trends can also vary depending on what niche of the algorithm you are trapped in. For example, what’s trending on &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@verge?lang=en"&gt;Tech TikTok&lt;/a&gt; may not be trending on Fashion TikTok. That’s totally okay, though, because this helps get your videos onto the For You pages of people who will appreciate that trend. If you are in a niche or want to be, finding trending features requires you to just pay attention to your For You page. If you notice a sound is appearing every few videos, it’s likely that it’s gaining traction. Same goes for hashtags, dances, or some transitions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ECQFEy"&gt;Use a trending feature &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="oJGZ7i"&gt;This can apply to anything that’s trending, but for the purpose of this article, I’ll be focusing on sounds. If you’ve found a song or other audio that is popular, add it to your favorites for easy access later. And don’t worry about repeating it — it’s common for a creator to use a sound multiple times. Once you’ve identified the sound, make a video using whatever matches that trend. Often, it’s a dance or lip-syncing skit. When you’ve finished recording your video, add your caption, slap on a few appropriate hashtags, and upload! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CMgISg"&gt;The key to successfully using a trending sound to get more views, though, is to ensure the sound is still popular. TikTok’s algorithm is designed to tailor your For You page to show things you like — it doesn’t pay as much attention to &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt; a video was posted so much as it does the content &lt;em&gt;within&lt;/em&gt; that video. This means you may have been following a sound from weeks ago that is no longer popular. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MIqCD5g7Pipu2-Itsyt8IYWzX2A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22729042/IMG_8197.PNG"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trending sounds are easy and fun to use.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mMIWm5VCN3mnvLzmoYh1o1f-N_k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22729045/IMG_8199.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The date above the caption can help you identify whether a sound may be old.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TCCnQe"&gt;The best way to ensure the timeliness of a sound is to go to the sound’s page and look at the most recent videos that use it. Ideally, they’ll have been posted as recently as a day or two ago. If most of the videos are over several days or weeks old, it’s safe to assume the window for high views on a video with that sound has passed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GemAj6"&gt;Don’t let that hold you back, though! TikTok is all about having fun, so post your video anyway! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BVY91i"&gt;Trends are a great way to boost your following and viewership if that’s what you’re interested in — but keep in mind that they change frequently and can be hard to keep up with. At its core, TikTok is a social media platform, and what makes social media so fun is participating in a way that’s fun for you! Bucking the trends and creating the content you want can be just as rewarding as learning the latest dance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="3BOEKw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"The Verge on TikTok","description":"Join us for TikToks about the future of technology and science","label":"Follow us!","url":"https://bit.ly/3ho6J5U"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="4myMPl"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22585656/tiktok-trends-sounds-hashtags-how-to-videos"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22585656/tiktok-trends-sounds-hashtags-how-to-videos</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kaitlin Hatton</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
