<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-07-21T14:32:31-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T14:32:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T14:32:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>FTC pledges to fight unlawful right to repair restrictions</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Senate Commerce, Science And Transportation Committee Holds Confirmation Hearing" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZfbtWGEnAjvFfrFzdf_YMqEGuRY=/0x1:3000x2001/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69613129/1232439143.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mDOho7"&gt;The Federal Trade Commission formally pledged to take on unlawful “right to repair” restrictions in a new policy statement issued Wednesday. The new policy could spell trouble for smartphone manufacturers like Apple that strictly inhibit users’ abilities to repair their own devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nditej"&gt;Wednesday’s new right to repair policy statement commits the FTC to encouraging competition in product repair markets with “vigor,” according to Chair Lina Khan. The statement, which was approved unanimously, makes it official FTC policy for the agency to use its existing authorities to support independent repair shops and lower repair costs for consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="77QymA"&gt;“While efforts by dominant firms to restrict repair markets are not new, changes in technology and more prevalent use of software has created fresh opportunities for companies to limit independent repair,” Khan said Wednesday. “These types of restrictions can significantly raise costs for consumers, stifle innovation, close off business opportunities for independent repair shops, create unnecessary electronic waste, delay timely repairs, and undermine resiliency.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="li1Iyl"&gt;The statement comes just days after the White House endorsed similar rules in an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/9/22570826/president-joe-biden-executive-order-right-to-repair"&gt;executive order&lt;/a&gt; on economic competition. In the order, signed by President Joe Biden on July 9th, the White House explicitly calls out smartphone makers that “impose restrictions on self and third-party repairs, making repairs more costly and time-consuming, such as by restricting the distribution of parts, diagnostics, and repair tools.” At Wednesday’s meeting, the FTC did not name any specific companies or industries that it could target in future investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0j8wy9"&gt;“The adoption of today’s policy statement makes clear that the Commission will investigate unlawful repair restrictions, using the Magnuson-Moss Warranty Act and other consumer protection laws, as well as antitrust law to promote fair and open repair markets,” Democratic Commissioner Rohit Chopra said in a statement Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KImRzw"&gt;Wednesday’s open session was just the second since Khan was confirmed as chair at an agency that traditionally works behind closed doors. In the first proceeding earlier this month, Khan’s FTC &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22559131/ftc-open-meeting-antitrust-chair-lina-khan-sherman-act-powers"&gt;passed a pair of competition measures&lt;/a&gt;, setting the agency up to take more aggressive action on antitrust violations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XnrZWf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZRBzO5"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22587331/right-to-repair-apple-iphone-ftc-lina-khan-open-meeting"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22587331/right-to-repair-apple-iphone-ftc-lina-khan-open-meeting</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T14:28:49-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T14:28:49-04:00</updated>
    <title>Go watch this WSJ investigation of TikTok’s algorithm</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Tessellated TikTok logos against a dark background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LMtiMh2tey_Xd8nIfRb4KxX7x-I=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69613102/acastro_190723_1777_tiktok_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0dru3s"&gt;TikTok users often express awe or dismay at the seemingly uncanny accuracy of the app’s recommendation algorithm. &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/video/series/inside-tiktoks-highly-secretive-algorithm/investigation-how-tiktok-algorithm-figures-out-your-deepest-desires/6C0C2040-FF25-4827-8528-2BD6612E3796"&gt;published a video&lt;/a&gt; today that dives into how TikTok customizes your feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vk7cbr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt; investigators ran an experiment where they created bot accounts with assigned interests. The bots “watched” videos in TikTok, pausing or replaying any that had images or hashtags relevant to those interests. The &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt; team reviewed the results with &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/feb/02/how-youtubes-algorithm-distorts-truth"&gt;Guillaume Chaslot&lt;/a&gt;, an algorithm expert who previously worked at YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="psGVNF"&gt;The findings line up with TikTok’s explanations of how its recommendations work. TikTok &lt;a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-us/how-tiktok-recommends-videos-for-you"&gt;has previously said&lt;/a&gt; the For You feed is personalized based on the kinds of videos you interact with, how you interact with them, details about the videos themselves, and account settings like language and location. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7TXUmq"&gt;If you hesitate on a weird video that caught you off guard, there’s no way for the algorithm to differentiate that from content you actually like and want to see more of. That’s how some people end up with a bunch of For You recommendations that &lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2021/06/your-tiktok-feed-embarrassing/619257/"&gt;don’t seem to reflect their interests&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="K3wysh"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;  Look at this hashtag map we put together. In the middle is the mainstream of TikTok. The arms are the rabbit holes. As you go down the arms, the content has less views and can be less moderated. &lt;a href="https://t.co/Niva4NT7LO"&gt;https://t.co/Niva4NT7LO&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/dKp2NtQ3lu"&gt;pic.twitter.com/dKp2NtQ3lu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Joanna Stern (@JoannaStern) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JoannaStern/status/1417856559611359239?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 21, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wwJEMS"&gt;Though humans have more diverse tastes than bots, the experiment demonstrates how quickly a user can be exposed to far reaches of potentially harmful content. According to the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt;, TikTok identified the interests of some of the bots in as few as 40 minutes. One of the bots fell into a rabbit hole of depressive videos, while another ended up at videos about election conspiracies. Though as Will Oremus &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WillOremus/status/1417866336609488898"&gt;points out on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, algorithmic rabbit holes can also bring people to positive content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ub3Sd3"&gt;The video has a lot of details and visualizations, so it’s a good way to wrap your head around the “magic” of how TikTok works. Watch the video above or &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/video/series/inside-tiktoks-highly-secretive-algorithm/investigation-how-tiktok-algorithm-figures-out-your-deepest-desires/6C0C2040-FF25-4827-8528-2BD6612E3796"&gt;at the &lt;em&gt;WSJ&lt;/em&gt; site&lt;/a&gt; — though be warned it includes clips from TikToks that reference depression, suicide, and eating disorders. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22587113/tiktok-algorithm-wsj-investigation-rabbit-hole"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22587113/tiktok-algorithm-wsj-investigation-rabbit-hole</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kait Sanchez</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T14:20:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T14:20:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>Jeff Bezos’ brief trip to space was also a commercial for Rivian</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iA6X63ZZHK1q1VUfjTOWbI_Q6So=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69613044/rivian_blue_origin_4830.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photos by Joey Roulette / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ush37m"&gt;After years of preparation and billions of dollars spent on the project, Amazon founder Jeff Bezos got to be one of the first people to ride a rocket built by his &lt;em&gt;other &lt;/em&gt;company, Blue Origin, to the edge of space. But the event itself was also a chance for Bezos to promote a third investment in the wider Amazon portfolio: EV startup Rivian. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mu78zh"&gt;Throughout the broadcast, Rivian’s electric pickup truck and SUV could be seen shuttling Bezos and his fellow astronauts around — an unsurprising decision considering Amazon now owns &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sokane1/status/1388538580881002501"&gt;more than 10 percent of the EV startup&lt;/a&gt; after leading and participating in multiple funding rounds. The hosts of Blue Origin’s livestream made sure to let everyone watching know what they were seeing, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="r2ErQG"&gt;&lt;q&gt;With commercial space, everything’s an ad&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0W5BsR"&gt;“And here the astronauts come. There you see Jeff Bezos in the foreground, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/15/22578356/blue-origin-new-shepard-teen-jeff-bezos-space-anonymous-auction"&gt;Oliver Daemen&lt;/a&gt; stepping into the Rivian,” Ariane Cornell, Blue Origin’s director of “astronaut and orbital sales,” cheerily said during the broadcast as the group hopped in one of the startup’s SUVs to head to the rocket for their ride to space. Then we got a long, continuous aerial shot of the electric SUV driving toward the pad, split side-by-side during an interview with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/1/22558908/wally-funk-flight-jeff-bezos-blue-origin-space-new-shepard"&gt;Mercury 13 legend Wally Funk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ng3D2D"&gt;After the crew safely landed an hour later, there they were again: a set of Rivian pickups and SUVs rumbling over the West Texas landscape to greet the recently returned astronauts. (The electric vehicles were tucked in among a few other pickup trucks and SUVs made by Ford — which also owns more than 10 percent of Rivian.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CrcqTB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10662656"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6ljI34"&gt;The Rivians — likely on loan, due to the fact that they’re still wearing manufacturer plates — weren’t just there for the sake of the broadcast, either. At one point, Blue Origin used the &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/07/08/rivians-camp-kitchen-in-action/"&gt;slide-out camping kitchen&lt;/a&gt; on a pair of Rivian pickups to cook up sausages and carne asada for guests attending the launch — an optional feature that the startup has promoted a lot in the run-up to production. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G5icsb"&gt;Blue Origin is a private company, and much like Virgin Galactic — which launched founder Richard Branson &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/11/22572374/richard-branson-virgin-galactic-space-unity"&gt;to the edge of space&lt;/a&gt; less than two weeks ago — this first mission was as much about promotion as it was about science or exploration. But while Branson’s event had a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/11/22572374/richard-branson-virgin-galactic-space-unity"&gt;music festival vibe&lt;/a&gt;, Blue Origin’s was more in line with Bezos’ notorious calculation. It was a chance for him to promote the things he plans to spend his time on now that he’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/5/22563671/andy-jassy-amazon-ceo-jeff-bezos"&gt;no longer Amazon CEO&lt;/a&gt;, like his space company and his &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/9/22321793/jeff-bezos-earth-fund-new-president-ceo"&gt;climate fund&lt;/a&gt;, and to toss a bone to the electric vehicle company that Amazon has dumped a bunch of money into. Perhaps the only surprising thing is that the delivery van Rivian is building for Amazon wasn’t there, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="LgV6GY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Rivian already has plenty of money — but it is planning an IPO&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2bGwLB"&gt;It’s not like Rivian, which recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/16/22580293/rivian-delay-september-deliveries-electric-pickup-r1t-amazon"&gt;delayed the first deliveries of its pickup truck and SUV to later this year&lt;/a&gt;, really &lt;em&gt;needs &lt;/em&gt;the attention. The startup has already raised more than $8 billion to date. Rivian has also already proven adept at coming up with &lt;a href="https://www.caranddriver.com/news/a33548089/rivian-r1t-electric-pickup-long-way-up-tv/"&gt;its own effective cross-promotions&lt;/a&gt;. But Rivian &lt;em&gt;is &lt;/em&gt;currently in the process of &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-05-28/electric-truck-maker-rivian-is-said-to-select-ipo-underwriters?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;preparing an initial public offering&lt;/a&gt;, so it’s possible this display of corporate synergy plays right into the hands of the bankers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m3En8Y"&gt;The commercialization of the space industry has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/11/20981714/spacex-commercial-spaceflight-space-industry-decade-nasa-business"&gt;been happening for a while&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s really ramped up in recent years as companies like Blue Origin, Virgin Galactic, and Elon Musk’s SpaceX matured. These companies have set out to dominate everything from the “boring” tasks like cargo runs and science missions to the riskier endeavors like strapping people inside a spaceship. They’ve realized the value of the eyeballs these missions attract, too. After all, before SpaceX launched the first humans to space from United States soil last year, those astronauts also took a promotional ride to the rocket — &lt;a href="https://electrek.co/2020/05/13/tesla-model-x-new-official-vehicle-transport-nasa-astronauts-spacex/#"&gt;in a Tesla Model X&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JYphGo"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Additional reporting by Joey Roulette. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="tgi3nm"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ve71jJ"&gt;Related: &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id="hC8F4a"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Watch Jeff Bezos launch into space and back on Blue Origin's New Shepard rocket|103083" data-volume-uuid="b36ac2f07" data-volume-id="103083" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-72" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22587043/jeff-bezos-space-blue-origin-rivian-electric-truck"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22587043/jeff-bezos-space-blue-origin-rivian-electric-truck</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T14:08:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T14:08:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>Jeff Bezos eyes space as a new ‘sacrifice zone’  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Jeff Bezos’ Blue Origin New Shepard Space Vehicle Flies The Billionaire And Other Passengers To Space" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CWbi8sK0ejk0rmkxLfl1MYKhsp0=/0x6:3000x2006/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69612961/1329731025.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;VAN HORN, TEXAS - JULY 20: Jeff Bezos walks near Blue Origin’s New Shepard after flying into space on July 20, 2021 in Van Horn, Texas. Mr. Bezos and the crew that flew with him were the first human spaceflight for the company. | Photo by Joe Raedle/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2rRQWd"&gt;After Jeff Bezos’ brief &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22582735/blue-origin-jeff-bezos-space-launch-landing"&gt;escape from&lt;/a&gt; Earth yesterday, the founder of retail giant Amazon had an idea. “We need to take all heavy industry, all polluting industry, and move it into space and keep Earth as this beautiful gem of a planet that it is,” he said in an &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/science/science-news/jeff-bezos-says-spaceflight-reinforced-commitment-solving-climate-chan-rcna1467"&gt;interview with NBC News&lt;/a&gt;. “That’s going to take decades to achieve, but you have to start. And big things start with small steps.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="9qnqiI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Long before rich, white men were catapulting themselves into space, they approached whatever was the “frontier” at the time with dollar signs in their eyes and destruction in their wake&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="e7dafJ"&gt;Big things do start with small steps, but this particular idea is a big step backward. Jetting up to space to manufacture stuff in zero gravity is a &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/jeff-bezos-we-need-to-move-all-polluting-industry-into-1847328711"&gt;logistical nightmare with astronomical costs&lt;/a&gt;, to say the least. And it’s not actually a very innovative plan. Sticking unwanted stuff in a place that’s seemingly out of sight, out of mind is a tired idea. It’s the same old mindset that has dumped industrial waste on colonized peoples and neighborhoods of color for centuries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8q61p2"&gt;Long before rich, white men were catapulting themselves into space, they approached whatever was the “frontier” at the time with dollar signs in their eyes and destruction in their wake. As a result today, land sacred to the Shoshone and Paiute tribes was designated a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/28/17765538/san-onofre-nuclear-generating-station-radioactive-spent-fuel-waste-yucca-mountain"&gt;nuclear dump site&lt;/a&gt; in Nevada. A rural stretch of land along the Mississippi River, where formerly enslaved people and their descendants made their homes, became &lt;a href="https://news.un.org/en/story/2021/03/1086172"&gt;Louisiana’s “Cancer Alley”&lt;/a&gt; after more than 150 refineries and petrochemical facilities moved in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HP6y5v"&gt;Their land and homes became “sacrifice zones” for industry and Western development, environmental justice advocates often say. As Amazon’s founder, Bezos is responsible for the creation of new “sacrifice zones” for his retail empire’s warehouses. Those still need to be addressed — maybe he could start there, before creating any new ones in space?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uz1W2R"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;You know what's also amazing? Paying taxes, treating workers with dignity &amp;amp; taking stock of one's carbon footprint as floods &amp;amp; fires rage. For too long, frontline communities have been the sacrifice zones for the excesses of rich. Our communities need real climate action NOW. &lt;a href="https://t.co/C080jaO9U5"&gt;https://t.co/C080jaO9U5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— GGJ (@ggjalliance) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ggjalliance/status/1417557915389419520?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 20, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ReFRXh"&gt;Speaking personally, Amazon now has a huge footprint in the region where I grew up, California’s “Inland Empire.” When I was a kid there, the place was still sort of the badlands of Los Angeles — a potential pitstop for city and beach town dwellers on their drive through the desert to Las Vegas. It was a place that was out of sight and out of mind for the Bezoses of the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1rB54R"&gt;Now the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21611862/satellite-images-online-shopping-growing-footprint-warehouses"&gt;region is increasingly dominated by retail warehouses&lt;/a&gt; that butt up against peoples’ houses and are magnets for polluting trucks and planes. The Inland Empire has some of the &lt;a href="https://grist.org/justice/san-bernardino-county-california-air-pollution-logistics-industry/"&gt;worst air pollution in the nation&lt;/a&gt;. Amazon is its biggest private employer in the region, and it’s faced pressure from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266225/jeff-bezos-climate-change-earth-fund-amazon-pollution"&gt;residents&lt;/a&gt; and its own &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453516/amazon-workers-pollution-petition-letter-demand"&gt;employees&lt;/a&gt; to clean up its act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3TStmB"&gt;“Every time I see one of those [Amazon] trucks with a smiley face on it, it feels like it’s taunting people,” says Adrian Martinez, a senior attorney with the nonprofit organization Earthjustice. Earthjustice currently represents environmental groups that have filed suit against the developer of a new air cargo logistics center in the Inland Empire that &lt;a href="https://www.sbsun.com/2021/04/28/amazon-begins-operations-at-san-bernardino-airport-hub/"&gt;houses Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="An Amazon Prime truck drives into the BNSF rail yard. The rail yard sits across the street from a soccer field and community center in San Bernardino, California and attracts a steady stream of truck traffic." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8uSIAx1bDnFaHyUh5qtgQHIZ9-Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22731194/IMG_1488.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Justine Calma / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An Amazon Prime truck drives into the BNSF rail yard across the street from a soccer field and community center in San Bernardino, California.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="IjKGcH"&gt;Amazon and Bezos have both made splashy &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/23/21300427/amazon-climate-change-commitments-greenhouse-gas-emissions-jeff-bezos"&gt;pledges to combat climate change&lt;/a&gt;. But the residents Martinez represents are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266225/jeff-bezos-climate-change-earth-fund-amazon-pollution"&gt;still breathing in Amazon’s pollution&lt;/a&gt;. “That’s what they are, they’re pledges. And I think I’ll feel a lot more confident when I see zero emission trucks rolling through the neighborhoods of my clients,” Martinez says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7jurjA"&gt;People like Martinez aren’t asking Bezos, Amazon, or other corporate polluters to move their pollution into space. They’re asking for things like more &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/19/20873947/amazon-electric-delivery-van-rivian-jeff-bezos-order"&gt;electric delivery vehicles&lt;/a&gt; on the road, a much lighter lift than figuring out how to expand industry in space. They’re asking for the pollution to stop in the first place, and for billionaires to stop engineering new “sacrifice zones.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="1a5Vn5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Jeff Bezos appreciates your efforts to get Jeff Bezos to space ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585470/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-space-amazon-customers"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id="rLC9VO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Walmart, Ikea, and Amazon have a dirty shipping problem ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22584335/ikea-amazon-walmart-shipping-emissions-climate-change"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="AOmrrd"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="gjkDP4"&gt;Related:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id="PAMECt"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Watch Jeff Bezos launch into space and back on Blue Origin's New Shepard rocket|103083" data-volume-uuid="b36ac2f07" data-volume-id="103083" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-290" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22587249/jeff-bezos-space-pollution-industry-sacrifice-zone-amazon-environmental-justice"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22587249/jeff-bezos-space-pollution-industry-sacrifice-zone-amazon-environmental-justice</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T13:23:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T13:23:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>Alexa finally gets a masculine-sounding voice option</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eWzPn1Dd31yriz53CqGjX-jtMac=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69612703/dseifert_201025_4263_0002.0.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xk1l0q"&gt;Amazon has quietly started rolling out a new &lt;a href="https://assets.aboutamazon.com/fa/c1/7a7f256f4a8d8905a253bf234cf6/traffic.wav"&gt;masculine-sounding voice option&lt;/a&gt; to its Alexa virtual assistant along with a similarly masculine-sounding wake word to trigger the assistant: “Ziggy.” (The odd choice of name is presumably to fit into Amazon’s love of “A to Z”-style branding.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ITORBH"&gt;The new voice option was actually added several days ago alongside an announcement for new celebrity voices like Shaq and Melissa McCarthy, but it went largely unnoticed until it was &lt;a href="https://www.the-ambient.com/news/alexa-male-voice-now-available-ziggy-2675"&gt;spotted by &lt;em&gt;The Ambient&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. You can hear a sample of the new voice option &lt;a href="https://assets.aboutamazon.com/fa/c1/7a7f256f4a8d8905a253bf234cf6/traffic.wav"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ddqlDt"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A new voice for Amazon’s digital assistant&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zjqck0"&gt;The “Ziggy” wake word joins the existing “Alexa,” “Computer,” “Echo,” and “Amazon” wake words that have already been available to use with Alexa for years. Amazon isn’t specifically associating “Alexa” with the feminine-sounding voice and “Ziggy” with the new masculine-sounding option; users can use either of the voice options with any of the wake words. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9QO80c"&gt;You can switch between the two voice options — which Amazon refers to as “Original” and “New” — by asking Alexa to “Change your voice,” and you can similarly select a new wake word by asking it to “Change your wake word.” The change seems to be device-specific, though, so you’ll have to set the new voice on each of your Alexa devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cmUuRs"&gt;Amazon has been a holdout when it comes to offering a masculine-sounding voice option for its digital assistant; Apple and Google offer multiple voice options for Siri and Google Assistant, respectively. Neither of those companies associates specific voices with gender anymore, either: Apple’s Siri options are presented as “Voice 1” and “Voice 2,” while Google’s voice options are listed under a variety of colors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/s43rj90HfgzAuy2Y_Rv8vbH4iB0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22731112/Image_from_iOS__1_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon’s new “Alexa’s Voice” setting menu.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jX_gyj_41v1nGKvcxnAhOoBndBs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22731104/Image_from_iOS.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can now choose between the “Original” feminine-sounding voice and the “New” masculine-sounding option.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="v1fle9"&gt;Amazon has only offered its feminine-sounding option since the Echo was first introduced back in 2013. And while &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/12/us/alexa-bots-female-voice.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;New York Times &lt;/em&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt; that Alexa will respond to questions about gender by replying “I’m not a woman or a man, I’m an AI,” Amazon itself still tends to refer to the Alexa personality using gendered “she” and “her” pronouns in &lt;a href="https://press.aboutamazon.com/contact-pr"&gt;its documentation&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JHGkTQ"&gt;That’s despite that same documentation emphasizing that Alexa is not “a person with a physical body or a gender identity” and that “Amazon doesn’t let organizations (for example, skills or AVS) refer to Alexa as ‘she’ or ‘her.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UVpXRk"&gt;The new masculine-sounding Alexa voice option is reportedly only available in the US for now, but it will presumably be making its way to other regions soon. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22587130/alexa-masculine-voice-gender-ziggy-amazon-smart-assistant"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22587130/alexa-masculine-voice-gender-ziggy-amazon-smart-assistant</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T13:12:37-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T13:12:37-04:00</updated>
    <title>‘PlugWalkJoe’ arrested in connection with 2020 hack of famous Twitter accounts</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/A2oj96oEEcSERl5_AYH9Lalh8hY=/0x2:2048x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69612639/VRG_ILLO_1777_twitter_bitcoin_verified.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Grayson Blackmon / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Ubzir0"&gt;Joseph O’Connor, a 22-year-old UK citizen who goes by the handle “PlugWalkJoe,” was arrested in Spain on Wednesday for his connection to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/15/21326200/elon-musk-bill-gates-twitter-hack-bitcoin-scam-compromised"&gt;the 2020 Twitter hack&lt;/a&gt; that compromised the accounts of former President Barack Obama and Elon Musk, and ran off with over $100,000 in Bitcoin. In &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/man-arrested-connection-alleged-role-twitter-hack"&gt;a press release announcing the arrest&lt;/a&gt;, the US Justice Department writes that O’Connor is also being charged with “computer intrusions related to takeovers of TikTok and Snapchat user accounts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zgsl2C"&gt;O’Connor was arrested on multiple counts of conspiring to and illegally accessing computers without authorization, and “with the intent to extort from a person a thing of value, transmitting a communication containing a threat,” among several other charges, the Justice Department writes. According to &lt;a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/07/whos-behind-wednesdays-epic-twitter-hack/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Krebs on Security&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, O’Connor was a well-known sim-swapper, a method of hijacking valuable social media accounts by manipulating cellular network employees to duplicate phone numbers so hackers can intercept two-factor authorization requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="dpdRrH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“They can come arrest me. I would laugh at them. I haven’t done anything.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tfXbdt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/17/technology/twitter-hackers-interview.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=Top%20Stories&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage"&gt;In an interview for &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;conducted with several of the hackers associated with the Twitter breach, O’Connor openly identified himself as “PlugWalkJoe” and confirmed that the hackers had obtained Twitter credentials to take over the accounts via an internal company Slack. At the time, O’Connor was fairly bullish about his involvement and apparent safety, “They can come arrest me. I would laugh at them. I haven’t done anything,” he told the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BlUaD8"&gt;Today’s arrest is just the latest in the fallout from the breach. Graham Ivan Clark, the “teenage mastermind” of the entire plan, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/31/21349920/twitter-hack-arrest-florida-teen-fbi-irs-secret-service"&gt;was arrested alongside&lt;/a&gt; Nima “Rolex” Fazeli and Mason “Chaewon” Sheppard in July last year. Clark has since been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334421/twitter-hacker-bitcoin-plea-deal-agreement-graham-ivan-clark-three-years"&gt;sentenced to three years in prison&lt;/a&gt; for his role in the hack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="nBXCkJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Twitter’s massive attack: What we know after Apple, Biden, Obama, Musk, and others tweeted a bitcoin scam ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/15/21326200/elon-musk-bill-gates-twitter-hack-bitcoin-scam-compromised"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22587022/twitter-hack-2020-man-arrested-uk-spain"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22587022/twitter-hack-2020-man-arrested-uk-spain</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T13:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Clubhouse is no longer invite-only</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TKHB35Lk5kjnpFYyCfpHrJUOluc=/1x0:4000x2666/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69612529/clubhousenewlogo.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Clubhouse&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XV6Gcb"&gt;Clubhouse is going wide. Co-founders Paul Davison and Rohan Seth announced today that the app is no longer invite-only. Around 10 million people are currently on the waitlist, a spokesperson confirms, and they’ll slowly be added to the app over time. (Essentially, millions of users won’t be added today, but seemingly, if you attempt to sign up anew, you’ll be able to do so.) Along with the news, Clubhouse showed off a new logo, as well as a new app icon: Justin “Meezy” Williams, rapper 21 Savage’s manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u5U2C6"&gt;“The invite system has been an important part of our early history,” a blog post about the changes says. “By adding people in waves, welcoming new faces each week in our Wednesday Orientations, and talking with the community each Sunday in Town Hall, we’ve been able to grow Clubhouse in a measured way, and keep things from breaking as we’ve scaled.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SYazJs"&gt;This change comes only a week after Clubhouse &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22576771/clubhouse-dm-backchannel-update-message"&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt; its DM product, Backchannel, which the team now says saw 10 million messages sent within the first day of launch, and more than 90 million over the first week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j8U9Mp"&gt;Of course, the app opening up comes amid increasing competition. As Clubhouse built out its product and acquired a waitlist, other social audio products, like Twitter Spaces, opened to everyone. If Clubhouse wants to compete, and keep acquiring new users, it’ll have to make sure everyone can actually access it. Part of that journey was bringing the app to Android, in addition to iOS, and now it’s completed the second major step, which is removing any gating around new user signup.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586845/clubhouse-open-beta-invite-access-android-ios"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586845/clubhouse-open-beta-invite-access-android-ios</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T12:24:13-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T12:24:13-04:00</updated>
    <title>WHO head cheers Olympic ‘hope’ as COVID-19 cases in athletes’ village rise</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Before the Tokyo Olympics" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rQzk6Q-vEXHQ-jWGH9UjbrVvUHE=/0x223:6633x4645/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69612289/1234022012.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Michael Kappeler/picture alliance via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jVJpmA"&gt;Olympic athletes in Tokyo continue to test positive for COVID-19 &lt;a href="https://gtimg.tokyo2020.org/image/upload/production/rbhzrrsabvocck506t2s.pdf"&gt;by the dozens&lt;/a&gt;, the United States gymnastics team &lt;a href="https://nypost.com/2021/07/20/u-s-womens-gymnastics-team-bolts-olympic-village/?utm_source=NYPTwitter&amp;amp;utm_campaign=SocialFlow&amp;amp;utm_medium=SocialFlow"&gt;left the Olympic Village&lt;/a&gt; for a hotel in an attempt to avoid the virus, and the chief of the games’ organizing committee said there &lt;a href="https://www.espn.com/olympics/story/_/id/31847805/tokyo-2020-organizing-committee-chief-rule-cancellation-summer-olympics"&gt;could still be a last-minute cancellation&lt;/a&gt;. Still, the head of the World Health Organization said Wednesday that the Tokyo Olympics could “inspire” and “bring the world together.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nzp9LH"&gt;“It is my sincere hope the Tokyo Games succeed,” said WHO director-general Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus on Wednesday. He said it was impossible to expect zero cases of COVID-19, and that the most important thing would be to isolate people, contact trace, and stop the virus from spreading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="t78KYz"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;"Beyond competition, medals &amp;amp; records, the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Tokyo2020?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Tokyo2020&lt;/a&gt; Games bring the nations of the   together in celebration of sport, health, excellence, friendship &amp;amp; respect. But ultimately, they are a celebration of something that our   needs now, more than ever:     "-&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DrTedros?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@DrTedros&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— World Health Organization (WHO) (@WHO) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WHO/status/1417654668776415235?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 21, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jXwzQ3"&gt;His optimism around the games stands in contrast to the Japanese medical community, which has called for the Olympics &lt;a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/world/olympics-tokyo-covid-19-1.6032206"&gt;to be canceled&lt;/a&gt;. COVID-19 cases are rising in Japan, and only around a third of medical providers are vaccinated. The games offer a chance for the virus to spread and are a risk to the health of the athletes and people in the community. Still, it’s a risk the WHO seems to think is reasonable to take, even as Ghebreyesus said that governments should commit to public health measures in the face of rising case counts. “If we throw caution to the wind, it will blow back in our faces,” he &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WHO/status/1417650711203139593"&gt;also said Wednesday&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v3CJLO"&gt;The WHO has a close relationship with the International Olympic Committee that stretches back decades. The two groups signed their first memorandum of understanding &lt;a href="https://olympics.com/ioc/news/ioc-and-who-strengthen-ties-to-advocate-healthy-lifestyles"&gt;in 1984&lt;/a&gt;. They reaffirmed that partnership in a &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news/item/07-01-2011-who-and-the-international-olympic-committee-sign-agreement-to-improve-healthy-lifestyles"&gt;2010&lt;/a&gt; memorandum focused on promoting healthy lifestyles, and signed another &lt;a href="https://olympics.com/ioc/news/ioc-and-who-strengthen-ties-to-advocate-healthy-lifestyles"&gt;in 2020&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LoSbBq"&gt;Experts worried about the relationship ahead of the 2016 Rio de Janeiro Olympics, which were held as the Zika virus — which the WHO called a Public Health Emergency of International Concern — spread through Brazil. A group of physicians called for the games to be moved or rescheduled and said &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/to-your-health/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2016/05/Zika-Olympics-Open-Letter-to-WHO-current2.pdf?itid=lk_inline_manual_17"&gt;in an open letter&lt;/a&gt; that they did not feel the WHO was appropriately assessing the risks of the virus. “We are concerned that WHO is rejecting these alternatives because of a conflict of interest,” the letter read. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B91Pk7"&gt;The WHO’s support of the Tokyo Olympics also creates the appearance of conflict, wrote MacIntosh Ross, an assistant professor of sports management at Western University in Canada, &lt;a href="https://theconversation.com/the-who-and-the-ioc-are-playing-with-lives-at-state-of-emergency-tokyo-olympics-164291"&gt;in &lt;em&gt;The Conversation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The stakes of holding the games during a pandemic are high for people in Japan, but the IOC stands to benefit financially if they go ahead, he wrote — and &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/business-health-coronavirus-pandemic-olympic-games-2020-tokyo-olympics-dd49a7aaaa6c59defea9670c5b19475c"&gt;lose billions&lt;/a&gt; if they don’t. It’s disconcerting to have even the suggestion that the WHO’s concerns aren’t first with the community in Tokyo. Yet, Ross adds: “When the IOC and WHO support a global mega-event held during a pandemic, it’s difficult to believe that the well-being of the host nation remains a priority.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RaHFvD"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586773/who-olympics-tokyo-ioc-covid"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586773/who-olympics-tokyo-ioc-covid</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon will let devs compete for your Echo Show’s screen and everything else Alexa just added</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AD75v4DQ6ctAAUWJk9-vczmNpZ0=/0x25:1404x961/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69612096/alexa_widgets.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="I6uOeH"&gt;Amazon’s Alexa devices are &lt;em&gt;ambient&lt;/em&gt; computers, not the kind you use all day. When you&lt;em&gt; do&lt;/em&gt; ask your Echo a question or glance at your Echo Show’s diminutive screen, the voice assistant only has a brief chance to impress. Today, Amazon is announcing it’s going to give more of those opportunities to third-party developers — including brand-new widgets and featured skill cards that might take up a chunk of your smart speaker’s precious real estate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e0exM6"&gt;Here’s what to expect from those and everything else the company’s announcing at its Alexa Live event today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LYKWVP"&gt;As you can see in Amazon’s mockup above, &lt;strong&gt;widgets&lt;/strong&gt; look pretty much as you might expect. In a blog post, Amazon describes them as “rich, customizable, glanceable, self-updating views of skill content” where you can check items off a to-do list or activate a skill’s functions, without needing to say “Alexa” first. It’s not yet clear how limited they are or if they might effectively be a way to build a touchscreen app for an Echo Show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="IOG98N"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Developers don’t have to pay for Amazon’s Alexa skill ads&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FltnSl"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Featured skill cards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;might be slightly controversial, depending on how useful they are. It promotes new Alexa skills on your home screen, even if you haven’t asked for them. It’s not exactly an advertising service, Amazon Alexa Skills VP Aaron Rubenson tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, not something developers will have to pay for. “It’s open to everybody to raise their hand and say they want to be part of it,” he says, adding that you’ll see personalized results based on other signals you send Alexa. One of the first featured skill cards will be Comedy Central, and Rubenson says he might well see it because he already listens to some comedy in his Alexa Flash Briefing each morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0HRWZ4"&gt;But even if you don’t have an Echo device with a screen, you may get more Alexa skills suggested to you soon. Amazon says it’s expanding its &lt;strong&gt;name-free interaction toolkit&lt;/strong&gt; to let skills volunteer to be promoted when you speak phrases like “Alexa, how did the Nasdaq do today?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QC1ejr"&gt;“We’re letting developers raise their hand and say, ‘My skill can handle that request,’” says Rubenson. And if you agree to use Amazon’s suggested skills, Alexa can pass along your request instead of making you repeat yourself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="u0CTe7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Here’s Alexa with the upsell&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OoyLQe"&gt;While Amazon was the only one that previously profited from physical merchandise sold through Alexa, the company will now let Alexa skill developers sell products inside their skills as well with &lt;strong&gt;Alexa shopping actions&lt;/strong&gt; and get up to a 10 percent affiliate marketing commission from Amazon, too. As expected, you can only sell products listed on Amazon.com, though they don’t need to be &lt;em&gt;your &lt;/em&gt;products. (Rubenson couldn’t say whether Amazon would allow skills that are effectively just stores.) Amazon’s also introducing &lt;strong&gt;paid skills&lt;/strong&gt;, so don’t be surprised if you have to pay before using your next Alexa app instead of using an in-app purchase afterward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="QpKP39"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NiJwyTOeCUk?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Wd7wiV"&gt;While Amazon &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/9/21429893/amazon-voice-interoperability-initiative-alexa-apple-google-samsung"&gt;still doesn’t&lt;/a&gt; seem to have attracted rivals Apple, Google, and Samsung to its voice interoperability initiative yet, it does have some news on that front as well. Rubenson says Samsung will have a fridge with both Bixby and Alexa “operating side by side,” and the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22231336/amazon-alexa-auto-ai-custom-digital-assistants-car-makers"&gt;Alexa Custom Assistant&lt;/a&gt; (which lets brands create their own Alexa-powered assistant) will appear in a Verizon smart display where Alexa can handle standard Alexa tasks while the new Verizon assistant can handle requests like checking your wireless bill. Rubenson says they can hand off requests to each other, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dyItDb"&gt;In addition to those highlights, here’s a quick bulleted list of other Alexa updates that caught my eye:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="Cndhyo"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Food Skill APIs&lt;/strong&gt; for “high-quality, food delivery and pickup experiences.” Domino’s Pizza will use it at some point; here’s an example:&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HIIL-sZQWvFpFJM8tcRPCVkT2CY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22731013/dominos.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="eGpyId"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Send to Phone &lt;/strong&gt;where “customers can start an experience on their Alexa-enabled device, and continue it on their mobile phone.”&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;McDonald’s UK, Twitter, Husqvarna, Iberia Airlines, Cookpad, and Lysol will connect their mobile apps with Alexa skills.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="bhCFMC"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wqyDeG5MnF4?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="V8vlG2"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Event-Based Triggers and Proactive Suggestions: &lt;/strong&gt;“For example, if a customer is heading out for work, customers could opt in to have a skill proactively suggest that they lock their home.” Whole Foods will launch a “curbside pickup experience” later this year.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="T9hBJt"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Later this year, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WholeFoods?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@WholeFoods&lt;/a&gt; will launch a proactive curbside pickup experience using event-based triggers and proactive suggestions. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AlexaLive?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#AlexaLive&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/AHSBXhOIvS"&gt;pic.twitter.com/AHSBXhOIvS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Alexa Developers (@alexadevs) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/alexadevs/status/1417881122436960256?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 21, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="ieiJeO"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Find My&lt;/strong&gt; is opening up the “Alexa, Find my” command to more companies with Tile-like device trackers, with Samsung and Remote+ arriving later this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DXu8MJ"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Alexa Device Discovery&lt;/strong&gt; will be able to discover new categories of devices like printers and smart TVs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="w62W6S"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Alexa Entities&lt;/strong&gt; now lets any skill developer access Alexa’s knowledge graph for general answers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="ulXl4r"&gt;That’s not the whole list, mind you: there’s even more &lt;a href="https://developer.amazon.com/en-US/blogs/alexa/alexa-skills-kit/2021/07/more-than-50-features-to-build-ambient-experiences"&gt;in Amazon’s full blog post&lt;/a&gt;. In addition, Amazon is announcing today that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22350418"&gt;almost every Echo smart speaker will support Matter&lt;/a&gt;, a new ambitious open standard for smart home devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sbKUM0"&gt;The new features are all coming as part of the company’s Alexa Live developer conference today, where it’s seeking to attract the next generation of programmers to build skills for its voice assistant. Amazon says it now has 900,000 registered developers and 130,000 skills (&lt;a href="https://developer.amazon.com/en-US/blogs/alexa/alexa-skills-kit/2020/07/enter-the-alexa-skills-challenge-alexa-conversations-to-compete-for-over-100-000-in-prizes"&gt;up from 750,000 developers&lt;/a&gt; a year ago and &lt;a href="https://developer.amazon.com/en-US/blogs/alexa/alexa-skills-kit/2019/09/congratulations-alexa-skill-builders-100-000-skills-and-counting"&gt;100,000 skills&lt;/a&gt; in September 2019), and Rubenson tells us developer revenue has doubled annually, with some skill developers  making over $1 million a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jge0Q1"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, 1:04 PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added a link to Amazon’s &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://developer.amazon.com/en-US/blogs/alexa/alexa-skills-kit/2021/07/more-than-50-features-to-build-ambient-experiences"&gt;&lt;em&gt;full blog post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, and some embedded videos.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KwSKiw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586033/amazon-alexa-widgets-featured-skill-api-developers-echo-show-screen"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586033/amazon-alexa-widgets-featured-skill-api-developers-echo-show-screen</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon promises most Echo speakers will get upgraded to Matter</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QkrgAO4AVmcTN-XMsprK1FImHAY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69612111/dseifert_201020_4247_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TU44j8"&gt;Amazon, Apple, Google, Samsung, and dozens of other firms have agreed to try to make setting up smart homes easier &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/11/22430666/matter-project-chip-smart-home-partnership-apple-amazon-google-zigbee"&gt;with Matter&lt;/a&gt;, a cross-platform open-source standard coming later this year. Now, Amazon has revealed the scope of its initial commitment: it will be upgrading almost every plug-in Echo smart speaker to support Matter, including most Echo and Echo Dot speakers and every Echo Studio, Echo Show, Echo Plus, and Echo Flex. &lt;br&gt;In fact, the only Echo smart speakers that won’t get upgraded to Matter are the first-gen Echo, first-gen Echo Dot and Echo Tap, a rep tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JMi5bn"&gt;While the company doesn’t provide a timeline for those upgrades, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22387252/project-chip-will-finally-ship-later-this-year"&gt;the general idea is that Matter will launch by late 2021&lt;/a&gt;, so it shouldn’t be long until Amazon’s newest and / or more popular devices receive the capability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wZ33I9"&gt;A bigger question is whether any of them will work as Matter hubs. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22193059/eero-pro-6-review-mesh-router-wifi-6-test-speeds-network"&gt;Google announced in May&lt;/a&gt; that in addition to upgrading its Nest devices to Matter, it would allow its devices that support the Thread protocol (like the Nest Wi-Fi, Nest Hub Max, and second-gen Nest Hub) to double as connection hubs for Matter, too, not simply as a voice assistant to control Matter gadgets. But while Amazon’s Eero routers were early to adopt Thread, Amazon’s Echo smart speakers were not. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="fywzZA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Amazon will let devs compete for your Echo Show’s screen and everything else Alexa just added","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586033/amazon-alexa-widgets-featured-skill-api-developers-echo-show-screen"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="F4WF0n"&gt;The announcement comes as part of Amazon’s Alexa Live developer event today, where it’s revealing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22350074"&gt;quite a few additional things that Alexa devs will soon be able to do&lt;/a&gt;. The company has a message for Matter developers: “We will soon be rolling out tools that make it easy for you to build Matter certified devices, and are ready to start testing your Matter devices now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WHqmr8"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586377/amazon-echo-matter-standard-dot-show-studio-flex-plus-upgrade"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586377/amazon-echo-matter-standard-dot-show-studio-flex-plus-upgrade</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
