<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-07-21T14:08:24-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T14:08:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T14:08:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>Jeff Bezos eyes space as a new ‘sacrifice zone’  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Jeff Bezos’ Blue Origin New Shepard Space Vehicle Flies The Billionaire And Other Passengers To Space" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CWbi8sK0ejk0rmkxLfl1MYKhsp0=/0x6:3000x2006/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69612961/1329731025.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;VAN HORN, TEXAS - JULY 20: Jeff Bezos walks near Blue Origin’s New Shepard after flying into space on July 20, 2021 in Van Horn, Texas. Mr. Bezos and the crew that flew with him were the first human spaceflight for the company. | Photo by Joe Raedle/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2rRQWd"&gt;After Jeff Bezos’ brief &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22582735/blue-origin-jeff-bezos-space-launch-landing"&gt;escape from&lt;/a&gt; Earth yesterday, the founder of retail giant Amazon had an idea. “We need to take all heavy industry, all polluting industry, and move it into space and keep Earth as this beautiful gem of a planet that it is,” he said in an &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/science/science-news/jeff-bezos-says-spaceflight-reinforced-commitment-solving-climate-chan-rcna1467"&gt;interview with NBC News&lt;/a&gt;. “That’s going to take decades to achieve, but you have to start. And big things start with small steps.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="9qnqiI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Long before rich, white men were catapulting themselves into space, they approached whatever was the “frontier” at the time with dollar signs in their eyes and destruction in their wake&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="e7dafJ"&gt;Big things do start with small steps, but this particular idea is a big step backward. Jetting up to space to manufacture stuff in zero gravity is a &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/jeff-bezos-we-need-to-move-all-polluting-industry-into-1847328711"&gt;logistical nightmare with astronomical costs&lt;/a&gt;, to say the least. And it’s not actually a very innovative plan. Sticking unwanted stuff in a place that’s seemingly out of sight, out of mind is a tired idea. It’s the same old mindset that has dumped industrial waste on colonized peoples and neighborhoods of color for centuries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8q61p2"&gt;Long before rich, white men were catapulting themselves into space, they approached whatever was the “frontier” at the time with dollar signs in their eyes and destruction in their wake. As a result today, land sacred to the Shoshone and Paiute tribes was designated a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/28/17765538/san-onofre-nuclear-generating-station-radioactive-spent-fuel-waste-yucca-mountain"&gt;nuclear dump site&lt;/a&gt; in Nevada. A rural stretch of land along the Mississippi River, where formerly enslaved people and their descendants made their homes, became &lt;a href="https://news.un.org/en/story/2021/03/1086172"&gt;Louisiana’s “Cancer Alley”&lt;/a&gt; after more than 150 refineries and petrochemical facilities moved in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HP6y5v"&gt;Their land and homes became “sacrifice zones” for industry and Western development, environmental justice advocates often say. As Amazon’s founder, Bezos is responsible for the creation of new “sacrifice zones” for his retail empire’s warehouses. Those still need to be addressed — maybe he could start there, before creating any new ones in space?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uz1W2R"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;You know what's also amazing? Paying taxes, treating workers with dignity &amp;amp; taking stock of one's carbon footprint as floods &amp;amp; fires rage. For too long, frontline communities have been the sacrifice zones for the excesses of rich. Our communities need real climate action NOW. &lt;a href="https://t.co/C080jaO9U5"&gt;https://t.co/C080jaO9U5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— GGJ (@ggjalliance) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ggjalliance/status/1417557915389419520?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 20, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ReFRXh"&gt;Speaking personally, Amazon now has a huge footprint in the region where I grew up, California’s “Inland Empire.” When I was a kid there, the place was still sort of the badlands of Los Angeles — a potential pitstop for city and beach town dwellers on their drive through the desert to Las Vegas. It was a place that was out of sight and out of mind for the Bezoses of the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1rB54R"&gt;Now the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21611862/satellite-images-online-shopping-growing-footprint-warehouses"&gt;region is increasingly dominated by retail warehouses&lt;/a&gt; that butt up against peoples’ houses and are magnets for polluting trucks and planes. The Inland Empire has some of the &lt;a href="https://grist.org/justice/san-bernardino-county-california-air-pollution-logistics-industry/"&gt;worst air pollution in the nation&lt;/a&gt;. Amazon is its biggest private employer in the region, and it’s faced pressure from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266225/jeff-bezos-climate-change-earth-fund-amazon-pollution"&gt;residents&lt;/a&gt; and its own &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453516/amazon-workers-pollution-petition-letter-demand"&gt;employees&lt;/a&gt; to clean up its act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3TStmB"&gt;“Every time I see one of those [Amazon] trucks with a smiley face on it, it feels like it’s taunting people,” says Adrian Martinez, a senior attorney with the nonprofit organization Earthjustice. Earthjustice currently represents environmental groups that have filed suit against the developer of a new air cargo logistics center in the Inland Empire that &lt;a href="https://www.sbsun.com/2021/04/28/amazon-begins-operations-at-san-bernardino-airport-hub/"&gt;houses Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="An Amazon Prime truck drives into the BNSF rail yard. The rail yard sits across the street from a soccer field and community center in San Bernardino, California and attracts a steady stream of truck traffic." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8uSIAx1bDnFaHyUh5qtgQHIZ9-Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22731194/IMG_1488.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Justine Calma / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;An Amazon Prime truck drives into the BNSF rail yard across the street from a soccer field and community center in San Bernardino, California.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="IjKGcH"&gt;Amazon and Bezos have both made splashy &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/23/21300427/amazon-climate-change-commitments-greenhouse-gas-emissions-jeff-bezos"&gt;pledges to combat climate change&lt;/a&gt;. But the residents Martinez represents are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266225/jeff-bezos-climate-change-earth-fund-amazon-pollution"&gt;still breathing in Amazon’s pollution&lt;/a&gt;. “That’s what they are, they’re pledges. And I think I’ll feel a lot more confident when I see zero emission trucks rolling through the neighborhoods of my clients,” Martinez says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7jurjA"&gt;People like Martinez aren’t asking Bezos, Amazon, or other corporate polluters to move their pollution into space. They’re asking for things like more &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/19/20873947/amazon-electric-delivery-van-rivian-jeff-bezos-order"&gt;electric delivery vehicles&lt;/a&gt; on the road, a much lighter lift than figuring out how to expand industry in space. They’re asking for the pollution to stop in the first place, and for billionaires to stop engineering new “sacrifice zones.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="1a5Vn5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Jeff Bezos appreciates your efforts to get Jeff Bezos to space ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22585470/jeff-bezos-blue-origin-space-amazon-customers"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id="rLC9VO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Walmart, Ikea, and Amazon have a dirty shipping problem ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/20/22584335/ikea-amazon-walmart-shipping-emissions-climate-change"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="AOmrrd"&gt;
&lt;h3 id="gjkDP4"&gt;Related:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id="PAMECt"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Watch Jeff Bezos launch into space and back on Blue Origin's New Shepard rocket|103083" data-volume-uuid="b36ac2f07" data-volume-id="103083" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-290" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22587249/jeff-bezos-space-pollution-industry-sacrifice-zone-amazon-environmental-justice"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22587249/jeff-bezos-space-pollution-industry-sacrifice-zone-amazon-environmental-justice</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T13:23:57-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T13:23:57-04:00</updated>
    <title>Alexa finally gets a masculine-sounding voice option</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eWzPn1Dd31yriz53CqGjX-jtMac=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69612703/dseifert_201025_4263_0002.0.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xk1l0q"&gt;Amazon has quietly started rolling out a new &lt;a href="https://assets.aboutamazon.com/fa/c1/7a7f256f4a8d8905a253bf234cf6/traffic.wav"&gt;masculine-sounding voice option&lt;/a&gt; to its Alexa virtual assistant along with a similarly masculine-sounding wake word to trigger the assistant: “Ziggy.” (The odd choice of name is presumably to fit into Amazon’s love of “A to Z”-style branding.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ITORBH"&gt;The new voice option was actually added several days ago alongside an announcement for new celebrity voices like Shaq and Melissa McCarthy, but it went largely unnoticed until it was &lt;a href="https://www.the-ambient.com/news/alexa-male-voice-now-available-ziggy-2675"&gt;spotted by &lt;em&gt;The Ambient&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. You can hear a sample of the new voice option &lt;a href="https://assets.aboutamazon.com/fa/c1/7a7f256f4a8d8905a253bf234cf6/traffic.wav"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ddqlDt"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A new voice for Amazon’s digital assistant&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zjqck0"&gt;The “Ziggy” wake word joins the existing “Alexa,” “Computer,” “Echo,” and “Amazon” wake words that have already been available to use with Alexa for years. Amazon isn’t specifically associating “Alexa” with the feminine-sounding voice and “Ziggy” with the new masculine-sounding option; users can use either of the voice options with any of the wake words. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9QO80c"&gt;You can switch between the two voice options — which Amazon refers to as “Original” and “New” — by asking Alexa to “Change your voice,” and you can similarly select a new wake word by asking it to “Change your wake word.” The change seems to be device-specific, though, so you’ll have to set the new voice on each of your Alexa devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cmUuRs"&gt;Amazon has been a holdout when it comes to offering a masculine-sounding voice option for its digital assistant; Apple and Google offer multiple voice options for Siri and Google Assistant, respectively. Neither of those companies associates specific voices with gender anymore, either: Apple’s Siri options are presented as “Voice 1” and “Voice 2,” while Google’s voice options are listed under a variety of colors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/s43rj90HfgzAuy2Y_Rv8vbH4iB0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22731112/Image_from_iOS__1_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon’s new “Alexa’s Voice” setting menu.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jX_gyj_41v1nGKvcxnAhOoBndBs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22731104/Image_from_iOS.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can now choose between the “Original” feminine-sounding voice and the “New” masculine-sounding option.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="v1fle9"&gt;Amazon has only offered its feminine-sounding option since the Echo was first introduced back in 2013. And while &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/12/us/alexa-bots-female-voice.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;New York Times &lt;/em&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt; that Alexa will respond to questions about gender by replying “I’m not a woman or a man, I’m an AI,” Amazon itself still tends to refer to the Alexa personality using gendered “she” and “her” pronouns in &lt;a href="https://press.aboutamazon.com/contact-pr"&gt;its documentation&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JHGkTQ"&gt;That’s despite that same documentation emphasizing that Alexa is not “a person with a physical body or a gender identity” and that “Amazon doesn’t let organizations (for example, skills or AVS) refer to Alexa as ‘she’ or ‘her.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UVpXRk"&gt;The new masculine-sounding Alexa voice option is reportedly only available in the US for now, but it will presumably be making its way to other regions soon. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22587130/alexa-masculine-voice-gender-ziggy-amazon-smart-assistant"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22587130/alexa-masculine-voice-gender-ziggy-amazon-smart-assistant</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T13:12:37-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T13:12:37-04:00</updated>
    <title>‘PlugWalkJoe’ arrested in connection with 2020 hack of famous Twitter accounts</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/A2oj96oEEcSERl5_AYH9Lalh8hY=/0x2:2048x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69612639/VRG_ILLO_1777_twitter_bitcoin_verified.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Grayson Blackmon / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Ubzir0"&gt;Joseph O’Connor, a 22-year-old UK citizen who goes by the handle “PlugWalkJoe,” was arrested in Spain on Wednesday for his connection to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/15/21326200/elon-musk-bill-gates-twitter-hack-bitcoin-scam-compromised"&gt;the 2020 Twitter hack&lt;/a&gt; that compromised the accounts of former President Barack Obama and Elon Musk, and ran off with over $100,000 in Bitcoin. In &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/man-arrested-connection-alleged-role-twitter-hack"&gt;a press release announcing the arrest&lt;/a&gt;, the US Justice Department writes that O’Connor is also being charged with “computer intrusions related to takeovers of TikTok and Snapchat user accounts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zgsl2C"&gt;O’Connor was arrested on multiple counts of conspiring to and illegally accessing computers without authorization, and “with the intent to extort from a person a thing of value, transmitting a communication containing a threat,” among several other charges, the Justice Department writes. According to &lt;a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/07/whos-behind-wednesdays-epic-twitter-hack/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Krebs on Security&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, O’Connor was a well-known sim-swapper, a method of hijacking valuable social media accounts by manipulating cellular network employees to duplicate phone numbers so hackers can intercept two-factor authorization requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="dpdRrH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“They can come arrest me. I would laugh at them. I haven’t done anything.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tfXbdt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/17/technology/twitter-hackers-interview.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=Top%20Stories&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage"&gt;In an interview for &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;conducted with several of the hackers associated with the Twitter breach, O’Connor openly identified himself as “PlugWalkJoe” and confirmed that the hackers had obtained Twitter credentials to take over the accounts via an internal company Slack. At the time, O’Connor was fairly bullish about his involvement and apparent safety, “They can come arrest me. I would laugh at them. I haven’t done anything,” he told the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BlUaD8"&gt;Today’s arrest is just the latest in the fallout from the breach. Graham Ivan Clark, the “teenage mastermind” of the entire plan, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/31/21349920/twitter-hack-arrest-florida-teen-fbi-irs-secret-service"&gt;was arrested alongside&lt;/a&gt; Nima “Rolex” Fazeli and Mason “Chaewon” Sheppard in July last year. Clark has since been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334421/twitter-hacker-bitcoin-plea-deal-agreement-graham-ivan-clark-three-years"&gt;sentenced to three years in prison&lt;/a&gt; for his role in the hack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="nBXCkJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Twitter’s massive attack: What we know after Apple, Biden, Obama, Musk, and others tweeted a bitcoin scam ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/15/21326200/elon-musk-bill-gates-twitter-hack-bitcoin-scam-compromised"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22587022/twitter-hack-2020-man-arrested-uk-spain"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22587022/twitter-hack-2020-man-arrested-uk-spain</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T13:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Clubhouse is no longer invite-only</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TKHB35Lk5kjnpFYyCfpHrJUOluc=/1x0:4000x2666/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69612529/clubhousenewlogo.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Clubhouse&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XV6Gcb"&gt;Clubhouse is going wide. Co-founders Paul Davison and Rohan Seth announced today that the app is no longer invite-only. Around 10 million people are currently on the waitlist, a spokesperson confirms, and they’ll slowly be added to the app over time. (Essentially, millions of users won’t be added today, but seemingly, if you attempt to sign up anew, you’ll be able to do so.) Along with the news, Clubhouse showed off a new logo, as well as a new app icon: Justin “Meezy” Williams, rapper 21 Savage’s manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u5U2C6"&gt;“The invite system has been an important part of our early history,” a blog post about the changes says. “By adding people in waves, welcoming new faces each week in our Wednesday Orientations, and talking with the community each Sunday in Town Hall, we’ve been able to grow Clubhouse in a measured way, and keep things from breaking as we’ve scaled.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SYazJs"&gt;This change comes only a week after Clubhouse &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22576771/clubhouse-dm-backchannel-update-message"&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt; its DM product, Backchannel, which the team now says saw 10 million messages sent within the first day of launch, and more than 90 million over the first week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j8U9Mp"&gt;Of course, the app opening up comes amid increasing competition. As Clubhouse built out its product and acquired a waitlist, other social audio products, like Twitter Spaces, opened to everyone. If Clubhouse wants to compete, and keep acquiring new users, it’ll have to make sure everyone can actually access it. Part of that journey was bringing the app to Android, in addition to iOS, and now it’s completed the second major step, which is removing any gating around new user signup.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586845/clubhouse-open-beta-invite-access-android-ios"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586845/clubhouse-open-beta-invite-access-android-ios</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T12:24:13-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T12:24:13-04:00</updated>
    <title>WHO head cheers Olympic ‘hope’ as COVID-19 cases in athletes’ village rise</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Before the Tokyo Olympics" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rQzk6Q-vEXHQ-jWGH9UjbrVvUHE=/0x223:6633x4645/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69612289/1234022012.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Michael Kappeler/picture alliance via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jVJpmA"&gt;Olympic athletes in Tokyo continue to test positive for COVID-19 &lt;a href="https://gtimg.tokyo2020.org/image/upload/production/rbhzrrsabvocck506t2s.pdf"&gt;by the dozens&lt;/a&gt;, the United States gymnastics team &lt;a href="https://nypost.com/2021/07/20/u-s-womens-gymnastics-team-bolts-olympic-village/?utm_source=NYPTwitter&amp;amp;utm_campaign=SocialFlow&amp;amp;utm_medium=SocialFlow"&gt;left the Olympic Village&lt;/a&gt; for a hotel in an attempt to avoid the virus, and the chief of the games’ organizing committee said there &lt;a href="https://www.espn.com/olympics/story/_/id/31847805/tokyo-2020-organizing-committee-chief-rule-cancellation-summer-olympics"&gt;could still be a last-minute cancellation&lt;/a&gt;. Still, the head of the World Health Organization said Wednesday that the Tokyo Olympics could “inspire” and “bring the world together.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nzp9LH"&gt;“It is my sincere hope the Tokyo Games succeed,” said WHO director-general Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus on Wednesday. He said it was impossible to expect zero cases of COVID-19, and that the most important thing would be to isolate people, contact trace, and stop the virus from spreading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="t78KYz"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;"Beyond competition, medals &amp;amp; records, the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Tokyo2020?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Tokyo2020&lt;/a&gt; Games bring the nations of the   together in celebration of sport, health, excellence, friendship &amp;amp; respect. But ultimately, they are a celebration of something that our   needs now, more than ever:     "-&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DrTedros?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@DrTedros&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— World Health Organization (WHO) (@WHO) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WHO/status/1417654668776415235?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 21, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jXwzQ3"&gt;His optimism around the games stands in contrast to the Japanese medical community, which has called for the Olympics &lt;a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/world/olympics-tokyo-covid-19-1.6032206"&gt;to be canceled&lt;/a&gt;. COVID-19 cases are rising in Japan, and only around a third of medical providers are vaccinated. The games offer a chance for the virus to spread and are a risk to the health of the athletes and people in the community. Still, it’s a risk the WHO seems to think is reasonable to take, even as Ghebreyesus said that governments should commit to public health measures in the face of rising case counts. “If we throw caution to the wind, it will blow back in our faces,” he &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WHO/status/1417650711203139593"&gt;also said Wednesday&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v3CJLO"&gt;The WHO has a close relationship with the International Olympic Committee that stretches back decades. The two groups signed their first memorandum of understanding &lt;a href="https://olympics.com/ioc/news/ioc-and-who-strengthen-ties-to-advocate-healthy-lifestyles"&gt;in 1984&lt;/a&gt;. They reaffirmed that partnership in a &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news/item/07-01-2011-who-and-the-international-olympic-committee-sign-agreement-to-improve-healthy-lifestyles"&gt;2010&lt;/a&gt; memorandum focused on promoting healthy lifestyles, and signed another &lt;a href="https://olympics.com/ioc/news/ioc-and-who-strengthen-ties-to-advocate-healthy-lifestyles"&gt;in 2020&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LoSbBq"&gt;Experts worried about the relationship ahead of the 2016 Rio de Janeiro Olympics, which were held as the Zika virus — which the WHO called a Public Health Emergency of International Concern — spread through Brazil. A group of physicians called for the games to be moved or rescheduled and said &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/to-your-health/wp-content/uploads/sites/26/2016/05/Zika-Olympics-Open-Letter-to-WHO-current2.pdf?itid=lk_inline_manual_17"&gt;in an open letter&lt;/a&gt; that they did not feel the WHO was appropriately assessing the risks of the virus. “We are concerned that WHO is rejecting these alternatives because of a conflict of interest,” the letter read. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B91Pk7"&gt;The WHO’s support of the Tokyo Olympics also creates the appearance of conflict, wrote MacIntosh Ross, an assistant professor of sports management at Western University in Canada, &lt;a href="https://theconversation.com/the-who-and-the-ioc-are-playing-with-lives-at-state-of-emergency-tokyo-olympics-164291"&gt;in &lt;em&gt;The Conversation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The stakes of holding the games during a pandemic are high for people in Japan, but the IOC stands to benefit financially if they go ahead, he wrote — and &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/business-health-coronavirus-pandemic-olympic-games-2020-tokyo-olympics-dd49a7aaaa6c59defea9670c5b19475c"&gt;lose billions&lt;/a&gt; if they don’t. It’s disconcerting to have even the suggestion that the WHO’s concerns aren’t first with the community in Tokyo. Yet, Ross adds: “When the IOC and WHO support a global mega-event held during a pandemic, it’s difficult to believe that the well-being of the host nation remains a priority.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RaHFvD"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586773/who-olympics-tokyo-ioc-covid"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586773/who-olympics-tokyo-ioc-covid</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon will let devs compete for your Echo Show’s screen and everything else Alexa just added</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AD75v4DQ6ctAAUWJk9-vczmNpZ0=/0x25:1404x961/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69612096/alexa_widgets.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="I6uOeH"&gt;Amazon’s Alexa devices are &lt;em&gt;ambient&lt;/em&gt; computers, not the kind you use all day. When you&lt;em&gt; do&lt;/em&gt; ask your Echo a question or glance at your Echo Show’s diminutive screen, the voice assistant only has a brief chance to impress. Today, Amazon is announcing it’s going to give more of those opportunities to third-party developers — including brand-new widgets and featured skill cards that might take up a chunk of your smart speaker’s precious real estate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e0exM6"&gt;Here’s what to expect from those and everything else the company’s announcing at its Alexa Live event today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LYKWVP"&gt;As you can see in Amazon’s mockup above, &lt;strong&gt;widgets&lt;/strong&gt; look pretty much as you might expect. In a blog post, Amazon describes them as “rich, customizable, glanceable, self-updating views of skill content” where you can check items off a to-do list or activate a skill’s functions, without needing to say “Alexa” first. It’s not yet clear how limited they are or if they might effectively be a way to build a touchscreen app for an Echo Show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="IOG98N"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Developers don’t have to pay for Amazon’s Alexa skill ads&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FltnSl"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Featured skill cards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;might be slightly controversial, depending on how useful they are. It promotes new Alexa skills on your home screen, even if you haven’t asked for them. It’s not exactly an advertising service, Amazon Alexa Skills VP Aaron Rubenson tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, not something developers will have to pay for. “It’s open to everybody to raise their hand and say they want to be part of it,” he says, adding that you’ll see personalized results based on other signals you send Alexa. One of the first featured skill cards will be Comedy Central, and Rubenson says he might well see it because he already listens to some comedy in his Alexa Flash Briefing each morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0HRWZ4"&gt;But even if you don’t have an Echo device with a screen, you may get more Alexa skills suggested to you soon. Amazon says it’s expanding its &lt;strong&gt;name-free interaction toolkit&lt;/strong&gt; to let skills volunteer to be promoted when you speak phrases like “Alexa, how did the Nasdaq do today?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QC1ejr"&gt;“We’re letting developers raise their hand and say, ‘My skill can handle that request,’” says Rubenson. And you agree to use Amazon’s suggested skills, Alexa can pass along your request instead of making you repeat yourself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="u0CTe7"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Here’s Alexa with the upsell&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OoyLQe"&gt;While Amazon was the only one that previously profited from physical merchandise sold through Alexa, the company will now let Alexa skill developers sell products inside their skills as well with &lt;strong&gt;Alexa shopping actions&lt;/strong&gt; and get up to a 10 percent affiliate marketing commission from Amazon, too. As expected, you can only sell products listed on Amazon.com, though they don’t need to be &lt;em&gt;your &lt;/em&gt;products. (Rubenson couldn’t say whether Amazon would allow skills that are effectively just stores.) Amazon’s also introducing &lt;strong&gt;paid skills&lt;/strong&gt;, so don’t be surprised if you have to pay before using your next Alexa app instead of using an in-app purchase afterward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="QpKP39"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NiJwyTOeCUk?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Wd7wiV"&gt;While Amazon &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/9/21429893/amazon-voice-interoperability-initiative-alexa-apple-google-samsung"&gt;still doesn’t&lt;/a&gt; seem to have attracted rivals Apple, Google, and Samsung to its voice interoperability initiative yet, it does have some news on that front as well. Rubenson says Samsung will have a fridge with both Bixby and Alexa “operating side by side,” and the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22231336/amazon-alexa-auto-ai-custom-digital-assistants-car-makers"&gt;Alexa Custom Assistant&lt;/a&gt; (which lets brands create their own Alexa-powered assistant) will appear in a Verizon smart display where Alexa can handle standard Alexa tasks while the new Verizon assistant can handle requests like checking your wireless bill. Rubenson says they can hand off requests to each other, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dyItDb"&gt;In addition to those highlights, here’s a quick bulleted list of other Alexa updates that caught my eye:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="Cndhyo"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Food Skill APIs&lt;/strong&gt; for “high-quality, food delivery and pickup experiences.” Domino’s Pizza will use it at some point; here’s an example:&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HIIL-sZQWvFpFJM8tcRPCVkT2CY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22731013/dominos.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="eGpyId"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Send to Phone &lt;/strong&gt;where “customers can start an experience on their Alexa-enabled device, and continue it on their mobile phone.”&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;McDonald’s UK, Twitter, Husqvarna, Iberia Airlines, Cookpad, and Lysol will connect their mobile apps with Alexa skills.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="bhCFMC"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wqyDeG5MnF4?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="V8vlG2"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Event-Based Triggers and Proactive Suggestions: &lt;/strong&gt;“For example, if a customer is heading out for work, customers could opt in to have a skill proactively suggest that they lock their home.” Whole Foods will launch a “curbside pickup experience” later this year.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="T9hBJt"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Later this year, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WholeFoods?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@WholeFoods&lt;/a&gt; will launch a proactive curbside pickup experience using event-based triggers and proactive suggestions. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AlexaLive?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#AlexaLive&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/AHSBXhOIvS"&gt;pic.twitter.com/AHSBXhOIvS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Alexa Developers (@alexadevs) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/alexadevs/status/1417881122436960256?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 21, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="ieiJeO"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Find My&lt;/strong&gt; is opening up the “Alexa, Find my” command to more companies with Tile-like device trackers, with Samsung and Remote+ arriving later this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DXu8MJ"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Alexa Device Discovery&lt;/strong&gt; will be able to discover new categories of devices like printers and smart TVs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="w62W6S"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Alexa Entities&lt;/strong&gt; now lets any skill developer access Alexa’s knowledge graph for general answers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="ulXl4r"&gt;That’s not the whole list, mind you: there’s even more &lt;a href="https://developer.amazon.com/en-US/blogs/alexa/alexa-skills-kit/2021/07/more-than-50-features-to-build-ambient-experiences"&gt;in Amazon’s full blog post&lt;/a&gt;. In addition, Amazon is announcing today that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22350418"&gt;almost every Echo smart speaker will support Matter&lt;/a&gt;, a new ambitious open standard for smart home devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sbKUM0"&gt;The new features are all coming as part of the company’s Alexa Live developer conference today, where it’s seeking to attract the next generation of programmers to build skills for its voice assistant. Amazon says it now has 900,000 registered developers and 130,000 skills (&lt;a href="https://developer.amazon.com/en-US/blogs/alexa/alexa-skills-kit/2020/07/enter-the-alexa-skills-challenge-alexa-conversations-to-compete-for-over-100-000-in-prizes"&gt;up from 750,000 developers&lt;/a&gt; a year ago and &lt;a href="https://developer.amazon.com/en-US/blogs/alexa/alexa-skills-kit/2019/09/congratulations-alexa-skill-builders-100-000-skills-and-counting"&gt;100,000 skills&lt;/a&gt; in September 2019), and Rubenson tells us developer revenue has doubled annually, with some skill developers  making over $1 million a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jge0Q1"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, 1:04 PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added a link to Amazon’s &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://developer.amazon.com/en-US/blogs/alexa/alexa-skills-kit/2021/07/more-than-50-features-to-build-ambient-experiences"&gt;&lt;em&gt;full blog post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, and some embedded videos.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KwSKiw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586033/amazon-alexa-widgets-featured-skill-api-developers-echo-show-screen"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586033/amazon-alexa-widgets-featured-skill-api-developers-echo-show-screen</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon promises most Echo speakers will get upgraded to Matter</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QkrgAO4AVmcTN-XMsprK1FImHAY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69612111/dseifert_201020_4247_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TU44j8"&gt;Amazon, Apple, Google, Samsung, and dozens of other firms have agreed to try to make setting up smart homes easier &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/11/22430666/matter-project-chip-smart-home-partnership-apple-amazon-google-zigbee"&gt;with Matter&lt;/a&gt;, a cross-platform open-source standard coming later this year. Now, Amazon has revealed the scope of its initial commitment: it will be upgrading almost every plug-in Echo smart speaker to support Matter, including most Echo and Echo Dot speakers and every Echo Studio, Echo Show, Echo Plus, and Echo Flex. &lt;br&gt;In fact, the only Echo smart speakers that won’t get upgraded to Matter are the first-gen Echo, first-gen Echo Dot and Echo Tap, a rep tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JMi5bn"&gt;While the company doesn’t provide a timeline for those upgrades, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22387252/project-chip-will-finally-ship-later-this-year"&gt;the general idea is that Matter will launch by late 2021&lt;/a&gt;, so it shouldn’t be long until Amazon’s newest and / or more popular devices receive the capability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wZ33I9"&gt;A bigger question is whether any of them will work as Matter hubs. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22193059/eero-pro-6-review-mesh-router-wifi-6-test-speeds-network"&gt;Google announced in May&lt;/a&gt; that in addition to upgrading its Nest devices to Matter, it would allow its devices that support the Thread protocol (like the Nest Wi-Fi, Nest Hub Max, and second-gen Nest Hub) to double as connection hubs for Matter, too, not simply as a voice assistant to control Matter gadgets. But while Amazon’s Eero routers were early to adopt Thread, Amazon’s Echo smart speakers were not. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F4WF0n"&gt;The announcement comes as part of Amazon’s Alexa Live developer event today, where it’s revealing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22350074"&gt;quite a few additional things that Alexa devs will soon be able to do&lt;/a&gt;. The company has a message for Matter developers: “We will soon be rolling out tools that make it easy for you to build Matter certified devices, and are ready to start testing your Matter devices now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WHqmr8"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586377/amazon-echo-matter-standard-dot-show-studio-flex-plus-upgrade"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586377/amazon-echo-matter-standard-dot-show-studio-flex-plus-upgrade</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Instagram can now automatically translate text in stories</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cowE-gK2yqAGL61897lqaM_6SWQ=/2x0:1535x1022/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69612103/Press__2_.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;When a foreign language is detected, an option to ‘See Translation’ now appears.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Instagram&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZJw1zO"&gt;Instagram is adding a new option to automatically translate text in story posts, the company announced today. Now, when the service detects a foreign language in a post, it will display a “See Translation” option on the top left of the screen, which users can tap to see a translation at the bottom. Instagram says the new translation feature will be available globally, and currently supports over 90 languages to make sharing content with an international audience easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YD3OkQ"&gt;The feature, whose development was previously reported by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/alex193a/status/1407835245781585926"&gt;app researcher Alessandro Paluzzi&lt;/a&gt;, means there’s now parity between Instagram stories and traditional posts. In 2016, Instagram added &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/6/23/12011008/instagram-text-translation-comments-in-app"&gt;automatic translations to comments, captions, and user bios&lt;/a&gt; but failed to include the feature with stories &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/8/2/12348354/instagram-stories-announced-snapchat-kevin-systrom-interview"&gt;which launched a month later&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3fe5KF"&gt;Although the new feature can translate text, Instagram says audio translation isn’t available “at this time.” Although given Instagram rolled out automatic captioning &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22417837/instagram-captions-sticker-stories-accessibility"&gt;for English stories in May&lt;/a&gt;, it doesn’t seem outside of the realms of possibility that it might one day be able to translate audio as well.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586568/instagram-stories-text-translation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586568/instagram-stories-text-translation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix’s Masters of the Universe erases the past to chart a new future</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HabPKxMLWg-ct_Als1Nb4srET_w=/282x0:3318x2024/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69611738/MastersoftheUniverse_Revelation_Part1_Episode5_00_19_39_05.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Atxnj3"&gt;Part of what made &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/15/18097423/she-ra-netflix-interview-reboot-noelle-stevenson-showrunner-nimona-lumberjanes"&gt;&lt;em&gt;She-Ra and the Princesses of Power&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;so good was the way it completely reimagined the classic cartoon. It was still set in a magical realm with talking horses and evil robot armies, but it took an old show — which, if we’re being honest, was created for the express purpose of selling toys — and gave its characters and world some real depth and meaning. It was funny and exciting, heartbreaking and beautiful, without a toy commercial in sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gu7p0e"&gt;On the surface, &lt;em&gt;Masters of the Universe: Revelation&lt;/em&gt;, which stars She-Ra’s long-lost twin brother He-Man, isn’t quite so exciting. It’s not a reboot but a direct sequel, one that’s meant to pick up right after the original cartoon ended in 1985. It has the same cast of characters, some of which are pretty goofy, like a wimpy battle cat and an alien sorcerer with self-esteem problems. Skeletor (now played by Mark Hamill) remains a gigantic dork. Yet, thanks to a bold decision early on, the show manages to become something that almost feels new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hln5Bw"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big spoilers for &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Masters of the Universe: Revelation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; ahead.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T3njnr"&gt;Because it’s a direct sequel, &lt;em&gt;Revelation&lt;/em&gt; wastes no time in setting things up. Immediately Skeletor is in the midst of a plan to destroy Castle Grayskull in order to reveal its true power so that he can harness it for himself. Unfortunately, his attack has the potential side effect of not only destroying the planet of Eternia, but also all of existence. The ensuing battle between the two iconic leads largely removes them from the story, and shifts the focus to other characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Js1lTH"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iXdEeRBh9Zk?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="SvCjtP"&gt;It’s a dramatic shift, and from there &lt;em&gt;Revelation&lt;/em&gt; resembles something of a post-apocalyptic fantasy wasteland. The story fast-forwards a few years when Teela (Sarah Michelle Gellar), a former royal guard, is now a scavenger, making a living by scrounging for old bits of tech and items imbued with magic. There’s a strange cult that worships technology, and, without Skeletor to lead them, Eternia’s many villains have scattered. Eventually, Teela learns that the planet is slowly dying as its magic leaks away, so she reluctantly sets about setting things right. It’s one of those epic quests that involves traveling to both heaven and hell, and pulling together a group of misfits to help you do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0IzWE3"&gt;This premise lets the show mostly get away from the Saturday morning cartoon vibe of the original, while still keeping the same characters and world. Eternia remains an interesting mix of sci-fi, swords, and sorcery, as if Frank Frazetta and Ralph McQuarrie had a jam session. Killer robots fight alongside beast men, and sword-wielding warriors ride mechanical horses and armored cats into battle. Things have a bit more of a &lt;em&gt;Mad Max&lt;/em&gt; vibe this time around, with villages fighting over the last drops of magic while the techno-cult terrorizes them. In addition, Teela has a new job as a mercenary, Man-at-Arms (Liam Cunningham) has become an Obi-Wan-style hermit, and Evil-Lyn (Lena Headey) is left confused without a dictator to support. They all end up joining forces in the quest.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-DQaDgFV6v9PQYlFVR7TLfTtNbs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22728252/MastersoftheUniverse_Revelation_Part1_Episode3_00_01_36_01.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="DGot4P"&gt;It can feel like a reboot, but the show does retain some of the inherent silliness of its predecessor. &lt;em&gt;Revelation&lt;/em&gt;’s writers never met a terrible pun they didn’t like, and characters like the dopey villain Mer-Man and the perpetually terrified Cringer feel out of place in this grittier world. The acting is also uneven. There are some good individual performances — Cunningham adds a welcome gravitas, Headey channels her inner Cersei, and Hamill hams it up as always — but it often sounds like a video game where everyone recorded their lines separately. (There are also a few bizarre jokes, like a “no glove, no love” quip that doesn’t seem appropriate in a PG cartoon.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="taXQ2s"&gt;Because of all of these elements, the show doesn’t feel quite as refreshing or daring as &lt;em&gt;She-Ra&lt;/em&gt;. But for a direct sequel to the original cartoon made to sell toys, its surprisingly modern; the dramatic opening paves the way for a new path even if &lt;em&gt;Revelation&lt;/em&gt; never fully breaks away from its source. What’s available now on Netflix is also only a beginning: the first part of &lt;em&gt;Revelation&lt;/em&gt; is five episodes long, and the final episode suggests there might be even bigger changes in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OXYN4U"&gt;&lt;small&gt;Masters of the Universe: Revelations &lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;will be on Netflix on July 23rd.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AfKClI"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update July 21st, 12:40PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; This review has been updated to remove a specific plot spoiler. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nVzOEX"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JHeUUf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22585095/masters-of-the-universe-revelation-netflix-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22585095/masters-of-the-universe-revelation-netflix-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-07-21T10:30:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-21T10:30:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google gives Pixel 4 XL an extra year of free repairs for power issues</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-adPzqMK7Q5i3AAb7EwEi3NHccw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69611569/vpavic_191016_3730_0029.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verg&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ENwDJK"&gt;If your out-of-warranty Pixel 4 XL has been exhibiting some problems, you might be able to get a free repair. Google recently &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/answer/10169830?hl=en"&gt;posted a support page&lt;/a&gt; outlining a “one-year extended repair program” for the larger of its two 2019 flagships. Those who are eligible can receive a free repair for up to a year after their original warranty expires. As for who’s covered by this program, Google points to “certain power-related issues.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EuqPLc"&gt;More specifically, the company says these are the problems that “may” get a free repair:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="wAVXaX"&gt;A Pixel 4 XL that can’t be powered on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NPYIhX"&gt;The Pixel 4 XL restarts or shuts down randomly without any user action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rGk1L3"&gt;Charging problems with the power adapter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="smPuWr"&gt;Wireless charging issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7lmSNv"&gt;The battery on a Pixel 4 XL is draining “significantly faster than earlier in its use”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="TM5eKI"&gt;That’s a pretty wide spread of potential ways to qualify for the repair program. But Google cautions that if there are other major problems with your phone (like a damaged screen) that “prevent” the complimentary repair, those will have to be fixed first — and for a fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZpK70V"&gt;Pixel 4 XL owners can bring their device to &lt;a href="https://www.ubreakifix.com/locations"&gt;a uBreakiFix store&lt;/a&gt; to see if it qualifies for a free fix. According to &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2021/07/20/google-might-be-extending-your-pixel-4-xls-warranty-for-an-extra-year/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, repair staff at those locations are very familiar with the situation. You can also start the repair process directly with Google to see if your issue is covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JFv7Xm"&gt;The extended repair program is available in the US, Canada, Singapore, Japan, and Taiwan. Google specifies that it does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; apply in Australia, France, Germany, Ireland, Italy, Spain, or the UK. That’s because Pixel 4 XLs purchased in those countries already came with a longer two-year manufacturer’s warranty.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586833/google-pixel-4-xl-extended-repair-program-announced"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/21/22586833/google-pixel-4-xl-extended-repair-program-announced</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
