<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-10-19T22:14:55-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T22:14:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T22:14:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook is planning to rebrand the company with a new name</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fBUh6E31xNvLxZx6U-nbWG7s13k=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70018751/acastro_072121_4674_zuckerberg.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge Photo by Justin Sullivan / Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3BQkSw"&gt;Facebook is planning to change its company name next week to reflect its focus on building the metaverse, according to a source with direct knowledge of the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dN7MdP"&gt;The coming name change, which CEO Mark Zuckerberg plans to talk about at the company’s annual Connect conference on October 28th, but could unveil sooner, is meant to signal the tech giant’s ambition to be known for more than social media and all the ills that entail. The rebrand would likely position the blue Facebook app as one of many products under a parent company overseeing groups like Instagram, WhatsApp, Oculus, and more. A spokesperson for Facebook declined to comment for this story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="roHgyg"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Facebook intends to transition to “being a metaverse company”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fJZxHn"&gt;Facebook already has more than 10,000 employees building consumer hardware like AR glasses that Zuckerberg believes will eventually be as ubiquitous as smartphones. In July, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22588022/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-ceo-metaverse-interview"&gt;he told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that, over the next several years, “we will effectively transition from people seeing us as primarily being a social media company to being a metaverse company.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JSxAWP"&gt;A rebrand could also serve to further separate the futuristic work Zuckerberg is focused on from the intense scrutiny Facebook is currently under for the way its social platform operates today. A former employee turned whistleblower, Frances Haugen, recently leaked a trove of damning internal documents to &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal &lt;/em&gt;and&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/5/22710539/facebook-whistleblower-hearing-instagram-child-safety-congress"&gt;testified about them before Congress&lt;/a&gt;. Antitrust regulators in the US and elsewhere are trying to break the company up, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/6/22702798/verge-tech-survey-2021-trust-privacy-security-facebook-amazon-google-apple-pandemic"&gt;public trust&lt;/a&gt; in how Facebook does business is falling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hB6AhR"&gt;Facebook isn’t the first well-known tech company to change its company name as its ambitions expand. In 2015, Google reorganized entirely under a holding company called Alphabet, partly to signal that it was no longer just a search engine, but a sprawling conglomerate with companies making driverless cars and health tech. And Snapchat rebranded to Snap Inc. in 2016, the same year it started calling itself a “camera company” and debuted its first pair of Spectacles camera glasses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rl2grI"&gt;I’m told that the new Facebook company name is a closely-guarded secret within its walls and not known widely, even among its full senior leadership. A possible name could have something to do with Horizon, the name of the still-unreleased VR version of Facebook-meets-Roblox that the company has been developing for the past few years. The name of that app was recently tweaked to &lt;a href="https://uploadvr.com/facebook-horizon-changes/"&gt;Horizon Worlds&lt;/a&gt; shortly after Facebook demoed a version for workplace collaboration &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/19/22629942/facebook-workrooms-horizon-oculus-vr"&gt;called Horizon Workrooms&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Ww3bJx"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Facebook has been laying the groundwork for a branding change&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PiMXev"&gt;Aside from Zuckerberg’s comments, Facebook has been steadily laying the groundwork for a greater focus on the next generation of technology. This past summer it set up a dedicated metaverse team. More recently, it announced that the head of AR and VR, Andrew Bosworth, will be promoted to chief technology officer. And just a couple of days ago Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/facebook-plans-hire-10000-eu-build-metaverse-2021-10-17/"&gt;announced plans&lt;/a&gt; to hire 10,000 more employees to work on the metaverse in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d7m6rI"&gt;The metaverse is “going to be a big focus, and I think that this is just going to be a big part of the next chapter for the way that the internet evolves after the mobile internet,” Zuckerberg told &lt;em&gt;The Verge’&lt;/em&gt;s Casey Newton&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;this summer. “And I think it’s going to be the next big chapter for our company too, really doubling down in this area.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="av8JCk"&gt;Complicating matters is that, while Facebook has been heavily promoting the idea of the metaverse in recent weeks, it’s still not a concept that’s widely understood. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22701104/metaverse-explained-fortnite-roblox-facebook-horizon"&gt;The term was coined&lt;/a&gt; originally by sci-fi novelist Neal Stephenson to describe a virtual world people escape to from a dystopian, real world. Now it’s being adopted by one of the world’s largest and most controversial companies — and it’ll have to explain why its own virtual world is worth diving into.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735612/facebook-change-company-name-metaverse"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735612/facebook-change-company-name-metaverse</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Heath</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T19:30:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T19:30:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Activision Blizzard is trying to get the discrimination suit thrown out of court</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Activision Blizzard employees stage a walkout in the response from company leadership to a lawsuit highlighting alleged harassment, inequality" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WG-BdiDrd3SmWZfeUX5KmcGmAHI=/10x0:4191x2787/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70018394/1234304012.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Allen J. Schaben / Los Angeles Times via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Zy4EVP"&gt;Activision Blizzard, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22597113/activision-blizzard-california-sexual-harassment-lawsuit-discrimination-employee-action"&gt;facing a discrimination lawsuit from the California Department of Fair Employment and Housing&lt;/a&gt; (or DFEH), has filed an application to stay that lawsuit so it can investigate claims that DFEH lawyers engaged in ethical misconduct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Ib1oil"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/21088626-activision-blizzard-et-als-ex-parte-application-to-stay-the-case/?embed=1&amp;amp;responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="ACTIVISION BLIZZARD, ET AL.'S EX PARTE APPLICATION TO STAY THE CASE (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="905" style="border: 1px solid #aaa; width: 100%; height: 800px; height: calc(100vh - 100px);" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6zB7gp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j7VHZD"&gt;The application claims that the DFEH is represented in the case by lawyers who previously worked for the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (or EEOC)  — a federal agency that investigates claims of workplace abuse. The application additionally claims such an arrangement is in violation of a California State Bar conflict of interest rule that says, “a lawyer who has formerly served as a public official or employee of the government [...] shall not otherwise represent a client in connection with a matter in which the lawyer participated personally and substantially as a public official or employee.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7SPcln"&gt;The application basically alleges that DFEH lawyers should be disqualified from participating in this case against Activision Blizzard since those lawyers previously worked on a similar, prior case against the company when they were employed by the EEOC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="06wp5V"&gt;Activision Blizzard &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22697341/us-eeoc-sues-activision-blizzard-sexual-harassment-discrimination"&gt;recently settled&lt;/a&gt; another discrimination lawsuit brought forth by the EEOC for $18 million. The DFEH is trying to block that settlement, and it’s actually the EEOC that raised ethical concerns against DFEH lawyers (perhaps to maintain its win). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8ahjdh"&gt;“The EEOC claims that two of the DFEH attorneys who have appeared in this case (and who currently ‘play leadership roles within the [DFEH]’) ‘previously served as EEOC [REDACTED],’ during which time they ‘helped to direct the EEOC’s investigation’ against Activision Blizzard,” the application states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7DRnRk"&gt;If the court upholds the stay and decides that DFEH lawyers did violate conflict of interest rules, Activision Blizzard claims the case could be in serious trouble. According to the company’s filing, “Violation of these rules could lead to the disqualification not only of the two attorneys at issue, but of the entire group of DFEH attorneys with whom they have worked. It also calls into question the integrity of the underlying investigation itself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wpZOho"&gt;This move comes just as Blizzard announced 20 employees &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735413/activision-blizzard-employee-terminations-harassment-discrimination"&gt;“exited” the company&lt;/a&gt; in the wake of harassment investigations and reprimanded some 20 more. In the months since these lawsuits were made public, some Blizzard employees have continued to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22598410/activision-blizzard-employee-walk-out-protest-sexism-discrimination-lawsuit"&gt;agitate for a more equitable workplace&lt;/a&gt;, making demands of the company to end forced arbitration and provide greater pay transparency. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZHbSbD"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Our demands remain as follows and chief suite still fails to acknowledge them. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ABetterABK?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#ABetterABK&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/EndAbuseInGaming?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#EndAbuseInGaming&lt;/a&gt;   &lt;a href="https://t.co/4Tk7aV9DjD"&gt;pic.twitter.com/4Tk7aV9DjD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— ABetterABK   ABK Workers Alliance (@ABetterABK) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ABetterABK/status/1433466353726361603?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 2, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KmeZxZ"&gt;The EEOC and the DFEH didn’t immediately respond to requests for comment, and neither the DFEH nor the EEOC have had a chance to formally challenge Activision Blizzard’s claims: neither have filed responses to this application in the courts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RMmKNQ"&gt;A Blizzard spokesperson says of the filings, “We look forward to resolving the case with the DFEH fairly in an appropriate court. We share the EEOC and DFEH’s goal of a safe, inclusive workplace that rewards employees equitably and remain committed to the elimination of harassment and discrimination in our workplace.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="isd4s9"&gt;A hearing on the application will take place October 20th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735273/activision-blizzard-requests-stay-in-harassment-lawsuit-alleging-conflict-of-interest"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735273/activision-blizzard-requests-stay-in-harassment-lawsuit-alleging-conflict-of-interest</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T19:20:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T19:20:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>PSA: the MacBook Pro 14-inch’s $20 power brick upsell is probably worth it</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NIO_tKL0ve33zAqcLcjYg4abcPg=/147x0:1761x1076/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70018348/lcimg_f1ce43fd_90a7_4584_bc4f_63c9935d516b.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dSAcBZ"&gt;If you’re looking at buying the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22724738/apple-macbook-pro-14-inch-features-price-release-date"&gt;$1,999 base model MacBook Pro 14-inch&lt;/a&gt;, there’s one upgrade that you may really want to make — the $20 one that gets you the 96W power adapter instead of the 67W included power adapter. That’s because, according to some wording on &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/buy-mac/macbook-pro/14-inch-space-gray-8-core-cpu-14-core-gpu-512gb#"&gt;Apple’s MacBook Pro configuration page&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/10/19/apple-67w-adapter-cant-fast-charge/"&gt;spotted by &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), you’ll need the more powerful charger if you want to take advantage of the computer’s fast charging feature, which can charge the laptop up to 50 percent in half an hour. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="om07HD"&gt;Is it ridiculous that Apple is basically taxing the people who want to buy its least expensive (but still very pricey!) new MacBook Pro? Yes, absolutely — but you should still probably pay it if you want to charge your laptop up quickly. The exception is if you already have a charging brick capable of 100W USB-PD power delivery: Apple tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that you can fast charge via Thunderbolt as long as your power brick provides enough power. If you already have a beefy power brick, you can skip the upsell.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MVvDLva6vYe47MyboXqOnpcfEkM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22940510/Screen_Shot_2021_10_19_at_3.41.14_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This may be the best $20 you can spend on an accessory for your new MacBook Pro.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="qZIY2O"&gt;I know it probably doesn’t feel great to encourage Apple’s nickel-and-diming, but if you want fast charging, this will likely be the best way to get it. There may be, somewhere in the world, a 100W USB-PD charging brick that sells for $20, but there’s no way I would trust it enough to charge a very expensive computer. (If it was $20, I might not even trust it not to burn down my house). I’d pick the upsell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CjWk18"&gt;The one silver lining is that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733119/apple-new-macbook-pro-magsafe-back"&gt;this is only a problem on the base 8 CPU core / 14 GPU core model&lt;/a&gt; — if you do any processor upgrades, you’ll get the 96W brick for “free.” Please note, though, that upgrading just the RAM and/or storage on the base MacBook Pro won’t get you that upgrade, but if you’re in the configuration screen anyways, you should absolutely check that box unless you hate fast charging.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22735545/macbook-pro-14-base-model-usb-c-adapter-upgrade"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22735545/macbook-pro-14-base-model-usb-c-adapter-upgrade</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T18:47:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T18:47:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s Pixel 6 doesn’t come with five years of Android updates — only three</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nSPoNXX5eOm7F6oh4iKbTkaetyA=/152x0:1768x1077/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70018216/qMm7BP1Fye.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VerlUH"&gt;For the first time ever, Google’s new phones &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22710844/google-pixel-6-pro-tensor-processor-ai-speed-specs-details"&gt;are powered by a Google-designed chip&lt;/a&gt;, giving the company an Apple-like level of control over the inner workings of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22731034/google-pixel-6-pro-price-specs-features-release-date-hands-on"&gt;the new Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro.&lt;/a&gt; But if you were hoping that meant they’d also get an Apple-like level of new OS updates, the company is throwing a bit of cold water on that. &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/answer/4457705#zippy=%2Cpixel-xl-a-a-xl-xl-a-a-g-a-g%2Cpixel-pixel-pro-phones"&gt;Google’s support page shows it’s only promising&lt;/a&gt; to offer Android updates through October 2024 (via &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/google-pixel-6-three-years-os-updates-five-years-security-patches/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;), &lt;/em&gt;a total of three years after release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l4ikZY"&gt;“Users will still get at least 3 years of OS updates, after which we’re committing to ensure that Pixels will stay up-to-date and secure,” Google tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “The frequency and categories of updates will depend on the capabilities and needs of the hardware.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7M9vCk"&gt;While Google prominently announced during its Tuesday keynote that the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro would get five years of &lt;em&gt;security&lt;/em&gt; updates — two years more! — it seems that Android version updates (like Android 11, Android 12, etc) are another story. And though Google is technically saying it will offer new versions of Android until “at least” October 2024, the company hasn’t historically gone above and beyond those sorts of promises. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qv8tNy"&gt;Meanwhile, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/8/22523351/ios-15-iphone-6s-plus-se-compatibility"&gt;the six-year-old iPhone 6S recently got an update to iOS 15&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735485/google-pixel-6-three-years-android-updates-security-feature"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735485/google-pixel-6-three-years-android-updates-security-feature</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T18:19:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T18:19:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>A future update to Facebook’s Portal will stop kids from watching content unsupervised</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Facebook Enters Living Room With Video Chat-Focused TV Box" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SYIaiMdcZYpnobu6AzEss0_7C50=/0x2:3000x2002/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70018131/1169034208.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="B7hcVR"&gt;Facebook is delivering an update to Portal devices that will make it possible to turn off the Watch Together feature during calls in Household Mode. The update comes shortly after&lt;em&gt; a &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/katienotopoulos/facebooks-portal-go-review"&gt;&lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; article criticized Facebook’s blatant oversight of not including an “off” switch for the feature. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wy6TwE"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/14/21433086/facebook-messenger-watch-together-video-messaging"&gt;Watch Together lets you watch shows, music videos, or funny clips&lt;/a&gt; with distant friends or family members. Choose a video from Facebook’s selection, and it’ll be simultaneously presented to you on your Portal and on your friend’s device, whether that may be a phone, tablet, or Portal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ytp59q"&gt;Watch Together may sound like a great idea, but it obviously isn’t ideal for parents who want to keep their kids away from videos on the internet. When a Portal device is in Household Mode, everyone in the house has access to it, and that includes kids. The Watch Together feature remains hidden in Household Mode, but it reappears during calls. This can be a recipe for disaster, as &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/em&gt; noted, since kids can grab ahold of the device, start up a call, and begin watching videos with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JfQNk3"&gt;Right now, there’s no way to disable Watch Together during calls in Household Mode — likely leaving some parents feeling frustrated — but that’s all about to change. In response to the &lt;em&gt;BuzzFeed News&lt;/em&gt; report, Andrew Bosworth, the vice president of Facebook Reality Labs, sent out a tweet that says Facebook is working on a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="k2pXz4"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;All Portal devices are for families to use together and not designed for kids to be used without parental supervision. That said, ask and you shall receive, we are rolling out the ability to turn off Watch Together in calls via Household Mode in December.&lt;/p&gt;— Boz (@boztank) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/boztank/status/1450494485536788485?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 19, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nMNm8E"&gt;Users will get the ability to disable Watch Together during calls in Household Mode in December, but it’s sort of disappointing that it didn’t come with this feature in the first place. It feels like an oversight that could’ve — and should’ve — never happened, especially because Facebook is catering &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22732472/facebook-portal-go-10-inch-2021-review"&gt;the new Portal Go&lt;/a&gt; to kids. If the device is so kid-friendly, why does it require you to have a Facebook account to use it, and why didn’t it come with stricter parental controls out of the box?&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735364/facebook-turn-off-watch-together-during-calls-household-mode"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735364/facebook-turn-off-watch-together-during-calls-household-mode</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T18:16:13-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T18:16:13-04:00</updated>
    <title>Activision Blizzard says 20 employees ‘exited’ as part of harassment investigations</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Activision Blizzard employees stage a walkout in the response from company leadership to a lawsuit highlighting alleged harassment, inequality" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/juGIllfyRRHwaX--E0CGafouQ6c=/110x0:4090x2653/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70018110/1234303856.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Allen J. Schaben / Los Angeles Times via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Bounvc"&gt;Activision Blizzard says more than 20 employees have “exited” the company, and more than 20 other employees have been reprimanded following complaints about misconduct. &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/7cb805b9-4d14-40ee-a1f2-72bc3c3e1ea6"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reported that the company sent a letter to staff on Tuesday with the details, and chief compliance officer Frances Townsend told the outlet that the list included game developers and “a few” supervisors but no members of the board. Activision Blizzard later &lt;a href="https://www.activisionblizzard.com/content/atvi/activisionblizzard/ab-touchui/ab/web/en/newsroom/2021/10/creating-a-more-accountable-workplace.html"&gt;posted the letter online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J8lVxm"&gt;The letter outlines a company attempt to “earn our team’s confidence that, when they speak up, they will be heard” — following a series of lawsuits accusing Activision Blizzard employees of systematic discrimination and gender-based harassment. It says the disciplinary actions followed an increase in reports about incidents that ranged from “years ago to the present.” After investigation, “in connection with various resolved reports, more than 20 individuals have exited Activision Blizzard and more than 20 individuals faced other types of disciplinary action.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FohtNF"&gt;In addition to the terminations and reprimands, Activision Blizzard says it will add 19 full-time employees to its ethics and compliance team (on top of three roles it’s already added) and triple its investment in training resources, echoing public promises to upgrade its compliance with workplace protection laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ra6mxe"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Activision Blizzard promises “additional updates” on reform&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wAPOF8"&gt;Townsend, a former Homeland Security advisor under the George W. Bush administration, apparently told &lt;em&gt;FT&lt;/em&gt; that an investigation had found misconduct across several parts of the company. She said employees were terminated if they exhibited “patterns” of bad behavior that couldn’t be addressed with training. “It doesn’t matter what your rank is, what your job is. If you’ve committed some sort of misconduct or you’re a leader who has tolerated a culture that is not consistent with our values, we’re going to take action,” she told &lt;em&gt;FT&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dJ6uZy"&gt;Activision Blizzard’s workplace problems became widely public in July, when &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22588215/activision-blizzard-lawsuit-sexual-harassment-discrimination-pay"&gt;California’s Department of Fair Employment and Housing (DFEH) sued it&lt;/a&gt; for fostering a culture of “constant sexual harassment” that included groping, derogatory comments, and other conduct that supervisors allegedly knew of or “encouraged.” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22598410/activision-blizzard-employee-walk-out-protest-sexism-discrimination-lawsuit"&gt;Hundreds of employees staged a walkout&lt;/a&gt; to protest its working conditions, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608320/blizard-jesse-meschuk-leave-company-hr-svp"&gt;multiple executives&lt;/a&gt; — including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22607356/blizzard-president-leaving-harassment-protest-brack"&gt;Blizzard president J. Allen Brack&lt;/a&gt; — subsequently left the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5tpshR"&gt;Activision Blizzard &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22697341/us-eeoc-sues-activision-blizzard-sexual-harassment-discrimination"&gt;settled a complaint&lt;/a&gt; from the US Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) last month, but its legal issues remain ongoing. The company is currently seeking a stay in the DFEH case, accusing the agency of ethics violations that compromise its complaint. California’s employment fairness watchdog has, in turn, objected to the EEOC settlement, which it says could allow for the destruction of evidence in its own case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wNkV5F"&gt;Townsend apparently acknowledged to &lt;em&gt;FT&lt;/em&gt; that Activision Blizzard hasn’t met all the demands of protesting employees — who have requested, among other things, an end to mandatory arbitration for harassment complaints. But she said that further changes would be coming, saying that Activision Blizzard’s board and CEO Bobby Kotick had given her a “blank check” for reform. “We are committed to making meaningful and positive change, and this is just the start,” the letter reads. “We will be sharing additional updates in the coming weeks and months.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735413/activision-blizzard-employee-terminations-harassment-discrimination"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735413/activision-blizzard-employee-terminations-harassment-discrimination</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T17:55:56-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T17:55:56-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Google Store is open again, and Pixel 6 delivery dates are all over the place</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TZ71o4Xo9Rmu-WcQclHf8CadVHE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70016823/bfarsace_211014_4802_0044.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DqywpW"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22734748/google-pixel-6-pro-preorder-buy-how-to-price-availability-release-date"&gt;Pre-orders for Google’s new line of phones&lt;/a&gt; started at the same time as their launch event, but for most of us, trying to buy a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22731034/google-pixel-6-pro-price-specs-features-release-date-hands-on"&gt;Pixel 6 or Pixel 6 Pro&lt;/a&gt; has meant seeing nothing but error screens. Some unsteadiness is to be expected given the sudden demand, but at 1PM ET, the doors opened, and Google’s store seemed to fall flat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XGyn0z"&gt;As of 5:40PM ET, Google says the store is operational again, and many of us have been able to put orders through. According to a spokesperson, “The Google Store was temporarily down but is now back up. We apologize for the inconvenience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3zzX7D"&gt;However, as &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2021/10/19/pixel-6-shipping-date-flux/#more-461552"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; points out, being able to submit an order is only part of it. Availability of different devices and projected delivery dates have continued to move around, with little consistency about what’s available and when it might show up at your front door. Some people are reporting delivery dates stretching into 2022 for the Pixel 6 Pro, while others have been able to secure orders scheduled to arrive in early November.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-VTM8N_HuEMKwCMJ5jQfb8z0u5k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22939534/google_store.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="feOHQ5"&gt;Since then, things have improved, but more than an hour later, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ChrisPirillo/status/1450522739442262018"&gt;most of us&lt;/a&gt; were &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/reneritchie/status/1450527567593758721"&gt;only seeing&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MishaalRahman/status/1450507803504881666"&gt;one error code after another&lt;/a&gt;. If you can get through, you can select to use the new Pixel Pass or add on a 30W phone charger. The fast wireless charging &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22732918/google-pixel-stand-23w-wireless-charging"&gt;Pixel Stand&lt;/a&gt;, however, says it’s “coming soon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HmY7tH"&gt;A quick scan of social media revealed that some people were able to complete purchases for the new Pixel 6 in the first hour or two they were available. For the rest of us, at least we’ve had time to learn patience while searching for a PlayStation 5, Nintendo Switch OLED, RTX 3090, or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/15/22727969/xbox-series-x-mini-fridge-price-release-date"&gt;Xbox Series X refrigerator&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="HhlNwC"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vNCYeN"&gt;Related:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="Oa4oo4"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Google Pixel 6 and 6 Pro hands-on: big screens, big ambitions, small price|104420" data-volume-uuid="0fd6d24c0" data-volume-id="104420" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-250" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jyKvTA"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update October 19th, 5:55PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Updated to reflect that the store is functional again, and added a statement from a Google spokesperson.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735046/google-pixel6-store-r013-r008-error-preorder-buy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735046/google-pixel6-store-r013-r008-error-preorder-buy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T17:47:47-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T17:47:47-04:00</updated>
    <title>Spec showdown: Google’s new Pixel 6 vs. Samsung, Apple, and more</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3dW1tEyzjUOCkXkveTllSgei3S4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70018000/cwelch_211015_4802_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gqqDWH"&gt;At &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22713338/google-pixel-6-event-top-announcements-tensor-processor-snapchat-pass"&gt;its fall event on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;, Google announced the Pixel 6 and Pixel 6 Pro, which feature its custom Tensor processor and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22727944/google-pixel-6-pro-cameras-computational-photography-features"&gt;the first big camera upgrade for Google’s phones&lt;/a&gt; since the Pixel 3. Since the Pixel 6s are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22734748/google-pixel-6-pro-preorder-buy-how-to-price-availability-release-date"&gt;available to preorder now&lt;/a&gt;, let’s take a look at how Google’s new phones compare on paper to their Android and iPhone competition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S8OO9p"&gt;At this point, how Google’s Tensor custom chip will perform is the biggest question mark — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22731034/google-pixel-6-pro-price-specs-features-release-date-hands-on"&gt;Google says&lt;/a&gt; it’s comparable to the Snapdragon 888, but that’s not even Qualcomm’s most powerful chip today, and Qualcomm is &lt;a href="https://www.qualcomm.com/company/events/snapdragon-tech-summit"&gt;holding an event in November&lt;/a&gt;, potentially to show off &lt;a href="https://www.qualcomm.com/company/events/snapdragon-tech-summit"&gt;even newer chips&lt;/a&gt;. Stay tuned to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, though, as we’re working on putting the Tensor through its paces to see how it performs in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yhC82S"&gt;With that in mind, let’s see how the mid-range Pixel 6 compares to some of its competitors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TW6y6Y"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10816344"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DtgE2c"&gt;Observant readers may have noticed that Samsung’s due to refresh its mainstream Galaxy S lineup in a few months. While that’s perhaps not a concern for someone looking to buy a phone &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt;, it’s something worth keeping in mind if you’re willing to wait a bit for an upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="HXPiol"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Samsung could bring the heat in a few months&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="S6XKUN"&gt;Today, though, the Pixel 6 is less expensive than its competitors and would physically tower over most of them. It’s actually bumping up against the &lt;em&gt;iPhone 13 Pro Max&lt;/em&gt; in terms of dimensions, which is great news if you like big phones — and not so great if you prefer more compact ones, like the original Pixel or iPhone Mini. While the Pixel 6’s battery is no slouch capacity-wise, it is a bit curious that Google didn’t choose to make it bigger. Though again — the phone starts at $599, so there’s only so much complaining you can do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hFvWPR"&gt;Let’s move on from the mid-range phones and take a look at the higher-end offerings from Google, Apple, and Samsung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3uzdo8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="table:10816311"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aMP0f9"&gt;As with the regular Pixel 6, the Pro’s price does it a lot of favors, especially when many of its competitors are playing in the $1,000-and-up range. We’re also seeing Google join the megapixel race that’s been kicked off among Android phone manufacturers, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22727944/google-pixel-6-pro-cameras-computational-photography-features"&gt;finally ditching the 12MP sensor that’s been featured on Pixels for so long&lt;/a&gt; (though we’ll have to test them out to see how the images actually look). The Pixel 6 Pro also has a top-tier amount of RAM for multi-taskers, and its battery is nothing to sneeze at either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Of3Wgw"&gt;Overall, it’s a phone that checks a lot of the boxes for a flagship Android phone — it has mmWave 5G, a 120Hz 1440p display, and promising camera specs. As always, though, stay tuned for the full review to find out if the Pixel 6 Pro is equal to (or, dare I hope, better than) the sum of its parts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GnAUXB"&gt;If you’re trying to decide between the Pixel 6 and the Pro or are currently rocking a lower-end Pixel and are wondering if it’s time for an upgrade, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22724481/google-pixel-6-pro-specs-comparison-price"&gt;check out our Pixel comparison article here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="z8iPvI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here’s how the Pixel 6 compares to the Pixel 6 Pro","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22724481/google-pixel-6-pro-specs-comparison-price"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="R2eS9j"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sstVsD"&gt;Related:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="vVRDck"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Google Pixel 6 and 6 Pro hands-on: big screens, big ambitions, small price|104420" data-volume-uuid="0fd6d24c0" data-volume-id="104420" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-386" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735208/google-pixel-6-pro-spec-comparison-iphone-samsung-oneplus-camera-battery-screen-size"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735208/google-pixel-6-pro-spec-comparison-iphone-samsung-oneplus-camera-battery-screen-size</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T17:28:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T17:28:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>Xbox will soon automatically mute your speakers when you plug in headphones</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Xbox Wireless headset" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZUwkVmkFKb8cr-7jjvFTV1nrT_s=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70017902/cfaulkner_210311_4469_0006.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="o3eqym"&gt;Microsoft is testing a feature that automatically mutes your speakers when you plug in headphones, fixing one of my biggest pet peeves with playing games on Xbox. The feature is rolling out &lt;a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2021/10/19/xbox-insider-release-notes-alpha-skip-ahead-2111-211017-2200/"&gt;to Xbox Insiders on the Alpha Skip-Ahead ring&lt;/a&gt;, which means it will very likely be available more broadly in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8AXc6F"&gt;Right now, when you plug in headphones to your controller on Xbox, your speakers stay on, too, which means if you want to have the audio just play in your headphones, you have to separately turn down the volume on your speakers. The PS5, on the other hand, handily mutes speaker audio when you plug in headphones, and I’m glad Microsoft is following suit by working on a similar feature for Xbox. The option to atuomatically mute speaker audio will appear in a revamped audio settings menu, according to Microsoft’s blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V6qi7a"&gt;This new Skip-Ahead build also includes a new accessibility feature: color blind filters. “While some games implement similar filters individually, this new feature applies globally to everything on Xbox Series X / S, including all games, movies, apps, menus, etc.,” Microsoft said in its blog. “It also supports multiple forms of color blindness, and the filters can be adjusted to your preference without impacting performance, screenshots, or game clips.” The company first talked about this feature during its Xbox Accessibility Showcase &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/1/22702660/xbox-games-accessibility-feature-tags"&gt;earlier this month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735389/xbox-mutes-speakers-plug-in-headphones-skip-ahead-ring"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735389/xbox-mutes-speakers-plug-in-headphones-skip-ahead-ring</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-10-19T17:16:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T17:16:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix is shifting the way it ranks its most popular titles </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/re4cATA64_ZbkC5VqIfaVWbx6ME=/563x0:3443x1920/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70017846/SquidGame_Season1_Episode1_00_44_44_16.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;An image from Netflix’s popular title &lt;em&gt;Squid Game&lt;/em&gt;. | Image: Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8lJc8j"&gt;Netflix will change the public-facing metrics it uses to rank the most popular titles on its streaming service, the company announced Tuesday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6PGuLq"&gt;In the past, the company has ranked titles based on the completion of at least the first two minutes of a film or TV show in its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723452/netflix-squid-game-biggest-ever-show-at-launch"&gt;first 28 days&lt;/a&gt; on the service. More recently, however, the company has released rankings based on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22697364/netflix-viewing-data-code-2021"&gt;total number of hours&lt;/a&gt; a movie or series is viewed — a metric it will shift to moving forward beginning later this year, the company said in a &lt;a href="https://s22.q4cdn.com/959853165/files/doc_financials/2021/q3/FINAL-Q3-21-Shareholder-Letter.pdf"&gt;letter to shareholders&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DzeZBK"&gt;“There is some difference in rankings [...] but we think engagement as measured by hours viewed is a slightly better indicator of the overall success of our titles and member satisfaction,” the company said. “It also matches how outside services measure TV viewing and gives proper credit to rewatching.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="LULOSE"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Netflix says hours viewed “is a slightly better indicator of the overall success of our titles”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6jVCvu"&gt;The change will not only shift one of its key public ranking systems from viewers to hours viewed but should, in theory, make its rankings a little easier to understand. While the company does track things like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/21/20924954/netflix-viewers-numbers-metrics-data-stranger-things-tuca-bertie-oa-renew-cancel"&gt;completion of its titles&lt;/a&gt; internally, the 2-minute metric was confusing and had the potential to misrepresent the true success of a series or film (for example, if an account holder watched &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; the first two minutes but then bailed).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gP94ea"&gt;Additionally, the company said, “we will start to release title metrics more regularly outside of our earnings report so our members and the industry can better measure success in the streaming world.” Transparency around streaming figures — and the accuracy with which services track their titles — has been called for by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22611516/scarlett-johansson-disney-lawsuit-streaming-services-transparency"&gt;industry figures&lt;/a&gt; who say that streaming services aren’t forthright about success metrics, complicating everything from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/17/22731087/hollywood-union-reaches-contract-agreement-iatse-avoids-strike"&gt;cast and crew payouts&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/29/22600396/scarlett-johansson-suing-disney-black-widow-release"&gt;contract negotiations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qAyd9acUZ4Xd6vaUg0dSgPLbqgE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22883359/Netflix_Code_Conference_V2.001_X3.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Code 2021&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="TlZlYg"&gt;Netflix co-CEO and chief content officer Ted Sarandos &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22697364/netflix-viewing-data-code-2021"&gt;last month at CodeCon&lt;/a&gt; shared rankings of Netflix’s top titles based on both the 2-minute metric and the hours watched metric, and a side-by-side comparison showed that — while overlap was certainly visible — the different metrics changed the title rankings noticeably. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NlO68h"&gt;What’s certain is that by many of its metrics, its Korean drama &lt;em&gt;Squid Game&lt;/em&gt; has been a massive success on the platform. Citing internal documents, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-17/squid-game-season-2-series-worth-900-million-to-netflix-so-far?sref=P6Q0mxvj"&gt;Bloomberg reported&lt;/a&gt; last week that the company estimated “89% of people who started the show watched at least 75 minutes (more than one episode), and 66% of viewers, or 87 million people, have finished the series in the first 23 days.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wFhrHL"&gt;Last week, the company announced the series had become its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/12/22723452/netflix-squid-game-biggest-ever-show-at-launch"&gt;biggest ever series at launch&lt;/a&gt;. In its shareholders letter on Tuesday, the company revealed that a “mind-boggling” 142 million households globally had tuned into the show, based on its 2-minute metric. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735379/netflix-changing-ranking-metric-popular-titles-hours-viewed"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22735379/netflix-changing-ranking-metric-popular-titles-hours-viewed</id>
    <author>
      <name>Catie Keck</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
