<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-06-16T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-16T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-16T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s first retail store opens this week </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Google Store in New York City" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/64SD7Ah55FOOOIwWErm3JqzHk0U=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69460500/Store_Interior_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The Google Store in New York City | Google and Paul Warchol&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VIo4bE"&gt;After years of pop-up experiments, Google is finally dipping its toes in the physical retail waters with its first store, located underneath its offices in the Chelsea neighborhood in New York City. It will primarily feature Google’s own hardware products, including Pixel phones, Nest smarthome gadgets, Fitbits, and assorted other devices. There will also be a selection of third party accessories and Google-branded swag like hats or T-shirts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KfKwUQ"&gt;Google characterizes this as its “first” store, but in a call with press yesterday declined to say when, where, or even whether other stores could open. Presumably one might, but it’s no sure thing. The retail space here is a relatively small way for Google to get into physical stores, not a big splashy entrance into competing with Apple Stores. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/26/21297400/microsoft-retail-stores-closing-cities-open"&gt;Microsoft closed all of its retail stores last July&lt;/a&gt; amid the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zKtKrp"&gt;The Google Store is designed more like a show room (or a brand activation experience) than a retail space intended to move lots of product. There are stools and chairs scattered throughout the main space as well as rooms that Google calls “sandboxes” with product-specific experiences. In one room, customers will go through a little skit of using a Nest hub to answer the door for a delivery person, complete with haptics in the couch to simulate a knock on the door. The room for Pixel phones will showcase their low-light photography feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="rXGXdD"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/m-klCvtE_eE?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VY1fde"&gt;The aesthetic of the Google Store is a sort of less antiseptic, more homey Apple Store. It’s filled with a lot of light, but also a lot of warm wood tones. Google emphasized how it worked with a local artist to design the cork and wood furniture. It’s also proud of the fact that it earned a platinum rating from Leeds for its environmental design. Much of the furniture and flooring are made from recycled materials, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yIe4aM"&gt;Along the outside of the store are diorama boxes featuring various Google products. There’s a Stadia room for gaming, another room meant to showcase Google’s living room products, and so on. Google also built a circular glass booth that it will fill with exhibits showing off its technologies — starting with Google Translate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nC46uw"&gt;Google says that it will offer on-site repair for Pixel phones and product support for all of its hardware devices. It’ll offer some software support as well — though only for its consumer products, not for enterprise users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VpFHHY"&gt;The store opens its doors at 10AM ET on June 17th. You can see more photos from the space below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="UNY6uF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10608825"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22535909/googles-first-retail-store-hardware"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22535909/googles-first-retail-store-hardware</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-16T09:15:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-16T09:15:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>Honor confirms Google’s apps will return to its phones with new 50 series</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TFP2N2ReVrDq1ocj9nT7bP6vZfw=/0x0:2400x1600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69460186/4f3a20f2_7289_4a1e_c995_e7b942aae685__1_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Honor 50 in silver, copper, green, and black.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Honor&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="crQozq"&gt;The Honor 50 series will be able to ship with Google’s apps and services, Honor officially announced today as it launched the Honor 50 and Honor 50 Pro in China. In a statement, Honor says its phones will go through Google’s security review and that “Honor devices will therefore have the option to have Google Mobile Services (“GMS”) preinstalled on compatible devices, in accordance with Google’s licensing and governance models.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IG9OAn"&gt;“Consumers will be able to experience Honor smartphones and tablets equipped with GMS,” the company said. A spokesperson confirmed that the “Honor devices” referred to in the statement include the newly announced Honor 50. The device will be available for preorder in China on June 25th and will come to international markets such as France, Malaysia, Mexico, Russia, Saudi Arabia, and the UK at a later date at a price that’s to be announced. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="EZlG5M"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Consumers will be able to experience HONOR smartphones and tablets equipped with GMS”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1I9tsI"&gt;Honor hasn’t been able to ship Google’s apps and services, including the Google Play Store, on its phones since its former parent company Huawei was placed on the US’s entity list, forcing Google to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/19/18631558/google-huawei-android-suspension"&gt;pull its Android license&lt;/a&gt;. What’s changed with the 50 series is that Huawei sold off Honor at the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/16/21570744/huawei-honor-sale-announced-us-sanctions"&gt;end of last year&lt;/a&gt;, allowing the company to work with Google once again. Huawei, meanwhile, is still unable to use Google’s software and is positioning its own &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/2/22463715/huawei-harmonyos-smartphone-mate-40-30-20-p40-p30-device-updates"&gt;HarmonyOS as a replacement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="blZ8l1"&gt;Reports about the return of Google’s software to Honor’s phones &lt;a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/honor-50-google-apps/"&gt;emerged last month&lt;/a&gt;, after the company’s German Twitter leaked the news in a now-deleted tweet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QsY2aEHSJ_IJq5rpktBM75HLpck=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22662120/a516cfcb_0b31_4e7f_937b_4873065d2f8d.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Honor&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The phones have four rear cameras in a pair of circular camera bumps.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Zt2SE92dIYZ0203qQPfz-_-JPos=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22662119/0648ccdb_6141_4277_8de1_b993e76cb9ef.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Honor&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Screen sizes range from 6.57 inches on the Honor 50 (pictured) to 6.72 on the 50 Pro. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NtlCPb"&gt;Turning to the devices themselves, the most eye-catching thing about the Honor 50 and Honor 50 Pro are their rear cameras, which are arranged into a pair of circular bumps. The phones have four rear cameras in total, including a 100-megapixel main camera, an 8-megapixel wide-angle, a 2-megapixel macro, and a 2-megapixel depth camera. On the front, the Honor 50 Pro has a pair of selfie cameras, combining a 32-megapixel camera with a 12-megapixel ultrawide, while the Honor 50 just has a single 32-megapixel camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fN2MUt"&gt;Both phones have a 120Hz display, though the Honor 50 Pro’s is slightly bigger at 6.72 inches compared to 6.57 for the regular Honor 50. Available colors include silver, bronze, green, and black. Internally, they’re powered by a Qualcomm Snapdragon 778G processor. The 50 Pro has a 4,000mAh battery that can be fast charged at up to 100W, while the regular 50 has a 4,300mAh battery and supports 66W fast charging. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7uTe1b"&gt;The return of Google’s software to Honor’s phones is unlikely to make much of a difference in China, where phones typically ship without the Play Store. But their absence has made Honor and Huawei’s phones &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/25/21193639/huawei-mate-30-google-apps-services-appgallery-p40-preview"&gt;pretty hard to recommend&lt;/a&gt; elsewhere. When the Honor 50 eventually releases in the West, that could all change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vXKN0v"&gt;In China, the Honor 50 will start at 2,699 yuan (around $422), while the Honor 50 Pro will start at 3,699 yuan (around $578). Alongside the two flagship phones, Honor is also announcing the cheaper Honor 50 SE, which will start at 2,399 yuan (around $375).&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22536512/honor-50-series-pro-release-date-news-features-google-mobile-services-apps-play-store"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22536512/honor-50-series-pro-release-date-news-features-google-mobile-services-apps-play-store</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-16T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-16T09:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Spotify’s Clubhouse competitor Greenroom launches today</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Mh1ZF3KIbpzeSrkoizrzKCGqzKo=/435x0:1535x733/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69460036/Screenshots.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Greenroom is Spotify’s take on live audio rooms. | Image: Spotify&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="AzcyZH"&gt;Spotify’s live audio app, Greenroom, &lt;a href="https://newsroom.spotify.com/2021-06-16/get-to-know-some-of-the-features-in-our-live-interactive-audio-offering-greenroom/"&gt;formally launches today&lt;/a&gt; on iOS and Android, marking the company’s first real attempt at creating a social media platform. The social audio app, which is similar to Clubhouse, allows users to host live conversations about sports, music, and culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TsmsY6"&gt;Today’s launch doesn’t come with a marquee creator announcement or specific event planned, but instead, the company is taking the opportunity to encourage people to sign up and figure out how they’ll want to use the app. Some of its core functionality, a person close to the situation says, will eventually make its way to the actual Spotify app, so the team will monitor what happens in Greenroom closely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UNj4MH"&gt;The app is built on Locker Room, which Betty Labs created and Spotify &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/30/22356993/spotify-locker-room-clubhouse-launch-acquisition"&gt;acquired in March&lt;/a&gt;. That app focused solely on sports content, so users who have been logged on since the start will have to get used to seeing more than just sports talk, which is likely the biggest change. Other noticeable changes to the app are mostly visual. It now has a Spotify green-and-black color scheme, as well as a new logo and font. Functionality-wise, it also now features native recording, which will allow users to save their shows and distribute them as podcasts. (Of course, Spotify owns Anchor, so one could easily imagine shows eventually being natively moved to the creation software for further editing and publishing.) &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/S37AgF41Ya7kfO-K6iheOQX2lxk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22662114/Screen_Shot_2021_06_16_at_8.28.32_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Spotify&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is what it’ll look like to create a room.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="sj2BYT"&gt;Users can sign up with their Spotify login, although it’s not required to use the app. The initial signup flow will also allow users to select their interests from a wider range of topics, like music genres and sports teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A86FVb"&gt;Additionally, Spotify is announcing a creator fund, although details are sparse. People on the app will be paid based on how popular their rooms are and their engagement in them, the source close to the situation says, and exclusive deals with creators are also in the works with announcements likely to come over the summer. It isn’t clear how much money Spotify will dedicate to lure creators to the app, but interested users can sign up more for information &lt;a href="https://greenroomcreatorfund.byspotify.com/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vVeGUI"&gt;Every tech company now seems to be interested in social audio, a thing that didn’t widely exist until March 2020, when Clubhouse launched. Since then, Twitter has launched Spaces, Facebook hosted its first Live Rooms, and other companies, like Slack, LinkedIn, Reddit, and Discord have started building similar products. Spotify might have the best chance of making social audio a real part of its business, simply because audio is already its full-time thing. But getting people to join an app live and spend time in it is a difficult sell, and one that’ll require top-tier programming, especially as it competes with all the other apps out there.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22535214/spotify-greenroom-locker-room-live-audio-app"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22535214/spotify-greenroom-locker-room-live-audio-app</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-16T08:42:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-16T08:42:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>The best wired or wireless gaming mouse you can buy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/emGA8ro9D4lNLBPQkh0oh092_xQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66870539/acastro_200323_1777_gamingMouse_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Whatever your budget or grip style is, we’ve found the best gaming mouse for you.&lt;/em&gt; | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Multiple picks for all budgets&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="IQp8AK"&gt;Finding the right gaming mouse amid all the options available can be a struggle. There are a lot of factors to consider, like how it looks, how it feels in the hand, the button selection and arrangement, the quality of its sensor, and whether you want a mouse that’s wireless or wired. These details, minor as they may seem, can have a major impact on your experience with the mouse you choose to buy. On the other hand, sometimes mice have features that get overblown and don’t actually work as well as advertised. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MOD0oD"&gt;If you’re looking for a wireless gaming mouse, you’ll want the best that your budget allows for. We’re going to make this decision easy for you. The best wireless gaming mouse is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07L4BM851?&amp;amp;linkCode=sl1&amp;amp;tag=vergereviews-20&amp;amp;linkId=0e8456acb6ff5049a8ca9a3010f859d7&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Logitech’s G502 Lightspeed&lt;/a&gt;. It’s the most well-rounded choice if you want comfort, a long-lasting battery, and the best selection and arrangement of buttons. The model’s design accommodates multiple grip styles, and Logitech’s companion software is unobtrusive and a breeze to use. It also has rock-solid wireless connectivity so you don’t have to deal with a wire entangling your gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bbAxZF"&gt;If you are looking for the best wired gaming mouse, look no further than the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B082G5SPR5?&amp;amp;linkCode=sl1&amp;amp;tag=vergereviews-20&amp;amp;linkId=efc848b34c5dbecff15ba71aac42299b&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Razer DeathAdder V2&lt;/a&gt;. It’s unbeatable in the ergonomics department, with a design that feels like a natural extension of your hand. And while this model has a fairly simple layout and button selection, it’s all just within reach and responsive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xBKPjC"&gt;Like our guide to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549510/best-gaming-headset-wired-wireless-features-specs-price-sound-microphone-test-buy"&gt;best gaming headset&lt;/a&gt;, what follows focuses mostly on newer models that you’re more likely to see on store shelves as opposed to older models, which may be tougher to find in stock — even if they might still be worth your money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="OI1GuQ"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="3lO4oA"&gt;The best wireless gaming mouse: Logitech G502 Lightspeed ($120)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best gaming mouse: Logitech G502 Lightspeed" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KjQweePnmr6NqW900etrvOctA34=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16219644/akrales_190507_3407_0017.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Logitech G502 Lightspeed  &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GenFNF"&gt;The Logitech G502 Lightspeed is a great gaming mouse for discerning gamers who don’t want to compromise on much of anything — or for casual users who just want a good, solid mouse. It’s comfortable and feature-packed, and even though it’s wireless, it’s a fast and accurate performer that doesn’t feel at a disadvantage against wired mice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gJdIHm"&gt;At $150, the best doesn’t come cheap (though you can sometimes find it for around $100 these days). But if you’ve tossed around the idea of making an investment in a high-end wireless mouse, no other model that I tested for this buying guide justified its price so easily. The G502 Lightspeed has the best features of Logitech’s gaming and general-use mice all rolled into one. The main buttons deliver a satisfying bounce response when you tap them, and unlike some other popular models, they click easily no matter how you grip your hand on the mouse. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qIq7sZ"&gt;This mouse also features a quick-release button, a feature borrowed from other Logitech consumer-focused and gaming mice. By default, the scroll wheel staggers down a single webpage with each step, which is how you expect a scroll wheel to work. Tapping the button releases the mechanism gripping the wheel, allowing it to freely sail to the bottom of a long page. It’s a small feature, but one that gives the mouse more versatility in certain situations, like being able to quickly scroll through your inventory when in a game.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Logitech G502 Lightspeed" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tRLAe6Nq6SE9DoYoV5sxbZJTxrk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16219645/akrales_190507_3407_0026.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The G502 Lightspeed may not have the most inviting design, but it’s incredibly comfortable to use.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="1Q3DLU"&gt;Another nice feature is the inclusion of 16 grams of weights you can insert into the mouse to give it more resistance. A mouse’s weight comes down to personal preference, and that could vary from game to game. This mouse is among the few modern wireless devices to give you the flexibility to change up the weight. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v2V6RE"&gt;The fact that the G502 Lightspeed is wireless makes it that much easier to bring along with you wherever you go. But if you just can’t swing the $150 price, I suggest that you check out the $50 &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07GBZ4Q68/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Logitech G502 Hero&lt;/a&gt;, which is the wired version of this mouse. It has almost every feature that you’ll find in the wireless model — except, you know, wireless capability. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="UBe8su"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9550529"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="1K4jR3"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="I7xlEt"&gt;The runner-up: Roccat Kone Pro Air ($110)&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Roccat Kone Pro Air" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SNyILDs_oyGZsMbHKwjRAkraPys=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22660669/koneproairlede.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Roccat&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Kone Pro Air is Roccat’s most refined wireless mouse yet.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="hpdhNm"&gt;Roccat’s high-end gaming mouse, the Kone Pro Air, is easier on the eyes than our top pick, and slightly easier on the wallet, too. It’s a simpler mouse than the G502 Lightspeed, with fewer buttons and features overall. But if all that you want are the basics done right, this one is a comfortable, no-fuss option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GJYm0q"&gt;The Kone Pro Air originally sold for $129.99 but is on sale sometimes for $110. Notably, it features dual wireless connectivity with Bluetooth and 2.4GHz support. A switch on its underside can toggle between the two modes, and next to that is a profile-switching button (which you can program using Roccat’s companion software) and a slot for the USB dongle to rest in. The mouse supports USB-C charging and includes a braided cable that didn’t snag on my desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mt56bi"&gt;The Kone Pro Air has a low arch and features thick, easy-to-reach thumb buttons. You might not totally jive with the feel of this mouse if your taste skews away from ergonomic-adjacent designs, but it’s comfortable to use with various grip styles. Aiding that comfort across play styles are the main mouse buttons, which cover almost half of the mouse’s topside. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="HmXPcq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10608279"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DYygOF"&gt;Throughout my time with the Kone Pro Air, connectivity was solid via 2.4GHz wireless, and it was a great companion for gaming. Its Titan optical switches deliver a satisfying click, while the force required to click and the bounce-back effect feel nicely tuned. The G502 Lightspeed’s scrollwheel is tough to beat, but Roccat’s model comes close — at least, in terms of feel. It’s an aluminum scrollwheel that yields a fine grip, and each step that it scrolls feels very tactile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bgfFJw"&gt;Roccat claims over 100 hours of battery life with this model, and indeed, I’ve gone weeks using the Kone Pro Air for work and play without having to recharge it. Its Rapid Charge feature via USB-C also meets the company’s claim that the mouse can charge a handful of hours after just 10 minutes of being plugged in. Roccat also sells a wired version of this mouse called the Kone Pro, with the same sensor and switches, but at $80, I recommend spending just a bit more on the Pro Air if you want to go wireless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="vOoCiS"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Corsair Dark Core RGB Pro SE" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/34H4GpKR93Xz1ejL3_3XCarRxQw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19984098/cfaulkner_200513_4020_0001.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="WRps16"&gt;Other good wireless options&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="LxusJS"&gt;Corsair’s Dark Core RGB Pro SE (&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1726258737981131320" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$89&lt;/a&gt;) is a good pick if you want oodles of features. It offers USB-C charging and supports Qi wireless charging. This mouse can switch between 2.4GHz wireless mode via its included USB dongle (cleverly tucked under its removable, magnetic wing), or Bluetooth. Of course, you’ll get better results by using the dongle, but it’s great to have options. I found that the battery life, while decent, wasn’t quite as long-lasting as the G502 Lightspeed or the Kone Pro Air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fOpEA3"&gt;Some smaller, but equally welcome, features here come in the form of that removable magnetic wing I just mentioned, which snaps onto its right side to let me comfortably rest my ring and pinky fingers. You might appreciate this most customizable design like I did.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="SteelSeries Aerox 3 Wireless" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YuU0vB9iDARo3BEjlybhYFTMpiM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21996070/steelseriesaerox3hero.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: SteelSeries&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MfOTnc"&gt;AT just 66 grams, the SteelSeries Aerox 3 Wireless (&lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1726257131796362447" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$90&lt;/a&gt;) weighs significantly less than our top and runner-up picks. That’s a big perk, as is its USB-C charging, which is still a rarity among other popular models from Razer and Logitech. It can operate on a 2.4GHz wireless mode with its included USB-C dongle, or using Bluetooth, and features an IP54 rating to protect it from some water and dust. It isn’t as ergonomic as mice I’ve described above, though. While that might not be much of an issue for people who use it simply to game, it’s not particularly comfortable to use as an all-day device. Also, I noticed that it lost connection with my PC regularly. That wasn’t a connectivity issue — the Aerox 3 Wireless falls asleep to preserve power if you don’t use it for a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="9tGmNh"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2q8aDd"&gt;The best wired gaming mouse: Razer DeathAdder V2 ($60)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Best wired gaming mouse: Razer DeathAdder V2" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JPODoDBPSU6YYV9veJq7J9hKMOA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19832658/deathadderv2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Razer&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Razer DeathAdder V2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QqAQPG"&gt;Razer’s DeathAdder V2 is proof that a wired mouse doesn’t need countless features to be worth the money. It just needs to be extremely good at the fundamentals, including being comfy enough to use for hours at a time with games that require quick reflexes, having a simple assortment of buttons that take little to no time to master, and, of course, great performance. If this matches what you want in a mouse, the $70 Razer DeathAdder V2 is the one to get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4oR5KE"&gt;Of all the wired gaming mice that I tested for this buying guide, no other mouse felt like a more natural extension of my hand. That’s crucial when you’re playing a game that requires precision, and it’s good to have when you just want to feel support while you’re using your computer in general. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0HHFi1"&gt;The DeathAdder V2’s design provides a lot of palm support, whether my fingers are flat and relaxed over the mouse or arched for faster reflexes. I use my index finger to left click and middle finger to right click; unlike most mice, this design gives me enough space on its right side to keep my ring and pinky fingers from dangling off the side and dragging on the mouse pad. That’s something I didn’t know I wanted out of a mouse until I started using this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pWZiOf"&gt;Those design features keep things comfortable, but I think the part of the mouse that sold me is where my thumb rests. Many mice etch out an area for your thumb to relax and laze around. That’s fine, but I find that it necessitates more arm movement when the action ramps up. I prefer this mouse’s solution: its ergonomic design keeps my thumb wrapped around its side, naturally resting upon the edges of the customizable macro buttons. It’s good to have multiple buttons within reach, and the thumb location makes it easy for me to push the mouse around using just my wrist. It’s comfortable and has the dual purpose of keeping me limber in case I need to make sudden movements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="20uVFV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10221835"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="zVjY6B"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Fjlknf"&gt;The runner-up: SteelSeries Prime Plus ($80)&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="SteelSeries Prime Plus" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CU-ZSEdoLEZdTXD28DuCS5oJ31g=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22528993/primeplus.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="jlJvtP"&gt;I prefer the feel of Razer’s DeathAdder V2 over any other wired gaming mouse, but coming in a close second place is SteelSeries’ new Prime Plus wired model. It could be a better choice than the Razer for people with smaller hands, or for those who prefer a gaming mouse that has a little more in the way of clever features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UMPQwJ"&gt;The Prime Plus is the middle child in SteelSeries’ new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22445746/steelseries-prime-arctis-headset-wireless-plus-gaming-mouse-features-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;made-for-esports Prime lineup&lt;/a&gt; of mice, yet it’s the most interesting and value-packed. It feels just like the others in that lineup, both in the way it fits your hand with a high arch that slopes to the right, as well as with what SteelSeries aptly calls “crispy” clicks. They’re a little louder than your average gaming mouse, and they have a more tactile feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xLVmkp"&gt;What sets the Prime Plus apart from the others in the Prime lineup (as well as the other options below) is the OLED screen and controls built into its underside. There’s no driver required to change in-depth settings. You hold the bottom button once it’s plugged in and use the scroll wheel to navigate a menu that lets you change things like the brightness of the OLED and the LED illuminating the scroll wheel. More importantly, you can adjust sensitivity, polling rate (125Hz to 1000Hz), and liftoff distance right from this display. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GH6fMe"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10608342"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="jPcwAC"&gt;Other good wired options&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="TeVjwP"&gt;As I mentioned near the top of this article, if $150 for Logitech’s wireless G502 Lightspeed is too much for you to spend, you might want to consider this wired version, the G502 Hero. It has the same design as our pick for the best wireless gaming mouse — actually, it’s basically the same in almost every way, down to the kind of sensor it uses and its adjustable weights. That makes it almost as good, though some might take issue with its thick braided cable and the somewhat slippery plastic used on the scroll wheel that isn’t on the Lightspeed model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="rm9W6Z"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10221788"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Hs4a0r"&gt;The Basilisk V2 is the wired mouse that I’d recommend to people who want the advantages of a modern Razer wired mouse, like the thin, braided SpeedFlex cable, fast performance, PTFE feet that let the mouse glide across your mouse pad, and, of course, LEDs. Despite having a design that might not fit well in everyone’s hands, it’s a smaller mouse that has more features than the DeathAdder V2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I15iEA"&gt;For instance, the Basilisk V2 has a removable sniper button that’s easy to reach. Perhaps my favorite feature here is the scroll wheel that has an adjustable tension. It’s not quite as cool as the Logitech G502’s free-spinning wheel, but you’ll probably love it if you want a custom feel to your wheel. One of the best things about this mouse is that it has most of the same features found in the more expensive &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/6/20947669/razer-wireless-basilisk-gaming-pc-mouse-ultimate-x-hyperspeed-battery-life-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Basilisk Ultimate&lt;/a&gt;, Razer’s wireless version of this mouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gmcFzc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10221776"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TsB5ht"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="KPe1W2"&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p id="VPma8f"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21252193/best-gaming-mouse"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21252193/best-gaming-mouse</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-16T06:50:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-16T06:50:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Atari VCS retro console gets its long-awaited retail release</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QCERDzPEAGgu7eQtnF9u9k_H1n8=/0x0:3600x2400/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69459612/download__1_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The “Black Walnut” version of the console, which comes with a joystick and controller.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Atari&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xGKuSV"&gt;The Atari VCS — a part-desktop PC, part-retro console modeled after the Atari 2600 — is finally available to buy at retail. Atari is selling the console via &lt;a href="https://atarivcs.com/atari-vcs-800-black-walnut-all-in-bundle/"&gt;its own site&lt;/a&gt; while &lt;a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/614286/10014?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Fatari-vcs-800-black-walnut-all-in-bundle%2F6459020.p%3FskuId%3D6459020&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.microcenter.com/product/627563/atari-vcs-800-black-walnut-full-bundle"&gt;Micro Center&lt;/a&gt; also have their listings. This isn’t the first time the console has been available to the public (&lt;a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/review/atari-vcs-review/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;VGC&lt;/em&gt; notes&lt;/a&gt; that IndieGoGo backers recently received their consoles) but it’s the first time the machine has been available to buy at retail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AdgMCA"&gt;The VCS has been a long time coming. Originally teased in 2017 as the “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2017/6/12/15783074/ataribox-teaser-new-atari-product"&gt;Ataribox&lt;/a&gt;,” the project re-emerged the following year &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/3/19/17140190/ataribox-atari-vcs-name-preorder-date-classic-gaming-console"&gt;as the Atari VCS&lt;/a&gt;, with Atari running an IndieGoGo campaign to fund its development &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/30/17408184/ataris-vcs-console-preorder-specifications-release-date-pricing"&gt;in June 2018&lt;/a&gt;. Originally, the console had been due to ship in mid-2019 but reportedly ran into a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/10/20907755/atari-vcs-troubled-development-architect-operating-system-crowdfunding-campaign"&gt;series of development difficulties&lt;/a&gt;, culminating in the project’s lead architect quitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WBnu9R"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q7DP4BouzT4?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="di0ndV"&gt;The device that’s been released technically does what Atari promised, but reviews have been pretty middling. &lt;a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/review/atari-vcs-review/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;VGC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; says the console’s built-in selection of 100 Atari games (18 from the arcade and 82 from the Atari 2600 console) might be emulated perfectly, but many are “so incredibly basic that they really don’t hold up to the mildest scrutiny in 2021.” There’s also an app store where you can buy modern games, but pickings are slim and lacking in exclusives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lAywAA"&gt;The console technically also works as a streaming box for services like Netflix and Disney Plus, but &lt;em&gt;VGC&lt;/em&gt; notes these are just “glorified Chrome bookmarks” rather than native apps. At least the promised desktop mode actually works, allowing you to install Windows, Linux, or ChromeOS and use the machine like a modestly-specced but cool-looking desktop PC. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K9xBCe"&gt;If you do decide to go down the desktop PC route, the Atari VCS is powered by an AMD Ryzen R1606G system-on-a-chip, paired with 8GB of RAM and 32GB of storage (both upgradeable). There are two USB 3.1 ports on the front and two on the rear along with Ethernet and HDMI 2.0 ports. In other words, don’t expect this machine to rival an Xbox Series S despite its similar $299.99 starting price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M8Rnnl"&gt;Suffice it to say that you probably shouldn’t be rushing out to drop upwards of $299.99 on the Atari VCS (or $399.99 for the Walnut version, which comes with an included wireless joystick and controller, which retail separately for $59.99 each). But despite its flaws, it’s still an interesting mini PC that might be worth checking out as a curiosity when it inevitably drops in price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Orp8vs"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22536429/atari-vcs-console-released-retro-computer-pc-gaming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22536429/atari-vcs-console-released-retro-computer-pc-gaming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-16T06:04:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-16T06:04:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft is bringing next-gen Xbox games to the Xbox One with xCloud</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EIu8nqfXVD48aseTMdH2L0XvbhI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69459566/acastro_210429_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kmxHXo"&gt;Microsoft will let Xbox One owners play next-gen Xbox games through its xCloud service. The news was &lt;a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2021/06/13/xbox-and-bethesda-games-showcase-recap/"&gt;buried in a blog post&lt;/a&gt; recapping Microsoft’s Xbox + Bethesda showcase, with the company confirming plans to leverage Xbox Cloud Gaming (xCloud) for Xbox One consoles. That means the 2013 hardware will be able to play Xbox Series X exclusive games from 2021 — extending the lifecycle of what would normally soon be obsolete boxes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O19nwD"&gt;“For the millions of people who play on Xbox One consoles today, we are looking forward to sharing more about how we will bring many of these next-gen games, such as &lt;em&gt;Microsoft Flight Simulator&lt;/em&gt;, to your console through Xbox Cloud Gaming, just like we do with mobile devices, tablets, and browsers,” says Will Tuttle, editor in chief of Microsoft’s Xbox Wire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Nurj5W"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Microsoft is launching xCloud for consoles later this year&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KcyjmE"&gt;Until now, Microsoft had only described &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22527461/xbox-xcloud-game-streaming-try-before-download-feature"&gt;xCloud on consoles as a way for players to “try [games] before you download&lt;/a&gt;,” but it’s clear the company sees the service as offering much more. Microsoft originally announced &lt;em&gt;Microsoft Flight Simulator&lt;/em&gt; as an Xbox One title, before &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22168892/microsoft-flight-simulator-xbox-release-date-announced"&gt;quietly removing references&lt;/a&gt; to the Xbox One launch in December. Microsoft recently confirmed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/13/22527483/microsoft-flight-simulator-xbox-series-x-s-launch"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flight Simulator &lt;/em&gt;will now launch&lt;/a&gt; on Xbox Series X / S consoles on July 27th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ngBECS"&gt;It’s not clear when xCloud game streaming will be available on Xbox One consoles, though. It’s unlikely to be ready in time for the July launch of &lt;em&gt;Microsoft Flight Simulator&lt;/em&gt;, and Microsoft’s head of cloud gaming, Kareem Choudhry, previously said xCloud will be integrated into consoles “later this year.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E9aEIQ"&gt;xCloud availability will provide a welcome boost for Xbox One consoles, particularly as Microsoft is upgrading its server blades to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/10/22527432/microsoft-xcloud-server-xbox-series-x-hardware-upgrade-game-streaming"&gt;run Xbox Series X hardware&lt;/a&gt; later this month. It will give this older hardware a way to play &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/13/22531868/starfield-bethesda-game-xbox-pc-november-11-2022-release"&gt;upcoming titles like &lt;em&gt;Starfield&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which, like &lt;em&gt;Flight Simulator,&lt;/em&gt; will also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/13/22531868/starfield-bethesda-game-xbox-pc-november-11-2022-release"&gt;launch exclusively on the new Xbox Series X / S consoles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22536418/microsoft-xbox-series-x-games-on-xbox-one-xcloud-streaming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22536418/microsoft-xbox-series-x-games-on-xbox-one-xcloud-streaming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-16T06:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-16T06:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Lincoln vehicles getting hands-free driving feature and native Android</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jZlKP8paNWnsL9Wojtg4pUFfPeU=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69459521/Future_Lincoln__Exterior_Tease_with_Embrace_Lighting.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="5y6cVe"&gt;Lincoln, Ford’s luxury brand, has announced plans to make its entire lineup either hybrid or all-electric by 2030 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22454728/ford-plus-pro-electric-explorer-suv-investment"&gt;as part of its parent company’s new business plan&lt;/a&gt;. The brand will reveal its first all-electric vehicle in 2022, and it expects that half of its global sales will be zero-emissions vehicles by around 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BhCSnY"&gt;In addition, Lincoln vehicles are gaining a hands-free advanced driver assistance feature based on Ford’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22383460/ford-bluecruise-hands-free-adas-f150-mustang-mache"&gt;BlueCruise&lt;/a&gt; system, though the luxury marque will call its version “ActiveGlide.” New Lincoln vehicles coming in 2023 will also feature Google’s native Android Automotive operating system, which is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260176/ford-google-android-infotainment-os-2023"&gt;is being added to “millions” of Ford vehicles&lt;/a&gt; that same year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7tQj6Z"&gt;Four of Lincoln’s electric vehicles will be built on the new flexible EV platform that Ford announced in May when it laid out its new $30 billion &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22454728/ford-plus-pro-electric-explorer-suv-investment"&gt;“Ford Plus” business plan&lt;/a&gt;. That platform can power vehicles with all- or rear-wheel drive setups, and it “allows [Lincoln] to reimagine the interior space, and deliver the power of sanctuary in a new way for our clients,” John Jraiche, the company’s global director for luxury vehicles, said in a briefing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ANNAGZ"&gt;In April, Lincoln &lt;a href="https://media.lincoln.com/content/lincolnmedia/lna/us/en/news/2021/04/19/lincoln-china-zephyr-reflection-preview-car.html"&gt;announced a concept car in China called Zephyr&lt;/a&gt; that the company said offers a good picture of what its future vehicles might look like, inside and out. It featured a dashboard-spanning screen and new user interface that Lincoln refers to as “Constellation.” Lincoln released a short video on Wednesday of what that new UI might look like. The company said its “designers and engineers are also experimenting with digital scenting techniques, exploring how warm, pleasant scents positively affect the mood and overall well-being of the passengers.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IZMHnc"&gt;Lincoln was previously working on co-developing its first all-electric vehicle &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/29/21113578/lincoln-rivian-electric-suv-ford-platform-tech"&gt;with EV startup Rivian&lt;/a&gt;, of which Ford owns at least a 10 percent stake. But the luxury automaker announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/28/21240212/ford-lincoln-cancel-rivian-suv-ev-coronavirus-pandemic-investment"&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt; at the beginning of the pandemic that the project was canceled. While it seemed at the time that Lincoln had said it was still working with Rivian on another EV, the company said this week that this was a miscommunication. Rivian is still working with Ford on a future product, but its involvement with the Lincoln brand ended last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rCbbjo"&gt;In more near-term news, Lincoln announced that the 2021 Nautilus will receive its first over-the-air software updates starting this summer. Those will upgrade the onboard navigation system and improve the Apple CarPlay experience. Later this year, an update will add hands-free capability for the built-in Amazon Alexa digital assistant. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22535666/lincoln-electric-vehicles-plan-hands-free-google-android"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22535666/lincoln-electric-vehicles-plan-hands-free-google-android</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-16T05:08:58-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-16T05:08:58-04:00</updated>
    <title>Windows 11’s default wallpapers are Microsoft’s best yet</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V04wTRtkcFsAMNFGnzWZZZLeqro=/63x0:738x450/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69459494/windows11wallpapers.0.gif" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PgGPhO"&gt;Windows 11 leaked yesterday, offering a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/15/22535123/microsoft-windows-11-leak-screenshots-start-menu"&gt;closer look at some of the UI changes&lt;/a&gt; Microsoft is planning for its next version of Windows. The leak has also revealed what will likely become Microsoft’s default wallpaper for Windows 11, and a collection of new wallpapers that are bundled with the operating system. They’re Microsoft’s best Windows wallpapers yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2o7Vfx"&gt;The main default wallpaper includes light and dark mode versions, with what looks like a crumpled piece of fabric. It’s a big departure from the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/6/25/8845379/windows-10-desktop-wallpaper"&gt;Windows logo that was used as the default in Windows 10&lt;/a&gt;, or the two &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/7/26/3188381/windows-8-wallpaper-rtm-leak"&gt;daisy flowers in Windows 8&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="g81W2a"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10609233"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xDEr2d"&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can download the full-size versions in the gallery above.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PeWASS"&gt;Microsoft has also included a collection of other wallpapers inside Windows 11. The “Captured Motion” set offer a more colorful option, and the “Flow” collection are a more subtle take on the default. “Glow” is a set of four colorful orbs that light up the Windows 11 backdrop, and the “Sunrise” collection are a clear nod to the Sun Valley codename for the Windows 11 UI work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BBbgTk"&gt;As this is an early and incomplete version of Windows 11, it’s not clear how many of these images will ship in the final version. These already look better than the flowers and scenic backgrounds included in Windows 10, and fit the overall UI changes to Windows 11. If you haven’t seen exactly what Microsoft is changing in Windows 11, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/15/22535123/microsoft-windows-11-leak-screenshots-start-menu"&gt;check out our hands-on&lt;/a&gt; to see the new UI, Start menu, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22536375/microsoft-windows-11-default-wallpaper"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22536375/microsoft-windows-11-default-wallpaper</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-16T05:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-16T05:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>New website tracks which colleges will use eproctoring software this fall</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gKN6pIX0ZTgrWm7XRwczmL-G8PQ=/302x0:1570x845/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69459461/Annotation_2021_06_15_150505.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qoLDQO"&gt;Privacy-focused nonprofit Fight for the Future has launched a &lt;a href="https://www.baneproctoring.com/"&gt;new website&lt;/a&gt; that tracks whether certain colleges and universities plan to use virtual proctoring software during the fall semester. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nn4Lae"&gt;The platforms — like ProctorU and Proctorio — often make use of students’ webcams to watch and record them as they work, using automated systems or live monitors to flag possible signs of cheating. The practice has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/28/22254631/university-of-illinois-urbana-champaign-proctorio-online-test-proctoring-privacy"&gt;sparked controversy&lt;/a&gt; in the US, with critics in both academia and government citing privacy concerns and the potential for such software to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/8/22374386/proctorio-racial-bias-issues-opencv-facial-detection-schools-tests-remote-learning"&gt;discriminate against marginalized students&lt;/a&gt;. Still, some colleges began using eproctoring last year to watch for dishonesty on take-home exams, after moving testing online due to COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FjFUVD"&gt;Many schools will resume in-person examinations this fall due to the wide availability of COVID-19 vaccines, but it seems that some plan to continue using eproctoring software in some capacity. Fight for the Future says it has asked a number of colleges about their plans and has stamped each one with labels for “Won’t Use,” “Might Use,” and “Are Using.” (Colleges that haven’t responded to Fight for the Future’s inquiries got a “Might Use.”) Viewers are prompted to tweet at and email each university to denounce the software’s use.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ox1dSClnRSx57tvuHX4z_g8vFCw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22660733/Annotation_2021_06_15_151054.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="bqorls"&gt;Also on the front page is a “webcam image test” meant to determine whether eproctoring algorithms could accurately identify a viewer’s face (following reports that such algorithms disproportionately &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/g5gxg3/proctorio-is-using-racist-algorithms-to-detect-faces"&gt;fail to identify faces with darker skin tones&lt;/a&gt;). Fight for the Future says the test uses the same computer vision software used by prominent eproctoring platform Proctorio, but insists that it doesn’t collect any data from the widget. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LUtYrbwwy80hFm7avmAQXR09ZKw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22660740/Annotation_2021_06_15_151330.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="NlUefA"&gt;The website also urges followers to sign a petition addressed to school administrators and to submit “eproctoring horror stories” to the organization. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22535439/ban-eproctoring-fight-for-the-future-colleges-online-tests"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22535439/ban-eproctoring-fight-for-the-future-colleges-online-tests</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-06-16T00:50:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-16T00:50:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sony reportedly plans PSVR successor for next holiday season</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uxJ0uSaJlMV8FMnrjNUxCi4ZYIU=/80x0:944x576/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69459135/01_withnotice_scaled.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Sony’s next-gen VR controllers. | Image: Sony&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="d8l7RU"&gt;Sony’s next-gen PlayStation VR headset is likely to come out in late 2022, according to a new report. &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-06-16/fading-iphone-lcd-screen-maker-pivots-to-virtual-reality"&gt;Bloomberg’s sources say&lt;/a&gt; Sony is “aiming to release the successor in the holiday period next year,” and that the headset will use OLED panels from Samsung Display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bekJ37"&gt;A release in that timeframe wouldn’t be too surprising, since Sony has already started talking up the PS5 headset’s potential. Its existence was first &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22296998/sony-ps5-next-gen-vr-headset-virtual-reality-features"&gt;confirmed&lt;/a&gt; in February along with some initial details, and Sony &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/18/22337700/sony-new-ps5-playstation-5-vr-controllers-features"&gt;followed up&lt;/a&gt; by showing off the new controllers in March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="5WTRHd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Doom 3 for PSVR is a solid showcase for Sony’s Aim Controller","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/1/22361736/doom-3-vr-edition-review-ps4-psvr-aim-controller"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="IHcna9"&gt;The headset itself hasn’t yet been revealed. But according to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/10/22429523/playstation-vr-ps5-rumors-eye-tracking-foviated-render-4k-screen-haptics"&gt;an &lt;em&gt;UploadVR&lt;/em&gt; report&lt;/a&gt; from last month, it’ll have a total resolution of 4000 x 2040 and make use of eye tracking to enable foveated rendering, which should ease the processing load by using lower resolution imagery in your peripheral vision. The next-gen PSVR is also said to use inside-out tracking and include haptic feedback in the headset as well as the controllers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oj1oTK"&gt;Bloomberg’s report is more broadly focused on Japan Display Inc, an LCD specialist that has seen smartphone display sales slump as the market moved to OLED but now considers VR headsets “big business.” While OLED was initially the standard for VR, more recently manufacturers like Facebook and HTC have been moving to LCD panels because they’re more practical at higher resolutions, despite having lower contrast. Sony, however, appears to be sticking with OLED for the next PSVR.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22536263/sony-playstation-vr-2-ps5-release-date-2022-samsung-oled"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22536263/sony-playstation-vr-2-ps5-release-date-2022-samsung-oled</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
