<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-06T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-06T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-06T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Here are a few of this week’s best deals</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HwgI1Y0Z0qltJ5jUQBV2inNa9mk=/0x0:1013x675/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68779474/destruction_all_stars_screenshots_14_disclaimer_ps5_en_15oct20.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A screengrab from Destruction All-Stars, a PS5 game you can get for free with a PS Plus subscription&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Sony&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bSOn1T"&gt;How has the first week of February been for you? Good, I hope. We’re keeping it simple with the weekend deals post by providing a variety of the best discounts we’ve seen this week. Whether you just got a PS5 and want an affordable way to get a PS Plus membership, your home is in desperate need of better Wi-Fi coverage and speed, or you need an affordable Sonos speaker, you might find something you want below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="8oQmf8"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="qrPDZX"&gt;Save big on a PS Plus membership&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="dYCcjE"&gt;This deal has been very popular with readers, and it’s easy to see why. A one-year subscription to PS Plus, Sony’s online service that allows multiplayer and complimentary titles each month, usually costs $60. But digital key seller Eneba is offering it to &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; readers for $28 when they put in offer code &lt;strong&gt;VERGE28&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kYxjqb"&gt;Sweetening the value, you can get two years of service (it’ll arrive in the form of two unique codes that you input in the PS Store) for just $56 when you use the offer code &lt;strong&gt;VERGEFEB &lt;/strong&gt;at checkout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4CamqP"&gt;With PS Plus this month, you can get &lt;em&gt;Destruction AllStars&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Control Ultimate Edition&lt;/em&gt; on PS5 as complimentary perks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xvvq2E"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9734577"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="7LQoQ3"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Eero 6" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ULhFUiPZOoJ20AyiMlZrf4rkjW8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22284101/eero6.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Eero&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="mUEkrt"&gt;Eero’s latest mesh Wi-Fi routers are discounted&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="zGymFF"&gt;Whether you’re looking to get a single Wi-Fi router or get set up with a variety bundle that’ll cast a wider blanket of Wi-Fi coverage over your house, there are some good deals happening on Amazon’s Eero products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4NW6nv"&gt;If you want a whole-home solution, Eero’s 6 router (supporting Wi-Fi 6) comes bundled with two Eero 6 extenders for $223 (usually $279). But if you want to get started with a single Eero 6 router, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B085VM9ZDD?&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;linkId=ad859221eb81bb566d28812855d03192&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;it’s just $103&lt;/a&gt; (down from $129). (Note that the Eero 6 router has two Ethernet ports, while the extenders are wireless only.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gqeJSP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9603441"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="ciX0mX"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Sonos Play:1 images" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lyy2rsEdOs2u1o8XSLN83tXsfvw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/2786320/sonosplay1-2040-8.1381709930.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="OYPRfV"&gt;Snag a refurbished Sonos Play:1 for $99&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="teeTyz"&gt;Sonos is selling refurbished Play:1 Wi-Fi speakers for $99 at its site. This is a solid investment if you want something affordable to build out your collection of Sonos speakers. It’s a little long in the tooth, having originally released in 2013, but it’s still supported by Sonos’ S2 platform and mobile app. These speakers should look and operate as new, and they come with a one-year warranty through Sonos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ShTtJe"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10322142"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="0VgxHU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/2/6/22268294/eero-6-router-extender-sonos-play-1-wifi-speaker-ps-plus-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/2/6/22268294/eero-6-router-extender-sonos-play-1-wifi-speaker-ps-plus-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-05T19:42:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-05T19:42:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>Miami mayor says Elon Musk will tunnel under the city for just $30 million</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fHo0o3ZmJAlndP_hbMxFV0rY34E=/0x0:6720x4480/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68778193/Boring_tunnel__2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: The Boring Company&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FpUyES"&gt;Elon Musk told Miami’s mayor Friday that The Boring Company could dig a two-mile tunnel under the city for as little as $30 million — a fraction of the $1 billion price tag once &lt;a href="https://www.miamiherald.com/news/local/community/miami-dade/article249037895.html"&gt;quoted by local transit officials&lt;/a&gt;. Musk also told the Mayor that The Boring Company could complete the job in six months, versus the original four year estimate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AujKa6"&gt;Mayor Francis Suarez shared these details about his “wonderful call” with Musk in a video posted to Twitter. “He’s focused on trying to deliver a project that will have the maximum utility for our residents for the least amount of money,” Suarez said. “The order of magnitude in terms of savings is significant.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Q4TKdH"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Just had my call w/ &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@elonmusk&lt;/a&gt; regarding &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/boringcompany?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@boringcompany&lt;/a&gt; tunnels coming to MIA&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;DETAILS BELOW   &lt;a href="https://t.co/NsJFYcvGeQ"&gt;pic.twitter.com/NsJFYcvGeQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Mayor Francis Suarez (@FrancisSuarez) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FrancisSuarez/status/1357796329263669258?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 5, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4YVrEd"&gt;Musk first &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1351091106805645312"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; about wanting to tunnel under Miami on January 18th. “Cars &amp;amp; trucks stuck in traffic generate megatons of toxic gases &amp;amp; particulate, but @boringcompany road tunnels under Miami would solve traffic &amp;amp; be an example to the world,” he wrote. Musk said in the tweet that he had already spoken to Florida Governor Ron DeSantis about the idea. “If Governor &amp;amp; Mayor want this done, we will do it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UebnY2"&gt;Suarez said Friday that he will speak to DeSantis and the mayor of Miami-Dade county. “I think we have a unique opportunity to create a signature project not just for Miami, but for the world,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z9iw3C"&gt;Tunneling under Miami is not easy because the city is built on limestone, which is spongey. That hurdle is one reason for the sky-high price tag quoted in 2018. It also helped drive up the price of a tunnel under the Port of Miami, which was less than a mile but &lt;a href="https://miami.cbslocal.com/2021/02/05/miami-mayor-francis-suarez-elon-musk-tunnel-transit/"&gt;still cost around $700 million&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Yqm6S0"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Miami is built on limestone, which would be hard to tunnel through&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RLzMh4"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.miamiherald.com/news/local/community/miami-dade/article249037895.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Miami Herald&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reported Friday that the limestone bedrock and the impact of rising sea levels were among the talking points for the call, though it’s unclear to what extent these items were discussed. Musk has previously talked about digging tunnels &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1305901516239273986"&gt;as deep underground as skyscrapers are tall&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aHwxRO"&gt;Musk started The Boring Company in 2016, and has started a handful of projects around the country in the years since. The purpose and scope of the tunnels has changed a bit over that time. These days, the company is trying to make a transportation service that uses Teslas traveling through the tunnels. The first commercial service is nearing completion underneath the Las Vegas Convention Center, though The Boring Company recently announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22176596/elon-musk-boring-company-las-vegas-strip-tesla-tunnels"&gt;a massive city-wide expansion that would service the Strip and the airport&lt;/a&gt;. The company is also &lt;a href="https://www.masstransitmag.com/rail/infrastructure/press-release/21208883/san-bernardino-county-transportation-authority-sbcta-sbcta-board-to-begin-negotiating-with-the-boring-company-on-the-ontario-loop-project"&gt;in negotiations for a tunnel in San Bernardino County, California&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GHeXRG"&gt;Other attempts have not gone so well, like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/25/18236075/elon-musk-chicago-boring-company-tunnel-politics"&gt;a failed project in Chicago&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/nov/28/elon-musk-underground-tunnel-los-angeles-lawsuit"&gt;a canceled tunnel in West Los Angeles&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22269188/elon-musk-boring-company-miami-tunnel-mayor-francis-suarez"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22269188/elon-musk-boring-company-miami-tunnel-mayor-francis-suarez</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-05T19:29:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-05T19:29:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>Reddit stopped rogue r/WallStreetBets mods from taking over the community</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gbqxwpYbBdGWcLC3CFMgG9v6jRw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68778141/acastro_180413_1777_reddit_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="m1RETn"&gt;Reddit’s r/WallStreetBets has grown significantly due to the community’s role in driving up the stock prices of companies like GameStop, AMC, and Nokia, and the whole saga has garnered so much attention that there are currently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22268952/gamestop-stock-stonks-reddit-wallstreetbets-movies-tv-shows-hbo-netflix"&gt;many movies and a TV show in the works&lt;/a&gt;. But that increased attention has also put strain on the r/WallStreetBets community itself, forcing Reddit to step in to help sort things out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZCLIB0"&gt;The trouble started Wednesday night, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/04/technology/wallstreetbets-gamestop-hollywood.html"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, as some r/WallStreetBets moderators talked with each other about trying to get a movie deal. On Thursday morning, “the WallStreetBets moderators who were considering the film deal began booting out other moderators who had questioned them for secretly trying to profit from the forum’s success,” reports &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;. A &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/wallstreetbets/comments/lcvluc/an_update_on_the_wsb_coup_d%C3%A9tat/"&gt;highly upvoted r/WallStreetBets post&lt;/a&gt; called the situation “a coup,” saying the moderators the community “know and love” were being tossed out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hNKvHp"&gt;At some point, Reddit stepped in to stop the takeover, and the company confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;that it had removed some r/WallStreetBets mods. The company says &lt;a href="https://www.redditinc.com/policies/moderator-guidelines-for-healthy-communities"&gt;they violated rule five of its moderator guidelines&lt;/a&gt;, which reads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="mYZyWv"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stable and Active Teams of Moderators:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kBIYIX"&gt;Healthy communities have moderators who are around to answer questions of their community and engage with the admins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="xDPirS"&gt;The company wouldn’t share how many mods were removed.  As of this writing, there are 28 mods listed on the &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/wallstreetbets/about/moderators"&gt;r/WallStreetBets mods page&lt;/a&gt;, and “in recent weeks there have been a few dozen,” according to &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dhftlg"&gt;Reddit said it had to take action due to the instability the situation created for the community, according to a message sent to the r/WallStreetBets mods by Reddit that was &lt;a href="https://mashable.com/article/reddit-steps-in-wallstreetbets-subreddit-moderator-bans/"&gt;obtained by &lt;em&gt;Mashable&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “We understand many will be upset with our decisions today, however it was clear to us an intervention was necessary for the continued health of the r/wallstreetbets community,” part of the message read. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X54uWP"&gt;The mods removed by Reddit can’t be immediately reinstated as moderators of r/WallStreetBets, the company tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. The mods removed by the bad actors &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be reinstated as mods on r/WallStreetBets, but at the discretion of the current mod team. It’s unclear which of the removed mods may return, or which have been invited to do so. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u7wNGh"&gt;Last week, Discord also had to step in to help moderate a WallStreetBets community. The company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253251/discord-bans-the-r-wallstreetbets-server"&gt;banned the original r/WallStreetBets server&lt;/a&gt; due to “hateful and discriminatory content” and has been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/28/22254339/discord-r-wallstreetbets-server-help-moderation-ban"&gt;helping the mods of the new one&lt;/a&gt; with moderation.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22269093/reddit-r-wallstreetbets-rouge-mod-moderator-takeover"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22269093/reddit-r-wallstreetbets-rouge-mod-moderator-takeover</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-05T18:30:07-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-05T18:30:07-05:00</updated>
    <title>Sonos FCC filing hints it’s coming for the UE Boom and other small Bluetooth speakers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gC6MHEWI_TRACI-0nQrmDDS6Tnk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68777896/dseifert_190826_3622_0017.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6CMqrq"&gt;Sonos is preparing for the release of a new product that, according to FCC documentation, is likely to be the company’s second portable speaker with a rechargeable battery. The unannounced device, &lt;a href="https://fccid.io/SBVRM027"&gt;listed at the FCC as model number S27&lt;/a&gt;, is shown in testing diagrams to have a wireless charging dock and offer both Bluetooth and Wi-Fi 5 (802.11ac) wireless technology.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PESOW0-rZqPH33lx7waZNR32TnE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22285206/Screen_Shot_2021_02_05_at_4.57.55_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://fccid.io/SBVRM027/Label/10-1-S27-FCC-ISED-Label-format-Location-12-14-2020-5097436" target="_blank"&gt;FCC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;FCC diagrams reveal a wireless charging dock.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="41y6tA"&gt;The mandatory FCC label reveals that this new product uses less power than existing Sonos speakers like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/18/20871409/sonos-move-wireless-bluetooth-speaker-review-alexa-google-assistant-wifi-price-specs-sound-quality"&gt;the Sonos Move&lt;/a&gt;, lending more credence to a smaller overall size. The circular label design, and the fact that Sonos says the label is visible on the bottom surface of the product hints that this Sonos speaker could feature a cylindrical design similar to Bluetooth speaker mainstays like the UE Boom.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YDF9ooDzVL5Og2YZqCD9TcUb2GM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22285059/Screen_Shot_2021_02_05_at_1.03.32_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://fccid.io/SBVRM027/Label/10-1-S27-FCC-ISED-Label-format-Location-12-14-2020-5097436" target="_blank"&gt;FCC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="PSj6Wh"&gt;The current Sonos Move’s size and weight help it to put out strong sound, but they also make it a less practical speaker for taking on the go. At a hefty 6.6 pounds, it’s something you’d bring from inside out to your porch, maybe, but Sonos still lacks a speaker portable enough for tossing into a bag and traveling with. S27 might just be the answer for that. The original Move, which was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/9/20799366/sonos-bluetooth-portable-speaker-model-s17"&gt;leaked soon after its own FCC filing&lt;/a&gt;, is model number S17. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ocFbokhKCH3C04RBtuVZZO_rsgs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19208408/dseifert_190915_3647_0007.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The current Sonos Move is far larger than many portable Bluetooth speakers. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="9A8C5W"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10322870"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YSoeGq"&gt;This would also be the first speaker from Sonos to include Wi-Fi 5; the Move supports Wi-Fi 4 (802.11n). Bluetooth would come into play more often when using the speaker outside somewhere, but improved Wi-Fi could help performance when playing it around the home as part of Sonos’ multi-room systems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BZAid2"&gt;Other products that Sonos is rumored to be actively developing include a pair of premium headphones. But a line in one of the FCC documents seems to rule out that we’re looking at those. “For satisfying FCC RF exposure compliance requirements, the device must be used with a separation distance of at least 20 cm from all persons,” it says. So all signs — especially that wireless charger — point to a small, rechargeable device. As much as I’d love to see a Sonos shower head speaker or something a little unconventional, I’m banking on a Move Mini. And hopefully for a price significantly lower than the $400 Move. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22269050/sonos-fcc-filing-mini-move-portable-bluetooth-speaker"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22269050/sonos-fcc-filing-mini-move-portable-bluetooth-speaker</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-05T18:02:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-05T18:02:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>Joe Biden’s executive order on refugees matters a lot for climate migration </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A destroyed community on the banks of the Chemelecon river..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pcOZH6JhNmNz7nfLiSqhvpmaCzo=/0x2:4000x2669/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68777745/1229526982.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;SAN PEDRO SULA, CORTES, HONDURAS - 2020/11/07: In the aftermath of Hurricane Eta, hundreds of thousands of people have been displaced due to flooding. | Photo by Seth Sidney Berry/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WaEjkE"&gt;Joe Biden’s administration is crafting a report that will include proposals for how the US might respond to global migration due to climate change. Biden commissioned the report as part of a broader &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/02/04/executive-order-on-rebuilding-and-enhancing-programs-to-resettle-refugees-and-planning-for-the-impact-of-climate-change-on-migration/"&gt;executive order&lt;/a&gt; he signed yesterday aimed at overhauling the US refugee resettlement program, which was gutted under the Trump administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aHgk3U"&gt;“I’ve worked on this very intersection of issues for over a decade, and I never thought that this would be a part of any American president’s priorities, especially within the first 30 days of their administration,” says Kayly Ober, climate displacement manager at the humanitarian organization Refugees International. “So I am delighted and surprised.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="2sjxz2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A game-changer for people who’ve fled their homes because of climate change&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0I6Y1Z"&gt;If Biden’s report, due in 179 days, leads to an actual pathway to resettlement in the US, it could be a game-changer for people who’ve fled their homes because of climate change. There are currently no policies that allow someone who’s been displaced by climate-related disasters to apply for a visa, green card, or refugee protections in the US. It’s a gap that’s, for the most part, missing globally, too. International institutions literally don’t even have the words to tackle the issue: there’s still a debate over whether to consider displaced people “migrants” or “refugees” since the terminology could affect what legal protections a person is entitled to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WbHhXP"&gt;Meanwhile, an average of &lt;a href="https://www.internal-displacement.org/publications/seizing-the-momentum-displacement-on-the-global-climate-change-agenda"&gt;21.5 million people&lt;/a&gt; are pushed from their homes each year because of climate-related hazards. That includes people who’ve survived disasters like storms and floods that have grown more intense as the planet heats up. For comparison, that’s almost &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/new-framework-us-leadership-climate-migration"&gt;nine times&lt;/a&gt; as many people as those who apply for political asylum because of the fear of persecution in their home country. What’s more, 21.5 million people is likely an underestimate of how many people climate change is actually pushing to the brink. That figure &lt;em&gt;doesn’t&lt;/em&gt; include people on the move because of the slower-moving consequences of climate change like drought and rising sea levels. The number of people seeking new homes as global temperatures rise is only expected to grow. So governments and international organizations need to start acting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vl5kBX"&gt;The US has a big role to play on the global stage when it comes to figuring out how to grapple with climate-driven migration. For one, the US has contributed the most to the climate crisis since it’s emitted &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2019/4/24/18512804/climate-change-united-states-china-emissions"&gt;more greenhouse gases historically&lt;/a&gt; than any other country. That aside, the US has played a leading role in refugee resettlement in the past. For decades until the Trump administration, it accepted &lt;a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2019/06/19/canada-now-leads-the-world-in-refugee-resettlement-surpassing-the-u-s/"&gt;more refugees every year than any other country&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WMNzPv"&gt;“If the US plants a flag that says that they’re willing to figure out a way to offer refugee-like status to people who are displaced by climate change, it will allow other countries to take up their fair share of that burden as well,” says Ober.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="aljzTL"&gt;&lt;q&gt;This executive order is still just a starting point&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qSTdmb"&gt;The executive order signed yesterday is still just a starting point. While Biden has signaled that climate change and immigration will be key priorities for his administration, there need to be real policies in place to impart the kinds of changes he talks about. Sweeping changes to America’s immigration and refugee resettlement will require legislation, as will a plan to wean the US off fossil fuels. The US also needs to stop polluting so much in the first place if it wants to keep climate change from driving displacement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fv1x5v"&gt;“With this climate and migration report, let’s make sure it’s not some sort of risk scenario and planning exercise,” says Ober. “Let’s make sure this is about actually offering a solution, especially for those who are at risk, who are already displaced.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22268961/joe-biden-climate-change-migration-refugees-executive-order"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22268961/joe-biden-climate-change-migration-refugees-executive-order</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-05T17:54:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-05T17:54:30-05:00</updated>
    <title>A German man is keeping $60 million in bitcoin from police by never revealing his password</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PDhPhON_vphR3OBILvcf5GpHaPw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68777659/mdoying_180308_2373_0092still.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Michele Doying / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="I9Cou2"&gt;The wonderful thing about bitcoin is many of its apparent benefits, like the ability to be anonymously owned and securely transferred, are also the things that often create situations like this: police in Germany have seized more than €50 million ($60 million) in bitcoin, but they can’t access any of it because, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-crypto-currency-germany-password/police-seize-60-million-of-bitcoin-now-wheres-the-password-idUSKBN2A511T"&gt;as &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;, the person they took it from won’t tell them his password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZXgUlQ"&gt;The man in question was sentenced and has served his time in jail for covertly installing bitcoin mining software on people’s computers, but throughout the entire process, he never shared a peep about how German authorities should get in. “We asked him but he didn’t say” is the explanation &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; was offered by a prosecutor. It presents a big, and probably obvious, question: can you really seize something, particularly money, that you can’t access or use?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yb0EtT"&gt;The even more glaring issue is how often passwords, PINs, &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/i-forgot-my-pin-an-epic-tale-of-losing-dollar30000-in-bitcoin/"&gt;and their collective absence&lt;/a&gt; pop up in stories about bitcoin, illegal or otherwise. There was &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/12/technology/bitcoin-passwords-wallets-fortunes.html"&gt;a recent story&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; about a programmer with his own bitcoin fortune locked away in a secure hard drive that revealed an amazing statistic: around 20 percent of bitcoin in existence today (totaling around $140 billion) are completely lost or locked up in wallets with lost passwords, meaning they’re completely inaccessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FF9y4t"&gt;So maybe this German bitcoin enthusiast is sticking it to the people who had him locked up, or maybe he’s simply forgotten his password. &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; reports that prosecutors have “ensured the man cannot access [his] largesse” but if they can’t access it either, I think it’s safe to say that pile of lost bitcoin just got a bit larger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ydvpiY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f3S1qe"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y0CHiL"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/2/5/22268646/german-police-bitcoin-digital-wallet-missing-password"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/2/5/22268646/german-police-bitcoin-digital-wallet-missing-password</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-05T17:45:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-05T17:45:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>Someone modded a Game Boy Color to act as a much better Apple TV remote</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CIkCC-1sxHHqVasNJ5FBvs7Rq8A=/0x0:1908x1272/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68777610/Screen_Shot_2021_02_05_at_12.31.38_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Otto Climan&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BEyLzi"&gt;Most people who have used the Apple TV Siri remote have probably craved something that isn’t &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/12/9/21002605/apple-tv-remote-salt-swiss-tv-company-replacement-buttons-normal"&gt;so darn frustrating to use&lt;/a&gt; — but most of us haven’t modded a Game Boy Color to work as one (&lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/i-think-we-can-all-agree-that-a-hacked-apple-themed-gam-1846188094"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). That’s exactly what &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mYPw_wN1a9I"&gt;Italian YouTuber Otto Climan did&lt;/a&gt;, and while his project looks sleek as all get-out, it’s surprising how well it works using the Game Boy’s original hardware. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0n0G3eg1f9fNxOvbMI9LHN3UUHk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22284964/Screen_Shot_2021_02_05_at_12.31.38_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Otto Climan&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wow, that custom case.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TssO1FdG6tIws3JyHjJJrtqOgWo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22284958/Screen_Shot_2021_02_05_at_12.28.47_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Otto Climan&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;That screen is looking nice.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Xm04pU"&gt;First off, we have to talk about the case he used. It was apparently made by a company called &lt;a href="https://www.retromodding.com"&gt;Retro Modding&lt;/a&gt;, specifically for the project, and it looks incredible with its blend of ‘90s Apple and Nintendo aesthetics. (Embarrassingly, it looks better than the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_Pippin#/media/File:Pippin-Atmark-Console-Set.jpg"&gt;actual video game console Apple worked on in the ‘90s&lt;/a&gt;.) If you’re familiar with the Game Boy Color, you may notice that the screen on Climan’s looks a bit crisper and better backlit. In addition to replacing the case, he also gave the screen an upgrade using what looks like another Retro Modding part.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d9FHNBiLgB59O0itxXlioWZ0F_Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22284966/Screen_Shot_2021_02_05_at_12.30.02_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Otto Climan&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The IR blaster is actually original equipment.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="BfuHbs"&gt;Apart from giving it an incredible aesthetic upgrade, though, there wasn’t a ton of hardware hackery needed. The Game Boy Color comes stock with an IR blaster, which the newest Apple TV set still supports. Of course, some custom software was needed to map the buttons to the IR controls.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NEr1Abjrua0UfeHXIsdra6wv6ag=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22284968/Screen_Shot_2021_02_05_at_12.31.56_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Otto Climan&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Climan’s UI for the ROM is clean and minimalist. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lk1gmEZPqb71eTYwn2i_4lYnROw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22284973/Screen_Shot_2021_02_05_at_12.32.05_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Otto Climan&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Even the Game Pak is custom-made and beautiful.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RG2xRSP5IjaqiGbp0P8cROb4dwE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22284987/Screen_Shot_2021_02_05_at_12.28.16_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Otto Climan&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Of course, there’s a time period-appropriate clear version.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="k0S2b3"&gt;I wouldn’t have blamed Climan for using a standard custom ROM cartridge, but of course he had one made that matches the Game Boy’s aesthetic. He loaded a ROM that he programmed with the Apple TV’s IR codes and button mappings, and there you have it: a Game Boy Color that can control an Apple TV. And because it has real directional buttons and not a feisty touchpad, it’s probably better at that task than Apple’s actual remote.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NOo1RW-RAN2_l4I_R0z30hboGT8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22284983/Screen_Shot_2021_02_05_at_12.31.48_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Otto Climan&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pictured: a reasonable navigation UX.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aDSD6qHx9ldSYHpmfGz4UIA7ZxI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22285025/GBC_Remote_Animated_Image__Large_.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF by Otto Climan&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;I need this in my life.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="HkIrAW"&gt;While this project is absolutely incredible, I have an idea for the next iteration: using a Nintendo DS. That way, you can have the touch input if you really want it along with a microphone for Siri support. It doesn’t have an IR blaster or support for Bluetooth like Apple’s remote, but maybe you could add it in with the Game Boy slot, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guitar_Hero:_On_Tour_(series)#/media/File:GuitarHero_On_Tour_Controller.jpg"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Guitar Hero&lt;/em&gt; style&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/22268724/apple-tv-remote-game-boy-color-mod"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/22268724/apple-tv-remote-game-boy-color-mod</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-05T16:57:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-05T16:57:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>Please GameStop it, Hollywood</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sJghYxaf6yktnYkjNRG-CqLEgx8=/0x0:2603x1735/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68777408/gamestop_sean_hollister_stock_photo.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mrbs5G"&gt;Okay, screenwriters, directors, authors, and production companies — we get it. You have some experience telling stories about Wall Street, the video game industry, or social networks, and you see some &lt;em&gt;mighty&lt;/em&gt; big dollar signs in the true tale of how Reddit managed to drive an ailing video game retailer’s stocks to completely ridiculous highs through sheer power of will plus a David versus Goliath narrative that probably &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/this-hedge-fund-made-700-million-on-gamestop-11612390687"&gt;doesn’t hold up under close examination&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JgitZr"&gt;So you’re making movies — four of them&lt;em&gt; — &lt;/em&gt;and a TV show. Why not? It’s not like any one person has the rights to a news event like this! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9B0px3"&gt;As of Friday, February 5th:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="NPyjwt"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/tv/news/gamestop-series-hbo-1234901914/"&gt;HBO now has a movie&lt;/a&gt; from the guy who wrote &lt;em&gt;Too Big to Fail &lt;/em&gt;and co-created Showtime’s &lt;em&gt;Billions&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="L4CGtC"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22261036/wallstreet-bets-movie-adaptation-deals-netflix-mgm"&gt;MGM optioned a movie&lt;/a&gt; based on a book that hasn’t even been written yet&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;whose author you’ll probably know from the book that became David Fincher’s &lt;em&gt;The Social Network&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="bmw51S"&gt;Netflix is negotiating with the screenwriter of &lt;em&gt;The Hurt Locker &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Zero Dark Thirty&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2021/02/netflix-gamestop-stock-movie-screenwriter-mark-boal-noah-centineo-scott-galloway-makeready-1234684568/"&gt;to write yet another movie&lt;/a&gt;, with one of those cute guys &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/12/21134580/netflix-to-all-the-boys-ive-loved-before-release-stream-subscriber"&gt;from &lt;em&gt;To All The Boys I’ve Loved Before&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; playing a role&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cxRrXy"&gt;The writer and director of &lt;em&gt;Console Wars &lt;/em&gt;(a book, also a movie) &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2021/02/jonah-tulis-gamestop-documentary-submarine-1234687991/"&gt;now have a feature-length documentary&lt;/a&gt; that’s “fully financed and already in production”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="IWCNng"&gt;And yes, &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2021/02/pinky-promise-limited-series-to-the-moon-1234684845/"&gt;a TV show&lt;/a&gt;. How can this possibly turn into a TV show?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="DcVG6v"&gt;No. But just in case &lt;em&gt;yes&lt;/em&gt;, we imagine this set of completely disparate productions will need some excellent titles going forward. May we humbly suggest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="x4vgLr"&gt;GameStop: Never Stop Stopping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="9Dbqnx"&gt;Uncut GMEs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EJW0P4"&gt;Meme Streets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="loazlg"&gt;Short Stop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="X0Y6yi"&gt;From Pre-Order to Stock Order&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7RC4H0"&gt;I Have No Shares, and I Must Sell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hQfsZM"&gt;Hate the Player, Not the GME&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="eEfdMO"&gt;The Weeb of Wall Street&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="X6plIl"&gt;The Game is Up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Z1PcBM"&gt;GameStop Won’t Stop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="g416y3"&gt;Diamond Hands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="l6gkQd"&gt;Robinhood and the Men in Gamer Chairs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LBHO7m"&gt;To The Moon, or How I Learned to Stop Worrying and HODL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RJjNcV"&gt;This Theater Still Exists Because of This Movie’s Events (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22251964/amc-stock-price-reddit-wallstreetbets-trading-gamestop"&gt;remember AMC&lt;/a&gt;?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qyXOgV"&gt;The Bankrupting of the Hedge Fund Melvin Capital by the Internet Message Board WallStreetBets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="ZsGbDh"&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.S. The dictionary definition of the word “stonk” is “a concentrated artillery bombardment,” so if I told you there is now a stonk of GameStop movies in development, that would largely be correct.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22268952/gamestop-stock-stonks-reddit-wallstreetbets-movies-tv-shows-hbo-netflix"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/22268952/gamestop-stock-stonks-reddit-wallstreetbets-movies-tv-shows-hbo-netflix</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-05T16:09:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-05T16:09:37-05:00</updated>
    <title>Destruction AllStars no longer turns on voice chat by default, thanks to new hotfix</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9xaxVvgYKXPZSu3J4D3mFLhMnvo=/125x0:1475x900/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68777131/destruction_all_stars_screenshots_19_disclaimer_ps5_en_15oct20.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Characters from &lt;/em&gt;Destruction AllStars&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Sony&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EsgIxC"&gt;Sony released the car-smashing game &lt;em&gt;Destruction AllStars&lt;/em&gt; exclusively for the PlayStation 5 on Tuesday, but it shipped with one very annoying feature: voice chat in multiplayer matches was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/3/22264461/destruction-allstars-voice-chat-default-turn-off-dualsense"&gt;turned on by default&lt;/a&gt;, meaning you could be subject to the unfiltered comments and background noise from your opponents. And worse, it wasn’t immediately obvious how to turn voice chat off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YpM0T2"&gt;On Friday, however, developer Lucid Games addressed the issue by releasing a hotfix for the game that disables voice chat in multiplayer lobbies by default (&lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/you-no-longer-have-to-hear-hate-speech-while-playing-de-1846205888"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Kotaku&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DCYZ7J"&gt;I jumped into a couple of matches with the hotfix installed to test things out, and I was greeted with glorious silence from my fellow players. However, it seems there’s no option for public voice chat at all right now. I couldn’t find a way to turn on voice chat in the game’s menus. Before this patch, you could mute voice chat on a per-match basis with the PlayStation 5’s Activity Cards, and I didn’t see a way to turn on voice chat from those either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xKZGuH"&gt;Perhaps public voice chat will return at some point down the line, though, as Lucid Games &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LucidGamesLtd/status/1357724839180709888"&gt;said it is&lt;/a&gt; “actively working on longer-term enhancements to the voice communications system.” And if you want to play &lt;em&gt;Destruction AllStars&lt;/em&gt; with friends and voice chat with them, that should still work, too. I was able to chat with a &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; colleague as part of a party we made with no issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PxwDaT"&gt;Here are the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LucidGamesLtd/status/1357724840405442567"&gt;full patch notes&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="FHIXDG"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;  Fixed several client crashes relating to Multiplayer Lobbies and UI.&lt;/p&gt;— Lucid Games (@LucidGamesLtd) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LucidGamesLtd/status/1357724840405442567?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 5, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="PbaMPU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"PS5 exclusive Destruction AllStars is the next generation of car crashing","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22261214/destruction-allstars-playstation-5-ps5-sony-interview-cars-demolition-derby"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22268854/destruction-allstars-voice-chat-default-sony-lucid-games-hotfix"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22268854/destruction-allstars-voice-chat-default-sony-lucid-games-hotfix</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-05T15:52:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-05T15:52:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>Patient names and colonoscopy results from US hospitals posted by hackers to the dark web</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/j8cE4orv8zVXCzBYNhooXedDds0=/0x0:2130x1420/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68776984/VRG_ILLO_1777_AK_body_data.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Ana Kova&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zEa8xz"&gt;Patients of two US hospital chains had their names, birthdays, and colonoscopy results posted on the dark web after a hack, &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/security/hackers-post-detailed-patient-medical-records-two-hospitals-dark-web-n1256887"&gt;reported NBC News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; The tens of thousands of files released were from patients at Leon Medical Centers in Miami and Nocona General Hospital in Texas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bLwxyn"&gt;The patient records posted in this hack also include letters to insurers. There does not appear to be ransomware locking up the systems at Nocona, and the organization did not open a ransomware demand, an attorney for the organization told NBC News. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zajmvv"&gt;Cyberattacks on hospitals and health care organizations are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21551050/cyberattacks-hospitals-coronavirus-deadly-tactics"&gt;increasingly common&lt;/a&gt;. These attacks doubled in the second half of 2020 compared to the first half. Two major attacks targeted US health care facilities in the fall. However, cybercriminals typically don’t post patient information publicly. It’s more common for them to introduce a bug that locks up computer systems until the facility pays a ransom and only release data if the ransom isn’t paid.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="5AHazV"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Cybercriminals typically don’t post patient information publicly&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PZFEjp"&gt;It’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/4/18293817/cybersecurity-hospitals-health-care-scan-simulation"&gt;dangerous&lt;/a&gt; for patients when ransomware attacks prevent doctors and nurses from accessing files. They may not be able to see patient health records, which include information about things like medication allergies, or use MRI and CT scan machinery. But it’s also dangerous when hospitals have data breaches — for 30 days after, more people die than usual, probably because people have to devote time to fix the systems rather than focusing entirely on medicine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QfFw8Z"&gt;Most health care organizations are unprepared for cyberattacks and have even fewer resources to devote to the issue after nearly a year fighting COVID-19. “They are financially strapped because of that pandemic,” Caleb Barlow, CEO of cybersecurity consulting firm CynergisTek, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21551050/cyberattacks-hospitals-coronavirus-deadly-tactics"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;in November.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22268778/hospital-hack-patient-data-colonoscopy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22268778/hospital-hack-patient-data-colonoscopy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Wetsman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
