<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-01-12T07:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-12T07:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-12T07:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>CES Day 1: TCL takes its shot and Intel hunkers down</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0niGOAeGhMkknE1uM082mZuo2O8=/0x1:2084x1390/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68654362/TCL8K.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: TCL&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dqRelE"&gt;One of the things that usually happens at CES in Las Vegas is you get a sense that one company or another is really going hard. A few years ago &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/6/16858000/google-assistant-ces-2018-ces-booth"&gt;Google started throwing unseemly amounts of money at an outdoor CES installation&lt;/a&gt; in a bid to show that the Google Assistant was ready to dominate the smart home. It was an acceleration of a trend in the smart home: a battle with Alexa to form an ecosystem. Standing outside the convention center in 2018, that trend loomed large both metaphorically and physically. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="40Lv8K"&gt;Now that CES is online-only, it’s a little harder for companies to puff their chests out and declare that they (or their products) have hit the big time. One company seemed to be doing its very best to try, though: TCL. And another company, Intel, is trying to drum up excitement for its processors even as we’re still goggle-eyed at the performance Apple achieved on its own chips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y8KbF5"&gt;I’ll have some thoughts on both TCL and Intel below, then a roundup of the rest of the biggest news from the first day of CES (including LG’s newer, brighter OLED TVs). Before that, though I’ve got a couple pieces of housekeeping. First, it’s time for the yearly requirement for this newsletter to point you to our &lt;a href="https://www.voxmedia.com/legal/privacy-notice"&gt;privacy notice&lt;/a&gt;, which I’m told has no major changes this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="dfhY2J"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9028921"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ELlrdk"&gt;Second, we have a new newsletter! &lt;strong&gt;Verge Deals&lt;/strong&gt; is a weekly email rounding up some of the best deals on gadgets our commerce team has found. You &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/pages/newsletters"&gt;can subscribe here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="upd0Jg"&gt;TCL&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="J7QwcQ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; readers might be most familiar with TCL thanks to its well-received TVs, which provide good quality for good prices. They regularly top our recommended lists because of that value. Last year TCL said it would be trying harder to establish its brand in the US phone market, but it didn’t really take. This year, the company has pulled out all the stops. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fmfjhP"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224277/tcl-tv-xl-collection-8k-6-series-od-zero-announced-ces-2021"&gt;TCL announced the XL Collection line of TVs, vowing to take 8K mainstream this year&lt;/a&gt;. TCL has that reputation for value, but it what it &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; wants is to be considered a tech innovator — in the same class as Sony, Samsung, and LG. As Chris Welch notes, the company went so far as to publish a “prickly” blog post that touted its early adoption of Mini LED technology. It also took a shot at OLED TV technology, which is functionally equivalent to taking a shot at LG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ix4uCV"&gt;TCL is also trying to get you to associate it with other categories of products. It is readying &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22221389/tcl-wearable-display-glasses-moveaudio-s600-pet-tracker-ces"&gt;Wearable Display glasses for launch, new wireless buds, a pet tracker&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22219269/tcl-nxtpaper-tablet-color-display-ereader"&gt;TCL NXTPAPER, a cross between a tablet and an e-reader&lt;/a&gt;. That last gadget has an interesting LCD screen that behaves a bit more like e-paper yet provides full color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q1ejzQ"&gt;TCL’s phone announcements today included &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22219101/tcl-20-5g-20-se-android-phone-price-specs"&gt;two low-end 5G phones with the promise of more to come&lt;/a&gt;. When I saw that, I joked that “TCL” stands for “Tryin’ to Copy LG.” But the more I think about it, the more I think it’s not a joke. When it comes to phones, TCL is in fact trying to occupy the space LG used to take up. It has 5G phones ready to go and wants to be the brand carriers turn to when they want something less expensive than Samsung and Apple to sell to customers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bcY2jt"&gt;TCL is flooding the zone with inexpensive smartphones this year, part of its overall push to gain more brand recognition in the US. So it’s not about copying LG after all — it’s about supplanting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9rNr0G"&gt;Why should TCL’s push matter to you? In a word: competition. Even if you don’t buy a TCL gadget this year, it’s worth watching to see if the pressure it’s trying to bring to bear will have any impact. Or if, like so many things at CES, it’s all for show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="FllMUL"&gt;Intel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="RxZTyD"&gt;Intel is another company that tried to tell a big story about big changes this year. Intel has tried to use CES as a launch point to bolster its brand more than once. The most notable recent example would be 2018, when its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/9/16867298/intel-keynote-ces-2018-brian-krzanich-behind-the-scenes-show-meltdown-spectre"&gt;flamboyant keynote happened immediately after a series of very bad security problems for its chips&lt;/a&gt;. The whole issue cast a shadow over the proceedings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DCMmHY"&gt;No security problems this year, but there’s still a shadow. This time it’s being cast by Apple, which recently introduced the truly superb M1 Arm-based chip on its laptops and gave Intel the boot in the process. Now I usually dislike the way these chip battles are sometimes set up because it’s too reductive: the PC market is vast and multifaceted. But Apple’s chips are such a big deal that there’s really no way to think about Intel and PCs without reference to how the company suddenly has a competitor that is producing systems vastly more efficient than Intel can manage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nMElSm"&gt;It’s not reasonable to expect Intel to have a full response to the M1 already, but it turns out the company does plan on introducing something &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225514/intel-12th-gen-hybrid-alder-lake-chips-2h-ces-2021"&gt;later this year that could be competitive in the form of its 12th Gen chips, dubbed Alder Lake&lt;/a&gt;. I have no idea if Intel can come anywhere close to the performance per watt Apple has achieved, but I do like that Intel is pushing to experiment with the the overall package of high-performance and high-efficiency cores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="I0mRHY"&gt;But what’s notable is Intel’s scope here, with plans for hybrid chips that will scale far beyond simple mobile devices. The timing is particularly apt: the Alder Lake chips represent Intel’s closest product to Arm-based chips that are built like the game-changing M1 processors that Apple introduced in November. The fact that Intel is looking to scale its hybrid chips across its lineup could indicate that the company is looking to emulate Apple’s Arm success with its own technology going forward — an intriguing idea, particularly as Intel’s more traditional chip strategies continue to face delays.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="TUaE28"&gt;The knock on Intel is that it can’t seem to get it together and transition its chips down to the 10nm and 7nm processes that power so much of the competition. That knock is well deserved, but it too is reductive in some ways. Even under the constraints of 14nm, Intel does have a few things coming that could power some pretty great devices this year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1255838446"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225541/intel-processor-11th-gen-ces-2021-chips-specs"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intel’s new Core i9-11900K flagship processor will arrive in early 2021 &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="qclnM8"&gt;Despite the 11th Gen moniker, though, the new Rocket Lake-S chips are still technically 14nm chips — they don’t use the 10nm process. However, they do feature Intel’s Cypress Cove cores, which bring over the 10nm core design back to 14nm, allowing for faster speeds along with Intel’s faster Xe integrated graphics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="1255837745"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225370/intel-11th-gen-h-series-chips-ultraportable-gaming-laptop-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intel’s latest 11th Gen H-series chips promise the fastest ultraportable gaming laptops yet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="IKlQHh"&gt;So while the new 35W H-series chips won’t be the processors found in the beefiest and best gaming laptops money can buy, they will offer some pretty impressive performance — meaning smaller or lighter laptops could start punching above their weight class, even with smaller core counts and less thermal headroom.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="Ty0iRc"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Fe6RRT"&gt;Laptops and PCs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="6T74ny"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22218445/microsoft-surface-pro-7-plus-features-price-specs-release-date"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft’s new Surface Pro 7 Plus has a bigger battery, removable SSD, and LTE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; All good additions, and it’s good Microsoft recognized this is a “Plus” update and not a full revision. Because the design here still looks stale compared to the Surface Pro X. Which makes me wonder what will come first: an Intel chip in a Surface Pro X, an Arm-based chip with powerful performance in the Surface Pro X, or the heat death of the universe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZGihnb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22221393/lenovo-thinkpad-x12-detachable-convertible-laptop-price-release-date"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lenovo’s ThinkPad X12 Detachable has a 12-inch screen that’s, well, detachable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s a dead-ahead ThinkPad take on the Surface Pro and in some ways it’s what I wish Microsoft would do. Slightly updated design that still feels classically “ThinkPad” with some very utilitarian benefits (MIL-SPEC 810G for durability), but sadly not enough ports. Excited to see this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1255857053"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224455/hp-elite-folio-announced-arm-convertible-laptop-specs-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HP announces Snapdragon-powered Elite Folio convertible&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Unique form factor and checks a lot of spec boxes. I just wish I could trust that Windows on Arm will be good enough this year to recommend to most people. Some people will get huge benefit out of this, though, as long as they know what they’re getting into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="jrfDrS"&gt;The processor is Qualcomm’s new Snapdragon 8cx Gen 2, and there’s also LTE and 5G connectivity through the X20 and X55 modems. The Folio can be configured with up to 16GB of RAM and 512GB of storage. There are two USB-C 3.2 ports and a headphone jack. HP is claiming up to 24.5 hours of battery life when watching locally stored video files, but we’ll have to see for ourselves how that plays out in more realistic workloads.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="sCmh6H"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/1/11/22225044/western-digital-portable-ssds-storage-4tb-price-announced"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Western Digital doubles the storage in its portable SSDs to 4TB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; It won’t work very well as external storage for next-gen consoles, but it could be a boon for video creators on the go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hn8A88"&gt;Smart home&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="5nBLKo"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22195916/chamberlain-myq-pet-portal-dog-door-price-date"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Chamberlain built a $3,000 automatic garage door for your dog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Sean Hollister, with a big and interesting look behind the scenes of developing a new product:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="0W1onf"&gt;So instead of building yet another flap, the garage door opener company set out to build an entire door of its own — with a doggie portal that would completely seal and lock when it closes. Preferably, it’d be a pet door you wouldn’t even know was there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="ajHNc5"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224950/lutron-caseta-outdoor-smart-plug-lights-severe-weather"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lutron’s outdoor smart plug can control your lights through any season&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Oh this is smart. Separating out the computer guts from the outdoor lighting is a really good idea, as outdoor lighting is way more diverse and less standardized than indoor bulbs — by necessity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YAG7tq"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224649/samsung-bot-handy-care-robots-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samsung is making a robot that can pour wine and bring you a drink&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; The “bring me a beer” test is the robot equivalent of the Turing test and this seems to pass. But as usual with Samsung’s CES robots, it’s not really going to be produced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EjMBGp"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22203382/netgear-nighthawk-raxe500-wifi-6e-5g-moden-wireless-router-price-release-date"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Netgear’s new Nighthawk RAXE500 is its first Wi-Fi 6E router&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K0VRMy"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22213115/tp-link-wifi-6e-first-routers-mesh-smart-speaker"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TP-Link’s first Wi-Fi 6E routers are coming this year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1255848959"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22221253/linksys-aware-tracking-motion-detection-wifi-6e-axe8400-router-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linksys’ mesh router motion-tracking system can now work with other smart home gadgets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Creepy? Maybe. Clever? Absolutely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="qJmHWG"&gt;The original Aware motion-sensing system detects how Wi-Fi signals bounce around your house between routers in a mesh system. Movement naturally interferes with those signals, allowing the routers to act as a motion-sensing setup without the need for any additional hardware. ... Now, Linksys is adding support to leverage other internet-connected smart home products — like speakers, smart switches, and thermostats&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="FNWOzO"&gt;TVs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="aSpK7c"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224271/lg-2021-tvs-oled-qned-g1-c1-a1-announced-specs-ces"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LG’s 2021 TV lineup includes its brightest OLED ever&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; LG’s whole lineup is detailed in this post, but the brightness is the most important part. The “bright room” thing is second only to high prices when it comes to things that make me reticent about OLED (burn-in is third, but it’s a distant third).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="apBLxu"&gt;Brightness has remained a winning factor for LCD TVs over many years; despite perfect blacks and amazing viewing angles, sometimes an OLED set just won’t get the job done if you stick it in an ultra-bright room. But LG says the Evo panel found in its new G1 series — succeeding 2020’s GX lineup — can crank higher than any of its previous OLED TVs for improved luminosity and HDR. LG likens this achievement to past OLED milestones like 4K HDR and the introduction of 8K.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="yNjU20"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22223767/lg-webos-6-tv-software-oled-qned-lcd-redesign"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LG is overhauling its webOS TV software — and maybe ruining it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; ”Look how they massacred my boy,” &lt;em&gt;The Godfather&lt;/em&gt;, 1972 and also me, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1255855559"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224359/google-stadia-nvidia-geforce-now-lg-tv-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Stadia and GeForce Now are coming to LG TVs in 2021&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1255849196"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224922/lg-ultrafine-oled-pro-4k-monitor-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LG announces a stunning 4K OLED monitor for creative pros&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Not a TV but it’s very pretty so I’m including it. Some time ago Apple anointed an LG monitor as the go-to display for its computers. It was and is a very nice monitor — and this seems like it will be a worthy successor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1255851575"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225768/sony-bravia-core-movie-platform-service-xr-television-quality-stream"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sony promises streaming quality nearly as good as 4K Blu-ray on Bravia Core movie service&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Julia Alexander:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="3Wj12T"&gt;Bravia Core isn’t going to replace Netflix, but it seems like it was specifically designed to show customers the ultimate capabilities of their new TV set. Kind of like when you buy a TV with true 4K HDR capabilities, and you play the best 4K YouTube channels to try to see the difference between your new set and that old clunker you just tossed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="CLSJj2"&gt;Gadgets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="TWrPlF"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225758/sony-airpeak-drone-alpha-photography-cameras-ces-2021-announcement"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is Sony’s Airpeak drone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; A Sony drone designed to carry Sony Alpha cameras is a Very Big Deal for filmmakers from amateur to pro. There are still lots of open questions, but keep an eye out for this thing to make an impact. Small piece of advice: make sure the sociopaths in charge of Sony’s camera software interfaces are kept far, far away from this thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DCj8Iv"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225605/vuzix-microled-smart-glasses-next-gen-ar-heads-up-display-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vuzix’s new microLED smart glasses look like something you’d actually want to wear on your face&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Vuzix is a CES staple, showing some form of on-face displays for almost as many years as I can remember. Usually it’s clear they’re designing for industrial applications, but this year’s version is the most consumer-friendly I’ve seen yet. It’s a good example of a company making small, iterative improvements out in the open, year after year, without fanfare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rFB6SL"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225023/coldsnap-ice-cream-pod-machine-froyo-frozen-cocktails-ces-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally you can have ice cream at home thanks to ice cream pods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; My goal for 2021 is to distribute the very newsletter you’re reading right now via pods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1255855988"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22218777/ysl-beaute-rouge-sur-mesure-perso-ces-gadget-2021"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YSL’s lipstick pod gadget will create whatever shade you want&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; POD ALL THE THINGS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="KkPVqW"&gt;Phone accessories&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="qiexxE"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224469/oneplus-band-release-date-price-features-india-heart-rate-battery-life-exercise-modes"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OnePlus’ first wearable is a budget fitness tracker with two-week battery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; These look alright!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="iezjuO"&gt;The OnePlus Band includes a rectangular 1.1-inch OLED display with a resolution of 126x294 and a silicone watch strap. It’s available in black, navy, and “tangerine gray,” and it’s got a dust and water resistance rating of IP68. Its 5ATM rating means it’s water-resistant at a depth up to 50 meters for 10 minutes. Internally there’s a 100mAh battery, which OnePlus says should offer up to two weeks of battery life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="fP7lSM"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225701/popsockets-magsafe-accessory"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PopSockets are going MagSafe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; I love PopSockets but I am VERY dubious that this is a good idea. One of the most important things a PopSocket provides is a sense that you have a more reliable grip on your phone, that it’s less likely to drop. MagSafe is strong but it’s not strong enough for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1255843337"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;┏ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22223494/qualcomm-ultrasonic-fingerprint-reader-samsung-galaxy-s21-announcement"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Qualcomm’s second-gen ultrasonic fingerprint reader is bigger and faster than the original&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; I’d gotten used to the half-a-beat-longer in-screen fingerprint sensors take to unlock, but I went back to using a Pixel 5 this past winter and damn, I forgot how much faster traditional sensors are. Really hope Qualcomm’s speed promises pan out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QHi701"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wWxHut"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MNVxC6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SucIIF"&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="1255849229"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="or9uyG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1255847879"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226110/ces-2021-recap-tcl-intel-lg-sony"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226110/ces-2021-recap-tcl-intel-lg-sony</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-12T07:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-12T07:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Yelp lets you tattle on places that don’t enforce masks and social distancing</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/O1y9uUSHcY6uOl8F7PC3i07bDiE=/0x0:4500x3000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68654347/Compliant_and_Noncompliant_Health___Safety_Restaurant_Example.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A green tick will be shown if users report a business is following the measures.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Yelp&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dlXhPy"&gt;Yelp is adding a new option that lets customers provide feedback on whether a business is enforcing COVID-19 safety guidelines, the company announced today. Initially, users will be able to report whether staff at a business are wearing masks, and whether they’re enforcing proper social distancing guidelines. The aim is to “instill confidence in consumers to continue supporting local businesses,” Yelp says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jjPQtr"&gt;You’ll be able to provide feedback on a business’ safety measures via its page on Yelp, either through survey questions or by tapping the “Edit” icon in the top-right of a page’s COVID-19 updates section. The listing will display either a green check mark or an orange question mark next to the listed safety measures, depending on what a majority of users report. The icons shown will be based on an overall consensus from visitors, and only count responses over the last 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AvyoZE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7rA139"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226545/yelp-covid-19-safety-measures-mask-wearing-social-distancing"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226545/yelp-covid-19-safety-measures-mask-wearing-social-distancing</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-12T06:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-12T06:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>GM teases new Chevy Bolt with Super Cruise, sets release date for February</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/n--T2cok-o5IFVKcPvQzhBM6C08=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68654294/akrales_170313_1481_A_0019.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fZwTgQ"&gt;GM says that two new versions of the Chevy Bolt are set to be unveiled in February 2021. The company has released a new teaser that highlights a new feature coming to the electric vehicles: GM’s well-regarded advanced driver assist system, Super Cruise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g2v3Q1"&gt;GM is planning to release a refreshed Chevy Bolt, which was first released in 2017, as well as a Bolt Electric Utility Vehicle, or EUV. The teaser was timed to coincide with GM CEO Mary Barra’s keynote speech at the 2021 Consumer Electronics Show — which is being held virtually this year because of the coronavirus pandemic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dGXTq1"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Chevrolet Bolt teaser|100186" data-volume-uuid="6e31a291d" data-volume-id="100186" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-620" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AK25Ak"&gt;The refreshed Bolt will &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/26/21401302/gm-chevy-bolt-tease-image-electric-ev"&gt;feature a sportier look&lt;/a&gt;, new seats, adaptive cruise control, and a few other minor changes. GM bumped up the range &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/22/20828821/2020-chevy-bolt-259-miles-battery-upgrade"&gt;in this past year’s version of the Bolt&lt;/a&gt;, from 238 miles to 259 miles, but no further increase is expected in the refresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="kDjsOz"&gt;&lt;q&gt;A major change will be the inclusion of Super Cruise&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="t50n7x"&gt;The Bolt EUV (not an acronym we expect to catch on, but go off I guess) will have a longer wheelbase than the regular Bolt and should appeal to customers looking for a more crossover SUV look than hatchback. The EUV looks longer than the regular Bolt but that much taller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uHzvcR"&gt;A major change will be the inclusion of Super Cruise, GM’s “hands free” advanced driver assist system. When it first debuted in 2017, Super Cruise drew immediate comparisons to Tesla’s Autopilot system. It uses cameras, radar, and LIDAR mapping data, combined with a robust driver monitoring system, to take a lot of stress out of highway driving. When engaged, drivers can take their feet off the pedals and hands off the steering wheel, and the car generally drives itself on divided highways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gVPgcc"&gt;The two new Bolts are the latest GM vehicles to get Super Cruise, and the first from Chevrolet. Super Cruise is also available in the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/3/16709660/cadillac-ct6-super-cruise-self-driving-holidays"&gt;2018 Cadillac CT6&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/28/18515802/cadillac-super-cruise-ct5-ny-auto-show-2019"&gt;2021 Cadillac CT5 and CT4&lt;/a&gt;, the&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/16/21024331/cadillac-escalade-2021-38-inch-curved-oled-screen"&gt; 2021 Cadillac Escalade&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/20/21525290/hummer-ev-electric-truck-gmc-price-specs-range"&gt;GMC Hummer EV&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qGYyOc"&gt;Both the Bolt EV and Bolt EUV will be built on GM’s BEV2 platform, which is distinct from the new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/16/21439374/gm-unveils-ultium-drive-family-of-electric-motors"&gt;“Ultium” battery pack&lt;/a&gt; announced in early 2020. The recently unveiled &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/6/21357717/cadillac-lyriq-gm-ev-suv-touchscreen-size-specs-release-date"&gt;Cadillac Lyriq&lt;/a&gt; and the GMC Hummer EV will be the first vehicles to be built on this new electric architecture. As such, the Bolt EV and EUV were expected to go into production at the end of 2020 but were &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/1/21203020/refreshed-chevy-bolt-delay-coronavirus-covid-19"&gt;delayed until this year&lt;/a&gt; due to the coronavirus pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NoI1Z2"&gt;The new Bolts can’t come quick enough, given the controversy surrounding the current versions of the EV. GM was recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/22135764/chevy-bolt-batteries-catching-fire-class-action-lawsuit"&gt;slapped with a class action lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; alleging that the Chevy Bolt’s battery is “prone to burst into flames.” The lawsuit comes on the heels of GM announcing that it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/13/21564217/gm-chevy-bolt-recall-battery-fire-lg-chem"&gt;recalling 68,000 Bolts&lt;/a&gt; over a malfunctioning battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cNZMcS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226098/gm-chevy-bolt-electric-car-tease-super-cruise-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226098/gm-chevy-bolt-electric-car-tease-super-cruise-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-12T06:06:10-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-12T06:06:10-05:00</updated>
    <title>LG’s Rollable phone is real and launching in 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="LG’s Rollable phone." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/g2JsLPB2aTOESeBVp2QgQB7R4hU=/63x0:738x450/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68654276/lgrollable.5.gif" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BYZPz4"&gt;LG &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22224591/lg-rollable-phone-extending-display-teaser-ces-2021"&gt;teased its Rollable phone&lt;/a&gt; yesterday at the Consumer Electronics Show, and now the company is confirming it’s a real product that will be available in 2021. The LG Rollable has what the company calls a “unique resizable screen” that extends from a phone into a small tablet display. The screen slides in and out of place to provide a bigger screen area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o2UBIR"&gt;“Our management wanted to show that it is a real product, as there were many rumors around the rollable phone,” says an LG spokesperson in a &lt;a href="https://asia.nikkei.com/Business/CES-2021/LG-to-release-world-s-first-rollable-smartphone-developed-with-BOE"&gt;statement to &lt;em&gt;Nikkei&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “As it is released at CES 2021, I can tell that it will be launched this year.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xg1zXf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nikkei &lt;/em&gt;also reports that LG is working with China’s BOE Technology Group on the rollable screen technology. LG has not yet confirmed what display tech the Rollable is using, or any details on the different display sizes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xBfIxp8m7s2ODj8XyglH2RUF9Lk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21990608/cgartenberg_201022_4254_0009.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The LG Wing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fr2MA9"&gt;LG first started working on the Rollable as part of the company’s “Explorer Project” experiments. The company has used this project to previously launch its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21536659/lg-wing-review-dual-screen-price-specs-features"&gt;LG Wing smartphone&lt;/a&gt;, with a rotating design and two OLED displays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H2S3qG"&gt;Now that LG has branded its new LG Rollable phone and confirmed it’s coming to market this year, we’ll likely see a race among phone manufacturers to roll this rollable screen technology out. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2020/3/5/21165069/tcl-foldable-trifold-phone-hands-on-rollable-concept-prototype-display-tablet"&gt;TCL also demonstrated&lt;/a&gt; future phone concepts back in March, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/17/21571056/oppo-x-2021-rolling-phone-ar-glass-concept-inno-day-2020"&gt;Oppo teased&lt;/a&gt; a concept device with an expandable OLED display late last year.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226532/lgs-rollable-phone-launch-release-date-ces-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226532/lgs-rollable-phone-launch-release-date-ces-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-12T05:31:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-12T05:31:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter bans 70,000 QAnon accounts as conservatives report lost followers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_2xU6wTn1zVBIeOLTcTYYqyNBSk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68654209/acastro_180827_1777_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZSGoAu"&gt;Twitter has permanently suspended over 70,000 accounts since Friday in an attempt to clamp down on QAnon-fueled conspiracies on its service, &lt;a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/company/2021/protecting%E2%80%94the-conversation-following-the-riots-in-washington%E2%80%94.html"&gt;the company has announced&lt;/a&gt;. It says the accounts were “engaged in sharing harmful QAnon-associated content at scale and were primarily dedicated to the propagation of this conspiracy theory across the service.” At the same time, prominent conservative voices on Twitter complained about lost followers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gnkPE8"&gt;Twitter began suspending accounts on Friday afternoon, two days after President Trump incited a mob that broke into the US Capitol building. Twitter categorized the suspensions as part of an attempt to “protect the conversation on [its] service from attempts to incite violence, organize attacks, and share deliberately misleading information about the election outcome.” &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/01/11/trump-twitter-ban/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; notes&lt;/a&gt; that there were a large amount of QAnon followers among last week’s rioters, including the self-described “QAnon Shaman” photographed shirtless inside the Capitol wearing horns and a fur hat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="vHOlKp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The company banned 7,000 QAnon-related accounts last July&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QN5m0r"&gt;Twitter’s suspension of QAnon accounts coincided with some prominent GOP members complaining about lost followers — namely, those supporting false claims of a stolen election. Republican representative &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mattgaetz/status/1348079725353324544"&gt;Matt Gaetz complained&lt;/a&gt; of having lost tens of thousands of followers, a claim which is supported by data from &lt;a href="https://socialblade.com/twitter/user/mattgaetz"&gt;Social Blade&lt;/a&gt;. Similar drops were observed for figures like &lt;a href="https://socialblade.com/twitter/user/tedcruz"&gt;Ted Cruz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://socialblade.com/twitter/user/hawleymo"&gt;Josh Hawley&lt;/a&gt;, and elected &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/03/us/politics/qanon-candidates-marjorie-taylor-greene.html"&gt;QAnon supporter&lt;/a&gt; from Georgia &lt;a href="https://socialblade.com/twitter/user/mtgreenee"&gt;Marjorie Taylor Greene&lt;/a&gt;. All had been regularly gaining followers prior to the QAnon purge that Twitter says began on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1X65A4V85FRlhVVX1Q6Q3SbuWa4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22229808/msedge_n0a6X0QrR1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://socialblade.com/twitter/user/mtgreenee" target="_blank"&gt;SocialBlade.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marjorie Taylor Greene, Republican representative from Georgia, has lost tens of thousands of followers since Twitter started banning QAnon accounts on Friday.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fnVcqR"&gt;The amount of Twitter accounts suspended is a marked escalation compared to previous crackdowns detailed by the social media company, and follows one of the most striking examples yet of the real-world impact of online misinformation. Last July, the company announced it had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/21/21333570/twitter-crackdown-qanon-conspiracy-ban-search-trending"&gt;banned 7,000 accounts&lt;/a&gt; in relation to the QAnon conspiracy theory. Although its latest crackdown has banned tens of thousands of profiles, Twitter says that single individuals were operating “numerous” accounts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lCMt9w"&gt;As well as suspending accounts directly, Twitter says it has applied restrictions on other accounts which have tweeted or retweeted “associated content.” It has reduced the visibility of these accounts across search, replies, and timelines, and will not recommend them to others on Twitter. It’s also asking other accounts suspected of spamming to verify their authenticity, which can cause them to temporarily disappear from follower counts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yR6vcq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226503/twitter-qanon-account-suspension-70000-capitol-riots"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226503/twitter-qanon-account-suspension-70000-capitol-riots</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T20:56:29-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T20:56:29-05:00</updated>
    <title>Ubiquiti, maker of prosumer routers and access points, has had a data breach</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uakJkN-cvYQweiw7PE4mwoRk7Pw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68653361/acastro_170629_1777_0008.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="N9l1Ly"&gt;Ubiquiti, the company I bought networking gear from because I wanted Wi-Fi that’s totally under my control, now tells me something may not have been under my control after all: my basic account information. According to an email it’s sending out to users today, a “third party cloud provider” was accessed by an unauthorized user, and that provider might possibly have some of our data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="thJmnw"&gt;While the company says it isn’t hasn’t found any evidence that our user data has been accessed, it also “cannot be certain that user data has not been exposed”. The potential data at risk will be familiar if you’ve received these kinds of emails before: names, emails, phone numbers, addresses, and (encrypted, hopefully unreadable) passwords. You’ll want to change your password now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="reeNsw"&gt;It doesn’t sound like that bad a breach as breaches go, but it’s annoying news to hear from a company that prides itself on giving users control. If I had wanted my data on someone else’s server, I might have picked a router that gave me some benefit for it, like plug-and-play setup. The database of customer info, it seems, is hard to get away from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5FXzYl"&gt;The full email text, which can also be &lt;a href="https://community.ui.com/questions/Account-Notification/96467115-49b5-4dd6-9517-f8cdbf6906f3"&gt;viewed on the Ubiquiti forums&lt;/a&gt;, is below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="C1huiT"&gt;We recently became aware of unauthorized access to certain of our information technology systems hosted by a third party cloud provider. We have no indication that there has been unauthorized activity with respect to any user’s account.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We are not currently aware of evidence of access to any databases that host user data, but we cannot be certain that user data has not been exposed. This data may include your name, email address, and the one-way encrypted password to your account (in technical terms, the passwords are hashed and salted). The data may also include your address and phone number if you have provided that to us.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As a precaution, we encourage you to change your password. We recommend that you also change your password on any website where you use the same user ID or password. Finally, we recommend that you enable two-factor authentication on your Ubiquiti accounts if you have not already done so.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We apologize for, and deeply regret, any inconvenience this may cause you. We take the security of your information very seriously and appreciate your continued trust.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Thank you,&lt;br&gt;Ubiquiti Team&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="bSH3ES"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22226061/ubiquiti-data-breach-email-third-party-unathorized-access"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22226061/ubiquiti-data-breach-email-third-party-unathorized-access</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T20:12:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T20:12:21-05:00</updated>
    <title>Salesforce says it has taken action against the RNC, but won’t say how</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Trump Supporters Hold “Stop The Steal” Rally In DC Amid Ratification Of Presidential Election" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qDxQ-EHGGqV2EZ_ZfOgVAbXKaAg=/0x0:7200x4800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68653217/1294967493.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="e1gtPE"&gt;Salesforce has “taken action” to stop the Republication National Committee (RNC) from sending emails that could incite violence, though the company won’t say what that action is. The RNC is using ExactTarget, a Salesforce tool, for campaign emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mx5h5o"&gt;The move, first reported by &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/pkdmdv/salesforce-takes-action-to-prevent-rnc-emails-from-inciting-violence"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; comes after the Trump campaign sent an email urging supporters to “step up RIGHT NOW” and “defend the integrity of this Election” shortly before the breach of the US Capitol on January 6th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="5qTElO"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The enterprise software company declined to elaborate on what action it has taken&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="k5axVT"&gt;Salesforce confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that it hasn’t dropped the RNC as a client. “The Republican National Committee has been a long-standing customer, predating the current Administration,” a spokesperson said. “We have taken action to prevent its use of our services in any way that could lead to violence.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tPy8sL"&gt;The enterprise software company declined to elaborate on what action it has taken and whether the mysterious measure would affect the Trump campaign, as well as the RNC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cj6KmW"&gt;Before the attack, the Trump campaign sent emails saying the election was rigged and the results needed to be overturned. The campaign sent 569 emails between November 3rd and January 6th, including four emails the morning of the breach, &lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt; reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xexZmN"&gt;Each email asked supporters to donate money to the campaign. While it’s not known how big the ExactTarget email list was, in 2018, the &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/13/us/politics/trump-political-data.html"&gt;Trump campaign reportedly had contact information for 20 million supporters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uORcD5"&gt;The RNC told &lt;em&gt;Motherboard&lt;/em&gt; that it had ‘independently’ decided to stop its digital fundraising efforts on January 6th. The following day, another email service — Campaign Monitor — suspended the Trump campaign’s account. That alone would make it harder for the campaign to raise money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="iAep0k"&gt;&lt;q&gt;We can’t know for sure, because Salesforce won’t answer our questions&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0csf3M"&gt;Social media platforms are also taking action against Trump in the wake of the attacks in DC. On January 7th, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22218725/facebook-trump-ban-extended-capitol-riot-insurrection-block"&gt;Facebook blocked the president indefinitely&lt;/a&gt;, and at least until Joe Biden’s inauguration. The following day, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22218753/twitter-bans-trump-permanently-realdonaldtrump"&gt;Twitter permanently banned Trump’s account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cs9J6Z"&gt;The news from Salesforce isn’t quite so decisive. Perhaps, like Campaign Monitor, the company is making it more difficult for Trump to fundraise. We can’t know for sure, because Salesforce won’t answer our questions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xtf6be"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CWj5e1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EYLMl7"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NMKnOA"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225936/salesforce-stop-rnc-sending-emails-incite-violence"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225936/salesforce-stop-rnc-sending-emails-incite-violence</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T19:55:12-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T19:55:12-05:00</updated>
    <title>Some monster scraped Trump’s name into this poor manatee’s back</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xXAH84Qo8PbmmlU3XWRSXhQMrC4=/102x0:1598x997/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68653127/5ffc72b6af600.image.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Citrus County Chronicle&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uS2QuH"&gt;Last week was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/9/22221669/what-just-happened-this-week-trump-social-media-capitol-twitter-facebook-parler"&gt;a cacophony of horrible Trump-related news&lt;/a&gt;, but this is the one that hit home hardest for me: a manatee with his name scraped into its back was found in the headwaters of Florida’s Homosassa river (&lt;a href="https://www.chronicleonline.com/news/local/federal-officials-seek-information-on-manatee-harassment/article_c84a3b66-5423-11eb-93b6-1bf69750167f.html"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Citrus County Chronicle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). At the moment it’s unclear whether the animal was actually injured, or if the name was just scraped into the algae on its back, but it’s a crime either way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gy90Yo"&gt;While US Fish and Wildlife officials told the &lt;em&gt;Chronicle&lt;/em&gt; that they “[could not] comment on a current, ongoing investigation”, they’re asking anyone who may have information about who did this to reach out to the Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission. The Center for Biological Diversity &lt;a href="https://biologicaldiversity.org/w/news/press-releases/5000-reward-offered-for-info-on-trump-carved-into-florida-manatees-back-2021-01-11/"&gt;is also offering a $5,000 reward&lt;/a&gt; for information that leads to a conviction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1RmTGu"&gt;An investigation could be difficult, though — manatees are, of course, live creatures, and while this particular one was found near a local swimming spot called Blue Hole, it’ll be hard to figure out where the manatee was when someone did this to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7rrUi7"&gt;If the person is caught, however, it won’t be good news for them. Manatees &lt;a href="https://myfwc.com/wildlifehabitats/wildlife/manatee/"&gt;are classified as threatened&lt;/a&gt;, and are therefore fall under the federal Endangered Species Protection Act. If someone is found to have criminally harassed a manatee, they could be facing up to a $50,000 fine, a year in jail, or both. Even just chasing a manatee while it’s swimming is considered harassment, so imagine scraping something into one’s back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JjLBUy"&gt;I lived in Florida for 15 years, and was on the water a lot. If there’s one thing that’s extraordinarily clear, it’s that you &lt;em&gt;should not&lt;/em&gt; mess with the manatees. There are signs on every public dock telling boaters to watch out for manatees, and every natural science museum I went to had an exhibit on how manatees were threatened by motorboats and human activity. I vividly remember camping trips where rangers told us that we had to stop swimming in Manatee Springs because, surprise, there were manatees there, and they were not to be disturbed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FY0559"&gt;Getting to see them up close was a literally awesome experience, and it provided the one good piece of news that I can give you: manatees are tough creatures, and I’ve seen many swimming around with scars from boat propellers. Despite someone being so thoughtless as to scrape anything into its back, it should hopefully be okay. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225867/manatee-harassed-with-trumps-name"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225867/manatee-harassed-with-trumps-name</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T18:25:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T18:25:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>Only one person showed up to the pro-Trump protest outside Twitter’s San Francisco HQ</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GZm6SDx-Q8bGaID_348OK8S6298=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68652818/vpavic_210111_4366_0039.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rare pro-Trump protester Rebecca Brooks came to show her discontent toward Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey who is “silencing conservative voices.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;30 police officers were there to monitor the scene&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="JrPhIK"&gt;It’s the second week of 2021. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/9/22221669/what-just-happened-this-week-trump-social-media-capitol-twitter-facebook-parler"&gt;Last week&lt;/a&gt; began with an insurrection, siege of the US Capitol building, and rejection of democracy, and it ended with all major social media companies banning the one-time impeached 45th president of the United States, Donald J. Trump. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yymacB"&gt;One of those companies was Twitter. On the Donald.win forum, Trump supporters announced a plan to show their discontent by protesting in front of the San Francisco headquarters earlier today. The building was empty, with Twitter employees working from home to prevent the spread of COVID-19, but there was still a heavy police presence to protect against mob violence. What happened instead was a fairly quiet event, with just a single pro-Trump protester in evidence — and two counter-protesters there to applaud Twitter’s decision to deplatform the outgoing president.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h8LylWd4kUwQH_LOaoYGZ10FDw4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228551/vpavic_210111_4366_0056.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter’s headquarters on Market St. in San Francisco was barricaded with fences.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fdY8vHXmAP0GJPNhO2eHUsTtS-U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228547/vpavic_210111_4366_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moderate police presence at the Twitter headquarters in downtown San Francisco.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wrDUvZs2bXdw-2vM8CPmUWVLcpU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228548/vpavic_210111_4366_0016.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ray Blanco was one of the two anti-Trump protesters who showed up on Monday morning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dQxFOSlCF_vI5eCHWuCXQznjjMc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228558/vpavic_210111_4366_0151.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Press and protesters mostly cleared out by 11:30AM.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ee9MdBKRUP_WNN0RxFjgtwWjzUU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228553/vpavic_210111_4366_0063.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Approximately 30 police officers were standing near the entrance awaiting protesters since early in the morning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/j0IZTsM8M4ZEANnlST5Wf6ltd7o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228560/vpavic_210111_4366_0219.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Police officers lined up since early in the morning expecting a protest to start at 8AM local time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/085e_YfZaMKrsSaduuVjilzeMxc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228557/vpavic_210111_4366_0140.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Katherine King is happy with the actions Twitter took, but only wishes they came sooner.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sUjZmlPsb13Bd22A_Kkwd_aRC8s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228559/vpavic_210111_4366_0165.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Police vans parked in the alley behind the Twitter headquarters.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aSvicE8I30ddVOIWMakhR2mHOgQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228564/vpavic_210111_4366_0245.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Riot gear was left unused during the pro-Trump protest near Twitter’s headquarters.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5YJzUqtR94I5tzPI9fVeIT052xU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22228566/vpavic_210111_4366_0278.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Graffiti on the wall wasn’t related to the protest, but was sprayed on the night before.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="B9q2eH"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225721/twitter-protest-san-francisco-trump-stopthesteal-deplatforming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225721/twitter-protest-san-francisco-trump-stopthesteal-deplatforming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Vjeran Pavic</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-01-11T18:04:50-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T18:04:50-05:00</updated>
    <title>Sony promises streaming quality nearly as good as 4K Blu-ray on Bravia Core movie service</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xFgWHD7ft8cVShIB782neCN1o5Y=/174x0:1269x730/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68652657/Screen_Shot_2021_01_11_at_5.34.08_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YZTEu6"&gt;Sony’s new line of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/7/22218693/sony-tv-lineup-8k-4k-z9j-a90j-a80j-x95j-x90j-ces-2021"&gt;Bravia XR television sets&lt;/a&gt; will allow customers to watch and stream movies at some of the highest quality available in the consumer market through its new Bravia Core platform, according to the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CFDnzU"&gt;Bravia XR owners will be able to choose from a number of Sony Pictures titles and watch them using Sony’s “Pure Stream” technology, which achieves “near lossless” ultra high-definition, Blu-ray disc quality, according to Sony. Pure Stream also allows for streaming of up to 80 megabits per second. To compare, most streaming services recommend maintaining an internet speed &lt;a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/tech/columnist/2017/12/10/youre-buying-4-k-tv-how-much-internet-bandwidth-do-you-need/933989001/"&gt;between 15 and 25 megabits per second&lt;/a&gt; to achieve proper 4K Ultra HD streaming quality. If Sony’s numbers are accurate, that’s better than a lot of the competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6B5a91"&gt;The platform comes preloaded on all new Bravia XR models (MASTER Series Z9J 8K LED, MASTER Series A90J and A80J OLED, and X95J and X90J 4K LED) and effectively uses a voucher system. Depending on the model that someone purchases, they’re given a number of credits. Those credits can be cashed in for a number of new titles. It’s unclear if people can keep those titles after they’re purchased with the credits, but &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;has reached out to Sony for more information. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pXVZNI"&gt;On the streaming front, Sony’s website states that customers can stream a number of titles “anytime and as many times as you like, in up to 4K HDR quality,” but there are limits to this, too. Time periods for streaming availability are depending on the Bravia XR model purchased, according to the site. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BpIp5E"&gt;Bravia Core isn’t going to replace Netflix, but it seems like it was specifically designed to show customers the ultimate capabilities of their new TV set. Kind of like when you buy a TV with true 4K HDR capabilities, and you play the best 4K YouTube channels to try to see the difference between your new set and that old clunker you just tossed. Bravia XR TVs also have “the largest IMAX Enhanced movie collection,” according to Sony. It’s unclear exactly how many movies that works out to, though. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RaqRQE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225768/sony-bravia-core-movie-platform-service-xr-television-quality-stream"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/11/22225768/sony-bravia-core-movie-platform-service-xr-television-quality-stream</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
