<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-18T13:01:27-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T13:01:27-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T13:01:27-05:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook’s Oculus begins rolling out multiuser support, starting with the Quest 2</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wrP6XwRYDlTFsz9iCBX3lsJoY1k=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68837741/akrales_200904_4160_0135.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bgrVwV"&gt;Facebook is now rolling out multiuser support as an experimental feature for Oculus Quest 2 headsets, the company &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/02/share-your-oculus-quest/"&gt;announced on Thursday&lt;/a&gt;. The primary account holder will be able to add up to three additional accounts to one device. Facebook is also rolling out app sharing as an experimental feature for the Quest 2, which will allow accounts on one device to access the apps owned by the primary account holder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5V48oa"&gt;For now, the new features are exclusive to the Oculus Quest 2, but Facebook plans to bring them to all Quest users “eventually.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z3XjNB"&gt;There are a few other caveats to be aware of. Facebook began requiring people to log in to their Quest headsets with their Facebook accounts last year, and that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/19/21375118/oculus-facebook-account-login-data-privacy-controversy-developers-competition"&gt;controversial rule&lt;/a&gt; still applies to everyone who signs in to one headset. Apps can only be shared by the primary account holder to other accounts logged in to a Quest device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rVaiKG"&gt;And not all apps support app sharing just yet. It will work with all new apps in the Quest Store, but Facebook says “a limited number of existing games will not yet be available through App Sharing unless players purchase their own copy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Sv0hbI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Oculus Quest 2 review: better, cheaper VR","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21437674/oculus-quest-2-review-features-photos"},{"title":"Facebook is making Oculus’ worst feature unavoidable","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/19/21375118/oculus-facebook-account-login-data-privacy-controversy-developers-competition"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="78XvIa"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289577/facebook-rolling-out-multi-user-support-oculus-quest-2"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289577/facebook-rolling-out-multi-user-support-oculus-quest-2</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T13:00:14-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T13:00:14-05:00</updated>
    <title>Donald Glover’s reported Amazon deal could lead to a more curated Prime Video</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3k1OlNa-0b_inDpJ0Wuo8wLdOeg=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68837734/donald_glover.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vWfC7S"&gt;After calling FX home for several years, &lt;em&gt;Atlanta &lt;/em&gt;creator Donald Glover is reportedly moving to Amazon with an overall deal worth eight figures, according to multiple publications. The news was &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/live-feed/one-day-at-a-time-creator-signs-deal-at-amazon-1257297"&gt;first reported by &lt;em&gt;The Hollywood Reporter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OqQqY7"&gt;As part of the deal, Glover will work on a series of projects for Amazon, including the recently announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/13/22281597/phoebe-waller-bridge-donald-glover-amazon-mr-and-mrs-smith-series"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mr. and Mrs. Smith &lt;/em&gt;series&lt;/a&gt;, which he’ll star in alongside &lt;em&gt;Fleabag &lt;/em&gt;creator Phoebe Waller-Bridge. (Waller-Bridge also has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/24/20881938/amazon-fleabag-phoebe-waller-bridge-deal-prime-video-exclusive-emmys-streaming-wars"&gt;an overall deal with Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.) One rumored project includes &lt;em&gt;Hive, &lt;/em&gt;which is centered on a “Beyoncé-like figure,” according to the &lt;em&gt;Reporter&lt;/em&gt;. Glover’s most popular show, &lt;em&gt;Atlanta&lt;/em&gt;, will continue at FX where the show is set for a third and fourth season. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p9ywvP"&gt;Arguably, the most interesting aspect of the deal is that Amazon will create “a content channel of sorts that will spotlight Glover’s work and other curated content on Amazon’s Prime Video hub,” according to the &lt;em&gt;Reporter&lt;/em&gt;. It’s unclear if Glover will have control over the curated works that appear on his own channel. If that’s the case, however, it could become a key creative and product feature that accomplishes two important tasks for Amazon Prime Video in particular — showcasing the impressive talent working with the company and fighting “algorithm fatigue.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KZfdqA"&gt;Amazon Prime Video could be one of the better streaming platforms, but its terrible product interface and browsing capabilities can make it a pain to use. It’s even more baffling that Amazon’s team hasn’t figured out a way to fix this considering the roster of talent the company has on deck. Waller-Bridge, Steve McQueen (&lt;em&gt;Small Axe&lt;/em&gt;), Jordan Peele (&lt;em&gt;Us&lt;/em&gt;), Gloria Calderón Kellett (&lt;em&gt;One Day at a Time&lt;/em&gt;), Lisa Joy and Jonathan Nolan (&lt;em&gt;Westworld&lt;/em&gt;), Lena Waithe (&lt;em&gt;The Chi&lt;/em&gt;), and Amy Sherman-Palladino and Daniel Palladino (&lt;em&gt;Marvelous Mrs. Maisel&lt;/em&gt;) are just some of the most prolific creators, but their work gets lost in the mess that is Prime Video’s current setup. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="shZii4"&gt;Adding a specific “channel” that exists on Amazon Prime Video’s homepage and highlights a creator’s work is a better form of marketing for the type of series and films Amazon has. It’s a marketing and product tactic being used by many streaming platforms in slightly different ways. HBO Max &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21268972/hbo-max-design-recommendation-human-curation-friends-kids-profiles"&gt;allows subscribers&lt;/a&gt; to click on an actor or director’s “playlist” and see what they’ve been watching. For example, &lt;em&gt;Lovecraft Country &lt;/em&gt;actor Jurnee Smollett’s playlist celebrating Black History Month and Black film can be seen in the screenshot below. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iYjjuTv35HgZhOmgZV5e4bhJDL8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22312439/playlist_hbo_max.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="AKOEU7"&gt;Other streaming services like Peacock and Discovery Plus have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21321482/peacock-hands-on-app-mobile-tv-channels-browse-trending-nbcuniversal-streaming"&gt;dedicated channels&lt;/a&gt; for specific series or creators. On these platforms, the idea is to replicate the feeling of live TV for people who want to throw on something like &lt;em&gt;House Hunters &lt;/em&gt;or &lt;em&gt;Saturday Night Live &lt;/em&gt;and not touch the remote again. On HBO Max and Amazon, the strategy is creating a feeling of curation from the talent working on shows and films that are available to stream. (This is also a strategy that that Criterion Channel’s streaming service and film streaming platform MUBI mainly focus on.) If Netflix gave Martin Scorsese his own channel, for example, and handed over a list of films the company had the rights to stream, he could include &lt;em&gt;The Irishman &lt;/em&gt;and other films he truly adores. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HAnQGU"&gt;As is everything with the industry right now, it all comes back to Scorsese. The director &lt;a href="https://harpers.org/archive/2021/03/il-maestro-federico-fellini-martin-scorsese/"&gt;wrote an essay in &lt;em&gt;Harper’s&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;about Italian director Federico Fellini and touched upon the necessity of cinema in an algorithm-defined, everything-is-content world. Algorithm fatigue isn’t new, nor is Scorsese the only one frustrated by it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AcH12p"&gt;It’s a tricky thing to get right. Most subscribers likely enjoy that Netflix’s recommendation algorithm helps surface shows or movies they’ll likely be interested in. There are thousands of things to sift through otherwise. At the same time, developing creative product features that highlight an artist’s work and make it feel like a more personal connection to film or television — and less like another piece of content — is crucial to making a platform feel like a hub for great TV and film instead of just a storage space for any kind of content. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FDMzsj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vLqMTf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sDs4lX"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289258/donald-glover-amazon-deal-channel-curation-phoebe-waller-bridge-fx-atlanta"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289258/donald-glover-amazon-deal-channel-curation-phoebe-waller-bridge-fx-atlanta</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T13:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T13:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Nyan Cat is being sold as a one-of-a-kind piece of crypto art</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-nqRj0a0UTzIDKwXzTiHwqrwd8w=/0x234:1400x1167/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68837725/poptart1redrainbowfix_1.0.gif" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;GIF: Chris Torres&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wfNk2i"&gt;Nyan Cat turns 10 this year, and to mark the occasion, &lt;a href="https://foundation.app/NyanCat/nyan-cat-219"&gt;a one-of-a-kind edition&lt;/a&gt; of the iconic GIF is going up for auction. Chris Torres, the artist behind Nyan Cat, has remastered the original animation and will be selling it through the crypto art platform Foundation. The auction begins at 1PM ET today and will run for around 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vaDag9"&gt;“I’m looking at [the GIF] right now, and I’m like, ‘Yes, it looks good,’” Torres said in a phone call with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “I think it turned out really well this time around.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EwEeKZ"&gt;Crypto art has been growing in popularity over the past few years, and there are now a number of digital marketplaces — including Zora, SuperRare, and Nifty Gateway — where collectors can buy and sell digital works. Last year, the digital artist Beeple sold a series of works for more than $3.5 million in total, and the musician Deadmau5 sold thousands of digital pins, stickers, and other collectibles in December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="oTROrv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“You also get to directly support an artist, and I think that is really exciting for people.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DYvYQH"&gt;Buyers of these works get the privilege of “owning” a piece of digital art — to the limited extent one can really own an endlessly reproducible image file. Artwork typically comes with a license that allows the buyer to display them for personal use on, say, a social media page, another digital marketplace, in a game world, or in a virtual museum. The artists generally maintain all intellectual and creative rights to the works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p1eR2t"&gt;That means, in some ways, buyers are really just purchasing bragging rights. “To be able to say that I’m the collector who actually owns and is a patron of this artist carries a certain kind of prestige that is really appealing to people,” Lindsay Howard, Foundation’s head of community, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “You also get to directly support an artist, and I think that is really exciting for people.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NLaQcG"&gt;Pieces of crypto art are generally sold through “non-fungible tokens,” or NFTs, which are unique digital tokens that live on a blockchain and verify ownership of a piece. Digital artworks can be resold, and in some cases — like on Foundation — artists continue to get a cut of future sales. That means, like so much else involving the blockchain, there’s also an element of investment and speculation when purchasing crypto art since you may be able to resell a work for profit down the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="3YnYhf"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I think it’s cool knowing you own the only piece in existence.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="e8u02D"&gt;There are some drawbacks to crypto art — particularly when it comes to energy consumption. Like bitcoin, NFTs are powered by inefficient computer processes designed to validate data. Ethereum, which most crypto art platforms rely on, is much more efficient than bitcoin, but even its creator &lt;a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/computing/networks/ethereum-plans-to-cut-its-absurd-energy-consumption-by-99-percent"&gt;has called the system&lt;/a&gt; “a huge waste of resources.” Ethereum is still in the process of whittling down its energy usage to a far tinier footprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7HMQ1s"&gt;Foundation is one of the newest entrants to the crypto art space. It launched just two weeks ago, and it’s already facilitated more than $410,000 in sales. (Though, like many crypto art platforms, sales are actually made with the cryptocurrency Ether.) “There’s an explosion that’s happening right now where artists are finally being compensated for the work that they’re creating and sharing online,” Howard said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="71pjsT"&gt;Torres says crypto art offers meme creators like himself a way to directly profit off of work that has otherwise spread freely across the web. “It gives power to the creator,” Torres said. “The creator originally owns it, and then they can sell it and directly monetize and have recognition for their work.” (Torres has also built a licensing business around Nyan Cat so the character can appear in games or be made into toys.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jCp1gk"&gt;To remaster Nyan Cat, which turns 10 on April 2nd, Torres went back to the original GIF to make it larger and touch up minor flaws that have bugged him over the years. One star in the original 12-frame animation would pop in out of nowhere, Torres said, so he took it out for the remastered edition. “That always bothered me,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WqVza6"&gt;Once this remaster sells, Torres doesn’t plan to offer another of Nyan Cat’s original image. That means only one buyer will be able to lay claim to Nyan Cat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1lPNhS"&gt;“I think it’s cool knowing you own the only piece in existence,” Torres said. “And I feel like Nyan Cat will be a really special one to own.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bgmeau"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P2HFvx"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287956/nyan-cat-crypto-art-foundation-nft-sale-chris-torres"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287956/nyan-cat-crypto-art-foundation-nft-sale-chris-torres</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T13:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T13:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Android 12 developer preview is available now with many under-the-hood updates</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wjqabYCSaLcqnND2KqbOIQlINhI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68837707/wjoel_180413_1777_android_001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by William Joel / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BlpL2i"&gt;Google is releasing a developer preview for the next version of Android, Android 12, for Pixel devices today. As is the norm for Google, the very first previews of Android are full of a lot of developer-facing changes. Android 12 has updates to how the OS handles images, video, and future security updates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YEIOhd"&gt;It’s also the norm for Google to hold some of the major UI changes in reserve for its Google I/O conference, typically held in May. Although this developer preview does include some changes to the UI for notifications, until we install it we won’t know how closely it will map to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274071/google-android-12-ui-screenshots-privacy-indicator-conversations-widget-leak-rumor"&gt;the leak we saw earlier this month&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4B47yQ"&gt;It’s available for Pixel 3 and newer phones but needs to be manually installed by flashing your device. It’s likely nowhere near ready for day-to-day use, but Google is promising that it will continue its beta program for regular users later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H6DS3u"&gt;Although the point of this first preview is to give developers a jump-start on getting their apps ready for the new version of Android, there are still features that should make a tangible difference to users. Specifically, Android is going to become more adept at handling different types of media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cxqfmC"&gt;Google did not provide images of Android 12’s user interface ahead of time. We will update this post with more details and images as soon as we are able.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="HlNDJ2"&gt;New media formats in Android 12&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="UWPyqw"&gt;There will be a new transcoding layer that will automatically make the HEVC video format work in apps that don’t natively support them. Currently, choosing to shoot in HEVC on an Android phone may mean that third-party apps won’t be able to natively use that video. The new transcoding layer for those apps should let users make the switch with more confidence. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G9mpAK"&gt;Android 12 will support spatial audio, support MPEG-H, and be optimized for up to 24 channels of audio (up from eight before). It will also make it easier for developers to tie rumble effects to audio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="talPGl"&gt;Google appears to be throwing its weight behind the AV1 Image File Format — otherwise known as AVIF. AVIF is meant to replace JPGs as the de facto image format, offering much better and cleaner compression with fewer artifacts. &lt;a href="https://netflixtechblog.com/avif-for-next-generation-image-coding-b1d75675fe4"&gt;Netflix in particular has been a big proponent of the format&lt;/a&gt;. If AV1 sounds familiar, that’s because it’s an offshoot of the AV1 video format &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/4/16850402/apple-joins-open-media-alliance-streaming-online-video-compression-codec"&gt;that major tech companies proposed some years back&lt;/a&gt; and both &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/6/21126039/netflix-android-av1-video-codec-efficient-support-bandwidth-quality-vp9"&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/22/21231959/google-duo-update-video-call-quality-av1-codec"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; have partially adopted. AVIF also isn’t to be confused with the similar HEIF, which Apple’s cameras have been shooting for some time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zlfcr6"&gt;Google says that it does not intend to make AVIF the default image format for the camera app, so this is still just a first step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AsIR4s"&gt;Sticking with multimedia, Android 12 will simply do a better job moving different kinds of media between apps. It’s creating a new “Rich content insertion” API that will let you cut and paste or drag and drop multiple kinds of content, including “plain and styled text to markup, images, videos, audio files, and more.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A leaked look at Android 12. As of publication we don’t know precisely how accurate this is, but it lines up with Google’s description in its blog post." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7nIDCrY_DOLGMu2QihzZLRnWVvM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22291645/android12conversationswidget.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: XDA-Developers&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A leaked look at Android 12. As of publication we don’t know precisely how accurate this is, but it lines up with Google’s description in its blog post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bBFYq0"&gt;Android 12 interface changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="i6MxkT"&gt;We will need to install the developer preview ourselves to get a closer look at the changes Google is introducing right now. Its blog post describes what’s new in somewhat general terms. It’s a safe bet that what Google is showing today will be a hint to larger changes due later in the year. Whether those changes really will match up with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274071/google-android-12-ui-screenshots-privacy-indicator-conversations-widget-leak-rumor"&gt;leaked screenshots you see above&lt;/a&gt; remains to be seen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KM1zFX"&gt;Here’s how Google describes the changes it is making to notifications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="1CHmDW"&gt;We’re refreshing notification designs to make them more modern, easier to use, and more functional. In this first preview you’ll notice changes from the drawer and controls to the templates themselves. We’re also optimizing transitions and animations across the system to make them more smooth. As part of the updates, for apps targeting Android 12 we’re decorating notifications with custom content with icon and expand affordances to match all other notifications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="doiWRV"&gt;The app icons do line up with the leaked screenshot above, though, again, that doesn’t necessarily mean that’s what the final version will look like. The “expand affordances” also line up — the downward-pointing caret you can see in the screenshot above would be easier to tap than the current system. Google also notes that it is asking developers to use an API that makes apps open up more quickly in the right spot when a user taps a notification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fJhrOL"&gt;Finally, Google says that it is changing how Android 12 will behave when you’re in a full-screen app like a video, a Kindle book, or a video game. Currently, it often takes two gestures to exit out of those apps — one to bring up the UI, another to actually exit out. With Android 12, Google says that it is “changing the default to allow users to navigate their phone with one swipe.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="DHX9r8"&gt;Changes under the hood&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="gH0iMt"&gt;In 2019, Google started updating certain components deep inside the Android OS directly, rather than waiting for carriers to push through a major update. Dubbed “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/7/18531350/google-android-q-project-mainline-security-updates-play-store-io-2019"&gt;Project Mainline&lt;/a&gt;,” it meant Google could issue security updates for critical parts of Android using the Google Play infrastructure. Ever since, it’s been adding more pieces of Android to the Mainline system. Android 12’s big addition to this system is the Android Runtime (ART), a fundamental subsystem for making Android apps run. The aforementioned media transcoder will also become a Mainline module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="671KYK"&gt;Android 12 will have a few privacy and security updates, but they won’t be as prominently visible to users. The WebView engine that third-party apps use will adopt one of Chrome’s more recent cookie settings called “SameSite,” which could help mitigate some tracking. Google says that “more privacy and security features [will be] coming in later preview releases.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6TMOld"&gt;Android recently began requiring apps to pop a notification when it needs to run a background activity — which turns out to be really distracting. In Android 12, Google says it “will be blocking foreground service starts from the background,” redirecting developers to a new API. If one of these background activities can finish up in less than 10 seconds, it may not need to display a notification at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="loarav"&gt;Google is also releasing an Android 12 preview for Android TV right away, including giving developers the chance to test their apps on Google’s own Google TV platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Bd3Sxd"&gt;What’s next for Android 12&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="IEat3v"&gt;Google is releasing the developer preview today, but again, it requires that you flash your device’s system image, so really it’s meant for developers only right now. Google says it will work on a “Pixel 3 / 3 XL, Pixel 3a / 3a XL, Pixel 4 / 4 XL, Pixel 4a / 4a 5G, or Pixel 5 device” or developers can simply run it inside the Android emulator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KOvU9D"&gt;There &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; be a public beta at some point, but expect it to take a few months. And if Google follows its past habits, there will be a more comprehensive look at what’s coming in Android 12 in May (or possibly June). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g6icVS"&gt;Last year, Android’s “platform stability” release &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/8/21317085/android-11-beta-2-platform-stability-apis-developer-update-google-pixel"&gt;came in early July&lt;/a&gt;, but this year Google is targeting August — the official release usually comes shortly thereafter. That could mean that Android 12 will arrive just a little later in the year than usual. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iQyOuh"&gt;In the meantime, we and others will be digging in to the developer preview to see what other details we can find. More often than not there are enough hints scattered throughout the code to give us a good idea of Google’s final plans for Android.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22288084/android-12-developer-preview-available-google-pixel"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22288084/android-12-developer-preview-available-google-pixel</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Bohn</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T12:59:44-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T12:59:44-05:00</updated>
    <title>Go read this article about how Prop 22 may have opened the gates for the gig economy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-VOTE-IT-LIFESTYLE-TRANSPORT" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d3rYzKRWgQPkRa71IGLjJKGMd8s=/0x1:4257x2839/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68837694/1229135526.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by JOSH EDELSON/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dmtynq"&gt;Last November, California passed Proposition 22, which made it so that companies like Uber and Lyft could classify their workers as contractors instead of employees, avoiding the obligation to give them benefits. &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2021-02-17/gig-economy-coming-for-millions-of-u-s-jobs-after-california-s-uber-lyft-vote?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; has written a great report&lt;/a&gt; about how this type of change — replacing regular employees with contractors — could be coming to many other industries across the nation, which could affect millions of workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ivqJFs"&gt;While the law was pushed for by ride-share companies, the article talks about the effects already being seen in other industries, like how grocery delivery workers are being fired and replaced by on-demand DoorDash workers. It also details an op-ed by an Uber investor, talking about how Prop 22 could be used to replace employees with contract workers in various industries, from nursing to agriculture.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="buos9f"&gt;Companies moving their workers to independent contract employment, instead of traditional employment, helps them keep their labor costs low. Contract employees aren’t entitled to benefits like health insurance, overtime pay, etc. The companies also don’t have to pay employees for time that they’re on the clock but not carrying out their job duties — if a grocery delivery employee is waiting for an order to come in, the company still has to pay for them to be there, which is not the case if that person works for DoorDash. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AiBYfD"&gt;We’ve already seen ride-share companies &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/5/21551136/uber-prop-22-victory-national-q3-2020-earnings"&gt;talking about taking Prop 22-like legislation nationwide&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; digs into how Uber has plenty of contacts in the Biden administration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="2vUMvY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Tony West, Uber’s top lawyer, is Vice President Kamala Harris’ brother-in-law&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FJwHOb"&gt;The article also casts some doubt on the idea that unions will be able to stem the tide. It goes into the dilemma labor leaders are facing: do they work with companies to make sure contract workers are getting an okay deal, or do they work against them and possibly lose everything?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="xDNnR3"&gt;Now Uber, after successfully reshaping culture and politics to accommodate its business model, is bending unions, too. Labor groups have to take seriously the prospect that if they don’t come to the table, the companies will write the laws themselves, as they did with Prop 22.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="w0YVzk"&gt;While the future may be uncertain for millions of workers, it’s a good idea to stay informed on what it could look like, so that workers can be prepared if and when similar legislation starts popping up around the country. &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2021-02-17/gig-economy-coming-for-millions-of-u-s-jobs-after-california-s-uber-lyft-vote?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; is a great place to start.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22288488/prop-22-gig-economy-expansion-industries-bloomberg"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22288488/prop-22-gig-economy-expansion-industries-bloomberg</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T12:54:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T12:54:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>Puss is a seemingly simple puzzle game except for the psychedelic cats</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cxtvCwghXIOSLnbRHWEZ1SACSvU=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68837646/08_FullHD.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: teamcoil&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3kBCKX"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Puss&lt;/em&gt; might be the strangest video game I’ve ever played. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="URTKrg"&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Puss&lt;/em&gt;, you play as a small pixelated cat head navigating short mazes. The mazes are often filled with obstacles and bullets impeding your route to the end, and if you touch a wall for too long, you’ll get zapped and lose a life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CbMns1"&gt;That’s only part of the experience, though. It’s the mind-meltingly psychedelic aesthetic that permeates every aspect of the game that makes &lt;em&gt;Puss&lt;/em&gt; stand out. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oz5y4ZoOvddyzUN2201vAsqgGaA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22312461/01_EN_FullHD.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: teamcoil&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7NRMvU"&gt;Nearly every maze in &lt;em&gt;Puss&lt;/em&gt; offers an entirely new visual experience, and most have bright colors that regularly change, shift, or flash as you navigate through the level. The intensity of the graphics can sometimes feel overpowering, often distracting me from actually completing a level. In one, for example, nearly the entire background was taken up by a looping video of giant, chattering teeth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8waHhr"&gt;Every once in a while, I would even notice that my eyes hurt while playing, forcing me to stop. When you boot up &lt;em&gt;Puss&lt;/em&gt;, it suggests consulting a doctor before playing video games if you have epilepsy or have had reactions to flashing lights. There’s also a very brief message that “player discretion is advised.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UEUEyB"&gt;The music doesn’t make the game any easier to play. The soundtrack regularly mashes up different genres and sound effects to create weird and often uncomfortable soundscapes. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4Ja5v66SH0c&amp;amp;t=952s"&gt;In one section of one song&lt;/a&gt;, a low, industrial hum rumbles beneath occasional guitar twangs and incomprehensible mumbling voices. Sometimes these mashups created interesting, lo-fi hip-hop-esque beats. But more often than not, the music just put me on edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="EozrZ8"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/l8aRSMG0gtA?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="b7PEw4"&gt;The mazes themselves are short, and each has different mechanics and puzzles that are fun to figure out, despite everything that’s going on. Some mazes have you time movements across ever-shifting platforms. Others have timer buttons that reveal a new platform you’ll have to race across in order to get to the end. Sometimes you’re just dodging a lot of bullets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fgsNeZ"&gt;I was able to finish many of the mazes on my first try, and the ones that tripped me up at first would get easier with practice. The game also has truly outlandish bosses. During one stage of a boss fight, there’s a dog with three heads fused into one that shoots lasers out of its eyes. The bosses often reminded me of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RJ4kumxv_1k"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Undertale&lt;/em&gt;’s memorable final foe&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nHfzs4"&gt;Everything about &lt;em&gt;Puss&lt;/em&gt; is overwhelming, and I’m convinced that the game is trying to make you feel like you’re high on catnip. But the absurdity of that conceit works. A part of me was always looking forward to what unexpected combination of visuals, sounds, and puzzle-solving awaited me with each new maze or boss fight. It just sometimes hurt my head to try to comprehend it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mCAXwo"&gt;&lt;small&gt;Puss&lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt; launches on February 19th on the Nintendo Switch, PlayStation 4, and Xbox One. It’s already available on iOS, Android, PC, Mac, and Linux.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k9cEeA"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289445/puss-review-puzzle-game-psychedelic-cats-switch-xbox-ps4"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289445/puss-review-puzzle-game-psychedelic-cats-switch-xbox-ps4</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple TV app now available on the latest Google Chromecast</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zVOSMThHUPqFqBdRZwA3O_niMzg=/0x0:1569x1046/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68837077/Blog_header.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2rB2lJ"&gt;The Apple TV app is now available for Google’s 2020 Chromecast. It was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22178364/google-chromecast-apple-tv-plus-app-2021-announcement"&gt;announced in December&lt;/a&gt; that Apple’s streaming app, which offers access to its Apple TV Plus originals, would be coming to the awkwardly named Chromecast with Google TV. Starting today, owners of the excellent $50 device can download Apple TV and start using it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nlwBpL"&gt;Apple TV originals like &lt;em&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; The Morning Show&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;For All Mankind&lt;/em&gt; will appear in Google TV’s recommendations and search results. Of note, you’ll also be able to add Apple’s original shows and movies to Google TV’s universal Watchlist. Some bigger streaming services like Netflix have decided against participating in Watchlist in the months since the Chromecast’s release, as they seemingly prefer to keep that sort of functionality inside the app itself. As &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2020/11/25/google-tv-netflix-dropped/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; in November, the Google TV mobile app doesn’t even include Netflix recommendations anymore. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wU5zHi"&gt;Apple TV is also getting Google Assistant integration on Chromecast; you can start watching any of Apple’s originals with a voice command. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QQPyiZ"&gt;In addition to being home to Apple’s original programming, the Apple TV app offers easy streaming of your movie / TV show rentals and purchases from Apple. And as on other platforms, any Apple TV Channel add-on subscriptions you might have — CBS All Access, Showtime, etc. — will be available in the app on Chromecast with Google TV. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZO61r8"&gt;Jonathan Zepp, Google’s director of media and entertainment, says that “in addition to Chromecast with Google TV, the Apple TV app will also be available on Google TVs from Sony and TCL.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287905/apple-tv-app-now-available-chromecast-google-tv"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287905/apple-tv-app-now-available-chromecast-google-tv</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T11:42:06-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T11:42:06-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google is restructuring its AI teams after Timnit Gebru’s firing</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PP_s8tIngc2zcoYyW-9kWnm0lmw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68836952/acastro_180427_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JTWl5H"&gt;Google is reorganizing its responsible AI teams in the wake of Timnit Gebru’s firing. The ethical AI team will now roll up to Marian Croak, a prominent Black executive in the engineering department. Croak will also oversee employees focused on engineering fairness products, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-02-18/google-to-reorganize-ai-teams-in-wake-of-researcher-s-departure?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. She will report to Jeff Dean, who leads the company’s AI efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tVNJ61"&gt;The ethical AI team was not aware of the reorganization until news broke Wednesday night. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="awxVBm"&gt;The change is an attempt to stabilize the department, which has been in turmoil for months, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-02-18/google-to-reorganize-ai-teams-in-wake-of-researcher-s-departure?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;. In December, Timnit Gebru, co-lead of the ethical AI team, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/3/22150355/google-fires-timnit-gebru-facial-recognition-ai-ethicist"&gt;announced she’d been abruptly fired&lt;/a&gt;. The following month, &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/scoop-google-is-investigating-the-actions-of-another-top-ai-ethicist-50030739-ea3d-4ea2-b452-c228b4fc9773.html"&gt;the company began investigating her counterpart Margaret Mitchell&lt;/a&gt;, who had been using a script to go through her emails to look for examples of discrimination against Gebru. Mitchell now says she’s been &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mmitchell_ai/status/1361415627781459971"&gt;locked out of her corporate accounts for more than five weeks&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vDmFav"&gt;Prior to her dismissal, Gebru had been trying to publish a &lt;a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2020/12/04/1013294/google-ai-ethics-research-paper-forced-out-timnit-gebru/"&gt;paper on the dangers of large language processing models&lt;/a&gt;. Megan Kacholia, vice president of Google Research, asked her to retract the paper. Gebru pushed back, saying the company needed to be more transparent about the publication process. Shortly afterward, she was fired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hXXe5K"&gt;The ethical AI team &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/12/17/googles-ai-ethics-team-makes-demands-of-executives-to-rebuild-trust.html"&gt;published a six-page letter&lt;/a&gt; in the wake of Gebru’s termination, calling on Kacholia to be replaced. “We have lost confidence in Megan Kacholia and we call for her to be removed from our reporting chain,” the letter read. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rn4hfa"&gt;Now, the team may be getting its wish. As part of the reorganization, Kacholia will no longer lead the ethical AI researchers, according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg. &lt;/em&gt;It’s not clear what this means for Margaret Mitchell, who is still being investigated by the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QOgQxU"&gt;Google did not immediately respond to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vwInYh"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289264/google-restructuring-ethical-ai-team-timnit-gebru-firing"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289264/google-restructuring-ethical-ai-team-timnit-gebru-firing</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T11:35:27-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T11:35:27-05:00</updated>
    <title>Panasonic made a farting cat robot!</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fu3fJ9ZLBrI6OGo5srVFy0QcDjs=/122x12:1318x809/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68836879/Screen_Shot_2021_02_18_at_11.04.55_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="sVuxBa"&gt;I am so tired, and there are so many things happening. Days like today have become the norm over this last, lost year; there is a tragedy happening every second of every day, and if you’re lucky enough to be outside of the blast radius you’re only able to perceive what’s happening through a screen. Just last night, Texas Senator Ted Cruz decided to take a family trip to Cancún as large swaths of his state are without power or potable drinking water in the midst of a historic deep freeze. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JakeSherman/status/1362418963196485634"&gt;He’s now on his way back&lt;/a&gt;, after being shamed online for his bafflingly cruel choice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lyipGx"&gt;That was the first thing I saw this morning. &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/resisting-the-urge-to-pet-panasonics-farting-robot-sock-1846252962"&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; was the second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="K0Pwzr"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-DsYUo6hios?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oS11la"&gt;This funky little robot’s name is Nicobo, and it was created by Panasonic for companionship.  It’s loosely catlike; it farts. It cannot do more than wiggle its head and its tail and blink its unnervingly digital eyes. It can sort of talk. And no, if you’re interested, you cannot buy it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CpgbGG"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/resisting-the-urge-to-pet-panasonics-farting-robot-sock-1846252962"&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;, Panasonic is only planning to make a few hundred Nicobo units; it made them available for preorder via its own crowdfunding platform, and they have all been claimed as of six hours after the campaign launch. (Nicobo costs about $360.) If you managed to get your hands on one, you’re expected to pay around $10 a month to get things like software updates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k7Jqte"&gt;I am not sure why I’m telling you this. It’s not like you can buy this robot, which is cute in its way. It’s also not like learning about a small Japanese robot will change your life or even fend off existential despair for more than the time it takes you to get to this paragraph in this article. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Y3xqv"&gt;Perhaps there’s a lesson here, nestled between the juxtaposition of the logic of production and the reality of widespread human suffering. Nicobo was created by Panasonic in partnership with robotics researchers from Toyohashi University of Technology as a companion — as a technological salve for atomization, capitalist alienation, and good old-fashioned loneliness. After a year of drastically less human touch, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/6/21051662/robot-cat-headless-yukai-engineering-petit-qoobo-ces-2020"&gt;we’ve yet another robotic Band-Aid&lt;/a&gt; for a gaping psychic wound. I guess it’s cuter than a Zoom call?&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289331/panasonic-farting-cat-robot"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289331/panasonic-farting-cat-robot</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bijan Stephen</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T11:21:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T11:21:24-05:00</updated>
    <title>Mortal Kombat’s first trailer is almost as violent as the games</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YO28mbjHDgk9tHNwcIwSIp6syEk=/265x0:1819x1036/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68836770/Screen_Shot_2021_02_18_at_11.10.41_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2BA4Jb"&gt;The rebooted &lt;em&gt;Mortal Kombat&lt;/em&gt; movie has debuted its first trailer — and, much like the games it’s based on, the upcoming film looks to be &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; violent. (Warner Bros. has actually released two trailers, with &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J983DiVbZ9k&amp;amp;has_verified=1"&gt;a more gory red-band version&lt;/a&gt; available on YouTube.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Js26W8"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mortal Kombat&lt;/em&gt; stars Lewis Tan as an MMA fighter Cole Young, who seems remarkably blasé about the suspiciously dragon-shaped scar on his chest (he assumes it’s just a birthmark, which certainly strains credulity.) But Cole is quickly recruited to fight in a legendary tournament — the titular “Mortal Kombat” — with the fate of Earth in his hands. (Literally. There’s going to be a lot of fighting.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="tvjr6J"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Mortal Kombat 11 is a game nearly 30 years in the making","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/23/18512337/mortal-kombat-11-ps4-xbox-switch-ed-boon-interview"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="QwmuZQ"&gt;The trailer also gives the first good look at the latest live-action versions of Sonya, Kano, Raiden, Jax, Liu Kang, Shang Tsung, and Kung Lao, along with the dueling supernatural warriors Sub-Zero and Scorpion (the video game’s unofficial mascots). The new film is set to be a rebooted attempt to adapt the hyper-violent fighting game after the original&lt;em&gt; Mortal Kombat&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Mortal Kombat: Annihilation&lt;/em&gt; films from the 1990s. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bWLIZt"&gt;Like all of Warner Bros.’ 2021 blockbusters, Mortal Kombat will be released in theaters and on HBO Max simultaneously on April 16th, 2021. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287377/mortal-kombat-first-trailer-warner-bros-hbo-max-sub-zero-scorpion"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287377/mortal-kombat-first-trailer-warner-bros-hbo-max-sub-zero-scorpion</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
