<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-10T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Rocket League developer is adding a Ford F-150 to the game</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7maEI9JaxIE-QwxukVtsbSZKoDc=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68798206/f150_core_art.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Psyonix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xaq8tB"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt; developer Psyonix announced today it's partnering with an auto company to add an actual truck into the game. Sadly, no, it is not the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/22/20976539/tesla-cybertruck-test-drive-electric-truck-pickup-video-features-price-elon-musk"&gt;Tesla Cybertruck&lt;/a&gt;. It's the Ford F-150. A &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt;-themed F-150 will be available for a limited time, beginning February 20th until February 28th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w0Sz0R"&gt;The Ford F-150 RLE bundle will be available in the item shop with its own tab and costs 1,500 credits. The bundle includes the Ford F-150 RLE (pictured below), a set of standard and special edition wheels, boost, audio engine, player banner, and decal, all of which are themed after the special edition pickup truck. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="pC9Gzd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10334323"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sGru4L"&gt;As someone who enjoys pickup trucks, I am crying tears of joy because I can use one in &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt;. There is something hilarious about the fact that I can drive a rocket-powered F-150 in the game and do ridiculous trick shots with it. I really want to see other auto companies like Chevrolet and Toyota add their trucks to the game. Seriously, imagine having the Tesla Cybertruck in &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt;; I’d never stop laughing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Npgr9A"&gt;Alongside a new, limited-time vehicle, Psyonix and Ford are also introducing a new competitive two-day event where the best freestyles in &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt; will compete and demonstrate their best moves for a chance to win a real 2021 Ford F-150. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22274788/rocket-league-ford-f150-limited-edition-announced"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22274788/rocket-league-ford-f150-limited-edition-announced</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T10:56:02-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T10:56:02-05:00</updated>
    <title>Epic’s new MetaHuman tool lets you craft realistic faces inside a browser</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8fFw8i6wR-iciookm-Us46KzKMw=/56x0:644x392/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68798169/epic_meta_human_creator.0.gif" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="olQHfa"&gt;Epic Games has announced a new, browser-based software tool powered by its Unreal Engine called the &lt;a href="https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/digital-humans"&gt;MetaHuman Creator&lt;/a&gt; that can craft highly realistic human faces and help power more realistic body movements and facial animations. Epic provided a sneak peek at the platform today in a pair of YouTube videos showing off examples of creations built using the MetaHuman Creator, and “metahuman” appears to be the term the company is using to describe this brand of virtual, non-real individual. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4ow8Dw"&gt;Epic says the MetaHuman Creator can be used in conjunction with modern motion capture and animation techniques for creating lifelike movements and human interactions scenes built for video games, film, TV, and other formats. The company says these photorealistic humans can be generated in a matter of minutes and equipped with unique hairstyles and clothing, and then they can be tailored further to meet the needs of a production. And these “metahumans” can be manipulated in real time within the tool itself and just using a web browser, Epic says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="LpT5pX"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/S3F1vZYpH8c?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JMkhT6"&gt;“Up until now one of the most arduous tasks in 3D content creation has been constructing truly convincing digital humans. Even the most experienced artists require significant amounts of time, effort, and equipment, just for one character,” said Vladimir Mastilovic, Epic’s vice president of digital humans technology, in a statement. “After decades of research and development, and thanks to bringing companies like 3Lateral, Cubic Motion, and Quixel into the Epic family, that barrier is being erased through Unreal Engine, and we’re thrilled to introduce MetaHuman Creator.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BDuF1B"&gt;The humans created with Epic’s new tool don’t approach the photorealism of, say, the digitally rendered photographs of fake people produced by generative adversarial networks, which is the AI technique underpinning projects like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/3/18244984/ai-generated-fake-which-face-is-real-test-stylegan"&gt;“This Person Does Not Exist.”&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bpHWl5qlbGEj1q6xDlGKiF4O3ts=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22294597/epic_meta_human_creator.gif"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="AKsT9o"&gt;But as a kind of supercharged video game character creation tool, MetaHuman Creator does seem capable of making some shockingly realistic-looking people that could easily pass for a real-life motion captured actor. Though perhaps we’d need to wait to see what the tool is truly capable of in the hands of third-party creators before making a verdict on whether it escapes the uncanny valley. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g4kpQo"&gt;It’s not clear when Epic intends to release MetaHuman Creator outside a broad 2021 release window, but interested developers and artists can &lt;a href="https://ue.unrealengine.com/ENT-1883-01-2021-Digital-Humans_LP.html"&gt;sign up for updates on the Unreal Engine website&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276265/epic-games-digital-human-creator-unreal-engine-realistic-human-faces"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276265/epic-games-digital-human-creator-unreal-engine-realistic-human-faces</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T10:55:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T10:55:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix is turning iconic series Redwall into a TV show, film</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/F1M9CFRksLgqD8Kvz0niTQwSvKI=/223x0:978x503/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68798161/Et1wZBOVoAAcZxI.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="sUe0lp"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Redwall&lt;/em&gt;, Brian Jacques’ fantasy novels about heroic anthropomorphic animals, is coming to Netflix in a new film and TV show. The company announced on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NXOnNetflix/status/1359492313081393153"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;em&gt;Over the Garden Wall&lt;/em&gt; creator Patrick McHale is helming the project. The movie will be based on the series’s first book, &lt;em&gt;Redwall&lt;/em&gt;, while the TV show will tackle the story of Martin the Warrior. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eB4dEa"&gt;Jacques, who died in 2011, published &lt;em&gt;Redwall&lt;/em&gt; in 1986. The book follows a young mouse monk, Matthias, as he defends Redwall Abbey from an invading rodent army. Matthias’ story is deeply linked to Martin’s, a legendary warrior whom he idolizes. Although &lt;em&gt;Redwall&lt;/em&gt; has been previously made into a TV show, &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/film/news/netflix-redwall-movie-tv-show-brian-jacques-1234904865/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reports that the Netflix deal is the first time the same company has held rights to the entire series. It’s also the first time &lt;em&gt;Redwall&lt;/em&gt; has gotten a movie adaptation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6uXbrX"&gt;Netflix hasn’t released any additional details about the adaptations, including who will play key voice roles or when it will be released. The &lt;em&gt;Redwall&lt;/em&gt; series spans 22 novels, with the last published posthumously in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276221/redwall-tv-show-netflix-announcement-film"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276221/redwall-tv-show-netflix-announcement-film</id>
    <author>
      <name>Megan Farokhmanesh</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T10:50:02-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T10:50:02-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s most affordable iPad is even cheaper at several retailers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aUo2kCyGrGnmfsqkSO3DiYNXJN8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68798148/DSC01911.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TqtUnA"&gt;Starting at $329, Apple’s most affordable iPad model comes at a very attractive price — but if you have been holding off in the hopes of buying it at an even better price, your patience has paid off. At &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-10-2-inch-Wi-Fi-32GB/dp/B08J65DST5?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-10-2-inch-iPad-8th-Gen-Wi-Fi-32GB-Space-Gray%2F989344107%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt; (in select colors), you can buy a 32GB model for $299; you can also get it for &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1731914581454635364" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$300 at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. This is the lowest price we have seen for this model to date. If you need a little bit more storage, you can grab the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1731909318076698536" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;128GB model at Best Buy for $380&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5GyzV5"&gt;While its design looks similar to its predecessor, the 2020 iPad model features a faster A12 Bionic processor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="HFw4ZS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9508346"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9cZKIq"&gt;Over at OnePlus’ website, now until February 17th, the company has a few discounts going. Most notably, you can grab an unlocked &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.oneplus.com%2Foneplus-8-pro%3Ffrom%3D8pro#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;OnePlus 8 Pro with 12GB of RAM 256GB of storage for $799&lt;/a&gt; ($200 off). If you buy the phone directly from the OnePlus website, you will also receive an Urban backpack at no additional cost. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="hjeC34"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10335875"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ReHGBt"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ori and the Blind Forest&lt;/em&gt; and its sequel, the &lt;em&gt;Will of the Wisps,&lt;/em&gt; are 2D Metroidvania platformer titles known for their stunning visuals. Both games are available on Microsoft’s subscription service, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=vergdeals&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-US%2Fxbox-game-pass" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xbox Game Pass&lt;/a&gt;. If you don’t have a subscription or want to own the games in your digital library, you can grab &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=vergdeals&amp;amp;murl=http%3A%2F%2Fhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fp%2Fori-the-collection%2F9p5mbbff3rnt" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ori: The Collection&lt;/em&gt; for $12&lt;/a&gt; at the Microsoft Store — that's roughly $24 off its usual price of $35. The compilation includes both titles and is compatible with the Windows PC, Xbox One, and Xbox Series X / S. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qJJPjy"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10335896"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4UWxzJ"&gt;Sling TV, Dish’s streaming service, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22252810/sling-tv-price-increase-free-dvr-youtube-hulu"&gt;recently increased its price to $35 per month&lt;/a&gt;. If you are interested in trying the service with no strings attached&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;Sling TV &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/am/sid/verge/http://sling.com?SID=___vg__e_20848077__t_w__d_D" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;new customers free viewing&lt;/a&gt; between 5PM ET and midnight until February 14th. No credit card is required. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RYORIN"&gt;Additionally, if you’re a new customer and want to continue using the service, Sling TV is offering a $25 discount on the first month if you decide to purchase a Sling Orange or Blue package. Alternatively, you can choose an option to receive an AirTV Mini at no additional cost if you shell out $35 in your first month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="CxKNWA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Sling TV","description":"New users can get $25 off their first month","label":"Subscribe","url":"https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/am/sid/verge/http://sling.com?SID=___vg__e_20848077__t_w__d_D"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;aside id="c5sgjM"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/2/10/22276122/apple-ipad-2020-one-plus-8-ori-collection-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/2/10/22276122/apple-ipad-2020-one-plus-8-ori-collection-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T10:31:19-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T10:31:19-05:00</updated>
    <title>Nvidia is requiring laptop makers to be more transparent about RTX 30-series specs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="MSI GS66 Stealth" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GGkFO5nAOrnsUmAJF7szxbdGn4s=/0x85:2040x1445/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68774775/cfaulkner_210121_4379_0007.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="J5GHXZ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 10th, 10:31AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The bullet list at the bottom now reflects that Gigabyte has updated all of its product pages with the required information about the RTX 30-series graphics chips its laptops use.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="emYkbk"&gt;Nvidia is now requiring, not just encouraging, companies selling laptops with its new RTX 30-series graphics chips to be more transparent about the kind of power people can expect. Nvidia tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;these companies will have to disclose specific clock speed stats and total graphics power on online product pages — all of which tells people everything they need to know about a laptop’s graphics potential, for better or worse. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZXHuKd"&gt;However, companies won’t have to mention that these chips are Max-Q variants because, according to an Nvidia spokesperson, “Max-Q is no longer part of the GPU name.” Rather, Max-Q is now solely used to communicate that a laptop with an RTX 30-series graphics chip ships with efficiency features like Whisper Mode 2, Dynamic Boost 2, and Advanced Optimus. Previously, seeing Max-Q branding made it easy to determine a laptop’s general performance without having to know its specific clock speeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A2DsTp"&gt;It’s encouraging to see Nvidia no longer &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22243065/nvidia-gaming-laptop-graphic-chips-capability-manufacturer-transparency"&gt;allows companies to hide this vital information&lt;/a&gt; from marketing materials. It should go far enough in helping buyers make an educated purchase without having to wait on reviewers and early adopters to report on the specs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9RsrBF"&gt;By sharing these specs, companies can make it much easier for consumers to understand how it’s possible that, in some instances, the RTX 3070 in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22244409/msi-gp66-leopard-gaming-laptop-review-price-specs-features"&gt;MSI’s GP66 Leopard&lt;/a&gt; can outperform an RTX 3080 in the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22248630/msi-gs66-stealth-2021-review-rtx-3080-nvidia-qhd-1440p-gaming-laptop"&gt;MSI GS66 Stealth&lt;/a&gt;, which is something we saw first-hand. Since the Max-Q brand no longer signifies a graphics chip’s power capabilities, being transparent with clock speed and how much power it can consume is more crucial than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Nvidia RTX laptops" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/W7bY5R4IZGgiPi2jLRWNzVa8gRA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22260491/nvidia_ampere_mobile_gpus_tdp.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Nvidia&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nvidia now requires companies share the clock speed and power on laptop product pages&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="P7RJdo"&gt;“We’re requiring OEMs to update their product pages to the Max-Q technology features for each GeForce laptop, as well as clocks and power — which communicates the expected GPU performance in that system,” an Nvidia spokesperson told &lt;em&gt;The Verge. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZpvjoM"&gt;Nvidia says manufacturers have already begun sharing this info, including Asus and Gigabyte, which we confirmed at the time of publishing. We’re going to keep tabs on some models coming out soon (and those currently on the market) to see how long it takes for these requirements to roll out across the industry. Let us know in the comments if you notice that one has been updated with info or needs to be added to this list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tcfAjN"&gt;Origin PC&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="A4CCh8"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.originpc.com/gaming/laptops/evo15-s/"&gt;EVO 15-S&lt;/a&gt; (not updated as of Feb. 10th with clock / power specs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="svdGQL"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.originpc.com/gaming/laptops/new-evo17-s/"&gt;EVO 17-S&lt;/a&gt; (not updated as of Feb. 10th with clock / power specs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="5Mi2NI"&gt;Acer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="lB0La7"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.acer.com%2Fac%2Fen%2FUS%2Fcontent%2Fseries%2Fnitro5&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F5%2F22266921%2Fnvidia-requiring-companies-share-clock-speed-power-gaming-laptop-rtx-30-series-gpu-specs#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nitro 5&lt;/a&gt;  (not updated as of Feb. 10th with clock / power specs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0NdQKW"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.acer.com%2Fac%2Fen%2FUS%2Fcontent%2Fpredator-series%2Fpredatortriton300se&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F5%2F22266921%2Fnvidia-requiring-companies-share-clock-speed-power-gaming-laptop-rtx-30-series-gpu-specs#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Predator Triton 300 SE&lt;/a&gt; (not updated as of Feb. 10th with clock / power specs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="eqonrU"&gt;Asus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="AiF5xO"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://rog.asus.com/laptops/rog-zephyrus/2021-rog-zephyrus-g15-series/spec/"&gt;ROG Zephyrus G15&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(updated as of Feb. 5th with clock / power specs)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DgyjAz"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://store.asus.com/us/item/202101AM120000003/TUF-ASUS-TUF-Dash-15-%282021%29-Ultra-Slim-Gaming-Laptop%2C-15.6%E2%80%9D-240Hz-FHD%2C-GeForce-RTX-3070%2C-Intel-Core-i7-11375H%2C-16GB-DDR4%2C-1TB-PCIe-NVMe-SSD%2C-Wi-Fi-6%2C-Windows-10%2C-TUF516PR-DS77-WH"&gt;TUF Dash 15&lt;/a&gt;  (not updated as of Feb. 10th with clock / power specs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Rm8kzt"&gt;Razer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="tWBoCz"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://razer.a9yw.net/c/482924/642901/10229?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.razer.com%2Fgaming-laptops%2FRazer-Blade-15%2FRZ09-0369BEA2-R3U1&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Blade 15&lt;/a&gt; (not updated as of Feb. 10th with clock / power specs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="92Vgdo"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://razer.a9yw.net/c/482924/642901/10229?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.razer.com%2Fgaming-laptops%2FRazer-Blade-Pro-17%2FRZ09-0368BEA2-R3U1&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Blade 17 Pro&lt;/a&gt; (not updated as of Feb. 10th with clock / power specs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="rFIIsg"&gt;Gigabyte&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="iM1fHs"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.gigabyte.com/Laptop/AORUS-15G--RTX-30-Series/sp#sp"&gt;Aorus 15G&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;strong&gt;(updated as of Feb. 5th with clock / power specs)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Hp8eZ8"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.gigabyte.com/Laptop/AORUS-15P--RTX-30-Series/sp#sp"&gt;Aorus 15P&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;strong&gt;(updated as of Feb. 10th with clock / power specs)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rSZYDu"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.gigabyte.com/Laptop/AORUS-17G--RTX-30-Series/sp#sp"&gt;Aorus 17G&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(updated as of Feb. 10th with clock / power specs)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZSoOJE"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.gigabyte.com/Laptop/AERO-15--RTX-30-Series/sp#sp"&gt;Aero 15&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(updated as of Feb. 10th with clock / power specs)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WPyvQ5"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.gigabyte.com/Laptop/AERO-17--RTX-30-Series/sp#sp"&gt;Aero 17&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(updated as of Feb. 10th with clock / power specs)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="eCnGX4"&gt;MSI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="OxvE1m"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://us.msi.com/Laptop/GE76-Raider-10UX/Specification"&gt;GE76 Raider&lt;/a&gt; (not updated as of Feb. 10th with clock / power specs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nEMXgT"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://us.msi.com/Laptop/GP76-Leopard-10UX/Specification"&gt;GP76 Leopard&lt;/a&gt; (not updated as of Feb. 10th with clock / power specs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="UR8N9Z"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://us.msi.com/Laptop/GP66-Leopard-10UX/Specification"&gt;GP66 Leopard&lt;/a&gt; (not updated as of Feb. 10th with clock / power specs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Az3rvi"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://us.msi.com/Laptop/Stealth-15M-A11UX/Specification"&gt;Stealth 15M&lt;/a&gt; (not updated as of Feb. 10th with clock / power specs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="B2nyDO"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://us.msi.com/Laptop/GS66-Stealth-10UX/Specification"&gt;GS66 Stealth&lt;/a&gt; (not updated as of Feb. 10th with clock / power specs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="zeEo3M"&gt;Alienware&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="bIIfDL"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dell.com%2Fen-us%2Fmember%2Fshop%2Fgaming-laptops%2Falienware-m15-r4-gaming-laptop%2Fspd%2Falienware-m15-r4-laptop%2Fwnm15r410h&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F5%2F22266921%2Fnvidia-requiring-companies-share-clock-speed-power-gaming-laptop-rtx-30-series-gpu-specs#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;M15 R4&lt;/a&gt; (not updated as of Feb. 10th with clock / power specs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Zn3y8d"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dell.com%2Fen-us%2Fmember%2Fshop%2Fcty%2Fpdp%2Fspd%2Falienware-m17-r4-laptop%23tabs_section&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F5%2F22266921%2Fnvidia-requiring-companies-share-clock-speed-power-gaming-laptop-rtx-30-series-gpu-specs#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;M17 R4&lt;/a&gt; (not updated as of Feb. 10th with clock / power specs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="rQLrYA"&gt;Lenovo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="XD3Gf3"&gt;Product pages aren’t yet live for the Legion 7 and Legion 5 Pro, and it didn’t share specs in &lt;a href="https://news.lenovo.com/pressroom/press-releases/lenovo-legion-goes-all-out-new-futuristic-gaming-machines/"&gt;its press release&lt;/a&gt; or in the information provided to us &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22227013/lenovo-legion-7-slim-5-pro-gaming-laptops-amd-ryzen-5000-cpu-nvidia-rtx-gpu-ces-2021"&gt;for our coverage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="St2s5t"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22266921/nvidia-requiring-companies-share-clock-speed-power-gaming-laptop-rtx-30-series-gpu-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22266921/nvidia-requiring-companies-share-clock-speed-power-gaming-laptop-rtx-30-series-gpu-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T10:26:13-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T10:26:13-05:00</updated>
    <title>The TikTok-Oracle deal is on life support under Biden</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wkQTlYHLYoTtKCON0NHcYymGj1w=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68798018/acastro_190723_1777_tiktok_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VAb3Aa"&gt;Nearly five months after it was announced, a proposed hosting deal between Oracle and TikTok is on permanent hold, according to &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/tiktok-sale-to-oracle-walmart-is-shelved-as-biden-reviews-security-11612958401?mod=djemalertNEWS"&gt;a report by &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The deal has been “shelved indefinitely” pending a broader review of the Trump administration’s China policy, says the &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt;, citing sources familiar with the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y2aLgV"&gt;Oracle announced in September that it was planning to take over as TikTok’s “trusted tech partner” for the United States as part of a broader arrangement by the Trump White House. But the deal was widely criticized as a “glorified hosting deal” that did little to resolve underlying concerns about Chinese government influence over the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qV11wU"&gt;The Trump White House had pushed hard for a deal between TikTok and some US corporation, beginning with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/10/21358505/trump-tiktok-wechat-tencent-bytedance-china-ban-executive-order-legal-sanctions-rules"&gt;a legally dubious executive order on August 6th&lt;/a&gt; that sought to ban any transactions with the company unless security concerns could be resolved. After extensive discussions, Treasury officials presented an Oracle partnership as the only way for TikTok to continue operating in the country. In the months after its announcement, the deal was stalled by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/7/22160239/tiktok-ban-judge-trump-administration-us-commerce-department"&gt;a string of successful court challenges&lt;/a&gt; to the August 6th order. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k9wHWf"&gt;If President Biden shifts away from Trump’s aggressive policy toward the app, TikTok would likely continue its US operations without any assistance from Oracle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0chclN"&gt;Biden’s tech policy is still taking shape, but the new president has shown some willingness to continue Trump-era efforts to stem Chinese influence. Earlier this month, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-02-04/biden-commerce-pick-sees-no-reason-to-pull-huawei-from-blacklist"&gt;incoming Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo told Congress&lt;/a&gt; that she saw “no reason” to remove Huawei from the Entity List, suggesting that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/13/21257675/trump-extends-huawei-ban-may-2021-china-us-android-google-telecom"&gt;Trump’s ban on Huawei telecom products&lt;/a&gt; will likely continue under the Biden administration.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276090/tiktok-oracle-deal-biden-trump-ban-china-bytedance-white-house"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276090/tiktok-oracle-deal-biden-trump-ban-china-bytedance-white-house</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T10:17:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T10:17:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to use Snap Camera to become a cat (or anything else) on Zoom</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dD3oSd4DvsqVEWnkHjESVonKpJA=/0x0:1900x1267/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68797965/Barbara_with_towel.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bixet1"&gt;The latest absurd YouTube video to do the rounds is that of a lawyer named Rod Ponton who accidentally attended a civil hearing on Zoom &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/2/9/22274865/zoom-hearing-cat-filter-lawyer-texas-live-court-hearing"&gt;wearing a cat filter&lt;/a&gt; (and couldn’t figure out how to turn it off). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MdtND7"&gt;While we’re not absolutely sure where Mr. Ponton’s filter came from (&lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-56010156"&gt;according to an article from the BBC&lt;/a&gt;, it’s an old app called Live Cam Avatar that used to be preinstalled on some Dell computers), there is at least one app out there called &lt;a href="https://snapcamera.snapchat.com/"&gt;Snap Camera&lt;/a&gt; that will let you turn yourself into a variety of on-camera creatures. While it doesn’t provide the exact cat head the lawyer found himself wearing, it does let you add a wide range of effects, backgrounds, and distortions, some of which are downright nightmarish. (My favorite is the one that places a restive cat on top of your head.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g42Tcv"&gt;Once installed on your Windows PC or Mac, Snap Camera works with Zoom, Twitch, Skype, and a variety of other online services. In fact, according to the company, it can be used with most apps that use a webcam. For example, here’s how to add Snap Camera’s effects to your Zoom app:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="hNV2Gh"&gt;Download and install Snap Camera &lt;a href="https://snapcamera.snapchat.com/"&gt;from its website&lt;/a&gt; (after signing off on the usual privacy policy, license agreement, and terms of services). You’ll need a computer running Windows 10 or Mac 10.31 or later. During the installation, you’ll be asked for access to your computer’s camera and microphone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NPbxt2"&gt;If you’re running any active video or streaming apps, you’ll be asked to close them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cFGlzh"&gt;Start Zoom. On a Mac, use the top menu to go to “Preferences” &amp;gt; “Video.” On a PC, click on the gear icon in the upper-right corner and select “Video.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0c5FWM"&gt;Click on the drop-down menu labeled “Camera” and select “Snap Camera”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="After finding Zoom’s Settings menu, use the drop-down menu to select “Snap Camera.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SpP2fOKxnUjCknGWLZ5dNg9OAfg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22294386/Screen_Shot_2021_02_10_at_8.48.54_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;After finding Zoom’s Settings menu, use the drop-down menu to select “Snap Camera.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="a49THd"&gt;That’s it! Now you can go into the Snap Camera app and choose your filter. There is a wide variety to choose from. A window at the top of the app shows you how each filter will affect your appearance — and what your video feed will look like next time you start a Zoom meeting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GAYS5C"&gt;If you no longer want to use Snap Camera, just follow the directions above to go back to your default Zoom camera app. And if you’re really ambitious, you can try playing with &lt;a href="https://lensstudio.snapchat.com/?_ga=2.164728765.384583738.1612906864-1833670117.1610049906"&gt;Snap’s app Lens Studio&lt;/a&gt; to create your own filters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6lapCd"&gt;One piece of advice: use Snap Camera’s settings (found by clicking on the gear icon in the upper-right corner) to create a hotkey that will quickly turn the app on and off. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="After finding Zoom’s Settings menu, use the drop-down menu to select “Snap Camera.”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sHcTMu3D8Plk7u_cWslyjQFkX0c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22294388/Screen_Shot_2021_02_10_at_9.09.47_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Use Snap Camera’s settings to create an on / off hotkey.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="2KshB1"&gt;That way, if you’re ever caught in a business meeting with your cat filter on, you can turn it off immediately without too much embarrassment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rDdnKQ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pCni74"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="THyoiJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PA8v8Q"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OWjelz"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VxPIe1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RmhRif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Eqnfb3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5BwKy7"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6HFpDw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EUhpT0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22276091/zoom-snap-camera-filter-how-to-youtube-cat"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22276091/zoom-snap-camera-filter-how-to-youtube-cat</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Why social networks need better blocking tools</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GZ-80oMR9BfeJdcYzZD98PeEuZ4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68797818/acastro_180329_1777__brains_science_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;h2 id="MRscL3"&gt;I.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="DOTSMN"&gt;Blocking is having a moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ingr8K"&gt;Last month, Tracy Chou &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/01/15/block-party-launch/"&gt;announced that she had raised a little under $1.5 million&lt;/a&gt; to launch &lt;a href="https://www.blockpartyapp.com/"&gt;Block Party&lt;/a&gt;, an anti-harassment startup that helps people filter abuse out of their social media experiences. On Monday, &lt;a href="https://www.blocknyt.com/"&gt;Block the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a tool to block 800 &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; reporters on Twitter at once, materialized via a satirical website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tzyA3p"&gt;Meanwhile, the unique blocking mechanics of the audio social network Clubhouse — and their enthusiastic use by the platform’s lead investors — have &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Jessicalessin/status/1356091226093588482"&gt;raised questions&lt;/a&gt; about whether people in positions of power should be blocking to avoid public scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0rKJKu"&gt;Behind all these stories, I think, is a kind of despair over what public social networks have done to public debate. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/bonerwizard/status/1358923285480628230?s=21"&gt;Context collapse&lt;/a&gt; — the disorientation that comes from addressing infinite audiences online, each with their own norms and expectations for others’ behavior — is driving more and more conversation away from the public square. And while platforms have gradually begun paying more attention to safety issues, trolling and harassment remains a fact of life for too many people who use social networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LZlnIo"&gt;Viewed in that light, aggressive use of the block button makes all the sense in the world. By shrinking the size of your audience, even if only one person at a time, you can gradually rebuild context around the audience to whom you are speaking. And when trolls and abusers rear their heads, the block button remains an effective tool we have for preventing them from harassing us in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6W67Wk"&gt;When it comes to Twitter — or to Facebook, or Instagram, or Snapchat — blocking is relatively uncontroversial. And Twitter has added features in recent years that offer users ways to fight context collapse without requiring you to, for example, block 800 reporters. Maybe you want to limit replies to people you follow. Or maybe you don’t want anyone to be able to reply at all. Tools like these remove what my friend Hunter Walk calls the “paper cuts” a product can inflict on a user: small, unpleasant interactions that erode your affection for a tool over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="06RxBl"&gt;Clubhouse is a new kind of social network, though, and &lt;a href="https://www.notion.so/Community-Guidelines-461a6860abda41649e17c34dc1dd4b5f"&gt;its approach to blocking&lt;/a&gt; has drawn some scrutiny. What sets it apart is that audience members can effectively prevent other people from joining the audience for public discussions, if at any point that audience member is made a speaker or moderator of the chat. (It’s common for small Clubhouse chats to invite everyone to become a speaker as soon as they enter the room.) If I’m listening to an interesting conversation and raise my hand to speak, and I ask a question, anyone I block will henceforth be unable to enter the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JaLX92"&gt;This phenomenon was most visible during &lt;a href="https://www.platformer.news/p/clubhouses-moment-arrives"&gt;Elon Musk’s January 31st appearance on the app&lt;/a&gt;. While the show he appeared on was created by its hosts, Sriram Krishnan and Aarthi Ramamurthy, Andreessen Horowitz co-founder Marc Andreessen was made a speaker — and, as a result, many journalists found themselves shut out of the room. For reasons he has never really explained, Andreessen &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/clubhouse-investor-marc-andreessen-blocking-journalists-2021-2"&gt;has blocked most of the press corps on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and now on Clubhouse, myself included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5EdAL5"&gt;“It is one thing to block people from sending you messages,”&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Jessicalessin/status/1356092980122148865"&gt; tweeted Jessica Lessin&lt;/a&gt;, founder of &lt;em&gt;The Information&lt;/em&gt;, in a short thread about the issue, “but listening to public conversations?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="oukQ1W"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="sBWKew"&gt;As someone who &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/a/verge-2021/marc-andreessen-horowitz-verge-interview"&gt;has interviewed Andreessen before&lt;/a&gt;, and really enjoyed it, I feel this pain acutely. I’d like to know what he’s tweeting about and saying in Clubhouse rooms. And I’d also probably like to listen in on some future Clubhouse conversations where he gets called on to be a speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ciywto"&gt;At the same time, an important aspect of blocking is that the person you block doesn’t get a say in it. If you’ve ever blocked someone yourself, you probably wouldn’t want them to. I wish Andreessen hadn’t blocked me, but I also don’t think I’m entitled to an explanation. Maybe not seeing my dumb tweets has improved his experience of Twitter. That’s fine!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yu41cR"&gt;I thought of this over the weekend when my friend Taylor Lorenz and other journalists entered a Clubhouse room in which the Andreessen Horowitz founders were discussing r/WallStreetBets, of the recent GameStop stock mania. Some members of that forum refer to themselves using an offensive word, which Horowitz repeated in a question to a guest (“take us through the r***** revolution”). Some people wrongly thought Andreessen had used the word; breakout rooms began to appear in Clubhouse to criticize him over it. Journalists tweeted about it, confusing Andreessen with Horowitz. Tweets were deleted; Lorenz apologized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NtH0hE"&gt;The whole incident, to me, makes the case for blocking. In offline life, when we worry that our public comments might be misconstrued, we limit the audience for those comments. In online life, when our potential audience is exponentially larger, it makes sense that we would want to limit that audience with extra care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X1KI57"&gt;It also makes sense not to use offensive words when addressing an audience of thousands in a business context. But context collapse means that once you’re above a certain number of followers, there will always be an audience coming after you about &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nuuzK5"&gt;Ultimately, I think we should support strong blocking tools for the same reason we should support strong encryption: the more that we live our lives online, the more important that private spaces become. And yes, there are trade-offs: the internet makes it easier for bad actors to come together in private spaces, and platforms should take steps to mitigate the harms that they can cause. But a healthy democracy requires both public and private conversations, and platforms ought to facilitate the best of both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="mKq8ag"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;III.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Zc635d"&gt;Okay, sure. But isn’t there something &lt;em&gt;unseemly&lt;/em&gt; about the rich and powerful building private spaces only to exclude journalists from scrutinizing them? I sympathize with Lessin on this point, particularly during a time when the media has been under assault from all quarters. (Andreessen Horowitz’s decision to shun the media extends far beyond social networks, &lt;a href="https://www.newcomer.co/p/the-unauthorized-story-of-andreessen"&gt;as Eric Newcomer recently reported&lt;/a&gt;.) Some of the recent fervor in Silicon Valley to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/balajis/status/1264361513990582273?lang=en"&gt;go “direct”&lt;/a&gt; — which is to say, &lt;em&gt;around&lt;/em&gt; the media — has a Trumpist cast to it: &lt;em&gt;reporters are the enemy of the people, and talking to them is beneath us&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g7cTQ9"&gt;Moreover, if several people you follow on Clubhouse have blocked an account, that profile will display a badge when you visit to warn you. While this likely has some safety benefits, Lorenz told me that it can also be abused by people who mass-block accounts of good citizens on the app just to exclude them from popular conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="astZwU"&gt;All this makes me wonder whether Clubhouse could refine its blocking tools over time to enable private conversations while also being more inclusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="010SEZ"&gt;I asked Block Party’s Tracy Chou. She reminded me that blocking means something different on every platform, giving each company a chance to reimagine how it might be most effective for its users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="06I0tx"&gt;“On Twitter, blocking someone means they can’t follow you, they can’t see your profile when they’re logged in, and it tells them that they’re blocked, they can’t respond to your tweets and have their replies show up,” Chou told me over direct message. “But there’s no actual reason that those all &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to be properties of blocking someone. Clubhouse has designed blocking in a specific way with a different set of permissions and consequences. Just because Twitter block and Clubhouse block are both called ‘block’ doesn’t mean they’re the same at all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2b8tBj"&gt;If it wanted to, Chou said, Clubhouse could develop other constructs beyond blocking and muting to offer users more fine-grained control. I’d like to see the app consider a “broadcast” mode that eliminated caps on how many people could attend — no more spillover rooms when an Elon Musk or Mark Zuckerberg shows up to chat. Perhaps such a mode could allow everyone to listen, unless the original moderators of the chat (and not someone who was later invited to speak) had blocked them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z9MAoa"&gt;When any new social network becomes popular, reporters will scrutinize how powerful people are using it. That scrutiny is necessary and good. But privacy is necessary and good, too. Blocking is a blunt tool to achieve that end, but it can be refined over time — complemented with tools that achieve similar ends with more inclusive means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VexeTj"&gt;That could introduce complexity for both developers and for users. But then again, as Chou told me, “the users with the most need will probably try to figure it out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="HJw29d"&gt;
&lt;p id="jpbv8e"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This column was co-published with &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.platformer.news/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Platformer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, a daily newsletter about Big Tech and democracy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22275568/blocking-clubhouse-block-party-social-networks"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22275568/blocking-clubhouse-block-party-social-networks</id>
    <author>
      <name>Casey Newton</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Super Mario 3D World + Bowser’s Fury is the best of Mario in one package</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CSXpwrkwC3Bx5xaRsfvSOCWDbNc=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68797507/Switch_SM3DWBowsersFury_screenshot_28_copy.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7hTsRh"&gt;Ever since the open green fields of &lt;em&gt;Super Mario 64&lt;/em&gt;, Nintendo has experimented with the best way to transport Mario into three dimensions. From the bite-sized planetoids of &lt;em&gt;Galaxy&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/26/16552118/super-mario-odyssey-review-nintendo-switch"&gt;the &lt;em&gt;hakoniwa&lt;/em&gt;-inspired worlds of &lt;em&gt;Odyssey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; the Kyoto game maker has never settled on just one formula. Mario’s side-scrolling adventures largely all worked the same, but in 3D, players never knew what to expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="todHHn"&gt;That’s part of what made &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/11/22/5133098/super-mario-3d-world-review"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Super Mario 3D World&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; so beloved when it launched on the Wii U in 2013. It took the familiar level-based gameplay of classic two-dimensional &lt;em&gt;Super Mario&lt;/em&gt; games and fused it with the more expansive 3D gameplay, building off of the portable-only &lt;em&gt;Super Mario 3D Land&lt;/em&gt;. Plus, it let Mario dress up as an adorable cat for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IXvRSi"&gt;Inevitably, the game is now launching on the Switch. But this week’s rerelease of &lt;em&gt;3D World&lt;/em&gt; is more than just a simple port. The base game remains identical to the original, but Nintendo has packaged it with a brand-new, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22250703/super-mario-3d-world-bowsers-fury-nintendo-switch-hands-on-preview"&gt;expansion pack-like adventure called &lt;em&gt;Bowser’s Fury&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It takes many of the same ideas as &lt;em&gt;3D World&lt;/em&gt; but puts them in a new kind of open world, one filled with constant danger thanks to a kaiju-sized Bowser roaming around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D4iJ2W"&gt;Put these in the same collection and you end up with the best of both worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jXp9ZGvhQHLs9hhTv246Mrd8c60=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22293016/Switch_SM3DWBowsersFury_screenshot_21_copy.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ZxjAUv"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Super Mario 3D World&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="m0BYOd"&gt;When &lt;em&gt;Super Mario 3D World&lt;/em&gt; first launched it was something of a contradiction: it was both a departure &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; a return to the series’ roots. While it’s a 3D game, it doesn’t take place in one large world. Instead, the experience consists of a series of discrete, smaller levels that you access from an overworld map, much like if you were playing &lt;em&gt;Super Mario World&lt;/em&gt; on the SNES.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="40UPNb"&gt;The game strikes a nearly perfect balance between structure and creativity. While it’s full of short levels with a distinct beginning and end, it plays around with the formula with so many interesting ideas, whether that’s stages where you have to track shadows across the walls or chase down Bowser in a fireball-spewing convertible. &lt;em&gt;3D World&lt;/em&gt; also introduced several important ideas to the series. Perhaps the most notable are the cat suit, which lets Mario scamper up walls and slice at goombas with his claws, and the puzzle-oriented side missions starring Captain Toad. (The former even spawned its own spinoff which, like &lt;em&gt;3D World&lt;/em&gt;, eventually made the transition from the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/12/1/7303799/captain-toad-treasure-tracker-review"&gt;Wii U&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/13/17568040/captain-toad-treasure-tracker-nintendo-switch-review"&gt;Switch&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="il64aY"&gt;This was all true eight years ago, and the game remains a delight today. It doesn’t exactly look like a modern game, but the bright, colorful visuals hold up well. More importantly, even with all of the &lt;em&gt;Super Mario&lt;/em&gt; titles that have come since, &lt;em&gt;3D World&lt;/em&gt;’s particular blending of styles remains distinct. It’s still fun to revisit, but this is also a great opportunity for those who missed out the first time around. (And given the Wii U’s relative failure, that’s probably a large amount of people.) Of course, &lt;em&gt;3D World&lt;/em&gt; also benefits from the shift to the Switch, as its small levels are ideal for playing on the go. The only drawback is the touch controls, which made more sense when you had a clunky Wii U tablet in your hands but can be awkward when playing on the Switch in TV mode where touch is replaced by an on-screen cursor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sZKYwr"&gt;Essentially, this is an ideal port of one of the best &lt;em&gt;Super Mario&lt;/em&gt; games to date...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DRvASMloA4Z-11xgldlzaxjYh44=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22293035/Switch_SM3DWBowsersFury_screenshot_07_copy.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id="2mNRwf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bowser’s Fury&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="CmcDd4"&gt;...but it’s also a lot more. The other half of the equation, &lt;em&gt;Bowser’s Fury,&lt;/em&gt; is a standalone experience, one you can choose to play right away from the main menu. Mechanically, it’s nearly identical to &lt;em&gt;3D World&lt;/em&gt;. You can still dress up like a kitty and zip around in transparent tubes, though it adds 360-degree camera control, giving it a much more modern feel. Outside of that, there are two main elements that make this expansion interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ogqATk"&gt;The first is its structure. &lt;em&gt;Bowser’s Fury&lt;/em&gt; takes place in a large archipelago, with no discrete worlds or levels, just a whole bunch of small islands. The goal, as always, is to collect bright shiny coins, which in turn open up new areas for exploration. Essentially, the whole island chain is one big series of challenges, and it’s your job to find and complete them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OGhUWN"&gt;There’s a huge range of things to do: fight bosses, chase down bunnies, race on the back of a sea creature, climb giant towers, navigate treacherous stretches of molten lava, and a lot more. In true &lt;em&gt;Super Mario&lt;/em&gt; fashion, some of these tasks are fairly simple, while others — particularly toward the end of the game — are deviously hard challenges with tight time limits. Suffice to say, getting every coin will take some work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7FlWF8"&gt;What makes this structure work particularly well is Bowser himself. The game’s story involves you teaming up with Bowser Jr. — who floats alongside you and can help fight enemies or point out areas of interest — to help restore his dad, who has been blown up to Godzilla-like proportions. His newfound size and powers manifest in two ways. To start, he’s constantly lurking in the background, and every so often he’ll emerge and attack. You’ll know it’s coming: first there’s a bit of wind and rain, and then the whole world turns dark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uWyYIT"&gt;It’s almost like a twist on the light and dark worlds in a &lt;em&gt;Zelda&lt;/em&gt; game. When Bowser is in Godzilla attack mode, flaming balls rain down and he spews a stream of fire at you. This makes things more dangerous, but it also has its benefits: some areas can only be accessed if Bowser’s flames destroy bricks blocking the way. You have to think strategically during these moments, instead of just staying in survival mode. It gives you a chance to see familiar spaces in a different way.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VQSaDNGhQXTL0cxgP-yJqUI3ju0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22293279/Switch_SM3DWBowsersFury_screenshot_02_copy.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Jszwx6"&gt;And then there are the gigantic boss battles. Normally, you can’t actually attack Bowser. But when you collect enough coins, you’ll unlock the temple, where you can use a massive bell to turn into a giant cat Mario, one that’s able to go toe-to-toe with Bowser. This happens periodically throughout the game — it takes more than a few tries to finally take down Mario’s nemesis — and the battles are thrilling. Each time you take on Bowser he has new abilities and patterns, and just seeing the scale and destruction of these battles is unlike anything I’ve experienced in a &lt;em&gt;Super Mario&lt;/em&gt; game before. It also gives you something tangible to work toward: you aren’t just collecting coins to get them all, you’re also trying for another shot at Bowser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UfBEfw"&gt;There are two other important things to note about &lt;em&gt;Bowser’s Fury&lt;/em&gt;. One, it’s not a full-scale &lt;em&gt;Super Mario&lt;/em&gt; game. While it’s a meaty adventure with lots to do and unlock, it’s probably about one-third the size of comparable games in the series. The other thing to note is that, despite its dark themes, &lt;em&gt;Bowser’s Fury&lt;/em&gt; is achingly adorable. The islands you explore appear to have been rendered by the world’s biggest cat fan. Seriously, everything in the game, from the bushes to the goombas to the lighthouses to the pigeons, is cat-themed. At one point, while I was wearing the cat suit, an entire gang of rainbow-hued cats started following me, and when I stopped running away it turned into an impromptu cuddle party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MhMqVk"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bowser’s Fury&lt;/em&gt; is essentially a remix of &lt;em&gt;3D World&lt;/em&gt;, one that takes the same basic themes and mechanics but turns them into something that feels both new and familiar at the same time. Really, this package is indicative of 3D &lt;em&gt;Super Mario&lt;/em&gt; games as a whole: it’s a series where you never quite know what to expect with each new release. Sometimes that means a whole new structure or gameplay twist. Other times it means towering monsters and lots of cute cats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CEj1pY"&gt;&lt;small&gt;Super Mario 3D World + Bowser’s Fury &lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;launches on February 12th on the Nintendo Switch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22274990/super-mario-3d-world-bowsers-fury-review-nintendo-switch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22274990/super-mario-3d-world-bowsers-fury-review-nintendo-switch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-10T08:58:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-10T08:58:26-05:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook will test cutting back on political posts in the News Feed</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q5-kF_sYuPPj6Y-QzPPrBloO1hE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68797499/acastro_180720_1777_facebook_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IjfAhA"&gt;Facebook plans to test how people respond to seeing fewer posts about politics in the News Feed. Starting this week, Facebook will “temporarily reduce” political posts for a “small percentage” of people in Canada, Brazil, and Indonesia, with a test in the US following some weeks later. The tests will continue for the next few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4c9mTl"&gt;The experiment comes in response to feedback Facebook has (somehow just now) heard that “people don’t want political content to take over their News Feed,” Aastha Gupta, product management director at Facebook, wrote &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/02/reducing-political-content-in-news-feed/"&gt;in a blog post&lt;/a&gt; this morning. The goal is to improve the News Feed by “finding a new balance of the content people want to see.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ah6rzM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Users “don’t want politics and fighting to take over their experience on our services.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5aVqcW"&gt;Gupta says that political content only makes up about 6 percent of the typical News Feed right now in the US. Nonetheless, that small percentage has clearly had an oversized impact, prompting years of discussions around the polarizing effects of people being served up too-often misleading political stories. Facebook has widely been blamed for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/interface/2020/5/28/21272001/facebook-polarization-wall-street-journal-guy-rosen-platform-integrity-twitter-trump"&gt;stoking polarization&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/14/opinion/facebook-far-right.html"&gt;boosting far-right voices&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z0x1hJ"&gt;In October, Facebook said it would temporarily stop recommending civic and political groups to users in the US, and &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-facebook-groups/facebook-says-it-will-permanently-stop-recommending-political-groups-to-users-idUSKBN29X00C"&gt;last month&lt;/a&gt; it said that change would become permanent. Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg said on &lt;a href="https://s21.q4cdn.com/399680738/files/doc_financials/2020/q4/FB-Q4-2020-Conference-Call-Transcript.pdf"&gt;a call&lt;/a&gt; with investors that the goal was to “turn down the temperature and discourage divisive conversations and communities.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="szJWYp"&gt;The tests around reducing political content overall are part of the same initiative. Zuckerberg said Facebook wants to allow political discussions and grassroots organizing to keep happening, but that users “don’t want politics and fighting to take over their experience on our services.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o7XRx3"&gt;Facebook says health agencies and information on COVID-19 from authoritative groups like the WHO will be exempt from the reduced political distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7bIjyw"&gt;The tests come after years of frustrations, from pretty much all directions, around how Facebook handles political content. Facebook shut down an internal effort in 2018 to make its site less divisive, &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-knows-it-encourages-division-top-executives-nixed-solutions-11590507499?mod=hp_lead_pos5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal &lt;/em&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; last year. At the same time, Facebook was making choices of its own that seemed to up the divisiveness. In 2017, the company pulled back on reductions to political content distribution would have had an outsized impact on right-wing sides, and instead put forward changes that more significantly limited the reach of left-wing sites, &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/how-mark-zuckerberg-learned-politics-11602853200"&gt;the &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; also reported.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276076/facebook-political-posts-reduce-news-feed-tests"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22276076/facebook-political-posts-reduce-news-feed-tests</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
