<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-05-25T13:31:51-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-25T13:31:51-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-25T13:31:51-04:00</updated>
    <title>The first trailer for Last Night in Soho shows a neon-filled time-traveling ghost story</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/InhHiG_0GU_g1XL097cteNp4FrY=/159x0:3312x2102/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69340273/Screen_Shot_2021_05_25_at_9.53.10_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Focus Features&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9twlIf"&gt;Being a young person in the city is hard enough without being haunted by a cabaret singer from the 1960s, but that’s exactly what Thomasin McKenzie (&lt;em&gt;Jojo Rabbit)&lt;/em&gt; appears to be dealing with in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/edgarwright/status/1397205817879928835?s=20"&gt;the first trailer for Edgar Wright’s &lt;em&gt;Last Night in Soho&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The film is set to premiere in theaters in October, but the trailer seems like a nice taste of Wright’s clever style through a horror lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tKw9HQ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last Night in Soho &lt;/em&gt;follows McKenzie as Eloise, a young fashion fan who seemingly has the ability to dream herself into the past. The problem is she isn’t herself when she visits London’s West End in the 1960s; she’s Anya Taylor-Joy’s Sandy, a singer who, if the trailer is anything to go by, probably shouldn’t be dating whoever Matt Smith is playing (“Jack,” &lt;a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt9639470/fullcredits?ref_=tt_cl_sm#cast"&gt;according to IMDb&lt;/a&gt;). Things take a turn toward the ghostly from there as the past bleeds into the present. It turns out dreaming you’re Taylor-Joy isn’t as chill as I assumed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bsxyCi"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tB9WUIv9KH8?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="C6nF9F"&gt;The film’s distributor, Focus Features, describes &lt;em&gt;Last Night in Soho&lt;/em&gt; as a “psychological thriller,” which is a notable change of pace from Wright’s usual preference for action and comedy. Wright’s toyed with horror before in &lt;em&gt;Shaun of the Dead&lt;/em&gt;, but the &lt;em&gt;Soho&lt;/em&gt; trailer, with its neon reds and blues and focus on knives and / or stabbing is also harkening back to popular Italian “giallo” horror films — specifically the work of director Dario Argento, even more specifically, his 1977 film &lt;em&gt;Suspiria&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RyaSIf"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/23/18011868/suspiria-movie-review-dakota-johnson-luca-guadagnino-remake-2018"&gt;The 2018 remake of &lt;em&gt;Suspiria&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;leaned more into the gruesome body horror of “what if witches ran a dance school?” (In short, bodies can twist in horrifying ways.) But where that film didn’t really pick up Argento’s love of dramatic lighting and synths, Wright seems primed to at least carry forward some of that mantle with &lt;em&gt;Last Night in Soho.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WDk7mS"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last Night in Soho&lt;/em&gt; will hit theaters in October, with a more specific release date to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F3cXVi"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453132/last-night-in-soho-edgar-wright-ghosts-anya-taylor-joy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453132/last-night-in-soho-edgar-wright-ghosts-anya-taylor-joy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-25T13:22:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-25T13:22:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>You can now buy Asus’ gaming-ready ROG Phone 5</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k21J-gQWk1woZxBGM5nLi9PVksc=/0x0:1875x1250/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69340185/Screen_Shot_2021_05_25_at_9.54.34_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Asus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3x5FZD"&gt;Asus’ ROG Phone 5 is now available in the US &lt;a href="https://store.asus.com/us/item/202105AM210000001/ROG5-ASUS-ROG-Phone-5---6.78%E2%80%9D-FHD%2B-2448x1080-HDR-144Hz-Display---6000mAh-Dual-Cell-Battery---64MP%2F13MP%2F5MP-Triple-Camera-with-24MP-Front-Camera-%E2%80%9316GB-RAM---256GB-Storage-5G-LTE-Unlocked-Dual-SIM-Cell-Phone"&gt;from its official store&lt;/a&gt;, with a price tag of $999.99. It’s Asus’ latest maxed-out gaming phone, with all of the top-notch specifications: a Snapdragon 888 Plus, 144Hz display, front-facing speakers, and a massive 6,000mAh battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fpw3uf"&gt;Asus says the Ultimate and Pro versions of the phone will be available later this year. We &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321496/asus-rog-phone-5-ultimate-review-gaming-phone-snapdragon-888-ram-specs-features"&gt;reviewed the Ultimate in March&lt;/a&gt; and found that it was a good phone that went a little — okay, maybe a lot — overboard with its specs. The vanilla version available for sale today, though, is perhaps a bit more reasonable: it “only” has 16GB of RAM (as opposed to the Ultimate’s 18GB), has half the storage (256GB instead of 512GB), and features an RGB logo on the back instead of an entire OLED screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CpyEWY"&gt;The other thing the regular version is missing is the extra touch-sensitive buttons that provide an alternative to touchscreen controls (though it does still have two of the ultrasonic sensors). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="csxmTC"&gt;For those who want more buttons, though, there’s always &lt;a href="https://store.asus.com/us/item/202105AM250000006/ROG5-ASUS-ROG-Phone-5-and-Gamepad-Bundle"&gt;the gamepad bundle&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href="https://store.asus.com/us/item/202105AM220000003/ROG5-ASUS-ROG-AeroActive-Cooler-5"&gt;AeroActive Cooler 5 accessory&lt;/a&gt;, which has two buttons built in. They do cost extra — with the gamepad bundle coming in at $40 more than just the phone and the cooler costing $70 — but that’s still likely going to be way less than shelling out for the Ultimate version.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453190/asus-rog-phone-5-gaming-mobile-available-pro-ultimate-later"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453190/asus-rog-phone-5-gaming-mobile-available-pro-ultimate-later</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-25T13:08:47-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-25T13:08:47-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft teases a ‘next generation of Windows’ announcement ‘very soon’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FTshAnN9c8ArmLLCFFEBURqpyCk=/170x0:1430x840/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69340125/Windows_10_Sun_Valley_refresh.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="g9eIsg"&gt;Microsoft isn’t talking about its big Windows plans at Build 2021 this week, and that’s because the company is preparing to detail what’s next for its PC operating system separately. Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella teased this announcement during his Build keynote this morning, revealing he has been testing “the next generation of Windows” in recent months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="qeVKgM"&gt;“Soon we will share one of the most significant updates to Windows of the past decade to unlock greater economic opportunity for developers and creators. I’ve been self-hosting it over the past several months, and I’m incredibly excited about the next generation of Windows. Our promise to you is this: we will create more opportunity for every Windows developer today and welcome every creator who is looking for the most innovative, new, open platform to build and distribute and monetize applications. We look forward to sharing more very soon.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="iMG5Mx"&gt;Microsoft has been working on a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22393655/microsoft-windows-app-store-overhaul-apps-games-rumor"&gt;new app store for Windows&lt;/a&gt; in recent months, alongside some significant UI changes to the operating system. Nadella appears to reference the store changes here, with a promise to unlock a better economy for developers and creators within Windows itself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wrewyG"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label='Microsoft teases "next generation" of Windows|102301' data-volume-uuid="3c11e080c" data-volume-id="102301" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-397" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OwDOtX"&gt;This will likely include some significant changes to the Windows Store, allowing developers to submit any Windows application — including browsers like Chrome or Firefox. Rumors have suggested Microsoft may even allow third-party commerce platforms in apps, so developers could avoid Microsoft’s own 15 percent cut on apps and 12 percent cut on games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YtSptU"&gt;Nadella’s specific mention of a “next generation of Windows” is interesting, too. Microsoft typically refers to everything as “Windows 10,” and this language could suggest the company is preparing a more significant shift with Windows branding than just the user interface alone.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0wK5hIBQpwDqXN5Oh6VdVEkH-SY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19247642/akrales_190930_3649_0349.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Windows 10X was supposed to ship this year before it was canceled.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Pn6KYs"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22442421/microsoft-windows-10-x-canceled-official"&gt;Microsoft confirmed last week&lt;/a&gt; that Windows 10X, its OS originally built for dual-screen devices, will no longer ship. The software maker is now bringing the best bits of Windows 10X, a simplified version of Windows, into the main version of Windows 10 instead. We’re expecting to see some significant UI changes to Windows under something codenamed “Sun Valley.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HedK09"&gt;Some of that work has already started, with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/4/22313037/microsoft-windows-10-new-system-icons-ui-overhaul-sun-valley"&gt;new system icons&lt;/a&gt;, File Explorer improvements, and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/6/22422553/microsoft-windows-95-era-icons-removal-windows-10-update-sun-valley"&gt;end of Windows 95-era icons&lt;/a&gt;. Microsoft is also focusing on improving the basic foundations of Windows, with fixes for a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22407995/microsoft-windows-apps-rearranging-sleep-resume-fix-directx-12"&gt;rearranging apps issue&lt;/a&gt; on multiple monitors, the addition of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22336240/microsoft-windows-10-auto-hdr-pc-gaming-directx-11-12"&gt;Xbox Auto HDR feature&lt;/a&gt;, and improvements to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22410088/microsoft-windows-10-bluetooth-aac-support-update"&gt;Bluetooth audio support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CiQ8hb"&gt;Nadella says we’ll hear more about the future of Windows “very soon,” so we’d expect some type of announcement or event in the coming weeks ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453222/microsoft-windows-next-generation-announcement-sun-valley-build-2021-keynote"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453222/microsoft-windows-next-generation-announcement-sun-valley-build-2021-keynote</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-25T13:03:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-25T13:03:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>The founder of lidar maker Velodyne is going to war with his own SPAC</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Ford-Velodyne-CES-2016-verge-03" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/czbsq0mjct2Fe_jFJd6fL-jzFDk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69340093/Ford-Velodyne-CES-2016-verge-03.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PdXyz3"&gt;David Hall, the founder of leading lidar manufacturer Velodyne, is going to war with the SPAC that acquired his company. In a letter, Hall is calling for the resignation of two of the company’s SPAC-appointed board directors, whom he blames for Velodyne’s “poor financial performance.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0yULce"&gt;It’s the latest twist in the increasingly dramatic saga of Velodyne, a top maker of the laser sensors that are viewed as crucial for the operation of autonomous vehicles. Last month, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295550/velodyne-founder-lidar-david-hall-marta-investigation-board"&gt;Hall was ousted as chair of the company’s board, and his wife, Marta Thoma Hall, was removed as its chief marketing officer&lt;/a&gt;. The board cited an investigation into “inappropriate behavior” by both Halls in its justification for their removal. Marta Hall remains a member of Velodyne’s board of directors, while David Hall resigned his position on March 2nd. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zfddfR"&gt;Now, David Hall is striking back by directly challenging the special purpose acquisition company, Graf Industrial Corp, that merged with Velodyne last summer. He is calling for the ouster of two of the SPAC’s chosen board members, Michael Dee and Christopher Thomas, and their replacement with an “independent” member of his own choosing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="4uLNfg"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“I will not stand idly by and watch the Board squander Velodyne Lidar’s bright future”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ttfr38"&gt;“I will not stand idly by and watch the board squander Velodyne Lidar’s bright future with what I believe is a lack of strategic focus and poor corporate governance,” Hall writes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0pz5zI"&gt;Hall accuses the board of making several questionable moves in recent months, including padding Velodyne CEO Anand Gopalan’s compensation “despite knowing the company would miss its 2020 projections.” He also claims that he and his wife were censured by the board “based on an opaque, secret investigation into frivolous claims.” Hall claims he was removed as chairman and his wife’s position was terminated “without reasonable justification.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bHAmZy"&gt;“This seemingly retaliatory move followed our attempt to hold Dr. Gopalan more accountable for the company’s weak performance and reconstitute the board with more experienced and highly-qualified public company directors,” Hall writes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kMyDtQ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/18/16491052/velodyne-lidar-mapping-self-driving-car-david-hall-interview"&gt;Hall has long been revered in the world of autonomous vehicle technology&lt;/a&gt; as a pioneer in the use of laser sensors to enable AVs to “see” the world around them. Lidar, which stands for “light detection and ranging,” uses thousands of laser beams to sense objects and measure their distance. The cone- or cylindrical-shaped sensor perched on the roof of a vehicle has become synonymous with self-driving cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tdqbvl"&gt;Ford was an early backer of Velodyne, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/8/16/12499622/ford-baidu-velodyne-investment"&gt;investing $150 million&lt;/a&gt; in the company in 2017 along with Baidu, the Chinese search giant. Ford contributed $75 million of that total and held 13.1 million shares in the company. The automaker dissolved its stake in the lidar company earlier this month but noted that it would continue to use Velodyne’s sensors on some of its autonomous vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mK6uUb"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/7/21055011/lidar-sensor-self-driving-mainstream-mass-market-velodyne-ces-2020"&gt;Hall stepped down as CEO of Velodyne in January 2020&lt;/a&gt;, replaced by Gopalan, the company’s chief technology officer. But Hall remained executive chairman of the board, steering the company’s major financial decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N1Qn7E"&gt;In June 2020, Velodyne struck a deal with “blank check” company Graf Industrial Corp, with a market value of $1.8 billion. It was part of a wave of companies in the transportation technology space choosing to go public via SPAC and thus avoid a lot of the scrutiny that comes with a more traditional IPO. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Q1JLqM"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Hall’s move highlights a larger issue facing many similar SPAC deals&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="x2dAU0"&gt;Nearly a year later, that deal is starting to show strain. In his letter, Hall excoriates Dee and Thomas as inexperienced and unqualified. He points out that Dee’s other company, advanced recycling firm PureCycle, is itself embroiled in litigation related to his role as chief financial officer following its merger with a SPAC “with disastrous results.” Meanwhile, Thomas’ board position was changed so he wouldn’t face reelection until 2022, which Hall alleges was a move to “entrench” him for another year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2n3QEE"&gt;Hall’s move to strike back at Velodyne’s new parent company highlights a larger issue facing many similar SPAC deals across the industry: the question of controlling interest in the company. Hall says he owns 98,951,541 shares in Velodyne, or roughly 52 percent of the outstanding common stock, which gives him enough voting power to replace Dee and Thomas with a new board director. Hall is nominating Eric Singer, founder and managing member of VIEX Capital Advisors, for that position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EwOQXs"&gt;“In our view, the status quo at Velodyne Lidar is unacceptable,” Hall says. “Poor leadership and weak financial performance are not a recipe for success in the public markets. Stockholders deserve a Board that is committed to honoring its fiduciary duties and focusing on value creation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bWjMch"&gt;A spokesperson for Velodyne did not immediately respond to a request for comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7sQIUB"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update May 25th, 1:35PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;David Hall resigned his position as a member of Velodyne’s board on March 2nd. A previous version of this story incorrectly stated that Hall was still a board member. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453138/velodyne-david-hall-spac-letter-board-removal"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453138/velodyne-david-hall-spac-letter-board-removal</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-25T12:15:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-25T12:15:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>DC attorney general launches antitrust suit against Amazon</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WD6gpt7OasrSMiaP-O3Bq_6_rOE=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69339766/acastro_190920_1777_amazon_0001.0.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="axTcj2"&gt;On Tuesday, DC Attorney General Karl Racine &lt;a href="https://oag.dc.gov/sites/default/files/2021-05/Amazon-Complaint-.pdf"&gt;sued Amazon on antitrust grounds&lt;/a&gt;, accusing the e-commerce giant of suppressing competition by placing strict conditions on what third-party sellers can do outside of the company’s platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T2bctC"&gt;“Amazon’s policies have prevented competing platforms, including sellers’ own websites, from competing on price and gaining market share,” Racine said in a press call. “The loss of competition results in less innovation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y3mjG7"&gt;Filed in DC Superior Court, the lawsuit alleges that Amazon unlawfully maintains its monopoly power by preventing independent sellers from offering products at lower prices on other platforms. It also claims that these “most favored nation” agreements harm consumers by inflating prices and stifling competition and innovation in the online retail market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yZwBDF"&gt;In particular, the lawsuit takes aim at a clause in Amazon’s required agreements for third-party sellers that “explicitly prohibited [third-party sellers] from offering their products on a competing online retail sales platform, including the TPS’s own website, at a lower price or on better terms than the TPS offered the products on Amazon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cx06AX"&gt;Racine is seeking structural remedies, like Amazon ending its price agreements and recovering damages to curb additional anti-competitive conduct. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FZq8wc"&gt;Amazon did not immediately respond to a request for comment by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vy61hZ"&gt;Amazon’s Marketplace platform offers a way for independent sellers to list products and make sales on the site, leading to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/19/18140799/amazon-marketplace-scams-seller-court-appeal-reinstatement"&gt;an often chaotic mix of independent shops and offerings&lt;/a&gt;. Amazon’s pricing agreements with those sellers have long been controversial, and it quietly withdrew one of the clauses &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/11/18260700/amazon-anti-competitive-pricing-agreements-3rd-party-sellers-end"&gt;spelling out the requirement in 2019&lt;/a&gt;. But the new lawsuit argues the same provisions were later incorporated into the company’s Fair Pricing Policy, which deals primarily with deceptive listings or otherwise predatory pricing behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oQIRw2"&gt;The new DC lawsuit is the latest in a string of major antitrust cases against tech companies. Last December, 48 state attorneys general and the Federal Trade Commission &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22158483/facebook-antitrust-lawsuit-anti-competition-behavior-attorneys-general"&gt;sued Facebook&lt;/a&gt; for allegedly acquiring companies that it perceived as competitive threats to its business. That same month, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22178988/google-antitrust-ad-tech-lawsuit-texas-attorney-general-paxton"&gt;Texas Attorney General Ken Paxton&lt;/a&gt; led an antitrust lawsuit against Google for allegedly abusing its market dominance in the online advertising market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Mpq1dd"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/20788384-amazon-complaint-/?embed=1&amp;amp;responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="Amazon-Complaint- (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="905" style="border: 1px solid #aaa; width: 100%; height: 800px; height: calc(100vh - 100px);" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453125/dc-attorney-general-amazon-antitrust-lawsuit-favored-nation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453125/dc-attorney-general-amazon-antitrust-lawsuit-favored-nation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-25T11:54:47-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-25T11:54:47-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sonos updates the One SL to make it more power efficient and recyclable</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jiiyXnsjpqnhQDgyPIXX_Ly12qc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69339575/dseifert_190826_3622_0009.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="t4BEJY"&gt;Sonos is refreshing its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/5/20849821/sonos-one-sl-port-price-specs-features-announcement"&gt;One SL speaker&lt;/a&gt;, which doesn’t have always-on microphones or integrated voice controls, to make it more power efficient and recyclable, the company confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. However, the new model won’t have any additional features or functionality. The updated speaker first appeared in &lt;a href="https://fccid.io/SBVRM038"&gt;FCC filings published Monday&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rnFlfH"&gt;The primary change in this new One SL is a “more efficient” wireless radio, according to Sonos. The base of the speaker has also been redesigned to remove extra plastics and “stickering,” and the product packaging has a “more sustainable design” like what’s used with the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22368487/sonos-roam-bluetooth-speaker-review-features"&gt;recently released Sonos Roam&lt;/a&gt;. And while there won’t be any new functionality, Sonos says that this updated One SL will only work with its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/8/21283738/sonos-s2-platform-app-release-ios-store-google-play"&gt;newer Sonos S2 app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OvPDrU"&gt;Here is exactly what Sonos shared with us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="N6NQ3B"&gt;We continually seek opportunities to make our products more efficient and sustainable. In this case, we’ve made updates to One SL that reduce waste, improve recyclability and deliver efficiencies in power consumption. The principal change is a new, more efficient wireless radio (hence the need for an FCC filing). In addition, we’ve redesigned the base of the speaker to remove extra plastics and stickering as well as refreshing the packaging to the new more sustainable design introduced with Roam. These changes don’t deliver new features or functionality so it won’t be labeled and sold as a new product, but it will only be compatible with S2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="5vQMLi"&gt;The refreshed One SL is now available on Sonos’ websites and from third-party retailers, the company tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AmmPni"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update May 25th, 12PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Added confirmation that the updated speaker is available now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453033/sonos-one-sl-update-refresh-power-efficient-recyclable-radio-base"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453033/sonos-one-sl-update-refresh-power-efficient-recyclable-radio-base</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-25T11:48:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-25T11:48:52-04:00</updated>
    <title>Tidal now also offers offline listening on the Apple Watch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vzihcGwATCdsY0OUrDD7qarx8kQ=/255x0:2145x1260/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69339545/TIDAL_on_Apple_Watch_3.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Tidal&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="o5Ek5G"&gt;Music streaming service Tidal is now available &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Ftidal.com%2FAppleWatch&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F5%2F25%2F22453031%2Ftidal-apple-watch-offline-listening-spotify-deezer" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on the Apple Watch&lt;/a&gt;, allowing subscribers to stream music directly to Apple’s wearable or download it for offline listening. Instructions on how to get set up can be found on &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Ftidal.com%2FAppleWatch&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F5%2F25%2F22453031%2Ftidal-apple-watch-offline-listening-spotify-deezer" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Tidal’s site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447222/spotify-adding-feature-music-downloads-offline-apple-watch"&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/19/22443522/deezer-apple-watch-offline-listening"&gt;Deezer&lt;/a&gt; both announced similar offline listening features for the Apple Watch last week. Subscription prices for Tidal start at $9.99 a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KpKOR7"&gt;Tidal has historically sold itself on the quality of its audio streaming, offering features like lossless playback and even hi-res streaming before many of its bigger rivals. But this year, some of its biggest competitors are starting to catch up. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22295273/spotify-hifi-announced-lossless-streaming-hd-quality"&gt;Spotify’s lossless HiFi tier&lt;/a&gt; is set to launch later this year, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22440090/apple-music-lossless-audio-dolby-atmos-support-audio"&gt;Apple Music will introduce support&lt;/a&gt; for lossless and hi-res streaming next month. Tidal’s high audio quality won’t translate to its Apple Watch app however. The music service has confirmed audio will be limited to 96Kbps on the wearable, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447222/spotify-adding-feature-music-downloads-offline-apple-watch"&gt;like Spotify&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="f8uVMB"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Tidal is facing renewed competition from Spotify and Apple Music&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="n4wHzl"&gt;The service’s other major selling point is the amount it pays artists in royalties to stream their music. Analysis &lt;a href="https://www.digitalmusicnews.com/2018/12/25/streaming-music-services-pay-2019/"&gt;from &lt;em&gt;Digital Music News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; puts Tidal’s rates ahead of Spotify, Apple, and Deezer, and it looks like this artist-supporting trend is set to continue after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/4/22313108/square-inc-tidal-majority-stake-jack-dorsey-jay-z"&gt;Jack Dorsey’s financial services company Square recently acquired a majority stake&lt;/a&gt; in the streaming service for $297 million. Dorsey specifically cited wanting to find “new ways for artists to support their work” as the reason for the acquisition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YV11Ry"&gt;“Square created ecosystems of tools for sellers &amp;amp; individuals and we’ll do the same for artists,” the CEO &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jack/status/1367460914149003271"&gt;tweeted at the time&lt;/a&gt;, “We’ll work on entirely new listening experiences to bring fans closer together, simple integrations for merch sales, modern collaboration tools, and new complementary revenue streams.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ewwp6Q"&gt;Tidal’s Apple Watch support requires a Series 3 model or later running watchOS 7.1. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453031/tidal-apple-watch-offline-listening-spotify-deezer"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453031/tidal-apple-watch-offline-listening-spotify-deezer</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-25T11:43:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-25T11:43:20-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sling TV announces completely redesigned app, and it looks way nicer</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/c2fl8sQAly3jMLGV5BMcEh7wBcM=/63x0:737x449/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69339536/SlingApp2.0.gif" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DjxL6H"&gt;Compared to competitors like YouTube TV and Hulu, Sling TV has never had the flashiest app, and the overall user experience leaves something to be desired. It’s been easy enough to overlook these faults since Sling TV undercuts those rivals on price, but today the company &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.sling.com/pm/newapp" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;announced a completely redesigned app&lt;/a&gt; that focuses on more polish and personalized recommendations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IBcfV6"&gt;The new Sling TV app is rolling out first to “select customers” using Amazon’s Fire TV devices, and other platforms will be added as the year stretches on. (It’ll arrive on Roku sometime this summer, for example.) The Dish-owned company describes this as the “most comprehensive update in Sling TV’s history.” And based on screenshots and the GIF above, it does look like a significant makeover. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ss4kdg"&gt;“After a year of talking to customers and working with our design and advanced engineering teams, we’re happy to roll out the new Sling TV app to deliver the best in live sports, news and entertainment, at the same unbeatable low price point,” Michael Schwimmer, group president of Sling TV, said &lt;a href="https://news.sling.com/2021-05-25-SLING-TV-unveils-new-app-experience-delivering-live-sports,-news-and-entertainment#assets_all"&gt;in a press release&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AJAEf2"&gt;The redesign comes with a lot of changes, including a left-side navigation column and a new homescreen that focuses on content recommendations. The channel guide has been “reimagined” to make favoriting channels and filtering easier, though it will still feel familiar to customers who want that traditional cable-like grid. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DbNKqc_V-2_Z5fSi8yh6O6lB1Rk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22538521/Screen_Shot_2021_05_25_at_11.26.32_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Sling TV&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A dedicated DVR section provides easy access to your cloud recordings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="NFx8tH"&gt;Sling TV’s cloud DVR now gets its own tab, which should make it easier to sort through your recordings. By default, the service comes with 50 hours of DVR space, but you can expand this to 200 hours for an extra $5 per month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B0TLCv"&gt;“If a streaming app is done right, it should be practically invisible, allowing the user to get to the most relevant content quickly and easily — the new Sling TV experience does just that,” said Jon Lin, Sling TV’s VP of product. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22452993/sling-tv-new-app-features-design-amazon-fire-tv"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22452993/sling-tv-new-app-features-design-amazon-fire-tv</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-25T11:26:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-25T11:26:23-04:00</updated>
    <title>Pansonic teases a GH6 and focuses on streaming with the GH5 Mark II</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gB5mdIs0pKJNtKLYSWRcluejVLM=/0x134:2667x1912/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69339418/GH5M2_MKIT_slant_K_T4.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Panasonic&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iHxknI"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fRXhezdFxhM"&gt;Panasonic has announced&lt;/a&gt; not one but two follow-up cameras to the Lumix GH5, a camera that’s been popular with videographers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/1/4/14145730/panasonic-gh5-fz80-gx850-compact-cameras-ces-2017"&gt;since it launched in 2017&lt;/a&gt;. There’s the GH6, which Panasonic says features a brand-new sensor and will launch by the end of the year for $2,500, and the GH5 Mark II, which is &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1639337-REG%2Fpanasonic_dc_gh5m2body_lumix_gh5_ii_mirrorless.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F5%2F25%2F22451677%2Fpanasonic-gh6-gh5-mark-ii-2-live-streaming-video-camera" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;going up for preorder today&lt;/a&gt;, with a body-only package coming in at $1,700.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NdLR3A"&gt;The GH6 will feature a new image engine along with the sensor and will have the capability to record 10-bit 4K at 120fps and 10-bit 5.7K at 60fps. The camera also promises DCI 4K60 at 4:2:2 without a recording time limit. The GH6 is currently in development, so Panasonic didn’t provide many more details, but it did say that the camera would feature a Micro Four Thirds sensor. The impressive video capabilities might sound familiar, as they’re very similar to the full-frame &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21341095/sony-a7s-mark-iii-camera-video-price-specs-features"&gt;Sony A7S III&lt;/a&gt; (which also has a much heftier price tag). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lsUbaW"&gt;While the details on the GH6 were light, we got a very good look at the GH5 Mark II. It’s, as the name implies, an improved version of the GH5, and Panasonic’s idea for it seems to be that it’s built to serve people who aren’t looking to spend $2,500 on a GH6 but want something more capable than a G7 or older GH4. When the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/1/4/14145730/panasonic-gh5-fz80-gx850-compact-cameras-ces-2017"&gt;GH5 originally launched&lt;/a&gt; it was $2,000, so it seems like Panasonic is trying to split the difference with the Mark II and GH6, offering cameras on both sides.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2QzfDIuaAaLeQndE04Lai3Clqw0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22537072/GH5M2_MKIT_top_K_T4.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Panasonic&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s also a kit that comes with a 12-60mm f/2.8-4 image-stabilized lens for $2,300.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="qegNcN"&gt;The GH5 Mark II has the same body as the GH5 (making it compatible with any previous accessories or cages), but it packs internals that make it an even more powerful video camera. While the original did support &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2016/9/19/12971066/panasonics-lumix-gh5-4k-60p-video-6k-photos-mirrorless-camera"&gt;4K recording at 60 frames a second&lt;/a&gt;, it was only 8-bit — the Mark II supports it at 10-bit 4:2:0, which can simultaneously be recorded internally and externally (with some HDMI recorders supporting 4:2:2). The cinema 4K mode, which provides a wider-than-16:9 aspect ratio, also now supports 30p and 25p, where the GH5 only supported 24p. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ntoUea"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The GH5’s famous in-body stabilization is also getting a bump in performance&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RLakWz"&gt;The color profiles have also gotten a revamp in the Mark II, with the camera including Cinelike D2 and V2 profiles. It also now includes the V-Log L profile for free, which was previously &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fshop.panasonic.com%2Fcameras-and-camcorders%2Fcamera-and-camcorder-accessories%2Fcamera-accessories%2FDMW-SFU1-VLOG.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F5%2F25%2F22451677%2Fpanasonic-gh6-gh5-mark-ii-2-live-streaming-video-camera" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a $100 upgrade to the GH5&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to the improved color, the sensor (which is the same as the one found in the GH5) has also gotten an anti-reflective coating to avoid unwanted lens flares, and Panasonic claims it has 25 percent wider dynamic range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KFVnRX"&gt;The GH5 Mark II’s in-body stabilization is getting a bump in performance, too: the original could provide five stops of compensation, according to Panasonic, while the Mark II will be able to compensate up to 6.5 stops (though for longer lenses, achieving this number will require the lens to also have optical stabilization). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KIw2kM"&gt;Panasonic is also saying that the autofocus system will be improved — a good sign, given the GH5’s &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.premiumbeat.com%2Fblog%2Fsolutions-for-gh5-autofocus%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F5%2F25%2F22451677%2Fpanasonic-gh6-gh5-mark-ii-2-live-streaming-video-camera" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;lackluster performance in the area&lt;/a&gt;. The GH5 Mark II will feature head and body detection, as well as support for tracking animals, in addition to the eye and face detection found on the previous camera. The tracking will also be twice as fast, with the system looking for objects 60 times a second, while the GH5 tracks at 30 times a second. Panasonic also says that the system should lock on to subjects better and will have better support for tracking people who are farther in the distance. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SYWOs5ESDi0Eeb3pw44ZPow_tfE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22537069/GH5M2_body_back_K_T4.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Panasonic&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Panasonic says the screen is 1.5 times brighter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="l5ATkJ"&gt;The Mark II also has some creature comfort improvements and really nerdy additions. The rear LCD is both higher-resolution and brighter, and the USB-C port is now compatible with the Power Delivery standard so it can run the camera and trickle-charge the batteries at the same time. It also takes higher-capacity batteries, though the older batteries the GH5 used will still work in the camera, and vice versa. There’s also now the option to add a red border around the screen when recording, and the ability to have two levels of zebra patterns to help determine exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OBhHBL"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Panasonic knows its audience is mostly made up of video people&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="m6OaOW"&gt;When shooting with supported lenses, creators will now be able to change the focus ring mode, setting it to be linear if that’s what they prefer, and even setting a specific focus throw if their use case calls for it. Panasonic has also updated its in-camera anamorphic de-squeezing feature (which allows people shooting with the special lenses to get a non-distorted preview of their picture) to include more lenses: the GH5 supported lenses with 1.33x and 2x aspect ratios, while the Mark II also supports lenses at 1.3x, 1.5x, and 1.8x. There’s also now support for image stabilization with anamorphic lenses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nxhXLt"&gt;The GH5 Mark II can, of course, also shoot pictures, but it seems like Panasonic knows its audience is mostly made up of video people: new photo features were largely absent, apart from a brief mention of improved color science and some new profiles. But while Panasonic doesn’t seem to be putting in a lot of work to entice photo shooters to its platform, it does seem to be trying to make the GH5 Mark II appealing to a different breed of video creators: the livestreamers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vNaeVB"&gt;The GH5 Mark II’s presentation for journalists focused heavily on its livestreaming capabilities: it can stream to platforms like YouTube, Facebook, and Twitch directly over Wi-Fi, with compression being done on-camera. The streaming compression can be done at various levels and resolutions, depending on the requirements of the platform. Streamers can either input their streaming URLs and keys manually, for platforms like Twitch that support RTMP (or RTMPS), or they can directly sign on to Facebook or YouTube if they’re using the Lumix Sync smartphone app to set up the stream. Panasonic says that the ability to hardwire to a phone or even directly to a LAN via USB will be coming in a future firmware update. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hoy2Yv"&gt;I was shown a live demo of the streaming, which was conducted over YouTube, and to my eye it looked about as good as a stream can be expected to. Panasonic also said that the XLR microphone adapter built for the camera would work while streaming, and that an HDMI recorder could be used to capture a full-quality recording of any stream (though internally recording stream footage isn’t possible). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="qmnGyN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s hard to find a direct competitor to the GH5 Mark II&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6NNnFC"&gt;It’s hard to find a direct competitor to the GH5 Mark II, especially in its price range: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/26/21151718/fujifilm-xt4-announced-specs-pricing-ibis-stabilization-vlogging"&gt;Fujifilm’s X-T4&lt;/a&gt; is no slouch when it comes to video, but it doesn't have the heaps of options the Panasonic does (for example, you probably won’t get a custom menu for your most-used frame rates and resolutions, or filters to help pare down that information in the main menu like the GH5 Mark II has). The story is similar &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21497207/sony-a7c-review-camera-price-specs-features"&gt;with Sony’s A7C&lt;/a&gt;, and the A7S III has similar specs but costs almost twice the price. And while &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2018/4/9/17217394/blackmagic-pocket-cinema-camera-4k-announced"&gt;BlackMagic’s Pocket Cinema Camera 4K&lt;/a&gt; has comparable video power as well as RAW video support, there are some places it falls way short when compared to the GH5 Mark II: the lack of a flip-out screen and autofocus spring to mind. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mXmj8C"&gt;Panasonic has also announced that its &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/PANASONIC-Mirrorless-Megapixels-High-Resolution-DC-G9KBODY/dp/B0774KTV1X?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;G9&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mirrorless-Sensitivity-Multi-Aspect-Megapixels-DC-GH5S/dp/B078J119BC?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GH5S&lt;/a&gt; cameras would also be getting firmware updates, bringing some of the new features from the GH5 Mark II. Both cameras will be getting the autofocus performance improvements, along with the frame indicators and markers, as well as support for vertical video detection. The GH5S will additionally be getting 12-bit raw over HDMI support when outputting to an &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Atomos-Daylight-Viewable-Portable-ATOMNJAV01/dp/B07C2QQGM3?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Atomos Ninja V&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4IhEhJ"&gt;Panasonic also announced that it was working on a new lens, the Leica DG 25-50mm f/1.7. The aperture is constant throughout the 50-100mm full-frame equivalent focal range, and while there weren’t any additional details announced, Panasonic has emphasized it as a companion to the existing &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1480838-REG%2Fpanasonic_h_x1025_panasonic_lumix_g_10_25mm.html%2Freviews&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F5%2F25%2F22451677%2Fpanasonic-gh6-gh5-mark-ii-2-live-streaming-video-camera" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;10-25mm f/1.7&lt;/a&gt;. That lens features dust and moisture resistance and produces &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=t2fDOOgzxcY"&gt;some lovely images&lt;/a&gt;, so it’s exciting to hear that the more tele-oriented version in the works will likely be similar in terms of build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3BWZW6"&gt;Panasonic is still, for better and worse, dedicated to Micro Four Thirds. In its presentation to journalists, it said that the format was necessary to get all the features and readout speeds it wanted at the price point it was looking to hit. It’s obviously invested a lot into these cameras, with the addition of livestreaming and the upcoming GH6’s monster specs, but the limitations of the format are something aspiring cinematographers will have to keep in mind when choosing their next video camera.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22451677/panasonic-gh6-gh5-mark-ii-2-live-streaming-video-camera"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22451677/panasonic-gh6-gh5-mark-ii-2-live-streaming-video-camera</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-25T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-25T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft has built an AI-powered autocomplete for code using GPT-3</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/l5IAAG1NfIUw9AMjc_Srg_IaitU=/0x12:503x347/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69339291/microsoft_gpt3_powerapps_code.0.gif" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="B5jsjU"&gt;In September 2020, Microsoft purchased an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/22/21451283/microsoft-openai-gpt-3-exclusive-license-ai-language-research"&gt;exclusive license&lt;/a&gt; to the underlying technology behind GPT-3, an AI language tool built by OpenAI. Now, the Redmond, Washington-based tech giant has announced its first commercial use case for the program: an assistive feature in the company’s PowerApps software that turns natural language into readymade code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gICEYz"&gt;The feature is limited in its scope and can only produce formulas in &lt;a href="https://powerapps.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/introducing-microsoft-power-fx-the-low-code-programming-language-for-everyone/"&gt;Microsoft Power Fx&lt;/a&gt;, a simple programming language derived from Microsoft Excel formulas that’s used mainly for database queries. But it shows the huge potential for machine learning to help novice programmers by functioning as an autocomplete tool for code. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="om6Q70"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Why don’t we ... speak the language of a normal human?”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fQGv5x"&gt;“There’s massive demand for digital solutions but not enough coders out there. There’s a million-developer shortfall in the US alone,” Charles Lamanna, CVP of Microsoft’s Low Code Application Platform, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “So instead of making the world learn how to code, why don’t we make development environments speak the language of a normal human?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="33mvCV"&gt;Autocomplete for coders&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="rVoF8A"&gt;Microsoft has been pursuing this vision for a while through Power Platform, its suite of “low code, no code” software aimed at enterprise customers. These programs run as web apps and help companies that can’t hire experienced programmers tackle basic digital tasks like analytics, data visualization, and workflow automation. GPT-3’s talents have found a home in PowerApps, a program in the suite used to create simple web and mobile apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EVgYag"&gt;Lamanna demonstrates the software by opening up an example app built by Coca-Cola to keep track of its supplies of cola concentrate. Elements in the app like buttons can be dragged and dropped around the app as if the users were arranging a PowerPoint presentation. But creating the menus that let users run specific database queries (like, say, searching for all supplies that were delivered to a specific location at a specific time) requires basic coding in the form of Microsoft Power Fx formulas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gBkR0q"&gt;“This is when it goes from no code to low code,” says Lamanna. “You go from drag and drop, click click click, to writing formulas. And that quickly becomes complex.” Which makes it the right time to call for an assist from machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qu6ZYr"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Microsoft GPT-3 PowerApps demo|102277" data-volume-uuid="911690cf4" data-volume-id="102277" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-171" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PeIUvy"&gt;Instead of having users learn how to make database queries in Power Fx, Microsoft is updating PowerApps so they can simply write out their query in natural language, which GPT-3 then translates into usable code. So for example, instead of a user searching the database with a query “FirstN(Sort(Search(‘BC Orders’, “Super_Fizzy”, “aib_productname”), ‘Purchase Date’, Descending), 10),” they can just write “Show 10 orders that have Super Fizzy in the product name and sort by purchase date with newest on the top,” and GPT-3 will produce the correct the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2BMxB8"&gt;It’s a simple trick, but it has the potential to save time for millions of users, while also enabling non-coders to build products previously out of their reach. “I remember when we got the first prototype working on a Friday night, I used it, and I was like ‘oh my god, this is creepy good,’” says Lamanna. “I haven’t felt this way using technology for a long, long time.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sTK6gT"&gt;The feature will be available in preview in June, but Microsoft is not the first to use machine learning in this way. A number of AI-assisted coding programs have appeared in recent years, including some, like Deep TabNine, that are also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/24/20708542/coding-autocompleter-deep-tabnine-ai-deep-learning-smart-compose"&gt;powered by the GPT series&lt;/a&gt;. These programs show promise but are not yet widely used, mostly due to issues of reliability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t46xHs"&gt;Programming languages are notoriously fickle, with tiny errors capable of crashing entire systems. And the output of AI language models is often haphazard, mixing up words and phrases and contradicting itself from sentence to sentence. The result is that it often requires coding experience to check the output of AI coding autocomplete programs. That, of course, undermines their appeal for novices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="LMbVAP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The simplicity of Power Fx is its greatest strength in this scenario&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="EPmdiW"&gt;But Microsoft’s implementation has one big advantage over other systems: Power Fx is extremely simple. The language has its roots in Microsoft Excel formula, explains Lamanna, and is very constrained in what it can do. “It’s data-binding, single-line expressions; there’s no concept of build and compile. What you write just computes instantly,” he says. It has nothing like the power or flexibility of a programming language like Python or JavaScript, but that also means it doesn’t have as much room to commit AI-assisted errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uX3r7w"&gt;As an additional safeguard, the Power Apps interface will also require that users confirm all Power Fx formulas generated from their input. Lamanna argues that this will not only reduce mistakes, but even teach users how to code over time. This seems like an optimistic read. What’s equally likely is that people will unthinkingly confirm the first option they’re given by the computer, as we tend to do with so many pop-up nuisances, from cookies to Ts&amp;amp;Cs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="RP8yjy"&gt;Mitigating bias&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="F1LDgy"&gt;The feature accelerates Microsoft’s “low code, no code” ambitions, but it’s also noteworthy as a major commercial application of GPT-3, one of a new breed of AI language models that dominate the contemporary AI landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5CpsE1"&gt;These systems are extremely powerful, able to generate virtually &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21346343/gpt-3-explainer-openai-examples-errors-agi-potential"&gt;any sort of text&lt;/a&gt; you can imagine and manipulate language in a variety of ways, and many big tech firms have begun exploring their possibilities. Google has incorporated its own language AI model, BERT, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/25/20931657/google-bert-search-context-algorithm-change-10-percent-langauge"&gt;into its search products&lt;/a&gt;, while Facebook uses similar systems for &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2020/10/first-multilingual-machine-translation-model"&gt;tasks like translation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="AfZSob"&gt;&lt;q&gt;One medical chatbot built on GPT-3 told a mock patient to kill themself&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DEN7mr"&gt;But these models also have their problems. The core of their capacity often comes from studying language patterns found in huge vats of text data scraped from the web. As with Microsoft’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/3/24/11297050/tay-microsoft-chatbot-racist"&gt;chatbot Tay&lt;/a&gt;, which learned to repeat the insulting and abusive remarks of Twitter users, that means these models have the ability &lt;a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3442188.3445922"&gt;to encode and reproduce&lt;/a&gt; all manner of sexist and racist language. The text they produce can also be toxic in unexpected ways. One experimental chatbot built on GPT-3 that was designed to dole out medical advice &lt;a href="https://www.theregister.com/2020/10/28/gpt3_medical_chatbot_experiment/"&gt;consoled a mock patient by telling them to kill themself&lt;/a&gt;, for example. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Gd5aG"&gt;The challenge of mitigating these risks depends on the exact function of the AI. In Microsoft’s case, using GPT-3 to create code means the danger is low, says Lamanna, but not nonexistent. The company has fine-tuned GPT-3 to “translate” into code by training it on examples of Power Fx formula, but the core of the program is still based on language patterns learned from the web, meaning it retains this potential for toxicity and bias. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SSRI23"&gt;Lamanna gives the example of a user asking the program to find “all job applicants that are &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt;.” How will it interpret that command? It’s within GPT-3’s power to invent criteria in order to answer the question, and it’s possible it might assume that “good” is synonymous with white-sounding names, given that this is one of a number of categories favored by &lt;a href="https://www.nber.org/digest/sep03/employers-replies-racial-names"&gt;biased hiring practices&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C3IgE9"&gt;Microsoft says it’s addressing this issue in a number of ways. The first is implementing a ban list of words and phrases that the system just won’t respond to. “If you’re poking the AI to generate something bad, we’re not going to generate it for you,” says Lamanna. And if the system produces something it &lt;em&gt;thinks&lt;/em&gt; might be problematic, it’ll prompt users to report it to tech support. Then, someone will come and register the problem (and hopefully fix it). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GOJx6x"&gt;But making the program safe without limiting its functionality is difficult, says Lamanna. Filtering by race, religion, or gender can be discriminatory, but it can also have legitimate applications, and it sounds like Microsoft is still working out how to tell the difference. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="tlKpC2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Like any filter, it’s not perfect.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OQdRla"&gt;“Like any filter, it’s not perfect,” says Lamanna, emphasizing that users will have to confirm any formula written by the AI, and implying that any abuses of the program will ultimately be their responsibility. “The human does choose to inject the expression. We never inject the expression automatically,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="STkoqf"&gt;Despite these and other unanswered questions about the program’s utility, it’s clear that this is the start of a much bigger experiment for Microsoft. It’s not hard to imagine a similar feature being integrated into Microsoft Excel, where it would reach hundreds of millions of users and dramatically expand the accessibility of this product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0oeveP"&gt;When asked about this possibility, Lamanna demures (it’s not his domain), but he does say that the plan is to make GPT-3-assisted coding available wherever Power Fx itself can be accessed. “And Power Fx is showing up in lots of different places in Microsoft products,” he says. So expect to see AI completing your code much more frequently in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22451144/microsoft-gpt-3-openai-coding-autocomplete-powerapps-power-fx"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22451144/microsoft-gpt-3-openai-coding-autocomplete-powerapps-power-fx</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
