<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-08-24T06:23:09-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-24T06:23:09-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-24T06:23:09-04:00</updated>
    <title>Check your permissions: default settings in Microsoft tool exposes 38 million user records online</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Aa0vMFJ1mwm_2P_lJ48h6T_zgQ4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69767509/acastro_190204_1777_privacy_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="PUl8OJ"&gt;Default permissions settings in an app-building tool from Microsoft &lt;a href="https://www.upguard.com/breaches/power-apps"&gt;have been blamed&lt;/a&gt; for exposing the data of 38 million people online. Information including names, email addresses, phone numbers, social security numbers, and COVID-19 vaccination appointments was inadvertently made publicly accessible by 47 different companies and government entities using Microsoft’s Power Apps platform. There’s no evidence of the data being exploited, though, and the underlying issue has now been fixed by Microsoft. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CCZGow"&gt;The problem was originally discovered in May by security research team UpGuard. In a recent &lt;a href="https://www.upguard.com/breaches/power-apps"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; from UpGuard and &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/microsoft-power-apps-data-exposed/"&gt;report from &lt;em&gt;Wired&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the company explains how organizations using Power Apps created apps with improper data permissions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WFy8Gt"&gt;“We found one of these [apps] that was misconfigured to expose data and we thought, we’ve never heard of this, is this a one-off thing or is this a systemic issue?” UpGuard’s vice president of cyber research Greg Pollock told &lt;em&gt;Wired&lt;/em&gt;. “Because of the way the Power Apps portals product works, it’s very easy to quickly do a survey. And we discovered there are tons of these exposed. It was wild.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="FwHn8G"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“we discovered there are tons of these exposed. It was wild.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YMedsv"&gt;Power Apps allows companies to build simple apps and websites without formal coding experience. Organizations implicated in the breach — including Ford, American Airlines, J.B. Hunt, and state agencies in Maryland, New York City, and Indiana — were using the site to collect data for various purposes, including organizing vaccination efforts. Power Apps offers tools for quickly collating the sort of data needed in these projects, but, by default, leaves this information publicly accessible. This is the exposure UpGuard discovered. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m79riC"&gt;The mechanism of this particular ‘breach’ is interesting, as it blurs the line between what is a software vulnerability and what is merely poor choice in user interface design. UpGuard says Microsoft’s position is that this was not a vulnerability as it was users’ fault for not properly configuring the apps’ permissions. But, arguably, if you are making an app designed to be used by people with little coding experience, then making things as safe as possible by default would seem to be the smart move. As &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/microsoft-power-apps-data-exposed/"&gt;reported by &lt;em&gt;Wired&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Microsoft has now changed the &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/powerapps/maker/portals/important-changes-deprecations#table-permission-changes-for-forms-and-lists-on-new-portals"&gt;default permissions settings&lt;/a&gt; responsible for the exposure.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/24/22639106/microsoft-power-apps-default-permissions-settings-user-records-exposed-38-million-upgard"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/24/22639106/microsoft-power-apps-default-permissions-settings-user-records-exposed-38-million-upgard</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-24T05:21:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-24T05:21:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>TikTok follows Snap and Facebook by testing new augmented reality developer tools</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Tessellated TikTok logos against a dark background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LUC0q5dUTG9yDtcyQGGR1bzxOqM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69767399/acastro_190723_1777_tiktok_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IY55bH"&gt;TikTok is testing an experimental set of developer tools that might one day let creators build augmented reality effects for the popular app. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RzInwX"&gt;The platform is called TikTok Effect Studio and is currently in private beta, according to a &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/08/23/tiktok-is-building-its-own-ar-development-platform-tiktok-effect-studio/?tpcc=ECTW2020"&gt;report from &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. TikTok told the publication that Effect Studio is simply an “experiment” at this stage and may not make it to a full launch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pS2cgv"&gt;It would, though, be a sensible product for TikTok to build. Both &lt;a href="https://ar.snap.com/"&gt;Snap&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://developers.facebook.com/blog/post/2018/05/01/ar-studio-create-distribute/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; have their own AR developer initiatives, which encourage people to build new camera effects for their respective platforms. It seems like a streamlined way to keep your audience engaged, outsourcing the development of new effects to users who know best what they want to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="amLcq2"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;TikTok is launching an Effects Studio in beta &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;h/t &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sam_Schmir?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Sam_Schmir&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/K3LS5S2Yoq"&gt;pic.twitter.com/K3LS5S2Yoq&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Matt Navarra (@MattNavarra) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MattNavarra/status/1426639697829322762?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 14, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QeL2aC"&gt;The Effects Studio was first spotted by social media consultant &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MattNavarra/status/1426639697829322762"&gt;Matt Navarra&lt;/a&gt; (with a tip from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sam_Schmir"&gt;Sam Schmir&lt;/a&gt;). You can view the sign-up page &lt;a href="https://effecthouse.tiktok.com/"&gt;here on the web&lt;/a&gt; (where it’s confusingly named TikTok Effect &lt;em&gt;House&lt;/em&gt;), but it doesn’t give anything away about what tools may actually be available in future. It will ask for your name, email, TikTok username, years of experience developing AR tools, and whether you plan to create effects for personal or business use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tIEoEP"&gt;The site apparently launched earlier this month, but seems it’s still very much in the early stages of development. Speaking to &lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt;, a TikTok spokesperson gave an impressively bland and vague statement. “We’re always thinking about new ways to bring value to our community and enrich the TikTok experience,” said the spokesperson. “Currently, we’re experimenting with ways to give creators additional tools to bring their creative ideas to life for the TikTok community.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PZeMcp"&gt;Watch this space, basically.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/24/22639081/tiktok-effects-house-studio-private-beta-launch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/24/22639081/tiktok-effects-house-studio-private-beta-launch</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-24T04:59:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-24T04:59:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>Xiaomi moves away from its ‘Mi’ product branding</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-h5HloF3s93W4qA5aaP7l2tgOTE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69767365/DSCF5652.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A Mi Home store in Beijing. | Photo by Sam Byford / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="c1gMiZ"&gt;Xiaomi is phasing out its “Mi” product branding, a spokesperson tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge.&lt;/em&gt; Products including flagship smartphones like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22310843/xiaomi-mi-11-review-samsung"&gt;this year’s Mi 11&lt;/a&gt; will instead simply carry the Xiaomi name. The news was first reported &lt;a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/xiaomi-ditches-mi-branding/"&gt;by &lt;em&gt;XDA Developers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XH8Z8C"&gt;“Starting in 2021 Q3, Xiaomi’s product series ‘Mi’ will be renamed to ‘Xiaomi,’” says the spokesperson. “This change will unify our global brand presence and close the perception gap between the brand and its products. This change may take some time to take effect in all regions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="35KsqH"&gt;Xiaomi says that it’ll still keep the Redmi brand around, meaning that the higher-end Xiaomi products will form a distinct line alongside Redmi products. Xiaomi products “represent the pinnacle of technology and offer a premium experience,” according to the company, while Redmi products “bring big innovation at a more accessible price point and are aimed at a younger audience.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pRTAA1pDRtWYVHJNG5B6nOYjEtM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22802188/WechatIMG118.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="7Bog7E"&gt;This naming convention “will also be applied to our ecosystem and IoT products over time,” says the spokesperson, though the Mi brand logo will continue to be used in Xiaomi’s Mi Home stores for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RlkLvs"&gt;This month’s announcement of the latest phone in the Mi Mix series served as a harbinger of the shift, since Xiaomi referred to it as the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22617979/xiaomi-mi-mix-4-announced-under-display-camera-cup-specs-price"&gt;Xiaomi Mix 4&lt;/a&gt;. The previous phones were called the Mi Mix, the Mi Mix 2, and the Mi Mix 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mzmv7b"&gt;The Mi brand was largely used in Western markets, presumably for readability and pronunciation reasons — phones like the Mi 11 are already called the Xiaomi 11 in China, for example. But Xiaomi evidently believes its company name is now recognizable enough and better represents its products.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/24/22639020/xiaomi-mi-brand-ending-mix-4-confirmed"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/24/22639020/xiaomi-mi-brand-ending-mix-4-confirmed</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-24T04:53:09-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-24T04:53:09-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google dismantles Health unit in favor of tried-and-tested ‘throw everything at the wall’ strategy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NdBXyvY-NMM-kmFIQqVaeoWZ-yU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69767359/acastro_210121_1777_google_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9MjWah"&gt;Once again, Google is headed back to the drawing board to rethink its healthcare strategy. &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/google-health-shutting-down-david-feinberg-leaves-2021-8"&gt;As first reported by &lt;em&gt;Business Insider&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the tech giant is dissolving its single, unified Google Health division, founded in 2018, in favor of a distributed approach to building health products. The head of the division, David Feinberg, is &lt;a href="https://www.cerner.com/newsroom/cerner-announces-appointment-of-david-feinberg-md-as-president-and-chief-executive-officer"&gt;leaving the company&lt;/a&gt;, while an unknown proportion of Google Health employees will be sent to other teams at Google (like Search and Fitbit) to work on specific services, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JeffDean/status/1429899635791843328"&gt;according to Google’s AI head Jeff Dean&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QJlIUe"&gt;It’s a messy change for what was already a messy initiative. Tech giants like Google and Apple have become increasingly interested in the healthcare industry in recent years, but have failed to make in-roads in such a fractured ecosystem. Google’s efforts in health have at least been fittingly disparate, covering everything from Android &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/fit/"&gt;fitness apps&lt;/a&gt;, to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/13/17670156/deepmind-ai-eye-disease-doctor-moorfields"&gt;AI-powered eye-disease detectors&lt;/a&gt;, to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/16/14932764/deepmind-google-uk-nhs-health-data-analysis"&gt;bungled data deals&lt;/a&gt;, to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22165465/google-health-research-app-covid-flu-apple"&gt;medical study apps&lt;/a&gt;, to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22331567/google-nest-hub-new-2021-smart-display-sleep-tracking-soli-price-specs-features"&gt;sleep-tracking features&lt;/a&gt; in the Nest Hub, to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/18/22440754/google-health-ai-skin-condition-model-dermatology"&gt;machine learning tools&lt;/a&gt; for clinicians. And &lt;em&gt;so on&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="MpuTjx"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GoogleHealth?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@GoogleHealth&lt;/a&gt; is no longer just a single team, but a significant company-wide effort that touches many of our products. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Moving forward the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GoogleHealth?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@GoogleHealth&lt;/a&gt; name will encompass all our health initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;— Jeff Dean (@ ) (@JeffDean) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JeffDean/status/1429899911978373126?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 23, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hVlqQV"&gt;Google Health was supposed to unify these efforts, giving some sense of purpose and direction to the company’s sprawling ambitions. The brand dates back to 2006, but Google seemed to be embarking on a more serious path in 2018 when it hired &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/9/18079420/google-health-care-strategy-fit-home-nest-deepmind-verily-ceo-geisinger"&gt;respected healthcare exec Feinberg&lt;/a&gt;. As this recent news suggests, that hasn’t worked out, though the Google Health brand will live on. As &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JeffDean/status/1429899911978373126"&gt;tweeted by Dean&lt;/a&gt;: “@GoogleHealth is no longer just a single team, but a significant company-wide effort that touches many of our products. Moving forward the @GoogleHealth name will encompass all our health initiatives.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M9ZEME"&gt;What does that mean for you, the avid Google Health consumer? Diddly squat, really. If you enjoy using any of the company’s current health products — whether that’s wearing a Fitbit or Googling “why am I tired all the time” at 3AM in the morning — then these core experiences will likely continue exactly as before. Whether or not Google can offer anything more meaningful from its healthcare strategy, though, remains to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/24/22639075/google-health-team-dispersed-strategy-change"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/24/22639075/google-health-team-dispersed-strategy-change</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-24T03:46:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-24T03:46:16-04:00</updated>
    <title>Google Meet now warns you when you're causing an echo</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b4srPD4I3Fn22sxVX2VY8AbYRU4=/38x0:640x401/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69767289/Screenshot_2021_06_15_9.37.42_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google Meet now warns you with a red dot and alert message if it thinks you have an echo.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="a4jmRQ"&gt;Google Meet will soon tell you when it thinks you’re creating an echo in calls, &lt;a href="https://workspaceupdates.googleblog.com/2021/08/helping-users-prevent-echo-in-google.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+GoogleAppsUpdates+%28Google+Workspace+Updates+Blog%29"&gt;Google announced in a blog posting Monday&lt;/a&gt;. Right now, it’s hard to know if you’re creating an irritating echo for meeting participants unless they interrupt the meeting to tell you. Google’s new proactive warnings should therefore help minimize everyone’s suffering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pUVeND"&gt;Google says that Meet already controls audio to remove echo. But it can’t account for all remote desktop speaker and mic configurations that result in audio being fed back into the call. The new echo warning appears as both a red dot on the Meet interface as well as a notification and a text alert. Clicking the notification provides steps to fix the echo, which include muting your mic, lowering your speaker volume, or switching to headphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SSy6E9"&gt;Google says that the new echo warnings are rolling out now to Google Workspace and G Suite Basic and Business customers. The rollout will take up to 15 days to complete. The warnings are on by default and don’t require any admin intervention to enable. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/24/22638696/google-meet-echo-warning-text-alert"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/24/22638696/google-meet-echo-warning-text-alert</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
      <name>Thomas Ricker</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-24T03:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-24T03:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>EA is opening the patents for some of its accessibility tech</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Screenshot of Apex Legends, showing a dessert landscape and a hand holding a knife, with text in the upper right corner that says “you pinged shield battery.”" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pirQy0r_WzxfAEQ88WgRFV6sKss=/96x0:1607x1007/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69767263/Shield_Battery_Ping.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A player uses the Ping System in &lt;/em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;em&gt; to alert their team of the presence of a “Shield Battery”.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Electronic Arts&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SbuZYk"&gt;Electronic Arts is pledging to open the patents for some of its accessibility-related tech, including the much-celebrated &lt;em&gt;Apex Legends&lt;/em&gt; ping system, the company announced today. EA says it won’t file infringement lawsuits against people or companies for using tech that falls under patents listed in the pledge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GYcajp"&gt;The ping system in Apex Legends, which allows people to play the team-based game without hearing or speaking, has been praised both as an impressive &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/6/18213537/apex-legend-voice-chat-solo-play-xbox-ps4-pc"&gt;alternative to voice chat&lt;/a&gt; and as a great &lt;a href="https://www.cbr.com/apex-legends-ping-system-is-still-its-best-feature-and-its-most-accessible/"&gt;accessibility feature&lt;/a&gt; for players with a variety of disabilities. A patent that covers the system (&lt;a href="https://pdfpiw.uspto.gov/.piw?PageNum=0&amp;amp;docid=11097189"&gt;US 11,097,189&lt;/a&gt;) was issued the same day as EA’s announcement of the pledge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iesF0h"&gt;Along with the ping system patent, EA is opening patents for the tech it uses in &lt;em&gt;Madden&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;FIFA&lt;/em&gt; to make them more accessible for people with colorblindness and low vision. The tech includes automated systems for improving visibility by detecting and modifying colors (&lt;a href="https://pdfpiw.uspto.gov/.piw?PageNum=0&amp;amp;docid=10118097"&gt;US 10,118,097&lt;/a&gt;) and contrast ratios (&lt;a href="https://pdfpiw.uspto.gov/.piw?PageNum=0&amp;amp;docid=10878540"&gt;US 10,878,540&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Screenshot from Madden 21, showing different options of plays, with color contrast adjusted for color blindness." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Czz5ZQ8J2PsH6I-EFtctXo8OMbk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22801446/Ex._1___Deuteranopia_On__as_seen_with_deuteranopia_.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Electronic Arts&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Tampa Bay play calling screen in &lt;/em&gt;Madden NFL 21&lt;em&gt; with color blindness settings set to deuteranopia, simulated as seen by someone with red-green color blindness. &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="HGymNb"&gt;The pledge also includes a patent for a “personalized sound technology” (&lt;a href="https://pdfpiw.uspto.gov/.piw?PageNum=0&amp;amp;docid=10878540"&gt;US 10,878,540&lt;/a&gt;) that will modify or create music for people based on their listening preferences and level of hearing, though EA says this tech hasn’t been developed yet.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r1Y5cu"&gt;In addition to opening some of its patents, EA is open-sourcing code that helps address issues with brightness, contrast, and colorblindness in digital content. Developers can find the code &lt;a href="https://github.com/electronicarts"&gt;on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and adapt or build on it for their own games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aQeNK5"&gt;“We hope developers will make the most of these patents and encourage those who have the resources, innovation and creativity to do as we have by making their own pledges that put accessibility first,” says Chris Bruzzo, EVP of Positive Play, Commercial and Marketing at EA. “We welcome collaboration with others on how we move the industry forward together.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dRdQVg"&gt;EA says it plans to add patents for future accessibility-related tech to the pledge, as well as open-sourcing more of its tech. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/24/22638535/ea-accessibility-patent-pledge-apex-legends-ping-system"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/24/22638535/ea-accessibility-patent-pledge-apex-legends-ping-system</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kait Sanchez</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-23T22:23:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-23T22:23:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>Watch the first trailer for Spider-Man: No Way Home</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/A50RyE9AHqutRolA_sbnFnuQsoE=/0x0:1500x1000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69766839/nwh.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="w9tptL"&gt;After it &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-news/sony-block-alleged-spider-man-no-way-home-trailer-leak-1235001375/"&gt;leaked&lt;/a&gt; over the weekend, Sony Pictures has released the first official teaser trailer for the upcoming &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: No Way Home&lt;/em&gt;, the third Spider-Man movie to be part of the Marvel Cinematic Universe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l8fP5e"&gt;I will just say up front that if you consider the basic premise of &lt;em&gt;No Way Home&lt;/em&gt; to be a spoiler, you probably shouldn’t watch this trailer. There are already reveals in it that big Spider-Man and Marvel fans might want to save for the theater, though I’m not sure how practical that’ll be in the lead-up to release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ZMr0sq"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;shout-out to the real ones who are watching the trailer for the first time right now&lt;/p&gt;— Spider-Man: No Way Home (@SpiderManMovie) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SpiderManMovie/status/1429982989228810249?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 24, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yoq9p1"&gt;Suffice it to say for now that &lt;em&gt;No Way Home&lt;/em&gt; follows on directly from the mid-credits scene in the last movie, &lt;em&gt;Far From Home&lt;/em&gt;, which was released in 2019. Peter Parker is dealing with the fallout of being exposed as Spider-Man and, well, there is just a whole lot going on with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qTXezy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: No Way Home&lt;/em&gt; is set to be released on December 17th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22638877/spider-man-no-way-home-first-trailer"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22638877/spider-man-no-way-home-first-trailer</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-23T20:11:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-23T20:11:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>Joe Biden reportedly hosting cybersecurity meeting with Tim Cook, Satya Nadella, and Andy Jassy attending</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Key Speakers At 2019 Dreamforce Conference" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q_ns6qHpSM2ZQEkHxNJqcg898cE=/0x0:4000x2667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69766544/1183490754.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="p03RW0"&gt;President Joe Biden plans to host a meeting on Wednesday to discuss how companies are improving cybersecurity after the waves of recent security breaches and ransomware attacks, and Apple CEO Tim Cook, Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella, and Amazon CEO Andy Jassy will be attending, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-08-23/apple-s-cook-microsoft-s-nadella-plan-to-visit-white-house?sref=9hGJlFio"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Google, IBM, JPMorgan Chase, and the energy firm Southern Company have also been invited, and Southern Company CEO Tom Fanning is also set to attend, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xYxElX"&gt;While it’s not clear exactly what the president and any attendees plan to discuss, there will surely be a lot to talk about given incidents like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22288961/solarwinds-hack-100-companies-9-federal-agencies"&gt;massive Solarwinds hack&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/5/22564054/ransomware-revil-kaseya-coop"&gt;Kaseya ransomware attack&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/8/22426158/cyberattack-forces-shutdown-major-us-fuel-colonial-pipeline"&gt;the Colonial Pipeline shutdown&lt;/a&gt; resulting from a cyberattack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="isr1jL"&gt;Apple, Microsoft, Google, Amazon, IBM, JPMorgan, and Southern Company all declined to comment to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg,&lt;/em&gt; and a Southern Company spokesperson declined to comment to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. The other companies and the White House have not replied to requests for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22638724/joe-biden-cybersecurity-meeting-white-house-tim-cook-satya-nadella-andy-jassy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22638724/joe-biden-cybersecurity-meeting-white-house-tim-cook-satya-nadella-andy-jassy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-23T18:46:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-23T18:46:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>Offline playback on Spotify’s Wear OS app is rolling out now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aAwtAPEBWT8hyKGNMPeRGomg0_g=/0x7:883x596/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69766296/Spotify_wearOS_banner01_1.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spotify’s Wear OS app.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Spotify&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bhwuSr"&gt;Support for offline playback in Spotify’s Wear OS app is rolling now, the company confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. As spotted &lt;a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/spotify-wear-os-update-offline-listening-coming-soon?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+androidcentral+%28Android+Central%29"&gt;by &lt;em&gt;Android Central&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, some users &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/WearOS/comments/p9wy9s/got_the_new_spotify_update/"&gt;on Reddit&lt;/a&gt; report that they are already able to use the feature, so if you’ve been waiting for it, you might want to check and see if it’s already rolled out to you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xtApg4"&gt;There’s a couple caveats to offline playback on Wear OS, though: &lt;a href="https://newsroom.spotify.com/2021-08-11/enjoy-all-your-music-and-podcasts-offline-on-smartwatches-running-wear-os/"&gt;according to a Spotify blog&lt;/a&gt;, your watch will need to be on Wear OS 2.0 or newer to be able to use the feature, and only Spotify Premium subscribers will be able to download and albums and playlists for offline listening. Both paid and free users can download podcasts for offline playback, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WT3w3D"&gt;Spotify revealed on August 11th that its Wear OS would be getting offline playback &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22621394/spotify-wear-os-2-app-offline-playback-smartwatch"&gt;“over the coming weeks,”&lt;/a&gt; so it’s nice to see that it’s now starting to roll out. Offline playback for Spotify was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/21/22447222/spotify-adding-feature-music-downloads-offline-apple-watch"&gt;also recently added to the Apple Watch&lt;/a&gt;, though &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/19/22443522/deezer-apple-watch-offline-listening"&gt;Deezer beat Spotify to the punch&lt;/a&gt; by adding the feature to its Apple Watch app just a couple days before. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22638628/spotify-offline-playback-wear-os-now-rolling-out"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22638628/spotify-offline-playback-wear-os-now-rolling-out</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-23T18:44:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-23T18:44:38-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook tries adding video and voice calls back into its main app</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qrhBz1dNzp3NWhrrIO9dPVR4NR4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69766292/acastro_180522_facebook_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="D8EEFX"&gt;Facebook is testing adding voice and video calls to the main Facebook app, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-08-23/facebook-retools-messaging-again-by-adding-calling-to-main-app?sref=dZ65CIng"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;. The features are currently part of the standalone Messenger app, which Facebook originally &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2011/08/09/facebook-launches-standalone-mobile-messenger-app-and-it%E2%80%99s-beluga/"&gt;spun out of its big blue main app in 2011&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/4/9/5598440/facebook-will-turn-off-messaging-in-its-mobile-app-forcing-you-to-download-messenger"&gt;officially removed in 2014&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j2MdCV"&gt;Voice and video calls are two of several Messenger features that Facebook has introduced in its other products like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/15/20913653/facebook-portal-10-inch-2019-review-price-specs-features-whatsapp-video-calling"&gt;Portal video cameras&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/16/21440086/facebook-oculus-connect-recap-biggest-announcements-quest-rift-games"&gt;Oculus virtual reality headsets&lt;/a&gt;. The company hasn’t shared if it plans to bring other parts of Messenger back into the fold, but Messenger’s director of product management did tell &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; that “you’re going to start to see quite a bit more of this over time.”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ZQTBSd"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Messenger features in everything might make Facebook a harder knot to untangle&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="k84gSk"&gt;Facebook confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that it is testing voice and video calls in “several countries, including the US.” The company did not share how many users will see the features or what this means for the standalone Messenger app in the future other than “for a full-featured messaging, audio and video call experience, people should continue using Messenger.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6hMmQj"&gt;Adding voice and video calls to the Facebook app makes about as much sense as spinning off Messenger in the first place. Yes, it means there’s one less app to switch between while you’re doing other things on your computer or phone, but it also means you’ll have to interact with (or at least see) Facebook on the way — something I’m not sure everyone is interested in doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CPUIgw"&gt;There’s also the risk that weaving Messenger into Facebook draws the same kinds of criticism that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/30/21495068/facebook-messenger-instagram-cross-platform-messaging-integration"&gt;unifying Messenger and Instagram direct messages&lt;/a&gt; did. It seems like it makes a giant company like Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/interface/2020/10/1/21495514/facebook-account-center-instagram-messenger-direct-integration-adam-mosseri-interview"&gt;even harder to break up&lt;/a&gt; — which may be the point. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="st3RHJ"&gt;This isn’t the first suggestion that Facebook was considering getting Messenger back into Facebook, either. In 2019, the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/12/18307443/facebook-messenger-app-integration-manchun-wong-standalone"&gt;tested bringing text chats back into the main app&lt;/a&gt; with a dedicated inbox &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/2/20752324/instagram-whatsapp-renamed-adding-facebook-branding"&gt;and splashed “from Facebook”&lt;/a&gt; across Oculus, Instagram, and WhatsApp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9K77RS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22638530/facebook-messenger-video-voice-calls-back-main-app"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/23/22638530/facebook-messenger-video-voice-calls-back-main-app</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
