<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2020-12-08T19:03:18-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-08T19:03:18-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-08T19:03:18-05:00</updated>
    <title>Halo Infinite is officially launching fall 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qozT4rXW7wG-D93n3QbIy8sKGwI=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68481593/hi_multiplayer_map_2_1920x1080_4b85484a2b294c07951bec8b636d2270.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: 343 Industries&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hwDPxX"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;, the next game in Microsoft’s iconic franchise, will officially launch in fall 2021, developer 343 Industries announced in a blog post &lt;a href="https://www.halowaypoint.com/en-us/news/inside-infinite-december-2020"&gt;on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TgIZfY"&gt;The game was originally supposed to launch alongside the Xbox Series X / S in November, but it was delayed to 2021 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/11/21363769/halo-infinite-delay-launch-2021-release-date-xbox-series-x"&gt;in August&lt;/a&gt; due in part to challenges created by the COVID-19 pandemic. Since Microsoft hasn’t specified a month or day, this fall 2021 window could effectively mean that the game gets delayed as much as an entire year from its original release date. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j1X3Vt"&gt;Microsoft did demo &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; during its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21335520/halo-infinite-gameplay-xbox-series-x-trailer-demo"&gt;July Xbox Series X games showcase&lt;/a&gt;, but received some criticism for the graphics and visuals shown during the demo (a dead-eyed enemy shown then even spawned the now-infamous &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/news/craig-from-halo-infinite-is-the-new-xbox-mascot-jokes-xbox-chief"&gt;Craig meme&lt;/a&gt;). In Tuesday’s blog post, 343 Industries said that it is working hard to “create the best-looking Halo game ever,” and spends some time delving into graphics specifically. According to creative director Joseph Staten, it’s already possible to play through the entire campaign, so much of the work remaining is polish, fixing bugs, and multiplayer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="07K02F"&gt;You can read more about the current development of &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;a href="https://www.halowaypoint.com/en-us/news/inside-infinite-december-2020"&gt;343 Industries’ blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ZABApP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Microsoft delays Halo Infinite to 2021","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/11/21363769/halo-infinite-delay-launch-2021-release-date-xbox-series-x"},{"title":"Microsoft confirms Halo Infinite multiplayer will be free-to-play and up to 120fps","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/31/21349236/halo-infinite-multiplayer-free-to-play-120fps-rumors"},{"title":"Halo Infinite: watch 8 minutes of gameplay on Xbox Series X","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21335520/halo-infinite-gameplay-xbox-series-x-trailer-demo"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22164440/halo-infinite-launch-date-fall-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22164440/halo-infinite-launch-date-fall-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-08T18:45:34-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-08T18:45:34-05:00</updated>
    <title>American Airlines offers at-home COVID tests for US travel</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-AVIATION-ACCIDENT-BOEING-AMERICANAIRLINES" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RdOZi-JJR8kyKCc2AuL-hb5UVk4=/0x0:6000x4000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68481482/1229909022.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by COOPER NEILL/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="M3FLzl"&gt;American Airlines is &lt;a href="http://news.aa.com/news/news-details/2020/American-Airlines-Offers-Preflight-COVID-19-Testing-For-All-US-Destinations-with-Travel-Requirements-OPS-DIS-12/default.aspx"&gt;about to start offering at-home COVID-19 tests&lt;/a&gt; to domestic fliers in order to help them meet various state travel restriction requirements, the company announced Tuesday. The airline is partnering with direct-to-consumer home testing company LetsGetChecked, which will sell the tests for $129 on top of the cost of travel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nkZ6a8"&gt;The at-home tests help travelers check off one of the most common travel restrictions that states have implemented, which is a negative test result either before departure or upon arrival. It will also help customers get reliable access to testing, which is still hit-or-miss in many parts of the United States. But there are still holes in the process; it is still possible to get infected on the way to or at the airport, for example. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0tgzRf"&gt;Different states also have different restrictions. Some states still require travelers to quarantine even with a negative test result. So American Airlines and LetsGetChecked are &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.letsgetchecked.com%2Fus%2Fen%2Famerican-airlines%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2020%2F12%2F8%2F22164032%2Famerican-airlines-home-covid-19-tests-domestic-flights-cost#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;advising customers to make sure they know what’s required of them when they land&lt;/a&gt;. American Airlines previously offered at-home tests for travelers heading to international destinations with restrictions, like the United Kingdom, Belize, and Chile. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="tRj3NX"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Receive a kit, swab your nose, send it back&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bZ1lV3"&gt;LetsGetChecked’s test kits use a nasal swab, so customers will have to take a sample at home and send back through the mail (using UPS) to be run through a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/17/21184015/coronavirus-testing-pcr-diagnostic-point-of-care-cdc-techonology"&gt;Polymerase Chain Reaction, or PCR, test&lt;/a&gt;. That whole process takes a few days, so LetsGetChecked says travelers should be sure to order their tests at least five days before their flights. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7gPIka"&gt;American Airlines is the first to offer access to at-home testing for domestic flights. But other major airlines and airports have also been trying to introduce testing protocol as part of a way to encourage travelers to return to the skies. Delta Air Lines and Alitalia &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/26/21721520/quarantine-flights-rome-fiumicino-airport-italy-us-delta-alitalia"&gt;recently announced&lt;/a&gt; they will test passengers multiple times on flights from New York’s JFK airport, New Jersey’s Newark Airport, and Georgia’s Hartsfield-Jackson Atlanta airport to Rome’s Fiumicino airport. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ELBzqw"&gt;Facing historic losses but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21363675/delta-america-united-airlines-layoffs-cash-covid-19-losses-loans-cares-act"&gt;buoyed by billions of dollars in government aid&lt;/a&gt;, companies like American and Delta have been trying to resurrect the industry after the coronavirus pandemic devastated air travel earlier this year. The number of fliers did dramatically increase over the Thanksgiving holiday despite a sharp increase in case counts and warnings from the Centers for Disease Control, but it’s not yet clear whether people will remain as willing to fly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yeqkMq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vUBdIH"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22164032/american-airlines-home-covid-19-tests-domestic-flights-cost"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22164032/american-airlines-home-covid-19-tests-domestic-flights-cost</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-08T18:08:59-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-08T18:08:59-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s Pixel 2 has gotten its last update</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Google Pixel 2" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_3Bbm49tan4sB3mVTYElmT9rD98=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68481108/jbareham_171013_2050_0159.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The Google Pixel 2 and Pixel 2 XL were flawed-yet-likable devices with a camera that stood out from the competition | Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wimsdZ"&gt;After three years of support, the Pixel 2 has received its last update from Google: a delayed November security patch going out to the devices this month, as &lt;a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/rip-pixel-2-google-rolls-out-its-final-update-phone"&gt;noted by &lt;em&gt;Android Central&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Google’s &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/pixelphone/answer/4457705#pixel_phones&amp;amp;nexus_devices"&gt;device support schedule&lt;/a&gt; indicates that the Pixel 2 and Pixel 2 XL aren’t guaranteed security updates after October 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nXne4T"&gt;Google announced the Pixel 2 and Pixel 2 XL in October 2017. The two devices were identical in every way except size, and they earned plenty of praise for their somewhat groundbreaking camera. Google was early to really lean into camera software and computational photography, and the results showed in the Pixel 2 — its single rear-facing camera was in many ways ahead of the multi-camera-toting competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="09Ge0p"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Google Pixel 2 review: plainly great","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/17/16486108/google-pixel-2-xl-review-android-phone-camera"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="ddQoQO"&gt;Aside from a highly capable camera and an overall likable design, it wasn’t without its troubles. The Pixel 2 XL’s screen suffered some &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2017/10/18/16489756/google-pixel-2xl-awful-lg-oled-screen"&gt;well-documented woes&lt;/a&gt;, including a tendency toward a blue color cast when viewed at slightly off angles. Shortcomings aside, the 2 and 2 XL will be best remembered as the smartphones that put truly incredible image processing capabilities into your pocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fL7SfU"&gt;Nevertheless, time marches on, and current Pixel devices will see a December security patch arriving this week. The Pixel 3 and newer will also be receiving &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/7/22158452/google-pixel-december-feature-drop-features"&gt;new features&lt;/a&gt; borrowed from recent devices, like adaptive sound and Extreme Battery Saver mode.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22164027/google-pixel-2-final-update-security-patch-november-2020"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22164027/google-pixel-2-final-update-security-patch-november-2020</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-08T18:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-08T18:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix wants to help parents connect with their kids by explaining what they’re watching</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wbOR3w5sWowhUq5l-p0iyDmOpYM=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68481072/Netflix_Kids_Activity_Report_3_phonesmockup.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="otJejR"&gt;Netflix is rolling out a new tool for parents to better understand and monitor what their kids are watching. Called the Kids Activity Report, as seen in the image above, the new breakdown includes data on what type of programming kids are spending the most time watching, who their favorite character is, and recommendations for new shows based on their interests. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="utHhQY"&gt;Emails sent out to customers who have kids accounts enabled started going out this weekend, letting parents know they could opt into the report. The report also comes with a “joke of the day,” coloring pages (based on Netflix characters and shows) to print out for kids stuck at home, and prepared questions to ask their kids based on their favorite show or character. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RzcrCT"&gt;Parents will hopefully be able to better connect with their kids by having a more thorough understanding of what they’re watching — even if they don’t want to watch it themselves, Michelle Parsons, who leads Netflix’s product innovation team for kids and family, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qNTkpbb5zpiwD4oRVxq_rNgV3ck=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22155498/Netflix_Kids_Activity_Report_phonemockup.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="DsvhcZ"&gt;“Most parents have a pulse on what their kids like, based on their Halloween costumes or toys they ask for at Christmas, but we don’t always know what those shows are about,” Parson said. “What is the show, in essence, talking about?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LibQBG"&gt;Netflix’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/7/21211338/netflix-parent-controls-filter-movies-tv-shows-rating-pin-password"&gt;kids profiles&lt;/a&gt; are typically made for children between “pre-school and pre-teen” ages, Parsons said. If older kids don’t want their parents knowing what they’re watching — or just don’t like the idea of being monitored — that’s a conversation for families to have, Parsons added. Parents can opt out of the reports at any time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kHExGM"&gt;Alongside the new kids report, Netflix is also rolling out a global test for a Family Profile setting. Unlike regular profiles or kids-only profiles, family profiles will pull in TV shows and films that people can select as family-friendly, and it will appear in one profile. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LG3l2k"&gt;Netflix accounts are designed around individual interests. The algorithm learns what people are into and suggests recommended programming to keep them glued to their screens. Like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/27/21340050/netflix-the-witcher-blood-origin-live-action-prequel-announced"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Witcher&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;? Try &lt;em&gt;Cursed&lt;/em&gt;, or something along those lines. The family profile uses ratings to bring in a number of different titles that are then prioritized and recommended based on those individual interests. Movies up to a PG-13 rating and TV shows up to a TV-14 rating will appear. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AQtUNnKCGTsaoPFMQC9FZGU-VPw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22155491/Family_Profile_1.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="rgM0cc"&gt;“The key thing to understand is that it creates a family profile with co-viewing in mind that’s most relevant for specific family audiences,” Parsons said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0VekCe"&gt;What people won’t be able to do right now, however, is add shows or movies in that are more mature than PG-13 or TV-14. Hypothetically, if a family wanted to watch &lt;em&gt;The Witcher &lt;/em&gt;together, that wouldn’t show up because of the rating. Parsons acknowledged that the team is communicating with members about what they want out of a family profile, and Netflix can work on a setting that allows subscribers to add titles beyond the PG-13 and TV-14 rating if that becomes a popular request. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ikoq58"&gt;The family profiles are rolling out today as part of a global test, while the kids activity report is also rolling out in select markets as part of a global test. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163863/netflix-family-profile-kids-activity-report-data-movies-tv-shows-individual"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163863/netflix-family-profile-kids-activity-report-data-movies-tv-shows-individual</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-08T17:40:19-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-08T17:40:19-05:00</updated>
    <title>Pornhub limits uploads and disables downloads after New York Times exposé</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="pornhub billboard times square" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hyyCOJxjQzgls-e9ImfuGbN_xLc=/0x125:740x618/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68480930/pornhub-billboard-1-sq.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A Times Square billboard for PornHub from 2015&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hF1lBJ"&gt;Pornhub has made significant changes to its content policies after &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/04/opinion/sunday/pornhub-rape-trafficking.html"&gt;a &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; report&lt;/a&gt; detailed the damage done by nonconsensual videos posted to the platform, often involving underage girls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yCChq6"&gt;&lt;a href="https://help.pornhub.com/hc/en-us/categories/360002934613"&gt;In a statement today&lt;/a&gt;, Pornhub announced a new set of policies aimed at keeping nonconsensual videos off the site. Most significantly, the platform will no longer accept uploads from unidentified users, a significant shift for a company that built its platform on non-professional uploads. In the short term, that will restrict uploads to content partners and members of the platform’s Model Program, although Pornhub plans to roll out a broader verification process for regular users in 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dc7hRM"&gt;Once content has been uploaded, Pornhub will block downloading content entirely, no longer allowing users to export content from the site outside of paid downloads triggered through the company’s verified system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="R12ych"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“these seem significant”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Zhk6it"&gt;PornHub has also pledged to increase moderation of content currently on the platform through a newly established “Red Team,” dedicated to “proactively sweeping content already uploaded for potential violations and identifying any breakdowns in the moderation process.” The company has also pledged to publish its first transparency report in 2021, detailing the results of moderation from the previous year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oUbdyD"&gt;In its statement, Pornhub attributes the changes to an independent review launched in April, aimed at eliminating all illegal content from the platform. However, the move comes just four days after &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/04/opinion/sunday/pornhub-rape-trafficking.html"&gt;a searing &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; report&lt;/a&gt; from Nicholas Kristof, which triggered a significant backlash against the company and its practices. The report highlighted a number of young girls who appeared in videos uploaded to Pornhub without their consent. Even after the videos were flagged and removed, downloaded copies continued to circulate, often with severe and alarming personal consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LWXIny"&gt;In the wake of Kristof’s article, Pornhub’s business partners faced mounting pressure to cut ties with the platform — particularly &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/07/business/visa-mastercard-pornhub.html"&gt;payment processors like Visa and Mastercard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M894pN"&gt;Dawn Hawkins, senior vice president and executive director of the National Center on Sexual Exploitation, was outspoken in calling for the site to be shut down. “Companies like Visa and MasterCard who partner with Pornhub are also profiting from the rape of children,” Hawkins said in a statement after the piece was published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KeXlIS"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NickKristof/status/1336413019769856008"&gt;Reacting to the changes on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, Kristof seemed cautiously optimistic. “A great deal depends on how responsibly Pornhub implements these, and it hasn’t earned my trust at all, but these seem significant,” he wrote. “A great deal will also depend on whether past content, already on the site, is vetted or removed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bvsI69"&gt;Pornhub did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22164031/pornhub-upload-limit-blocked-download-nyt-kristof-child-abuse"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22164031/pornhub-upload-limit-blocked-download-nyt-kristof-child-abuse</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-08T17:16:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-08T17:16:26-05:00</updated>
    <title>The PS5 and Xbox Series X made us fall back in love with old games</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RqjKTm4pxfGn4AoZYETRNPHCuEo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68480776/vpavic_4261_20201023_0068.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uxfzLy"&gt;The PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X / S have been out for a few weeks now. And while we’ve been loving next-gen titles like &lt;em&gt;Astro’s Playroom&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: Miles Morales&lt;/em&gt;, many &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; staffers have been marveling at something unexpected: older games on newer consoles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pCUlbf"&gt;Thanks to more powerful hardware, many games now have more stable resolutions, better frame rates, and faster load times, which makes playing them even better than before. And the PlayStation Plus Collection and Xbox Game Pass offer a plethora of older titles at a monthly price that’s far cheaper than a brand-new next-gen game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BTBIXd"&gt;We’ve all spent time with different games, so our newsroom wanted to share some of our experiences in case you’ve been wondering just how well older games might fare on the PS5 and Xbox Series consoles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="QFsxn8"&gt;Halo: The Master Chief Collection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="CnOQAC"&gt;I was first introduced to &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; in 2004 when I got two games for Christmas: &lt;em&gt;Halo 2&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Blinx 2: Masters of Time and Space&lt;/em&gt;. (Full disclosure: I was more excited to play the latter than the former.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FDLDGL"&gt;But after I realized how disappointing &lt;em&gt;Blinx 2&lt;/em&gt; was, I decided to fire up &lt;em&gt;Halo 2&lt;/em&gt; and I was hooked. When &lt;em&gt;Halo 3&lt;/em&gt; came out, I spent the entire weekend in my room splitting time between the campaign and multiplayer modes. Thanks to backwards compatibility, I was able to play &lt;em&gt;Halo: Combat Evolved &lt;/em&gt;on the Xbox 360. I drifted apart from the series after &lt;em&gt;Halo 3: ODST&lt;/em&gt; but got back into it after I decided to buy an Xbox One so I could play &lt;em&gt;Halo: The Master Chief Collection&lt;/em&gt;. I purchased the Xbox One bundle, which included a digital copy of the game and I felt nostalgic for my younger years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S5LLZU"&gt;When &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; was announced, I knew I had to buy an Xbox Series X to experience the next entry in the series. It was the only reason I wanted a Series X at launch, but disappointingly, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/11/21363769/halo-infinite-delay-launch-2021-release-date-xbox-series-x"&gt;the game was delayed until next year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SuFMHe"&gt;I decided to keep my Series X preorder because it’s so hard to buy either next-gen console right now. I’m glad I did because Microsoft announced that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/20/21524911/halo-the-master-chief-collection-microsoft-xbox-series-x-s-optimization"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Master Chief Collection&lt;/em&gt; was getting a next-gen update&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rsHNCX"&gt;I have a pretty good gaming PC and own the compilation on console and PC, but I was excited to play this version of the game that was fully optimized for the next-gen Xbox. Fully experiencing &lt;em&gt;Halo 3&lt;/em&gt;’s epic campaign with a frame rate higher than 30fps made me fall in love with the original trilogy all over again. The way the next-gen version of this compilation takes full advantage of the Xbox Series X has helped me fill the void &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt;’s delay left, and it will surely keep me occupied until &lt;em&gt;Infinite&lt;/em&gt; gets a new release date. &lt;em&gt;—Taylor Lyles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="N42GO7"&gt;Fortnite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="HbZpQQ"&gt;There are so many things I could do with my new PS5, from finally learning to play &lt;em&gt;Demon’s Souls&lt;/em&gt; to spending a few more hours swinging around a virtual rendition of New York City in &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: Miles Morales&lt;/em&gt;. And yet, here I am, playing more &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;. I can’t help it: the game is so much better on Sony’s new console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CGED8r"&gt;Part of it is visual. &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; looks incredible on both next-gen consoles, with features like ray tracing and realistic fog bringing the battle royale island to life. When &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/21831926/fortnite-chapter-2-season-5-battle-pass-trailer-mandalorian-baby-yoda"&gt;the new season launched&lt;/a&gt;, I spent a lot of time exploring newly introduced areas — which include an alien desert and a dense jungle arena — because they looked so vibrant and detailed. Much of it is smaller details that you really have to look for: the sun reflecting off of the Mandalorian’s helmet or the hazy glow of purple desert crystals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B8skDv"&gt;But it’s also the way the game feels. It runs fast and smooth, but more importantly for me, the adaptive triggers in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21562206/ps5-dualsense-controller-review-games-features-vibrations"&gt;the PS5’s DualSense controller&lt;/a&gt; make shooters much more tactile and interesting. I love how I can feel the difference between each weapon based on the tension in the trigger when firing. Now when I play &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; on a different platform, it feels like something’s missing. &lt;em&gt;—Andrew Webster&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="6ygLEr"&gt;Monster Hunter World&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="T7g7uf"&gt;I love &lt;em&gt;Monster Hunter World&lt;/em&gt;, but it’s been a little awkward to play because of how Capcom keeps staggering releases. The game first came out on the PS4, then I started over on the PC version six months later for its better performance, and then I had to go back to the PS4 for the &lt;em&gt;Iceborne&lt;/em&gt; expansion because the PC version was several months late again. The result is I never really got into &lt;em&gt;Iceborne&lt;/em&gt; on either platform as much as I should’ve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nWLsr3"&gt;Now I have the best of both worlds on the PS5. Even though the PS4 version hasn’t been updated, it runs so much better on the newer console because it never had a locked frame rate. That’s the reason I wanted to play on PC in the first place, ironically, but it also means the PS5 can just throw its raw processing power at the game and achieve 60fps. I’ve been able to go back to my PS4 save, and it’s like I never stopped playing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iUry6s"&gt;It’s unfortunate that a lot of last-gen games remain stuck at 30fps on the PS5 and Series X because of hard-coded limits, but &lt;em&gt;Monster Hunter World&lt;/em&gt; is pretty much the best-case scenario. &lt;em&gt;—Sam Byford&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="6FdVQs"&gt;Uncharted&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="wYkpml"&gt;I’ve just been blown away by &lt;em&gt;Uncharted 4&lt;/em&gt; on the PS5. Despite playing on the same TV, I’ve been seeing elements of the actors’ performances that I didn’t notice the first couple of times I played. There are emotional beats that hit harder because I can see the acting better. Also, the sightseeing is incredible. Apparently, on the PS4 Pro, &lt;em&gt;Uncharted 4&lt;/em&gt; ran at 1440p, up from 1080p on the regular PS4, so I’d suspect that’s also what it’s running at on the PS5, and it just looks great. I’ll definitely be playing through the whole game again because of the improvements on the PS5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bEFZYV"&gt;And just for fun, I tried out &lt;em&gt;Uncharted 2&lt;/em&gt;, a game that I first played on the PS3, and then again on the PS4 when it was mildly remastered in the &lt;em&gt;Nathan Drake Collection&lt;/em&gt;. Playing it on the PS5, though, it felt and looked almost no different than it did on the PS4. That is, until I died, and the PS5’s ultra-fast SSD let me reload in two seconds. Next on my list: &lt;em&gt;Ghost of Tsushima&lt;/em&gt;, which actually got &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/suckerpunchprod/status/1314641549406265346"&gt;a PS5-specific patch&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;—Mitchell Clark&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="17I7lH"&gt;Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice and Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="hI9wu9"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/22/18277376/sekiro-shadows-die-twice-review-xbox-ps4-pc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is my go-to game for testing cloud gaming services like Nvidia’s GeForce Now because of the unforgiving timing it takes to properly deflect blows with your sword and strike true. But personally, I couldn’t see myself playing through it even on my PS4 Pro because of &lt;a href="https://www.kotaku.com.au/2019/03/sekiro-shadows-die-twice-pc-ps4-xbox-one/"&gt;the unstable frame rate and frame pacing on consoles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g7ULvR"&gt;Yet, when I fired it up on my PS5 the other night, it was &lt;em&gt;butter&lt;/em&gt;. Smooth as can be! I didn’t want to stop testing, even though I’m &lt;em&gt;so &lt;/em&gt;much further on my PC save. I swapped back to PS4 Pro just to check, and sure enough, stuttery as heck by comparison, even though the resolution (1800p) looks exactly the same. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bwjv86"&gt;The other game I can’t go back to my PS4 Pro for is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/6/21207441/final-fantasy-7-remake-ff7-review-ps4"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. But it’s not because of the frame rate or even the fidelity (which, to my eye, looks like &lt;em&gt;maybe&lt;/em&gt; it can maintain its dynamic resolution of 1620p more often but could be my imagination). It’s the fact that I no longer have to deal with a jet engine in my living room. More than any other PS4 game I’ve played, &lt;em&gt;FFVII&lt;/em&gt; makes my PS4 Pro’s fan scream so loud I have to turn up the volume to make out the game. Meanwhile, my PS5 stays whisper-quiet.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wQT9fTilvYNdEayhsDFcz-4oVUs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22155433/ps4_ps5_final_fantasy_vii_remake.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;I swear PS5 (right) looks slightly better, but I wouldn’t be surprised if you don’t see a difference.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Dg3y4j"&gt;I’m playing through it for the first time, to be honest, after putting it off to start… and while I’m kind of kicking myself for sleeping on this pitch-perfect nostalgia bomb this long, I’m also glad I can listen to its epic orchestral score without an additional unwanted instrument screeching in the background. &lt;em&gt;—Sean Hollister&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="XB25UY"&gt;PlayStation Plus Collection and Xbox Game Pass&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="ZRyCGn"&gt;I only had a PS4 for a few months this year, and I never owned an Xbox One, so I just haven’t played a lot of the defining games of the last console generation. But with the sheer volume of games on the PlayStation Plus Collection and Xbox Game Pass, I’ve already sunk hours into older games on both the PlayStation 5 and the Xbox Series X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xrNAOQ"&gt;I’ve already completed &lt;em&gt;Ori and the Blind Forest&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and I can’t wait to dive into its sequel, &lt;em&gt;Ori and the Will of the Wisps&lt;/em&gt;. I’ve started to play the first &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; via &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Master Chief Collection&lt;/em&gt;, and I intend to work through the whole &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; series before &lt;em&gt;Halo Infinite&lt;/em&gt; comes out sometime next year. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/3/22151470/fortnite-god-of-war-kratos-skin-now-available"&gt;Kratos’ recent appearance in &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is pushing me toward &lt;em&gt;God of War&lt;/em&gt; sooner rather than later. Now that I’ve finished the &lt;em&gt;Demon’s Souls&lt;/em&gt; remake, I’m eager to try &lt;em&gt;Bloodborne&lt;/em&gt; sometime soon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1agFnF"&gt;Even though there aren’t a lot of truly next-gen games to play on the consoles right now, I already have a big backlog of older games thanks to the huge library of titles on Sony and Microsoft’s subscription services. I can’t wait to catch up with the last generation of consoles on the newest hardware; I’m late to play the games, but I get to play them at their very best. &lt;em&gt;—Jay Peters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2TVBq2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tc1Ucx"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22163921/ps5-playstation-5-xbox-series-x-old-games-next-gen-consoles"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22163921/ps5-playstation-5-xbox-series-x-old-games-next-gen-consoles</id>
    <author>
      <name>Verge Staff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-08T17:16:03-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-08T17:16:03-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to buy Apple’s new AirPods Max headphones</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CfiK42iNqsVMxlGzJ_eeS-Kmsqg=/0x0:980x653/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68478037/apple_airpods_max_listening_experience_12082020_big_carousel.jpg.large.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="cXTBOA"&gt;After many months of rumors, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/21438042/apple-max-studio-noise-canceling-headphones-price-date"&gt;Apple officially announced the AirPods Max&lt;/a&gt;, its own over-the-ear, wireless, noise-canceling headphones. This is the first pair of noise-canceling headphones to feature the Apple logo. They cost $549 and are available for preorder now with shipping slated for December 15th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="swfJ7i"&gt;Unlike the AirPods and AirPods Pro, the AirPods Max come in multiple colors (dark gray, silver, blue, green, and pink). They feature high-fidelity audio, adaptive EQ, active noise cancellation, and spatial audio. Apple says the headphones offer a 20-hour battery life with charging done through Apple’s Lightning connector and not through a USB-C cable. (No, a charging brick does not come in the box.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uzaX5q"&gt;We’ll be reviewing the new wireless headphones soon, but if you are interested in placing an order ahead of time, below are the retailers that currently have product listings available.  Currently, you can preorder the AirPods Max at &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fshop%2Fbuy-airpods%2Fairpods-max%2Fspace-gray#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1726003076182366997" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-airpods-max%2F-%2FA-82065675%3Fpreselect%3D54191104%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;. We expect other retailers to put up listings soon and will update this article when they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xTCpe8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10215065"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="1IVLgF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22163175/apple-airpods-max-headphones-preorder-how-to-buy-price-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22163175/apple-airpods-max-headphones-preorder-how-to-buy-price-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-08T17:11:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-08T17:11:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>Senate confirms Trump FCC nominee over Democrat objections</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-POLITICS-PROTEST-FCC" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/79zL79h84i0D7pK-cqTb64udCZ0=/0x0:3843x2562/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68480747/891675448.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Alex Edelman / AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MQKbcQ"&gt;On Tuesday, the Senate voted to confirm the controversial nomination of Republican Nathan Simington to the Federal Communications Commission, despite pleas from Democrats and advocacy groups to hold off on a vote until next year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KTAsBm"&gt;By confirming Simington, the Republican-led Senate will be handing the incoming Joe Biden administration a deadlocked FCC. In November, current FCC chairman Ajit Pai announced that he would be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/30/21726572/ajit-pai-fcc-step-down-date-trump-telecom-net-neutrality"&gt;stepping down&lt;/a&gt; from the agency once Biden is inaugurated, leaving the incoming administration with two Republicans, two Democrats, and no voting majority. If a Republican-led Senate refuses to confirm Biden’s choice for a replacement, it could bring the commission to a standstill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="lI21uZ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Nathan Simington is a deeply dangerous nominee to the FCC.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ynZNBz"&gt;This threat of gridlock paired with concerns over Simington’s qualifications for the job prompted Democrats and advocacy groups to oppose the nomination. In a virtual protest event, Sen. Richard Blumenthal (D-CT) said, “Nathan Simington is a deeply dangerous nominee to the FCC.” He continued, “Simington has proven himself an adversary, not an advocate for online access. He is conflicted, unprepared, and unqualified.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CKlfVl"&gt;Blumenthal was joined by groups like Public Knowledge, Fight for the Future, and MediaJustice on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RUzmFz"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/10/21431384/donald-trump-fcc-nomination-section-230-executive-order-bias-conservative"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;first reported&lt;/a&gt; in September that Simington was in talks to become President Donald Trump’s next nominee to the FCC. The nomination followed the president’s abrupt withdrawal of Republican Commissioner Mike O’Rielly’s renomination after O’Rielly made remarks opposing changes to Section 230. Several months earlier, Trump had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/28/21273822/trump-signs-executive-order-facebook-twitter-section-230-social-media-companies"&gt;signed an executive order&lt;/a&gt; prompting the FCC to reinterpret Section 230 shortly after Twitter moved to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/26/21271207/twitter-donald-trump-fact-check-mail-in-voting-coronavirus-pandemic-california"&gt;fact-check one of his tweets&lt;/a&gt; for the first time.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7kneIW"&gt;It’s unclear how large of a role Simington played in drafting a government petition to the FCC requesting changes to Section 230, but the Republican confirmed in a hearing earlier this year that he &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/22048854/trump-nathan-simington-fcc-ajit-pai-section-230-moderation"&gt;at least “edited” it&lt;/a&gt;. Last week, Blumenthal said Simington was not forthright in his answers to the committee regarding his role in drafting the petition. Blumenthal cited answers Simington provided after his confirmation hearing, suggesting that he “sought to enlist Fox News” to help push the FCC to reinterpret Section 230 as requested in the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/22048854/trump-nathan-simington-fcc-ajit-pai-section-230-moderation"&gt;government’s petition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DfFVNb"&gt;In October, Pai said that the agency would move forward on Trump’s executive order seeking to regulate social media companies. It’s unclear how the agency plans to move forward on rulemaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8lFMM0"&gt;“With the right leadership the FCC can be a tremendous force for improving American lives and getting the economy back on track,” Sen. Ron Wyden (D-OR) said Monday. “Unfortunately, Nathan Simington’s only qualification for this job is following Donald Trump’s orders to turn the FCC into government speech police.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163800/senate-trump-fcc-nominee-confirmed-nathan-simington-section-230-ajit-pai"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163800/senate-trump-fcc-nominee-confirmed-nathan-simington-section-230-ajit-pai</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-08T16:25:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-08T16:25:38-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple reportedly hands over its self-driving car project to executive who oversees Siri</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/glZ7wc-hDgvDNKQytQeIpIp8uQk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68480486/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Ddwq7I"&gt;“Siri, drive my car...” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WLoCLe"&gt;Apple is shuffling its leadership that oversees its secretive self-driving car project, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-12-08/apple-shifts-leadership-of-self-driving-car-division-to-ai-chief?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The team’s engineers will now report to John Giannandrea, the company’s head of artificial intelligence, who also oversees voice-based digital assistant Siri. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CJGTz4"&gt;Giannandrea, Google’s former head of search and artificial intelligence, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/3/17195076/google-ai-chief-john-giannandrea-joining-apple-machine-learning-siri"&gt;joined Apple in 2018&lt;/a&gt;. His hire was seen as a huge get for Apple, which has struggled for years to make progress in fast-moving and increasingly important AI fields like computer vision and natural language processing. Giannandrea reports directly to CEO Tim Cook as the leader of machine learning and AI strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="txAEHk"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Not much is known about Apple’s so-called Project Titan&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iCwL67"&gt;Not much is known about Apple’s so-called Project Titan. Unlike most of its competitors, the company has been frustratingly tight-lipped regarding the self-driving cars it’s testing in California. After beginning with the aim of developing a purpose-built self-driving car, the plans were later scaled back to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/10/17/13303710/apple-car-project-titan-self-driving-focus"&gt;just developing software&lt;/a&gt;, with Apple partnering with car manufacturers such as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/23/17387214/apple-volkswagen-partnership-self-driving-cars-project-titan"&gt;Volkswagen&lt;/a&gt; to provide the hardware. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BdG6JF"&gt;There has also been legal drama. In 2019, an Apple employee who is a Chinese citizen was accused by the FBI of attempting to steal trade secrets related to the company’s autonomous car project. It was the second time the government has charged an Apple employee for trying to steal self-driving secrets in the last seven months. Apple also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/24/18195598/apple-project-titan-200-employees-dismissed"&gt;laid off about 200 employees from the project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iOmsjX"&gt;In June 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/25/18758820/drive-ai-self-driving-startup-shutting-down-apple"&gt;Apple acquired the struggling self-driving startup Drive.ai&lt;/a&gt;. Apple purchased the company’s assets, including its autonomous cars, and hired many of its engineers away from Drive.ai directly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wotXIB"&gt;Earlier this year, Apple filed a report with the California Department of Motor Vehicles that showed the company has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/26/21142685/california-dmv-self-driving-car-disengagement-report-data"&gt;seriously downgraded&lt;/a&gt; its public road testing in 2019. After driving nearly 80,000 miles in 2018, the company only logged 7,544 miles in 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V3lNzO"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163939/apple-self-driving-car-john-giannandrea-ai-siri"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163939/apple-self-driving-car-john-giannandrea-ai-siri</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-08T15:54:28-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-08T15:54:28-05:00</updated>
    <title>Cyberpunk 2077 to add new epilepsy warning as devs work on a permanent fix</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qUw_WuiTOHEyIB2Oqro1EmZXk7w=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68480286/Cyberpunk_2077_screen_5.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: CD Projekt Red&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kkaIeh"&gt;CD Projekt Red has &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CyberpunkGame/status/1336389181988343812"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that it’s working on adding a new epilepsy warning to &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;in response to a &lt;a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2020/12/07/cyberpunk-2077-epileptic-psa"&gt;recent article by &lt;em&gt;Game Informer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;that raised the issue. The studio says that it’s also working on “a more permanent solution” for the game’s epilepsy issues “as soon as possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="IZjoRb"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Thank you for bringing this up. We’re working on adding a separate warning in the game, aside from the one that exists in the EULA (&lt;a href="https://t.co/eXpPn73VSK"&gt;https://t.co/eXpPn73VSK&lt;/a&gt;). Regarding a more permanent solution, Dev team is currently exploring that and will be implementing it as soon as possible. &lt;a href="https://t.co/lXFypnSit2"&gt;https://t.co/lXFypnSit2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Cyberpunk 2077 (@CyberpunkGame) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CyberpunkGame/status/1336389181988343812?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 8, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vccRI3"&gt;CD Projekt Red’s response comes after &lt;em&gt;Game Informer&lt;/em&gt; editor Liana Ruppert published a piece cataloging several areas in the upcoming game that could be of concern to players sensitive to epileptic triggers, like flashing patterns or lights. Of particular note is a cutscene of the game’s “braindance” feature, which actually caused Ruppert to experience a serious seizure while playing the game. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xu0cMO"&gt;Ruppert details that during those braindance sequences, white and red lights flash in a rapid pattern for a few seconds before the screen flickers white. Ruppert explains that this cutscene resembled “the actual device neurologists use in real life to trigger a seizure when they need to trigger one for diagnosis purposes.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5naUFS"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Warning: I’ve been sent hundreds of videos disguised as support that are deliberate flashing to induce photosensitive triggers. If you’re sharing this saying you’re epileptic and receive a video, don’t press play.  I’m back to being on my ass. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Be better, please.&lt;/p&gt;— Liana Ruppert (@DirtyEffinHippy) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DirtyEffinHippy/status/1336204870970433536?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 8, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jHnPwt"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; does already include a “Seizure Warning” detailed in the &lt;a href="https://www.cyberpunk.net/en/user-agreement/"&gt;game’s end-user license agreement&lt;/a&gt;. But given that it’s buried deep in a 6,500-plus-word legal document that few, if any players will ever read (even with CD Projekt Red’s helpful explanations), adding another warning that makes the potential risks more accessible is a good thing. Here’s what the current disclosure looks like: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="Ebbjbj"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; may contain flashing lights and images, which may induce epileptic seizures. If you or anyone in your household has an epileptic condition, please consult your doctor before playing &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt;. If you experience dizziness, altered vision, eye or muscle twitches, loss of awareness, disorientation, any involuntary movement, or convulsions while playing, immediately discontinue use and consult your doctor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="9Umzdx"&gt;With &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077 &lt;/em&gt;two days away from release, it’s not clear if the new epilepsy warning or permanent fixes to solve the game’s epilepsy issues will arrive before launch day, or what form they’ll take when they do arrive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WktMhS"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; has reached out to CD Projekt Red for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163783/cyberpunk-2077-epileptic-seizure-warning-permanent-fix-cd-projekt-red"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/8/22163783/cyberpunk-2077-epileptic-seizure-warning-permanent-fix-cd-projekt-red</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
