<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-08-04T17:18:33-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-04T17:18:33-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-04T17:18:33-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple places female engineering program manager on administrative leave after tweeting about sexism in the office</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Apple" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pfOdMl213orTGUFd0OKn-9z4C_Y=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69679863/acastro_170731_1777_0003_v6.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ONzepy"&gt;Apple has placed senior engineering program manager Ashley Gjøvik on indefinite administrative leave after she tweeted about sexism in the office. The company is currently investigating claims Gjøvik made about a hostile work environment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DcaR7F"&gt;“For months, I have been raising concerns with Apple employee relations about years of experiences with sexism, a hostile work environment, sexual harassment, unsafe working conditions, and retaliation,” Gjøvik says in an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “I asked them to mitigate the hostile work environment while they investigate, and they initially offered me EAP therapy and medical leave. I told them that made no sense, and said they should talk to my leadership and set up oversight and boundaries. I added that if there was no other option they could give me paid administrative leave. They apparently made no effort to set boundaries and instead said they were placing me on administrative leave and implied they did not want me on Slack where I had been vocal about my concerns with certain policies at the company. They also implied they didn’t want me to meet one-on-one with other women at the company about their concerns with Apple policies, which I had been doing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dYW22k"&gt;This afternoon, Gjøvik set an out of office message informing colleagues that the employee relations team had placed her on indefinite paid leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dpRzyx"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;So, following raising concerns to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Apple?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Apple&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/sexism?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#sexism&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/hostileworkenvironment?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#hostileworkenvironment&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/unsafeworkconditions?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#unsafeworkconditions&lt;/a&gt;, I'm now on indefinite paid administrative leave per &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Apple?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Apple&lt;/a&gt; employee relations, while they investigate my concerns. This seems to include me not using Apple's internal Slack.&lt;/p&gt;— Ashley M. Gjøvik (@ashleygjovik) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashleygjovik/status/1423014977661591552?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 4, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QDTXTo"&gt;This is the second time Apple has investigated Gjøvik’s claims about sex discrimination at the company. The employee relations team closed an earlier investigation, allegedly finding that nothing was wrong, prompting Gjøvik to tweet screenshots with what she says is just a small portion of what she experienced:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="A4YgO7"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Wanted to share: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Apple?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Apple&lt;/a&gt; employee relations confirmed this &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/tonepolicing?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#tonepolicing&lt;/a&gt; is totally ok feedback for me to get from my &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/bigtech?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#bigtech&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/male?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#male&lt;/a&gt; leaders &amp;amp; not &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/sexist?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#sexist&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As this investigation rolls on, I've decided to start Tweeting the stuff they say is "ok." I mean, they did say it was ok? &lt;a href="https://t.co/EImLTjRTBl"&gt;pic.twitter.com/EImLTjRTBl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ashley M. Gjøvik (@ashleygjovik) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashleygjovik/status/1422380335703101443?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 3, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="Z3eNab"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;In today's &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Apple?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Apple&lt;/a&gt; employee relations said its fine update, here's the heartfelt email I sent my &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/bigtech?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#bigtech&lt;/a&gt; male leadership in 2018 during the Kavanaugh hearings. I asked for support of women &amp;amp; to condemn &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/sexism?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#sexism&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/sexualassault?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#sexualassault&lt;/a&gt;. The reply: a text saying "FWIW, RBG thinks he's ok." &lt;a href="https://t.co/0GTthZNEgH"&gt;pic.twitter.com/0GTthZNEgH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ashley M. Gjøvik (@ashleygjovik) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashleygjovik/status/1422953562724737024?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 4, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="f11v2A"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This happened to me at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Apple?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Apple&lt;/a&gt; too: they offered EAP and suggested medical leave after I spoke up about &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/sexism?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#sexism&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/discrimination?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#discrimination&lt;/a&gt;, and a hostile work environment. They also suggested requesting &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ADA?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#ADA&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/disability?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#disability&lt;/a&gt; accommodations after I raised concerns about unsafe &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/workconditions?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#workconditions&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://t.co/LW0Ueq1Leb"&gt;https://t.co/LW0Ueq1Leb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ashley M. Gjøvik (@ashleygjovik) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ashleygjovik/status/1421204989687472130?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;July 30, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yVcnq6"&gt;Apple is currently contending with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/25/22453302/apple-culture-secrecy-leak-antonio-garcia-martinez-letter"&gt;a wave of employee activism&lt;/a&gt;, including multiple women tweeting about their dissatisfaction with the company culture. In May, employees wrote a letter demanding an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/12/22432909/apple-petition-hiring-antonio-garcia-martinez-chaos-monkeys-facebook"&gt;investigation into the hiring of Antonio García Martínez&lt;/a&gt;, who’d written a book about Silicon Valley with descriptions of women many people found offensive.  Hours later, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/12/22433437/apple-hire-antonio-garcia-martinez-out-petition-investigation"&gt;García Martínez was fired&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fvqKiC"&gt;Apple did not immediately respond to a request for comment from&lt;em&gt; The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22610112/apple-female-engineering-manager-leave-sexism-work-environment"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22610112/apple-female-engineering-manager-leave-sexism-work-environment</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-04T17:15:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-04T17:15:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Playdate’s first season of games won’t hit every handheld at the same time</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Z2B-kXc-6jJ_pGhWGuNVo3EU3fo=/0x0:4000x2667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69679840/Playdate_model_shot.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Panic&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7ktTm2"&gt;One of the most intriguing aspects of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22587172/playdate-hands-on-preview"&gt;Panic’s Playdate&lt;/a&gt; — besides its lovely crank — is the unique game delivery method that will bring 24 free games to the device. Panic plans to release a season of games (Season One), two games at a time each week. &lt;a href="https://help.play.date/games/season/"&gt;In a new FAQ released on Wednesday&lt;/a&gt;, Panic explains a bit more about how that’ll work and reveals that, due to limited manufacturing capacity, not everyone will be playing new games at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PYcxYQ"&gt;All Playdates will download new games weekly on “New Game Day” as long they’re connected to Wi-Fi, starting with the first two games when you connect your device. The catch is that not everyone will connect their Playdate to the internet on day one due to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/22/22587193/playdate-preorder-how-to-panic-teenage-engineering-handheld-console"&gt;limited preorders&lt;/a&gt;. That means rather than being in sync with the entire Playdate population (what Panic’s original “season of games” pitch implied), players will instead receive games in more or less the same cadence as the people in their preorder batch. Panic explains that this slight adjustment is due to what level of manufacturing and distribution is possible during the pandemic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="xlGUGp"&gt;Our initial dream was a fully synchronized season for every owner, but that turned out to be really really hard to do with the reality of manufacturing (the factory can only make so many a week!) and distribution (international package delivery is only so reliable!)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="OZFI1h"&gt;If Panic does decide to do a Season Two of games,  it says it should be able to pull off its original plan since many people will already own Playdates. The company also makes it clear that even though the Playdate will automatically download games, you don’t have to be committed to them. You can delete and re-download games at any time if you need to make room on your device for other homemade titles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FfUTqk"&gt;You can see our impression of the Playdate &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22587172/playdate-hands-on-preview"&gt;in our hands-on here&lt;/a&gt; and a preview of what games Panic has lined up for Season One &lt;a href="https://play.date/"&gt;on its Playdate site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R6Hgw8"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609923/playdate-handheld-crank-panic-game-season-one"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609923/playdate-handheld-crank-panic-game-season-one</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-04T16:54:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-04T16:54:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>This Flo Rida Roblox Amazon TikTok ad is fake but amazing</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Tessellated TikTok logos against a dark background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3q3Hl7JynqSdBbPkOcltMEnt-0s=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69679707/acastro_190723_1777_tiktok_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="f35lYL"&gt;On Wednesday, a surreal TikTok ad from an advertiser posing as Amazon confused users into thinking the e-commerce giant was taking a stab at including absurdist internet humor into its online marketing strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l9EsHu"&gt;The ad featured gaming footage from the lego-like title &lt;em&gt;Roblox &lt;/em&gt;interspersed with strange clips of a man dancing to Flo Rida and T-Pain’s 2008 hit “Low,” but only the part where T-Pain says “Apple Bottom jeans.” There are also robot voices bullying each other about grandmas and girlfriends overlaid on the ad. The bizarre video was highlighted by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/eddyburback/status/1422972566629543941?s=20"&gt;Eddy Burback&lt;/a&gt;, a popular YouTuber and streamer, on his Twitter feed Wednesday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TCsgIo"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;this was an amazon ad I got on tik tok???&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;this is 100% real I just recorded it &lt;a href="https://t.co/cST0JoKb33"&gt;pic.twitter.com/cST0JoKb33&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Eddy Burback (@eddyburback) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/eddyburback/status/1422972566629543941?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 4, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OiWTsT"&gt;The ad purported to be purchased by the e-commerce giant Amazon, but Amazon told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;Wednesday that the ad was fake. Amazon said that it was investigating the issue with TikTok. TikTok did not immediately respond to requests for comment by &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nUcmI8"&gt;It’s unclear how the fake ad made it onto the platform, but it appears to have been purchased by a third-party Amazon seller pretending to be the company itself. When you click the link attached to the ad, it brings you to an Amazon search results page for the key word “revealhome1.” The results include home decor and kitchen items like curtain ties and food jars. The ad could be an attempt to promote an Amazon referral code, and purchases made through the link would give the advertiser a cut of Amazon’s revenue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XJ4rSw"&gt;Last year, TikTok opened up its self-serve advertising platform to all advertisers, taking on other digital ad market competitors like Facebook and Google, &lt;a href="https://digiday.com/media/tiktoks-self-service-platform-launch-is-perfectly-timed-to-kick-facebook-while-its-down/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Digiday&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. While these self-service ad management services can create loads of revenue for companies like TikTok and Facebook, they’ve also been subject to fraud and &lt;a href="https://www.consumerreports.org/social-media/facebook-approved-ads-with-coronavirus-misinformation/"&gt;misinformation&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EtDmgq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NV0qlf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22610175/amazon-tiktok-fake-ad-flo-rida-low-roblox-apple-bottom-jeans"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22610175/amazon-tiktok-fake-ad-flo-rida-low-roblox-apple-bottom-jeans</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-04T16:49:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-04T16:49:52-04:00</updated>
    <title>NYT crossword puzzle no longer works in third-party apps, crosses puzzle solvers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Photo of a crossword puzzle being completed by a hand holding a pen. " src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Er_bTM3EJt1t4Uhc2_jPMAtKyQs=/169x0:4119x2633/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69679665/834509654.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Clive Gee - PA Images/PA Images via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lA0MmX"&gt;People will no longer be able to play the digital version of &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; daily crossword puzzle in third-party apps, according to &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/02/crosswords/nyt-games-no-longer-available-on-across-lite-as-of-aug-9.html"&gt;an announcement&lt;/a&gt; made by the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; on Monday. Starting August 10th, the crossword will be available digitally only via the &lt;em&gt;NYT&lt;/em&gt; site or on its own crossword app. Downloadable PDFs, in addition to the physical newspaper, will still be available for people who want to print and play. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TpWDze"&gt;Until now, crosswords were available in the &lt;a href="http://www.word-buff.com/across-lite.html"&gt;Across Lite .puz file format&lt;/a&gt;, so anyone with a &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; games subscription could download a puzzle and open it in the desktop or mobile app of their choice. The change applies not just to future puzzles but to the archive of puzzles that are currently in the .puz format. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xTOYDK"&gt;Everdeen Mason, editorial director of games at the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/EverdeenMason/status/1422548999018516482"&gt;said on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; that she made the decision to end .puz support in an effort to build something where editors can “edit and make games rather than adapt things for tools we can’t control.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="53XWKZ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We also need to adapt to future technologies and build a foundation we can make more things on&lt;/p&gt;— EverQueen Mason (@EverdeenMason) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/EverdeenMason/status/1422549001673584640?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 3, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yNrGi6"&gt;Some crossword solvers &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/danfeyer/status/1422348847020351498"&gt;are peeved&lt;/a&gt; about the change. &lt;a href="https://www.xwordblog.com/2021/08/02/no-more-across-lite/"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;XWord Blog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a site for crossword enthusiasts, speed solvers and people who parse .puz files for puzzle analysis will likely be hit the hardest. Some people with low vision have mentioned that the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;’ official crossword app doesn’t work well with screen readers, which will hopefully be addressed as third-party options disappear. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609944/nyt-crossword-puzzle-puz-file-format"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609944/nyt-crossword-puzzle-puz-file-format</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kait Sanchez</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-04T16:39:28-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-04T16:39:28-04:00</updated>
    <title>The best deals on true wireless earbuds right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EMA4Er2sFrxHrUuDpHfpSH0b1VM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68898291/bfarsace_201130_4322_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="USGxSy"&gt;When it comes to true wireless earbuds, there are a ton of brands and products to choose from. Whether you enjoy the unconventional design of Samsung’s Galaxy Buds Live or prefer Jabra’s compact Elite 75t, there’s a pair of wireless earbuds for just about everyone. Fortunately, many of the best wireless earbuds go on sale on a regular occurrence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AsWVXq"&gt;Regardless of which brand you prefer, we have compiled some of the best deals on wireless earbuds available right now. Of course, if you want to do more research before making a buying decision, we also encourage you to read our guide to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds"&gt;best wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt;, which can help you determine which pair of earbuds are best for you. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Apple’s second-generation AirPods" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/H4c7403UDVQ2p-JvX1pB9iSnj8U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/15993021/akrales_190327_3315_0012.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="c27rNd"&gt;Apple AirPods deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="2vr3VH"&gt;If you own an iPhone or multiple Apple products, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942472/apple-airpods-pro-review-design-price-specs-features-noise-cancellation"&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt; are likely the best true wireless earbuds on the market for you. Unlike the base AirPods, the Pro variant offer better sound quality and feature active noise cancellation, not to mention seamless integration with iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ftMREv"&gt;Apple’s flagship Pro wireless earbuds tend to go on sale frequently, and we often see them drop as low as $200. Right now, for instance, you can get a new pair for &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-Pro%2F520468661&amp;amp;subid1=VergeBestAirPodsDeals02262021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$197 at Walmart&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MWP22AM-A-AirPods-Pro/dp/B07ZPC9QD4?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kPY6Vk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="X9766m"&gt;Alternatively, you can buy a pair of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;second-generation AirPods&lt;/a&gt;, which include either a wired or wireless charging case. Although they normally retail for $160, you can get the version with the wired charging case for &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/994132/9383?subId1=VergeBestAirPods030121&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-with-Charging-Case-Latest-Model%2F604342441%3F&amp;amp;veh=aff" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$119 at Walmart&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Charging-Latest-Model/dp/B07PXGQC1Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="DcXNMK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eJgls2"&gt;If you prefer a little more convenience, you can also get a new pair of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;AirPods with a wireless charging case&lt;/a&gt; for a few dollars more. At their regular price of $200, they aren’t as good of a value, but you’ll rarely find yourself paying the usual price. At the moment, you can get them for &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-airpods-with-wireless-charging-case%2F-%2FA-54191099%3Fclkid%3D48833994N865a11eb8ae142010a246e3b%26lnm%3D81938%26afid%3DVox%2520Media%26ref%3Dtgt_adv_xasd0002%23lnk%3Dsametab&amp;amp;subid1=VergeAirPodsDeals03172021&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;$160 at Target&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Wireless-Charging-Latest/dp/B07PYLT6DN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iGBbls"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9507432"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GvE4V_5ezL8yYRQFDA0uPj1WyN8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21700189/IMG_0628_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung Galaxy Buds Live.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="HGCqrw"&gt;Samsung Galaxy Buds Deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="v5RLzc"&gt;Samsung has a few different wireless earbuds to choose from, including its latest flagship wireless earbuds, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/15/22231848/samsung-galaxy-buds-pro-review"&gt;Galaxy Buds Pro&lt;/a&gt;. These earbuds include active noise cancellation and the best sound quality yet for Samsung earbuds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pyxi2K"&gt;There are a couple of deals going on right now at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Samsung-Wireless-Cancelling-Charging-Included/dp/B08MWZHHKP?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fsamsung-galaxy-buds-pro-earbuds-black%2F-%2FA-82026965&amp;amp;sharedid=VergeTrueWirelessHeadphones042921"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, both of which are offering the Galaxy Buds Pro for $30 off, bringing the price down to $170.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WZ42v1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10401237"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="4pY4R1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best AirPods deals you can get right now ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals"},{"title":"The best deals on 4K TVs ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22371561/best-4k-tv-deals-sale-lg-samsung-sony-tcl"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="aZthMF"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/24/21147654/samsung-galaxy-buds-plus-review-wireless-earbuds-sound-quality-battery-life"&gt;Galaxy Buds Plus&lt;/a&gt; were our top pick last year for the best wireless earbuds overall. A successor to the original Galaxy Buds, the Plus model extends the battery life by up to 11 hours and, unlike AirPods, comes in an assortment of colors. Right now, you can buy the Galaxy Buds Plus for $100 at places such as &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B083KVM9VW?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1748159989908648779#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/3Pk6Pr" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, which is the lowest price we’ve seen in the last several months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="c8pRgb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10368022"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mPBmzD"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21356260/samsung-galaxy-buds-live-review-wireless-earbuds-beans-design-specs-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Galaxy Buds Live&lt;/a&gt; are some of the more unconventional wireless earbuds on the market right now, but don’t let their bean-shaped design fool you. The Buds Live are a good option if you want earbuds that produce powerful sound and showcase marathon battery life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="52C6bu"&gt;Right now, you can purchase a pair of the Galaxy Buds Live for &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1577733-REG%2Fsamsung_sm_r180nznaxar_galaxy_buds_live_noise_canceling.html%3Fap%3Dy%26smp%3Dy&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22307388%2Fwireless-earbuds-deals-airpods-galaxy-buds-powerbeats" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$130 at B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Samsung-Wireless-Cancelling-Charging-Included/dp/B089B658NP?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1748160308471290156#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, more than 10 percent off their initial MSRP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xJfsfQ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10685823"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a2Ol0J-O6sW1PwuvoXPBBDrB7Pc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/18279734/cwelch_190702_3528_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="i2Ah0B"&gt;Sony WF-1000XM3 deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="HggHzb"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22523584/sony-wf-1000xm4-wireless-earbuds-headphones-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sony’s WF-1000XM4&lt;/a&gt; are the true wireless headphones to beat, but they haven’t been discounted yet given how recently they launched. Their predecessor, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/5/20682334/sony-wf-1000xm3-wireless-earbuds-hands-on-preview-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;WF-1000XM3&lt;/a&gt;, however, remain an excellent pair of headphones that do routinely go on sale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="haWqZJ"&gt;Like the most recent model, the WF-1000XM3 feature phenomenal sound quality and considerable battery life, a small feat for a pair of true wireless earbuds. They also manage to deliver noise cancellation in a sleek, copper-adorned package, one that’s both attractive and professional. Typically $230, Sony’s last-gen WF-1000XM3 are on sale at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WF-1000XM3-Industry-Canceling-Wireless/dp/B07T81554H/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1747336499962657708#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; for $168, one of the best prices we’ve seen on the earbuds outside of Prime Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8F3h1H"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9563643"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="9wJvFX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Verge Deals on Twitter","description":"Join our 38,000 followers, and keep up with our best daily tech deals with @vergedeals","label":"Follow us!","url":"http://bit.ly/2JzR5Ud"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="1TXXf4"&gt;Other true wireless earbuds deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="58GOfq"&gt;Compared to the competition, Jabra’s wireless earbuds have a rare feature that has yet to become standard in the true wireless earbud market: the ability to connect to two devices concurrently. Ideally, this is great for users who switch between two devices often (like, say, a phone and a laptop). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vJ5wIC"&gt;Last year, Jabra released the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21549587/jabra-elite-85t-review-features-specs-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Elite 85t wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt;, which are the highest-tier model in Jabra’s lineup. They have more advanced noise cancellation than the 75t, however, they also feature less bass and an inferior fit. If you can live with those compromises, however, you can buy the Jabra Elite 85t for $180 — their second-best price to date — at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Jabra-Wireless-Bluetooth-Earbuds-Titanium/dp/B08HR78C46?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1740940140202691153" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.jabra.com/bluetooth-headsets/jabra-elite-85t?utm_medium=affiliate&amp;amp;utm_source=cj&amp;amp;utm_campaign=100084481&amp;amp;cjevent=d1b5f6f7b81f11eb80a000a90a1c0e0c#/donotlink#100-99190700-98" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jabra&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LacpUE"&gt;If the current sale price on the Elite 85t is still intimidating but you want a pair of Jabra earbuds, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/15/21066947/jabra-elite-75t-review-wireless-earbuds-airpods-alternative" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Elite 75t&lt;/a&gt; are also a good option, and they see regular price cuts. We consider the Jabra 75t — on sale in gold for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Jabra-Elite-75t-Earbuds-Comfortable/dp/B082Y256ZV/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$113 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1744674062317456142#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; — the best true wireless earbuds for multitaskers, and they remain a solid alternative if you don’t want to buy AirPods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OvElfP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10386608"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mqq7gj"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22532970/beats-studio-buds-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Beats Studio Buds&lt;/a&gt; may be the latest fitness earbuds from Apple, but if you’re currently in the market for a reliable pair of wireless earbuds for your workouts, you also can’t go wrong with their predecessor, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/10/18563329/apple-powerbeats-pro-review-wireless-fitness-headphones-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Beats Powerbeats Pro&lt;/a&gt;. These earbuds have an over-ear hook that keeps them in place while exercising; they’re also IPX4 sweat- and water-resistant, so you don’t have to worry about ruining them should your workout get intense. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aryAiB"&gt;There are a few different discounts available right now for the Powerbeats Pro. The lowest we currently see is at Walmart, where you can pick up the &lt;a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPowerbeats-Pro-Totally-Wireless-Earphones-with-Apple-H1-Headphone-Chip-Ivory%2F869400130%3Fselected%3Dtrue" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;white&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?subId1=Verge&amp;amp;veh=aff&amp;amp;sourceid=imp_000011112222333344&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPowerbeats-Pro-Totally-Wireless-Earphones-with-Apple-H1-Headphone-Chip-Black%2F587866546%3Fselected%3Dtrue" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;black models&lt;/a&gt; for $179 and $190, respectively. Walmart offers a slew of other discounted colorways, as do &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1744674259269836975#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Powerbeats-Pro-Totally-Wireless-Earphones/dp/B088KTR418/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, but most hover around $200, which is notably higher than some of the more recent sale prices we’ve seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0RcdxX"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10058925"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="11vDvx"&gt;Much like their &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/29/20937559/amazon-echo-buds-wireless-earbuds-review-features-bose-noise-reduction-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;first-gen predecessor&lt;/a&gt;, the 2021 edition of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22432633/amazon-echo-buds-2021-review-features-specs-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Echo Buds&lt;/a&gt; represent a tremendous value. Amazon’s latest true wireless earbuds offer improved comfort and better noise cancellation, along with a terrific passthrough mode that ensures you can always hear what’s going on around you. They also feature hands-free Alexa support and sound that’s remarkably satisfying, with more bass than AirPods Pro and an appropriate amount of restraint when it comes to the high end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RhZp6r"&gt;Although they normally retail for $120, the white model is now &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fecho-buds-2nd-gen-wireless-earbuds-glacier-white%2F-%2FA-82819990%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on sale at Target for $90&lt;/a&gt;, a cool 25 percent off Amazon’s typical retail price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PgPi8b"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10600144"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="de2M6w"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22307388/wireless-earbuds-deals-airpods-galaxy-buds-powerbeats"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22307388/wireless-earbuds-deals-airpods-galaxy-buds-powerbeats</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
      <name>Brandon Widder</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-04T16:12:30-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-04T16:12:30-04:00</updated>
    <title>Peloton is updating its treadmills to again be useful without a subscription</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NyU_LBGt0vL_aAlBBglCI2YXAAE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69679388/akrales_190328_3240_0031.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3wIGPL"&gt;Peloton owners will again be able to use their treadmills without a subscription to the Peloton All-Access Membership, according to the company. In June, Peloton &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/22/22545663/peloton-tread-plus-treadmill-subscription-plan-recall"&gt;released a software update&lt;/a&gt; that required its treadmills to be secured with a passcode, a feature the company said was only available to paying subscribers due to “technical limitations.” At the time, Peloton promised that another software update was coming that would enable the feature for everyone, and it provided three free months of the subscription that usually costs $40 per month. On Wednesday, the company told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that “all Tread owners can now access Tread Lock” along with the “Just Run” feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vh9rhV"&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://support.onepeloton.com/hc/en-us/articles/360060884531-Tread-Lock"&gt;Peloton’s support page&lt;/a&gt;, the Tread Lock feature locks the treadmill if you’re not in a class and haven’t used the treadmill in 45 seconds. You’ll then be required to put in your four-digit passcode before it can be used. The aforementioned June software update made using the feature mandatory, after Peloton &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22420918/peloton-treadmill-recall-tread-accidents-cpsc-voluntary-refund"&gt;recalled its treadmills&lt;/a&gt; following several reported injuries and one death. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="CgTy6B"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The company seems to have bought itself enough time to work around the “technical limitations”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8k30xx"&gt;The Tread Lock requirement essentially made the treadmills unusable without a subscription. While Peloton may be best known for its classes (which require a paid membership), the Tread Plus’ Just Run mode allowed owners to use it as a normal treadmill, no subscription required. But because Tread Lock became mandatory and using Tread Lock required a subscription, Just Run was no longer available to owners who weren’t subscribers. The company did, however, provide all owners with three free months of membership after the change, which seems to have given it enough time to make the treadmills usable again without paying the monthly fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d7PV1u"&gt;The update that created this situation served as a reminder that internet-connected devices can have their functionality changed — just because a feature was present at launch doesn’t mean it will stick around for the lifetime of the product. This case was, however, especially painful for users, as it made a subscription that was optional at the time of purchase a mandatory one (if only for a short time). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ftPdqJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Internet-connected devices are always subject to change&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gWs1vj"&gt;Because of the recall issued by Peloton, Tread Plus owners are eligible for a full refund if they choose to return their treadmills by November 6th, 2022, &lt;a href="https://cpsc.gov/Recalls/2021/peloton-recalls-tread-plus-treadmills-after-one-child-died-and-more-than-70-incidents"&gt;according to the Consumer Product Safety Commission&lt;/a&gt;. Those who choose to keep their Pelotons, though, should again have the choice to subscribe.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609744/peloton-update-tread-plus-treadmill-lock-subscription"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609744/peloton-update-tread-plus-treadmill-lock-subscription</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-04T15:58:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-04T15:58:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>TikTok is testing a Snapchat-style stories feature</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jQPcejj7efOkQi9qpOxk77NbpqU=/0x44:1230x864/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69679298/Screen_Shot_2021_08_04_at_3.30.01_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/MattNavarra/status/1422994358400389123" target="_blank"&gt;Matt Navara / Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DOSnVJ"&gt;On a long enough timeline, every social media app &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22577166/twitter-fleets-shuts-down-stories-clone"&gt;trends to adding stories&lt;/a&gt;, and now it’s apparently TikTok’s turn: the popular video app is experimenting with a new stories feature. The feature was highlighted by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MattNavarra/status/1422994358400389123"&gt;Matt Navarra on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, and a TikTok spokesperson confirmed the test in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SkEGVg"&gt;The new feature, simply called “TikTok Stories,” appears to work similarly to other stories functions on apps like Instagram or Snapchat. Stories live in a newly added slide-over sidebar, where you’ll be able to see stories posted by accounts that you follow on TikTok for 24 hours before they’re automatically deleted. Other users will be able to react and comment on your story, too. And just like on Instagram and other platforms, you’ll also be able to tap on a user’s profile picture to load a story. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DWfifZ"&gt;TikTok describes the feature in the app as “a new way to interact with your fans.” Users can create a new story by tapping a “create” button that’s been added to the sidebar, and they can add the usual captions, music, and text. True to TikTok’s video-first nature, it seems stories have to be videos, not still images. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="or2iV1"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="da" dir="ltr"&gt;Introducing TikTok Stories ✨ &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Plot twist!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;h/t &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/amanfirdaus?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@amanfirdaus&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/gvQMzixYtS"&gt;pic.twitter.com/gvQMzixYtS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Matt Navarra (@MattNavarra) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MattNavarra/status/1422994358400389123?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 4, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="raGn1q"&gt;“We’re always thinking about new ways to bring value to our community and enrich the TikTok experience,” a TikTok spokesperson wrote in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Currently we’re experimenting with ways to give creators additional formats to bring their creative ideas to life for the TikTok community.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ws6DqP"&gt;The company didn’t provide any details on how extensively it’s testing TikTok Stories, nor when (or even if) it’ll see a wider release. However, a quick search on Twitter reveals a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/InahEvans/status/1422675950471245824"&gt;number of TikTok users&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/beaupcy/status/1422795441083543557"&gt;who have already gotten access&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SabriKolod/status/1422996011803365380/photo/2"&gt;to the feature&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iuajvM"&gt;The fact that TikTok would experiment with stories isn’t surprising. Stories have been one of the &lt;a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/will-now-have-stories"&gt;only true constants&lt;/a&gt; in social media, with platforms from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/8/2/12348354/instagram-stories-announced-snapchat-kevin-systrom-interview"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/28/15081398/facebook-stories-snapchat-camera-direct"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/27/21156247/linkedin-testing-instagram-stories-feature-social-network-resumes-why"&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/26/22249152/pinterest-story-pins-carousel-home-screen-update"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/19/17255966/netflix-30-second-video-previews-mobile"&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/29/18117670/youtube-stories-creators-subscribers-instagram-philip-defranco"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/16/22537243/microsoft-xbox-app-stories-feature"&gt;Xbox app&lt;/a&gt; replicating &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/10/3/4791934/snapchats-next-big-thing-stories-that-dont-just-disappear"&gt;Snapchat’s original feature&lt;/a&gt; from 2013. When they work, stories are a great way to get users to interact with each other on an app, offer a new place for ads, and generally keep the feedback loop of a social media app in motion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LWqTRg"&gt;Stories aren’t always successful, however: just ask Twitter, which was forced to shutter its own stories clone — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/14/22577166/twitter-fleets-shuts-down-stories-clone"&gt;the creatively named Fleets&lt;/a&gt; — earlier this week, just eight months after it launched them, due to a general apathy toward the feature. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22610011/tiktok-stories-snapchat-feature-social-media"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22610011/tiktok-stories-snapchat-feature-social-media</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-04T15:28:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-04T15:28:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon’s new MMO delayed for the fourth time, but this time by just one month</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nw38Cg5KdRRvtrRYbAU1qwDLcPk=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69679135/ss23.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A screenshot from Amazon’s &lt;/em&gt;New World&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Amazon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="d5FWQt"&gt;Amazon Games has delayed &lt;em&gt;New World&lt;/em&gt;, its upcoming MMO, from August 31st to September 28th, the studio announced on Wednesday. The delay — the game’s fourth —  comes shortly after the end of &lt;a href="https://www.newworld.com/en-us/news/articles/new-world-closed-beta"&gt;a closed beta&lt;/a&gt;, which wrapped up on August 3rd at 2:59AM ET.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G2d0l2"&gt;The team will be “making some improvements” based on what players found in the beta, taking time to “smash bugs, improve stability, and polish the game,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/playnewworld/status/1422969580394319877"&gt;according to a post on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4cZDRe"&gt;“This was not an easy decision to make,” the team said. “We know this isn’t the first time we’ve changed our launch date in pursuit of quality, and that it can be disappointing to wait a bit longer. But we want to be sure we deliver you the highest quality game possible at launch.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4NwR4S"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;A message from the New World team. &lt;a href="https://t.co/oAZdK7dxTn"&gt;pic.twitter.com/oAZdK7dxTn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— New World (@playnewworld) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/playnewworld/status/1422969580394319877?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 4, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AUG2BN"&gt;&lt;em&gt;New World&lt;/em&gt; was first set to release in &lt;a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/history-and-magic-collide-in-mmo-new-world-releasing-may-2020/"&gt;May 2020&lt;/a&gt;, then was &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2020-04-09-amazon-delays-launch-of-mmo-new-world-to-august-due-to-coronavirus"&gt;delayed to August 25th, 2020&lt;/a&gt;, then &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/10/21320325/amazon-new-world-delayed-spring-2021-crucible"&gt;to spring 2021&lt;/a&gt;, then &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22285810/new-world-amazon-delay-august-2021-release-date"&gt;to August 31st&lt;/a&gt;, and now the new September 28th date. And the game hasn’t been the only Amazon Games title with a bumpy history. Hero shooter &lt;em&gt;Crucible &lt;/em&gt;went &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/5/21246923/amazon-crucible-relentless-studio-free-to-play-launch-date-may-20"&gt;from launch&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/30/21308638/amazon-game-studios-crucible-closed-beta-failure-relentless-studio"&gt;to closed beta&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/9/21510190/amazon-crucible-canceled-game-studios-closed-beta"&gt;to eventually being canceled&lt;/a&gt; across the span of a few months in 2020. &lt;em&gt;Breakaway&lt;/em&gt;, a competitive fantasy brawler, was announced in 2016 &lt;a href="https://www.polygon.com/2018/4/2/17187836/amazon-game-studios-breakaway-status-canceled"&gt;but was canceled in 2018&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Pac-Man Live Studio&lt;/em&gt;, a version of &lt;em&gt;Pac-Man&lt;/em&gt; designed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/22/21266881/pac-man-live-studio-playable-on-twitch-june"&gt;to be played right on Twitch&lt;/a&gt; and developed in partnership with Bandai Namco, was announced in May 2020 for a June 2020 release, but the game still isn’t out yet and isn’t listed on Amazon Games’ website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qJafy3"&gt;Bandai Namco told me &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/17/22440891/amazon-games-pac-man-live-studio-twitch-bandai-namco"&gt;in May&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;em&gt;Pac-Man Live Studio&lt;/em&gt; “is not quite ready to launch yet” and that it was working to determine a release date. I happened to ask this week if there was any update, but the company said it still does not have any news to share.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609898/new-world-mmo-amazon-delayed-release-launch-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609898/new-world-mmo-amazon-delayed-release-launch-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-04T15:09:47-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-04T15:09:47-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook can project your eyes onto a VR headset, and it’s exactly as uncanny as it sounds</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Facebook’s prototype for “reverse passthrough VR,” a system for creating the illusion of eye contact while wearing a VR headset." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/16XI0TT2ThWtjkxYNUUxSN4J5W0=/96x0:1104x672/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69679043/Reverse_passthrough_VR_hero_image.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Facebook Reality Labs&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CeYFOQ"&gt;Facebook Reality Labs wants to help people see your eyes while you’re in virtual reality — even if the results sit somewhere between mildly unsettling and nightmarish. Earlier this week, FRL released a paper &lt;a href="https://research.fb.com/publications/reverse-pass-through-vr/"&gt;on “reverse passthrough VR,”&lt;/a&gt; a recipe for making VR headsets less physically isolating. Researchers devised a method for translating your face onto the front of a headset, although they emphasize it’s still firmly experimental.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hBzfou"&gt;“Passthrough VR” refers to a feature that displays a live video feed from a headset’s cameras, letting users see the real world while they’re still wearing the device. Facebook’s Oculus Quest platform, for instance, shows users a passthrough feed when they step outside their VR space’s boundaries. It’s useful for quickly dropping out of VR, and it can also enable a form of augmented reality by adding virtual objects to the camera feed. But as FRL notes, the people around a headset user can’t make eye contact, even if the wearer can see them perfectly. That’s awkward if bystanders are used to seeing their friend or co-worker’s uncovered face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yra8cy"&gt;FRL scientist Nathan Matsuda decided to change this. &lt;a href="https://research.fb.com/blog/2021/08/display-systems-research-reverse-passthrough-vr/"&gt;A blog post explains&lt;/a&gt; that Matsuda started in 2019, when he mounted a 3D display onto an Oculus Rift S headset. The screen displayed a virtual rendering of his upper face, and custom-rigged eye-tracking cameras captured where Matsuda was looking, so his avatar’s eyes could point in the same direction. The result was basically Matsuda wearing a telepresence tablet showing a copy of his own face — which is arguably just as awkward but with a more intriguingly postmodern twist.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="FRL scientist Nathan Matsuda wearing a custom Oculus Rift S headset fitted with a flat 3D display on the front, displaying his upper face." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q47OoHzgIORQKPH4-MjNX-SnyqY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22761139/Image_1_v2.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A prototype of Facebook’s reverse passthrough system.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="yaO5hF"&gt;According to the blog post, FRL chief scientist Michael Abrash — quite understandably — didn’t find the idea very practical. “My first reaction was that it was kind of a goofy idea, a novelty at best,” he notes. “But I don’t tell researchers what to do, because you don’t get innovation without freedom to try new things.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TmZzam"&gt;Matsuda ran with the concept, and over the next two years, he led a team in developing a svelter design. The team’s prototype headset — which it revealed ahead of next week’s SIGGRAPH conference — adds a stack of lenses and cameras to a standard VR headset display. The stereo cameras capture an image of the face and eyes inside the headset, and their motion is mapped onto a digital model of the face. Then, the image is projected onto an outward-facing light field display. That display creates the illusion of looking through the lenses of thick goggles and seeing a pair of eyes, although in reality you’re still seeing a real-time animated copy. If the wearer jumps back into full VR, the display can go blank to signal that they’re no longer engaging with the outside world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Q1nCrA"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Facademics%2Fvideos%2F200861371993198%2F&amp;amp;show_text=0&amp;amp;width=560" width="560" height="210" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8vlPDc"&gt;The result is a pair of octagonal goggles that would look right at home in a Terry Gilliam film. FRL used a simple rendering of a virtual face, but it also showed off the system with its more realistic Codec Avatars, as seen below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="oaJylV"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Facademics%2Fvideos%2F526686541937428%2F&amp;amp;show_text=0&amp;amp;width=560" width="560" height="315" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DuI0sD"&gt;FRL acknowledges that the system’s individual components aren’t all revolutionary. HTC already has a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323093/htc-vive-pro-vr-facial-lip-tracker-third-gen-tracker-announcement-price"&gt;face tracking add-on&lt;/a&gt; for its Vive Pro headsets; it maps movement onto an avatar inside VR, not an outward-facing screen, but the principle is similar. This week’s paper focuses on the potential of light field displays and the system’s opportunities for better in-person social interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kWBxUi"&gt;HoloLens-style projection glasses theoretically leave your face much clearer than passthrough displays — although a lot of those glasses have darkened lenses, and &lt;a href="https://www.roadtovr.com/facebook-reality-labs-research-reverse-passthrough-prototype/"&gt;as &lt;em&gt;Road to VR &lt;/em&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt;, projected light on clear lenses can also block your gaze. But as companies like Apple &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/19/21296674/apple-vr-ar-headset-glasses-external-hub-jony-ive-bloomberg-go-read-this"&gt;reportedly experiment with&lt;/a&gt; passthrough designs, Facebook’s new research shows that solid screen isn’t necessarily a barrier to eye contact... of a sort.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609564/facebook-reality-lab-reverse-passthrough-vr-prototype-research-siggraph"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609564/facebook-reality-lab-reverse-passthrough-vr-prototype-research-siggraph</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-04T15:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-04T15:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>HBO Max is getting its own exclusive podcasts, starting with Batman</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="“Westworld” Comic Con Panel 2019" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/31DF5gI0BTUb-rB5Uowcb7GR-YY=/0x183:3000x2183/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69678957/1163281017.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Jeff Kravitz/FilmMagic for HBO&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HyqVVO"&gt;The HBO Max team wants its app to not just be the place people find big movie premieres but podcasts, too. The company announced today that it’s planning to release its new Batman podcast, &lt;em&gt;Batman: The Audio Adventures&lt;/em&gt;, as an in-app exclusive, meaning it won’t make its way to other podcasting apps or be available through an RSS feed. The scripted show, which features Jeffrey Wright as Batman and Rosario Dawson as Batwoman, will premiere this fall, although no exact date was provided.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FIxBQH"&gt;In a chat with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, Joshua Walker, chief strategy officer at HBO Max, says the decision to make &lt;em&gt;Batman: The Audio Adventures &lt;/em&gt;exclusive has to do with the show being a scripted original series. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oHtu5O"&gt;“For scripted originals our working theory now is that they should sit aside our other scripted original content exclusively within the HBO Max environment,” Walker says. “But because we’re early days on scripted original audio content we do look at this as something that we’ll learn from, and we’ll see how it develops over time as we go from here.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ynSKr6"&gt;The show won’t include ads and will be part of HBO Max subscribers’ included content. (It won’t cost extra to access the audio.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ELFt34"&gt;Along with that news, HBO also announced other new, forthcoming podcasts including a scripted sequel to Issa Rae’s &lt;em&gt;Looking For Latoya&lt;/em&gt;, called &lt;em&gt;We Stay Looking&lt;/em&gt;, as well as a new &lt;em&gt;OC&lt;/em&gt; companion podcast called &lt;em&gt;Welcome to The OC, Bitches&lt;/em&gt;. Both of these will be available on HBO Max, with Walker declining to say definitively whether &lt;em&gt;Looking For LaToya&lt;/em&gt; would be an exclusive or not, given that it’s a scripted original show. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="YEDfTG"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s just unclear if anyone wants to listen to their podcasts on HBO Max&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2HejtD"&gt;HBO is trying to turn its app into a destination for audio, as well as video, but making HBO Max the only place for &lt;em&gt;Batman: The Audio Adventures &lt;/em&gt;is an interesting gamble. The app in its current form is clearly designed for video functionality, and right now, listening to a podcast in the app, like the &lt;em&gt;Chernobyl&lt;/em&gt; companion show, requires users to search for it manually — there’s no dedicated podcast landing page. Also, locking your phone shuts off the podcast, and when open, the video player just keeps a static image on-screen advertising the ability to listen to the show on other podcast apps. It’s clearly not a fully built-out podcast experience. The team says it plans to allow for locked phone listening at some point, but didn’t commit to a date when that rollout might happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K02S4W"&gt;Still, the strategy behind the exclusivity decision appears to be trying to leverage valuable IP and star power to draw more people to the HBO Max app. It’s just unclear if anyone wants  to listen to their podcasts there, especially if the experience isn’t comparable to actual podcasting apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mlm9bJ"&gt;At the same time, it’s easy to see why HBO wants to double down on audio. Its competitors, namely Netflix, have also become more invested in a more robust podcasting strategy. Netflix &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-07-08/netflix-hires-ex-apple-executive-to-lead-podcasting-operations?utm_source=google&amp;amp;utm_medium=bd&amp;amp;cmpId=google&amp;amp;sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;hired&lt;/a&gt; its first podcast executive, N’Jeri Eaton, previously of Apple Podcasts, last month and uses podcasting as a marketing tool to encourage more people to come to its video app and subscribe. The podcasts are available everywhere, though, presumably to reach people who aren’t already in the Netflix ecosystem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8boPKE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609212/hbo-max-podcast-exclusive-batman-audio-jeffrey-wright"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609212/hbo-max-podcast-exclusive-batman-audio-jeffrey-wright</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
