<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2022-01-24T15:06:42-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T15:06:42-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T15:06:42-05:00</updated>
    <title>TikTok is feeling emotional damage over the market crash</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Tessellated TikTok logos against a dark background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aJt13Yw7D0SpyAQw8i5uLAT4fok=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70426891/acastro_190723_1777_tiktok_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kZXUp3"&gt;My TikTok For You page is generally a wonderland of soothing cooking videos, lesbian carpentry, dieticians frothing at the mouth at fitness scams, and whatever it is &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@yoleendadong?lang=en"&gt;@yoleendadong&lt;/a&gt; is up to. But every so often, my FYP will land me in FinanceTok and CryptoTok. And buddy, I do not think everyone there is OK. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UA23Ok"&gt;I’ve never turned down a chance to leap down the TikTok rabbit hole, and perusing the #marketcrash2022 and #cryptocrash2022 tags is truly tragic. There’s &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/foryou?amp%3Bis_from_webapp=v1&amp;amp;amp%3Blang=en&amp;amp;amp%3Bq=stock%20market%20crash%202022&amp;amp;amp%3Bt=1643043336608&amp;amp;is_copy_url=1&amp;amp;is_from_webapp=v1&amp;amp;item_id=7055695869743467823#/@lamafole2/video/7055695869743467823"&gt;this baby&lt;/a&gt; going through a rollercoaster of emotions watching stocks go up and down. There’s also this grown adult man &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@market_moves/video/7055037785132240175?_d=secCgYIASAHKAESPgo8tzApyaJisKgrLs2oWjQ7aPT7OOzNmlX%2BguuBi1346pSwV9vzQs2ErtxXk8YenuHYm0n%2BVerAP17DNQhwGgA%3D&amp;amp;checksum=85a9018a6a1f3c8651a680360e48a9ee6370967c230d5fe11ecc76f785b48eb5&amp;amp;language=en&amp;amp;preview_pb=0&amp;amp;sec_user_id=MS4wLjABAAAA-g6EtWefuLvM-Iw7GeZ9YqcbXkX0GvOYNInEH77mgv_N28jxqV6yfWtQ_hRxTnJK&amp;amp;share_app_id=1233&amp;amp;share_item_id=7055037785132240175&amp;amp;share_link_id=667327A8-509F-4FA0-BA17-A49DFA0FA1D4&amp;amp;source=h5_m&amp;amp;timestamp=1643042272&amp;amp;tt_from=copy&amp;amp;u_code=d3eib1bcahliii&amp;amp;user_id=6632321522571935749&amp;amp;utm_campaign=client_share&amp;amp;utm_medium=ios&amp;amp;utm_source=copy&amp;amp;_r=1"&gt;doing the same thing&lt;/a&gt;, set to the Emotional Damage vs. Pompeii by William Li sound. Actually, it seems like a lot of &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@j0nasr_/video/7056040047933443333?is_copy_url=1&amp;amp;is_from_webapp=v1&amp;amp;q=market%20crash%202022&amp;amp;t=1643044079639"&gt;grown men&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@hustlewithuli/video/7056339694291782914?is_copy_url=1&amp;amp;is_from_webapp=v1&amp;amp;lang=en&amp;amp;q=market%20crash%202022&amp;amp;t=1643043811510"&gt;are&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@online_income_streams/video/7056046432410668294?is_copy_url=1&amp;amp;is_from_webapp=v1&amp;amp;q=market%20crash%202022&amp;amp;t=1643044079639"&gt;crying&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@itscashflow/video/7056039826751032582?is_copy_url=1&amp;amp;is_from_webapp=v1&amp;amp;q=market%20crash%202022&amp;amp;t=1643044079639"&gt;about their&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@cryptobound/video/7056411862644215086?is_copy_url=1&amp;amp;is_from_webapp=v1&amp;amp;q=crypto%20crash%202022&amp;amp;t=1643044421695"&gt;cryptocurrency&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@doge2m00n/video/7051732911904574725?is_copy_url=1&amp;amp;is_from_webapp=v1&amp;amp;q=market%20crash%202022&amp;amp;t=1643051289291"&gt;and investment&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@master23mind/video/7055841071619837230?is_copy_url=1&amp;amp;is_from_webapp=v1&amp;amp;q=crypto%20crash%202022&amp;amp;t=1643044421695"&gt;portfolios&lt;/a&gt; tanking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gpDPpj"&gt;Those are just the tip of the iceberg. FinanceTok is a menagerie of self-proclaimed money experts telling you which stocks to buy and sell. It seems they’ve all read &lt;em&gt;Rich Dad Poor Dad&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;I Will Teach You to Be Rich &lt;/em&gt;but come to very different conclusions about what the lessons ought to be. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="cr2hxy"&gt;&lt;q&gt;But once a crash actually happens, so do new types of videos&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CwLVZO"&gt;But once a crash actually happens, so do new types of videos. There are the self-satisfied creators who &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@cloud9.crypto/video/7055711262109404418?is_copy_url=1&amp;amp;is_from_webapp=v1&amp;amp;q=crypto%20crash%202022&amp;amp;t=1643046535014"&gt;called the crash several months ago&lt;/a&gt; and are using that as clout so you’ll “hit plus for more.” Then there are the &lt;a href="https://vm.tiktok.com/TTPdhLQgg1/"&gt;smug creators&lt;/a&gt; opining about why they’re “not worried about the crash” because “historically markets always rise after a crash.” An absurd number are obsessed with that &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@studentloanmillionaire/video/7056766134342667525?is_copy_url=1&amp;amp;is_from_webapp=v1&amp;amp;q=crypto%20crash%202022%20fearful%20greedy&amp;amp;t=1643046158131"&gt;one&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@victor_patino11/video/7055512940711005486?is_copy_url=1&amp;amp;is_from_webapp=v1&amp;amp;q=fearful%20greedy%20waren%20buffet&amp;amp;t=1643046272366"&gt;Warren&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@realcryptooverkill/video/7052011707979369775?is_copy_url=1&amp;amp;is_from_webapp=v1&amp;amp;q=fearful%20greedy%20waren%20buffet&amp;amp;t=1643046272366"&gt;Buffet&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@newmoneyclips/video/7055215462124244229?is_copy_url=1&amp;amp;is_from_webapp=v1&amp;amp;q=marketcrash%202022&amp;amp;t=1643046350648"&gt;quote&lt;/a&gt;, “Be fearful when others are greedy, and greedy when others are fearful.” It’s used to justify either &lt;a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2017/12/meaning-of-hodl-and-btfd-bitcoin-terms-defined.html"&gt;HODLing&lt;/a&gt; (that is, continuing to hold) or going on a crypto buying spree when the market is down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hmBzsC"&gt;Meanwhile, a TikTok astrologer who &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/06/13/maren-altman-tiktok-astrology-bitcoin/"&gt;pivoted to cryptocurrency&lt;/a&gt; has over a million followers. One of her latest YouTube videos, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RjslGHW3TKE"&gt;a 22-minute&lt;/a&gt; clip about how Pluto returning to the US’s second house of finance hints at economic malaise (and a good time to invest in crypto), has more than 36,000 views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VhgBRO"&gt;Even the real estate TikTokkers are joining in, &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@inthisjennaration/video/7049912573029944622?is_copy_url=1&amp;amp;is_from_webapp=v1&amp;amp;q=market%20crash%202022&amp;amp;t=1643046768211"&gt;sighing at the discourse&lt;/a&gt; about whether this is exactly like 2008. Others are keen to explain why or why not a housing crash is also on &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@reitv_/video/7019771127497067782?is_copy_url=1&amp;amp;is_from_webapp=v1&amp;amp;q=market%20crash%202022&amp;amp;t=1643046768211"&gt;the way&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@mrjebsmith/video/7049877566286630190?is_copy_url=1&amp;amp;is_from_webapp=v1&amp;amp;q=market%20crash%202022&amp;amp;t=1643046768211"&gt;because the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@sam_jarman/video/7051678632372194607?is_copy_url=1&amp;amp;is_from_webapp=v1&amp;amp;q=real%20estate%202022&amp;amp;t=1643046674094"&gt;Fed is going&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@gavinjlarnard/video/7046560694598143278?is_copy_url=1&amp;amp;is_from_webapp=v1&amp;amp;q=market%20crash%202022&amp;amp;t=1643046768211"&gt;raise&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@the_genz_realtor/video/7054670122849586478?is_copy_url=1&amp;amp;is_from_webapp=v1&amp;amp;q=market%20crash%202022&amp;amp;t=1643046768211"&gt;interest rates&lt;/a&gt;. It all sounds plausible when you see it on TikTok. Housing markets usually cool off when interest rates go up — and the Fed plans on raising interest rates this year — but there are usually &lt;a href="https://www.investopedia.com/articles/07/housing_bubble.asp"&gt;way more factors&lt;/a&gt; that go into housing busts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EUsJiw"&gt;If you’re trying to find an idea of who in these videos is worth trusting — I recommend closing the TikTok app and sticking your head out the window for some fresh air. Finance is labyrinthine. Entertaining snippets on TikTok and other social media are digestible. Occasionally, you scroll away knowing something you didn’t beforehand. But as confusing as investing can be, going off “advice” you saw on TikTok (or r/wallstreetbets) might not be the best idea. That’s how that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22251427/reddit-gamestop-stock-short-wallstreetbets-robinhood-wall-street"&gt;GameStop chaos&lt;/a&gt; happened. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pGlVNA"&gt;It’s all good fun, but some of us are actually using these platforms for investing advice. Just as influencers and social media helped drive the market up, it’s possible they can also inadvertently shepherd it in the other direction. Sure, many influencers are urging us to HODL and see slumping prices as an opportunity. But it only takes a few scared folks in an echo chamber to spark panic selling. This is how memes end up in the back of people’s minds as they make real-life decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OVAZ08"&gt;Stocks can go up or down, but FinanceTok has just made an important discovery: markets going up&lt;em&gt; or &lt;/em&gt;down provide good fodder for the content mill. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IY0yUj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZwxE30"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wjAwPB"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899098/tiktok-market-crash-social-media-investing"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899098/tiktok-market-crash-social-media-investing</id>
    <author>
      <name>Victoria Song</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T14:58:05-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T14:58:05-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter suspends Wordle-ruining bot</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EdX8yAbYICN_dd1xar17w0mXygg=/89x0:1265x784/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70426860/Screen_Shot_2022_01_24_at_10.33.22.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wordlinator account tweeted rude messages with spoilers at people posting results.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Abv3Um"&gt;Twitter has banned @wordlinator, a bot that replied to people’s Wordle posts with rude messages that include spoilers for the next day’s game. The account’s spoilers appeared to be accurate (the key is easily accessible in the game’s code, so it’s not necessarily a surprise), which could end up ruining the game for anyone who sees them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tiKeZV"&gt;For anyone who’s managed to avoid it, Wordle is a game where you get six chances to guess a five-letter word — if you’re interested, you can &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22892044/wordle-free-game-online-how-to-puzzle"&gt;learn how to play it here&lt;/a&gt;. The answer is the same for everyone playing, and it only changes once a day. The game also has an interesting sharing mechanic, where you can copy and paste a series of emoji to let people know how easy or hard it was for you to guess the word of the day. If you’ve seen a ton of yellow, gray, and green squares on Twitter, they’re probably either Wordle results or a joke about Wordle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PoQtqn"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Note: if you like tweeting your wordIe scores, someone’s made a bot you should block as it auto-responds with tomorrows answer &lt;a href="https://t.co/u62kBaTivn"&gt;pic.twitter.com/u62kBaTivn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— dan nguyen (@dancow) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dancow/status/1485660308622528513?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 24, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cxqjWV"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The bot wasn’t well-received by Wordle fans.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GF0r0D"&gt;Given that the game is about guessing a word, knowing what the next one will be can ruin the entire point. It’s also one of those things that’s almost impossible to put out of your head — when you’ve seen what the next word is, you probably won’t be able to forget it no matter how hard you try. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Spxb8W"&gt;While this particular bot is gone, Twitter could become a dangerous place for people who want to post their Wordle results — the internet has already figured out &lt;a href="https://reichel.dev/blog/reverse-engineering-wordle.html"&gt;how to predict what the next word will be&lt;/a&gt;, and someone else could make another bot to do the same thing as Wordlinator. (If you do end up seeing a new version of the bot, it’s best to block it to keep it from spoiling you and your followers.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="oi2QzT"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The Wordle code has already been cracked&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7q7QOy"&gt;Before Wordlinator was banned, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; reached out to Twitter to ask if it was in violation of the platform’s rules. The company didn’t immediately reply, but the bot seemed to break at least one of the standards laid out on &lt;a href="https://help.twitter.com/en/rules-and-policies/twitter-automation"&gt;Twitter’s Automation Rules page&lt;/a&gt;. Under the word “Don’t!” it lists “spam or bother users, or otherwise send them unsolicited messages.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3I9Ldg"&gt;If you’re tired of seeing Wordle tweets and want to know how to mute them, we’ve &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22878708/twitter-mute-tweets-word-name-tag-how-to"&gt;got a how-to for that as well&lt;/a&gt;. I recommend taking that route over trying to make people feel bad for enjoying things.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899339/wordle-twitter-spoilers-banned-word-puzzle-answers"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899339/wordle-twitter-spoilers-banned-word-puzzle-answers</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T14:47:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T14:47:47-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google could bring the fight to Roku and Amazon with an even cheaper Chromecast</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/06B6rCXbQAgQ3Ap_JlhOHso9hq8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70426801/DSCF2108.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EHELU6"&gt;Google is working on a lower-end Chromecast with Google TV that would slot in below its current model in price — and also video resolution. According to &lt;a href="https://www.protocol.com/entertainment/google-chromecast-hd-boreal-1080p"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Protocol’s&lt;/em&gt; Janko Roettgers&lt;/a&gt;, the upcoming, cheaper Chromecast will run the same Google TV software as the existing hardware and will still include a remote control. But it will be limited to a maximum of 1080p video quality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CRwOB1"&gt;Playing to that limitation, &lt;em&gt;Protocol&lt;/em&gt; believes Google might market the device as “Chromecast HD with Google TV,” similar to the branding of Apple’s Apple TV HD. The product would be marketed towards consumers with 1080p TVs who don’t necessarily care about having the very best picture quality. Other specs mentioned in the report include a maximum of 2GB RAM and 60fps frame rate and confirmation that the hardware would be capable of decoding Google’s preferred AV1 codec.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xHBWCG"&gt;With the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21495609/google-chromecast-2020-review-streaming-remote-control"&gt;2020 Chromecast with Google TV&lt;/a&gt; priced at $49.99, potential price points for the HD version could range anywhere from $19.99 to $39.99. The entry-level streaming hardware market is fiercely competitive, with multiple models to choose between from Amazon and Roku alone; clearly, Google wants in on that pool of potential customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T8lDhu"&gt;The only thing that would give me pause about a lower-end Chromecast with Google TV would be performance. The current model can already get bogged down from time to time, so, hopefully, Google can deliver a device that sacrifices resolution without ruining the day-to-day experience of browsing streaming recommendations and apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ktfzVd"&gt;This new Chromecast HD with Google TV would likely replace the aging, older-generation Chromecast that Google &lt;a href="https://store.google.com/product/chromecast?hl=en-US"&gt;continues to sell&lt;/a&gt; for $29.99 — despite it coming without any built-in entertainment apps or a remote. Like its predecessors, the standard Chromecast relies on users to stream content from another device like their smartphone or PC to the HDMI dongle. Google TV is a much simpler approach that offers a vast app store, voice search, Google Assistant integration, and more. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899441/chromecast-hd-google-tv-rumor-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899441/chromecast-hd-google-tv-rumor-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T14:36:09-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T14:36:09-05:00</updated>
    <title>It’s 2022, and the Surface Duo is finally getting Android 11 </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nMessnesE1lF-i5Ll_UiG-dAeOI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70426723/vpavic_4176_20200905_0142.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Surface Duo is getting Android 11 at last.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="a5fKdZ"&gt;At the beginning of this month, my colleague Monica Chin published an article with the headline “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/1/22862649/microsoft-surface-duo-android-11-missed-update"&gt;It’s 2022, and the Surface Duo still doesn’t have Android 11&lt;/a&gt;,” pointing out that Microsoft hadn’t brought Android 11 to the dual-screen phone despite &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/23/22690003/microsoft-surface-duo-android-11-update-release-date"&gt;having said in September&lt;/a&gt; that it was working on delivering the by the end of 2021. That’s finally changing, as Microsoft has begun to roll out Android 11 for unlocked Surface Duos in North America and Europe, &lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2022/01/24/surface-duo-android-11-ota/"&gt;as reported by &lt;em&gt;9to5Google&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e3WUrd"&gt;Not every Surface Duo will be getting the update right away; if you have a Surface Duo that’s tied to AT&amp;amp;T, it sounds like you’re going to have to wait just a bit longer. “For locked or unlocked AT&amp;amp;T Surface Duos, we are testing this release and it is pending final validation,” according to &lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/surface/surface-duo-update-history-fe857377-c3ae-12f6-98e9-32982b5665f1"&gt;Microsoft’s page about the update&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VpTWVW"&gt;Now, the wait begins for Android 12 — which still hasn’t arrived on the Surface Duo 2. However, &lt;a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/microsoft-fails-deliver-android-11-surface-duo-end-2021"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Windows Central&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Microsoft apparently plans to bring Android 12L, which is designed to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22824287/google-android-12-beta-1-release-large-screen-devices-tablet-pixel"&gt;improve the Android 12 experience on bigger screens&lt;/a&gt;, to Surface Duo devices at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899348/microsoft-surface-duo-android-11"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899348/microsoft-surface-duo-android-11</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T14:24:42-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T14:24:42-05:00</updated>
    <title>NASA’s revolutionary James Webb Space Telescope reaches final orbit in space</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9Th29BuWF7nJLQiMNgVYQaHDiGc=/0x59:1060x766/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70426687/webb_artists_conception.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="d8Kd2l"&gt;After traveling hundreds of thousands of miles through space over the last month, NASA’s revolutionary new James Webb Space Telescope &lt;a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/webb/2022/01/24/orbital-insertion-burn-a-success-webb-arrives-at-l2/"&gt;performed its last big course correction maneuver&lt;/a&gt; this afternoon, putting itself into its final resting place in space. Now, the observatory will live in perpetuity at a distance of roughly 1 million miles from the Earth, giving the vehicle a front-row view of the most ancient stars and galaxies of the Universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jJnvM2"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/25/22850167/james-webb-space-telescope-jwst-launch-mission-success"&gt;Launched on Christmas Day&lt;/a&gt;, NASA’s James Webb Space Telescope, or JWST, has had a wild ride to its destination. Too enormous to fly to space in its final form, the telescope had to launch folded up inside its rocket. Once it reached space, JWST began an extremely complex routine of shape-shifting and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/4/22857571/nasa-jwst-space-telescope-sunshield-deployment-success"&gt;unfurling&lt;/a&gt;, a type of choreography that no spacecraft had ever performed before. Yet JWST performed every step flawlessly, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/8/22873592/james-webb-telescope-final-mirror-deployment-conclusion"&gt;completing its major deployments on January 8th&lt;/a&gt; and blossoming into its full configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="opfX0v"&gt;&lt;q&gt;live in perpetuity at roughly 1 million miles from the Earth&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hGKC4k"&gt;Plenty of anxiety surrounded those deployments, as they &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; to work as planned; one failure could have jeopardized JWST’s entire mission. But the mission team’s unease didn’t end when unfurling was complete. JWST still had to get into its final position in space in order to do its job properly. If the observatory didn’t slow down just right today, the vehicle ran the risk of getting into the wrong orbit or missing its target trajectory completely. Such a failure could have complicated the mission’s future, making it incredibly difficult for scientists to communicate with the nearly $10 billion space observatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jSFfty"&gt;Fortunately, JWST performed this last maneuver flawlessly. “During the past month, JWST has achieved amazing success and is a tribute to all the folks who spent many years and even decades to ensure mission success,” Bill Ochs, the JWST project manager at NASA’s Goddard Space Flight Center, said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="IfdppA"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6cUe4oMk69E?rel=0&amp;amp;list=TLGG8tIphgpDAHkyNDAxMjAyMg" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zpYFeZ"&gt;Though it’s been a month getting to this point, it didn’t take long for JWST to put itself into its final destination this afternoon. At around 2PM ET, JWST fired its onboard thrusters for roughly 5 minutes. It was the last of three course correction burns that JWST has done, slowing the spacecraft down enough to put it into a very precise orbit in space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ctkr8k"&gt;JWST is now orbiting around an invisible point in space known as an Earth-Sun Lagrange point. It’s a somewhat mystical area of space where the gravity and centripetal forces of the Sun and the Earth are just right, allowing objects to remain in a relatively “stable” position. “There’s a little tug of war going on where [gravity] balances out perfectly,” Jean-Paul Pinaud, the ground operations delta-V lead at Northrop Grumman, the primary contractor of JWST, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “So nobody wins that tug of war.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="uTckvj"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“There’s a little tug of war going on where [gravity] balances out perfectly.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vD8CnX"&gt;The Sun and the Earth share five of these Lagrange points, peppered around our planet. There’s one directly in between the Earth and the Sun and one on the opposite side of our star from us. JWST is orbiting around one Lagrangian point located on the far side of the Earth further from the Sun, called L2. In this position, as Earth moves around the star, JWST will follow the planet almost in lockstep, like a constant companion always in the same location in relation to our planet. No matter where Earth is on its course around the Sun, JWST is guaranteed to be about 1 million miles away from us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8G8ypI"&gt;The track that JWST is taking around L2 is actually fairly wide, stretching roughly the distance between the Earth and the Moon. But the observatory can’t stay on that trajectory forever without some help. L2 is what’s known as “pseudo” stable, meaning objects that orbit this location will have a tendency to drift away in one direction. “It’s like sitting on a saddle of a horse,” Pinaud says. “On a saddle of a horse, you’re kind of stable. Imagine yourself as being a marble... from head to tail, you’ll probably roll down to the center, but then once you go to either side of the saddle, you’re just gonna fall to the ground.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TN24dnCbn2cdMC2N8C5QgBXoAWQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23191693/754_990528.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ead6Ry"&gt;So JWST will have to make small adjustments to its path over its lifetime. Every 20 days or so, the telescope will fire its thrusters for two to three minutes at a time to ensure that it stays on track in its orbit. Ultimately, these adjustments will determine how long JWST can stay active in space. When the propellant runs out in the next 10 to 20 years, that’s when the observatory’s mission will end. (Luckily, JWST’s ride to space, the Ariane 5 rocket, put it on such a great trajectory that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/29/22858406/nasa-james-webb-space-telescope-mission"&gt;the telescope’s lifespan will last way longer than originally predicted&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FuB9Hm"&gt;It may seem like a complicated position, with a lot of extra effort needed to keep JWST stable. But L2 is a pretty attractive place for this observatory for a variety of reasons. Perhaps the biggest advantage is how far away it is from both the Earth and the Sun. JWST was made to collect infrared light, a type of light that is associated with heat. Because of this design choice, the telescope must remain extremely cold at all times. That’s why it’s equipped with a sunshield that will always be facing the Sun, a protective umbrella that will reflect the star’s heat and keep the telescope extra frigid. Still, any nearby object emitting heat and infrared light could muck up JWST’s observations if NASA isn’t careful. By putting the telescope nearly 1 million miles away from our planet, NASA is guaranteeing that the infrared light coming from the Earth and the Moon will not interfere or heat up the telescope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="agzTg2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;L2 is a pretty attractive place for this observatory&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kfQtkV"&gt;L2 is also great from a power standpoint because one side of JWST will always be facing the Sun. On that heated side, the telescope has a solar panel that is constantly gathering sunlight for power. Other spacecraft, such as the Hubble Space Telescope in orbit around Earth, don’t have that luxury. Whenever Hubble orbits on the nightside of Earth, it loses the view of the Sun and must store power in its batteries. That will never be the case for JWST. “We have basically limitless power for mission operations, and we don’t have to worry about any eclipses,” Kyle Hott, the mission systems engineering lead for JWST at Northrop Grumman, tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y6sb6b"&gt;There are also some downsides of constantly switching between day and night when orbiting the Earth; the extreme fluctuations in temperature can jostle and vibrate a spacecraft, causing its instruments to degrade over time. JWST will operate at roughly the same temperatures all throughout its lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hxGWdP"&gt;And then there is the benefit of continuous communication. With L2 always in the same position relative to Earth, JWST will be a set distance away from our planet at all times. That means we can be in constant contact with the observatory. “We can sort of be tugged along at L2 by the Earth-Sun system, such that we have that nice convenient constant communications with the vehicle,” says Hott. “And so that simplifies just a lot of the mission operations as well.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="16PFKg"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="How the James Webb Space Telescope will revolutionize astrophysics|105132" data-volume-uuid="10e6068e6" data-volume-id="105132" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-788" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gOeFPL"&gt;This crucial finale caps off the observatory’s risky journey through the cosmos, paving the way for the science to finally begin. We still have to wait some more for JWST’s observations to get underway, though. Scientists and engineers will soon start aligning the telescope’s mirrors ever so precisely before commissioning the observatory, testing out all of its instruments to make sure they’re ready to collect the first extraordinary images of the most ancient stars and galaxies in the Universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wJ1cMm"&gt;That process will take many months, but if it goes well, the first historical images captured by JWST could be beamed back to Earth as soon as this summer.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22895050/nasa-jwst-space-telescope-final-orbit-lagrange-point"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22895050/nasa-jwst-space-telescope-final-orbit-lagrange-point</id>
    <author>
      <name>Loren Grush</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T14:09:32-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T14:09:32-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla Cybertruck walkaround video shows the absurdly huge windshield wiper in detail</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MPqXh-zvhT2qar2CEj4vgr-sF9M=/0x40:1429x993/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70426636/Tesla_Cybertruck_leak_photo.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Even in handheld video, the truck looks a little unreal.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Cybertruck Owners Club&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="F4INAK"&gt;We got the closest look yet at an alleged prototype of the Tesla Cybertruck, thanks to a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yHT040_Pt3w"&gt;walkaround video&lt;/a&gt; posted to the &lt;a href="https://www.cybertruckownersclub.com/forum/threads/cybertruck-photos-leaked-%F0%9F%93%B8-added-video-showing-whole-truck-rear-bed.4660/"&gt;Cybertruck Owners Club forum&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://electrek.co/2022/01/24/tesla-cybertruck-prototype-shown-in-detail-in-new-leaked-walkaround-video/"&gt;via &lt;em&gt;Electrek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). We get to see a good deal of the vehicle, including its giant windshield and wiper. You can watch the whole thing below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BXb84A"&gt;We &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/10/22828220/tesla-cybertruck-prototype-drone-shot-windshield-wiper-elon-musk"&gt;saw the wiper last month&lt;/a&gt; when a drone video captured a Cybertruck doing laps on the company’s test track in Fremont, California. Tesla CEO Elon Musk commented on the wiper at the time, saying that it troubled him and that a wiper you could stow away in the front trunk would be “ideal, but complex.” (Is getting out in the rain, sleet, or snow to put on your windshield wiper &lt;em&gt;really &lt;/em&gt;ideal, though?)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YD8MRP79jMfagBqU1Lh-7ak4QLw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23191536/Screen_Shot_2022_01_24_at_09.55.31.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: CybertruckOwnersClub.com&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The person in the video seems to express doubt that it can clean the entire windshield but is assured it can.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="bgIGP6"&gt;The video shows the rest of the truck as the person walks around it, giving us a look at the wheels, tailgate, and bed. It’s been said before, but the Cybertruck still looks a little unreal to me with its stainless steel finish and trapezoidal shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bWFAOK"&gt;Unlike the version shown off during &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/21/20975475/tesla-cybertruck-announcement-musk-electric-truck-pickup-features-range-price-release-date"&gt;Tesla’s 2019 announcement event&lt;/a&gt;, this version of the truck doesn’t have any door handles. How to open the doors was a topic of discussion while the video was being filmed, according to the subtitles. (The actual audio isn’t included, so it’s not clear if that’s actually what’s being said.) It seems to be explained that you can tap your phone or a keycard on a specific sensor, and the door will open. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zPPZeKpUJTyCViclvWPJvPS4lHk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23191540/Screen_Shot_2022_01_24_at_09.56.47.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: CybertruckOwnersClub.com&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The rear quarter-panel shot. Earlier in the video, you can see that this particular truck has a hitch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="lFmDxK"&gt;The subtitles also indicate that the truck is a “concept,” so the version that actually ends up going out to consumers may be different. The subtitles also capture a funny comment from someone present: “Man, tell Elon he doing too much,” going on to compare the truck to a stainless steel fridge that you’d “put your produce” in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Aaygwj"&gt;The Cybertruck was supposed to start shipping this year but has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/13/22881646/tesla-cybertruck-production-date-2022-removed-website"&gt;reportedly been delayed until early 2023&lt;/a&gt; — those reports are backed up by the fact that Tesla removed references to 2022 from the Cybertruck’s webpage. In theory, an official timeline should be coming soon as Elon Musk has promised to share a “product roadmap update” on Wednesday’s earnings call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bQQq7F"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yHT040_Pt3w?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899176/telsa-cybertruck-walkaround-video-wiper-ev-roadmap-incoming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22899176/telsa-cybertruck-walkaround-video-wiper-ev-roadmap-incoming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T13:21:06-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T13:21:06-05:00</updated>
    <title>AT&amp;T’s new 5-gig and 2-gig fiber internet is here, starting at $110 a month</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gvlIWG6HpbO56w2vES3zlvcZmH0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70426119/acastro_180322_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="K66hn1"&gt;&lt;a href="https://about.att.com/aboutus/pressrelease/2022/fastest-major-internet-provider.html"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T is rolling out 2Gbps and 5Gbps&lt;/a&gt; speed tiers for its &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.att.com/internet/fiber/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;fiber-optic internet option&lt;/a&gt;. The company made the announcement to kick off its Life Gigified event, where it said new and existing AT&amp;amp;T Fiber customers will soon be able to take advantage of these multi-gig connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xUOSaz"&gt;If you don’t know what multi-gig is, it means a single connection that offers speeds higher than 1Gbps. And because it’s a fiber-optic connection, this speed goes both ways. “It’s symmetrical; your upload and download speeds are the same.” Chris Sambar, AT&amp;amp;T’s executive vice president of technology operations said in an interview with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rQf68L"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T’s new multi-gig speeds need Wi-Fi 6 technology for “optimal” performance, which means you’ll probably want to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21283756/arris-surfboard-max-pro-wi-fi-6-mesh-router-review-price-specs-features"&gt;upgrade your router&lt;/a&gt;. But Sambar told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; it will supply customers with its multi-gig and Wi-Fi 6 capable &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.att.com/support/article/u-verse-high-speed-internet/KM1395833/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;BGW320 gateway&lt;/a&gt; when you sign up for its fiber-optic service, so you won’t have to buy any new equipment. AT&amp;amp;T may offer even faster speeds eventually; the company says it reached speeds of 10Gbps in a lab environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="58w0YC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The 2Gbps plan will cost $110 / month, while the 5Gbps plan is priced at $180 / month&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qlytlu"&gt;The 2Gbps plan will cost $110 / month, while the 5Gbps plan is priced at $180 / month. Business plans will cost a bit more, however, at $225 / month for 2Gbps and $395 / month for 5Gbps. AT&amp;amp;T is also introducing “straightforward pricing” for all of its Fiber plans, which it says will eliminate equipment fees, annual contracts, data caps, and 12-month price increases for new customers. Its new plans come with a free HBO Max subscription as well as &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.att.com/security/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;ActiveArmor&lt;/a&gt;, AT&amp;amp;T’s cybersecurity service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kBVu5e"&gt;These new speed tiers will be available in over 70 metro areas, including Los Angeles, San Francisco, and Dallas. AT&amp;amp;T &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.att.com/internet/gigapower/coverage-map/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently offers its fiber-optic network&lt;/a&gt; near cities spread out across the Southern, Midwestern, and Western portions of the US, but it plans to expand its service network to 30 million customers by 2025. Sambar says the locations that support multi-gig speeds will have access to both 2Gbps and 5Gbps plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1nA9Q5"&gt;Previously, AT&amp;amp;T’s fiber-optic speeds ranged from 300Mbps to 1Gbps. Its move into multi-gig territory follows &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/15/21437958/google-fiber-2-gig-gbps-internet-nashville-huntsville-speed-webpass-pilot"&gt;Google Fiber’s 2Gbps rollout&lt;/a&gt; in 2020 as well as Comcast’s &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xfinity.com%2Flearn%2Foffers%2Fdetails%3FofferId%3D9626100376&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2022%2F1%2F24%2F22898876%2Fatt-fiber-multi-gig-connections-speeds" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;3Gbps offering for $299 / month&lt;/a&gt;. AT&amp;amp;T offers more information about the new speeds &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/http://att.com/hypergig" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on its site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LSi9Mk"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update January 24th 1:20PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated to add a statement and additional context from Chris Sambar, executive vice president of AT&amp;amp;T’s technology operations.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22898876/att-fiber-multi-gig-connections-speeds"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22898876/att-fiber-multi-gig-connections-speeds</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T13:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T13:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Meet the auto repair professor pivoting to EVs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lEEf008xJcbOxJYOlezl0gX2C6U=/0x0:5184x3456/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70426327/Ruth_Morrison1.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xsKaVg"&gt;With the number of electric vehicles on the roads poised to skyrocket this decade, millions of drivers are going to need auto mechanics who can fix their new batteries-on-wheels. But today, the &lt;a href="https://cleantechnica.com/2018/12/10/97-of-auto-mechanics-cant-work-on-electric-cars-new-report-concludes/?utm_source=Triggermail&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Post%20Blast%20bii-transportation-and-logistics:%20Tesla%20owners%20dissatisfied%20with%20wait%20for%20services%20%7C%20Ford%20will%20use%20over-the-air%20updates%20in%202020%20%7C%20US%20govt%20grounds%20Chinese%20drones&amp;amp;utm_term=BII%20List%20T%26L%20ALL"&gt;vast majority of auto repair professionals&lt;/a&gt; do not have the training or equipment to repair EVs, which are anatomically very different from their gas-powered predecessors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6EI8JQ"&gt;As a result, many early EV adopters have been forced to rely on vehicle manufacturers and dealerships to service their cars — a situation that can &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2011/02/26/your-money/26shortcuts.html"&gt;drive up repair costs&lt;/a&gt; and lead to &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/tesla-owners-dissatisfied-with-wait-for-services-2019-11"&gt;frustratingly long wait times&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C1HEqQ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.smccme.edu/faculty-profiles/#morrison"&gt;Ruth Morrison&lt;/a&gt;, who chairs the &lt;a href="https://www.smccme.edu/academics/degree-programs/automotive-technology/#cert"&gt;Automotive Technology Department&lt;/a&gt; at Southern Maine Community College (SMCC), wants to change that. Morrison, who was an auto mechanic before she began teaching in 2003, took a course focused on hybrid and EV repair back in 2009. She’s wanted to teach the subject ever since. And with SMCC recently receiving funds from the state for additional workforce training, she now has the opportunity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i8dUfT"&gt;Last month, SMCC did its first run of a new class designed to teach mechanics to work on hybrid and electric vehicles — the first in Maine, to Morrison’s knowledge, and one of a relatively small number of such programs nationwide. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; spoke with Morrison to learn more about what her course offers and the fast-evolving EV repair landscape. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nEOtdk"&gt;This conversation has been edited for length and clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vJrEdr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maddie: &lt;/strong&gt;We’re on the cusp of a huge electric vehicle boom in the United States and also globally. What are the implications of that for independent auto repair? What new skills are mechanics going to have to learn?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DIrGaR"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruth: &lt;/strong&gt;[Electric vehicles] have different components. They’re going to require different equipment and tools, and technicians are going to need to get trained in how to use them. The safety concerns are one issue, but then, the equipment we use in this class is specific to diagnosing the electric machines [motors or generators], the power inverters, and the batteries. And if independent shops want to get into repairing these components, rather than just putting in a whole new unit, then they’re going to need to get training in this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rJxzke"&gt;Which is different from what the dealerships have been doing. Dealerships will generally replace an entire battery rather than try and balance it or replace the cells and balance it after that. As there’s more of these vehicles that are outside of warranty, and people are buying them used, I would think that the consumers are going to want to spend less money and not have to foot the bill for the entire component, just get it repaired. And then, if somebody is buying a used car, it’s nice to know what condition it’s in before buying it. So there’s some predictive maintenance that can be done to see how the motor is, kind of like doing a compression test on a gasoline engine or a diesel engine. If you want to know how worn the engine is before you buy the car, you can do some sort of predictive testing. And for electric vehicles, there’s also predictive testing that can be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aOoFam"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maddie: &lt;/strong&gt;How did your idea for a course focused on training independent mechanics on electric vehicles first come about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="enWGWc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruth: &lt;/strong&gt;Well, I first took a class in [2009] with Dr. Quarto, who came and did training for us, and I wanted to start offering that training to our students. [&lt;em&gt;Editor’s Note: Dr. Mark Quarto is a former General Motors engineer who teaches EV and hybrid vehicle repair through &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.futuretechauto.com/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;a company called FutureTech&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.] And there’s special tools that we had to buy. There was an expense involved, and I didn’t get a lot of support for getting tools up in order to do that. But now the Maine Community College System has &lt;a href="https://www.mccs.me.edu/press_release/president-daigler-statement-on-governor-signing-legislation-to-implement-maine-jobs-and-recovery-plan/"&gt;received support&lt;/a&gt; from the governor of Maine, and she wants us to be training in green jobs, and so now we have the ability to buy the equipment and get ourselves trained, and that’s really opened the door for us. I’ve been struggling to fit this into our budget for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lWZbAk"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maddie: &lt;/strong&gt;As you developed the course, were there any other programs you modeled it after or took inspiration from? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SBH9lk"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruth: &lt;/strong&gt;Well, what happened was &lt;a href="https://www.siemens.com/global/en.html"&gt;Siemens&lt;/a&gt; was involved with a chain called VIP Tires and Service, which is up here in the Northeast, and VIP had approached Siemens for guidance on getting their technicians trained in this area. So they [Siemens] approached me in summer of 2019 and asked us if we could train the technicians. And so then I started working directly with VIP, and the first thing I thought of was this course that I had taken with Dr. Quarto years ago. I looked around for other curriculum rather than reinventing one, and I liked his the best. So we have modeled it after the training his company offers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fZ6O9t"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maddie: &lt;/strong&gt;Did you find many other EV repair courses out there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dm2Bea"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruth: &lt;/strong&gt;There’s a few. I know that there’s one in Worcester, Massachusetts &lt;a href="https://www.fixhybrid.com/training-calendar/"&gt;called ACDC&lt;/a&gt;. [&lt;em&gt;Editor’s note: The Verge was unable to find data on how many EV and hybrid repair training programs exist nationally. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RebuildsRich"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rich Benoit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, co-founder of the Tesla-focused repair shop The Electrified Garage, told &lt;/em&gt;The Verge&lt;em&gt; in an email he suspects there are “under 50 dedicated EV repair programs in the US.&lt;/em&gt;] &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mg9yhD"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maddie: &lt;/strong&gt;Walk me through the nuts and bolts of how your course works?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6MghjH"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruth: &lt;/strong&gt;So when we first rolled this out for VIP, it was [also] a “train the trainer” event for me and my partner, Joe. What we did was use the web-based training from FutureTech — all of us did that web-based training first — then Dr. Quarto came and did a week-long hands-on class. That was back in December. And I think as we go forward, I’m going to break that big class down into smaller pieces. Because it was a lot of web-based training before we got to the hands-on. If we can break it down into systems, I think that would be a lot easier to offer to the general public. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ql7bua"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maddie: &lt;/strong&gt;Can you highlight a few things mechanics learn in the course?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WqTbHW"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruth: &lt;/strong&gt;Sure. We went through the safety systems first — understanding how those worked and checking them to make sure they were working properly. And then, we did battery testing and balancing or reconditioning. So you can take an older battery and recondition it, and it’ll be much better for many years. And then we looked at motor generators and diagnosing those; we looked at power inverters and the air conditioning compressors. Pretty much all of the high voltage systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cifjxH"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maddie: &lt;/strong&gt;When it comes to battery balancing, is the idea that we can take batteries from older vehicles and do a heart transplant into a newer vehicle? Or is it more about rehabilitating the battery to remain in the same vehicle?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JhJLqU"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruth: &lt;/strong&gt;Both. So, somebody who drives a Prius might notice after five years that their gas mileage has gone down significantly. And that’s because the gas engine is powering the powertrain rather than the electric motor because the battery doesn’t have enough power anymore. So that battery in that vehicle could be reconditioned and bring it back up to its original condition. And then the gas mileage would go back to 45 [mpg] or whatever it started out at. And then also, one of the things we did during our class was get a couple batteries from salvage yards and reconditioned them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5YCkJi"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maddie: &lt;/strong&gt;What kind of feedback did you receive on the course from the folks who took it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NJHsHt"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruth: &lt;/strong&gt;The company VIP, the technicians learned a lot. They’re ready to set up these services at their shops. They have enough hybrids, Priuses coming through their shops on a regular basis. They could be selling these services — the maintenance services, the predictive maintenance, and the repair services. It’s applicable knowledge that they can start offering for their customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8hNlDL"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maddie: &lt;/strong&gt;Do you have additional courses planned for later this year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NHlj9D"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruth: &lt;/strong&gt;Yeah, with the grant, we need to start training more people. I think we said it was going to be about a hundred people. By the time we were done in the next year or so, we’re going to start offering courses outside of our regular curriculum. So that would mostly be in the summer and maybe during our winter break again next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hYfTLY"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maddie: &lt;/strong&gt;The right-to-repair movement has &lt;a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/13504851.2021.1896669?journalCode=rael20"&gt;played a pretty big role&lt;/a&gt; in opening up the independent auto repair landscape, but some repair advocates are concerned that with the EV transition, &lt;a href="https://grist.org/politics/tesla-want-to-fix-your-own-massachusetts-just-made-it-easier/"&gt;new repair restrictions could start to emerge&lt;/a&gt;. Are the mechanics you’re talking with bringing up any particular challenges repairing electric cars? Are there restrictions on these vehicles, or vehicle data that they’re not getting from manufacturers, that’s making repair harder? Is that something you’re concerned about in the future?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L5zI6k"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruth: &lt;/strong&gt;I haven’t run into a problem yet. But yes, I mean, it’s always a problem. As an automotive technician, it’s always a problem to try and get the substantial information that you need and the diagnostic information. [EVs] are going to have the same challenge for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22883604/auto-repair-course-electric-vehicles-interview"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22883604/auto-repair-course-electric-vehicles-interview</id>
    <author>
      <name>Maddie Stone</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T13:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T13:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Coinbase makes it easier to report cryptocurrency taxes</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pvCLPg6W5VVFOdCybrtJkB9tX5E=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70426322/acastro_180927_2968_Coinbase_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bIGjhJ"&gt;Coinbase, one of the largest and most popular cryptocurrency exchanges, is adding a new tax center to its app and website to help US customers work out how much they might owe to the IRS as a result of their crypto transactions, the company has announced. The section is designed to gather every taxable transaction into one place to simplify matters come tax day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6hqKtd"&gt;Although cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin often appear similar to the fiat money we’re accustomed to, in the eyes of the IRS, the digital assets are actually property, according to &lt;a href="https://www.irs.gov/individuals/international-taxpayers/frequently-asked-questions-on-virtual-currency-transactions"&gt;this FAQ&lt;/a&gt; from the federal agency. That means cryptocurrency transactions may need to be reported as capital gains or losses, and &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; means keeping track of a cryptocurrency’s value as it’s bought and sold over time. Documenting these transactions can get complicated quickly if you’re regularly buying and selling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Xcfaya"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The information can be passed to an accountant or used with tax software&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bgWtew"&gt;According to Coinbase, its new section will show “a personalized summary of [a customer’s] taxable activity on Coinbase, broken out over time by realized gains/losses and miscellaneous income.” This information can then be taken to an accountant or used with tax software like TurboTax. If you’re someone who’s transferred crypto to external exchanges, wallets, or other DeFi (decentralized finance) services, then Coinbase says its customers can also get tax reports for up to 3,000 of these transactions &lt;a href="https://www.cointracker.io/coinbase"&gt;free with CoinTracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eLpnX0"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/07/14/irs-new-rules-on-bitcoin-ethereum-dogecoin-trading.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CNBC &lt;/em&gt;reported last year&lt;/a&gt; on suspicions that a lot of the taxes due on cryptocurrency transactions are going unpaid. Although confusion about the evolving tax rules about cryptocurrencies is one reason for this, another is that exchanges like Coinbase have historically not given as much help as traditional brokerage houses to customers when it comes to reporting their gains and losses for tax purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Np0QtG"&gt;The new Coinbase tax section is accessible from the profile icon in the top right-hand corner of the interface, where “Taxes” will appear as a menu item. In its app, the Taxes section is accessible from the “Profile &amp;amp; Settings” menu, accessible from the top left of the app’s interface. In addition to the new tools, Coinbase is also planning to offer written guides and help videos in the coming weeks to explain cryptocurrency and digital asset taxes, but for now, this &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/personal-finance/crypto/bitcoin-and-cryptocurrency-taxes-in-2022/"&gt;overview from &lt;em&gt;CNET&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a helpful place to start.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22898610/coinbase-tax-center-capital-gains-losses-irs-taxes"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22898610/coinbase-tax-center-capital-gains-losses-irs-taxes</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-01-24T12:49:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T12:49:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon’s Blink outdoor cameras with floodlight and solar-charging configurations are $50 off</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Blink Floodlight Cam" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QuaJYDnSagCLW_DNH5d5uo9ePy4=/40x0:1155x743/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70426284/Blink_Flood_Light_Cam_1000.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Amazon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mZNMmI"&gt;Mondays are for football hangovers, extra strong coffee, and deals. If the weekend brought you grief due to some big playoff upsets, we’re here to ease the pain with great savings on gadgets. What better way to dull the sting of an abysmal 13-10 loss to the sixth seed when you’re supposed to be the favorite to win it all? Put down the cheese and dry those tears with some excellent deals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="512vpf"&gt;First up, the latest Blink Outdoor cam with a floodlight attachment is currently just $89.98 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Blink-Floodlight-Camera/dp/B094YXVVRF?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cgub0TC81Bm" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, which is $50 less than its regular price of $139.98. It comes equipped with a 700-lumen LED floodlight and the Sync Module 2 for connectivity. If you want to make battery anxiety a thing of the past, the Blink Outdoor camera with a solar charger mount is just $79.98 (also $50 off) at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Blink-Outdoor-Solar-Panel-Charging/dp/B099HXDWZS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cguca3anb1U" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. It’s the same camera in a configuration that pretty much ensures you may never swap batteries (though you have to &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Blink-Sync-Module-2/dp/B084RQ6MHJ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;buy your Sync Module separately for about $35&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ff1CLA"&gt;If you’ve considered outdoor smart home cameras, you probably encountered the conundrum of going wireless and dealing with limited battery life or going wired and dealing with installation. These cameras from Blink offer a convenient compromise, with battery life that lasts up to two years on just two 1.5-volt AA lithium batteries. They may not offer some of the extra features like person detection or package detection, but they nail the essentials with motion detection and 1080p video. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="DxE2cw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Why does Blink still exist?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22704290/amazon-blink-ring-camera-doorbell-brands-smart-home-why"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="nDvb7o"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10993169"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="UJHwqo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10993173"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pC2h0U"&gt;The most basic Apple AirPods are still a fine choice in 2022, especially when they drop down to a price as affordable as one Benjamin. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PXGQC1Q/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon has the second-gen AirPods with a wired charging case for $99.99&lt;/a&gt; — saving you about $29 off the usual going rate. The only time that price gets any better is around Black Friday or maybe Prime Day. These AirPods from 2019 have been leap-frogged in performance by the excellent AirPods Pro (&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B09JQMJHXY?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;which are currently discounted to $179.99&lt;/a&gt;) and usurped by the newer third-gen model, but they’re still readily available and a worthwhile pickup if you have an iPhone, iPad, or Mac and value the convenience of their excellent connectivity and audible Siri notifications. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dw1Sda"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0LD2zi"&gt;Speaking of Apple’s products that perform well for their price and size, the popular &lt;a href="https://www.costco.com/homepod-mini.product.100696292.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;HomePod Mini is just $79.99&lt;/a&gt; ($20 off) at Costco in either white or space gray. This deal is exclusive for Costco members with a limit of three per member and costs another $2.99 for shipping. The HomePod Mini is the diminutive smart speaker from Apple that supports Siri voice commands, easy HomeKit integration for smart home connectivity, and solid audio quality from a small speaker — complete with multi-speaker pairing. It’s the only smart speaker currently on offer from Apple since its larger sibling was discontinued in 2021. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21561589/apple-homepod-mini-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lJE19a"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10883175"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JHnYFX"&gt;If you’re getting started a little early on securing a new TV before the Super Bowl, the deals are slowly beginning to trickle in. The 48-inch LG C1 OLED, one of our favorite picks around for watching movies or sports and playing games, is currently &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.buydig.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FLGOLED48C1PUB%2FLG-OLED48C1PUB-48-Inch-4K-Smart-OLED-TV-2021-Model&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2022%2F1%2F24%2F22898743%2Famazon-blink-outdoor-camera-floodlight-solar-apple-airpods-homepod-mini-lg-c1-google-nest-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$1,096.99 at BuyDig and comes with an extended four-year accidental damage warranty and $50 Visa gift card&lt;/a&gt;. If you buy it from &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ebay.com%2Fitm%2F324842746233%3Famdata%3Denc%253AAQAGAAAAoGTUIR8%252BZ4lujSDlpkPX60tQCoc7kdJ94wOGR9%252Bznn%252B9dKyrdNEuQqNFju%252F%252BFnF81jFyvxTUwGR48Iwn4BhpJ6HpAB1OwwrmEybri0Jo6h21Net8c%252Fu6%252FK28iIbLnH2Y%252BDmhOPJuWNb481GQIyXniGwv0UBxeTRARu2SVhB7EBZFUFpCoc5pr2hcP2SPn5waqUQztsDqbNA5nSjpVLj0rmw%253D%257Ctkp%253ABFBM6Lna0dFf%26mkcid%3D1%26mkrid%3D711-53200-19255-0%26siteid%3D0%26campid%3D5338794975%26customid%3DVergeDealsRoundup012422%26toolid%3D10001%26mkevt%3D1&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2022%2F1%2F24%2F22898743%2Famazon-blink-outdoor-camera-floodlight-solar-apple-airpods-homepod-mini-lg-c1-google-nest-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;BuyDig’s eBay store, that $50 gift card is replaced by a $100 eBay credit&lt;/a&gt; to be used later. That eBay deal is one of the best possible prices around for the 48-inch model, and there is a &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ebay.com%2Fitm%2F313720184065%3Famdata%3Denc%253AAQAGAAAAoHa2%252F6I4Rot6zAi1kRjunIzKz3%252FGATMVxo1QBpjzvFhA4gMoqJt%252FBenEXYkNIONK7OeE47HiOKlqbPwOw7cYpdP%252B%252F8X0n47JrKpU6e%252FgbKy9GD8%252Bin3BJAtLXbUIZ67OBDwV1C582VoA9UeL%252BVDDoozR2fuwBYDcDjvmMLPJwr6xeeHBuOvewKRqsDwqCME%252FgGa3HvrN1zvzIE9tyyzzhMw%253D%257Ctkp%253ABFBM7vXW0dFf%26mkcid%3D1%26mkrid%3D711-53200-19255-0%26siteid%3D0%26campid%3D5338794975%26customid%3DVergeDealsRoundup012422%26toolid%3D10001%26mkevt%3D1&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2022%2F1%2F24%2F22898743%2Famazon-blink-outdoor-camera-floodlight-solar-apple-airpods-homepod-mini-lg-c1-google-nest-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;similar deal on the 55-inch version for $1,296.99&lt;/a&gt; if you prefer a bigger size of LG’s excellent OLED.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="3yZsOJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"LG C1 OLED vs. Samsung Odyssey Neo G9: the perfect monitor doesn’t exist","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/11/22815110/lg-c1-48-oled-samsung-odyssey-neo-g9-review-monitor-tv"},{"title":"LG’s C1 and G1 OLEDs get even better at gaming with 120Hz Dolby Vision","url":"https://www.theverge.com/games/2021/6/28/22554939/lg-dolby-vision-hdr-xbox-c1-g1-4k"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="qiIhEo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10933930"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3b32g9"&gt;We’ve seen a plethora of deals on the Google Nest Hub Max come and go, but today’s hits a new all-time low that even bests Black Friday by an additional $10. &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cgubPXrLWZA" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.buydig.com%2Fshop%2Fproduct%2FGONESHUBCHLK&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2022%2F1%2F24%2F22898743%2Famazon-blink-outdoor-camera-floodlight-solar-apple-airpods-homepod-mini-lg-c1-google-nest-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;BuyDig&lt;/a&gt; have the 10-inch camera-equipped smart display for about $170, a savings of $60. That is an exceptional value for the larger Nest Hub with bigger sound output that also works great for video calls. One of the killer features of Google’s displays is the integration with Google Photos, allowing the screensaver to be automatically populated by a shared album — and that experience is maximized with the big display of the Max. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/9/20855944/google-nest-hub-max-review-assistant-smart-display-price-specs-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="e4RRb2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Sonos wins major patent infringement victory against Google","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/6/22871121/sonos-google-patent-itc-ruling-decision-import-ban"},{"title":"Your Google home speakers are about to get slightly worse because Sonos sued and won","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/6/22871304/google-home-speaker-group-volume-control-changes-sonos-patent-decision"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="CumLA4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10872961"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="VfeskJ"&gt;More deals that are better than a QB sneak with 14 seconds left:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Z2IWyG"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.microcenter.com/product/644033/apple-macbook-pro-with-m1-pro-chip-mk193ll-a-late-2021-162-laptop-computer-space-gray" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;16-inch MacBook Pro with M1 Pro processor is $2,449.99&lt;/a&gt; ($250 off) at Micro Center, though it is limited to in-store purchases. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22751921/apple-macbook-pro-14-16-inch-2021-m1-pro-max-review" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="KFi8Qq"&gt;A few great Nintendo Switch titles are $20 off at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/b?node=23718724011&amp;amp;smid=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;amp;pf_rd_p=49c226c9-6cec-4b74-9448-b2ec4bda9569&amp;amp;pf_rd_s=merchandised-search-3&amp;amp;pf_rd_t=101&amp;amp;pf_rd_i=18895855011&amp;amp;pf_rd_m=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;amp;pf_rd_r" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cgueZ657QVn" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, including &lt;em&gt;Hyrule Warriors: Age of Calamity, Bravely Default II, Xenoblade Chronicles Definitive Edition&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Fire Emblem: Three Houses&lt;/em&gt;. Amazon has the deals on digital copies, and Best Buy has them on the physical cartridges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="sQT80u"&gt;The 13-inch Surface Pro X tablet with 512GB of storage and 16GB of memory is &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cgue0v15pZM" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$300 off at Best Buy, knocking the price down to $1,199.99&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/23/21526702/microsoft-surface-pro-x-2020-review-arm-windows-10-apps-features-specs-price" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="S8SU4k"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2022/1/24/22898743/amazon-blink-outdoor-camera-floodlight-solar-apple-airpods-homepod-mini-lg-c1-google-nest-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2022/1/24/22898743/amazon-blink-outdoor-camera-floodlight-solar-apple-airpods-homepod-mini-lg-c1-google-nest-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
