<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-24T17:38:37-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-24T17:38:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T17:38:37-05:00</updated>
    <title>Cyberpunk 2077’s next big patch delayed to second half of March after studio hack</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Cyberpunk 2077" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FtvImbX9KA246udBhI-xlVDSYgk=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68867769/Cyberpunk_2077_screen_5.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: CD Projekt Red&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6BgMK6"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077’s&lt;/em&gt; next big patch has been delayed following developer CD Projekt Red’s disclosure that it fell victim to a ransomware attack earlier this month. The next big patch, 1.2, is now scheduled for a release sometime in the second half of March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jUZgzo"&gt;“While we dearly wanted to deliver Patch 1.2 for Cyberpunk 2077 in the timespan we detailed previously, the recent cyber attack on the studio’s IT infrastructure and extensive scope of the update mean this unfortunately will not happen — we’ll need some additional time,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CyberpunkGame/status/1364607741680115717"&gt;CD Projekt Red said&lt;/a&gt; via the &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; Twitter account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="8WQsdR"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Our goal for Patch 1.2 goes beyond any of our previous updates. We’ve been working on numerous overall quality improvements and fixes, and we still have work to do to make sure that’s what you get. With that in mind, we’re now aiming for release in the second half of March. 2/3&lt;/p&gt;— Cyberpunk 2077 (@CyberpunkGame) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CyberpunkGame/status/1364607743399755780?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 24, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NFMupz"&gt;The ransomware attack has been a source of considerable disruption for CDPR, as it included personal details of employees and other sensitive information that was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278121/cd-projekt-red-ransomware-hack-cyberpunk-2077-the-witcher-3-auction-sale"&gt;allegedly later auctioned off on the internet&lt;/a&gt;. According to &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-02-24/cd-projekt-hack-severely-disrupts-work-on-cyberpunk-game-updates"&gt;a new report from &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;on Wednesday&lt;/a&gt;, the hack has made it nearly impossible for some CDPR employees to effectively perform their jobs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L21hEm"&gt;Here’s Jason Schreier for &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reporting the level of disarray the hack has left the studio in: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="kQR2Yc"&gt;CD Projekt has said it refused to pay a ransom to the hackers. As a result, employees remain unable to log onto the company’s virtual private network, making it impossible to access the systems and tools needed to do most of their jobs, said the people, requesting anonymity because they weren’t authorized to talk publicly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="ZpyWAR"&gt;And here’s more information on how the leaking of personal identification data in the hack has caused havoc on the personal lives of employees: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="q0rN1Q"&gt;Despite the unplanned vacation, the hack has been a nightmare for employees. The invaders had access to their personal information including Polish identification numbers and passport details, leading the company to tell staff to freeze their accounts and report the security breach to the government and their banks, said the people familiar with the matter. Workers were also asked to ship their computers to the company’s IT staff to be scanned for malware or other intrusions, the people said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="nUgv92"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; launched in an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/23/22197547/cyberpunk-2077-glitches"&gt;extremely buggy state&lt;/a&gt;, which led Sony to take the drastic step of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22188007/sony-cyberpunk-2077-removed-playstation-store-full-refunds-policy"&gt;removing the game from the PlayStation Store&lt;/a&gt;. CD Projekt Red has released numerous &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/22/22239765/cyberpunk-2077-update-patch-bug-fixes"&gt;updates&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/5/22268382/cyberpunk-2077-1-12-new-hotfix-patch-mods-vulnerability-security"&gt;hotfixes&lt;/a&gt; since launch in an attempt to address issues, and it sounds as if patch 1.2 could be the most significant yet. “Our goal for Patch 1.2 goes beyond any of our previous updates,” &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CyberpunkGame/status/1364607743399755780"&gt;CD Projekt Red said&lt;/a&gt;. The studio is also &lt;a href="https://www.cyberpunk.net/en/news/37298/our-commitment"&gt;working on&lt;/a&gt; free DLCs and a free next-gen console update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5vorVT"&gt;Hackers &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274035/cd-projekt-hack-source-code-cyberpunk-2077-witcher-3-encrypt-data-ransom"&gt;reportedly accessed&lt;/a&gt; source code from some of CD Projekt Red’s games, including &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Witcher 3&lt;/em&gt;, as well as internal company documents. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278121/cd-projekt-red-ransomware-hack-cyberpunk-2077-the-witcher-3-auction-sale"&gt;hackers reportedly sold&lt;/a&gt; the data they stole at auction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="flKr5v"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 24th, 5:38PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added information from a &lt;/em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;em&gt; report published this afternoon detailing how the ransomware attack on CDPR has disrupted the studio’s ability to work. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="xWjaAW"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Cyberpunk 2077 studio’s hacked data has reportedly been sold","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278121/cd-projekt-red-ransomware-hack-cyberpunk-2077-the-witcher-3-auction-sale"},{"title":"Cyberpunk 2077 studio falls victim to ransomware attack, data leak threatened","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274035/cd-projekt-hack-source-code-cyberpunk-2077-witcher-3-encrypt-data-ransom"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299184/cyberpunk-2077-patch-1-2-delayed-cd-projekt-red-studio-hack"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299184/cyberpunk-2077-patch-1-2-delayed-cd-projekt-red-studio-hack</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-24T17:30:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T17:30:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>Niantic permabanned a million cheaters since the start of 2020</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IAIHap2RcPU4L-zQ6OvV48cmIcA=/0x44:841x605/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68870246/Qto1N_hg.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Niantic&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rPYazP"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go &lt;/em&gt;creator&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Niantic &lt;a href="https://nianticlabs.com/blog/cheatingupdate-022321"&gt;has published a blog post&lt;/a&gt; detailing some of its anti-cheat efforts, and it seems the company has been busy. Since the start of 2020, Niantic has issued over 5 million “punishments” to players caught cheating, with over 20 percent of those being permabans. Doing the math, that’s over a million people who have gotten the boot in just over a year. This includes bans from &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Ingress&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter: Wizards Unite.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L6pOfy"&gt;The post did contain some encouraging news about the player base: apparently over 90 percent of people stopped cheating after they received their first warning. That’s a wonderful thing to hear, because it’s relatable; I also like to live just on the edge until someone tells me to knock it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ci9eY5"&gt;While it looks like 2020 was a bad year for people trying to cheat at &lt;em&gt;Pokémon Go&lt;/em&gt;, it was also rough for Niantic, as it tried to figure out how to adapt its games, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/19/22189424/pokemon-go-covid-2020-safety"&gt;which are all based on going outside and walking around&lt;/a&gt;, to a locked-down world. The developer had to make adjustments, not just to its anti-cheat software, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/13/21178230/pokemon-go-coronavirus-niantic-updates-temporary-discounts-inside"&gt;to the mechanics of the games as well&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299742/niantic-banned-million-cheaters-anti-cheat-pokemon-go"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299742/niantic-banned-million-cheaters-anti-cheat-pokemon-go</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-24T17:28:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T17:28:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>Shows based on Italian Job, Fatal Attraction, Flashdance, and more heading to Paramount Plus </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mddN6uQyLLlOWO5xQeq6_qgBOC8=/100x0:1900x1200/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68870229/itlian_job.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8KCeJu"&gt;A series based on Michael Caine’s 1969 &lt;em&gt;Italian Job &lt;/em&gt;is in the works for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22238502/paramount-plus-launch-date-cbs-all-access-streaming-event-shows-movies"&gt;Paramount Plus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9EOUz5"&gt;The series is just one of several shows that will head to Paramount Plus, ViacomCBS’s new streaming service. Donald De Line, one of the original producers for the series, will work on the show in some capacity, &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/live-feed/love-story-fatal-attraction-parallax-view-italian-job-flashdance-tv-shows-a-go-at-paramount?utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=social"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;The Hollywood Reporter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The original film was remade in 2003 and starred Mark Wahlberg, Charlize Theron, Ed Norton and Jason Statham. The other shows announced include &lt;em&gt;Love Story, Fatal Attraction, Flashdance, &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;The Parallax View, &lt;/em&gt;according to the &lt;em&gt;Reporter&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rPkokQ"&gt;These new shows join a series of shows already announced for the streaming platform. &lt;em&gt;The Offer&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;a limited series based on the making-of process behind &lt;em&gt;The Godfather&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;Lioness&lt;/em&gt;, a show about a young marine who is recruited to befriend a terrorist in order to bring down the organization; a reimagining of MTV’s &lt;em&gt;Behind The Music; &lt;/em&gt;a documentary series based on FBI profilers; a revival of BET’s &lt;em&gt;The Game; &lt;/em&gt;a new SpongeBob SquarePants series called &lt;em&gt;Kamp Koral; &lt;/em&gt;and a new version of &lt;em&gt;The Real World&lt;/em&gt;. More original series are expected to be announced as the event progresses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lCPC9w"&gt;Paramount Plus will be released on March 4th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Kpgu6v"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This story is developing...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299958/italian-job-sequel-series-flashdance-fatal-attracion-shows-paramount-plus-streaming"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299958/italian-job-sequel-series-flashdance-fatal-attracion-shows-paramount-plus-streaming</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-24T17:22:45-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T17:22:45-05:00</updated>
    <title>How to leave LastPass and move to another password manager</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1lOMZnVzMXG0pu9CbqacP18WVXo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68862981/acastro_210217_1777_passwords_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1614009890.001500"&gt;Ever since LastPass announced that it was tweaking its free tier to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22285531/lastpass-free-tier-mobile-computer-device-premium-family"&gt;only allow a single category of device&lt;/a&gt; — mobile or computer — there’s been a lot of interest in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22285499/password-manager-lastpass-free-bitwarden-zoho"&gt;finding alternatives&lt;/a&gt; among LastPass users. Luckily, once you do find an alternative, it’s pretty easy to pull your data from LastPass and upload it to another password manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G9dgOZ"&gt;What follows are instructions on how to download your LastPass data, and where to find instructions from several popular password managers that will help you upload that data to their services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="XzCgsh"&gt;Export your LastPass data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="p0nU83"&gt;LastPass allows you to export your data as a CSV or an XML file. If you’re planning to move that data to another service, then CSV is the far better choice. Since CSV stands for comma-separated values and is a plain text file, it’s a good idea not to hold on to it once you’ve moved your data to another password manager — or to put that file in a secure place where it can’t be easily read by someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xeasma"&gt;Before you start, you should be aware that the best (and really only way) you can export your data from LastPass is from its browser extension on a desktop or laptop computer. (You can technically do it from LastPass’ website, but as I’ll explain, it’s more trouble than it’s worth.) If you haven’t downloaded the extension for your browser (links for which are at the bottom of the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lastpass.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22295354%2Flastpass-export-delete-bitwarden-1password-zoho" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;LastPass webpage&lt;/a&gt;), go ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zeiu7w"&gt;Ready?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="dLuNCb"&gt;Click your extension icon and proceed to “Account Options” &amp;gt; “Advanced” &amp;gt; “Export” &amp;gt; “LastPass CSV File” &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="zkuNGI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10357378"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="wFkJ78"&gt;You’ll be asked to put in your master password to continue. If you think you may be interrupted at some point, and you’re working in a safe place (like a home office), feel free to ask it not to prompt you again for up to 24 hours.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Fill in your master password to download your data." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CobeFB32JkC412Nfc7R9QdgDlX4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22323021/Screen_Shot_2021_02_22_at_3.19.10_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fill in your master password to download your data.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="UkWlck"&gt;That’s it! LastPass will immediately download your CSV file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ufu3cs"&gt;If you really, &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; don’t want to install the browser extension, here’s how you can get your info from the LastPass website”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="ghoVJG"&gt;Go to &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2FLastPass.com&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22295354%2Flastpass-export-delete-bitwarden-1password-zoho" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;LastPass.com&lt;/a&gt; and sign in to your account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cyi6V4"&gt;Click on “Advanced Options” in the left-hand menu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="49WLuB"&gt;Click on “Export” and enter your Master Password if asked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="OGUdTE"&gt;If your experience is anything like mine, you should then see a comma-delimited list of all your passwords on a separate webpage. You can select all the content of the page by going to your top menu and selecting “Edit” &amp;gt; “Select All.” You can then copy the data and paste it to a text page using a word processor or other text app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="5oOQ7w"&gt;Once you’ve downloaded your info, you can upload it to the password manager of your choice. There are a variety out there, free and otherwise, and we’ve included a sampling below, along with their starting prices (if any) and links to their instructions on how to import your data. But first, we’re assuming that you’ll want to eventually delete your passwords from LastPass. Here’s how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2RNDLc"&gt;Delete your LastPass account&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Ro31y2"&gt;Once you’ve chosen your new password manager (and we strongly suggest you live with it for at least a week or so first), you can delete your account and data from LastPass. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="I69pUD"&gt;Using your browser, go to the LastPass &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Flastpass.com%2Fdelete_account.php&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22295354%2Flastpass-export-delete-bitwarden-1password-zoho" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;“Delete Your Account”&lt;/a&gt; page &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The LastPass “Delete Your Account” page" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YIrrK8mwD5_V4s_lVhfSHLLS0Xg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22323028/Screen_Shot_2021_02_23_at_10.15.26_AM__1_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The LastPass “Delete Your Account” page.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="U2ghoU"&gt;Click on the red “Delete” button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ovimRl"&gt;Where you go from here depends on whether you remember your master password. If you do remember it, click on “Yes.” You’ll be given one last chance to download your data, will be asked to enter your master password, and asked why you are deleting your account. Then click on Delete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Before you delete your account, you get a last chance to download your data" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7kTTC5TS3eIat49_QSNdYvOU2tQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22323037/Screen_Shot_2021_02_23_at_10.21.25_AM__1_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Before you delete your account, you get a last chance to download your data.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="jocBsx"&gt;If you don’t remember your master password, click on “No.” You’ll be given a chance to download your data and asked for your email address. You’ll be sent an email with a link that will let you delete the account.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="5Ej9In"&gt;In either case, remember &lt;em&gt;there is no rush to delete your account&lt;/em&gt;. Make sure that you have a useable copy of your passwords and a new password manager that you’re satisfied with first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="92vI29"&gt;Alternative password managers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="WTT0PE"&gt;What follows is a list of some alternative password managers and where you can find instructions for importing your LastPass data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="S4oUCj"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://bitwarden.com/"&gt;Bitwarden&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="cmCuL1"&gt;Free version? Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="S8egTf"&gt;Paid features start at $10 / year and include file storage, authenticator, two-step login, others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="eS3eKE"&gt;&lt;a href="https://bitwarden.com/help/article/import-from-lastpass/#export-from-lastpass"&gt;Instructions for importing from LastPass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="iulnkY"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dashlane.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22295354%2Flastpass-export-delete-bitwarden-1password-zoho" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Dashlane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="vGR2kl"&gt;Free version? Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="TclFRm"&gt;Paid features start at $4.99 / month and include unlimited passwords and devices, a VPN, others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kPaAdv"&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.dashlane.com/hc/en-us/articles/202699141"&gt;Instructions for importing from LastPass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="zHjAlr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://keepass.info/"&gt;KeePass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="YpsRxK"&gt;Free version? Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="tudA3y"&gt;No paid features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="twkz8i"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://keepass.info/help/base/importexport.html#genericcsv"&gt;Instructions for importing CSV files&lt;/a&gt;. (Note: According to &lt;a href="https://keepass.info/help/base/importexport.html"&gt;KeePass’ Import / Export help page&lt;/a&gt;, the app does have a specific import for LastPass that is accessible from within the app.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="uNJbNU"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.logmeonce.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22295354%2Flastpass-export-delete-bitwarden-1password-zoho" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;LogMeOnce&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="9ttYUw"&gt;Free version? Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="HK4ZEI"&gt;Paid features start at $2.50 / month and include encrypted storage, additional password sharing, emergency access, live password tracker, others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vpooYn"&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.logmeonce.com/hc/en-us/articles/231830127-How-to-import-your-password-from-LastPass-Vault"&gt;Instructions for importing from LastPass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="3Jrz5d"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fnordpass.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22295354%2Flastpass-export-delete-bitwarden-1password-zoho" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;NordPass&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="4MBvaM"&gt;Free version? Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="sMxIhR"&gt;Paid features start at $1.49 / month and include syncing across devices, ability to have more than one active device, secure item sharing, others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EapF29"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://support.nordpass.com/hc/en-us/articles/360002377197-How-to-import-passwords-to-NordPass-"&gt;Instructions for importing CSV files&lt;/a&gt;. (Note: has separate instructions for &lt;a href="https://support.nordpass.com/hc/en-us/articles/360002451278-How-to-export-passwords-from-LastPass-"&gt;exporting data from LastPass&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="iOroP9"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.tkqlhce.com/click-8836598-14464697?sid=VergeHowToLeavLastPass&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2F1password.com%2F"&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="SzuEc3"&gt;Free version? No&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="QWbZz4"&gt;Paid features start at $35.88 / year and include unlimited passwords, 1GB storage, email support, one year of item history, and others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="5Rj7n7"&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.1password.com/import-lastpass/"&gt;Instructions for importing from LastPass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="HB9C1T"&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.roboform.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22295354%2Flastpass-export-delete-bitwarden-1password-zoho" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;RoboForm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="QTomo3"&gt;Free version? Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="BLK9R0"&gt;Paid features start at $23.88 / year and include syncing across devices, cloud backup, two-factor authorization, shared folder, and others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="E63I52"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://help.roboform.com/hc/en-us/articles/360019139931-How-to-Import-from-a-CSV-File"&gt;Instructions for importing CSV files&lt;/a&gt;. (Note: RoboForm has specific instructions for importing LastPass files to &lt;a href="https://help.roboform.com/hc/en-us/articles/229761267-How-to-import-from-LastPass-on-Windows"&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://help.roboform.com/hc/en-us/articles/360001433452-How-to-import-from-LastPass-on-Mac"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt; systems; however, they include statements that separate apps are needed to export data from LastPass, which is no longer the case.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="yIZ6k6"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.zoho.com/vault/"&gt;Zoho Vault&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="9HQqBR"&gt;Free version? Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hGrPFX"&gt;Paid features start at $10.80 / year and include secure password sharing, password expiration alerts, cloud backup, and others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="A8L9st"&gt;&lt;a href="https://help.zoho.com/portal/en/kb/vault/user-guide/articles/vault-import-passwords-from-other-password-managers#Import_passwords_from_LastPass_CSV"&gt;Instructions for importing CSV files&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="5DlZlZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Six free alternatives to the LastPass password manager","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22285499/password-manager-lastpass-free-bitwarden-zoho"},{"title":"LastPass’ free tier will become a lot less useful next month","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/16/22285531/lastpass-free-tier-mobile-computer-device-premium-family"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="G5nkGM"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 24th, 5:30PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article has been updated to add instructions for importing to Dashlane.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22295354/lastpass-export-delete-bitwarden-1password-zoho"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22295354/lastpass-export-delete-bitwarden-1password-zoho</id>
    <author>
      <name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-24T17:10:03-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T17:10:03-05:00</updated>
    <title>Museum Alive is dioramas but AR, with narration by David Attenborough</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T0i7ulWujYsPCDmIwX__hataYUk=/0x0:2000x1333/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68870131/DSC00276_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Museum Alive includes three exhibits that bring extinct creatures back to life. | Photo: Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="iv9TUX"&gt;Remember dioramas? They were the friggin’ best. I’d jump on any excuse to grab a shoebox, fire up the hot glue gun (okay, Dad handled that), and strategically place plastic tigers and shrubs in their tiny cardboard habitat. I might have learned something, too, but that was beside the point. I was a tiny god with a world of my own creation in my hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lCCe9B"&gt;That’s not unlike the sense of wonder I felt just now watching a miniature prehistoric habitat spring to life on my dining room table. That little bit of magic happened courtesy of &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/museum-alive/id1548503337"&gt;Museum Alive&lt;/a&gt;, an augmented reality iPhone app available today featuring narration by none other than Sir David Attenborough. It’s an extension of his &lt;a href="http://naturalhistorymuseumalive.com/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Natural History Museum Alive&lt;/em&gt; film&lt;/a&gt; and includes three interactive AR exhibits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="QLenp9"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Move your phone around for a different view as you watch a saber-toothed Smilodon track and maul its unsuspecting prey&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="62EN46"&gt;Each exhibit features an extinct animal in a recreation of its particular habitat. The app directs you to find a flat surface and pinch to zoom the image to the right scale. Once that’s done, the habitat comes to life and a 3D animation begins with Attenborough’s narration. You can move your phone around for a different view as you watch a saber-toothed Smilodon track and maul its unsuspecting prey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="em0dkL"&gt;My only disappointment with the app is that there are only three of these AR exhibits. There’s promise of an upcoming fourth addition of a dodo, but it’s not really clear if the app, which costs $2.99, will get updates beyond that. I can see kids really liking the experience but probably losing interest soon after they’ve explored the three current exhibits. Maybe that’s the right time to bust out the shoeboxes and hot glue gun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xNTGX4"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22299611/museum-alive-iphone-app-david-attenborough-augmented-reality"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22299611/museum-alive-iphone-app-david-attenborough-augmented-reality</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-24T17:07:48-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T17:07:48-05:00</updated>
    <title>Reddit seems to be back after crashing as GME soared</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/48uGJF85_cX_2QhxOeXqNULwC6M=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68869818/acastro_180413_1777_reddit_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="wKiCQy"&gt;Reddit seems to be recovering after what &lt;a href="https://www.redditstatus.com"&gt;its status page called a “major outage”&lt;/a&gt;. For about an hour, users who tried to load the site as it was down were met with a blank white page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BJqxR7"&gt;The site seems to have gone down after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22251427/reddit-gamestop-stock-short-wallstreetbets-robinhood-wall-street"&gt;GameStop stock&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299795/gamestop-stock-up-reddit-wallstreetbets-gme-pump"&gt;shot up 100 percent&lt;/a&gt; in late hours of trading on Wednesday. One of Reddit’s most controversial communities, r/WallStreetBets, has championed the stock and was intensely active after the surge. At the moment, it’s unclear if the two are related, but the subreddit seemed to be getting &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/b_fung/status/1364679012279279616?s=20"&gt;a lot of heavy traffic&lt;/a&gt; right before Reddit began crashing. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ffQ6MI5ADIX-gDYY2yBaj85Peas=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22326593/Screen_Shot_2021_02_24_at_1.12.39_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot: &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Beautiful, minimalistic design.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="IBhOjm"&gt;As of 5PM ET, the site seems to be reliably accessible, if a bit slow to respond. &lt;a href="https://www.redditstatus.com"&gt;Downdetector reports&lt;/a&gt; are falling rapidly, indicating that most people are starting to be able access the site again, and we here at the &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; have been able to load the site as well. &lt;a href="https://www.redditstatus.com"&gt;The status page&lt;/a&gt; also shows the site as “Operational.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="lV9c8r"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Resolved: We're sounding the all clear! This incident is resolved. &lt;a href="https://t.co/7y8D9F3AgI"&gt;https://t.co/7y8D9F3AgI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— reddit status (@redditstatus) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/redditstatus/status/1364700302230704128?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 24, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="c5n02g"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 24th, 5:07PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reddit is now back up and operational.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299822/reddit-down-gme-up-wallstreetbets-stocks"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299822/reddit-down-gme-up-wallstreetbets-stocks</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-24T17:05:49-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T17:05:49-05:00</updated>
    <title>Verizon and AT&amp;T just spent almost $70 billion on spectrum to improve their 5G networks</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0Bs9FQcNFugaRY6eJ7o9M0O050g=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68870113/acastro_180430_1777_5G_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oxXD2Q"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.fcc.gov/document/fcc-announces-winning-bidders-c-band-auction"&gt;much-anticipated results&lt;/a&gt; of the FCC’s Auction 107 are in, with Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T spending big as anticipated on the coveted C-band spectrum. Verizon in particular spent nearly twice as much as AT&amp;amp;T, with a total spend of $45.4 billion. AT&amp;amp;T’s total bid adds up to $23.4 billion. T-Mobile is in a distant third at $9.3 billion, which was also expected thanks to the strong midband spectrum holdings that the company already had following its acquisition of Sprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jGtcsG"&gt;There’s nothing outright surprising here: we’ve known for a while that the total bidding added up to &lt;a href="https://www.fiercewireless.com/regulatory/c-band-clock-phase-auction-tops-charts-80-9b"&gt;over $80 billion&lt;/a&gt;, and that Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T in particular would be the top bidders. Those two carriers’ nationwide 5G networks currently rely on narrower low-band frequencies that offer speeds not much greater than 4G LTE — and extremely fast millimeter wave frequencies that face significant coverage challenges. If there’s any surprise here, it’s just how much more Verizon spent than AT&amp;amp;T.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3ottI2"&gt;What remains to be seen is if the new spectrum will help either carrier catch up to T-Mobile. &lt;a href="https://www.lightreading.com/5g/verizon-wont-catch-t-mobile-with-c-band---analysts/d/d-id/767264"&gt;Some analysts&lt;/a&gt; don’t think it will. In any case, the new frequencies won’t become available until the end of the year at the earliest, and even then, they will be available in limited locations first.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299903/fcc-cband-auction-results-verizon-att-tmobile"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299903/fcc-cband-auction-results-verizon-att-tmobile</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-24T16:50:50-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T16:50:50-05:00</updated>
    <title>Biden signs executive order calling for semiconductor supply chain review</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="President Biden Delivers Remarks On Lives Lost To Covid-19" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kD3njk4f_gprF1Jqgc5oS5sdmH0=/0x0:6000x4000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68866371/1231330766.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ekuCQk"&gt;President Biden signed an executive order Wednesday addressing growing concern over a global semiconductor shortage hampering the production of goods like automobiles and smartphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RnZ0SG"&gt;The White House’s executive order directs the federal government&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;to conduct 100-day reviews of supply chains in four sets of products, including computer chips and large capacity batteries, like those used in electric vehicles, according to administration officials. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aPS5p1"&gt;“This is about making sure the United States can meet every challenge we faced in this new era of pandemics, but also in defense cybersecurity, climate change, and so much more,” Biden said at a press conference Thursday. “The best way to do that is by protecting and and sharpen and America’s competitive edge by investing here at home.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SNlhx7"&gt;The chip shortage was a result of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22278431/biden-administration-global-semiconductor-chip-shortage-executive-order"&gt;a number of factors&lt;/a&gt; created by the coronavirus pandemic. As more of daily life moved online, consumer electronics manufacturers saw an increase in demand for products like laptops. Production of chips also slowed down in part because of the pandemic, and former President Trump’s trade war with China made it more difficult for US companies to work with Chinese chip producers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jrttfz"&gt;This resulted in companies like Apple, AMD, Sony, and Qualcomm raising concern over shortages over the last few weeks, including parts for iPhones and consoles like the PlayStation 5. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="bQ2zyv"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Semiconductors play a critical role in enabling the products and services that fuel our economy”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sdj2Fi"&gt;Earlier this month, lobbying groups for the auto, telecommunications, and technology industries &lt;a href="https://www.semiconductors.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/CHIPS-multi-assn-letter-feb-18-2021_1.pdf"&gt;called on the White House&lt;/a&gt; to work with Congress to provide additional funding for domestic chip research and production. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xbu682"&gt;“Semiconductors play a critical role in enabling the products and services that fuel our economy, contribute to American innovation, and enhance our national security,” the groups said in a letter to Biden last week. “Given the central role of semiconductors, strengthening the US position in semiconductor research, design, and manufacturing is a national priority.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZhAwap"&gt;In a press conference Wednesday, Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer (D-NY) said that Congress &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-china-democrats/top-u-s-senate-democrat-directs-lawmakers-to-craft-bill-to-counter-china-idUSKBN2AN2HJ"&gt;would be working to draft a legislative package&lt;/a&gt; to “outcompete China and create new American jobs” as well as making new investments in the US semiconductor industry. Schumer said he’s looking to bring these items up for a floor vote in the Senate this spring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sfRknH"&gt;“Right now, semiconductor manufacturing is a dangerous weak spot in our economy and in our national security, that has to change,” Schumer said on Wednesday. “We cannot let China get ahead of us in chip production.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mOfHY2"&gt;Outside of the semiconductor supply chain, Biden’s order also calls for similar reviews into the defense, public health, biological preparedness, information communications technology, transportation, and energy and food production sectors, the administration officials said.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dkfMCn"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 24th, 4:50PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article has been updated to reflect that President Biden has signed the executive order.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22298376/biden-sign-semiconductor-shortage-executive-order-apple-amd-playstation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22298376/biden-sign-semiconductor-shortage-executive-order-apple-amd-playstation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-24T16:43:32-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T16:43:32-05:00</updated>
    <title>Watch composer Yuzo Koshiro play his iconic chiptunes through an NEC PC-88</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DmerScADZw2XK-fVPUV7FufAOMw=/0x15:2094x1411/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68869995/koshiropc88.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by &lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://twitter.com/yuzokoshiro" target="_blank"&gt;Yuzo Koshiro / Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IhAdtE"&gt;It’s not hard to listen to your favorite video game soundtracks online. Just load YouTube or some other music streaming services, and search there. But that experience pales in comparison to hearing (and seeing) that music played through the hardware it was originally composed on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lx2LCt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/yuzokoshiro"&gt;Legendary gaming composer Yuzo Koshiro&lt;/a&gt; has been posting nostalgia bombs on Twitter, playing songs that he made for games like &lt;em&gt;Streets of Rage, Streets of Rage 2&lt;/em&gt;, and the 8-Bit Game Gear and Sega Master System versions of &lt;em&gt;Sonic The Hedgehog. &lt;/em&gt;And he’s playing them using an NEC PC-88, the 39-year-old PC that was a popular gaming platform in Japan, as well as Koshiro’s machine of choice for creating music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="naFRGA"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="ja" dir="ltr"&gt;Recorded SOR2 Go Straight from PC88FA headphone out. No EQ and compression. -14.5LUFS.&lt;br&gt;If you want the best sounding of SOR, nothing can beat the PC88. &lt;br&gt;88FAのヘッドフォンアウトがなかなか良い音していたのでベア2 Go Straightを録音してみました。やはり実機が一番良い音です   &lt;a href="https://t.co/Je4nmUBKaW"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Je4nmUBKaW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Yuzo Koshiro (@yuzokoshiro) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/yuzokoshiro/status/1362778079383359495?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 19, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="4Bu5P1"&gt;Listening to the tunes is fun, especially if you’ve played the games, but these videos are even better than going to a concert. You get to watch a storied music-maker play his tunes through hardware that’s likely very difficult and expensive to find currently. I like the little gadgets he uses to make loading files and navigating easier. There’s just a tiny monitor on top of the PC-88 instead of a gargantuan CRT monitor from another era, and the music is being loaded into the PC through a controller and interface that helps it recognize the SD card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="HNAOmI"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Have you ever known GG/SMS Sonic music was made with PC88? I made most of my PSG-leveled music (GG, MSX, etc.) with it. It couldn't use all the DCSG functions but was comfortable and fast. This video plays all the song's intro including unused tracks running through. &lt;a href="https://t.co/LOpImRZbJ6"&gt;pic.twitter.com/LOpImRZbJ6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Yuzo Koshiro (@yuzokoshiro) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/yuzokoshiro/status/1364128000699101186?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 23, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fuwmkr"&gt;Koshiro obviously has a lot of experience in composing music, but it’s his knowledge of programming in BASIC that helped him get comfortable using something like the PC-88 to express his musical talents. I learned that about him in this extensive Red Bull Music Academy interview he did a few years ago, which I’ve embedded below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="OWHAkk"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TAuAM75Pf5w?rel=0&amp;amp;%3Bstart=1988&amp;amp;start=1988" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/2/24/22299391/yuzo-koshiro-nec-pc88-pc-streets-of-rage-sonic-music"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/2/24/22299391/yuzo-koshiro-nec-pc88-pc-streets-of-rage-sonic-music</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-24T16:24:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T16:24:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>Showtime’s live-action Halo TV show is now a Paramount Plus exclusive</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/flwTEFjknQhEYwjxUkJV4JtUzfY=/425x0:2018x1062/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68869828/Screen_Shot_2019_03_18_at_4.04.49_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Microsoft/343 Industries&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Xta8sR"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/28/17514578/halo-tv-series-showtime-microsoft-xbox"&gt;Showtime’s upcoming &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; TV series&lt;/a&gt; is getting a new home — the live-action adaptation of the popular sci-fi shooters will now debut exclusively on the relaunched Paramount Plus streaming service when it arrives at the beginning of 2022, &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2021/02/halo-tv-series-latest-paramount-plus-move-1234698703/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deadline&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DdFkGB"&gt;There have been a few attempts at adapting &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; to live action (including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/11/6/7164047/ridley-scott-halo-nightfall-thoughts"&gt;the less-than-stellar &lt;em&gt;Halo: Nightfall&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), of which the Showtime series is the latest. It’s been in the works since 2018 and promises to actually focus on the star of the series: Master Chief Petty Officer John-117, the armored star of the series more commonly known as Master Chief (played by &lt;em&gt;American Gods&lt;/em&gt;’ Pablo Schreiber.) The show will also see Jen Taylor return to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/11/21561137/halo-tv-show-cortana-recast-jen-taylor"&gt;reprise her role as Cortana&lt;/a&gt;, Master Chief’s AI companion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LcYojm"&gt;“We were on the hunt for signature shows beyond the &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt; franchise on CBS All Access and were thinking, what could be a defining series for Paramount+,” David Nevins, who serves both as the chief creative officer at CBS  and the CEO of Showtime, said to &lt;em&gt;Deadline&lt;/em&gt;. “&lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; always fit the bill but seeing it, we felt it would work.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1SCXjQ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halo &lt;/em&gt;was originally intended to release in 2021, but the show has since been delayed due to a pause in production caused by the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RLAGTl"&gt;Paramount Plus is the relaunched version of CBS All Access, which will combine content from the recently remerged CBS and Paramount together into a single streaming service. &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; joins other marquee titles for the service, including &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt; shows like &lt;em&gt;Picard&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Discovery&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;SpongeBob SquarePants&lt;/em&gt; spinoff &lt;em&gt;Kamp Koral, &lt;/em&gt;and the Godfather making-of drama &lt;em&gt;The Offer&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299828/halo-tv-show-paramount-plus-exclusive-showtime-microsoft"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22299828/halo-tv-show-paramount-plus-exclusive-showtime-microsoft</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
