<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-04T18:23:10-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-04T18:23:10-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-04T18:23:10-05:00</updated>
    <title>Ford is more than doubling its investment in electric and autonomous vehicles to $29 billion </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HGpTkCCf6RneVUTJh7Otk6R3Ke8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68771759/sokane_210125_4386_1753.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Sean O’Kane / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SkFBfj"&gt;Ford is increasing its investment in electric and autonomous vehicles to $29 billion, the company’s top executives said in an earnings call Thursday. The automaker had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/15/16892386/ford-electric-car-11-billion-2022-detroit-auto-show-2018"&gt;previously committed to spend $11.5 billion&lt;/a&gt; on electrifying its vehicle lineup through 2022. Now, Ford says it will spend double that amount, while extending the timeline to 2025. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OCUVZg"&gt;The automaker will spend $7 billion on autonomous vehicles and $22 billion on electric ones. That $22 billion includes $7 billion that the company has already spent since 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OkBldR"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The automaker will spend $7 billion on autonomous vehicles and $22 billion on electric ones&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="F5Jgfu"&gt;Ford said a majority of vehicles it plans on producing will be battery-electric vehicles, but the company also has hybrid and plug-in hybrid models that also have traditional internal combustion engines. The company introduced an all-electric Transit van last year, and plans on unveiling an electric version of its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21288000/ford-electric-f-150-2022-sale-launch-jim-farley"&gt;best-selling F-150 pickup truck&lt;/a&gt; later this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a0i4V3"&gt;Ford’s new CEO Jim Farley touted the company’s increased investment as a “more aggressive” plan to position the nation’s oldest automaker as a leader in the future of mobility and transportation. Farley cited Ford’s recent announcement that it would work &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260176/ford-google-android-infotainment-os-2023"&gt;with Google to integrate the tech giant’s Android software&lt;/a&gt; into “millions” of vehicles starting in 2023 as representative of the type of deals involved in Ford’s pivot to a more digital future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nLXGDR"&gt;The increased investment is meant to convince those on Wall Street who have been jittery about Ford’s ability to catch up to Tesla, which has been the only automaker to successfully build an EV business over the last few years. Ford is keeping pace with other legacy automakers like GM and Volkswagen, having just begun delivering its hotly anticipated &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22265570/mustang-mach-e-review-electric-ford-ev-photos-video"&gt;Mustang Mach-E&lt;/a&gt; to customers late last year — though a &lt;a href="https://www.freep.com/story/money/cars/ford/2021/01/16/ford-mustang-mach-e-delivery-delay/4189265001/"&gt;quality review issue&lt;/a&gt; delayed hundreds of additional deliveries last month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="qNEi2O"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Mustang Mach-E review: Ford’s big bet is about to pay off","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22265570/mustang-mach-e-review-electric-ford-ev-photos-video"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="yr6bZS"&gt;Most of the big automakers have said in the past year that they plan on pivoting to all-electric lineups. Daimler AG, the parent company of Mercedes-Benz (Daimler itself is soon to be renamed Mercedes-Benz), said it will produce &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/7/16267856/mercedes-benz-concept-eqa-frankfurt-showcase-mobility-plans"&gt;electrified versions of all of its cars by 2022&lt;/a&gt;. Volvo announced it would start to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/7/5/15921208/volvo-all-electric-by-2019"&gt;phase out gas-only&lt;/a&gt; car production in 2019, while the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/11/16289292/vw-electrify-entire-300-car-lineup-2030"&gt;Volkswagen Group&lt;/a&gt; is going to make everything electric in some shape or form by 2030. And China’s rising prominence in the auto market, in addition to that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/28/16379094/china-fossil-fuels-electric-vehicles"&gt;country’s restrictions&lt;/a&gt; on manufacturing fossil-fuel burning vehicles, is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/11/8/16625938/ford-china-zotye-electric-cars-manufacturing"&gt;certainly putting pressure&lt;/a&gt; on the entire industry to go electric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N9KRvN"&gt;Ford isn’t even the only car maker to greatly increase its bet on electric. Late last year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/19/21575153/gm-electric-ev-investment-deadline-cadillac-chevy-hummer"&gt;GM said it would spend $27 billion&lt;/a&gt; on electric and autonomous vehicles through 2025 — up from the $20 billion it announced before the COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22267195/ford-electric-autonomous-investment-29-billion"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22267195/ford-electric-autonomous-investment-29-billion</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-04T17:55:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-04T17:55:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>Pinterest had a giant fourth quarter thanks to a strong holiday season</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BgkXZDEzf6aKb3zbLBSz3KgvACY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68771540/akrales_170802_1743_0198.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JI8rg3"&gt;Like other online platforms, Pinterest reaped the benefits of an uptick in e-commerce advertising during the holiday season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8LCvWI"&gt;The image-sharing platform saw a 76 percent year-over-year jump in fourth quarter revenue, to $706 million, the &lt;a href="https://investor.pinterestinc.com/press-releases/press-releases-details/2021/Pinterest-Announces-Fourth-Quarter-and-Full-Year-2020-Results/default.aspx"&gt;company said Thursday&lt;/a&gt;. Pinterest had 459 global million monthly active users (MAUs) in the fourth quarter, up from 442 million in &lt;a href="https://investor.pinterestinc.com/press-releases/press-releases-details/2020/Pinterest-Announces-Third-Quarter-2020-Results/default.aspx"&gt;its third quarter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L6kOE5"&gt;Pinterest said in its &lt;a href="https://s23.q4cdn.com/958601754/files/doc_financials/2020/q4/Pinterest-Q4-Shareholder-Letter.pdf"&gt;letter to investors&lt;/a&gt; that its revenue growth was mostly driven by a robust holiday season and product improvements in advertising. It saw a six-fold increase in the number of businesses that used its shopping ads format during the fourth quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hyHUKJ"&gt;“We welcomed over 100 million additional monthly active users to Pinterest in 2020, more than any other year in our history,” CEO and co-founder Ben Silbermann said in a statement. During a call with analysts Thursday, Silbermann said the company was encouraged by its growth among Gen Z consumers, who he said are well-served by other social media platforms, but come to Pinterest “because they want spaces where they can explore their own interests and hobbies.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="tqexeZ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Pinterest is experimenting with sponsored story pins&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bwRDme"&gt;Pinterest saw revenue in the US — its biggest market — rise 67 percent in the fourth quarter, to $582 million. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fqJbGH"&gt;“Our investments in ad tools and sales coverage continued to pay off, especially during a strong holiday season. Advertising demand was healthy across different advertiser sizes and verticals, with retail demand further building off last quarter’s recovery,” the letter said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e9JHft"&gt;In response to an analyst question about Pinterest’s roadmap for helping creators make money on the platform, Silbermann said the company was bringing on creators known for their ability to teach something rather than pure entertainment. And Pinterest content has a much longer shelf life than other online platforms, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kYOQPW"&gt;“[Pinterest] creators are in an environment where there’s a strong search dynamic, more like YouTube than other social spaces that tend to be more ephemeral,” he said. The company also is experimenting with things like sponsored story pins, Silbermann added. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pe7vvk"&gt;The company’s growth comes amid &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/1/21755406/pinterest-shareholders-lawsuit-sue-toxic-work-culture-discrimination"&gt;allegations of a toxic work environment&lt;/a&gt;; a group of shareholders is suing Silbermann and other top Pinterest executives for “marginalizing women who dared to challenge Pinterest’s White, male leadership clique,” and hurting the company’s reputation, the complaint alleges. Several women sued the company last year, &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/07/03/pinterest-race-bias-black-employees/"&gt;alleging racial discrimination,&lt;/a&gt; and its former &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/08/11/technology/pinterest-francoise-brougher-gender-discrimination-lawsuit.html"&gt;COO said she was underpaid&lt;/a&gt; compared to her male colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JCQTFt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/finance/quote/PINS:NYSE"&gt;Pinterest shares were up&lt;/a&gt; more than 10 percent in after-market trading Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0r6FRk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="brQrUA"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266974/pinterest-fourth-quarter-revenue-holiday-growth-creators"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266974/pinterest-fourth-quarter-revenue-holiday-growth-creators</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-04T17:48:31-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-04T17:48:31-05:00</updated>
    <title>Even you can afford Serena Williams’ gamer chair</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r0uqc3ozgb637VyVpPDOY8jU6IU=/320x0:2354x1356/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68771476/Screen_Shot_2021_02_04_at_4.56.20_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qq8XB6"&gt;There’s a great deal to gawk at in Serena Williams’ house, from the perfectly shined wood floors to furniture made of Elmo dolls. But there’s one item that feels out of place in house full of luxury: a cutesy pastel gamer chair. You can spot the oddly pedestrian item in a &lt;a href="https://www.architecturaldigest.com/story/step-inside-serena-williams-striking-florida-home"&gt;recent feature from &lt;em&gt;Architectural Digest&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OqScUJ"&gt;There’s no rule that a legendary athlete like Williams needs a bougie, high-end chair that costs more than most people’s rent. But given the other features of her house (see: hidden room and big clear piano), it’s surprising, and a little endearing, to spot something so... average. As &lt;a href="https://jezebel.com/serena-williamss-interior-decor-is-a-nerds-delight-1846199282"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jezebel &lt;/em&gt;points out&lt;/a&gt;, Williams’ chair — dubiously named “Zeanus Pink Ergonomic Gaming Chair for Girl” because it’s pink, I guess — is shockingly affordable. Right now, it’s going for $189.99 on sites like &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newegg.com%2Fp%2F358-007Z-00004%23&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F2%2F4%2F22267001%2Fserena-williams-gamer-chair#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Newegg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WJdDT2"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-TeeIEh2IE8?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Qhi5n6"&gt;Anyway, maybe it’s not about the price or quality at all. This chair? Only for girl. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22267001/serena-williams-gamer-chair"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22267001/serena-williams-gamer-chair</id>
    <author>
      <name>Megan Farokhmanesh</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-04T17:42:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-04T17:42:47-05:00</updated>
    <title>Diablo IV and Overwatch 2 aren’t launching this year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Overwatch" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ADtgvvlfqbwyH-XwB8ol4gZy6Hs=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68771439/OVR_Ashe_000.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YDBJRn"&gt;Blizzard has two huge sequels in the works, but it looks like neither will launch this year. During its most recent earnings call, Activision Blizzard revealed that it doesn’t expect &lt;em&gt;Overwatch 2&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Diablo IV&lt;/em&gt; to be part of its 2021 financials, suggesting both will launch in 2022 or later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ph5R0F"&gt;Technically, this doesn’t represent a delay since neither game had a specific release date in place. Both&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20943766/blizzard-overwatch-2-sequel-announcement-blizzcon-2019"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Overwatch 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20942565/diablo-4-announced-release-date-blizzcon-2019"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Diablo IV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; were first announced at BlizzCon 2019, and the developer has been relatively quiet since then, particularly about the &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; sequel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V98E9t"&gt;That said, while the games may be further off than many fans expected, we’ll still likely hear more about them soon. Blizzard will kick off a remote version of BlizzCon on February 19th, and the keynote presentation is typically filled with trailers and announcements for all of the studio’s franchises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lKG64R"&gt;There will be at least some &lt;em&gt;Diablo&lt;/em&gt; this year, however, with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22180377/diablo-immortal-iphone-android-technical-alpha-preview"&gt;the mobile spinoff &lt;em&gt;Diablo Immortal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; expected to launch in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22267131/diablo-4-overwatch-2-release-date-2022-activision-blizzard-earnings"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22267131/diablo-4-overwatch-2-release-date-2022-activision-blizzard-earnings</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-04T17:33:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-04T17:33:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>The latest GameStop stock dip looks like the end of the line</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="gamestop" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fUcvbW3Gf66pxzabVr6_zu9iQwE=/0x32:1100x765/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68771381/GameStop_Store_Front_0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CNBYIE"&gt;When GameStop’s stock price fell by over 50 percent on Tuesday, closing at $90, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22262546/gamestop-amc-stock-down-short-squeeze"&gt;we weren’t sure if it was going to pick back up or keep going down&lt;/a&gt;. It seems we now have our answer, as GME is down another 41 percent, closing today at just $53.50. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sD8OHh"&gt;That's &lt;a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/GME/history/"&gt;less than the stock sold for&lt;/a&gt; the week before it took off on a wild rollercoaster ride induced by Reddit retail investors and an unprecedented social media frenzy. So it seems like we’re not so much in a dip, but on the long, slow ride back to the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YB3j2r"&gt;When I wrote &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22262546/gamestop-amc-stock-down-short-squeeze"&gt;about GameStop’s stock dip on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;, the stock was down 81 percent from its peak of $483. Now, it’s down 89 percent from that peak. There was always the chance of a rally (and I guess, technically, there still is), but it seems like the meme may truly be over. If it is, it’s a sad ending: anyone who bought the stock during the rush and has held on to it until now is in the red on GME.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Graph of GameStop’s stock over the past month." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/s5q2UGmhwg7QCoi08iRrbG0xIg8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22282255/Screen_Shot_2021_02_04_at_1.31.58_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple Stocks&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;We’re back to where we were before the big spikes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266684/gamestop-stock-gme-down-dip-falling-wallstreetbets-reddit"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266684/gamestop-stock-gme-down-dip-falling-wallstreetbets-reddit</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-04T17:28:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-04T17:28:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google union files labor board charge against contract company</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gr_PWtwhgS0hsg5AjiNYAWC351Q=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68771360/acastro_180508_1777_google_IO_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KgZx2K"&gt;The Alphabet Workers Union (AWU) has filed an unfair labor charge against Adecco, a subcontracting firm that provides data center services to Google. The union says managers tried to stop Google contractors from discussing pay, which is illegal. Shannon Wait, a union member and contractor, was suspended after posting about working conditions on Facebook. &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-02-04/alphabet-union-alleges-contract-workers-were-silenced-about-pay"&gt;The news was first reported by &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U78oHc"&gt;The charge is the first legal action the Alphabet Workers Union has taken to protect employees. Since the union went public in early January, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/8/22220778/alphabet-workers-union-demands-youtube-ban-trump"&gt;it’s called on YouTube to ban Donald Trump&lt;/a&gt; and voiced concern with the treatment of AI ethics researcher Margaret Mitchell, but both of these actions took the form of open letters and had no legal force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ByNUAh"&gt;Now, AWU is alleging that Adecco and Google retaliated against Wait after she posted about working conditions at a data center in Berkeley County, South Carolina. The complaint classifies the two companies as joint employers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="njCn1R"&gt;Wait’s Facebook post centered in part on management’s refusal to replace broken water bottles at the facility. She said she’d joined the union to fight for better treatment for contractors, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-02-04/alphabet-union-alleges-contract-workers-were-silenced-about-pay"&gt;according to an interview in &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “We are the backbone of Google,” she added. “We are doing the hard work.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mZVD1w"&gt;The charge also alleges Wait was retaliated against for her union support. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lj3vhP"&gt;After Wait published the post, she was questioned by a supervisor. This same individual previously asked her not to talk about pay with colleagues after she inquired about some workers not receiving a promised bonus. Shortly after, Wait was suspended. Management said she was being investigated as a possible security risk, according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F3zmQV"&gt;“I want other TVCs [temporary, vendor, and contract employees] to see this and know they have recourse if they see something illegal or unethical in their workplace,” said Parul Koul, executive chair of the Alphabet Workers Union, in a press release. “Alphabet’s segregated, two-tiered employment system will not stand in the way of worker solidarity. We will continue to support Shannon and all Alphabet workers against unjust working conditions and fear mongering from management.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L6L6FH"&gt;Google did not immediately respond to a request for comment from &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266962/alphabet-workers-union-filing-unfair-labor-charge-google-contractor-adecco"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266962/alphabet-workers-union-filing-unfair-labor-charge-google-contractor-adecco</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-04T16:54:41-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-04T16:54:41-05:00</updated>
    <title>Niagara is a minimalist Android launcher I wish I’d had on my bus commute</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sHQI40ORAsdl-YM_pTV2MbVvYYk=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68771065/DSC00106.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Niagara Launcher puts your apps within easy striking distance of your thumb.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TOd31n"&gt;After a couple years of beta testing, Niagara Launcher is now &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=bitpit.launcher&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;gl=US"&gt;available for download from the Google Play Store&lt;/a&gt;. It’s designed to replace the default Android app drawer and home screen grid with a layout that’s easier to access with one hand. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fZIrlX"&gt;You pick your favorite apps to pin on the home screen, and the rest are accessible under an alphabetized list on the right side of the screen in easy striking distance of your thumb. It’s quick and very responsive; you can either tap on the part of the alphabet you’re aiming for or swipe up and down to scroll your list of apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eS7Yah"&gt;Niagara also allows you to take quick action from the home screen by swiping across any app to bring up a list of options, like setting a new timer in the clock app or starting a session with Strava. Favorited apps will also show a preview of notification content on the home screen, and a swipe will expand this to show the full text without opening the app. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ukD9Cp"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Favorited apps will also show a preview of notification content on the home screen&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="p2csS7"&gt;These basic features are available with the free version, but customizing your home screen further with additional widgets and displaying your battery life percentage requires an upgrade to the paid pro version, which costs $6 per year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fr5uw5"&gt;Niagara features a clever design, and it would really come in handy on a big phone. I also would have appreciated it on my standing-room-only bus commutes in the Before Time, when I often clung to a rail with one hand for dear life while checking my email with the other. It’s pretty handy on a smaller phone, too, for a more informative look at your notifications without requiring you to open an app. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hONDG7"&gt;The free version does not contain ads, which is another plus. Yet while the launcher does offer the basics, it’s a little bit of a letdown that it doesn’t let you add something as simple as a weather widget without paying for the upgrade. Overall, though, Niagara offers a clean look and a unique solution for those of us with one-handed woes.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266910/niagara-android-launcher-minamalist-one-hand-commute"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266910/niagara-android-launcher-minamalist-one-hand-commute</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-04T16:47:35-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-04T16:47:35-05:00</updated>
    <title>Snap says its TikTok competitor already has 100 million monthly users</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r-9qvqgfzetwFA8YD5MQSNHBdK4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68771024/snapChatPattern_BW.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="T9LAwZ"&gt;Snap says &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/23/21585513/snapchat-snap-spotlight-creators-app-update-tiktok"&gt;its TikTok competitor&lt;/a&gt;, Spotlight, &lt;a href="https://investor.snap.com/news/news-details/2021/Snap-Inc.-Announces-Fourth-Quarter-and-Full-Year-2020-Financial-Results/default.aspx"&gt;had 100 million users&lt;/a&gt; in January 2021, just two months after it launched. The figure would suggest a surprisingly successful debut for the service, which has taken over the rightmost tab inside of Snapchat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4vupOS"&gt;“We’re very pleasantly surprised with the momentum,” Snap CEO Evan Spiegel said on a call with investors this afternoon to discuss the company’s Q4 2020 earnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C5wYl0"&gt;TikTok likely still has a significant lead on the new service, though. TikTok said it &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/08/24/tiktok-reveals-us-global-user-growth-numbers-for-first-time.html"&gt;had 100 million monthly users&lt;/a&gt; in the United States alone as of June 2020, and signs suggest the app has only continued to grow since then. (On the other hand, Instagram’s leader has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22238513/instagram-adam-mosseri-reels-decoder-interview-podcast"&gt;said he’s “not yet happy with” Reels&lt;/a&gt;, its shortform video competitor.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="TIujEw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Snapchat officially launches in-app TikTok competitor called Spotlight","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/23/21585513/snapchat-snap-spotlight-creators-app-update-tiktok"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="t57Tg9"&gt;Snap has put a lot of money behind Spotlight in order to help the section catch on. The company promised to give away $1 million per day to creators for more than a month in order to get people posting videos, filling the service with fun stuff to watch. The initiative seemingly worked, with some creators seeing the service as &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/15/style/snapchat-spotlight.html"&gt;a quick way to make a lot of cash&lt;/a&gt;. Creators are now uploading an average of 175,000 videos per day, Spiegel said in prepared remarks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EEXxqt"&gt;“While it is still very early in the development of this new content platform, we are highly encouraged by the initial results and excited about the potential for Spotlight to further expand our monetization opportunity in the future,” Snap CFO Derek Andersen said in prepared remarks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WQSH5f"&gt;Now that the service has been seeded with videos, Spiegel said that Snap can start doing more work around optimizing its recommendation system. Ads will come down the road, but for now the company has its “focus on growing engagement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="akdsJ0"&gt;Spotlight is still far more limited than TikTok. Exploration options are limited, and you can’t remix sounds or go down a rabbit hole of dance videos to a popular song, both features that have helped TikTok continue to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nLJgLo"&gt;It’s also worth noting that Snap gave the figure in terms of monthly users when the company has long placed a focus on daily users overall. That suggests the daily usage of the feature is a good amount lower, given that someone only needed to open the tab once in January to be considered a monthly user. Snap now boasts 265 million daily users overall, up from 249 million the prior quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NDVT3g"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update February 4th, 6:14PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This story has been updated with remarks from Snap’s earnings call.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266970/snap-spotlight-100-million-mau-q4-2020-earnings"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266970/snap-spotlight-100-million-mau-q4-2020-earnings</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-04T16:30:12-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-04T16:30:12-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google is weighing an anti-tracking feature for Android, following Apple’s lead</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7GqZ7rzl3eJHMMEzH_uM2rn3p38=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68770894/acastro_190228_1777_vpn_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OQOo4A"&gt;Google is considering developing an Android alternative to Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/28/22253366/apple-app-tracking-transparency-opt-in-requirement-beta-launch"&gt;upcoming App Tracking Transparency&lt;/a&gt;, a new planned opt-in requirement the iPhone maker will impose on developers that demands they ask for permission to track iOS users across apps and websites. The news, first &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-02-04/google-explores-alternative-to-apple-s-new-anti-tracking-feature?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;reported on Thursday by &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, underscores the increasing pressure on large tech companies, many spurred on by Apple, to take more proactive measures to better protect user privacy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MkP3j3"&gt;Google won’t say whether it is indeed working on an anti-tracking privacy measure for Android. But in a statement, a Google spokesperson tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, “We’re always looking for ways to work with developers to raise the bar on privacy while enabling a healthy, ad-supported app ecosystem.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w2S3M4"&gt;First announced at Apple’s developer conference last summer, App Tracking Transparency effectively slides a system-level opt in between an app’s tracking capabilities and a user’s preferences. If the user says they would rather not be tracked, there’s nothing the developer can do to get around that because Apple will disable a developer’s ability to gather the so-called Identifier for Advertisers code, or IDFA. That code both lets advertisers track users from one app or website to another for ad targeting while also helping advertisers measure the effectiveness of ads, such as whether a user ends up purchasing a product they saw on one app by using the mobile website of the merchant. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="vdCIpJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Google’s take on App Tracking Transparency may not be as severe&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CWkW9z"&gt;Apple intends to police developers using audits and other methods to enforce its policies, which include potentially suspending or banning apps from the App Store if a developer does not comply. Both Facebook and Google have publicly expressed concern for how Apple’s opt-in requirement could negatively affect their mobile advertising networks. But Facebook has gone a step further and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/1/22260274/facebook-prompt-apple-ios-ad-tracking-opt-in-permission-privacy-update"&gt;begun waging a public relations war&lt;/a&gt; against Apple over the change by complaining it will harm small businesses and accusing Apple of being self-serving. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vNoHfl"&gt;Google’s take on App Tracking Transparency would likely not be as severe, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;reports. Instead of forcing opt-in requirements on app developers, the Android alternative may resemble some of the upcoming privacy controls planned for Google’s Chrome browser, in which the company seeks to end some of the more insidious tracking technologies on the web today by developing less invasive alternatives and giving users more opt-out mechanisms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cf9YCA"&gt;Google’s work to develop new privacy practices and standards for the web is known as the &lt;a href="https://www.chromium.org/Home/chromium-privacy/privacy-sandbox"&gt;Privacy Sandbox&lt;/a&gt;. As part of that ongoing project, Google has taken steps to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/31/21349538/google-changes-ads-data-cookies-privacy"&gt;phase out third-party cookies on Chrome&lt;/a&gt; and is working on tools that allow advertisers to target groups of users instead of directly targeting individuals. All of this could inform how Google develops an anti-tracking measure for Android, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;reports. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266823/google-anti-tracking-feature-android-privacy-apple-ios-app-tracking-transparency"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266823/google-anti-tracking-feature-android-privacy-apple-ios-app-tracking-transparency</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-04T16:11:16-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-04T16:11:16-05:00</updated>
    <title>Smartmatic sues Fox News, Rudy Giuliani, and others over election disinformation campaign</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-POLITICS-ELECTION-TRUMP" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rF8vzfFRRyvvIFjYDz12d0TKHe4=/0x0:4500x3000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68770796/1230450427.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Brendan Smialowski / AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZMjKjC"&gt;Voting tech company &lt;a href="https://www.smartmatic.com/uploads/Smartmatic_Complaint_Against_Fox_Corporation.pdf"&gt;Smartmatic has sued&lt;/a&gt; Fox News, former Trump attorneys Rudy Giuliani and Sidney Powell, and TV host Lou Dobbs for spreading a conspiracy theory about the 2020 US presidential election. The New York state court lawsuit says Fox and others deliberately made Smartmatic the “villain” in a false story about fraudulent voting. Since then, it says, employees have received death threats, and clients have balked at the company’s tarnished reputation. It’s demanding $2.7 billion in damages and a full retraction of all false statements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pZo5Pf"&gt;Smartmatic figured heavily in a sprawling and baseless claim that former President Donald Trump won the 2020 election. The conspiracy &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/uk-factcheck-smartmatic-ceo-biden-team-d/fact-checksmartmatic-ceo-is-not-on-bidensteamsmartmatic-software-is-not-on-dominion-voting-machines-idUSKBN2801ZJ"&gt;alleged that Smartmatic&lt;/a&gt; secretly owned its competitor Dominion and was founded by associates of long-dead Venezuelan President Hugo Chavez in order to steal elections. (Smartmatic’s founders are from Venezuela, but they launched the company in Florida and deny any links to Chavez.) It also asserted that Smartmatic technology contained a “backdoor” that had let conspirators remotely change vote counts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="hjR1U6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Smartmatic was roped into a sprawling conspiracy involving rigged votes and Hugo Chavez&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Txmsez"&gt;As Smartmatic notes, the company is unaffiliated with Dominion and played a minimal role in the election, providing software only to Los Angeles County. However, the claims received &lt;a href="https://www.mediamatters.org/voter-fraud-and-suppression/smartmatic-conspiracy-theories-proliferated-throughout-right-wing-media"&gt;widespread coverage&lt;/a&gt; on conservative news networks like Fox, often through Powell and Giuliani, who were promoting a &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/4ad3ad/sidney-powells-release-the-kraken-lawsuits-are-a-real-mess"&gt;fruitless legal fight&lt;/a&gt; to overturn the election results. “Defendants’ story was a lie. All of it. And they knew it,” the complaint reads. “Overnight, Smartmatic went from an under-the-radar election technology and software company with a track record of success to the villain in Defendants’ disinformation campaign.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hfryjj"&gt;Smartmatic — which operates in several fields outside election tech — claims the disinformation campaign caused at least two commercial partners to suspend their business relationship. The complaint also says it has threatened employees’ safety. Soon after the reports started, the company was “inundated” with emails and voicemails, some claiming that “you all will be hunted” or that the only way to restore election integrity was to “shoot dead your company executives.” One caller allegedly harassed an executive’s 14-year-old son, and despite increased security, the threats have “left Smartmatic’s personnel shaken and scared.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="PR9601"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Threats “left Smartmatic’s personnel shaken and scared”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PoCcme"&gt;The company previously threatened Fox News and other outlets with a lawsuit, leading Fox hosts to &lt;a href="https://video.foxbusiness.com/v/6217257237001"&gt;air&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://video.foxnews.com/v/6217367139001#sp=show-clips"&gt;a&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://video.foxnews.com/v/6217414534001#sp=show-clips"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; effectively contradicting their earlier segments. However, it argues that Dobbs (along with Maria Bartiromo and Jeanine Pirro, who are also named in the suit) never acknowledged the network had promoted false claims. And it says Fox “intentionally avoided” experts who might contract the false claims about Smartmatic, even after the stories were widely debunked elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ApAiyz"&gt;Fox News denied the suit’s claims in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge.&lt;/em&gt; “Fox News Media is committed to providing the full context of every story with in-depth reporting and clear opinion. We are proud of our 2020 election coverage and will vigorously defend against this meritless lawsuit in court,” a spokesperson said. Powell called the suit “another political maneuver motivated by the radical left that has no basis in fact or law” in &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/04/business/media/smartmatic-fox-news-lawsuit.html"&gt;a statement to &lt;em&gt;The New York Times.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LmkYtJ"&gt;Smartmatic’s competitor Dominion has &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22249207/dominion-voting-systems-rudy-giuliani-defamation-billion-2020-election-donald-trump-sidney-powell"&gt;already filed lawsuits&lt;/a&gt; against Powell and Giuliani. Together, the cases will test whether libel law can defend some targets of disinformation campaigns — which often spread online but &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/20/business/media/smartmatic-lawsuit-fox-news-newsmax-oan.html"&gt;start with major media networks&lt;/a&gt; and public figures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a39j5m"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5:45PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added statement from Fox News Media.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266731/smartmatic-fox-news-lawsuit-rudy-giuliani-defamation-election-disinformation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22266731/smartmatic-fox-news-lawsuit-rudy-giuliani-defamation-election-disinformation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
