<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-14T12:58:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-14T12:58:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T12:58:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket launches for a record ninth time bringing 60 more Starlink satellites into orbit</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket " src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i2_Sr4NAfcWFZjTn2VDO-lXfjKw=/0x96:4200x2896/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68963903/1231200134.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Paul Hennessy/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rAe70S"&gt;A SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket launched the latest batch of 60 Starlink satellites into orbit Sunday, and returned to Earth successfully, landing on its Of Course I Still Love You drone ship in the Atlantic Ocean, &lt;a href="https://www.spacex.com/launches/"&gt;the company announced&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yMiSM3"&gt;Sunday’s mission marked a record ninth flight and landing for this Falcon 9 booster, SpaceX said, which was part of five earlier Starlink launches and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/8/18255060/spacex-crew-dragon-nasa-dm-1-international-space-station-landing-splashdown-atlantic-ocean"&gt;DM-1 mission for its Crew Dragon capsule&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Gkh8HM"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Deployment of 60 Starlink satellites confirmed &lt;a href="https://t.co/AMLK4R9dMn"&gt;pic.twitter.com/AMLK4R9dMn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— SpaceX (@SpaceX) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SpaceX/status/1371055836802387971?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 14, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kTXBo0"&gt;The satellites are part of growing Starlink constellation, which SpaceX is building to provide internet connectivity to rural areas on Earth. The company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/14/21043229/spacex-starlink-satellite-mega-constellation-concerns-astronomy-space-traffic"&gt;has permission to launch 12,000 satellites&lt;/a&gt; as part of the project, and has more than 1,000 in orbit so far. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aOJ4Lv"&gt;Starlink also has some 10,000 users in the beta program it launched last year. The Starlink kit, which comes with a router and antenna, costs $499, with a monthly subscription of $99 for internet speeds between 70 and 130 Mbps. The company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274385/musk-spacex-starlink-deposit-price-satellite-internet"&gt;opened pre-orders for Starlink&lt;/a&gt; in the US, Canada, and UK last month, with a $99 deposit fee. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9oRVzR"&gt;Sunday’s launch from NASA’s Kennedy Space Center was the second in the past few days for SpaceX, which sent another of its Falcon 9 rockets skyward from Cape Canaveral Space Force Station on Thursday. That launch also brought 60 satellites into orbit. The next Starlink launch is tentatively scheduled for March 21st, from Cape Canaveral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T1KBAj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZXwuwk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GE1rDf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330176/spacex-falcon-9-rocket-launch-starlink-satellites-internet"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330176/spacex-falcon-9-rocket-launch-starlink-satellites-internet</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-14T12:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T12:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Honda plans to sell two electric SUVs in the US in the 2024 model year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Honda moves toward more EVs" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/m22w-ZCsZ3P6Uwg1pn6L7U0pElM=/0x0:6000x4000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68963738/1230549990.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Artur Widak/NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1615731822.158600"&gt;Honda has announced it will sell two electric SUVs in the US in the 2024 model year, and plans to introduce hybrid gas-electric versions of its best-selling models. It’s the second Japanese automaker that has recently announced a future EV in the United States;  last month &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/10/22187113/toyota-electric-vehicles-us-suv-debut-hybrids"&gt;Toyota said it plans&lt;/a&gt; its first mass-market electric vehicle by the end of 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wBMQsj"&gt;Dave Gardner, the head of sales for Honda of America, said last week one of the EVs will be an Acura, and the other will be a Honda brand, &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/technology-cd6e144889db43e45566186f92f60481"&gt;according to the &lt;em&gt;Associated Press&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. He said more details would be coming later in 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hkZ2fS"&gt;Japanese automakers— and Toyota in particular— once were the leaders in hybrid vehicles, but have lagged American companies in the all-electric vehicle market in recent years. But with California banning sales of new internal-combustion engine vehicles by 2035, and the Biden administration moving toward taking the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/25/22249237/biden-electric-vehicle-government-fleet-ev"&gt;government vehicle fleet all-electric&lt;/a&gt; along with other plans to reduce emissions, automakers have their EV work cut out for them&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="07zhIC"&gt;Honda plans to make its vehicles in partnership with General Motors, Gardner said during the announcement last week. Honda has lately dominated passenger-car sales in the US, and makes many vehicles with internal combustion engines, Gardner noted, both of which put Honda a bit behind its competitors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c80yhv"&gt;“We’re really good at a couple of things that seem to be going out of vogue today, so there’s no doubt that we have work to start moving quickly in the zero-emission direction,” Gardner said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XXDGV4"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330086/honda-plans-electric-suv-2024-hybrid-toyota-emissions"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330086/honda-plans-electric-suv-2024-hybrid-toyota-emissions</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-14T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>How to watch the 2021 Grammys online</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Grammy Statue" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cGg9F4uRBDJC0jaZoBQKlwo9UO8=/18x0:5478x3640/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68963660/529168430.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Kurt Krieger/Corbis via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mscfxT"&gt;The 63rd Grammy Awards ceremony will be held Sunday March 14th, as awards show season continues apace despite the coronavirus pandemic. The show will honor the best music of 2020 and all the performers, producers, and behind-the-scenes people who made it happen. As with most of this year’s awards shows, the Grammys look a bit different this year, broadcasting from “in and around” the Los Angeles Convention Center, but without a live audience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Es6DgX"&gt;As is usually the case with awards ceremonies, there’s some controversy around this year’s Grammys. The Weeknd, whose song &lt;em&gt;Blinding Lights&lt;/em&gt; topped music charts around the world in 2020, received zero nominations — the consensus seems to be it had something to do with the anonymous expert committees who get final say in which artists make the cut. The Weeknd said he would boycott the Grammys going forward.  “Because of the secret committees,” he &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/11/arts/music/grammys-the-weeknd-beyonce.html"&gt;told the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, “I will no longer allow my label to submit my music to the Grammys.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SckAmh"&gt;What time do the Grammys start?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="w9pOmL"&gt;The Grammys  start at 8PM ET / 5PM PT on March 14th and will air live on CBS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="4xKR7T"&gt;Who’s Hosting the Grammys? &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="wRWJNE"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Daily Show’&lt;/em&gt;s Trevor Noah will be this year’s host, and awards presenters will include employees of independent music venues that have been hard-hit by the coronavirus pandemic, such as the Apollo Theater in New York, the Station Inn in Nashville, and The Troubador and Hotel Cafe in Los Angeles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="UsE6Av"&gt;How Do I watch the Grammys?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="62bZLw"&gt;In addition to airing live on CBS, the Grammys will stream live on Paramount Plus, CBS’ new streaming service, which has a free one-month trial if you want to check it out. You can also watch the Grammys on &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2FCBS.com&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F14%2F22329964%2Fgrammy-awards-2021-how-to-watch-online" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;CBS.com&lt;/a&gt; or the CBS app but you need to sign in with a TV provider (such as Verizon). &lt;a href="http://Grammy.com"&gt;Grammy.com&lt;/a&gt; will air pre-show programming beginning at 3PM ET. And “Grammy Live,” which will have behind-the-scenes content will be on &lt;a href="http://Grammy.com"&gt;Grammy.com&lt;/a&gt; and on Facebook Live via the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/RecordingAcademy/videos/3850046275043092"&gt;Recording Academy’s Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="qGVmWq"&gt;Who’s Performing at this year’s Grammys?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="iFgcc7"&gt;So many people! In addition to Swift, this year’s show will include performances by Bad Bunny, Black Pumas, Cardi B, BTS, Brandi Carlile, DaBaby, Doja Cat, Billie Eilish, Mickey Guyton, Haim, Brittany Howard, Miranda Lambert, Lil Baby, Chris Martin, John Mayer, Megan Thee Stallion, Maren Morris, Post Malone, and Harry Styles. Bruno Mars and Anderson .Paak’s Silk Sonic will also perform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="GWrxrq"&gt;Who’s Nominated?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="SajRrz"&gt;Beyonce leads the pack of artists with nine nominations, followed by Taylor Swift, Dua Lipa, and Roddy Ricch, who have six nominations apiece. You can check out the full &lt;a href="https://www.grammy.com/grammys/awards/63rd-annual-grammy-awards-2020"&gt;list of nominees here.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22329964/grammy-awards-2021-how-to-watch-online"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22329964/grammy-awards-2021-how-to-watch-online</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-14T10:43:15-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T10:43:15-04:00</updated>
    <title>Pi Day is here and Google’s calculator will test how well you know the mathematical constant</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="pi, cc J.Gabás Esteban" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5XJ9u51IFUplRBd-P8QJ8JXote0=/80x0:944x576/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68963486/8476624791_ac7a5a8357_b.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CA2ThF"&gt;It’s Pi Day, the nerdiest of holidays because it’s all about a mathematical constant that represents the ratio of a circle’s circumference to its diameter (yes, sometimes writing majors do pay attention in geometry class). March 14th has become known as Pi Day because it’s written numerically as 3.14 and pi starts at 3.14 ... and goes on indefinitely. Irrational number, indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eOsRDR"&gt;In case you’ve forgotten the digits of pi, Google is celebrating (marking? observing? idk, choose the term that feels right to you) the day with an Easter egg game hidden in its calculator (also: TIL Google will bring up a calculator if you search for “calculator”). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2b6Q73"&gt;The pi symbol in the upper left corner of the calculator should have some twinkling stars around it, and when you click on it, the calculator will show you pi’s first three digits. Type those digits into the calculator in order and hit enter. Next you’ll see pi to four digits, which you repeat into the calculator, and it will show you pi to five digits, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TSi-OoMMxPeJEBSoTIn4yg9Mn_0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22369326/pi_4.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Pi to four digits, as computed by Google’s calculator&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="FWl5jQ"&gt;Is it possible the pi calculator game will go on forever like pi itself does? I mean, I’m working today so I don’t really have time to check (I don’t think I could get away with telling Nilay and Dieter I spent my day punching pi into a calculator in the name of “research” heh), but you should feel free to investigate and report back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="r2bLir"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"It’s Pi Day! Here are 3.14 facts about pi","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2016/3/14/11218914/pi-facts-pi-day-i-did-it-pi-way"},{"title":"Tau Day is here: celebrate tau, not pi, as the true circle constant","url":"https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2018/3/14/17119388/pi-day-pie-math-tau-circle-constant-mathematics-circumference-diameter-radius-holiday-truth"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Py16u3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B4nCqO"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330036/pi-day-google-calculator-math"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330036/pi-day-google-calculator-math</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-14T10:00:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T10:00:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>Epic Games teases Fortnite appearance by Brazilian soccer star Neymar </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US-IT-LIFESTYLE-GAMES-COURT-APPLE-FORTNITE" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oNLBvINFfvuuza5EDfSZmX2ypOM=/204x0:5333x3419/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68963353/1228049811.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by CHRIS DELMAS/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DIyQTy"&gt;Epic Games and Brazilian soccer player Neymar are teasing a likely appearance by the star athlete in &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; on March 16th, with clues coming via a couple of tweets. &lt;a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2021-03-13-it-looks-like-neymar-is-coming-to-fortnite"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eurogamer&lt;/em&gt; first reported&lt;/a&gt; the news, including a video tweeted from the Epic Games account showing Neymar’s No. 10 jersey. Neymar &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/neymarjr/status/1370797692406874117?s=20"&gt;retweeted the video&lt;/a&gt; with the “eyes” emoji— not exactly confirmation, but another clue that something is brewing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qo6uDA"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;He’s given everything to the Order... and for what? &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;3.16.2021. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FortniteSeason6?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#FortniteSeason6&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/vP0tZytkaU"&gt;pic.twitter.com/vP0tZytkaU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Fortnite (@FortniteGame) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FortniteGame/status/1370751505733722116?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 13, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="i2mJXo"&gt;So details about how exactly Neymar might appear in Fortnite are still scarce, but as &lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/neymar-fortnite-teaser-222544175.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Engadget&lt;/em&gt; points out&lt;/a&gt;, it’s coming at the same time the &lt;a href="https://comicbook.com/gaming/news/fortnite-zero-crisis-finale-event-teaser/"&gt;Zero Crisis Finale&lt;/a&gt; single-player mission— which is the focus of the video teaser— launches. Neymar himself hasn’t played in a soccer (or football, take your pick) game since being &lt;a href="https://www.cbssports.com/soccer/news/neymar-injury-update-psg-star-ruled-out-for-champions-league-first-leg-vs-messi-barcelona/"&gt;injured several months ago&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vdb_03320e62-7835-46f2-9003-cc300f1017e6"&gt;Live events in&lt;em&gt; Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; have proven &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/2/18208223/fortnite-epic-games-marshmello-concert-exciting-bizarre-future-music"&gt;hugely popular&lt;/a&gt;, with a 2019 concert by Marshmello &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/21/18234980/fortnite-marshmello-concert-viewer-numbers"&gt;drawing 10 million people&lt;/a&gt;, which was a record event for the game at the time, and a performance last year by Travis Scott, which also took place inside of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/23/21233946/travis-scott-fortnite-concert-astronomical-record-breaking-player-count"&gt;drew more than 12 million people&lt;/a&gt;. In January, developer Epic Games &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/19/22239161/fortnite-esports-fncs-prize-pool-2021"&gt;pledged $20 million&lt;/a&gt; for esports in&lt;em&gt; Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; in 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mUUYPu"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="VBjERY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Travis Scott’s first Fortnite concert was surreal and spectacular","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/23/21233637/travis-scott-fortnite-concert-astronomical-live-report"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="ZG5uOx"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330003/epic-games-fortnite-brazilian-soccer-star-neymar"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22330003/epic-games-fortnite-brazilian-soccer-star-neymar</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-14T09:32:53-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-14T09:32:53-04:00</updated>
    <title>Oman blocks Clubhouse for not having a permit, but activists suggest it may be censorship</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Surveillance Fears After Clubhouse App Takes Saudi By Storm" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XLVGO1JKeX9BvEwWY7VJZJAbtV4=/0x2:8192x5463/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68963255/1231631217.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Jaap Arriens/NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9h0BVP"&gt;The middle eastern country of Oman has blocked the Clubhouse voice chat app saying it lacked the proper permit to operate, as some activists raised concerns that it was an act of censorship, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-oman-clubhouse/oman-blocks-audio-app-clubhouse-citing-lack-of-permit-but-some-fear-censorship-idUSKBN2B607V"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3S34sY"&gt;The Omani Telecommunications Regulatory Authority &lt;a href="https://wafoman.com/2021/03/14/oman-bans-clubhouse/?lang=en"&gt;told news site WAF&lt;/a&gt; that communications applications operating in the country must get a permit from the authority. According to WAF, Oman “prohibits the use of several encrypted VoIP applications without an official license.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rymfBs"&gt;&lt;a href="https://ochroman.org/eng/category/updates/"&gt;The Omani Association for Human Rights&lt;/a&gt; said in a statement that Oman’s government views “the authoritarian government of China as a role model,” and has banned the app even though it’s used by many Omanis “as a space to express their opinions freely without government censorship.” &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/08/world/asia/china-clubhouse-blocked.html"&gt;China blocked access to Clubhouse&lt;/a&gt; in February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T1iukQ"&gt;The popular app, which is currently invite-only and only available on iOS, has grown in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/16/21325678/venture-capitalists-vc-media-silicon-valley-clubhouse-tech-journalists"&gt;popularity among the Silicon Valley&lt;/a&gt; crowd, many of whom are not shy about speaking their opinions to a listening audience. It’s been criticized for a lack of robust moderation tools, which as led to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/30/21495419/clubhouse-conversation-antisemitism-content-moderation"&gt;some anti-Semitic rhetoric&lt;/a&gt; and COVID-19 misinformation spreading on the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XyrgCz"&gt;However, after barely a year in existence, Clubhouse recently did a funding round where it was &lt;a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/clubhouse-gets-investment-interest-at-1-billion-valuation"&gt;valued at $1 billion&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="Pi3FkP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Safe Space: Silicon Valley, Clubhouse, and the cult of VC victimhood","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/16/21325678/venture-capitalists-vc-media-silicon-valley-clubhouse-tech-journalists"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="2SeQ3E"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XTQRGT"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2zhmO0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22329983/oman-blocks-clubhouse-app-privacy-censorship"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/14/22329983/oman-blocks-clubhouse-app-privacy-censorship</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-13T17:20:12-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-13T17:20:12-05:00</updated>
    <title>Free streaming platform Tubi reportedly getting into original programming</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wew5vdATk2Inza4LZPnvVRvMLJw=/78x0:923x563/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68961615/tubi.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kLe56r"&gt;Free streaming platform Tubi has plans to branch out into original programming, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-13/fox-s-tubi-made-millions-with-reruns-now-it-wants-original-programming?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;, citing sources familiar with the company’s plans. The streamer will likely start with original movies, but is also exploring episodic TV shows, and is speaking with potential advertisers about partnerships, the report states. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xpiz8q"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/17/21184294/fox-tubi-acquisition-streaming-wars-news-sports-xumi-comcast-pluto-viacomcbs"&gt;Fox Corp. acquired Tubi for $440 million&lt;/a&gt; last March, in an attempt to get in on the streaming wars. Before the acquisition, Fox didn’t have its own streaming offering. Fox said at the time it planned to offer a large number of its older shows and movies to Tubi subscribers for free, as well as some sports programming. There was no talk at that time of Tubi creating original content to try to compete with the likes of established, paid streaming platforms like Netflix and Hulu. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CksVL0"&gt;But Fox Corp. CFO Steve &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/tubi-ad-revenues-to-eclipse-broadcast-entertainment-network-fox-corp-cfo-predicts"&gt;Tomsic said during an investors’ conference&lt;/a&gt; earlier this week that while the company would eventually create original content for Tubi, any shows or movies would be “cheap and cheerful,” not the big-budget offerings of larger streamers. “I stress it’s going to be cost-effective,” Tomsic said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q5jO90"&gt;Fox expects Tubi to generate $300 million in ad revenue in the current fiscal year, Tomsic predicted. &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/fox-expects-tubi-revenues-to-surpass-broadcast-networks-2020-12"&gt;Tubi reported 33 million active users&lt;/a&gt; in December, a 65 percent increase from the year prior. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/13/22329368/tubi-streaming-original-programming-fox"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/13/22329368/tubi-streaming-original-programming-fox</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-13T15:40:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-13T15:40:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Judge rules Google has to face lawsuit that claims it tracks users even in Incognito mode</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p5o_us9NdLAuJewvyDvWAx4PaTI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68961348/acastro_191014_1777_google_pixel_0005.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="XNNOGb"&gt;A judge in California ruled Friday that Google has to face a class action lawsuit that claims the search giant secretly collects data from  users even when they’re using its private “Incognito” mode, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-13/google-must-face-suit-over-snooping-on-incognito-browsing?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DUaFgd"&gt;Three users &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-alphabet-google-privacy-lawsuit/google-is-sued-in-u-s-for-tracking-users-private-internet-browsing-idUSKBN23933H"&gt;filed a complaint last June&lt;/a&gt; alleging Google has a “pervasive data tracking business,” and its tracking persists even if users take steps to protect their private information, such as using incognito mode in Chrome, or private browsing in Safari and other browsers. The lawsuit seeks at least $5 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X3aH3m"&gt;Google had sought to have the case thrown out, but US District Judge Lucy Koh wrote in her ruling that the company “did not notify users that Google engages in the alleged data collection while the user is in private browsing mode.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lrQ10Q"&gt;The company said in a court filing that it makes clear to users “that ‘Incognito’ does not mean ‘invisible,’ and that the user’s activity during that session may be visible to websites they visit, and any third-party analytics or ads services the visited websites use.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n6XYnT"&gt;Google spokesperson José Castañeda said in an email to The Verge on Saturday that the company disputes the lawsuit’s claims “and we will defend ourselves vigorously against them.”  He added that Chrome’s Incognito mode gives users the choice to browse the internet without activity being saved to their browser or devices. “As we clearly state each time you open a new incognito tab, websites might be able to collect information about your browsing activity during your session.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JMYBaN"&gt;Google said earlier this year it is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/14/21064698/google-third-party-cookies-chrome-two-years-privacy-safari-firefox"&gt;phasing out third-party tracking cookies&lt;/a&gt;, and says it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/3/22310332/google-privacy-replacing-third-party-cookies-privacy-sandbox"&gt;doesn’t plan to replace&lt;/a&gt; the cookies with something that may be as invasive even though it will affect the company’s advertising business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Aedbjt"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 13th, 4:39PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Adds statement from Google spokesperson&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZTowcy"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/13/22329240/judge-rules-google-5-billion-lawsuit-tracking-chrome-incognito-privacy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/13/22329240/judge-rules-google-5-billion-lawsuit-tracking-chrome-incognito-privacy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-13T13:25:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-13T13:25:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>Go watch this drone video that will really make you miss movie theaters</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bHTaYzR8zpUHCdbrfkDeFADtHoY=/141x0:1119x652/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68960985/box_office.5.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mTWZf2"&gt;Last week everyone was fixated on the “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/9/22321576/fpv-drone-footage-short-film-bowling-alley-bryant-lake-bowl"&gt;Right Up Our Alley&lt;/a&gt;” drone video that made us all nostalgic for bowling alleys. On Friday night, a VP at drone company DJI &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dronelaws/status/1370550353922506754"&gt;tweeted this video&lt;/a&gt; of a drone flight through a mostly-empty movie theater in Minnesota, and I don’t know about you but I really miss going to the movies. This video makes that longing about 100 times worse. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GJTc9F"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4bVh_XfxQoU?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TOLEe0"&gt;According to its YouTube page the video is by SkyCandy, and is a one-take fly-through of Mann theaters’ Plymouth Grand in Plymouth, Minnesota. It was filmed using a DJI Air Unit and Rotor Riot Cinewhoop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2KBzEc"&gt;The video is just over a minute long, but the drone takes us through the lobby — after being welcomed through the front doors by a masked theater employee— where people are deciding what to see, and buying tickets “for the 7:30 show,” according to the audio. There’s some very familiar-sounding background music playing in the lobby portion that I couldn’t quite identify, but it felt exactly right. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s92Dwx"&gt;Next we fly by the concession stand where a couple snags a bucket of that overpriced movie popcorn, then we spin past the bar where we can overhear the bartender telling his patron, “you name it, I’ve seen it,” before heading down a long hallway into one of the actual theaters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oqKSGw"&gt;There are so many empty seats in that theater it actually felt a little sad— but then we briefly hear a familiar pre-movie sound: someone forgot to mute their iPhone. Rude! But funny. We end up looking at and then flying “into” the movie screen where guess what’s playing (I thought for one second it might be &lt;em&gt;Tenet&lt;/em&gt;, but no): The beginning of the video we’ve been watching. Wild!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gaXKDE"&gt;For those of us who haven’t been to a movie theater since social distancing started last year, this video is a welcome, wistful reminder of the joys of seeing a film on the big screen. One more thing to put on the “things I’m going to do when everything gets back to normal,” which hopefully will be sooner rather than later. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2jihMC"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8N1pqw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="imiHzX"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/13/22329091/go-watch-this-drone-video-movie-theaters-dji"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/13/22329091/go-watch-this-drone-video-movie-theaters-dji</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-13T12:21:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-13T12:21:30-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tesla reportedly had 450 cases of coronavirus at its California plant after reopening last May</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hHuoMYhs0BUTxVTk1zWpQvRhfnc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68960784/acastro_180430_1777_tesla_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="RhCGB7"&gt;After it reopened in defiance of health department orders last May, Tesla’s plant in Fremont, California saw 450 cases of COVID-19 through December 2020, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PlainSite/status/1370549174731608064?s=20"&gt;new data&lt;/a&gt; from legal website PlainSite shows (via &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/03/12/hundreds-covid-cases-reported-tesla-plant-following-musks-defiant-reopening-county-data-shows/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G1LISs"&gt;Last March public health officials in Alameda County, where the Fremont plant is located, restricted all but “essential” businesses from remaining open as coronavirus cases surged across the country. Tesla fought the order but eventually shut down the plant on March 23rd. But a few days later, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/11/21254871/tesla-fremont-shutdown-factory-production-model-3-y-elon-musk"&gt;Tesla restarted production&lt;/a&gt; at the Fremont plant, even though it was in violation of the public health order. Tesla CEO Elon Musk said on Twitter at the time that he planned to be on the factory floor with Fremont workers and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/11/21255149/elon-musk-tesla-fremont-factory-reopen-order-arrest-alameda"&gt;taunted local officials to arrest him&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ruvY9U"&gt;Tesla’s reopening plan was later approved, even though it was already open in defiance of the March orders. Musk, a vocal critic of last year’s coronavirus shelter-in-place orders, threatened to move the Fremont factory out of California. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/9/21253127/elon-musk-lawsuit-alameda-coronavirus-tesla-fremont-lockdown"&gt;Tesla filed a lawsuit &lt;/a&gt;against Alameda County over the shutdown order on May 9th of last year, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/20/21265358/tesla-drops-lawsuit-alameda-county-coroanvirus-lockdown"&gt;dropped the suit&lt;/a&gt; less than two weeks later. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="geW1uE"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Post&lt;/em&gt; reports that the documents obtained by PlainSite show Tesla had around a dozen reports of COVID-19 cases in May 2020 and the numbers continued to rise through December, a month that saw 125 new cases of the virus at the plant. Tesla employs about 10,000 people at the Fremont facility. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xgBugd"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="p9hm2h"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/13/22329041/tesla-450-cases-coronavirus-fremont-california-coronavirus-elon-musk"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/13/22329041/tesla-450-cases-coronavirus-fremont-california-coronavirus-elon-musk</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
