<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2020-12-10T12:07:33-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-10T12:07:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-10T12:07:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>Uber asks governors to give drivers early access to COVID-19 vaccines</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Uber logo against a dark background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uHVzCFT9K25KigFPb9R8LkWWImg=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68491286/acastro_180927_1777_uber_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LC6xMC"&gt;Uber sent letters today to every US governor asking that their drivers and delivery people be classified as essential workers and given prioritized access to COVID-19 vaccines. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) has recommended the first batch of vaccines go to health care workers and residents of long-term care facilities, with essential workers — including those in transportation — following in a second phase. But it’s up to each state to decide the specifics of their vaccine distribution plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QuRDkp"&gt;“After nine months on the frontlines keeping their communities running, we are asking governors in all 50 states to prioritize drivers and delivery people for early vaccine access,” said Uber CEO Dara Khosrowshahi in a statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="8lvnKu"&gt;&lt;q&gt;If classified as essential, Uber drivers would be part of the planned second phase for vaccination&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vgcSFn"&gt;Uber made &lt;a href="https://beta.regulations.gov/comment/CDC-2020-0121-0238"&gt;a similar appeal&lt;/a&gt; to the CDC earlier this week, saying in a letter that early access to a COVID-19 vaccine “would help drivers and delivery people continue to play their essential role while also reducing the risk that they may inadvertently contract, or possibly transmit, the virus.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lzpOXN"&gt;In the letter to state governors, Khosrowshahi argues that Uber can use their services “to remove transportation barriers faced by individuals who will need to travel to their vaccination appointments.” Both letters point to the use of Uber by health care workers, restaurants, and people relying on delivery to stay at home during the pandemic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y531DG"&gt;While Uber is asking for its workers to be considered essential, the company has long been criticized for repeatedly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/4/21546037/prop-22-california-uber-lyft-ballot-measure-result"&gt;fighting to classify those same drivers as contractors rather than employees&lt;/a&gt;. Uber has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/11/20861362/uber-ab5-tony-west-drivers-core-ride-share-business-california"&gt;gone so far as to say&lt;/a&gt; that “drivers’ work is outside the usual course of Uber’s business.” Part of its business or not, more drivers and delivery people could continue working through the pandemic with early access to vaccination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MCg5ki"&gt;The FDA advisory committee is meeting on Thursday to discuss emergency authorization of the Pfizer / BioNTech COVID-19 vaccine, and it will be doing the same next week for the Moderna vaccine. States have already begun their preparations for vaccine distribution, but with limited supply, there &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21779433/covid-vaccine-priority-health-care-workers-long-term-care"&gt;may not be enough doses&lt;/a&gt; available to vaccinate all health care workers by the end of the year. As more doses become available in 2021, it will take careful consideration from state officials to determine which populations of people should be prioritized.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167583/uber-driver-early-access-covid-19-coronavirus-vaccine"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167583/uber-driver-early-access-covid-19-coronavirus-vaccine</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kait Sanchez</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-10T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-10T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google, Dell, and Intel form new computing group for transforming cloud and IT tools</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DfZulGtp9BkTNFT9pDGuuuTIJdM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68491191/acastro_180416_1777_chrome_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xq284Z"&gt;Google, Dell, Intel and a handful of other major tech companies in the IT and cloud computing industries have banded together to tackle joint problems around security, remote work, and other enterprise issues that have only become more important during the coronavirus pandemic. The consortium these companies have formed is called the Modern Computing Alliance, and its founding members also include Box, Cirtrix, Imprivata, Okta, RingCentral, Slack, VMWare, and Zoom. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gN5Q3G"&gt;The Modern Computing Alliance will initially be focused on four areas: performance; security and identity; remote work, productivity, and collaboration; and health care. The goal is to pool knowledge and resources toward solving shared problems around how companies perform work in the cloud and the tools they use to do so. The alliance will focus on developing new standards and interoperable technologies that can be used by any company that relies on one of the partners’ platforms or products. In particular, Google is engaged in the effort with its Chrome browser and Chrome OS teams, as well as the division responsible for Google Workplace. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="3n8NTB"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The needs that our users are expecting and the way that compute is changing really require a new way of working.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9T823Z"&gt;“Today, we’re excited to announce Google’s membership in the Modern Computing Alliance — to address the biggest IT challenges facing companies today with integration from silicon to cloud,” says John Solomon, Google’s vice president of Chrome OS. “Working with a group of forward-thinking industry leaders, we’re aligning standards and technologies to provide companies with the choice of high-performance, cloud-first computing solutions from the vendor of their choice who provide modern solutions for the modern era of business.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AwjZLi"&gt;The Modern Computing Alliance predates the coronavirus pandemic; Solomon tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;discussions first began at the Consumer Electronics Show in Las Vegas last year. But in March, as the reality of COVID-19 set in and companies everywhere began transitioning to remote work, the group decided it needed to expand its scope and bring in even more partners, like Slack and Zoom, that were witnessing massive shifts in how corporate work was being performed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sgd3x6"&gt;“The needs that our users are expecting and the way that compute is changing really require a new way of working,” Solomon tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “It’s not the most natural thing to say, ‘Let’s form a consortium.’ But this isn’t an ordinary time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R3AfVg"&gt;Looking ahead, the group aims to bring in as many IT professionals as it can to help build a council of experts that can identify problems and figure out ways to solve them. The group also intends to have some concrete action plans to share in the first half of 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ekxjko"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167324/google-dell-intel-modern-computing-alliance-cloud-consortium"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167324/google-dell-intel-modern-computing-alliance-cloud-consortium</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-10T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-10T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Gmail will now let you edit Office documents directly from email attachments</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VPx4apCBs66iuWpD3VYIqKplZb8=/0x0:1320x880/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68491182/newgmaillogo.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="29ZSGA"&gt;Google is making it even easier to work with Microsoft Office files, with the company now allowing users to directly edit attached Office files in Gmail, much like it already allows with Google Docs or Sheets files. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HeNgZD"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/6/21503649/google-workspace-g-suite-gmail-chat-meet-docs"&gt;Google Workplace&lt;/a&gt; (the recently rebranded G Suite, which encompasses Google Docs, Sheets, Slides, Meet, and Calendar) has offered compatibility with &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/drive/answer/9276408"&gt;Office files from Word, PowerPoint, and Excel&lt;/a&gt; for some time. But previously, documents had to be imported into Google Drive in order to edit or modify them — while emailed attachments were only able to be viewed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q89HS6"&gt;The new workflow, however, streamlines that process considerably. Now, you can directly open and edit an Office file using the Google Docs editor just by clicking on it — just like you would a native Google Doc. But the new editing function doesn’t convert Office files into Google Docs, instead preserving the original file format. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NQhfe6"&gt;Gmail will allow users to respond to the original email and include the now-updated file (still in an Office file format) without first requiring that they download and then re-attach the updated file. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P0BqdR"&gt;Google is also working to help ensure that Office files work more smoothly in Google Docs, with the company launching a new &lt;a href="https://gsuite.google.com/marketplace/app/macro_converter/383201976440"&gt;Macro Converter add-on&lt;/a&gt; for Google Workspace that’s designed to help users and organizations import their macros from Excel to Sheets more easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4H4Yez"&gt;Similarly, Google is working on adding better document orientation and image support to Google Docs, allowing for documents with both horizontally and vertically oriented pages, along with images placed behind text and watermarks (although the new image features won’t be available until next year.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BhGVEc71Yk8B4Lsy5K-rxnX5jpA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22159737/Watermarks_MPO_combined.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167325/gmail-edit-microsoft-office-documents-google-workplace"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167325/gmail-edit-microsoft-office-documents-google-workplace</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-10T11:45:59-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-10T11:45:59-05:00</updated>
    <title>Geoff Keighley, gaming’s inescapable hypeman, on ‘the most expensive’ Game Awards yet</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Esf2pWgMc9M83k4Stuk5N0783yo=/0x0:4095x2730/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68491069/1193629349.jpg.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Geoff Keighley speaks at the 2019 Game Awards in Los Angeles. | Photo by JC Olivera/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="InrPkO"&gt;Geoff Keighley doesn’t get enough sleep. It’s December, which means he’s averaging four or five hours on a good night. “One of the toughest things about [the Game Awards] is that I’m hosting it, and I’m also producing it,” he says. Sure, he’d probably be a better host with more rest, but there’s an added benefit to knowing the whole thing front to back. He could do this in his — ah, never mind. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4xIikw"&gt;This year, the 20-hour days leading up to the annual Game Awards &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22163974/2020-game-awards-how-to-watch-time-date-premieres"&gt;on December 10th&lt;/a&gt; look a little different. Seating charts for an event of hundreds used to keep him up late, but now, group gatherings are a quaint concept. COVID-19 safety precautions have made the whole process a little stranger. “It’s obviously an evolving situation so we’re kind of staying on top of it — especially [in] Los Angeles now with some of the stay at home orders,” the Game Awards creator says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lad4Vj"&gt;Keighley has long played the role of the game industry’s rich uncle, a benevolent force with deep pockets and a genuine interest in giving the medium a bigger platform. He’s been endlessly interviewed and profiled for his work on creating the industry’s biggest awards show — a self-funded venture created from the ashes of the infamous Spike Video Game Awards, now pulling in more than &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/2019-game-awards-shatters-prior-years-record-hits-452-million-live-streams-1263419"&gt;45 million streams&lt;/a&gt;, as of last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IHDK9y"&gt;In the absence of events like E3, after an utterly exhausting year, the Game Awards  — already online anyway, outside of a small industry presence in LA — remain largely unchanged. There will be celebrity cameos and musical performances. There will be exclusive game reveals. It is all in service of the same &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/7/18131058/game-awards-2018-geoff-keighly-creaotr-streaming-tga-hydrobot"&gt;saccharine view&lt;/a&gt; of a complicated industry demonstrated in past years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="tQvciL"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Oh, here’s Geoff doing another stream.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Tk7ipa"&gt;Gone is the red carpet and studio audience this year. Most appearances will take place over video calls. It’s not much different from the rest of life in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hNAVdD"&gt;“Game Awards is kind of perfectly suited for the world we’re in now,” Keighley says. “In 2014, it was a crazy idea to do this streamed-only award show. And now everyone’s announcing a streaming service, and every movie’s going to streaming… We were kind of ahead of the curve in that way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="05hpUw"&gt;That’s been a trend for Keighley this year in particular. He’d already made the choice to skip E3 back in early February, now an antiquated notion 10 months into COVID, when all major events for the year have been canceled. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JpfsMa"&gt;“I was just like, oh, I guess I’m not really going to do anything for the year,” he says. He went to Europe for a few weeks of vacation and made plans to visit Valve in Bellevue, Washington, for &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1361700/HalfLife_Alyx__Final_Hours/"&gt;a project&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;em&gt;Half-Life: Alyx&lt;/em&gt;. By his return in March, COVID had begun to take root — particularly in Washington, where the US had its first confirmed case. He canceled his trip and opted for virtual interviews with Valve. He hasn’t left LA since, and conducts business over Zoom calls from a white-walled den with little in the way of decoration. Next door is the spare room he streams from, the now-familiar backdrop to events like the four-month long Summer Game Fest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8ygklc"&gt;“Summer Game Fest grew out of, honestly, all the game companies coming to me,” Keighley says. E3 wasn’t happening, but developers still wanted to do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. Could he help them pull together an event? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T1SP2p"&gt;“Normally I do E3 and I’m done,” he says, referring to himself as “the guy who does one big thing and then disappears.” This year, he’s been a larger presence than ever: “Oh, here’s Geoff doing another stream.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2hk18k"&gt;His presence is one driven both by professional obligation and personal determination. “The first year of Game Awards, what petrified me was this sense that we’re not going to have an award show for our industry this year if we don’t do the Spike thing,” he says. “I was like, no, I have to create something.” The same goes for this summer and the vacuum of events created by that whole bothersome pandemic. “This is the year that new consoles are coming out... That’s huge. We can’t just kind of let that fall by the wayside.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="9uGupJ"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;My view tonight! &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TheGameAwards?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#TheGameAwards&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/jX4sGjTPTl"&gt;pic.twitter.com/jX4sGjTPTl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Geoff Keighley (@geoffkeighley) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/geoffkeighley/status/1337051032145321984?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 10, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="35zBJU"&gt;Despite the added pressure of COVID, the Game Awards this year will still be extended across three cities, albeit with more virtual components and safety precautions than anyone expected. “People are like, oh, you’re doing a virtual show, it’s gonna be super cheap this year,” he says of feedback he’s gotten. “No, actually it’s the most expensive Game Awards we’ve ever done ...  It’s actually extraordinarily challenging, mentally and emotionally, to do it, but also just financially to just be able to deliver something.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HcHPXR"&gt;Unlike earlier 2020 events — the originally-in-March GDC, or even E3 in June — the Game Awards has had the benefit of time. “Initially I was like, oh, it’s good Game Awards isn’t until December, so we’ll be through all this and it’ll be back to normal then,” says Keighley. By May, the reality of COVID had set in. Keighley and his team knew there would be no in-person event this year and opted to not “be under the false pretenses that it’s all going to be fine.” Weeks ahead of the event, they’ve settled on three or four possible scenarios, he says, that they’ll be able to quickly pivot to depending on how things change. “Worst case, there’ll be a satellite truck at my house,” says Keighley. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VE6SvE"&gt;He knows that most people just want to see game announcements, but they’ve still built a set. “We wanted to still have some spectacle to it. I think this industry deserves it, honestly... We’re going to do a full-on live show.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fKTfzR"&gt;Keighley has been isolating at home for the last few weeks. He hasn’t been to the set yet, and will arrive tonight, when the awards stream live. “You know where to find me if you need me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gSUKZB"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="swc7bI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22167464/geoff-keighley-game-awards-2020-covid-e3-cost"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22167464/geoff-keighley-game-awards-2020-covid-e3-cost</id>
    <author>
      <name>Megan Farokhmanesh</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-10T11:33:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-10T11:33:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>German regulators are investigating Facebook for its controversial Oculus account rules</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L0CspK4tTQWKQWufJ-Z3F6JOl2A=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68490996/akrales_200904_4160_0010.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="4hT4QA"&gt;Germany’s competition watchdog is investigating Facebook for tying its social app to its Oculus virtual reality headsets. Today, the Bundeskartellamt or Federal Cartel Office (FCO) &lt;a href="https://www.bundeskartellamt.de/SharedDocs/Meldung/EN/Pressemitteilungen/2020/10_12_2020_Facebook_Oculus.html"&gt;announced a probe&lt;/a&gt; of the increasingly close link between Facebook and Oculus, arguing that it could hurt competition in both VR and social networking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AQZ735"&gt;The new Oculus Quest 2 headset requires signing in with a Facebook account rather than a separate Oculus ID, and that’s raised antitrust concerns. “Linking virtual reality products and the group’s social network in this way could constitute a prohibited abuse of dominance by Facebook,” said FCO president Andreas Mundt. Mundt noted that Facebook is a dominant social network in Germany and plays a large role in the emerging VR market. “We intend to examine whether and to what extent this tying arrangement will affect competition in both areas of activity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TUxa1Q"&gt;Facebook &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2020/09/facebook-halts-oculus-quest-sales-in-germany-amid-privacy-concerns/"&gt;halted the original Quest’s sales&lt;/a&gt; in Germany earlier this year, citing regulatory concerns. “While Oculus devices are not currently available for sale in Germany, we will cooperate fully with the Bundeskartellamt and are confident we can demonstrate that there is no basis to the investigation,” a spokesperson tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gDBEwO"&gt;Oculus reportedly faces scrutiny in the US as well but on different grounds. Last week, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-12-03/facebook-accused-of-squeezing-rival-startups-in-virtual-reality"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; that Justice Department antitrust investigators were talking with Oculus app developers, following accusations that Oculus &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21455665/facebook-oculus-vr-indie-developers-power-monopoly-concerns"&gt;cloned smaller companies’ apps and favored its own alternatives&lt;/a&gt;. Facebook sells the popular Oculus Quest 2 VR headset, controls app developers’ access to its official store, and has developed and acquired several popular VR games and apps. That includes the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/28/21405249/facebook-vr-space-horizon-access-public-beta"&gt;virtual social space Horizon&lt;/a&gt;, which competes with smaller independent apps like Rec Room and VRChat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MBeS7e"&gt;The US Federal Trade Commission and 48 state and regional attorneys general &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22158483/facebook-antitrust-lawsuit-anti-competition-behavior-attorneys-general"&gt;sued Facebook&lt;/a&gt; for monopolistic behavior yesterday, although that suit doesn’t cover Facebook’s VR efforts. The FCO also has a separate pending case against Facebook. In 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/7/18215143/facebook-whatsapp-instagram-third-party-user-data-combined-banned-germany-fco-competition"&gt;it ordered Facebook&lt;/a&gt; to stop combining user data from different sources without consent. However, Facebook lodged an emergency appeal, and a hearing is scheduled for March 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Fk8uh"&gt;Facebook’s decision to link Oculus hardware with Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/19/21375118/oculus-facebook-account-login-data-privacy-controversy-developers-competition"&gt;has rankled users&lt;/a&gt;. The company acquired Oculus in 2014. But until recently, users could sign in with separate Oculus IDs, which didn’t require creating a public-facing social profile. Following the Oculus Quest 2’s launch, it started requiring Facebook logins to use new hardware, and some users &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/15/21518194/oculus-quest-2-headset-facebook-account-suspension-problems"&gt;temporarily lost access&lt;/a&gt; to their headsets after being mistakenly banned. Facebook hasn’t indicated plans to reverse the decision, but it’s now facing official pressure to change its rules.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167509/germany-fco-investigation-facebook-oculus-account-requirements-competition"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167509/germany-fco-investigation-facebook-oculus-account-requirements-competition</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-10T11:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-10T11:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The best phone to buy right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Wf83wFclSirud7lOEJUuTIR6O3c=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68490961/Best_Phone_Grid_2020_v2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;From top left, Samsung Galaxy S20, Apple iPhone SE,&amp;nbsp;Samsung Galaxy S20 FE, Apple iPhone 12, Pixel 4A, Samsung Galaxy Note 20.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Buying a new phone can be a chore, but we’ve done the work for you&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="833z64"&gt;There are a lot of great smartphone options available at any given moment, so it can be a challenge to sort through them all if you’re trying to choose the absolute best one. The stakes here can’t be understated: your phone is the most important gadget in your life, and you’ll probably be living with the one you buy for at least a year, if not two or three.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wQGOEA"&gt;Most of the time, the best phone stands out from the pack in all the areas that matter: performance, value, camera, and support. And most of the time, that’s usually the most expensive phone on the market. But as it turns out, you don’t have to buy the priciest phone to get the best experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a0USm3"&gt;This guide focuses on the best phones on the market, regardless of price. If you’re looking for something on a smaller budget, please &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/this-is-my-next/2018/7/27/17619088/best-cheap-phone-budget-iphone-android"&gt;check out our guide to budget smartphones&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="B7RXQo"&gt;The best phones 2020&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="XfQkHu"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The iPhone 12." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YuP5JW4ilTFsD1GqJPcjnL_wagE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21973509/vpavic_4243_20201017_0144.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple iPhone 12&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="DK8L4P"&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21522988/iphone-12-review"&gt;Apple iPhone 12&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="WnjecW"&gt;Best iPhone to buy in 2020&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="bEJfKg"&gt;There are many new iPhones to choose from this year, each with different characteristics and prices. The one that most people should buy is the iPhone 12, which starts at around $830 for a 64GB model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i5fl1U"&gt;The 12 has the same overall design, the same processor, the same wireless charging, the same Face ID system, the same 5G support, the same front camera, and the same main and wide-angle rear cameras as the pricier 12 Pro, but for hundreds of dollars less. On top of all that, it comes in five different colors, one more than you can choose from in the Pro models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="wUSPTz"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The iPhone 12 balances a big screen with manageable size well&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2sVfnG"&gt;Compared to the iPhone 12 mini, the iPhone 12 has a noticeably roomier display and a bigger battery — two things that are important to many people. At 6.1 inches, it’s big enough to make watching video and reading text comfortable and engaging, but isn’t so big that it’s terribly hard to use in one hand or fit in your pocket. Battery life is also very good — you can reliably expect this phone to last all day without needing to charge up before bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7XJXAT"&gt;The 12 gives up the telephoto camera that’s available on the 12 Pro and 12 Pro Max, but that’s something most people won’t miss. The iPhone 12’s camera system is the best you can get in this price range and is excellent at most anything you’d use it for. It also has the ability to shoot Dolby Vision HDR video for brighter and more dynamic video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="1vQlwk"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9527699"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eK0QNl"&gt;Since the 12 has Apple’s latest smartphone processor, the A14 Bionic, it has extremely fast performance and fluid animations. It also has a sleeker, more modern design than the previous iPhone 11 or iPhone XR, which feel frumpy in comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3Y0X1g"&gt;The base iPhone 12 comes with 64GB of storage, but as usual with an iPhone, it’s not expandable, so we recommend buying the 128GB model for only $50 more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mJZ9AM"&gt;In all, the iPhone 12 is an easy choice for most people: it offers top-level performance, design, and camera features, while providing reliable battery life for less money than other options on the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="hHkViI"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DwbKBItqbiGkzRe0WAo0Wbg67xo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19710510/vpavic_200206_3899_0094.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung Galaxy S20&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="zwDSsW"&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/11/21172039/samsung-galaxy-s20-plus-review-camera-5g-screen-android"&gt;Samsung Galaxy S20 / S20 Plus&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="qLPa8Y"&gt;Best Android phone to buy in 2020&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="4xfZgU"&gt;If you’re looking for an Android phone, the one that we recommend for most people is Samsung’s Galaxy S20 and S20 Plus. Even though these models came out way back in March 2020, they still balance performance, features, design, and build quality better than anything else you can get right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qPUenF"&gt;The S20 devices have excellent performance and great battery life. They have 120Hz displays that make every interaction as smooth as it can be. They also support 5G networks, just like any other flagship phone this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2S71nF"&gt;Both models have standard, ultrawide, and telephoto cameras on the rear, which provide a lot of flexibility when you’re composing photos. They may not be quite as good as the cameras you can get on an iPhone 12 or 12 Pro Max, but they are still very good and most people will find they take excellent photos and video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="JEKgzH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The S20 and S20 Plus have the right mix of performance, design, and features&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="t0nxLN"&gt;Samsung actually has another model in the S20 line that’s larger and more expensive than the S20 or S20 Plus: the S20 Ultra. We don’t recommend it: its camera system looks more advanced on a spec sheet but is less reliable and not as enjoyable to use and we don’t think it’s worth the extra $400 you’ll pay for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WR9r50"&gt;Choosing between the S20 and S20 Plus comes down to basically one thing: do you want an oversized screen or not? The S20 has a large 6.2-inch screen; the S20 Plus has an enormous 6.7-inch screen. The latter will definitely be harder to use in one hand and might not slip into your pocket as easily, but the screen is gorgeous to look at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="pt5XrR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9560504"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zGXnzc"&gt;Perhaps the best part of the S20 models is that you can get them for a good price, now that they’ve been on the market for more than six months. At launch, the S20 was about $1,000, while the S20 Plus was $1,200, both for 128GB models. But now you can regularly find the S20 in the $700 to $800 range, with the S20 Plus typically $200 more. At those prices, you can’t find a better Android phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9WVvG1"&gt;Rumors are pointing to Samsung releasing a new S21 model line as soon as January 2021. That can mean two things: if you are only looking for the latest and greatest, you might want to wait. But it could also mean we’ll see even more significant discounts on the S20 line than we already have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="IyREhz"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5BlmltRcyhOUzx5qiluhwmH-y_I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21939391/dbohn_201004_4227_0009.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dieter Bohn / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung Galaxy S20 FE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="UW0Jki"&gt;3. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21506470/samsung-galaxy-s20-fe-review-camera-processor-price"&gt;Samsung Galaxy S20 FE&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="gzg6sU"&gt;Best midrange Android phone in 2020&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="BHvw0G"&gt;The midrange phone market (models priced between $500 and $700) has exploded this year, but the one that stands out from the pack is Samsung’s Galaxy S20 FE. The reason is because it barely feels like a midrange phone; with just a couple of tweaks, this could easily pass for a premium flagship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m0zWPa"&gt;Like the other S20 models, the FE has a 120Hz display that makes every touch, scroll, or interaction feel smooth. It also has a top-tier Qualcomm Snapdragon 865 processor — you’re not giving up anything in terms of performance here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="utHVpW"&gt;Its camera system has the familiar wide, ultrawide, and telephoto setup, with all three cameras having 12-megapixel sensors. In good light, they all take reliably good phones; where you’ll notice a difference between this and more expensive phones is when it starts to get dark. But Samsung’s night mode does work surprisingly well and helps out quite a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="pRofCu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9546311"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xHfnRH"&gt;The biggest thing that separates the S20 FE from the other S20 models is its materials: instead of a glass back, it has a cheaper plastic one. It still feels well-made and sturdy, though, and once you put a case on it you won’t even notice it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gkgjI7"&gt;At its regular price of $700, the S20 FE is an excellent performing phone with a good value. But like most Samsung phones, you often can get it with a significant discount, making it an even more impressive value. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="UZDxTM"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="iPhone 12 mini" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7ys0KprJKXc3lDpQZD49h30F65Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22015272/cgartenberg_201105_4276_004.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The iPhone 12 mini is small enough to be used in one hand by almost anybody.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="a9366L"&gt;4. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21555295/iphone-12-mini-review"&gt;Apple iPhone 12 mini&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="YEmUyn"&gt;Best small phone in 2020&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="XOIazq"&gt;There’s really only one reason to buy an iPhone 12 mini, but it’s an important one: if you want a phone that’s easier to use in one hand or put into a small pocket. The iPhone 12 mini is the only small phone on the market with top-tier features and specs — you don’t have to compromise in performance, build quality, or cameras with this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EW9lbN"&gt;Though it’s much smaller in size than the other iPhones released this year, the mini’s 5.4-inch screen is still big enough for text messaging, email, web browsing, apps, video, and games, and if you’re coming from an iPhone 6 / 7 / 8, it will feel quite spacious. But it’s still small enough that most adults, even those with small hands, will be able to reach all of it with their thumb. You won’t need a PopSocket on this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O8rvOC"&gt;Otherwise, the mini is the same phone as the iPhone 12: it has the same design, processor, cameras, 5G support, and build quality as the larger model. It’s just smaller and has a smaller price tag, at about $100 less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vYYXqS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10215729"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8Zkn5M"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="x5NLwl"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Samsung Galaxy Note 20 Ultra" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4tFtN-bEShMB8qsd71536yIE1Bk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21765222/vpavic_200807_4133_0116.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy Note 20 Ultra has the battery life you need to go all day long.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="xyIPT9"&gt;5. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21372109/samsung-galaxy-note-20-ultra-review-camera-price-photos-s-pen-notes"&gt;Samsung Galaxy Note 20 Ultra&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="fEqbqa"&gt;Best battery life you can get&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="0OxORr"&gt;If you’re looking for the best phone to go from morning to night with heavy use and last through it all, Samsung’s top-of-the-line Galaxy Note 20 Ultra is the one to get. It has a massive 4,500mAh battery that keeps its enormous 6.9-inch screen going as long as you need it to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tJK8J3"&gt;The Note 20 Ultra is also a high-end phone in every other respect. Its giant screen supports a 120Hz refresh rate for smooth interactions; its triple rear camera system is one of the most advanced you can get; and the Qualcomm Snapdragon 865 Plus processor and 12GB of RAM allow it to perform without a hiccup. In addition, it supports Samsung’s S Pen for stylus input, allowing you to write or doodle on the screen with a pen instead of your finger. The Note 20 Ultra is a productivity powerhouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gBHFzE"&gt;There are other phones on the market with equally as big or even bigger batteries than the Note 20 Ultra, but they aren’t as premium or feature rich and they require you to make noticeable compromises elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="I5qlMp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10215736"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="lFEHuO"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nXbqRsJXIdQky0lT_oSOdnY1foA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22022559/bfarsace_201106_4269_022.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Becca Farsace / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The iPhone 12 Pro Max has the best camera you can get in a phone this year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="cqDZyL"&gt;6. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21555901/iphone-12-pro-max-review"&gt;Apple iPhone 12 Pro Max&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="UnCwn5"&gt;Best phone for photography and video in 2020&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="HMWyVS"&gt;The iPhone 12 Pro Max has the best camera system you can currently get on a smartphone. Its three rear cameras — standard wide, ultrawide, and telephoto — combine with Apple’s image processing to produce stunning images, even in poor lighting. If camera quality is your most important factor when buying a phone, the 12 Pro Max is where you should be spending your money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8SOLCW"&gt;The big difference between the 12 Pro Max and the other iPhone 12 models is found in its main camera sensor. The 12 Pro Max has a physically larger camera sensor that allows it to gather more light and produce better quality images when in dark or challenging lighting conditions. In addition, the 12 Pro Max has an improved image stabilization system that helps keep your images sharp as light levels drop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Lzlez"&gt;But unless camera quality is all you care about, the 12 Pro Max isn’t the best iPhone for most people. It’s enormous and the squared sides make it feel even bigger than its spec sheet implies. Most people will be happier with the smaller but still large-screened iPhone 12.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="5uBVLj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10215756"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="LbIFDi"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Apple’s iPhone SE" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/o_vDohLV6-GOZvVX3cOOiONKhrU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19916237/vpavic_042020_3980_0040.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s iPhone SE provides the most bang for your buck.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="QIIlAI"&gt;7. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/22/21230308/apple-iphone-se-2-2020-review-features-specs-camera-price"&gt;Apple iPhone SE&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sJumlJ"&gt;Best budget phone in 2020&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="jUoPHA"&gt;The budget phone (under $500) that strikes the right balance of camera, build quality, speed, battery life, software, and longevity for most people is the Apple iPhone SE 2020. Specifically, we recommend upgrading to the model with 128GB of storage for $449, which is $50 over the base price but well worth it long term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PNXHmP"&gt;The iPhone SE follows a very tried-and-true formula. It has the same body and 4.7-inch LCD screen that Apple has been using since the iPhone 6. That puts the display on the smaller end of screen sizes today and also means the phone’s bezels are bigger than anything else sold on the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qqRVDv"&gt;But in exchange for that very familiar phone body, you get a lot of value. The best thing about the iPhone SE is its processor, Apple’s A13 Bionic. That matters not just because of speed, but because it also means the phone will have a much longer lifetime in your pocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="n2bsbC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9556638"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zPHfUO"&gt;Apple consistently supports its phones for four or more years with software updates. (That’s in opposition to Android, where getting software updates on anything but the Pixel is still a struggle.) So Apple’s choice of a fast processor means that in a few years the iPhone SE will still feel snappy and still be supported with iOS updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mhPqRw"&gt;The iPhone SE has just one camera on the back and just one selfie camera on the front, 12 megapixels and 7 megapixels, respectively. Neither is great by 2020 standards, but both are significantly better than what Apple shipped in older iPhones. It’s also fairly good by the standards of sub-$500 phones, though the Google Pixel 4A continues to win this category by a knockout. You will get a lot of camera features on the iPhone SE, including portrait and HDR, but unfortunately there is no night mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="ODEAze"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Google Pixel 4A has a rear-mounted fingerprint sensor." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zGSyayDrR2mXPWMiM9i0d_4YCk0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21691996/vpavic_200728_4113_0127.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google’s PIxel 4A is the best Android phone under $500.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="yteQuG"&gt;8. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21351770/google-pixel-4a-review-camera-specs-price"&gt;Google Pixel 4A&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="WMeIkj"&gt;Best Android phone under $500&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="cBeDqy"&gt;If you’re on a budget and prefer Android, then the Google Pixel 4A is the obvious choice. It doesn’t have the largest screen or the fastest processor, but it does have a clean version of Android that’s guaranteed to get software updates for at least three years. It only comes in one version: black with 128GB of storage for $349.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tZEqw2"&gt;The Pixel 4A’s main claim to fame is its camera, which can go head-to-head with smartphones that cost $1,500 or more. That’s because Google does so much of the image processing in software — the sensor itself is actually quite old and not very special. It means that the Pixel 4A can take night photos, do astrophotography, and has a passable portrait mode. It can’t hang with the iPhone SE for video but beats it for photos every time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lZsgOa"&gt;The rest of the Pixel 4A’s specs are good but not great. It has a 5.8-inch screen, just enough RAM to keep apps from closing in the background, and a headphone jack. There’s no wireless charging, no fancy face unlock, and the body is made out of plastic instead of something more premium like glass. The Pixel 4A doesn’t even offer any IP water resistance ratings (but a splash of water is probably fine).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ftzlw6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9556642"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sUP4Y7"&gt;But for all that, the Pixel 4A is probably the safest bet if you want to get an Android phone for less than $500. You’ll get better software support and a better camera for $350. Not a bad deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="bozVVC"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 2" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NtDtkO85MCRRENbxtnPm7guG9-Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21829980/Product_image_14.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy Z Fold 2 is expensive, extravagant, and the easiest way to fit a tablet-sized screen into your pocket.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="mre8Bq"&gt;9. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21427462/samsung-galaxy-z-fold-2-review"&gt;Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 2&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="4x700N"&gt;Best folding phone in 2020&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="JDL8H8"&gt;Folding phones have been around for less than two years and have already seen their share of controversies. But if you are interested in buying one and are willing to pay the hefty price required, there’s really only one model worth considering: Samsung’s Galaxy Z Fold 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2Mbw2f"&gt;The Fold 2 is Samsung’s second-generation folding phone. Its main premise is this: it is sized like a normal smartphone that fits in your pocket, but it unfolds to reveal a tablet-sized 7.6-inch display on the inside. That inside screen makes everything from reading books, to browsing the web, to watching video, to playing games more enjoyable and immersive. When you’re done using it, just fold it back up and stick it in your pocket just like any other phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nKplTb"&gt;That flexibility is unmatched by any other phone you can buy right now, but it doesn’t come without a significant list of compromises. The Fold 2 is twice as thick when closed compared to normal phones, and its outside screen is much smaller than you’re used to. It is also delicate — there’s no rated dust or water resistance and its inner screen is more likely to get damaged if you poke it too hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Rta9KS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10215758"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Fp3cHb"&gt;But the biggest compromise is its cost: at $2,000, the Fold 2 is literally twice as expensive as other high-end phones. You’re paying a lot for the ability to fold a tablet screen in half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="xA969T"&gt;If you’re willing to put up with those compromises for an experience that’s unlike anything else though, the Fold 2 delivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iahfYJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AKGbug"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22163811/best-phone"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22163811/best-phone</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-10T11:27:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-10T11:27:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>Next-gen sports games get subtle, solid improvements</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jYWC6h4nLQnqX1Mk-xro6P3Bi0s=/74x0:887x542/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68490946/960x0.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="57IEtp"&gt;One of my favorite things to do whenever new consoles come out is see how sports games run on them. It’s not that I necessarily expect them to be all that different on more powerful hardware — quite the opposite, in fact. Since sports games tend to depict enclosed, fixed environments and need to have perfectly smooth performance every year, they’re normally stable and reliable whatever system you play them on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zu8x2I"&gt;If you look at &lt;em&gt;FIFA&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;NBA 2K&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Madden&lt;/em&gt;, for example, they already run at native 4K and 60 frames per second on the PS4 Pro and the Xbox One X — a pretty rare achievement for most games on those machines. But that means when it comes to the PS5 and the Xbox Series X, 2K and EA have had to figure out new ways to make the next-gen versions stand out. I’ve been playing the 2021 versions of all three games on the PS5, and they’ve all taken different approaches to making the most of the new hardware. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2NX21V"&gt;First and foremost is how you actually get a hold of your copy. EA is offering free PS5 and Xbox Series S / X upgrades to anyone who bought the PS4 or Xbox One versions of &lt;em&gt;FIFA 21&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Madden 21&lt;/em&gt;, but it’s not automatic. You need to go to the console’s respective store to get your next-gen version. 2K, meanwhile, has decided to make &lt;em&gt;NBA 2K21&lt;/em&gt; an entirely separate product for next-gen consoles, meaning you’ll have to buy it regardless of whether you own it on other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3XBkE3"&gt;The next-gen version of &lt;em&gt;NBA 2K21&lt;/em&gt; has a totally new UI for the series and much faster loading times. It feels a lot sleeker and flashier than the functional but occasionally clunky menus that the game had made use of in recent years. &lt;em&gt;2K21&lt;/em&gt; on the PS5 and Xbox Series S / X also has an ambitious new open-world multiplayer hub called The City that lets you explore multiple boroughs with your created player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="UpGri9"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q2MMM00yC7Y?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XGBKGR"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Madden 21&lt;/em&gt; has also had a UI overhaul, particularly for the play-calling system, but much of EA’s most vaunted improvements are under the hood. The company says it’s making use of &lt;a href="https://nextgenstats.nfl.com"&gt;NFL’s Next Gen Stats&lt;/a&gt; — an NFL initiative that has nothing to do with next-gen consoles — to increase the realism of movements, animations, and replays for specific players. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N3xgyx"&gt;&lt;em&gt;FIFA 21&lt;/em&gt; has undergone the most evolutionary next-gen upgrade of the three, with a near-identical UI to the last few last-gen versions. The most immediate difference you’ll notice in gameplay is the new default camera, which pans as well as moving on rails in order to better replicate the TV broadcast camera used in most stadiums. I like this option and plan to stick with it, but I’m not sure why it took so long — or why it required a generational power increase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1PLsNe"&gt;All three games make use of the PS5 DualSense controller’s improved haptics in various ways. Both &lt;em&gt;NBA 2K21&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;FIFA 21&lt;/em&gt; increase the resistance on the right “sprint” trigger when players get tired, which I’ve found pretty useful as someone who sometimes overuses the feature. &lt;em&gt;2K21&lt;/em&gt;’s use of the left trigger to convey defense pressure is a little less successful. It just feels loud and clunky as opposed to helpful feedback. And while &lt;em&gt;Madden 21&lt;/em&gt; uses the haptics effectively to convey the impact of catches and tackles with finer detail, I noticed the DualSense most when audibles were called through its speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qLDOIQ"&gt;The graphical updates to these games are fairly similar across the board. All three run in 4K and 60fps on the PS5 and Series X, as expected, and the biggest improvements are in assets, crowd detail, and, above all else, lighting. The games all handle light in a subtle but much more natural and realistic way, making the last-gen versions look flat when you return to them. It’s particularly effective in &lt;em&gt;FIFA&lt;/em&gt;, which does a better job of capturing the atmosphere of a stadium than ever before, even when you’re watching the crowd celebrate with the same animations you’ve seen in rotation for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="NwgH2M"&gt;&lt;q&gt;‘NBA 2K21’ is the best-looking game of the bunch&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LjfkY7"&gt;&lt;em&gt;NBA 2K21&lt;/em&gt; is the best-looking to my eyes, which perhaps isn’t surprising considering the more intimate nature of the sport and its broadcast presentation. Many of the player models have seen huge improvements, and graphical effects like sweat and skin shading make them look more realistic than ever before. The one area where I wish there’d been an improvement is right at the start of every game: it still runs at 30fps as the camera zooms in for tipoff and continues for the first few seconds of the possession, which is still pretty jarring when the game ultimately shifts to 60. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f6Vs82"&gt;One issue with all of these games is the uneven degree to which they’ve updated the player models. For example, it was understandable that Raptors guard Matt Thomas looked like a generic create-a-player in &lt;em&gt;NBA 2K20&lt;/em&gt; because he was a fairly obscure player that Toronto plucked from the Spanish basketball league last off-season. But he ended up carving out regular minutes in the Raptors’ rotation throughout the year, so it’s a little disappointing to see him with the same model in &lt;em&gt;2K21&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ziCmYy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;FIFA 21&lt;/em&gt; has similar problems. EA seems to have spent a considerable amount of time on a lavish (and admittedly impressive) re-creation of Lionel Messi’s increasingly voluminous beard, and every high-profile Champions League star looks just as good. But as a Southampton fan, I don’t see much year-to-year improvement in the player models. Striker Che Adams looks absolutely nothing like the real guy, for example. I know Southampton aren’t the biggest club in the world, but come on. This is a Premier League-topping team. (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/southamptonfc/status/1324836694420578304"&gt;Briefly&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="un8zmU"&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic could well have affected EA and 2K’s plans for asset creation, so I don’t want to be too harsh here. Xbox boss Phil Spencer &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/video-game-delays-due-to-coronavirus-early-2021-2020-5"&gt;suggested to &lt;em&gt;Business Insider&lt;/em&gt; back in May&lt;/a&gt; that sports games might be more affected than many others, and it’s easy to see why that may have been the case. Between national lockdowns, the NBA bubble, and the quick restart of the upcoming season, I don’t really know when someone like Matt Thomas would have found the time to get his face captured. But it does stand out in the final product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="u1Fmkt"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sSUx54kmUD8?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AhHJiw"&gt;&lt;em&gt;NBA 2K21&lt;/em&gt; was also the victim of unfortunate timing, given its initial last-gen release in September halfway through the playoffs. Normally, this date would be just in time for the start of the regular season, but instead, NBA fans picking the game up at the next-gen consoles’ launches had to deal with a league where the draft never happened and Russell Westbrook was still on the Rockets. 2K did put out roster updates last month, but not in time to stop me from needing to orchestrate a complex trade just to replace Serge Ibaka with Aron Baynes on the Raptors for maximum authenticity on my save file. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YSSucL"&gt;It’ll take a while to properly appreciate the differences in how the new versions of all three games play. Sports titles get countless updates and balancing tweaks on a year-to-year basis, so it’s hard to say right now whether any of the differences I’m feeling are the result of that or a more fundamental shift in how the games will be handled going forward. &lt;em&gt;FIFA&lt;/em&gt; feels a little slower to me, for example, and I feel like I’m having more success with crosses and set pieces than before, but I’m not going to call that a pronouncement of fact just yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m5ETVj"&gt;Overall, the next-gen upgrades to &lt;em&gt;Madden&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;FIFA&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;NBA 2K&lt;/em&gt; are fairly subtle but appreciated nonetheless — particularly in the case of the EA games, where they’re a nice bonus for anyone who would’ve bought the PS4 or Xbox One versions in the first place. If you’re an annual player of any of them, then you’ll see a nice bump for the new hardware. But if you only occasionally play sports games, now might be a good time to check back in. Substantial new games are often thin on the ground after console launches, but any one of these is a solid demonstration of what next-gen systems can do, and you could easily play them for a year or more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8SsQL1"&gt;At least unless Russell Westbrook somehow gets traded again.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167326/ps5-xbox-series-x-s-games-fifa-madden-nba-2k-next-gen-version"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167326/ps5-xbox-series-x-s-games-fifa-madden-nba-2k-next-gen-version</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-10T11:27:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-10T11:27:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>Target is hosting a buy one, get one half off deal on some Nintendo Switch games</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bA56Iycfr_d3V-BJUzxv-Gc8-rE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68490942/jbareham_190718_3551_0011.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="nUuN1z"&gt;As the holidays get closer (and with some arriving now — Happy Hanukkah!), we’re searching for tech deals that make for easy, relatively affordable gifts. It’s always nice when the selection fits a particular theme, but sometimes you’ve got to take what you can get. Like today, wherein we have a great buy one, get one half off deal on some Nintendo Switch games at Target, a solid deal on lightly used Sony WH-1000XM4 wireless, noise-canceling headphones, and a few other odds and ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="HaTcPE"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="4L7VuA"&gt;Nintendo Switch game deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="zUQuDr"&gt;Some of Nintendo’s own titles for the Switch are looped into a buy one, get one half off deal at Target, including must-have games like &lt;em&gt;Super Mario Odyssey&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Super Mario Party&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Luigi’s Mansion 3&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Mario Tennis Aces&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Splatoon 2&lt;/em&gt;, and a few more. You’ll get the discount on the least expensive game in your cart, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fpl%2F734778975%3Fclkid%3D4371ffb9N107311eba65842010a246e32%26lnm%3D360518&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;you can find all of the options here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PS1TdA"&gt;Most of these games have been down to $40 or even $30 during Black Friday, but today’s deal is just about as good, depending on the game you’re looking for. For instance, &lt;em&gt;Super Mario Odyssey&lt;/em&gt; purchased alongside &lt;em&gt;Mario Tennis Aces&lt;/em&gt; costs just over $60.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="u24DOm"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/drjMTWklrIZUSPI6bmVbXgYrGFo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/13728680/jbareham_190131_3203_0008.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by James Bareham / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="RIfwee"&gt;Save on Smart Battery cases for the iPhone XS/XS Max&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="9dS5gN"&gt;Daily Steals is offering a special discount for &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; readers interested in snagging a Smart Battery case for their iPhone XS or XS Max. These usually cost around $100, &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dailysteals.com%2Fproducts%2Fapple-iphone-xs-or-xs-max-smart-battery-case%3Fvariant%3D32442307838039#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;but you can get one in either size for $42&lt;/a&gt; by using the offer code &lt;strong&gt;VERGEACASE&lt;/strong&gt; at checkout. They’re currently available in black, white, or pink, so you have a few options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="xk7NZq"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="FTy9EH"&gt;Lightly used Sony WH-1000XM4 are $60 off&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A photo of Sony’s WH-1000XM4, the best noise-canceling headphones for most people, resting on a table." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nfnb67pDrZK7noQDhl7_IliL-CM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21699857/IMG_0620-1.0.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XBYeZA"&gt;Sony’s WH-1000XM4 noise-canceling headphones are a great gift for people who appreciate excellent sound quality and blocking out noise. Back Market, which sells refurbished tech products, is &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.backmarket.com%2Ftested-and-certified-used-headphones-bluetooth-noise-cancelling-with-micro-sony-wh-1000xm4-black%2F136108.html%3Foffer_type%3D6%23%3Fl%3D0#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;selling them for $228 with a one-year warranty&lt;/a&gt;. This is their normal price for “mint” condition (no scratches, appears brand new) refurbished units of this model, but &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;readers can save an extra $10 to bring the price down to $218 before tax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a3frPq"&gt;To get this deal, visit the link, add them to your cart, and enter the code &lt;strong&gt;Verge2020 &lt;/strong&gt;at checkout to see the right price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="6j1YFv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2020/12/10/22167319/nintendo-switch-games-deal-iphone-xs-max-sony-wh1000xm4"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2020/12/10/22167319/nintendo-switch-games-deal-iphone-xs-max-sony-wh1000xm4</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-10T11:05:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-10T11:05:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>Instagram would be better off without Facebook</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ny4Zt_c7Kc3bCaA-2azdMAO2934=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68490805/acastro_190919_1777_instagram_0002.0.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="E7KrIV"&gt;For years, critics have argued that Facebook’s acquisition of Instagram was a missed opportunity to rein in the company. But now, they’ll have the chance to actually undo it. On Wednesday afternoon, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22158483/facebook-antitrust-lawsuit-anti-competition-behavior-attorneys-general"&gt;the Federal Trade Commission joined with 48 state attorneys general&lt;/a&gt; to call for a court-ordered divestiture of Instagram and WhatsApp — essentially, forcing Facebook to undo both acquisitions and spin them back into independent companies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3AzhMg"&gt;Regulators are still a long way from making that happen, but for the first time, it’s a possibility that Facebook can’t ignore. And for Instagram users, it raises a question that’s both alarming and tantalizing: what would Instagram look like without Facebook?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P1xcNj"&gt;In the years since the 2012 acquisition, Instagram has benefited hugely from its relationship with Facebook, gaining massive scale and freeing itself from the pressure to achieve profitability. Even now, Facebook’s support is crucial to Instagram’s aggressive product development cycle and low-profile navigation of content moderation challenges. If regulators succeed, Instagram would have to build much of that from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TOMtTt"&gt;At the same time, there are reasons to think Instagram might be better off without Facebook’s baggage and might actually thrive outside the Menlo Park bubble. The Facebook name and tie mean an association with a chaotic mess of a platform and a branding nightmare. Every day Instagram stays within the Facebook family is another where it’s at risk for user backlash because of its parent company’s actions. Without that headache, Instagram could focus on what made it a popular app in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="yGf4gx"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Instagram has a chance to leave Facebook behind&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qUc4kk"&gt;Less than 24 hours after the cases were announced, Facebook has yet to mount its full defense against the antitrust lawsuits. But &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2020/12/lawsuits-filed-by-the-ftc-and-state-attorneys-general-are-revisionist-history/"&gt;in a blog post yesterday&lt;/a&gt;, the company’s general counsel gave an early preview of its case, arguing a spinoff would be both unfair and unfeasible. “No American antitrust enforcer has ever brought a case like this before, and for good reason,” wrote general counsel Jennifer Newstead. “The FTC and states stood by for years while Facebook invested billions of dollars and millions of hours to make Instagram and WhatsApp into the apps that users enjoy today.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0i1szy"&gt;But peeling apart a conglomerate isn’t quite as difficult as Newstead makes it sound. Companies do it all the time when they see profit in it, whether it’s Hewlett-Packard’s &lt;a href="https://www.hpe.com/us/en/newsroom/press-release/2017/09/hewlett-packard-enterprise-completes-spin-off-and-merger-of-software-business-with-micro-focus.html"&gt;spinoff of its enterprise business&lt;/a&gt; in 2017 or IAC’s spinoff of Match Group &lt;a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/iac-and-match-group-complete-full-separation-301086627.html"&gt;earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;. Of course, it’s different when it’s mandated by the government, but even that has a fairly recent precedent in the Bell breakup of the ‘80s. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0hLt7T"&gt;After eight years of corporate integration, a spinoff of Instagram would surely be difficult. Facebook bought Instagram for $1 billion in 2012 during a quainter time for both companies, and since then, Facebook has attempted to tightly integrate the two apps. From the onset, it boosted Instagram’s visibility by tagging photos posted to Facebook from Instagram with a link to the app and prompted people to follow their Facebook friends on Instagram. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IvuniP"&gt;“Instagram was easier to buy than to build because once a network takes off, there are few reasons to join a smaller one,” writes Sarah Frier in her book &lt;a href="https://www.simonandschuster.com/books/No-Filter/Sarah-Frier/9781982126803"&gt;&lt;em&gt;No Filter: The Inside Story of Instagram&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “It becomes part of the infrastructure of society.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="DOwHyN"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Facebook has pushed to integrate the two apps&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0TCejJ"&gt;Facebook also backed the company financially and shared its ad technology to help it actually make money, which Instagram wasn’t doing prior to the acquisition. But even though Facebook eventually ended its promotional support, its network effects already took hold: Instagram now has 1 billion users and ads all over the place. In the most important areas, Facebook’s work is already done. If Instagram spun off now, those crucial changes would remain in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oFN5eJ"&gt;The remaining integrations with Facebook seemingly work more for Facebook’s own good than Instagram’s. In recent years, Facebook has tried even harder to link the two apps, allowing users to cross-post their content across both Facebook and Instagram. Facebook Messenger &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2020/09/new-messaging-features-for-instagram/"&gt;is now available&lt;/a&gt; through Instagram, tying the platforms together in a single, unified messaging system. But for Instagram users, those integrations mostly serve to make Facebook that much more inescapable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IZvDDB"&gt;It’s these tight ties that reportedly pushed Instagram co-founders Kevin Systrom and Mike Krieger &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/24/17899208/instagram-cofounders-resign-facebook-kevin-systrom-mike-krieger"&gt;to resign&lt;/a&gt;. Both executives quit after Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/interface/2019/4/17/18411363/why-instagram-founders-quit-hamburger-button-location-tracking"&gt;reportedly revoked&lt;/a&gt; its growth support and tested new designs and features while Systrom was away on paternity leave, including a hamburger menu and location tracking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OsY9lA"&gt;The Messenger integration is the most obvious place where users might be disadvantaged — people on Facebook wouldn’t be able to message a friend who’s on Instagram and vice versa — but that feature is fairly recent and only intermittently visible to users. Before now, users seemed to be fine with siloing off their respective platform friends, so it’s hard to argue it would be traumatic to put the silos back in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Pxhpzf"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Facebook only merged Messenger and Instagram DMs earlier this year&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FxlY6M"&gt;The biggest question is whether Instagram could survive without Facebook’s money. Facebook has never broken out Instagram’s financials, so we have no official idea whether the platform is profitable on its own. However, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-02-04/instagram-generates-more-than-a-quarter-of-facebook-s-sales"&gt;wrote early this year&lt;/a&gt; that Instagram generated more than a quarter of Facebook’s revenue in 2019, or about $20 billion from advertising. That’s obviously significant and more than most social competitors, like Snap, bring in on their own. We don’t know Instagram’s independent operating costs, but with $20 billion in only advertising revenue, it’s easy to imagine the team could still manage to profit while developing new products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pBFVMG"&gt;One area Instagram could struggle without Facebook is its burgeoning commerce business. This is an area where the Facebook infrastructure certainly helps Instagram and also where the company would have to invest. Right now, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/12/20961447/facebook-pay-whatsapp-instagram-messenger-features"&gt;Facebook Pay&lt;/a&gt; allows Instagram users to buy products directly from the platform. Facebook doesn’t license Facebook Pay out to third-party apps yet, so Instagram would have to either continue a relationship with PayPal, which it also already uses for some payment processing, or build its own payment technology to encourage people to keep buying from the app. Instagram currently isn’t making money off transactions — &lt;a href="https://business.instagram.com/blog/updates-to-checkout-on-instagram-and-shops-features"&gt;selling fees have been waived for this year&lt;/a&gt; — but shopping revenue would become critical to growing Instagram’s business. Already, though, Instagram has a solid start on commerce that it could likely continue without Facebook’s help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y2vSnU"&gt;Of course, the reason advertisers and shops look to buy space on Instagram is its ability to target users with products and ads that most appeal to them. Much of that data is brought in through Facebook, which would be a major loss for both Facebook and Instagram and could reduce how much both platforms know about their users. Instagram might not be able to charge as much for ads without that precise targeting, but it still has a massive user base that brands would want to reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Zkdg9y"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Without Facebook, Instagram could lose valuable user data&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5Y3hI7"&gt;The biggest loss to Instagram if it spun off would be Facebook’s moderation investments. For all its blunders, Facebook has invested an enormous amount in moderation policy and enforcement, from its unprecedented &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/22/21528364/facebook-oversight-board-content-zuckerberg-policy"&gt;Oversight Board&lt;/a&gt; to the small army of international moderators hired in recent years. And while Facebook has taken the blame for most of the failures, Instagram has benefited from the response, able to implement premade policy and take down content after it’s been flagged on the larger platform. After a spinoff, Instagram would have to build its own system from scratch, a daunting task for even the most successful platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GxX4vo"&gt;But despite that significant hurdle, Facebook ownership feels like more of a liability than an asset. The platform is a moderation mess that’s spurred &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/28/17789202/facebook-myanmar-ban-genocide-military-leadership"&gt;local genocide&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/11/14/13626694/election-2016-trending-social-media-facebook-twitter-influence"&gt;influenced elections&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/interface/2020/5/28/21272001/facebook-polarization-wall-street-journal-guy-rosen-platform-integrity-twitter-trump"&gt;polarized the world&lt;/a&gt;. Instagram has, miraculously, avoided most of this blowback, although misinformation and conspiracy theories &lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2020/08/how-instagram-aesthetics-repackage-qanon/615364/"&gt;still thrive on the platform&lt;/a&gt;. Its lack of groups and a recommendation algorithm that doesn’t thrust fake news stories in front of users, however, have helped it dodge the worst of Facebook’s problems. If separated, Instagram could rid itself of Facebook’s issues entirely. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Txyt2N"&gt;Instagram has become the go-to app for many people, sometimes replacing their use of Facebook. Under Facebook’s guidance, the app’s become more feature-packed with more formats than ever. It’s no longer just a photo app. But for the users who rely on Instagram to promote their business or reach new audiences, they might prefer if Facebook had nothing to do with the app at all. Instagram could exist on its own, untainted by Facebook’s problems, and become, again, an independent place online where people can truly connect with the people and things they care about.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22165534/instagram-facebook-antitrust-ftc-lawsuit-monopoly-case-opportunity"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22165534/instagram-facebook-antitrust-ftc-lawsuit-monopoly-case-opportunity</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-12-10T10:45:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-10T10:45:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>The good and the bad in the government’s case against Facebook</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e18iqEwaA5SNPK8Qj5nz8mpkXeA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68490632/acastro_180406_1777_facebook_Congress_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;h2 id="D74t6l"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="xUclNM"&gt;After writing about the potential breakup of Facebook for years, it’s somewhat surreal for me to see the prospect actually arrive. But it’s here: &lt;a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/press-releases/2020/12/ftc-sues-facebook-illegal-monopolization"&gt;the Federal Trade Commission voted 3-2 to sue Facebook for illegally maintaining a monopoly in social networking&lt;/a&gt;, arguing it has used acquisitions and harsh restrictions on third-party developers to prevent competitors from ever gaining a foothold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PFMSzW"&gt;If successful, the FTC’s case — which was joined by 46 states, the District of Columbia, and Guam — could force the company to divest itself of Instagram and WhatsApp, radically reshaping the digital economy. The move comes less than six weeks after the Department of Justice &lt;a href="https://www.platformer.news/p/justice-comes-for-google"&gt;filed an antitrust lawsuit accusing Google of also maintaining an illegal monopoly on search&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vEf4pq"&gt;“For nearly a decade, Facebook has used its dominance and monopoly power to crush smaller rivals and snuff out competition, all at the expense of everyday users,” &lt;a href="https://ag.ny.gov/press-release/2020/attorney-general-james-leads-multistate-lawsuit-seeking-end-facebooks-illegal"&gt;said Letitia James&lt;/a&gt;, New York’s attorney general. “Today, we are taking action to stand up for the millions of consumers and many small businesses that have been harmed by Facebook’s illegal behavior.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mplymw"&gt;You can &lt;a href="https://www.ftc.gov/system/files/documents/cases/1910134fbcomplaint.pdf"&gt;read the FTC’s complaint here&lt;/a&gt;; it’s 53 pages long and the only one I made it through today before succumbing to deadline pressure. &lt;a href="https://ag.ny.gov/sites/default/files/facebook_complaint_12.9.2020.pdf"&gt;The states’ complaint clocks in at 123 pages&lt;/a&gt;, and I expect to have more to say about it tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="WXt2cK"&gt;&lt;q&gt;I expect the lawsuit that follows will be a years-long affair&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eikZYT"&gt;As presented in the FTC’s complaint, the case against Facebook is relatively straightforward. The government argues that social networks supported by digital advertising are part of a defined market, that Facebook acquired Instagram and WhatsApp to eliminate competition in this market, and that it also restricted access to its developer platform to harm competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fvz6Qk"&gt;In response, it calls for the company to divest itself of both apps. It also calls for any future Facebook acquisitions to be subject to prior approval from the FTC, for Facebook to stop “imposing anticompetitive conditions on access to APIs and data,” and to file regular compliance reports with the FTC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d0IWqv"&gt;Facebook, though, calls all that “revisionist history.” In a response credited from the company’s chief counsel, Jennifer Newstead, &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2020/12/lawsuits-filed-by-the-ftc-and-state-attorneys-general-are-revisionist-history/"&gt;the company protests the government’s attempt to force a breakup despite having declined to stop the acquisitions of either Instagram or WhatsApp at the time&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8Hw2wf"&gt;“Now, many years later, with seemingly no regard for settled law or the consequences to innovation and investment, the agency is saying it got it wrong and wants a do-over,” Newstead writes. “In addition to being revisionist history, this is simply not how the antitrust laws are supposed to work. No American antitrust enforcer has ever brought a case like this before, and for good reason. The FTC and states stood by for years while Facebook invested billions of dollars and millions of hours to make Instagram and WhatsApp into the apps that users enjoy today.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3CGhNO"&gt;I expect the lawsuit that follows will be a years-long affair. (Mark Zuckerberg said as much in a note to employees Wednesday.) In the end, I think the government will likely fail in its attempt to break Facebook up. But I think it will succeed in preventing Facebook from making anti-competitive mergers in the future — and that the ongoing rise of TikTok, and whatever comes after TikTok, will begin to restore balance to the sector of the economy that Facebook dominated for the next decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="GzaVON"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Facebook made the market less competitive, and now we’ll never know&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hp3WP7"&gt;And I’m glad the government took this case. It begins to change the standard for enforcement of antitrust law in the digital age away from the current one, which focuses on monopolies that raise prices for consumers to one that takes a broader view of consumer harm. Here, from the complaint, is the FTC’s take on what Facebook’s acquisition of Instagram, in particular, has cost us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="vl0dQU"&gt;This conduct deprives users of the benefits of competition from an independent Instagram (either on its own or acquired by a third party), including, among other things: the presence of an additional locus of competitive decision-making and innovation; a check on Facebook Blue’s treatment of and level of service offered to users; an alternative provider of personal social networking for users untethered from Facebook’s control; and a spur for Facebook to compete on the merits in response.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="kCJMzc"&gt;As for WhatsApp, the government argues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="I0bxwy"&gt;By acquiring WhatsApp, Facebook has suppressed the competitive threat that WhatsApp poses to Facebook’s personal social networking monopoly. Facebook has kept WhatsApp cabined to providing mobile messaging services rather than allowing WhatsApp to become a competing personal social networking provider, and has limited promotion of WhatsApp in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Tv3wdf"&gt;This can all feel a little abstract, and I’m sure Facebook will argue as much in court. It’s hard to weigh the value of Instagram and WhatsApp as they exist today against what they might have become had they remained independent or been acquired by another corporation. But from the government’s point of view, that’s exactly the point: Facebook made the market less competitive, and now we’ll never know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="kdm72U"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="AL6CYK"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="aFZwkW"&gt;At the same time, I think the government’s case has a hard road ahead of it. As I wrote this month, &lt;a href="https://www.platformer.news/p/facebooks-antitrust-showdown-approaches"&gt;the lawsuit would have felt much more vital two or three years ago&lt;/a&gt;. In the time it took the government to flesh out these arguments, many of which have been made in some form since at least 2014, TikTok was born and acquired 800 million users around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cWpii5"&gt;Now, the government argues that apps like TikTok aren’t relevant to the market. “Personal social networking is distinct from, and not reasonably interchangeable with, online video or audio consumption-focused services such as YouTube, Spotify, Netflix, and Hulu,” it writes, though TikTok itself is never mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="8HjLjr"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s clear that Facebook faces a real challenge from TikTok&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="G8vzDc"&gt;The idea that these apps are not interchangeable would be news to Facebook. In September, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21444203/facebook-leaked-audio-zuckerberg-trump-pandemic-blm"&gt;I wrote about what happened when TikTok — which children use for an average of 80 minutes a day — was banned in India&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="mXKGgt"&gt;On June 29th, India banned TikTok on national security grounds. A week later, in an internal post, a Facebook data scientist reported that usage of the company’s products was surging across India. With TikTok gone, Instagram’s daily users increased 9 percent and were spending 19 percent more time within the app. With TikTok gone, they posted 5 million more stories and sent 214 million more messages on Instagram alone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="FQmmfX"&gt;When companies are forced to argue that they are not, in fact, monopolies, they often try to define their market in comically broad terms. (Though it was not in an antitrust context, I’m reminded of &lt;a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/40491939/netflix-ceo-reed-hastings-sleep-is-our-competition"&gt;the time Netflix co-CEO Reed Hastings said the company’s chief rival is sleep&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nxkllU"&gt;And yet, looking at the data, it’s clear that Facebook faces a real challenge from TikTok. Just as WhatsApp once had the potential to grow into a more fully featured social network — something the government explains in careful detail — so does ByteDance’s shortform video app. TikTok’s success is transforming the entire industry; &lt;a href="https://www.platformer.news/p/snapchats-million-dollar-idea"&gt;Snapchat just added its own shortform video tab this month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pw3foR"&gt;Moreover, as the Stanford Internet Observatory’s Alex Stamos noted, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/alexstamos/status/1336761289004044289?s=20"&gt;the FTC’s push to force Facebook to open its APIs up to competitors raises real privacy concerns&lt;/a&gt;. It was only last July that &lt;a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/blogs/business-blog/2019/07/ftcs-5-billion-facebook-settlement-record-breaking-history"&gt;the FTC fined Facebook $5 billion for failing to honor the terms of a 2012 consent decree&lt;/a&gt; that forbid it from making deceptive claims about “consumers’ ability to control the privacy of their personal data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ObHPY3"&gt;That same FTC now says that placing restrictions on the flow of user data from Facebook to third-party developers is anti-competitive and illegal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R6XCk9"&gt;Also noteworthy: the FTC &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/ftc-request-to-reconsider-qualcomm-antitrust-case-rejected-by-appeals-court-11603908027"&gt;just lost a similar case against Qualcomm over its licensing practices&lt;/a&gt;. Sources familiar with Facebook’s thinking on the case have pointed to that decision as boding well for its defense, which will likely hold that companies have broad discretion to decide with whom they do business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="i6Rbdo"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hPCENP"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;III&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="QsVpxi"&gt;Whatever the outcome of this case or the government’s case against Google, it’s clear that the United States has entered a much bolder new era of antitrust enforcement. For the sake of competition and consumer benefits, I think that’s a good thing. Even if the cases themselves fall short of their most ambitious aims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="qi4NfP"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It’s a much different company than it was before the antitrust case&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="J1V88p"&gt;It’s tempting to begin to imagine a world where Instagram and WhatsApp are once again operating independently, forcing Facebook to innovate more and copy less. Perhaps we’ll all live in that world someday — and discover that &lt;em&gt;it&lt;/em&gt; comes with trade-offs, too. Or maybe the distraction of a multiyear antitrust case will blind Facebook to the next competitive threat, as the Microsoft antitrust case is often said to have done to that company, and it will stumble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HAyLp1"&gt;The thing about Microsoft, though, is that it’s still a giant of industry. It’s a much different company than it was before the antitrust case, to be sure. But so would be any company after 20 years in the technology industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iC7sjz"&gt;Lots of excited retweets in my timeline from critics and lawmakers today suggest that people believe today’s case could be the beginning of the end for Facebook. But while I expect that this will mark the start of a painful period for the company, in the end, I’d be surprised if the resolution of this case weren’t much less dramatic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="xhnmxF"&gt;
&lt;p id="TPOuVk"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This column was co-published with &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.platformer.news/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Platformer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, a daily newsletter about Big Tech and democracy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22166978/facebook-ftc-antitrust-instagram-whatsapp-tiktok"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22166978/facebook-ftc-antitrust-instagram-whatsapp-tiktok</id>
    <author>
      <name>Casey Newton</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
