<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-11-09T09:24:01-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-09T09:24:01-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-09T09:24:01-05:00</updated>
    <title>You.com wants to remake the search engine</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A You.com search page showing results for “Billie Eilish”" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/82wMCTjnN4Ffktr7gqFx7OvQHPA=/0x290:3106x2361/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70116184/Billie_Eilish.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;You.com&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="je6ArS"&gt;Google Search organizes the way billions of people think about facts and data, and for years, it’s been organized around &lt;a href="https://searchengineland.com/googles-one-true-answer-problem-featured-snippets-270549"&gt;a principle dubbed “one true answer”&lt;/a&gt;: the idea that most people are looking for something best answered by a succinct factual snippet. But that’s not the only way people might navigate the web, and today, a company called You.com is trying something different: a search engine built around sorting and comparing results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5P1qh1"&gt;&lt;a href="https://you.com/?safe_search=Moderate"&gt;You.com&lt;/a&gt;, founded by two former Salesforce employees, is opening today in public beta and announcing a $20 million funding round led by Salesforce CEO Marc Benioff. The service abandons the linear list of links you’ll find in most general-purpose search engines, opting for a grid of answers organized by source. The sources include generic categories like “web results” and “news” but also specific sites like StackOverflow, Wikipedia, Twitter, Amazon, LinkedIn, and individual news sites like &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A You.com search for “Section 230” offering a grid of search results" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/m86GIXFJQOIkwezYDPFlVyckbPM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22998185/Screen_Shot_2021_11_09_at_6.46.32_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="kTdY4N"&gt;On top of this organizational change, You.com’s big differentiating feature is that it lets people influence which sources they see. You can “upvote” and “downvote” specific categories, so when you run searches, you’ll see preferred sources first, neutral searches next, and downvoted sources last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="9uVHed"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The You.com grid encourages comparing sources instead of clicking the first link&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5w2q8E"&gt;When I searched for “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22268421/cda-section-230-25th-anniversary-reform-stakes-big-tech-internet"&gt;Section 230&lt;/a&gt;” on You.com’s pre-launch beta, for instance, it defaulted to showing a box of general “web results” first, including links to Cornell University and the Electronic Frontier Foundation. But I could also opt to see something like a Wikipedia snippet or a series of Reddit results first. The categories are also influenced by the context of your search. If I searched “Moonfall” it would favor an IMDb-powered “What to Watch” box for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/2/22654021/moonfall-trailer-date-halle-berry-roland-emmerich"&gt;upcoming Roland Emmerich film&lt;/a&gt;, while looking up “infrastructure bill” prioritized a general news grid and media coverage from many different outlets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sWhiH5"&gt;Some of these searches — like the Section 230 one — ultimately surface pretty similar results to Google. But the interface encourages looking across a range of sources rather than clicking the first one or two links. It also includes interesting tools for specific use cases. Searching “for loop javascript,” for instance, will summon lists of reference pages on Google, but You.com will surface actual plaintext snippets of syntax from sources like W3Schools that you can easily copy and paste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="o8I8VD"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The engine can’t guess what you’re thinking as well as Google&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IR1JTR"&gt;You.com isn’t optimized for answering basic questions the way Google is, especially for queries that require guessing what people &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; instead of what they literally type. It’s a lot more willing to encourage clicking through to other pages — if you want the “actor who plays Sherlock Holmes,” You.com will deliver links to lists while Google will give you a grid of movie stars. It doesn’t include little features like offering answers in the search bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4gkJTr"&gt;And You.com is generally worse at guiding your eye to the most relevant information. If you’re not used to closely reading the text of search results, it looks overwhelming and sort of cluttered. I only used a desktop version of the prelaunch beta, which feels like the way it’s &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt; to be experienced but isn’t necessarily where most people want to search the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dqdjME"&gt;But the service seems far more honest about its own limitations than Google. Google’s text snippets are arguably the platform’s worst feature, granting a &lt;a href="https://theoutline.com/post/1192/google-s-featured-snippets-are-worse-than-fake-news"&gt;false sense of authoritativeness&lt;/a&gt; to inaccurate or offensive information or even summarizing an accurate answer in a &lt;a href="https://mobile.twitter.com/emilymbender/status/1449539234210062340"&gt;dangerously wrong way&lt;/a&gt;. (Full disclosure: I could only find that last link through Google, where I got it by hunting down “google seizure snippet,” while You.com offered general information about snippets and seizures.) You.com does offer a “Quick Facts” box for queries like “distance from the Earth to the Moon,” but it’s delivered alongside a bunch of other results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bRO18H"&gt;You.com comes tantalizingly close to being an engine for web search power users who like comparing multiple sources of information. It’s still missing key features like searching within a limited date range, something co-founder and CEO Richard Socher says is coming later, and it’s not as all-purpose as Google. (Clicking the closed beta’s Maps icon actually just directs you to Google Maps.) But that’s part of the appeal — Socher reasonably describes You.com as “unbundling” search from a Google-style web empire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="I6lnax"&gt;&lt;q&gt;You.com avoids feeling like a more principled, less useful Google clone&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ireXUb"&gt;Weirdly, the company doesn’t make this pitch very well in its launch announcement. It describes its system as “summarizing results from across the web,” which feels almost precisely backward. Socher says the phrase refers to You.com’s grouping of results by source, but compared to Google, it features practically no explicit editorial summarizing of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QIKT49"&gt;Like DuckDuckGo, Brave Search, and other services trying to chip away at Google’s overwhelming dominance in search, You.com emphasizes the idea that it’s more private and less heavily tracked. It’s not supported by ads and linked with countless tie-in products the way Google is, and there’s an incognito mode that You.com says hides your IP address. Among other things, it promises that it will never target personalized ads at users. The service, unfortunately, doesn’t have a business model at all yet, however, so it’s not clear what kind of other tradeoffs it might have to make in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rWjHyL"&gt;You.com probably won’t appeal to everyone, but it’s offering an interesting and fairly unique feature set. It’s one of the rare non-subject-specific search engines that avoids feeling like a more principled but practically inferior version of Google — encouraging thinking about the web as an actual network of websites, not just grist for an answer box.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22770614/you-salesforce-startup-search-engine-privacy-information-control"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22770614/you-salesforce-startup-search-engine-privacy-information-control</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-09T09:02:09-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-09T09:02:09-05:00</updated>
    <title>Peloton takes on strength training with its $495 Guide camera system, coming in 2022 </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Lfuzx6iu-3Ami-x55ch5yOaWQ28=/120x0:1080x640/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70116113/Tiger_Announcement_Press_Image_11042021___01.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="hyfsUV"&gt;Peloton is moving into strength training with its latest product, &lt;a href="https://www.onepeloton.com/guide-announce"&gt;the Peloton Guide&lt;/a&gt;, a TV-connected camera that can display workouts and track your movements in real time to help make sure you’re doing things properly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r028ed"&gt;Peloton Guide is also the company’s cheapest product yet, set to cost $495 at launch in “early 2022” for a bundle that includes the Guide camera, the company’s newly updated Peloton Heart Rate Band, and a remote. You’ll have to provide other workout equipment like weights or resistance bands on your own, though. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VnWJt2"&gt;Additionally, &lt;a href="https://support.onepeloton.com/hc/en-us/articles/4409958503444"&gt;Guide owners&lt;/a&gt; will need a $12.99 per month membership (the same price that Peloton charges for its app-only subscription) to use the service, although if you already own a Tread or Bike and pay for the $39-per-month All-Access Membership, you won’t have to pay more to use a Guide. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2cFwaVJGmjaciPCDukMSiCvz4QQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22998217/Fullwidth_Media_02_Desktop.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="6aL98u"&gt;Technically, Peloton has already offered strength training classes for a while now (the rotating screen on the Peloton Bike Plus is even designed to help facilitate them). But the Guide aims to provide a more comprehensive experience by offering what the company calls “Self Mode,” which uses the Guide’s built-in camera to track your movements and show your workout on the screen alongside the instructors to make sure you’re doing exercises properly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aRvKWS"&gt;That said, with the cost of membership the same between using &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/2/21202979/peloton-android-tv-app-launch-social-distancing"&gt;the free app on an existing set-top box&lt;/a&gt; and buying Peloton’s $495 bespoke hardware, Peloton’s tracking will have to be very impressive to justify the added cost here. It’s about on par with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/2/22758939/tempo-move-iphone-smart-home-gym-workout-tracker-live-classes"&gt;competitors like the Tempo Move&lt;/a&gt; ($495 at launch), although that bundle simply uses an iPhone for a camera and does include weights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AC3RRk"&gt;In addition to the camera for tracking movement, the Guide also features a built-in microphone, allowing you to play, pause, rewind, or fast forward through a class without having to put down your weights or stop whatever exercise you’re doing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vX5Wfb"&gt;Of course, with any smart device that features a microphone and a camera that lives in your living room, there are the obvious questions of privacy. Peloton promises that customers will be able to fully control the device with an integrated camera cover for when you’re not using it and a physical switch to disable the microphone. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zFvQpKHdWYmvNBTp-QS6FalIpZg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22998218/Tiger_Announcement_Press_Image_11042021___02.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="KxYnSe"&gt;To start, the Guide will only offer strength-focused classes (both bodyweight only and with added weights), although Peloton says that it plans to add support for more types of workouts over time. The company’s announcement also conspicuously doesn’t have any information about whether the Guide will offer live classes for strength workouts like those Peloton offers for its Tread and Bike products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ofQJAc"&gt;In addition to the Guide, Peloton is also debuting a new heart rate monitor (which will be included with all Guide purchases). The updated monitor is an armband, instead of a chest strap, and features integrated LEDs to allow you to more easily check your heart rate with a quick glance. The new strap will be sold separately for $89 in “early 2022,” a $40 increase over the company’s soon to be discontinued $49 chest strap. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vIk5tx"&gt;The Peloton Guide is set to launch in the US and Canada in early 2022, and in the UK, Australia, and Germany “in 2022.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22771827/peloton-guide-camera-movement-tracking-price-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22771827/peloton-guide-camera-movement-tracking-price-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-09T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-09T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Fitbit is rolling out an ECG app to the Charge 5</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DuTjMoDXckniFUj-CqknrSlu3gY=/0x85:2040x1445/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70116011/jpeters_210914_4757_0007.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Jay Peters / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EWtsu6"&gt;Fitbit released its Charge 5 fitness tracker with a brand new design and a color screen &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/27/22697200/fitbit-charge-5-fitness-tracker-price-available"&gt;in September&lt;/a&gt;, but it launched without two key software features: an electrocardiogram (ECG) app and Fitbit’s new Daily Readiness Score, which recommends how hard you should work out. More than a month after the Charge 5’s release, those features are now rolling out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="seu2XI"&gt;The ECG app takes a reading of your heart’s rhythm to assess for atrial fibrillation. To take the reading, open the app, put your fingers on the stainless steel panels on each side of the Charge 5, and wait for 30 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xW8fBpxLnx8aBIQklwqzcmI4ALY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22859125/Fitbit_Charge_5_Still_Deep_Sea_Sport.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Fitbit&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Each side of the Charge 5 has a stainless steel panel where you place your fingers during an ECG test.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="48aDwq"&gt;ECG apps are showing up in more wearables, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/4/22152346/fitbit-sense-electrocardiogram-ecg-reading-hardware-issue-replacement"&gt;Fitbit’s own Sense smartwatch&lt;/a&gt; and the Apple Watch, but you shouldn’t take readings from the apps as a definitive diagnosis of atrial fibrillation. Research has shown that the Apple Watch &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/30/22702151/apple-watch-heartbeat-irregular-pulse-afib"&gt;can flag multiple types of irregular heartbeats&lt;/a&gt;, for example, so if you have any concerns about your heart health, consult a doctor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q9D5he"&gt;The new Daily Readiness Score uses data tracked by your Fitbit to recommend a level of intensity for your workout that day. Your Fitbit device assesses your activity, heart rate variability, and sleep to calculate the score. A higher score means Fitbit thinks you can take on a more intense level of activity, while a lower score means you should prioritize a lower-intensity workout to help with recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2AjDRt"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6rWc7gxgu6Y?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eSH0uO"&gt;The Daily Readiness Score is a Fitbit Premium-exclusive feature, so if you want to use it, you’ll have to be a member of the $9.99-per-month (or $79.99-per-year) subscription service. It’s supported by more Fitbit devices than just the Charge 5, though; it’s also available on the Fitbit Sense, Versa 3, Versa 2, Luxe, or Inspire 2 starting Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22765408/fitbit-charge-5-ecg-electrocardiogram-app-daily-readiness-score"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22765408/fitbit-charge-5-ecg-electrocardiogram-app-daily-readiness-score</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-09T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-09T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>This $252 Nokia X100 is a budget 5G phone with a 1080p display and 6GB RAM</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Iuo3ZS4_YPvZib4d0za9eKlQdNE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70116059/nokia_x100_product_photo__2_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nokia X100 is a T-Mobile and Metro by T-Mobile exclusive budge 5G phone.&lt;/em&gt; | HMD Global&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6K8CXr"&gt;Starting November 19th, 2021, T-Mobile and Metro by T-Mobile will be adding another budget 5G phone to the lineup — the $252 Nokia X100 that is exclusive to T-Mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OLQUYX"&gt;This addition is coming just as the holiday shopping season is ready for kickoff, and T-Mobile’s sales of other budget 5G phones from REVVL and certain OnePlus models have been limited by handset shortages, according to Wave7 Research’s September 2021 Smartphone Report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fIZwuq"&gt;Nokia is doing its part to jump-start sales by packing the X100 with lots of surprising features, despite its small sub-$300 price tag. While it shares similar looks and the same Qualcomm Snapdragon 480 5G processor as the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22760873/nokia-g50-review-mobile-5g-sub6hz-android-smartphone"&gt;$300 Nokia G50&lt;/a&gt;, that’s where their similarities end. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IDd0HT"&gt;Unlike the G50, the X100 is geared for entertainment. It has a 6.67-inch 1080p full HD display (1080 x 2400p resolution), with a 20:9 aspect ratio that is a little wider to better fit full-screen videos. It has 6GB of RAM to support its processor, 128GB of internal storage, as well as a microSD card slot that can accept up to a 1TB card for backup and extra storage. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a4069TCDv9dDJEAbUwGVTcz_6Nk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22996850/Nokia_X100_Lifestyle_Photo__6_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;HMD Global&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nokia X100 has quad rear cameras, including a 2-megapixel Macro camera for closeups and extreme details.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="S8PTBp"&gt;The cheaper Nokia X100 also has four cameras on the back: a 48-megapixel main camera, a 5-megapixel ultrawide camera, a 2-megapixel depth camera, as well as a 2-megapixel Macro camera for extreme closeups and details. It also has a 16-megapixel front-facing camera for selfies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kda8v6"&gt;Out of the box, the X100 uses Android 11, but it’s unclear if and when this model will get future OS or security updates from the carrier or manufacturer. It’s worth noting this Nokia doesn’t have the biggest battery at 4,470mAh, especially in combination with its high-resolution screen and 5G connectivity. However, it still has a 3.5mm audio jack for wired headphone fans, as well as NFC to handle contactless payments. As a 5G phone, the X100 is compatible with T-Mobile’s slower but more widely available sub-6Hz 5G network, in case you need 5G speeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bhd4QQ"&gt;You can find the Nokia X100 at T-Mobile and Metro by T-Mobile stores starting on November 19th for $252. Keep your eyes peeled for extra carrier holiday deals to sweeten the Nokia X100 even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cpHTAE"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fwywxv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y477jU"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22770393/nokia-x100-252-budget-5g-phone-1080p-display-6gb-ram-andriod-smartphone"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22770393/nokia-x100-252-budget-5g-phone-1080p-display-6gb-ram-andriod-smartphone</id>
    <author>
      <name>Gloria Sin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-09T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-09T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Motional’s robotaxis will be fully driverless in Las Vegas by 2023</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1K-fiRUkMfqHPr5hxU8IPwSd-oM=/0x1:1877x1252/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70116012/Motional1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Motional&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="afhbZS"&gt;Motional, the autonomous vehicle company that is a $4 billion joint venture between Hyundai and Aptiv, announced the city in which it would launch its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22291682/motional-fully-driverless-autonomous-cars-las-vegas"&gt;fully driverless robotaxi&lt;/a&gt; service in 2023, and surprise, surprise, it’s Las Vegas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QQ3ex4"&gt;Motional first began testing its autonomous vehicles in Las Vegas through a joint partnership with Lyft nearly four years ago. The testing began as a weeklong pilot between Aptiv and Lyft &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/2/16841090/lyft-aptiv-self-driving-car-ces-2018"&gt;during the annual Consumer Electronics Show in 2018&lt;/a&gt; and has since gone on to complete over 100,000 passenger trips. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iEZ6H2"&gt;Motional as a joint venture was &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-hyundai-motor-autonomous-aptiv/hyundai-motor-group-aptiv-to-set-up-4-billion-self-driving-car-venture-idUSKBN1W80WP"&gt;first announced in March 2020&lt;/a&gt;, when Hyundai said it would spend $1.6 billion to catch up to its rivals in the autonomous vehicle space. Aptiv, a technology company formerly known as Delphi, owns 50 percent of the venture. The company currently has facilities in Las Vegas, Singapore, and Seoul and has also tested its vehicles in Boston and Pittsburgh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="nL2yuq"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Motional has already tested its vehicles without a human safety driver behind the wheel&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="S1EaxE"&gt;The company’s test fleet is comprised of BMW 5 series vehicles, which will begin to be swapped out for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/31/22648789/motional-hyundai-ioniq5-robotaxi-lyft-photos"&gt;Hyundai Ioniq 5 SUVs&lt;/a&gt; starting next year. Throughout the year, Motional and Lyft will test the vehicles, collecting data on the customer experience, before launching a “full-fledged” commercial robotaxi service in 2023. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yrnuGp"&gt;Motional has already tested its vehicles without a human safety driver behind the wheel. The tests, which took place in February 2021, came less than three months after the company received the green light from the state of Nevada to test its vehicles without a human safety driver. A company employee sat in the passenger seat of the vehicle during the driverless tests and was capable of stopping the vehicle if needed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jktCF0"&gt;The company hasn’t said how many vehicles will be used during the testing process nor how many will be available at the launch of the commercial service. Motional also wouldn’t describe the geographic dimensions of the service area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RG9B1i"&gt;Currently, only a small handful of AV operators have actually deployed fully driverless vehicles, also known as Level 4 autonomous vehicles, on public roads. Waymo, the self-driving unit of Alphabet, has been operating its Level 4 vehicles in the suburbs of Phoenix, Arizona for several years now, and it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/8/21507814/waymo-driverless-cars-allow-more-customers-phoenix"&gt;recently began offering rides to paying customers&lt;/a&gt;. Cruise, a majority-owned subsidiary of General Motors, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/9/22165597/cruise-driverless-test-san-francisco-self-driving-level-4"&gt;recently tested its Level 4 vehicles&lt;/a&gt; in San Francisco. Yandex, the Russian tech giant, &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-51003224"&gt;tested its Level 4 vehicles in Las Vegas&lt;/a&gt; during the Consumer Electronics Show in 2020. And Chinese tech firm Baidu started &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/12/04/fully-driverless-cars-are-being-tested-in-china-for-the-first-time.html"&gt;testing its vehicles without safety drivers&lt;/a&gt; in its home country late last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZdKj60"&gt;Motional isn’t the only company eyeing Sin City for its robotaxi business. Zoox, a subsidiary of Amazon, is also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/3/20897526/zoox-self-driving-taxi-robot-las-vegas-2020"&gt;testing its autonomous vehicles in Las Vegas&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22770537/motional-robotaxi-lyft-driverless-las-vegas-2023"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22770537/motional-robotaxi-lyft-driverless-las-vegas-2023</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-09T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-09T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The case of Facebook’s puzzling podcast data</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Klaw3yaoA1LO2mAsCug-EpyLaH0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70116070/mdoying_180411_2400_0035still.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Michele Doying / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vuBY0a"&gt;Hey hey, Tuesday’s back again. Today’s a relatively tame one, but Aria has a fun piece on the website that we’ll tease below, along with a whole debacle around attributing podcast plays to Facebook. We’re talking user agents, yes, and then we’re getting into the wild world of podcast prefixes. It’s gonna get wonky up in here; let’s get to it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ip6Fff"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Music meets podcasting &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fkf4nw"&gt;(First up: Aria has a programming announcement — I’ll let her take it away.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K51Nrl"&gt;Morning, y’all! Aria here. I wrote &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22529145"&gt;a story&lt;/a&gt; for all of you about a funny feature popping up in podcasts: full musical tracks with lyrics and vocals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NxxjxE"&gt;Maybe you’re thinking, “Well, that sounds messy. Songs with words? Within a format that’s already… mostly words?” That’s an appropriate reaction. At face value, it seems wonky and hard to get right, and that’s why I wanted to dive into this trend. Why are people making these kinds of podcasts? How are they structured? And how do they sound?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ctDI7C"&gt;Well, my friends, you can hear ‘em for yourself — we’ve embedded the episodes! We’ve got cool art, too, courtesy of the &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; team! And many cultural references! Satan is also mentioned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lZ5L42"&gt;I would be real tickled if you &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/22529145"&gt;checked it out on the site&lt;/a&gt;. Happy reading — and listening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7zJKYS"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facebook podcast data is messed up — the company says it’s fixing it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IVEh43"&gt;We’ve been covering Facebook’s inclusion of podcasts on its platform closely, and I’m now hearing reports that people are unable to accurately pull performance data for their shows from their hosting providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UgUiYw"&gt;As a brief reminder: Facebook allows people all over the world to input their RSS feed links into their Pages, which then allows podcast episodes to populate there and for US-based app users to listen. As you can imagine, podcasters want to know how their shows are performing on Facebook — it’s pretty critical information for anyone trying to manage a show. If your show does amazing on Facebook, maybe you’ll double-down on your Page. If not, well, you’ll go on continuing to pretend Facebook doesn’t exist. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B8VsYU"&gt;The problem is that hosting companies, among other analytics providers, aren’t able to definitively say what plays are coming from Facebook. The issue relates to user agents, or the data a hosting company receives when a third-party server asks to receive a podcast. This user agent often tells the hosting company where a person is listening, like what platform, and what type of device they’re using. This is especially critical in podcasting, where data is scarce. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tg2lCj"&gt;In Facebook’s case, hosting platforms and other companies that monitor podcast data are receiving confusing user agent data. James Cridland over at &lt;em&gt;Podnews&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://podnews.net/article/facebook-podcasts-user-agent"&gt;compiled his findings&lt;/a&gt; on the Facebook user agents a couple weeks ago, and it’s a super helpful and technical write-up of what he saw happening. To put it as simply as I can: iOS devices appear to be pinging these hosting companies’ servers not only as iOS-Facebook but sometimes as AppleCoreMedia. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nbDXl0"&gt;[Takes deep breath] AppleCoreMedia is the generic user agent that iOS app makers receive when they build an app with Apple’s API — but it’s also the user agent Apple Podcasts submits, making this doubly confusing. Some Facebook plays might be attributed to Apple Podcasts — not good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l0qMFP"&gt;This is a lot, I know, but really the takeaway here is that people whose podcasts are on Facebook don’t have an accurate picture of how many people are listening. I reached out to Facebook for clarification on why this AppleCoreMedia agent is showing up, and here’s what I’m told: Facebook’s user agents are FB4A on Android and iOS-Facebook for iOS. That iOS user agent only works on the latest version of the iOS app, however, so that’s why some pings come from that while others come from AppleCoreMedia. As more people update the app, more accurate data will populate. The company also confirms to me that it’s working on providing native podcast analytics within its app, which would help avoid this situation entirely — assuming you trust Facebook’s data, which is a whole ‘nother thing we can talk about at a later point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8QpzJZ"&gt;PHEW. We did it. This is complicated and technical stuff, but it’s critical to the industry! Everyone needs to know how and where their shows are doing well, including on the newest Big Tech player to care about podcasts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aQ5ytA"&gt;I hate to do this to you, but we have one more techy thing to get through, and this one involves prefixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L5vuho"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magellan AI wants to validate your listens &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dljpRO"&gt;As you can tell from the above write-up, knowing how many people listen to a podcast is coveted data, and as I also hinted at above, trusting that data is critical. So, today, Magellan AI, the podcast media planning platform, is announcing “verified downloads.” These give Magellan a way for it to definitively tell advertisers that a podcast receives a certain number of downloads, which then entices them to (hopefully) spend more money on shows. To participate in this, podcast publishers have to include a prefix in their RSS feed. John Goforth, Magellan AI’s CRO, tells me “thousands” of publishers have already signed up, including NPR, which is the only name he shared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rnvB5i"&gt;I write about this feature because there are now quite a few prefixes podcasters can affix to their shows. Magellan AI, Chartable, Podsights, and Podtrac all offer them, just to name some I thought of immediately. These prefixes are one way to work around RSS technology; you can only do so much with a link, and these prefixes give all these companies an opportunity to build a business around the podcasting ecosystem. This also keeps the ecosystem open rather than closed. (For reference, with Spotify and Apple requiring shows to upload content to their backends, these companies, like Chartable, have to work around that by &lt;a href="https://help.chartable.com/article/22-why-ask-for-credentials"&gt;directly integrating into podcasters’ accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which is a lot of access to provide but also the only option when the RSS feed is lost.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YO8R2H"&gt;I wonder now, though, if we might reach a point of prefix bloat. How many prefixes will podcasters be willing to include? When does it become too much? (To say nothing of the fact that the data is now going to many companies rather than just the podcasters and their hosting providers, around which many people have many privacy thoughts.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T44FJa"&gt;“I think of prefixes the same way I think about layering up when it’s cold outside,” says Goforth in an email to me. “Is it slightly bulky and you’d prefer not to? Sure. But do the ends justify the means? Absolutely. Prefixes unlock a ton of opportunity in a myriad of ways for publishers. Also, much like layering up — the number of layers (prefixes) will vary depending on your needs.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jtwAx8"&gt;I honestly don’t have a hot take here, as much as I realize that’s the wrong thing to say in a newsletter that would probably do well with a hot take. I just raise this issue as something I’m thinking about and tracking (heh). If you have thoughts about the impending prefix bloat, I’m here for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xB8RGB"&gt;All right, that’s all for the techy stuff. Now we can move on to a couple quick bits and get you outta here and onto your week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="3GEnst"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"podcasts"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="o9RuVV"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acast podcasts come to Samsung Free&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZlaWEL"&gt;Acast &lt;a href="https://medium.com/acast/acast-teams-up-with-samsung-to-distribute-its-30-000-podcasts-directly-to-galaxy-users-globally-dc0ea6efa38f"&gt;announced yesterday&lt;/a&gt; that it’s bringing its 30,000-plus shows to Samsung Free, the company’s app that’s pre-installed on all Galaxy phones and, as of earlier this year in the US, supports podcasts. Acast is an inaugural partner for the app’s European launch, which, Acast says, is used by 31 percent of people on the continent. I admittedly haven’t paid much mind to Samsung’s inclusion of podcasts, but this feels like something. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZNPDD5"&gt;There are a few possibilities for how this could play out: In one scenario, this app is purely seen as bloatware, and Galaxy users refuse to tap into it. In another world, this app is akin to the free Roku Channel that, with the right programming, might do well? (The Roku Channel reached an estimated 70 million people in the US during the first quarter of this year, the company &lt;a href="https://newsroom.roku.com/news/2021/06/launch-of-roku-originals-drives-record-two-week-streaming-period/bzlc4wcp-1623988447"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;, and its acquired Quibi shows &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/digital/news/roku-viewing-quibi-shows-1235000172/"&gt;reportedly have&lt;/a&gt; more views than they did on Quibi, which is a small feat but nonetheless.) Then, there’s the chance the Samsung Free app turns into the Apple Podcasts of Android — something I’m skeptical will happen, but let’s be optimistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cMyqBt"&gt;Acast doesn’t lose much here  — why not get their shows in front of listeners? — while Samsung gains quality programming. Everyone is happy. I’ll be curious how this player pans out, just as I’m curious how Facebook is doing, and Amazon Music, and all the other apps that recently decided to get into the podcasting game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="womplu"&gt;One last thing, then we’re done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3yVArI"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Green Bay Packer Aaron Rodgers goes on a podcast, says wild things about COVID and vaccines and that Joe Rogan guided him through the virus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UE2lWx"&gt;I hate to end on this note, but we have to mention it. As many of you readers know, I don’t keep up with sports, but every so often, a story crosses into my feed, and this was one of those. Aaron Rodgers, the Green Bay Packers’ star quarterback, &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/z3nvby/aaron-rodgers-goes-full-anti-vax-says-hes-taking-ivermectin"&gt;caught COVID and isn’t vaccinated&lt;/a&gt;. The information around his vaccine status was murky, and Rodgers apparently told reporters, who directly asked if he received the shot, that &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/KyleMalzhan/status/1455917445739319301?s=20"&gt;he had been “immunized.”&lt;/a&gt; In reality, he received a homeopathic treatment that is not the vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aNQGCD"&gt;Anyway! For the podcast angle, Rodgers went on Pat McAfee’s SiriusXM podcast &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dhookstead/status/1456677091123007495?s=20"&gt;to say&lt;/a&gt; he “consulted” with a “now-good friend of mine,” Joe Rogan. He, like Rogan did, is taking Ivermectin, among other things, and touts the merits of natural immunity. Podcasts! People really seem to like to let loose on ‘em, huh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D6AENu"&gt;All right, that’s it for today. I’ll be back here Thursday for you paying Insiders, and I’m always around in my DMs or email, which you can get by replying to this email. Bye!!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mHOV41"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22771499/facebook-podcast-ios-user-agent-analytics-hot-pod"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22771499/facebook-podcast-ios-user-agent-analytics-hot-pod</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-09T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-09T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Mozilla’s Firefox browser arrives in the Windows store</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="firefox logo" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9QYp0pAfCeXlL7SAJKD1YQPxSgE=/123x0:1278x770/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70116010/FX_Design_Blog_Header_1400x770.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Mozilla&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Va99JG"&gt;Mozilla is bringing Firefox to Microsoft’s Windows store today. Firefox is one of the first third-party alternatives available in the Microsoft Store, and it’s using its own Gecko browser engine instead of Chromium alternatives like Opera or the many other alternatives that leverage Microsoft’s Edge webview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ukxkxL"&gt;Microsoft’s new open store policies have finally made it possible for third-party browsers like Firefox to appear in the Microsoft Store. While we haven’t seen Chrome appear yet, Opera was quick to ensure its own browser is also listed in the store. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ktYWR5Ivetx_tA2hTJo8-N7wD8w=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22998200/HJQ9z1a.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Firefox is available in both the Windows 10 and Windows 11 app stores.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dCTW8h"&gt;“Previously, if you were on Windows and wanted to use Firefox, you had to download it from the internet and go through a clunky process from Microsoft,” explains Mozilla. “Now that Microsoft has changed its Store policies, choosing Firefox as your desktop browser is even more seamless - and it comes with all the latest Firefox features.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wipfly"&gt;Firefox launching into the Microsoft Store comes just months after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22671182/mozilla-default-browser-windows-protections-firefox"&gt;Mozilla defeated Microsoft’s default browser protections&lt;/a&gt; in Windows. Mozilla has quietly made it easier to switch to Firefox on Windows, with a one-click process that isn’t officially available for anyone other than Microsoft. Mozilla appears to have reverse engineered Microsoft’s ability to set Edge as the default in Windows with a single click, instead of the multi-prompt process that exists in Windows 10 today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7y4J5Q"&gt;Interestingly, this one-click process doesn’t appear to work in the Microsoft Store version of Firefox. That means Mozilla either avoided submitting its workaround version of Firefox or Microsoft rejected it from the Microsoft Store and the company was forced to remove the default browser workaround.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XoqBou"&gt;Microsoft has made the process of setting the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22630319/microsoft-windows-11-default-browser-changes"&gt;default browser even harder in Windows 11&lt;/a&gt;, and Mozilla has been trying to convince Microsoft to improve its default browser settings in Windows since its &lt;a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/en/products/firefox/an-open-letter-to-microsofts-ceo-dont-roll-back-the-clock-on-choice-and-control/"&gt;open letter to Microsoft in 2015&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GhPDpx"&gt;Firefox is now &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24542&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Fen-us%2Fp%2Fmozilla-firefox%2F9nzvdkpmr9rd" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available in the Microsoft Store&lt;/a&gt; for both Windows 10 and Windows 11.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22771845/mozilla-firefox-microsoft-store-windows-download"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22771845/mozilla-firefox-microsoft-store-windows-download</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-09T08:45:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-09T08:45:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Podcasts always had instrumental music — now some have singing, too</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k8HJVD5DPCzN-9v_vDWnu8Xjjas=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70115982/4867_podcastSinging.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;It ain’t over ‘til the podcaster sings&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="dfRffs"&gt;In the podcast series &lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/4JNRQWCZI3PRn5rH87zbmS"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forever Is a Long Time&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, listeners hear a man gently ask his relatives about the details of their failed marriages. Then, they hear him sing a song about it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yvjJH2"&gt;Host &lt;a href="https://iancoss.com/"&gt;Ian Coss&lt;/a&gt; was a musician before he started producing and sound-designing podcasts, and he has long used songwriting to make sense of his life. When he needed to process the messy, emotional topic of divorce, he started by singing. Then, he interviewed his family to get more of the answers he sought. Neither would be complete without the other, he said — he “wanted it to feel like an integrated whole.” From there, a hybrid of an album and a podcast was born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VZ6EbW"&gt;Lots of musicians have translated their skills to podcast production, creating the &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/07/26/1019369946/how-jad-abumrad-radiolab-creator-and-co-host-got-hooked-on-storytelling"&gt;instrumentals&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://anchor.fm/gayotic"&gt;original theme songs&lt;/a&gt; heard in many shows. But songs with lyrics? Embedded right there in an episode? There hasn’t historically been a place for them since they compete with the words being spoken. But a desire to incorporate singing anyway has led several creators to reimagine the structure of the shows they produce, crafting songs that are meant to live right alongside interviews and discussions. As with Coss’ creations, their songs become just as important as the speech that surrounds them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="gBNXCt"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/0027WbuYa4vRlVAM7Xf6NO?utm_source=generator" width="100%" height="232" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6yIjwo"&gt;Speaking and singing have already mingled in the context of podcasts, but mostly fictional ones. The scripted series &lt;a href="https://qcodemedia.com/electric-easy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Electric Easy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; guides listeners from speech to song by featuring musical performances right in the plot; same goes for &lt;a href="https://www.audioup.com/shows/halloweeninhell"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Halloween in Hell&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which is about a singing competition hosted by Satan. But it’s less intuitive to follow along when songs are slipped into something like a chatcast or an interview-based show, which might not have natural segues between the two formats. Listeners may be turned off when they’re jolted from one to the other, especially since they can’t be walked through the transition by visual footage the way they can while watching movies or TV. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NLHb3l"&gt;Beyond fictional podcasts that roughly follow &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YzFbgRcafSE"&gt;the &lt;em&gt;Glee &lt;/em&gt;format&lt;/a&gt;, the interplay of song and speech has mostly been limited to things other than podcasts. Think hip-hop and rap albums, which swing from musical tracks to spoken interludes and scenes. Another example is the FM radio model, where DJs surface between songs to banter, often about things other than the music. Coss says he couldn’t find podcasts that achieved the balance he was trying to strike, where the songs deliberately pertained to the discussions or vice versa; instead, he drew inspiration from musical concept albums, like &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V6Qnd5vnpN0"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Point&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Harry Nilsson, as well as &lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/4iivcPAy7rSv4eY2PKOIfz?si=rUXg0ZQQRDenUWbqV6Y3iQ"&gt;Woody Guthrie’s&lt;/a&gt; “three hours of song and conversation,” housed by the Library of Congress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZvQ5bW"&gt;With these examples in other audio fields, audiences have had years to warm up to the idea that mediums will mix; to avoid turning off listeners within podcasts, producers aimed to be as unsurprising as possible with how they presented the music. In the scripted series &lt;a href="https://herecomesthebreak.com/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here Comes the Break&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the show’s narrator interviews real-life musicians for a fictional podcast (within this &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; podcast), on which the artists debut actual tracks they recorded in the real world. To prevent listeners from being disoriented by the otherwise unmusical plot suddenly switching to song, the music is always placed at the end of an episode; the same is true of Coss’ show. Both podcasts also keep their content the same length episode to episode — roughly 30 minutes —which, as a standard length in the industry, provides listeners with a familiar element within an otherwise unfamiliar concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;div id="R8T2vX"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/3oUF8LSqdPsap5yPgxB3gL?utm_source=generator&amp;amp;theme=0" width="100%" height="232" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pHRVU5"&gt;One musician and producer has experimented with how far podcast listeners are willing to go to hear the songs she wants them to hear. The movie-discussion podcast &lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/3hOk6wfvNsbPQNdjHFF8Vm"&gt;&lt;em&gt;You Are Good&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, hosted by Sarah Marshall and Alex Steed, features both covers and original tracks by the musician &lt;a href="https://www.carolynkendrick.com/"&gt;Carolyn Kendrick&lt;/a&gt; (who, using her technical skills, also produces the show). In a given episode, listeners hear a chat between Marshall and Steed, a song that Kendrick has recorded to complement the discussion, then a return to the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TxJd2P"&gt;“I definitely make the songs much shorter than I would if I was making a regular album,” Kendrick says. Creating songs for the middle of an episode, as opposed to the end, also requires generalizing lyrics and “trimming the fat” that doesn’t directly support the discussion, she says. “My number one fear is that the music will be distracting, and hopefully it’s not.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NgXJQs"&gt;Far from being distracting, given that &lt;em&gt;You Are Good&lt;/em&gt; is both silly and serious, lyrical music can be a helpful transitional tool. After the hosts joke around in the first few minutes of an &lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/4cZxyWsjEtObggQnHTbz7b?si=YkrqWgGAQpWsAZ-iWv42dQ"&gt;episode about &lt;em&gt;The Shining&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the listener hears low, spooky notes on a piano, with Kendrick repetitively singing the phrase “all work and no play makes Jack a dull boy,” which she says “conveyed the creepiness of that story.” It works as a transition into the markedly heavier conversation between the hosts that follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="8J2ctu"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/4cZxyWsjEtObggQnHTbz7b?utm_source=generator&amp;amp;theme=0" width="100%" height="232" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6MX5yQ"&gt;The music in these podcasts can be their selling point, says Brady Sadler, CEO and co-founder of the audio company &lt;a href="https://www.doubleelvis.com/"&gt;Double Elvis&lt;/a&gt;, which produced &lt;em&gt;Here Comes The Break&lt;/em&gt;. In that show in particular, which was branded as a “music-breaking podcast,” songs debuted exclusively in the episodes, and the musicians acted as a “built-in influencer base” to hype up the drops on social media, Sadler says. “Having the exclusive music definitely achieved what we were hoping for,” he adds: getting people excited to hear a song within the context of the podcast and its characters, even though they knew they could hear the song via wide release the very next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hf9c7W"&gt;The generally positive reception to these shows may be due to listeners’ expectations already beginning to shift. As Coss points out, Spotify has published &lt;a href="https://newsroom.spotify.com/2019-06-12/your-daily-drive-music-and-news-thatll-brighten-your-commute/"&gt;“Daily Drive” playlists&lt;/a&gt; for years, mixing music with reported news, and Sadler speculates that, more broadly, many listeners have gotten used to going to one place (e.g., Spotify, Amazon Music) to hear both music and podcasts, even if the two mediums aren’t often played in quick succession. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bBnFSF"&gt;Maybe Spotify knows something these creators can only speculate: that listeners do indeed want content that combines speaking and singing. That would make it seem as though projects like &lt;em&gt;You Are Good&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Forever Is a Long Time &lt;/em&gt;have popped up in response, taking cues from the industry’s biggest players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="G4VEph"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"podcasts"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KGJBDQ"&gt;“The timing is interesting, right? That I would be drawn to this kind of project in a moment where musical and narrative audio are crossing over more and more,” says Coss. He laughs, “I certainly don’t want to give Spotify credit.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="ndIBal"&gt;The “longer arc” toward this moment, he says, is likely more personal. He, like Kendrick, was a musician before he was a podcast producer. “I brought those skills with me to narrative audio as a new place to explore and create,” he says. “I think there was always a desire to bring those things together.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22765104/podcast-music-forever-is-a-long-time-hot-pod"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22765104/podcast-music-forever-is-a-long-time-hot-pod</id>
    <author>
      <name>Aria Bracci</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-09T08:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-09T08:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>SpaceX successfully brings crew of four home from the International Space Station</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TEh1kCU-rnywGE4fYq-XXpwb3dA=/176x0:1649x982/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70115040/Screen_Shot_2021_11_08_at_9.36.12_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nighttime view of the Crew Dragon capsule just before splashdown &lt;/em&gt; | Image: NASA&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LmSQEa"&gt;A crew of four astronauts successfully returned to Earth Monday evening, splashing down in the Gulf of Mexico off the coast of Pensacola inside a SpaceX Crew Dragon capsule. Their arrival back on the planet brings an end to a more than six-monthlong stay aboard the International Space Station, and it paves the way for another crew of four to launch to the ISS in the coming week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jMKPJE"&gt;The crew includes two NASA astronauts, Shane Kimbrough and Megan McArthur, Japanese astronaut Akihiko Hoshide from the Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency, and French astronaut Thomas Pesquet from the European Space Agency. The group launched to the space station on April 23rd atop a SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket, part of a mission called Crew-2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="0uRt5P"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Their flight marks the third time that SpaceX has brought people home from the space station&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eMA8ja"&gt;“On behalf of SpaceX, welcome home to planet Earth,” a SpaceX flight controller declared when the crew splashed down. SpaceX personnel on a recovery ship then hoisted the Crew Dragon out of the water and helped the crew leave the vehicle one by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CDq1pE"&gt;Their flight marks the third time that SpaceX has launched people to the International Space Station and then safely brought them home. Such trips are part of SpaceX’s contract with NASA through the space agency’s Commercial Crew Program, an initiative that tasks private companies with ferrying NASA’s astronauts and international partners to and from the ISS. SpaceX launched its first crew of two to the station in May 2020, part of a test flight to prove the safety of its Crew Dragon capsule, designed to launch on top of the company’s Falcon 9 rocket. That flight was followed by SpaceX’s Crew-1 mission in November 2020, which sent a crew of four to the ISS for a six-month rotation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="K4OEs3"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Space. Ain’t it something. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SpaceX?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#SpaceX&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/KoUWrnepLc"&gt;pic.twitter.com/KoUWrnepLc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— George Bevan (@gpbevan1) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gpbevan1/status/1457916030441897984?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6TyPC0"&gt;Now that Crew-2 is back on the ground, SpaceX will quickly pivot to its next crewed launch, aptly named Crew-3. Another crew of four — including NASA astronauts Raja Chari, Thomas Marshburn, and Kayla Barron, as well as German astronaut Matthias Maurer — are scheduled to launch inside a Crew Dragon capsule on Wednesday, November 10th at 9:03PM ET from NASA’s Kennedy Space Center in Cape Canaveral, Florida. The crew will take the place of the Crew-2 astronauts who just left and do another six-month rotation up in orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d4Smer"&gt;The original plan was for Crew-3 to launch on October 31st, before the Crew-2 astronauts left the station. That way, the outgoing crew could greet the newcomers, give them a brief introduction, and hand off duties before heading home. However, the Crew-3 mission suffered a series of delays. Bad weather at one of the launch’s abort locations pushed back the launch first. Then one of the crew members suffered a minor medical issue, prompting NASA to delay the launch further. The agency did not say what the issue was but said that it was not related to COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bxoK0S"&gt;Because of these setbacks, the Crew-2 astronauts are back on Earth before Crew-3 arrives at the ISS. SpaceX’s Crew Dragon capsule is able to last up to 210 days in orbit, and the Crew-2 capsule’s limit didn’t end until November 19th, but NASA ultimately decided to bring home Crew-2 now in anticipation of bad winter weather getting worse deeper into the month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="otnDsK"&gt;&lt;q&gt;the Crew-2 astronauts are back on Earth before Crew-3 arrives&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="P80dxO"&gt;However, there’s still a NASA astronaut on board the ISS to help ease the Crew-3 astronauts’ transition. Mark Vande Hei launched to the station on a Russian Soyuz rocket in April and won’t come home until March 2022, marking a nearly yearlong stay in orbit. His presence on board “definitely helped us and helped me feel more comfortable in the decision to land first before we launch,” Joel Montalbano, manager of the International Space Station at NASA’s Johnson Space Center, said in a press briefing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JFWKrR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10854410"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="83AtsX"&gt;The Crew-2 astronauts undocked from the space station at 2:05PM ET on Monday. When the astronauts first got inside their vehicle, one of the touchscreens needed a reboot, but the trouble didn’t seem to impact the flight. After they left the station, they spent a few hours flying around the ISS in a circular pattern. It was an intentional maneuver, allowing the astronauts to get pictures of the ISS from different vantage points that aren’t normally seen. Once that fly-around was complete, the Crew Dragon began drifting away from the station, putting it on its course back to Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GbAhUb"&gt;Though the astronauts came home safely, there was a brief scary moment when the Crew Dragon’s parachutes deployed just before splash down to slowly lower the capsule down into the water. Three of the four parachutes appeared to expand normally, while one chute inflated much more slowly. After the splashdown, a NASA official explained that the agency will review what happened. “It is behavior we’ve seen multiple times in other tests and usually happens when the lines kind of bunch up together until the aero-forces kind of open up and spread the chutes,” Kathy Lueders, associate administrator for space operations at NASA, said during the launch livestream. Lueders claimed that the way the Crew Dragon decelerated into the water looked normal. It’s unclear if the strange parachute deployment will affect the upcoming Crew-3 launch yet, but NASA will provide an update after a full launch readiness review.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-yuvRXvKG7tW4vP2Qg3JlYRJMqM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22998202/Screen_Shot_2021_11_09_at_7.29.17_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: NASA&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The fourth main parachute taking longer to inflate than the others.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ZXFPew"&gt;Otherwise, the splashdown seemed to go well and NASA felt vindicated about its decision to bring the crew home ahead of Crew-3, noting the weather at the splashdown site was perfect. “It was like a lake out there, a very calm lake,” Lueders said. “So this was the best decision we could have made.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nMhugQ"&gt;While on board the ISS, the Crew-2 astronauts performed more than 300 experiments, one of which involved growing Hatch chile peppers in orbit. &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/11/02/1051428046/astronauts-grew-green-chile-on-the-space-station-and-made-themselves-space-tacos"&gt;The crew ate their creations with some tacos&lt;/a&gt;, helping to spice up their diet while in space. The Crew-2 team also dealt with some unexpected moments aboard the ISS, notably when a newly docked Russian module &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/29/22600306/uncontrolled-firing-from-russian-module-causes-brief-tug-of-war-on-international-space-station"&gt;accidentally fired its thrusters&lt;/a&gt; and spun the station around its axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y5mX5B"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated November 9th, 8:00AM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was updated to include information from NASA about the Crew Dragon’s parachute deployment and weather at the splashdown site.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jwKSz0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YOrLkV"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22769970/spacex-crew-2-dragon-capsule-splash-down-success"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/8/22769970/spacex-crew-2-dragon-capsule-splash-down-success</id>
    <author>
      <name>Loren Grush</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-09T07:23:37-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-09T07:23:37-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google Maps on iOS now has a dark mode, here’s how to enable it</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y_Wpjt7SVUf-k8FyNYBPeqby5Uk=/14x0:2633x1746/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70115721/Screen_Shot_2021_08_02_at_3.19.53_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google Maps’ dark mode on iOS. &lt;/em&gt; | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IcYZ72"&gt;In August, Google announced its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22606644/google-maps-ios-dark-mode-widgets-share-location-imessage"&gt;iOS Maps app would soon be getting a dark mode&lt;/a&gt;. But although the feature fully launched at the beginning of September, it arrived quietly enough that several &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; staffers hadn’t even noticed its appearance until we started receiving in-app notices. If you’ve also been in the dark, rather than the dark &lt;em&gt;mode&lt;/em&gt; (sorry), here’s how to enable the feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6v2rhD"&gt;From the main Google Maps interface on iOS, tap your profile picture in the top right of the screen. Pick “Settings” from the menu, then select “Dark Mode” from the Using Maps section. Here you have three options: On, Off, and “Same as device setting” (which automatically turns dark mode on or off depending on what you have enabled at the OS level). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="mCMIfn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10854340"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="d4WKGy"&gt;If you’re on Android, a similar feature &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22297204/google-maps-dark-mode-android-auto-split-screen-games"&gt;launched earlier in the year&lt;/a&gt;, but the route to enable it is a little different than on iOS. Here you need to tap your profile picture, then “Settings,” and then pick “Theme,” and select from the same three options as iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aIandI"&gt;If you ask us, the best choice in both cases is to have Google Maps use the same setting as your device so that all your apps neatly match one another. But don’t let us tell you what to do. Follow your heart.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22771759/how-to-enable-dark-mode-in-google-maps-ios-android"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22771759/how-to-enable-dark-mode-in-google-maps-ios-android</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
