<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-05-05T07:27:16-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-05T07:27:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-05T07:27:16-04:00</updated>
    <title>Go read this report on how law enforcement can extract sensitive data from your car</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sy8ejrgkqNj_AUbTKtwaBrSkQk8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69239290/acastro_170629_1777_0008_v2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mBCNyc"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://theintercept.com/2021/05/03/car-surveillance-berla-msab-cbp/"&gt;new report from &lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has shed light on a worrying new technology that lets law enforcement agencies extract personal data from people’s cars. It reports that US Customs and Border Protection (CBP) recently made an order worth hundreds of thousands of dollars from Swedish data extraction firm MSAB which included iVe “vehicle forensics kits” made by US firm Berla. Here’s what MSAB advertises the kits can do, according to &lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="7aBA5E"&gt;MSAB marketing materials promise cops access to a vast array of sensitive personal information quietly stored in the infotainment consoles and various other computers used by modern vehicles — a tapestry of personal details akin to what CBP might get when cracking into one’s personal phone. MSAB claims that this data can include “Recent destinations, favorite locations, call logs, contact lists, SMS messages, emails, pictures, videos, social media feeds, and the navigation history of everywhere the vehicle has been.” MSAB even touts the ability to retrieve deleted data, divine “future plan[s],” and “Identify known associates and establish communication patterns between them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="yGU8c2"&gt;In some cases, it’s a comparable amount of personal data to what you might find on a smartphone. But while most people are aware of the sensitive data held in their phones, thanks in part to companies like Apple making a big show of promoting the privacy and security features of the latest models, &lt;em&gt;The Intercept &lt;/em&gt;argues we’re less aware of how much data our cars’ infotainment systems are collecting. And that leaves a treasure trove of data for the Berla-manufactured kits to vacuum up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="ZTQaIW"&gt;The people behind CBP’s new tool are well aware that they are preying on consumer ignorance. In a podcast appearance &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/snitches-wheels-police-turn-car-data-destroy-suspects-alibis-n1251939"&gt;first reported by NBC News&lt;/a&gt; last summer, Berla founder Ben LeMere remarked, “People rent cars and go do things with them and don’t even think about the places they are going and what the car records.” In a 2015 appearance on the podcast “The Forensic Lunch,” LeMere told the show’s hosts how the company uses exactly this accidental-transfer scenario in its trainings: “Your phone died, you’re gonna get in the car, plug it in, and there’s going to be this nice convenient USB port for you. When you plug it into this USB port, it’s going to charge your phone, absolutely. And as soon as it powers up, it’s going to start sucking all your data down into the car.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="fwuAyf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt;’s report focuses on just one agency, US Customs and Border Protection, but civil liberties campaigners, like Mohammad Tajsar from the American Civil Liberties Union of Southern California, fear that the technology could easily trickle down to other law enforcement agencies across the US:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="BXvkri"&gt;“What CBP have will trickle down to what your local cops on the street end up getting. That is not a theoretical concern.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="NQyTdC"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theintercept.com/2021/05/03/car-surveillance-berla-msab-cbp/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt;’s report&lt;/a&gt; is well worth reading in full.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22420674/go-read-this-intercept-report-vehicle-forensics-infotainment-personal-sensitive-data-law-enforcement"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22420674/go-read-this-intercept-report-vehicle-forensics-infotainment-personal-sensitive-data-law-enforcement</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-05T05:42:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-05T05:42:50-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook’s Nextdoor-clone Neighborhoods is coming soon to four US cities</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OL9Xyjocx2gwUSV7cnoj8uQkR5w=/0x8:1200x808/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69239049/facebook_neighborhoods.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="q5Nqlq"&gt;Facebook, which never saw a social network it couldn’t copy, says its Nextdoor-clone Neighborhoods is now available across Canada and is &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/05/connecting-local-communities-on-facebook/"&gt;coming soon to four US cities&lt;/a&gt;. According to &lt;a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/facebook-takes-on-nextdoor-with-neighborhoods-tool/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CNET&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the US locations being targeted are Charlotte, North Carolina; San Diego, California; Baton Rouge, Louisiana; and Newark, New Jersey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k2Gyg1"&gt;Like Nextdoor, Neighborhoods is all about corralling geographically-defined groups of users into a single space to discuss local goings-on. Facebook says users should be able to get to know neighbors, ask for recommendations for the best coffee shops or locksmiths, and organize local events. Users can also create splinter groups specific to their interests. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eSsBJB"&gt;“You can find vibrant local Facebook groups about your area, or you can create your own Neighborhoods-bounded groups based on your interests,” says Facebook in a &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/05/connecting-local-communities-on-facebook/"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;. “You can create Neighborhoods groups for local bird watchers, or discuss last night’s game with fellow basketball lovers in your area.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vNewVu_TkWY4lscLzlPxp4BVxsk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22493038/facebook_neighborhoods_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Facebook&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Users will be encouraged to share their thoughts about their local area and organize events.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="IrZapj"&gt;It’s fairly certain that at least some of the activity in these groups will also devolve into petty squabbles, fractious political arguments, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21283993/nextdoor-app-racism-community-moderation-guidance-protests"&gt;outright racism&lt;/a&gt;, as we’ve seen on Nextdoor. Facebook also has a pretty terrible track record when it comes to letting groups of users hang out. Facebook Groups, which also let users organize around shared interests, have been identified as a &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/feb/04/facebook-groups-misinformation"&gt;hot-bed of un-moderated extremism&lt;/a&gt;, nurturing everything from white supremacy to anti-vaccine misinformation to conspiracy theories. It’s not at all clear how Facebook is going to avoid these same problems erupting in its new neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EOwcqd"&gt;Only users aged 18 and up will be allowed to join these groups, where they can create a new profile separate to their main Facebook account. They can “choose to add interests, favorite places and a bio” to this profile before introducing themselves to the group. People will also be able to take on specific roles, reports &lt;em&gt;CNET&lt;/em&gt;, like ”socializer,” “helper” or “welcomer.” It’s not clear though what these roles will entail or how people will claim them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4eynjM"&gt;Reid Patton, a product manager for Facebook Neighborhoods, told &lt;em&gt;CNET &lt;/em&gt;that each group will have moderators to “make sure people are staying within the guidelines and being kind” (that’s a quote from &lt;em&gt;CNET&lt;/em&gt; not Patton). But yet again, it’s not clear who these moderators are (volunteers? Paid employees?) or what powers they will have to enforce Facebook’s rules. We’ve reached out to Facebook with questions and will update this story if we hear more.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22420597/facebook-nextdoor-clone-neighborhoods-canada-us-cities-launch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22420597/facebook-nextdoor-clone-neighborhoods-canada-us-cities-launch</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-05T04:49:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-05T04:49:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>PS5 designer helps Nike with latest Paul George sneakers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4VnjGSYpiunr9yykt5zg32Wy76k=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69238966/ezgif_7_babb1ce8bef2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: PlayStation&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7BXSrq"&gt;Nike, Sony, and basketball player Paul George have collaborated on another pair of sneakers, &lt;a href="//www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/am/sid/verge/https://www.nike.com/launch/t/pg5-playstation-5" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the PG 5&lt;/a&gt;, with help from PS5 designer Yujin Morisawa. &lt;a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2021/05/04/paul-george-playstation-back-together-with-the-pg-5-playstation-5-colorway/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+PSBlog+%28PlayStation.Blog%29"&gt;According to Sony&lt;/a&gt;, “the colors of the shoe are heavily inspired by the industrial design of the PS5” with the PlayStation’s signature circle, square, cross, and triangle shapes &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/2/7/22269634/how-sony-designed-ps5-dualsense-playstation-symbol-microtexture"&gt;woven into the materials like a DualSense controller&lt;/a&gt;. There’s also a PlayStation logo on the tongue of the right shoe, while the left’s tongue has Paul George’s PG logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MJxv65"&gt;The release comes a little over two years after Nike and PlayStation’s last sneaker collaboration, &lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018-11-28-nike-pg-2-5-playstation-classic-paul-george.html"&gt;the PG 2.5&lt;/a&gt;, which drew inspiration from the design of the original PlayStation console. Earlier that year, the two companies worked together &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/22/16918480/nike-pg2-limited-edition-playstation-shoes-paul-george-basketball"&gt;on the PG2&lt;/a&gt;, which were inspired by the PS4. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_-siVb8gQTDQR2GkGAYeddtx-44=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22493015/pg_5_playstation_5_release_date__6_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Nike / Sony&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NS1caF1SZfYiXYla2jFBxyx3znE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22493016/pg_5_playstation_5_release_date__5_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Nike / Sony&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SVcGuQaS9vbNMKGTztPz4HFVfLc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22493017/pg_5_playstation_5_release_date__4_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Nike / Sony&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xZv-4BeoBof7vu4DjwjVCiPD088=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22493011/ezgif.com_gif_maker__6_.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Nike / Sony&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="73QdUt"&gt;The PG 5 shoes are going on sale in “select regions” on May 14th, and they’ll arrive in North America on May 27th priced at $120, according to &lt;a href="//www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/am/sid/verge/https://www.nike.com/launch/t/pg5-playstation-5" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nike’s site&lt;/a&gt;. There’s no word on how many pairs Nike will release, but given how limited its previous run of PlayStation sneakers was, we’re expecting these to sell out fast. Fitting, given how hard it still is to find PS5 consoles in stock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sGEAFw"&gt;If you’re interested, Sony says you should keep your eye on the &lt;a href="//www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/am/sid/verge/https://www.nike.com/launch" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nike SNKRS app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="//www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/am/sid/verge/http://www.nike.com/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;local Nike website&lt;/a&gt; for more information on release dates and availability.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22420584/nike-pg5-playstation-shoes-sneakers-paul-george-basketball"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/5/22420584/nike-pg5-playstation-shoes-sneakers-paul-george-basketball</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-04T21:10:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-04T21:10:14-04:00</updated>
    <title>Epic says there’s an App Store payment lockout — but Apple just sees friction</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q6nGSrGgSPIrQ3333fxQU8fhUMs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69237973/acastro_20200818_1777_epicApple_0004.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yWVbvi"&gt;One of the &lt;em&gt;Epic v. Apple &lt;/em&gt;trial’s big keywords is “cross-wallet play.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UPNiWY"&gt;In Epic’s &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;, “cross-wallet” means you can buy in-game currency (known as V-Bucks) with real money on one device, then spend it on a different device. The latter platform doesn’t get a cut of your initial, non-virtual financial transaction, which is why Nintendo and Sony don’t support cross-wallet access on the Switch and PlayStation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vd1uJt"&gt;Apple &lt;em&gt;did &lt;/em&gt;support cross-wallet play before banning &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; last year — and on the trial’s second day, that fact became a serious pitfall for Epic. Apple continued a long cross-examination of Epic CEO Tim Sweeney, whose hours of testimony included a digression on whether &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/3/22417697/apple-epic-fortnite-app-store-antitrust-trial-day-1"&gt;counts as a true metaverse&lt;/a&gt; or simply a big free-to-play game that has concerts. (Judge Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers suggested, and Sweeney concurred, that “the most readily acceptable analogy” might be Steven Spielberg’s &lt;em&gt;Ready Player One&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="SIRLNJ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Is the web a viable alternative or a clunky workaround?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7NLGqN"&gt;Sweeney was followed by two witnesses from outside Epic: the founder of an iOS yoga app, followed by the product manager for Nvidia’s cloud gaming service. All argued that Apple’s tightly managed App Store forced customers to use clunky workarounds. Meanwhile, Apple argued that the workarounds weren’t necessarily worse — just different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="93znsi"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; was kicked off the App Store for adding its own V-Bucks purchasing system right inside the app, violating Apple’s restrictions on in-app payment processing. But as Apple’s lawyers pointed out today, Epic had another option for selling V-Bucks on iOS. The company just needed to sell them directly through its website, which users could visit through the iPhone or iPad Safari browser without Apple getting any kind of commission. When they booted up &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; on iOS, their V-Bucks would be waiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="werkN6"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Isn’t that a responsible way to deal with a young client base?”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="A1m6wo"&gt;Judge Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers found this argument compelling enough to follow up on. Why couldn’t iPhone users buy V-Bucks through Safari, she asked, before &lt;em&gt;Fortnite’s &lt;/em&gt;ban in August? Epic CEO Tim Sweeney admitted that Epic could have added the feature — but “it wasn’t a very attractive option for our customers,” Sweeney told her. If somebody wants to buy V-Bucks, he said, there’s a good chance they’re already looking at an item in &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;. “To set &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; aside and pull out some device, browse to a website, log in, make a transaction there, it’s extremely inconvenient.” In short, “there’s a huge amount of payment processing and customer friction associated with selling a user of an app an item outside of that app.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cXAC14"&gt;But after asking how old most &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; players were, Rogers suggested that a little friction might be a good thing. “Why is it so inconvenient that someone can’t make what I would call, as a parent, an impulse purchase?” she asked. “Isn’t that a responsible way to deal with a young client base?” If people can buy V-Bucks and then switch platforms, “what you’re really asking for is the ability to have impulse purchases.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wtZUqF"&gt;Sweeney said &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; had parental controls, but he didn’t dispute Rogers’ basic point. “Yes. Customer convenience is a huge factor in this. People are much more likely to make a purchase if it’s easy to make a purchase,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="RUBNej"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Customer convenience is a huge factor in this”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jeBjpA"&gt;A similar question arose with a later witness. Benjamin Simon is the CEO of a company called Yoga Buddhi, which runs an iOS app called Down Dog. (Sadly, nobody in court thought to&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/12/23/7443635/updog-finally-launches"&gt; make an Updog joke&lt;/a&gt;.) Yoga Buddhi offers a hefty discount for signing up outside the iOS app. And unlike Epic, it’s fine sending people to a website. Simon claims, however, that Apple makes finding that website as hard as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4pLxW9"&gt;Simon says that Apple rejected several versions of Down Dog that reference getting a discount elsewhere. Right now, about half the iOS user base apparently pays a premium to sign up through the App Store. For comparison, only 10 percent of Android users pay a similar premium through the Play Store, because Google doesn’t have the same restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WSE4Av"&gt;Simon acknowledged that Yoga Buddhi can reach customers via other methods like email and help them switch to the discounted version. The problem, again, is friction. “We’re restricted in our ability to communicate with our customers from within our product,” he complained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ltC0J0"&gt;From Apple’s perspective, both executives are making a big deal out of a small inconvenience. Customers might have to work a little harder to save money, but that doesn’t equate to a monopolistic lockdown. And while Sweeney describes &lt;em&gt;Fortnite &lt;/em&gt;as a lofty metaverse, Rogers put it in the very different context of “freemium” gaming — an industry whose powerful, frictionless gaming loops are regularly criticized as addictive and predatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4ZDuFe"&gt;Arguably, though, that very criticism bolsters Epic’s claims. In the past several years, regulators and researchers have shown increasing concern over subtle design choices in apps — like infinite scrolling,&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/31/22360639/robinhood-confetti-ipo-removed-app-stock-market"&gt; confetti animation&lt;/a&gt;, and tweaks to the sorting algorithms on social networks. There’s a broad consensus that small nudges can substantially increase how much people invest in digital platforms. But Epic might have to work harder to convince a court this investment isn’t a &lt;em&gt;bad&lt;/em&gt; thing.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419894/apple-epic-fortnite-app-store-antitrust-trial-day-2"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419894/apple-epic-fortnite-app-store-antitrust-trial-day-2</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-04T21:07:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-04T21:07:24-04:00</updated>
    <title>WhatsApp payments are finally coming back to Brazil after government suspension</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p0YFbzsSP1Qfk3Tn8gCQx8x5IUk=/6x0:1086x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69237951/verge-whatsapp-notification-2040pxl.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Thomas Ricker / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8MsiuP"&gt;WhatsApp is again &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davidmarcus/status/1389671822405214210"&gt;rolling out its payments service&lt;/a&gt; in Brazil, after the service &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/24/21301470/whatsapp-payments-brazil-suspended-central-bank-risk-regulators"&gt;was suspended by Brazil’s Central Bank&lt;/a&gt; in June of 2020 a few days after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/15/21291382/whatsapp-digital-payments-brazil-facebook-pay"&gt;it launched&lt;/a&gt; there. Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg made the announcement in a video aired in Brazil, where he spoke about how the payment information added to WhatsApp will also be able to be used on Facebook and Instagram. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xWFNjt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davidmarcus/status/1389671822405214210?s=20"&gt;According to David Marcus&lt;/a&gt; the head of Facebook Financial, the service returning to Brazil will be part of a “gradual rollout,” but it seems like the company is serious about it returning: it’s already posted a video promoting the service, and has &lt;a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/payments/br"&gt;published a page&lt;/a&gt; that states the underlying Facebook Pay system has been authorized by the Central Bank (Facebook is WhatsApp’s parent company).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="eInrdo"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="pt" dir="ltr"&gt;A gente sabe que vocês estavam esperando por isso. Pagamentos no WhatsApp começa hoje a ficar disponível pelo   . Para saber mais: &lt;a href="https://t.co/O3l4UJOfXl"&gt;https://t.co/O3l4UJOfXl&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/W2VFRuoWfC"&gt;pic.twitter.com/W2VFRuoWfC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— WhatsApp (@WhatsApp) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WhatsApp/status/1389672322785755142?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 4, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pAvtya"&gt;When the service originally launched in Brazil, the country’s central bank suspended it, citing concerns about competition in the payment system market. The bank said it planned to evaluate whether the service was compliant with regulations, despite the fact that Facebook said it had been in contact with the authority before the launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1vx9f2"&gt;In late March of this year, it was &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-facebook-brazil-payments/facebooks-whatsapp-gets-central-bank-nod-to-start-payments-in-brazil-idUSKBN2BM37H"&gt;reported by Reuters&lt;/a&gt; that the bank had approved the service, after Facebook had obtained formal approval to run payments. According to a press release, WhatsApp users will be able to connect debit, prepaid or combo cards from several banks that are working with its payment processor.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22420029/whatsapp-payments-brazil-launch-regulations-fight"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22420029/whatsapp-payments-brazil-launch-regulations-fight</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-04T19:43:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-04T19:43:29-04:00</updated>
    <title>Boost Mobile’s Unlimited Plus plan now comes with talk, text, and telemedicine</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4X_fGEwnFlZHAv7va5R3q9wr-xQ=/88x0:1242x769/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69237815/Image_22.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Boost Mobile&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vnZy8n"&gt;In what looks to be a first in terms of subscriber perks, Boost Mobile &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.boostmobile.com%2Fadd-on-services%2Fhealth.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F5%2F4%2F22419961%2Fboost-mobile-unlimited-plan-healthcare-k-health" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;has announced&lt;/a&gt; that its $60 per month Unlimited Plus cellphone plan will come with access to to 24/7 telemedicine through &lt;a href="https://khealth.com/primary-care/"&gt;K Health&lt;/a&gt; starting this summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IHkcNn"&gt;Specifically, Unlimited Plus subscribers will get all of the features of K Health’s usual $9-per-month offering. That includes the ability to text chat or hop on a video call with a doctor through the K Health app, which uses the app’s AI suggestions to identify symptoms and potential ailments, and receive actual treatment, including medications and other prescriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MC1ps4"&gt;The service is free and available for all Boost Unlimited Plus subscribers and offered at a discounted price of $7.99 per month for all of Boost Mobile’s other customers. You can sign up to get access to the service first &lt;a href="https://omniform1.com/signup/v1/5f8dbd4d4c7fa4332c668d65_607704924c7fa46eaf0721f2.html"&gt;on Boost Mobile’s site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BophuI"&gt;Because this is ultimately a phone plan, you’ll also get 35GB of 4G LTE data per month, after which you’ll get throttled to 2G speeds. That comes with “unlimited” talk and text, and a 30GB mobile hotspot as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bGVVJh"&gt;Offering online healthcare to customers was not on the top of my list of things Boost Mobile would do &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/1/21309968/dish-boost-sprint-tmobile-acquisition-spinoff-closes-prepaid"&gt;after getting absorbed by Dish Network&lt;/a&gt; (as part of T-Mobile’s merger with Sprint). But getting healthcare in the US is an often expensive proposition, and that’s before the bill comes after treatment. And, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/2/22364126/boost-mobile-3g-cdma-t-mobile-shutdown-customers-costs"&gt;Boost has a large percentage of low-income customers&lt;/a&gt;, many of whom have likely been affected by the pandemic, so providing access to healthcare could be a real shot in the arm. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zEoifF"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419961/boost-mobile-unlimited-plan-healthcare-k-health"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419961/boost-mobile-unlimited-plan-healthcare-k-health</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-04T19:25:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-04T19:25:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The story of Basecamp’s disastrous policy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OH_RqBSqxWbKozaAqbBEVWx4Os4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69237755/acastro_210503_4564_basecamp_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Basecamp’s CEO published a blog post about policy changes — it may have broken the company&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="ep2jnm"&gt;On April 26th, Basecamp founder and CEO Jason Fried &lt;a href="https://world.hey.com/jason/changes-at-basecamp-7f32afc5"&gt;posted on his blog&lt;/a&gt; about some policy changes that would be happening at the company, which makes team collaboration software. One policy stuck out to many on the internet — the company would no longer be allowing its employees to have discussions about society or politics on its internal account. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PXoHuB"&gt;What followed was a tidal wave of public outcry, employees speaking out against the policies (and talking about what led to them),&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/30/22412714/basecamp-employees-memo-policy-hansson-fried-controversy"&gt; several revisions of the blog post&lt;/a&gt;, and, finally, &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/e/22182249"&gt;almost a third of the company’s employees&lt;/a&gt; deciding to accept buyouts and leave. There has &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/e/22183840"&gt;since been an apology from Fried&lt;/a&gt;, but it remains to be seen if any more will be coming — there are still accusations made by employees that haven’t really been addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mpwOlP"&gt;Whether you’re looking to get caught up on the saga, or want to keep your eye out for future updates, we’re collecting the story into one place here.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419512/basecamp-political-speech-policy-fallout"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419512/basecamp-political-speech-policy-fallout</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
      <name>Casey Newton</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-04T18:55:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-04T18:55:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>I like X-wings as much as the next guy, but we don’t need one in the Smithsonian</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9md80o83W3Afkuplo43TD7jUk6s=/0x21:490x348/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69237645/Composite_X_wing.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Smithsonian National Air and Space Museum&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="2vqDzs"&gt;May Fourth is informally the &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; Day holiday, which random brands typically use to hawk their wares. Although it’s not as bad as the promotions that come out of the woodwork on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/1/22359046/april-fools-day-brands-pr-bad-stop"&gt;April Fools’ Day&lt;/a&gt;, I think I’m drawing the line at the Smithsonian National Air and Space Museum adding an X-wing Starfighter from &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; to its collection. &lt;a href="https://airandspace.si.edu/newsroom/press-releases/national-air-and-space-museum-welcomes-star-wars-x-wing-starfighter?fbclid=IwAR1Hubkz2IV_RfRWK1tMc5Fc8SZ4zbAt53IgKT6417AEohRWKyIsS5ODFEI"&gt;The museum announced today&lt;/a&gt; that the famous ship would be going on display in 2022, via a prop loan from the Disney-owned production company, Lucasfilm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sVoM72"&gt;The Smithsonian says the X-wing in question is from &lt;em&gt;Star Wars: The Rise of Skywalker&lt;/em&gt; and will be displayed outside the museum’s Albert Einstein Planetarium after undergoing “conservation in the Restoration Hangar in the Steven F. Udvar-Hazy Center.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/l5L5WC2ZIDzuFWc4L24FXRY5KZk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22491583/Screen_Shot_2021_05_04_at_11.53.14_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Smithsonian National Air and Space Museum&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The X-wing starfighter in the Mary Baker &lt;/em&gt;Engen&lt;em&gt; Restoration Hangar.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="V1ewY4"&gt;The first red flag I’d like to get out of the way: an X-wing from &lt;em&gt;The Rise of Skywalker&lt;/em&gt;? Really? The final film in the Skywalker Saga &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/18/21026630/star-wars-the-rise-of-skywalker-review-jj-abrams-daisy-ridley-adam-driver"&gt;is not exactly beloved&lt;/a&gt;, but we don’t really need to rehash that here. That’s what Reddit is for, and now, probably, my email inbox. What’s striking about calling out &lt;em&gt;The Rise of Skywalker &lt;/em&gt;to me is it really adds to the general feeling that including this spaceship is an advertising opportunity for Disney rather than some kind of grand contribution to our national memory of space travel. Of course Disney wants to continue to advertise its most recent &lt;em&gt;Star Wars &lt;/em&gt;film — it’s got a franchise to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bjzsLM"&gt;“Despite taking place a long time ago in a galaxy far, far away, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; introduced generations of fans here on Earth to outer space as a setting for adventure and exploration,” shared Margaret Weitekamp, Smithsonian space history chair. That’s undoubtedly true. &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; has had a huge impact &lt;a href="https://www.starwars.com/news/how-star-wars-inspires-real-scientists-and-engineers"&gt;on how people think about space&lt;/a&gt;, and Disney, with everything it’s made and purchased, has made about &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22167976/disney-investor-day-2020-biggest-announcements-plus-marvel-star-wars-pixar-animation"&gt;as big an impression on culture&lt;/a&gt; as a billion-dollar company can make. But that doesn’t keep this all from feeling a little icky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f7mNXw"&gt;Space and air travel have long been driven by public and private partnerships (see NASA’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/16/22387887/elon-musk-spacex-win-nasa-lunar-lander-contract-artemis"&gt;current dealings with SpaceX&lt;/a&gt;), and the Smithsonian National Air and Space Museum even has other Disney products in its collection, like &lt;a href="https://airandspace.si.edu/collection-objects/toy-buzz-lightyear-space-flown/nasm_A20120233000"&gt;a Buzz Lightyear toy that’s been to space&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://airandspace.si.edu/collection-objects/insignia-unit-10th-weather-squadron-united-states-army-air-forces/nasm_A19711344000"&gt;a Donald Duck Air Force patch&lt;/a&gt;. But I come to museums like the Smithsonian for the pieces of history and culture I don’t know about — the hidden triumphs, failures, and once-in-a-lifetime chances that lead to impressive things like landing people on the Moon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oDX5US"&gt;Not long ago, the Smithsonian hosted the &lt;a href="https://airandspace.si.edu/collection-objects/command-module-apollo-11/nasm_A19700102000"&gt;Apollo 11 Command Module Columbia&lt;/a&gt;, the pod that returned three astronauts to Earth from mankind’s first trip to the Moon in 1969. The museum also currently has &lt;a href="https://airandspace.si.edu/collection-objects/lunar-module-2-apollo/nasm_A19711598000"&gt;the LM-2&lt;/a&gt;, the second Lunar Module that was used in ground tests on Earth. These are all real spacecraft, and that’s not even counting the &lt;a href="https://airandspace.si.edu/collection-objects/communications-satellite-applications-technology-satellite-1-ats-1/nasm_A19761985000"&gt;satellites&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://airandspace.si.edu/collection-objects/payload-scientific-spartan-201/nasm_A20040121000"&gt;payloads&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://airandspace.si.edu/collection-objects/rake-apollo/nasm_A19781497000"&gt;other space ephemera&lt;/a&gt; that the Smithsonian has on hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ighNns"&gt;It’s not that &lt;em&gt;Star Wars &lt;/em&gt;or the X-wing aren’t cool, good, or significant. It’s that yielding physical and mental space to a product that’s meant to be sold rather than something that’s actually a part of human history feels like it distracts from the more meaningful pieces in the Smithsonian’s collection. Leave the props to the movies or Disney’s own curatorial efforts. I don’t think we’d be any worse for it.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/5/4/22419570/smithsonian-national-museum-star-wars-x-wing"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/5/4/22419570/smithsonian-national-museum-star-wars-x-wing</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-04T18:38:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-04T18:38:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>AT&amp;T violated labor law but can still ban workers from recording conversations, NLRB rules</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="In this photo illustration the AT&amp;amp;amp;T logo is seen behind a..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vGaP4iyZJ5usl-36np8MwMpow54=/0x0:3888x2592/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69237561/1231517624.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Pavlo Gonchar/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="g8kGWp"&gt;An AT&amp;amp;T policy that bars employees from recording conversations with managers or colleagues is legal, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.nlrb.gov/case/05-CA-178637"&gt;ruling from the National Labor Relations Board Monday&lt;/a&gt;. The board found that while AT&amp;amp;T violated US labor law in how it had applied the policy, the recording ban itself was not illegal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DJMi09"&gt;According to AT&amp;amp;T’s rules, “employees may not record telephone or other conversations they have with their co-workers, managers or third parties unless such recordings are approved in advance by the Legal Department.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ECrBeb"&gt;In its decision, the NLRB overturned part of an earlier ruling which said that the policy’s potential to infringe on workers’ rights outweighed AT&amp;amp;T’s need to keep customer data private. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Im8CHx"&gt;The case centers on a complaint filed by AT&amp;amp;T employee Marcus Davis in 2016. Davis served as the union steward for the Communications Workers of America Local 2336. In May 2016, he attended a meeting with an employee who was being fired and recorded the conversation. Davis’s manager found out, asked to meet with him, and deleted the recording off of his phone. He later told Davis not to encourage other employees to make in-store recordings since doing so violated AT&amp;amp;T’s rules, and noted he “did not want anyone held accountable for not following policy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3BP9jl"&gt;The NLRB found that Davis was engaged in protected union activity. The board said AT&amp;amp;T violated federal labor law by telling him not to encourage colleagues to make recordings and implying that there could be repercussions for those who did. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WAwj6D"&gt;Yet the board also said that just because the policy was &lt;em&gt;applied&lt;/em&gt; illegally doesn’t mean it is inherently illegal. “A blanket prohibition on the continued maintenance of such rules, simply because of a single instance of unlawful application — even if that single instance is carried out by a misguided low- or mid-level supervisor whose action does not reflect corporate policy — fails to give proper weight to those legitimate interests,” the board wrote. “Indeed, it fails to give them any weight at all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eKF8HX"&gt;In her dissent, NLRB chairman Lauren McFerran said the rule was unlawfully over broad. “We all agree that some recordings by employees are protected by the National Labor Relations Act,”  she wrote. “By its terms, the rule does not differentiate between recordings protected by the National Labor Relations Act and those that are not...Indeed, as written, the rule applies even to conversations on nonwork time and in nonwork areas: an employee could not record a union meeting held in a breakroom at lunch.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VaGYli"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T did not immediately respond to a request for comment from&lt;em&gt; The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419772/att-rule-barring-workers-recording-conversations-legal-federal-labor-law"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419772/att-rule-barring-workers-recording-conversations-legal-federal-labor-law</id>
    <author>
      <name>Zoe Schiffer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-05-04T18:35:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-04T18:35:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>HTC may announce two new Vive VR headsets on May 11th</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wyAXo64b5GDq8RdrBRyVqesJksM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69237537/akrales_191003_3707_0159.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HacaWl"&gt;HTC is planning to unveil two Vive virtual reality headsets at its ViveCon 2021 conference that’s happening on May 11th and May 12th, &lt;a href="https://www.protocol.com/htc-vr-focus3-vive-pro"&gt;according to&lt;em&gt; Protocol&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. While the original Vive and Vive Pro headsets were associated more with gaming, the high-end Vive Pro 2 and Vive Focus 3 Business Edition will reportedly be aimed toward the enterprise sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jt2xLO"&gt;No specs or images of either headset have surfaced, so it’s unclear if both will be tethered headsets that require a PC to use or if one will have a standalone, wire-free design to take on the likes of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21437674/oculus-quest-2-review-features-photos"&gt;Oculus Quest 2&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Wjum2"&gt;The report from &lt;em&gt;Protocol &lt;/em&gt;states that both headsets were mentioned in HTC company documents and were also briefly listed on European e-commerce site Alzashop. Before those shop listings were taken down, the Vive Focus 3 Business Edition showed a €1,474 ($1,771) price, and the Vive Pro 2 was listed for €842 ($1,012), according to &lt;em&gt;Protocol&lt;/em&gt;. Both headsets are reportedly launching sometime in May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6fLBvB"&gt;These headsets could be exciting in their own ways, but another device I’m holding out hope to see at ViveCon &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2021/4/21/22395284/htc-vive-air-leak-fitness-headset-concept-not-real-product"&gt;is the fitness-focused Vive Air&lt;/a&gt;. Pictures leaked a couple of weeks ago showing an attractive standalone VR headset with a breathable fabric design, and it prompted HTC to say that, unfortunately, it’s just a concept. But maybe that’s just what a company trying to downplay an exciting announcement would say, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NUX9K6"&gt;We’ll know much more come May 11th at HTC’s VR conference, where the company &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.vive.com%2Fus%2Fvivecon2021%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F5%2F4%2F22419755%2Fhtc-vive-pro-2-focus-3-business-edition-virtual-reality-vr-headset-vivecon-rumor" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;says it will debut “game-changing VR headsets” during the keynote&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="IJZEWN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"HTC now lets you directly buy Vive repair parts through iFixit","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/27/22405537/htc-vive-ifixit-repair-parts-guide-direct-to-consumer-sale"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419755/htc-vive-pro-2-focus-3-business-edition-virtual-reality-vr-headset-vivecon-rumor"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419755/htc-vive-pro-2-focus-3-business-edition-virtual-reality-vr-headset-vivecon-rumor</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
