<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-12T12:04:42-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-12T12:04:42-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-12T12:04:42-05:00</updated>
    <title>Disney’s MagicMobile pass is a contactless alternative to the MagicBand</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/y1VJ52mPW28fRWK4rlYXvVyv3wM=/48x0:576x352/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68956214/mmo012394820394820394823fi_624x352.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who needs a plastic wristband when you can use your iPhone to do the same thing?&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Disney&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="gC1KwZ"&gt;In 2013, Walt Disney World resort &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/1/7/3845622/disney-world-magicbands-mymagic-data-gathering"&gt;offered the MagicBands&lt;/a&gt; — a plastic bracelet that made it easy to perform numerous services such as park tickets. And now, almost a decade later, the company is finally making your trip to the most magical place on Earth a little more modern with &lt;a href="https://disneyparks.disney.go.com/blog/2021/03/coming-soon-disney-magicmobile-service-a-convenient-new-way-to-experience-walt-disney-world-resort/"&gt;MagicMobile&lt;/a&gt;, a digital pass accessible through your iPhone and Apple Watch starting later this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m6nlTg"&gt;As an alternative to spending money on a plastic NFC wristband, the MagicMobile pass will be added to your Apple Wallet. Guests can then use their iPhone or Apple Watch to gain entry into the park. Disney has not said exactly when MagicMobile will officially be available but confirmed Apple devices would get access to the service and features first. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EwX3sz"&gt;Disney confirmed in &lt;a href="https://disneyparks.disney.go.com/blog/2021/03/coming-soon-disney-magicmobile-service-a-convenient-new-way-to-experience-walt-disney-world-resort/"&gt;a blog post&lt;/a&gt; that the MagicBands will still be an option, and guests can choose which option is more convenient for them or even use both and alternate between the MagicBand and MagicMobile pass. (Disney says it’s introducing new MagicBand colors and designs featuring Disney characters.) The company also notes that MagicMobile will not replace the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdisneyworld.disney.go.com%2Fplan%2Fmy-disney-experience%2F%3FCMP%3DILC-DPFY21Q2wo0311210317210005C&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F12%2F22327351%2Fdisney-magicmobile-pass-announced-iphone-apple-watch" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;My Disney Experience app&lt;/a&gt;, which serves as a digital room key for guests staying at a Disney Resort hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22327351/disney-magicmobile-pass-announced-iphone-apple-watch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22327351/disney-magicmobile-pass-announced-iphone-apple-watch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-12T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-12T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook’s next big AI project is training its machines on users’ public videos</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DA2bTs3wRpPCld8egdN8FKVK4po=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68956126/acastro_171002_1777_0004_v1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Ys26ft"&gt;Teaching AI systems to understand what’s happening in videos as completely as a human can is one of the hardest challenges — and biggest potential breakthroughs — in the world of machine learning. Today, Facebook announced a &lt;a href="https://ai.facebook.com/blog/learning-from-videos-to-understand-the-world"&gt;new initiative&lt;/a&gt; that it hopes will give it an edge in this consequential work: training its AI on Facebook users’ public videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aZNvxd"&gt;Access to training data is one of the biggest competitive advantages in AI, and by collecting this resource from millions and millions of their users, tech giants like Facebook, Google, and Amazon have been able to forge ahead in various areas. And while Facebook has already trained machine vision models on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/2/17311808/facebook-instagram-ai-training-hashtag-images"&gt;billions of images&lt;/a&gt; collected from Instagram, it hasn’t previously announced projects of similar ambition for video understanding. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="3K08av"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“part of our broader efforts toward building machines that learn like humans do”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Hnnwk3"&gt;“By learning from global streams of publicly available videos spanning nearly every country and hundreds of languages, our AI systems will not just improve accuracy but also adapt to our fast moving world and recognize the nuances and visual cues across different cultures and regions,” said the company in a blog. The project, titled &lt;a href="https://ai.facebook.com/blog/learning-from-videos-to-understand-the-world"&gt;Learning from Videos&lt;/a&gt;, is also part of Facebook’s “broader efforts toward building machines that learn like humans do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y6oLfa"&gt;The resulting machine learning models will be used to create new content recommendation systems and moderation tools, says Facebook, but could do so much more in the future. AI that can understand the content of videos could give Facebook unprecedented insight into users’ lives, allowing them to analyze their hobbies and interests, preferences in brands and clothes, and countless other personal details. Of course, Facebook already has access to such information through its current ad-targeting operation, but being able to parse video through AI would add an incredibly rich (and invasive) source of data to its stores. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BsOOx1"&gt;Facebook is vague about its future plans for AI models trained on users’ videos. The company told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; such models could be put to a number of uses, from captioning videos to creating advanced search functions, but did not answer a question on whether or not they would be used to collect information for ad-targeting. Similarly, when asked if users had to consent to having their videos used to train Facebook’s AI or if they could opt out, the company responded only by noting that its &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/policy.php"&gt;Data Policy&lt;/a&gt; says users’ uploaded content can be used for “product research and development.” Facebook also did not respond to questions asking exactly how much video will be collected for training its AI systems or how access to this data by the company’s researchers will be overseen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t8NNmL"&gt;In its blog post announcing the project, though, the social network did point to one future, speculative use: using AI to retrieve “digital memories” captured by smart glasses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="32DPnG"&gt;Facebook plans to release a pair of consumer smart glasses &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/16/21439929/facebook-ar-smart-glasses-ray-ban-announcement"&gt;sometime this year&lt;/a&gt;. Details about the device are vague, but it’s likely these or future glasses will include integrated cameras to capture the wearer’s point of view. If AI systems can be trained to understand the content of video, then it will allow users to search for past recordings, just as many photo apps allow people to search for specific locations, objects, or people. (This is information, incidentally, that has often been indexed by AI systems trained on user data.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5qV26NsYHPQND7jeE97uRSvMApk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21885678/B0005907_logos_V5_close_cropped_4K.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Facebook&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook has released images showing prototype pairs of its augmented-reality smart glasses. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="MaQVyU"&gt;As recording video with smart glasses “becomes the norm,” says Facebook, “people should be able to recall specific moments from their vast bank of digital memories just as easy as they capture them.” It gives the example of a user conducting a search with the phrase “Show me every time we sang happy birthday to Grandma,” before being served relevant clips. As the company notes, such a search would require that AI systems establish connections between types of data, teaching them “to match the phrase ‘happy birthday’ to cakes, candles, people singing various birthday songs, and more.” Just like humans do, AI would need to understand rich concepts comprised of different types of sensory input. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GlYjh0"&gt;Looking to the future, the combination of smart glasses and machine learning would enable what’s referred to as “worldscraping” — capturing granular data about the world by turning wearers of smart glasses into roving CCTV cameras. As the practice was described in a &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2020/nov/25/part-human-part-machine-is-apple-turning-us-all-into-cyborgs"&gt;report last year from &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;: “&lt;/em&gt;Every time someone browsed a supermarket, their smart glasses would be recording real-time pricing data, stock levels and browsing habits; every time they opened up a newspaper, their glasses would know which stories they read, which adverts they looked at and which celebrity beach pictures their gaze lingered on.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OPJyBB"&gt;This is an extreme outcome and not an avenue of research Facebook says it’s currently exploring. But it does illustrate the potential significance of pairing advanced AI video analysis with smart glasses — which the social network is apparently keen to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="zs2CtD"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Facebook has deployed AI video models to recommend clips in Reels&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OT4VwN"&gt;By comparison, the only use of its new AI video analysis tools that Facebook is currently disclosing is relatively mundane. Along with the announcement of Learning from Videos today, Facebook says it’s deployed a new content recommendation system based on its video work in its TikTok-clone Reels. “Popular videos often consist of the same music set to the same dance moves, but created and acted by different people,” says Facebook. By analyzing the content of videos, Facebook’s AI can suggest similar clips to users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UIOBvL"&gt;Such content recommendation algorithms are not without potential problems, though. A &lt;a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2021/03/11/1020600/facebook-responsible-ai-misinformation/"&gt;recent report from &lt;em&gt;MIT Technology Review&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; highlighted how the social network’s emphasis on growth and user engagement has stopped its AI team from fully addressing how algorithms can spread misinformation and encourage political polarization. As the &lt;em&gt;Technology Review &lt;/em&gt;article says: “The [machine learning] models that maximize engagement also favor controversy, misinformation, and extremism.” This creates a conflict between the duties of Facebook’s AI ethics researchers and the company’s credo of maximizing growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T77RNu"&gt;Facebook isn’t the only big tech company pursuing advanced AI video analysis, nor is it the only one to leverage users’ data to do so. Google, for example, maintains a publicly accessible research dataset containing 8 million &lt;a href="https://medium.com/google-cloud/youtube-8m-dataset-c2ee9c79d136"&gt;curated and partially labeled YouTube videos&lt;/a&gt; in order to “help accelerate research on large scale video understanding.” The search giant’s ad operations could similarly benefit from AI that understands the content of videos, even if the end result is simply serving more relevant ads in YouTube. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MKUu3W"&gt;Facebook, though, thinks it has one particular advantage over its competitors. Not only does it have ample training data, but it’s pushing more and more resources into an AI method known as self-supervised learning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="agbNY2"&gt;&lt;q&gt;self-supervised learning is “the dark matter of intelligence.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TJkRfQ"&gt;Usually, when AI models are trained on data, those inputs have be to &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/1-cZkc7gyfI"&gt;labeled by humans&lt;/a&gt;: tagging objects in pictures or transcribing audio recordings, for example. If you’ve ever solved a CAPTCHA identifying fire hydrants or pedestrian crossing then you’ve likely labeled data that’s helped to train AI. But self-supervised learning does away with the labels, speeding up the training process, and, some researchers believe, resulting in deeper and more meaningful analysis as the AI systems teach themselves to join the dots. Facebook is so optimistic about self-supervised learning it’s &lt;a href="https://ai.facebook.com/blog/self-supervised-learning-the-dark-matter-of-intelligence/"&gt;called&lt;/a&gt; it “the dark matter of intelligence.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zo9zOL"&gt;The company says its future work on AI video analysis will focus on semi- and self-supervised learning methods, and that such techniques “have already improved our computer vision and speech recognition systems.” With such an abundance of video content available from Facebook’s 2.8 billion users, skipping the labeling part of AI training certainly makes sense. And if the social network can teach its machine learning models to understand video seamlessly, who knows what they might learn? &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22326975/facebook-training-ai-public-videos-digital-memories"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22326975/facebook-training-ai-public-videos-digital-memories</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-12T11:36:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-12T11:36:24-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tim Berners-Lee says internet access should be a basic right</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="sir tim berners-lee (Paul Clarke, Wikimedia)" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/PWeWIfyPtOiRvzL3XzLZLAGlM6k=/1x0:1600x1066/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68955901/Sir_Tim_Berners-Lee.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Paul Clarke / Wikimedia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jpOyH2"&gt;Tim Berners-Lee, the inventor of the world wide web, &lt;a href="https://webfoundation.org/2021/03/web-birthday-32/"&gt;writes in a new post&lt;/a&gt; on the internet’s 32nd anniversary that governments must work to ensure global broadband access by the year 2030 in order to bridge the digital divide and better hold tech companies accountable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rhfuh5"&gt;“Governments need to pass effective laws that govern technology and hold companies to account for creating responsible products and services,” Berners-Lee writes in the post co-authored by his Web Foundation co-founder Rosemary Leith. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="QsNTyA"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Far too many young people remain excluded and unable to use the web to share their talents and ideas.” &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dHZAiw"&gt;“Far too many young people remain excluded and unable to use the web to share their talents and ideas,” the post states. And for every young person without internet access, there’s a “lost opportunity for new ideas and innovations that can serve humanity.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UB9rRq"&gt;The breadth of the digital divide has come into sharp focus during the coronavirus pandemic, as people tried to work and learn from home, often on less-than-ideal internet connections. According to the &lt;a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/internet/fact-sheet/internet-broadband/"&gt;Pew Research Center&lt;/a&gt;, in the US alone, only two-thirds of people living in rural areas have broadband access, compared to 79 percent of people living in suburbs. And the Federal Communications Commission’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/24/17882842/us-internet-broadband-map-isp-fcc-wireless-competition"&gt;universally disliked broadband maps&lt;/a&gt; don’t give a totally clear picture of the state of broadband access in the US. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XTYeSl"&gt;Berners-Lee and Leith write that worldwide, the problem is similarly bad. “Only the top third of under-25s have a home internet connection, according to UNICEF, leaving 2.2 billion young people without the stable access they need to learn online, which has helped so many others continue their education during the pandemic.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7hQa8F"&gt;Berners-Lee and Leith also cite the need to protect young people online from abuse and misinformation, “which threatens their participation and can force them from platforms altogether,” they write. “This is especially true for those disproportionately targeted on the basis of their race, religion, sexuality, abilities, and gender.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wp6Vnj"&gt;The pair call for access to the internet to be recognized as a basic right, and they say the costs of making sure every young person is connected “is well within our reach. Through funding for network infrastructure, subsidies, and support for community networks, we can get the web into the hands of every young person on earth.” “An all-out push to connect the world will make sure that young people do not fall through the cracks.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="SQU0Lf"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Berners-Lee says internet access should be treated as a basic right&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="YhTg0y"&gt;Berners-Lee and Leith say that the Alliance for Affordable Internet (A4AI), an initiative of the Web Foundation, “has calculated that $428 billion of additional investment over ten years would provide everyone a quality broadband connection. To put this in perspective, that amounts to the equivalent of just $116 per person for the 3.7 billion people who remain offline today.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tt9JSI"&gt;Providing universal broadband access within the next ten years “would deliver around $8.7 trillion in direct economic benefits,” they write, &lt;a href="https://institute.global/policy/progressive-case-universal-internet-access-how-close-digital-divide-2030"&gt;citing a new analysis&lt;/a&gt; by the Tony Blair Institute for Global Change. “We can’t afford not to do it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oXdPzx"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22327246/tim-berners-lee-world-wide-web-internet-access-basic-right"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22327246/tim-berners-lee-world-wide-web-internet-access-basic-right</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kim Lyons</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-12T11:30:39-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-12T11:30:39-05:00</updated>
    <title>Almost all of LG’s Android 11 updates aren’t coming until the end of 2021</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3xU6sLQGi-VF0k51MRC4uxwX3c4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68955865/cgartenberg_201022_4254_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Chaim Gartenberg / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jB1tF0"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lg.com/de/android-updates"&gt;LG’s German&lt;/a&gt; website has revealed its Android 11 update roadmap — at least for Europe — and the news isn’t too encouraging. With the exception of the LG Velvet 5G, most of the company’s phones won’t get Android 11 until the back half of 2021, with the vast majority of devices not seeing the update until at least Q4 2021 (long after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22288084/android-12-developer-preview-available-google-pixel"&gt;Android &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; should be available, if Google’s release schedule is similar this year). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="98aXQk"&gt;It’s worth noting that the released schedule is only from LG’s German site. It’s possible that time frames will be different in other regions, that LG could add more devices over time, or that the updates will simply take less time to develop than the company expects. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BCIctszh8vH1l1bOUfYP14fxeUE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22365453/Screen_Shot_2021_03_12_at_10.43.55_AM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Gv2P4A"&gt;The slow update speed isn’t entirely surprisingly, though. LG’s phone business has been struggling for years, prompting reports that the company is considering exiting the smartphone space entirely this year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/20/22240282/lg-smartphone-business-exit-2021-internal-memo"&gt;although the company told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;in January that nothing has been finalized yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m4ZVjV"&gt;LG has also denied rumors that its next major smartphone, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22296298/lg-rollable-denial-not-on-hold-or-cancelled"&gt;the LG Rollable&lt;/a&gt;, has been canceled, although there’s still no firm release date for that device either outside of a vague 2021 window. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22327144/lg-android-11-software-update-wing-phones-mobile-q4-2021"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22327144/lg-android-11-software-update-wing-phones-mobile-q4-2021</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-12T11:23:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-12T11:23:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>Vergecast: NFT mania, the Sonos Roam, and the next Android phones </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2psGHSnyAWf8OamDxGgHfeSGFm4=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68955765/acastro_170726_1777_0008.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bVOQqg"&gt;Every Friday, &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; publishes our flagship podcast &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/the-vergecast"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, our chat show discussing the week in tech news featuring our reporters and editors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L9uIzC"&gt;This week, co-hosts Nilay Patel and Dieter Bohn talk to &lt;em&gt;Verge&lt;/em&gt; deputy editor Elizabeth Lopatto about the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22310188/nft-explainer-what-is-blockchain-crypto-art-faq"&gt;rise in interest of NFTs&lt;/a&gt;. Elizabeth explains the basics of how NFTs work and what someone actually owns when a transaction takes place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XpLDhr"&gt;In the second half of the show,&lt;em&gt; Verge&lt;/em&gt; deputy editor Dan Seifert stops by for a gadget roundup — there’s a review for the wild &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321496/asus-rog-phone-5-ultimate-review-gaming-phone-snapdragon-888-ram-specs-features"&gt;Asus ROG Phone 5&lt;/a&gt;, some rumors of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323979/oneplus-9-pro-leak-images-hasselblad-camera"&gt;OnePlus’ new flagship device&lt;/a&gt;, and the announcement of Sonos’ first fully mobile &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/9/22319251/sonos-roam-pricing-features-release-date"&gt;Bluetooth speaker&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="uPboG2"&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="200" scrolling="no" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm?e=VMP8386388336&amp;amp;light=true" width="100%"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xPsuAv"&gt;Listen here or in your preferred podcast player to hear the full discussion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JPUMiF"&gt;Stories mentioned in this week’s episode: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="90mXQO"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323268/covid-rapid-testing-pandemic-home-disease-pcr"&gt;COVID-19 took disease tests out of the lab — and may keep them there&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rND8wd"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22319514/vaccinated-people-vaccines-cdc-mask-coronavirus-social-guidelines"&gt;People who are vaccinated can socialize together without masks, CDC says&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="CTmfUp"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/6/22316094/covid-19-vaccine-supplies-us-antivirus-newsletter"&gt;COVID-19 vaccine supplies are on the rise in the US&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="xtUmYF"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/5/22315138/covid-vaccine-single-shot-johnson-distribution"&gt;Single-shot COVID-19 vaccine is popular at vaccination sites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="G6EGgN"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323850/artifacts-first-covid-19-vaccination-smithsonian-museum"&gt;Artifacts from the first COVID-19 vaccination in the US are headed to the Smithsonian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Nwoqbw"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/9/22320344/dr-b-covid-vaccine-standby-list-coronavirus-immunization-overflow"&gt;Meet Dr. B, the startup connecting people to leftover vaccines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JWq9GT"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22325054/beeple-christies-nft-sale-cost-everydays-69-million"&gt;Beeple sold an NFT for $69 million&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="mE43KE"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22310188/nft-explainer-what-is-blockchain-crypto-art-faq"&gt;NFTs, explained&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rxpQCP"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/9/22322218/john-legere-buys-steve-aoki-nft"&gt;Of course John Legere bought an $888,888.88 NFT from Steve Aoki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="di2Tc1"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/9/22321464/jack-dorsey-nft-tweet-auction-bitcoin-donate-charity"&gt;Jack Dorsey’s first tweet may fetch $2.5 million, and he’ll donate the NFTy proceeds to charity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kjg4gl"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/9/22319251/sonos-roam-pricing-features-release-date"&gt;Sonos Roam officially announced for $169, preorders start now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ni2ynK"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22322827/sonos-audi-q4-e-tron-auto-sound-partnership"&gt;Sonos partners with Audi to bring its audio tech to cars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="stGtQx"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321496/asus-rog-phone-5-ultimate-review-gaming-phone-snapdragon-888-ram-specs-features"&gt;Asus ROG phone 5 review &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="dHo4nb"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22323979/oneplus-9-pro-leak-images-hasselblad-camera"&gt;Leaked OnePlus 9 Pro and OnePlus 9 renders leave little to the imagination&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="WdNPOp"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/8/22315517/oneplus-9-launch-date-hasselblad-camera"&gt;OnePlus’ next phones will come out on March 23rd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="cRF725"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/9/22322232/samsung-galaxy-a52-a72-unpacked-event-awesome"&gt;Samsung will host another Unpacked event on March 17th&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="c32P9V"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/10/22322843/iphone-12-mini-apple-low-production-numbers-decrease"&gt;Apple reportedly overestimated iPhone 12 mini demand, by a lot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rx7u2V"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22319707/insta360-go-2-action-camera-test-price-specs-features"&gt;Insta360’s Go 2 is a $299 action camera with a surprisingly powerful case&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="FTM7pD"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/7/22314135/ticwatch-pro-3-fossil-gen-5-lte-review-smartwatch-wear-os"&gt;The most powerful Wear OS watches are held back by Wear OS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Y7yj3D"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22321471/asus-rog-zephyrus-g15-gaming-laptop-review"&gt;Asus ROG Zephyrus G15 review: AMD and Nvidia at their best&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fYAqMs"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22315386/razer-blade-15-base-2021-review-gaming-laptop-nvidia-rtx-3070-qhd-screen-performance"&gt;Razer Blade 15 Base review: losing its edge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kf6YtN"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22295181/best-gaming-laptop"&gt;Best gaming laptops in 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="y1VQGI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"The Vergecast","description":"The podcast you need to make sense of the week in tech news","label":"Subscribe","url":"https://pod.link/430333725"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22327173/vergecast-podcast-444-nft-sonos-roam-preorder-asus-rog-phone-5"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22327173/vergecast-podcast-444-nft-sonos-roam-preorder-asus-rog-phone-5</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Marino</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-12T11:16:28-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-12T11:16:28-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google slams Microsoft for trying ‘to break the way the open web works’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/o7_k5PBtfuyxetT14sHtCHmdwdY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68955715/acastro_180427_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IecWc1"&gt;Google and Microsoft engineers might collaborate on the Chromium browser code, but that hasn’t stopped corporate politics between the pair. Google has launched a scathing attack on Microsoft today, accusing it of trying “to break the way the open web works in an effort to undercut a rival.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GntoxW"&gt;Google is upset about what it believes is an attack by Microsoft to undermine the company’s efforts to support journalism and publishers. In January, Google threatened to remove its search engine from Australia, in response to a law that would force Google to pay news publishers for their content. Australia &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22283777/australia-new-media-bargaining-code-facebook-google-paying-news"&gt;passed the law in February&lt;/a&gt;, just days after Google caved and cut a deal with News Corp. and other publishers that ensured its services continue to be available in Australia. (Facebook, on the other hand, did remove the ability for users and publishers to share news content in the country, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/23/22296778/facebook-ends-australian-news-ban-bargaining-code-google"&gt;earned some concessions from the Australian government&lt;/a&gt;.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="DDfZk6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Australia passes law requiring Facebook and Google to pay for news content ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/24/22283777/australia-new-media-bargaining-code-facebook-google-paying-news"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="oy22Rl"&gt;In the middle of all of this, &lt;a href="https://news.microsoft.com/en-au/2021/02/03/microsoft-supports-australian-government-proposal-addressing-news-media-and-digital-platforms/"&gt;Microsoft was very public&lt;/a&gt; about its support of Australia’s new law, and it even &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-australia-media-facebook-microsoft/microsoft-teams-up-with-eu-publishers-amid-facebooks-australian-spat-idUSKBN2AM1MB"&gt;teamed up with European publishers&lt;/a&gt; to call for online platforms to reach deals to pay news outlets for content. Google isn’t happy about Microsoft getting involved and this is the first big public spat we’ve seen since the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/11/22/5135626/scroogled-microsoft-ads-attack-google"&gt;Scroogled era&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K9HFsb"&gt;“They are now making self-serving claims and are even willing to break the way the open web works in an effort to undercut a rival,” says Kent Walker, Google’s head of global affairs, &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/news/google-commitment-supporting-journalism/"&gt;in a blog post&lt;/a&gt;. “This latest attack marks a return to Microsoft’s longtime practices. Walker links to the Wikipedia entry for Fear, uncertainty, and doubt (FUD), and accuses Microsoft of muddying the waters to distract from recent security issues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9e5Qsx"&gt;“It’s no coincidence that Microsoft’s newfound interest in attacking us comes on the heels of the SolarWinds attack and at a moment when they’ve allowed tens of thousands of their customers ... to be actively hacked via major Microsoft vulnerabilities,” says Walker. “Microsoft was warned about the vulnerabilities in their system, knew they were being exploited, and are now doing damage control while their customers scramble to pick up the pieces from what has been dubbed the Great Email Robbery. So maybe it’s not surprising to see them dusting off the old diversionary Scroogled playbook.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="scroogled" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dMpeo-F3pgh8sVtCPJXw1m0QIZs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/14256901/scroogled_427.1419979343.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft’s old Scroogled ads.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fghZqY"&gt;This unusual attack from Google also comes just as the House Judiciary Committee looks at the antitrust and commercial aspects of competition for a free and diverse press. Google argues it doesn’t make money from Google News, but Microsoft argues it’s a lot more complicated and involves Google Search ads, ad tech business, ad exchange, ad tech tools, and Google’s overall consumer dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pt0RuM"&gt;“News organizations have ad inventory to sell, but they can no longer sell directly to those who want to place ads,” &lt;a href="https://docs.house.gov/meetings/JU/JU05/20210312/111315/HHRG-117-JU05-Wstate-SmithB-20210312.pdf"&gt;says Microsoft president Brad Smith&lt;/a&gt;. “Instead, for all practical purposes they must use Google’s tools, operate on Google’s ad exchanges, contribute data to Google’s operations, and pay Google money. All this impacts the ability of news organizations to benefit economically even from advertising on their own sites.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a9BjQ8"&gt;Google and Microsoft are clearly at odds over the core argument of whether publishers should have more control over a digital ad industry dominated by the search giant and Facebook. Microsoft wants Congress to move forward with the Journalism Competition and Preservation Act and “enable news organizations to negotiate collectively with online content distributors.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mR3xTz"&gt;Google, on the other hand, believes its &lt;a href="https://newsinitiative.withgoogle.com/"&gt;Google News Initiative&lt;/a&gt;, where it tries to collaborate with the news industry, is enough to help news organizations. While Microsoft and Google battle in a war of words, the &lt;a href="https://judiciary.house.gov/calendar/eventsingle.aspx?EventID=4440"&gt;House Judiciary Committee is meeting today&lt;/a&gt; to hear less scathing arguments about the future of the press in a digital era.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22327306/google-microsoft-attack-open-web-online-news-australia-laws"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22327306/google-microsoft-attack-open-web-online-news-australia-laws</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-12T11:15:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-12T11:15:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The engineers building ridiculous dart blasters that Nerf won’t touch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZYZHBaZY2EIu10OjcgNIVsHHog8=/0x3:2040x1363/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68955704/ajucevic_210225_4416_0029.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke Goodman, owner and founder of Out of Darts, is pictured in their Vancouver, WA factory and warehouse on February 25th, 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Inside the DIY Nerf arms race&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="9dE9dt"&gt;It was a beautiful summer day in San Jose, California, perfect for pegging people with foam. My brother was particularly proud: he’d already been getting some great tags with his Nerf revolver, and now some guy had sold him a nifty 3D-printed cylinder so it could hold seven darts instead of five. I wanted one, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E9hqii"&gt;It turned out the guy who sold him the cylinder, Luke, was mostly just there to say his goodbyes to the local Nerf group, before leaving the Bay Area for good. I didn’t think much of it at the time. I certainly didn’t know Luke Goodman was about to quit his day job to become the foam-slinging equivalent of James Bond’s gadget armorer Q.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vo8gu0"&gt;Luke, better known as Out of Darts, went viral in 2015 when he figured out how to turn Nerf’s 12-round Zeus blaster into a 108-shot ball-blasting contraption a little more worthy of the Greek god’s name. As many as 15 million people have watched PDK Films &lt;a href="http://youtube.com/watch?v=AS1tgn2qU3c"&gt;blow away an entire wall of Solo cups&lt;/a&gt; with Luke’s creation, after it got featured &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/how-to-upgrade-nerfs-70-mph-blaster-with-a-monstrous-10-1745233779"&gt;at &lt;em&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and by popular Nerf YouTube star Drac (aka &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8v1i83tmEwo"&gt;LordDraconical&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JyaFNP"&gt;He wasn’t yet out to build a better Nerf blaster; Luke was simply doing some irrigation work in his backyard when he realized the pipe he was holding might fit inside the Zeus. “I put a piece of it in there, pulled the trigger and just cackled,” he tells me. When he saw the YouTube numbers, he couldn’t believe his eyes. Then the emails started pouring in. Hundreds of people had tracked him down, asking to buy his “HIRricane” blaster. He whipped up a quick Etsy shop and got to work. But even at $160 per kit or $325 for an assembled blaster — an “absurd price” he set to see if it was worth his time — he still couldn’t keep up with the demand. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="aTAzKt"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XFfwXsr48kM?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vlxcy3"&gt;Now, Out of Darts is at the forefront of a cottage industry selling original blasters and parts that can leave the official Nerf brand (owned by Transformers, G.I. Joe, and &lt;em&gt;Magic: The Gathering&lt;/em&gt; giant Hasbro) in the dust. It’s almost something of an arms race, where the Nerf internet community one-ups each other by making their toy blasters shoot more foam faster, farther, and more accurately, whether to show off or to perform that much better in an actual game of Nerf. And while Hasbro is clearly taking some notes from the upstart maker community, 3D printers in particular are giving makers an edge they’ve never had before. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YPZzHB"&gt;Originally, Luke took the cottage industry part literally, selling blasters and parts out of his own house with just a few 3D printers to start. But today, he’s the proud proprietor of a 3,800-square-foot warehouse with eight employees, running a&lt;em&gt; 97-printer&lt;/em&gt; factory that consumes over 300 pounds of filament each month. &lt;a href="https://outofdarts.com/"&gt;They ship&lt;/a&gt; nearly 100 orders a day to an army of hobbyists eager to build epic blasters of their own, customers who can now select from 1,500 different products including individual batteries, motors, and original 3D-printed parts. It’s gotten to the point that they needed to build a custom inventory picking program just to keep it all organized and let workers box up multiple orders at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xm3s7s"&gt;He now makes more money than he ever did behind the camera; enough to pay his shop employees an average of $20 an hour, too. He’s the first person I’d heard of to make a comfortable living from the Nerf cottage industry. But he’s far from the only one reshaping what a Nerf blaster can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cNYkqWBjGSkn6XBKKING4xTahx0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363244/ajucevic_210225_4416_0021.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Little Rocket blaster with modular barrels.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/esWib8VSWdwWrgNv4P1f1-ha8VI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363231/ajucevic_210225_4416_0009.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twenty-four colors of filament are stacked and ready to use in the 3D printers at Out of Darts. They go through over 300 pounds a month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Mo6ah3Q4gSAWqPE2_slmTVsS_eE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363234/ajucevic_210225_4416_0012.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blaster barrels produced in-house with 3D printers are organized by size and color at the Out of Darts warehouse and factory.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hRxVfqCWIXNUnea82QDMHhAB86M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363233/ajucevic_210225_4416_0011.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A 3D printer produces original parts at Out of Darts. Out of Darts runs 97 3D printers to produce their original blasters and modification parts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="QAsr59"&gt;In the ’90s, Nerf was a simple game of tag you could play at a distance with your siblings, friends, maybe the neighbor kid down the street. You’d be lucky if you could afford a blaster that could shoot a single dart more than 50 feet, and that was only if you fired up at an angle praying it would land on target. There’s a reason the word “nerfing” means to weaken something — Nerf blasters were supposed to be safe for kids — but kids got wise. They’d cut off the tip of an arrow-firing blaster to make it shoot darts, plug safety holes with hot glue, and add rubber bands or bungies to make them shoot farther. Modding was part of the excitement of Nerf; you could bring anything you liked to the park as long as it wouldn’t put someone’s eye out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="teHHYi"&gt;Around the world, hotspots began to form — groups of Nerfers who pooled their knowledge and resources to host giant Nerf wars that could last days at a time. The internet brought them online, and the sophistication level of modders crept up from trial and error to actual science, discussing the optimal winding of an electric motor, the length of a barrel. Engineers who used to fling a few darts as children have realized there’s now an entire online community waiting for them to demonstrate what they can make foam projectiles do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GoSiGc"&gt;Steven Lawver was one of those kids who returned to the hobby as a science pro. Known as &lt;a href="http://captainslug.com/"&gt;Captain Slug&lt;/a&gt;, he’s a modder who has, arguably, single-handedly transformed the Nerf scene twice: once in 2007 with his “&lt;a href="http://nerfhaven.com/forums/topic/10387-bow/"&gt;Plusbow&lt;/a&gt;,” a DIY re-creation of Nerf’s legendary 1995 Crossbow (once considered one of the most powerful blasters in the sport), and more recently in 2016 with the Caliburn, a 3D-printed marvel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PCOvdZ"&gt;Properly tuned, the Caliburn was one of the first magazine-fed blasters that could reliably and repeatedly hit things at a distance, with a beefy 11-inch spring and a robust pump-action mechanism. It used to be you could simply run toward your foes in Nerf, dodging shots on the way; the first few times I faced off against a Caliburn, I got pegged in the head and torso multiple times before I even got within range. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MuTHu4"&gt;But perhaps the real genius of the Caliburn was that Slug gave the files away for free, letting anyone print and remix the open-source plastic pieces themselves. He’ll build you a turnkey blaster if you’ve got the cash, sure, but he primarily sells packs of the metal hardware to folks who enjoy the mild challenge of assembling one at home. I certainly did:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tdoFWXzREJ8kqzDBgTvqdAZIor8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363324/IMG_20190724_083148.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A traditional full-length Caliburn blaster, designed by Captain Slug.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A closer look at the Caliburn blaster, a long rifle with 3D printed parts." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-m8inO-3t-8EBBzOcqb4togli1U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363325/IMG_20190724_083232.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;I bought the metal parts from Slug’s online shop, but a friend printed the plastic ones locally.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Giqv6u"&gt;No readymade blaster ever offered that kind of performance until Slug showed the way. Now, they’re set to become a mainstay of sporting-grade Nerf, with companies like Jet Blaster and Dart Zone selling powerful, accurate rifle-shaped blasters for &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sdXeLAvkqJM"&gt;as little as $50 at Walmart&lt;/a&gt;. He’s even licensed his blaster designs to other shops; Worker, a quality Chinese aftermarket Nerf parts brand that increasingly sells blasters as well, cut a deal to mass-produce a “Worker Caliburn.” You can’t go to a modern Nerf war without seeing at least a handful of Caliburns, and forks off of the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cVTBXp"&gt;There have been strong signs that Hasbro is paying attention and might want a piece of the action. In 2015, &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/nerf-rival-review-the-evolution-of-foam-warfare-1730896686"&gt;it launched Rival&lt;/a&gt;, a line of blasters targeting older players, advertising “high-impact rounds” that would travel at “70 miles per hour.” After Luke’s 108-round “HIRricane” went viral, Hasbro released two $100-and-up blasters with 100-plus round capacities, too. But the official Nerf brand has yet to release anything anywhere near as powerful and accurate as Captain Slug’s Caliburn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7xtIIk"&gt;Last month, Slug decided to quit his day job, too. He tells me he was already spending nearly as much time on his expanding array of designs as he did working at a material science lab, but blasters have become the bigger breadwinner by far: after producing over 1,500 Caliburn kits, 4,500 metal hardware sets and inking eight licensing deals over the past few years, he now makes over $100,000 a year from custom Nerf blasters alone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OpVd7p0D3UuT3M6_es_rAWic8w8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363249/ajucevic_210225_4416_0026.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Out of Darts Jupiter blaster. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="rPNZb1"&gt;Meanwhile, Out of Darts is nearly ready to bring a long-awaited invention to the world. It’s a next-gen version of the blaster that brought Luke his original 15 minutes of fame: the Out of Darts Rival Jupiter — designed in large part by his friend Tarik Crnovrsanin — and its companion Proton Pack, a device that can continually feed an incredible amount of ammo to a blaster through its swiveling tube. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MWsoi3"&gt;Even by itself, the $99 Jupiter is an impressive sidearm, able to unleash a 12-ball blitz so fast foes don’t know what hit them. (That’s also partly because it’s so small.) I took it to a Nerf war before the pandemic hit, and I could tag out entire groups of foes at close range so long as I was willing to sacrifice myself — or lucky enough to find some cover for a rapid reload. But with the Proton Pack, it can live up to its &lt;em&gt;Ghostbusters&lt;/em&gt; namesake: a nonstop stream of balls, only limited by the size of the ammo drum you’re willing to haul around. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2FD3QP"&gt;I cram the entry-level 430-round hopper into my backpack, fill it to the brim with foam spheres, and seal it tight so the pressure from its brushless blower fan (and jam-busting auger) can feed them into the tube. And then, yes, I cackle too — as every single one of those 430 balls blast across my backyard from a veritable firehose I can hold in a single hand. Which in turn invites an obvious question: why not wield &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt;? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4NazGbuJDXCVn_0jjuLnB0qEgLQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363240/ajucevic_210225_4416_0017.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luke Goodman with the Out of Darts Proton Pack and Jupiter, which can fire 20 rounds a second. He says he’s shot tens of thousands of rounds through the system without jamming.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JOss8z"&gt;The answer might be the price: when Luke’s Proton Pack finally goes on sale later today (after teasing his customers for years), it’ll cost $165 for the DIY kit alone, not including a blaster or battery. If you want to pair it with a Jupiter, that’ll be an additional $99, though you’ll also be able to buy an adapter for some of the most popular blasters Hasbro sells — including the Perses, Zeus, Khaos, and Hera — just so long as you’ve got the basic soldering skills to rewire them. One financial consolation prize is you’ll only need one battery to power both: the Proton Pack doubles as a power source for your blaster, even sensing the current draw from your flywheels &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; it spins up its own motors to feed balls through the flexible swiveling tube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Loads of small yellow foam balls pour into a canister, then blast out a pistol-sized blaster." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2xWVU275YR1OWjorcDXajAO9wts=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22364778/nerf_proton_pack.gif"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;What the Jupiter and Proton Pack can do.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xTj6TK"&gt;Overpowered? Perhaps, but that’s the state of the Nerf hobby in 2021, where I see incredible original blasters appear at the &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Nerf/"&gt;r/Nerf&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/nerfhomemades/"&gt;r/NerfHomemades&lt;/a&gt; subreddits on what feels like a weekly basis these days. The wide availability of 3D printers, powerful miniature motors, and high-power LiPo batteries has transformed the hobby over the past few years, to the point that seemingly unbeatable blasters are foiled by new inventions before long. “The first two games I just hammered people,” says Luke of his early Proton Pack prototypes, but his advantage didn’t last. “Two or three games later, everyone had Caliburns, and I’d get shot before I stepped out from behind the tree.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VtKAVM"&gt;It’s the next expansion that might be Out of Darts’ most ambitious yet. Though he hasn’t been able to visit China for over a year, Luke managed to find a genuine factory to start mass-producing his original products with actual injection-molded plastic. He’s starting small with a new dart magazine for existing blasters, but says that it might make more sense to invest in tooling than 3D printing for anything they’re likely to sell a few thousand of — for instance, their popular Rival Perses hopper, which expands the 50-round capacity of Nerf’s fastest blaster to 160 rounds while making it far, far easier to reload. (It also helps that it’s a large, difficult part to 3D print, but comparatively easy to mold.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kQIWCEYTU_HVFHmyo8s_PfQcveI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363243/ajucevic_210225_4416_0020.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Nerf Rival Perses, with Out of Darts’ 3D-printed hopper. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OXbCUX"&gt;Luke admits that it’s a nerve-wracking experience, waiting to find out if the first production run from a factory he’s never actually managed to visit will be good enough — each set of tooling can cost tens of thousands of dollars. “That’s why we hadn’t gotten into it yet; I wasn’t going to risk my whole business on a design,” he tells me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cDsw2B"&gt;The not-so-dirty, not-so-secret dirty little secret of the Nerf cottage industry is that 3D-printed plastic isn’t very profitable, so injection molding is one way forward. Otherwise, metal’s where the money’s at; threaded rods, screws, and springs are the bulk of Slug’s business, and one-fifth of Out of Darts’ sales come from motors alone. With few exceptions, you could buy them from anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gUOBy6"&gt;But each business has amazing goodwill in the community, and it’s not hard to see why: they show up, time and again, with something new and exciting to contribute. Speak CaptainSlug’s &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Captain-Slug/"&gt;name on Reddit&lt;/a&gt;, and he’ll often magically appear — sometimes to share progress on a brand-new design, sometimes just to shoot the shit or comment on your build. Another community example: FoamBlast, a rival parts business that also collaborates with Out of Darts, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/FoamBlast/videos"&gt;hosts a weekly Nerf news show&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3Y3esi"&gt;When Luke’s not running the shop or answering customer email, he also spends much of his time on YouTube, filming remarkably high-quality video reviews and mod guides for Nerf’s latest blasters, often with parts he created specifically to make modding more accessible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S85W7y"&gt;In January 2019, I decided to try a high-power rapid-fire blaster mod with his custom parts instead of fiddling with hot glue, and was pleasantly surprised by how easy it was. For under $25, I bought some excellent hobby wire, a couple high-amperage Omron switches, and four 3D printed parts designed to perfectly mate those switches with a Nerf blaster’s triggers. A few hours later, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5G-fA-qrJTA"&gt;guided by this step-by-step Out of Darts video&lt;/a&gt;, I’d turned my Nerf Rival Nemesis, already one of Hasbro’s more powerful designs, into a beast kicking out 9 balls a second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0XvwG0b83c7__S5E1jthX6abfsk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22364793/luke_and_tarik_out_of_darts.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tarik Crnovrsanin (at right) holds two of his designs: a Proud Papa mounted atop a Jupiter. He’s a data scientist who also built the website and picker software for Out of Darts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8PQJvJ"&gt;And last November, Out of Darts collaborator Tarik surprised me with the accessory I’ve been secretly begging Nerf to make for years: a bolt-on blaster for your blaster, so you can shoot while you reload. He calls &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0MQuItpOcC4"&gt;his $20 Little Rocket / $22 mountable Proud Papa&lt;/a&gt; the world’s smallest 3D-printed blaster, but it also packs quite a punch, firing standard Nerf darts with more power than many of Nerf’s own blasters at a fraction of the size. Better still, it’s got modular twist ’n’ lock barrels to quickly swap out a single long-range dart for a three-round burst or a shield-busting Mega. (Shields are a thing in some Nerf games, and the big red Mega darts are traditionally what you need to take them out of commission.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eYnZWp"&gt;It’s exactly the kind of product that Out of Darts wants to be known for, Luke says: something the community wants, and that nobody had thought to create and sell quite yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9BiRWY"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0MQuItpOcC4?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="7juTOP"&gt;These days, Luke tells me, he buys every single blaster from every brand as soon as he possibly can, to test it, figure out whether it’s going to be popular, and — if so — where he sees room for improvements he can make and sell. That’s where the easy-to-reload Perses hopper idea came from, and more recently, a mod for that powerful $50 Walmart blaster, the 125-feet-per-second Dart Zone Nexus Pro. “We have games that don’t allow blasters to shoot that hard, and some where we’d like to shoot harder,” says Luke, who started selling an incredibly elegant solution in no time flat: &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/LIFOElOITvI?t=167"&gt;a “tuning cap”&lt;/a&gt; you can install in seconds to reduce or increase compression on the spring that powers your blaster. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jim4to"&gt;“It was probably two or three weeks from the second I got the blaster to us having a product out,” says Luke, who credits the low prototyping costs of 3D printing with the fast turnaround. It wouldn’t have been possible with injection molding alone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rtQMCU"&gt;There are risks to building your entire livelihood on a hobby predominantly controlled by a single company, of course. Nerf brand owner Hasbro discourages modding as a general rule, and when its entire 2020 lineup of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d9gyU0Nndc8"&gt;“Elite 2.0” blasters&lt;/a&gt; turned out to be a cut-rate selection of poor performers that were hard for modders to open, he wound up with nothing to sell. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yq3FjBbLLk5s2yCZhY218mNFu3U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22363223/ajucevic_210225_4416_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ninety-seven 3D printers produce modification parts and complete blasters at Out of Darts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vYdHKj"&gt;A few days after we spoke, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/25/22299490/nerf-hyper-announcement-first-blasters-rush-siege-mach"&gt;Hasbro revealed its biggest Nerf news in years&lt;/a&gt; — a successor to Rival that seems likely to replace it entirely, and, I imagine, make some of Luke’s planned products obsolete. I hopped back on the phone with Luke, to ask him what he’ll do. To my surprise, he didn’t seem even a little bit worried. If anything, he seemed giddy — already full of ideas for the new Hyper lineup. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o55CTh"&gt;Sure, he probably won’t make any more hoppers for the discontinued Perses, but he thinks a hopper might fit perfectly atop the similar Mach-100... should the community embrace the smaller (and likely easier to lose) Hyper ammo, of course. He thinks there’s more than enough Rival blasters already out in the world to sell the 1,000 Proton Packs he’s building, too. They’re out of Hasbro’s hands now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TXYQ8w"&gt;It makes me think back to the last big Nerf war I attended, where I saw more than a handful of Nerfers go into battle without a single scrap of actual Nerf-branded gear. The community has its own magazines, its own ammo, and is now regularly building blasters more powerful than anything Hasbro has ever put on shelves. “It’s Nerf or nothing” hasn’t been true for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="iY1Wfw"&gt;When I ask Luke what &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; keep him up at night, he says there isn’t much; perhaps just that he’s got seven employees whose livelihoods now depend on his business, too. There was a moment at the beginning of the pandemic where it seemed like everything would fall apart, the shop would be forced to close, and that would have been the end; he would have had to go back to shooting weddings and tech company videos. Instead, he closed for a couple days, switched most of the printers over to medical face shields for a few weeks, and that was it. The orders kept coming in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1la7L7"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KG0gvc"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22324389/nerf-gun-diy-homemade-blaster-out-of-darts-jupiter-caliburn-captain-slug-hasbro"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22324389/nerf-gun-diy-homemade-blaster-out-of-darts-jupiter-caliburn-captain-slug-hasbro</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-12T10:38:06-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-12T10:38:06-05:00</updated>
    <title>HBO Max will debut its cheaper, ad-supported tier in June</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/72RJIb4KLLpfbo417F3_kQS6pTw=/0x0:1725x1150/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68955404/Screen_Shot_2021_03_12_at_10.18.39_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="syNyc9"&gt;WarnerMedia is set to launch an ad-supported tier for its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21548253/hbo-max-netflix-hulu-streaming-cable"&gt;HBO Max streaming service this June&lt;/a&gt;, and executives are hoping that having a cheaper option will help boost subscriber growth. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ahQku"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T didn’t provide additional information in a press release sent out, including price or exact launch date, but noted that &lt;a href="http://voxmediapartner.go2cloud.org/aff_c?offer_id=2&amp;amp;aff_id=1&amp;amp;source=Verge&amp;amp;aff_sub=JuneCheaperAd031221"&gt;HBO Max&lt;/a&gt; will also launch in about 60 markets outside of the US in 2021. Pricing announcements will be made in the coming months, WarnerMedia CEO Jason Kilar told analysts gathered for AT&amp;amp;T’s analyst day. Considering we’re half-way through March, a couple of months is basically launch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F1t8cN"&gt;The main difference between the ad-supported tier and the normal plan is access to same-day theatrical releases, Kilar added. Customers on the ad-supported plan won’t be able to watch &lt;em&gt;Dune &lt;/em&gt;on HBO Max when it lands, for example. Kilar also confirmed that ads won’t play on HBO original titles like &lt;em&gt;Euphoria, The Sopranos, &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="mscVHC"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Most people on this planet are not wealthy”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JhorPt"&gt;An ad-supported plan is just one way to help grow HBO Max’s subscriber base. The expensive pricing tier ($15 a month) might be off-putting to a number of consumers. Kilar recently spoke about the incoming advertisement supported tier at the Goldman Sachs conference, noting that “most people on this planet are not wealthy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dxWx86"&gt;“And so if we can wake up and use price and be able to kind of invent and do things elegantly through advertising to reduce the price of a service, I think that’s a fantastic thing for fans,” he said, as &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2021/digital/news/warnermedia-jason-kilar-movie-windows-hbo-max-avod-1234921633/"&gt;reported by &lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VIXW8b"&gt;Executives seemingly have a lot of hope that an ad-supported tier will help subscriber count skyrocket. AT&amp;amp;T is raising subscriber targets for both 2021 and 2025, and the company now expects to end 2021 with roughly 67-70 million subscribers worldwide and end 2025 with anywhere between 120 and 125 million subscribers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LxHLG0"&gt;That’s a massive increase compared to what executives touted previously — 75 to 90 million — in October. HBO and HBO Max ended 2020 with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22252069/hbo-max-subscribers-wonder-woman-1984-att-earnings"&gt;combined 41 million subscribers, but with one giant asterisk&lt;/a&gt;. Of the 37.7 million cable HBO subscribers, less than half actually activated their free &lt;a href="http://voxmediapartner.go2cloud.org/aff_c?offer_id=2&amp;amp;aff_id=1&amp;amp;source=Verge&amp;amp;aff_sub=JuneCheaperAd031221"&gt;HBO Max &lt;/a&gt;upgrade.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D5yh9I"&gt;Two of the biggest issues impacting HBO Max from the get-go were price and awareness. With the company trying to figure out a better approach to communicating what HBO Max is (and how it differs from HBO), and a cheaper plan soon available, executives are clearly expecting things to pick up. Of course, that’s on top of measures taken to boost subscribers, including dropping new movies in 2021 on&lt;a href="http://voxmediapartner.go2cloud.org/aff_c?offer_id=2&amp;amp;aff_id=1&amp;amp;source=Verge&amp;amp;aff_sub=JuneCheaperAd031221"&gt; HBO Max&lt;/a&gt; the same day they’re available in theaters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C83TFR"&gt;Kilar did not comment on other streaming initiatives within WarnerMedia — the industry has speculated CNN could receive a streaming service to tap into a younger viewing base. But he did confirm sports will not be made available on HBO Max this year. Sorry, basketball fans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tNXNUY"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 12th, 11:57AMET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; The story has been updated to include more information from WarnerMedia CEO Jason Kilar. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22327217/hbo-max-ad-supported-tier-launch-date-international-price-subscriber-growth"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/12/22327217/hbo-max-ad-supported-tier-launch-date-international-price-subscriber-growth</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Alexander</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-12T10:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-12T10:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>How modders rebuilt Resident Evil 4’s graphics from scratch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Resident Evil 4 HD Project" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/odAVoAo43ufv_olKiEHmRTgy2us=/0x0:3240x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68955352/re4hdprojectlede.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A screenshot from the Resident Evil 4 HD Project.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WqjleW"&gt;Albert Marin has taken some very specific vacations. In Wales, he visited Raglan Castle to snap pictures of its stone wall. At the Palau Güell in Barcelona, he took meticulous photos, not of the building itself, but of the marble floor and its unique veins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8FbRZC"&gt;His trips followed in the steps of Capcom, which put bits of real-world architecture found across Europe into &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil 4&lt;/em&gt;, which was originally released over 16 years ago. “I collected a great number of locations the game’s developers use as source material,” Marin told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zm8OQE"&gt;Fast forward to 2021, and Marin is now seven years into a project to remaster &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil 4&lt;/em&gt;’s blurry GameCube-era graphics into crisp HD, in part using high-resolution photos he’s taken of everything from surfaces and doors to general architecture that seemed to have made their way into the original game. Even though Capcom published its own PC remaster in 2014, it wasn’t Marin’s idea of a true HD version of the game, so he and a small team have been poring through the game’s files to faithfully update every texture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="YgNYYU"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10371794"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9TShUG"&gt;In some cases, they work with what Capcom already made, sharpening the images with a mix of off-the-shelf apps and custom-built tools. Other times, Marin is making hand-crafted textures based on high resolution stock photos or pictures that he’s taken himself. If you own the &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/254700/Resident_Evil_4/"&gt;Ultimate HD version of the game on Steam&lt;/a&gt;, you can actually test out an &lt;a href="https://www.re4hd.com/?page_id=6064"&gt;in-progress version of the texture pack&lt;/a&gt; right now. Eventually, every rock, wall, button, and dial will have been retouched by this small team of modders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NPBWU5"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.re4hd.com/"&gt;The fan-funded &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil 4 &lt;/em&gt;HD Project&lt;/a&gt; is almost at the finish line and should be wrapped up later in 2021. Marin says he’s amassed over 4,500 Photoshop files and put in more than 9,000 hours of work (just on his part) to get to this point.    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N4OnIZ"&gt;I spoke with Marin over email about his experience tackling a project of this scale, balancing expectations from fans who are just as passionate about the game, how the team was able to deconstruct the game’s files, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0WdJRA"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How exactly do you remaster the visuals? Do you redraw textures from the ground up, or have a specialized way to increase the resolution of the original without degrading their quality?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vb9yLg"&gt;Most textures are re-created from scratch using some texture library images as a base. The original textures need to be analyzed several times in order to make sure the new source images match in terms of color, lighting, and even the material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w3DcmK"&gt;For example, a rock texture: It may sound like an easy challenge, and it is, if you don’t have an original texture you need to be faithful to. You can’t imagine how complicated it can be to find a rock surface that matches with the original among the hundreds of different kinds of rocks nature has to offer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kwpWNl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10371800"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="E14C5b"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What sorts of applications and tech do you use to accomplish your goals with this project?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3NjmRO"&gt;A talented modder and coder, “Son of Persia,” helped us a lot: He developed most of the tools I use to edit 3D models, lights, effects, collision data, and much more. I found out how some files work, but I needed to edit in a hexadecimal editor manually. This means a single light/effect would take hours to edit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sxwkPM"&gt;“Son of Persia” took all my findings about these files and generated automated tools that would make this work &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; easier. And he also deciphered how other files of the game work and what they do, and he generated the needed tools to edit these kinds of files as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6E5WZT"&gt;We also use Photoshop, 3ds Max, and dozens of custom tools courtesy of “Son of Persia” and other modders. These tools unpack and convert all the game files into editable data (mostly understandable .txt files and 3D files that can be opened with most 3D editors). Once the data is edited it can be repacked again with the same tools. But I have to admit sometimes I manually edit a few things in a hexadecimal editor, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="wHs7KG"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Modding and remastering this game is also a game for me”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="c7Nc9T"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is it intimidating to make certain adjustments to a game that has such a passionate fanbase, or are you confident in your changes?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C4T5HW"&gt;We are on the safe side because one of the main goals of this project is to be faithful to the original. And here is where subjectivity plays an important role: Low resolution textures leave a lot to the imagination, and you know... every person’s imagination is different!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="65Vc67"&gt;Sometimes we receive complaints even when we use the exact same texture, but in HD resolutions, because the low-res textures looked like it was dirtier or muddy or something like that. But the HD re-creation looked too clean in comparison, depending on what the person interpreted when looking at the low-res surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="njTJpY"&gt;And then we have all the lighting and effects changes I’ve done. Most of them are well-received, but I’m aware my personal taste is playing a role to some degree, so I’m always open to feedback and this is the reason I post all those videos and comparison images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TBLUYb"&gt;I’ve changed a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of things because of the feedback we receive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NIzyhkbI3M48r9q7kzhQeGriQN8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22342353/image__2_.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Albert Marin&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Albert Marin standing in front of Raglan Castle, specifically, in front of the wall he says is used in a few &lt;/em&gt;Resident Evil&lt;em&gt; titles.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rdkjAO"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are some of the biggest and smallest changes your team has made to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RE4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; during this project?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sI5TZh"&gt;The biggest change by far is an entire piece of area created from scratch in the Separate Ways mini-game. The transition between one room and the other made no sense. I combined the 3D structure of the connecting areas and I found out a portion of the path was missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dlwVJL"&gt;The smallest changes are any small texture and small 3D improvement done here and there. In fact, there are hundreds of small edits I’m sure most people won’t ever notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="beoa84"&gt;As an example, I remember some design changes in certain ammo boxes. This PC port has a HD textures option. The HD textures are 95 percent an upscaled and filtered version of the original [GameCube] textures, but some of the textures are redone or slightly adjusted.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Jz-Qy3vpUHZKv15LIFYJ_3d7F1Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22342376/COMPARISON_DETAIL.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Albert Marin&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marin’s team restored some of Capcom’s original texture work that had been lost in later ports, then enhanced it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="GhYJpj"&gt;In the image (above) you can see how they altered the TMP ammo box design. The “J” and the wolf drawing on the side are different. So, while I was upscaling that texture I took the opportunity to restore the original design from previous versions of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g0prUe"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What have been your favorite sections of the game to upscale textures for?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wOwKk5"&gt;The castle area, by far, because I used a lot of pictures I took myself during the trips I did around Spain and Wales. It was really satisfying to identify and improve all those architectural surfaces!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nFQF2N"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:10371810"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="c8MsLx"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What section(s) of the game required the most amount of work to remaster? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gfebLy"&gt;The laboratory and factory areas on the island are probably the most time-consuming in terms of texture and 3D retouching, because there are tons of weird and blurry control panels, medical and military devices, and cables. Any small inaccuracy becomes really apparent, unlike the organic textures of the village or the old architectural surfaces in the castle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GvTBSh"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is your HD project focused strictly on visuals, or has there been work done to the sound quality and other parts of the game as well?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5PCjQW"&gt;Unfortunately I do not have enough sound knowledge to remaster the game’s audio. Although I fixed some bugs, mostly related to wrong sounds playing in the wrong moment or low quality sounds during the Separate Ways campaign (shipped as part of the PS2 port and all ports following it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P5FouL"&gt;I also fixed some stage collision issues here and there.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Screenshots showing versions of a texture from the game. On the left is the HD Project, in the middle is the original texture, and on the right is a version upscaled by AI." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/caaGWI02NTi04UFoPbuNyNEPTxg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22365098/re4remake2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Albert Marin&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;AI upscaling looks far better than the original texture, but not as good as what Marin and the team eventually accomplished manually.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fdvyOw"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You currently accept donations to help fund the &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RE4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; HD project, but do you plan to sell the finished project once it releases?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7nSAGr"&gt;No, it will be for free. Modding and remastering this game is also a game for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XazxXL"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What sort of reception have you gotten from this project, and who do you hope to reach with it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UJR2ar"&gt;It surpasses anything I’d imagined. I guess some people, sites, and communities have spread its existence. But after all, &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil&lt;/em&gt; has a huge fanbase, so I guess it’s quite understandable a few thousands of this fanbase is interested in the remaster process of one of the best games of all history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lOB6TW"&gt;About our target audience, I’d say, everyone who likes the remasters for the sake of the visual pleasure; or playing their favorite game you like with no trace of blurriness, or simply the people who like this kind of fan project but don’t like the game at all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GMDleT"&gt;Because this project is more about the journey than the final result. After all, it can’t compete with any next-gen game in terms of visuals, no matter how crisp the textures are or how round the models look.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Qi8UtMOI3OQMFo12nfZYFuNvTMg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22342368/LAB.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Albert Marin&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;One of &lt;/em&gt;Resident Evil 4’&lt;em&gt;s laboratory environments, with upscaled textures applied.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="DcULTk"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you worked in any capacity with Capcom (or any of its current or former employees) on this project?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QTGiqY"&gt;No. We were in contact with them at the beginning. Someone at Capcom was interested in our project, and he took the time to send a planning document, but I guess the other Capcom people in Japan were not interested because the communication ended there. Other than that, there was no help on making the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XIE4aM"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Given that Capcom recently released the &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RE3 &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;remake, it’s likely that an &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RE4 &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;remake is in development. Does your team worry about Capcom eventually stealing your thunder, so to speak, with an improved version of the game?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NWGFfr"&gt;No, the remakes are really different games. Even now, the original &lt;em&gt;Resident Evil 2 &amp;amp; 3&lt;/em&gt; receive their own mods and visual improvements (&lt;a href="https://www.reshdp.com/re2/"&gt;Resident Evil 2 and 3 HD Seamless Project&lt;/a&gt;) They are different and complementary experiences. Just think about any Hollywood remake. Most of them don’t hurt the original movie, and they are alternative visions of the older title.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22309983/resident-evil-4-hd-project-remake-remaster-mod-pc-textures-graphics"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22309983/resident-evil-4-hd-project-remake-remaster-mod-pc-textures-graphics</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
