<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-16T10:32:22-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T10:32:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T10:32:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>Comcast adds a Ring-style video doorbell to its Xfinity Home package</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Xfinity Video Doorbell" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hUUPDRudzs8-yns2uNLCnJZJrpk=/200x0:1280x720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70281307/xfinity_video_doorbell.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Xfinity Video Doorbell&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Comcast&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uVvPSw"&gt;For customers who’ve chosen to trust Comcast with their home security, it’s &lt;a href="https://corporate.comcast.com/press/releases/comcast-launches-new-video-doorbell-for-xfinity-home-customers"&gt;adding a new Xfinity Video Doorbell&lt;/a&gt; that pops up a notification both in your Xfinity app and on your TV through a Flex or X1 box when someone is at the door. There are many options for video doorbells these days, but Comcast’s includes HD video quality, two-way audio so you can speak to visitors even if you’re not at home (or don’t want to get off of the couch), motion alerts, and 24/7 video recording.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Xfinity Video Doorbell" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DdeAdUpwNBFasnQVirmn0XWVmSg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23101215/xfinity_doorbell_pics.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Comcast&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Xfinity Video Doorbell&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="l8KSDO"&gt;If you want a video doorbell but have already gone the Ring, Nest, or Wyze smart home route, it’s unlikely to sway you, but it’s an option that slots in with the rest of the company’s security packages, and this is the first video doorbell available for Xfinity Home customers. The Xfinity Home package already offered security cameras with video clips and live monitoring, so the lack of a video product for your front door was a noticeable omission next to &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xfinity.com%2Fsupport%2Farticles%2Fdevices-help&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F16%2F22839444%2Fxfinity-video-doorbell-comcast-automation-smart-home-security" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;its sensors, thermostats, keypads, and the rest&lt;/a&gt;. For the rest of its pitch, Comcast also touts the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/8/18167912/comcast-xfinity-xfi-advanced-security-internet-protection-price-ces-2019"&gt;xFi Advanced Security package&lt;/a&gt; that comes for free with its security monitoring to keep an eye on your connected devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="fF4mem"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Ring Video Doorbell Pro 2 review: Ring’s best doorbell yet ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22359973/ring-video-doorbell-pro-2-review"},{"title":"Google’s latest Nest Doorbell and camera are not obvious upgrades","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22710545/nest-doorbell-battery-cam-battery-test-review-price-specs-features"},{"title":"Wyze’s new Video Doorbell Pro costs $65 and promises six months of battery life ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22734238/wyze-video-doorbell-pro-price-specs-shipping"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="UCtRaV"&gt;Assuming you still subscribe to cable TV, it lets you pull up video clips or view those motion alerts right on your TV. There’s no word on how many features still work during a service or internet outage, but the overall Home products include battery backup, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22837637/aws-west-is-down-twitch-outage-amazon"&gt;given the reliability of AWS lately&lt;/a&gt;, it’s hard to say who may have better uptime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RvvKRj"&gt;If you’re getting a professional installation with &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xfinity.com%2Flearn%2Fhome-security&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F16%2F22839444%2Fxfinity-video-doorbell-comcast-automation-smart-home-security" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Xfinity Home Pro Protection or Pro Protection Plus&lt;/a&gt;, it’s available for $120 upfront or for $5 per month paid over 24 months. Comcast says it will also be available for Self Protection Xfinity Home customers next year but did not specify pricing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EsVOWu"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclosure: Comcast is an investor in Vox Media, &lt;/em&gt;The Verge&lt;em&gt;’s parent company.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="JsVMwf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Matter’s plan to save the smart home","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22787729/matter-smart-home-standard-apple-amazon-google"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839444/xfinity-video-doorbell-comcast-automation-smart-home-security"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839444/xfinity-video-doorbell-comcast-automation-smart-home-security</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T10:31:44-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T10:31:44-05:00</updated>
    <title>TikTok says it’s varying For You recommendations to avoid harmful content holes  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Tessellated TikTok logos against a dark background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GhbkC_kY9luK4rGRz51C3pQr4sc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70281303/acastro_190723_1777_tiktok_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="kJ16Lk"&gt;TikTok is changing its For You Page algorithm to prevent users from seeing too many similar videos that could be harmful when viewed in clusters, the company &lt;a href="https://newsroom.tiktok.com/en-us/an-update-on-our-work-to-safeguard-and-diversify-recommendations"&gt;said today&lt;/a&gt;. The goal is to steer users away from clusters of videos that might “reinforce a negative personal experience,” listing extreme dieting, sadness, and breakup content as examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z2L9kK"&gt;“At TikTok, we recognize that too much of anything, whether it’s animals, fitness tips, or personal well-being journeys, doesn’t fit with the diverse discovery experience we aim to create,” the company says in its release. The For You feed uses metrics like how long a viewer &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/video/series/inside-tiktoks-highly-secretive-algorithm/investigation-how-tiktok-algorithm-figures-out-your-deepest-desires/6C0C2040-FF25-4827-8528-2BD6612E3796"&gt;lingers over content&lt;/a&gt; to recommend videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NISK3R"&gt;TikTok’s personalized recommendations algorithm has been the subject of scrutiny. An investigation by &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal &lt;/em&gt;demonstrated how the app can push young users down &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/tiktok-algorithm-sex-drugs-minors-11631052944?mod=article_inline"&gt;rabbit holes of sex and drugs&lt;/a&gt;, showing similar content repeatedly. Health experts say &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/29/22808011/tiktok-health-impact-research-plan"&gt;more research is needed&lt;/a&gt; on the app, which surpassed 1 billion monthly users in September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M2XMVL"&gt;The company also announced it was working on features that would allow users more ways to customize what content isn’t shown to them. Users would be able to choose hashtags and words related to content they don’t want to see on the For You feed. Users already have the option to signal they’re not interested in a video, and TikTok says similar content will be shown less often.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839453/tiktok-for-you-recommendations-harmful-content-fyp"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839453/tiktok-for-you-recommendations-harmful-content-fyp</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mia Sato</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T10:07:31-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T10:07:31-05:00</updated>
    <title>You can soon rate your favorite podcast on Spotify</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BCbCj6waOzLM3LAazP9cmcu9qG8=/471x0:1296x550/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70281175/Pod_Ratings_FTR_1920x733_1.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Spotify&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Rlaumz"&gt;Spotify is coming for Apple Podcasts’ star rating system with one of its own. The company &lt;a href="https://newsroom.spotify.com/2021-12-16/show-your-favorite-podcasters-you-love-them-with-spotifys-new-star-ratings-for-podcasts/"&gt;announced today&lt;/a&gt; that it’s launching a five-star rating system for podcasts. Listeners will be able to leave a rating after they listen to a show for at least 30 seconds, and the average rating will be displayed on a show’s landing page once at least 10 have been submitted. Spotify says the feature is meant to make it “easier for listeners to decide when to try out a new podcast” and that these ratings will “serve as the first chance to draw new listeners in.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uvkqpB"&gt;The company &lt;a href="https://blog.anchor.fm/updates/spotify-podcast-ratings"&gt;explicitly encourages&lt;/a&gt; podcasters to shout out Spotify and tell listeners to rate them there. This is likely the primary motivator for Spotify. The trope of “rate and review” on Apple Podcasts is silly but also a real driver for people to go to an app. If, instead, podcasters shouted out Spotify, maybe even just a few people would download the app or at least open it and figure out how to listen to a podcast there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="zm7RSq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"podcasts"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cAtqGt"&gt;At the same time, reviews often open platforms and their users up to harassment. They do indeed offer a helpful first impression of a show but are also easy to game. I wrote &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/28/20835812/podcast-review-bomb-apple-castbox-one-star"&gt;a story two years ago&lt;/a&gt; about angry fans review bombing shows on Apple Podcasts. In a year, I could probably write the same about Spotify. (The opposite can always be true, too, of a podcaster review bombing themselves for good.) Does that mean we shouldn’t have ratings? Probably not. But does that mean I hope Spotify has a good bot detection system or even one to detect broad harassment? Yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H2uNwt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839449/spotify-podcast-star-ratings-update-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839449/spotify-podcast-star-ratings-update-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ashley Carman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T10:04:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T10:04:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>Hyundai’s new four-wheeled robot is designed to carry anything you want it to</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3wQuQFroXGARLt4U53K_-TGKP_o=/58x0:793x490/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70281166/hyundai_robot.0.gif" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tz7K8f"&gt;South Korean automaker Hyundai is used to making machines that move, but the company is now tackling the problem of mobility on a much smaller scale than usual. Instead of new cars, it’s announced at CES this year &lt;a href="https://www.hyundainews.com/en-us/releases/3467"&gt;a four-wheeled robot named MobED&lt;/a&gt; that’s designed to carry, well, anything you like — from parcels to people; TV screens to trays of drinks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TZuP3X"&gt;MobED is about the size and shape of a dolly you might find in a workshop or garage. It’s 67cm long and 60cm wide, with four 12-inch pneumatic tires that can be controlled independently via a trio of motors at the end of each axel. A complex suspension system means its central platform can be tilted in any direction, letting MobED keep goods level when driving up or down a ramp and adjust the angle of its cargo (which would be handy if the robot is carrying a camera or screen).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jX9AhO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10927257"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IqXAe9"&gt;What exactly MobED will be used for is an open question. Hyundai is calling the device a “mobility platform,” and an official &lt;a href="https://www.hyundainews.com/en-us/releases/3467"&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; suggests it wants to sell MobED to industrial partners who will then adapt it for specific use cases. Prices are unknown, and judging by some flashy videos from Hyundai, it’s imagining some very varied applications. MobED could become a personal caddy, for example, like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/22/22685649/gita-gitamini-cargo-carrying-robot-piaggio"&gt;Gitamini&lt;/a&gt; — toting packages and shopping. And future versions might even be strong enough to carry people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nzhyfu"&gt;“MobED can be used as a mobility device for the elderly or the disabled when the platform is sufficiently increased for people to mount it,” said the company in a press release. “It can also be used as a stroller or leisure vehicle.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xJbJSq"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_9JTjO4cn4U?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dOt8sn"&gt;The robot has a top speed of 30km/h (18mph) and can drive for four hours on a single charge. How exactly it navigates is unknown, though. Hyundai makes no mention of sensors at all, whether cameras or lidar, nor does the company say whether it comes with any autonomous driving software — which would be very onerous for partners to develop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AZiS1T"&gt;Interestingly, Hyundai isn’t the only car manufacturer branching out into this sort of generalized robotics. Toyota and Honda are both investing heavily in this area, developing machines that might &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/11/6/9680128/toyota-ai-research-one-billion-funding"&gt;one day work in care homes&lt;/a&gt; or be used as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/7/16745340/honda-robot-concepts-mobility-empathy-ces-2018"&gt;personal mobility devices&lt;/a&gt;. Evidently, as self-driving technology develops, many car manufacturers are seeing new areas to apply this newly acquired expertise. MobED is just the latest example of this trend.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839417/hyundai-mobed-wheeled-robot-mobility-device-ces-2022"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839417/hyundai-mobed-wheeled-robot-mobility-device-ces-2022</id>
    <author>
      <name>James Vincent</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Can we regulate social media without breaking the First Amendment?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MpsQ3IQrfIs3QTInslsDlnPkOPg=/0x0:2050x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70281123/VRG_ILLO_Decoder_Jameel_s.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo Illustration by Grayson Blackmon / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Jameel Jaffer, executive director of the Knight First Amendment Institute, helps us answer the question&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="Af0qXc"&gt;One of the hardest problems at the intersection of tech and policy right now is the question of how to regulate social media platforms. Everyone seems to think we should do it — Democrats, Republicans — even Facebook is running ads saying it welcomes regulation. It’s weird. But while everyone might agree on the idea, no one agrees on the execution. Everyone agrees the platforms should be more transparent but not about what — should the algorithms be public? Should researchers have access to data about users? What about data privacy? That seems good, but those bills have been stalled out forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iC9K9b"&gt;And then there’s the biggest obstacle of all: the First Amendment. Like everyone else, social media companies have a First Amendment right to free speech, and a lot of the proposals to regulate these companies kind of look like government speech regulations and run right into the First Amendment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dzelyy"&gt;In fact, this has happened twice in the past year: both Texas and Florida passed state laws that would regulate big platforms, and both of those laws were ruled unconstitutional by courts and put on hold pending appeal. The Florida law was especially hilarious because it specifically excused any company that owned theme parks in the state, which was an openly corrupt concession to Disney. Very good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="plBA0D"&gt;Jameel Jaffer, executive director of the Knight First Amendment Institute, just co-authored a piece in &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/12/09/opinion/social-media-first-amendment.html?partner=slack&amp;amp;smid=sl-share"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; opinion section&lt;/a&gt; arguing that while these laws should be struck down, the arguments being made by the platform companies against them go too far — they stretch the First Amendment into preventing any regulation at all, including things like privacy and transparency. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vCf2Fi"&gt;I thought that was a fascinating line of argument coming from an organization dedicated to the First Amendment, so I asked Jameel on to &lt;em&gt;Decoder&lt;/em&gt; to talk it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TtNXHO"&gt;Here we go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dfBF5S"&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="200" scrolling="no" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm?e=VMP3605426787" width="100%"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="y7P3iK"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This transcript has been lightly edited for clarity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7NGUZf"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jameel Jaffer, you’re the executive director of the Knight First Amendment Institute at Columbia University. Welcome to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decoder&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CExvmF"&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xfryWb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You just wrote a piece in the &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/12/09/opinion/social-media-first-amendment.html?partner=slack&amp;amp;smid=sl-share"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The New York Times&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; opinion section&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; about the various laws in Texas and Florida that would regulate social media companies and the arguments that the companies are making against those laws. I want to talk about all that, but we should start with the basics. What is the Knight First Amendment Institute?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3TWtBd"&gt;Well, we are an institute based at Columbia University. We were established five years ago by Columbia and the Knight Foundation to focus on digital-age free speech issues. We do that through litigation, research, and public education. We have brought a number of lawsuits related to social media and free speech. The one that probably got the most attention was the lawsuit that forced President Trump to stop blocking critics from his Twitter account, but that is not the only case that we have brought over the last few years – just the most famous one. We’ve brought a number of other lawsuits relating to the intersection between new technology, especially new communications platforms, and the First Amendment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ja9THW"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is Knight’s primary product lawsuits and litigation? Is it research? What is the day-to-day?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oGlfUU"&gt;We are both of those things. We have a litigation team of about a dozen lawyers who work solely on key cases involving free speech and closely related values like privacy, as well as cases involving new technology. We bring those cases ourselves and we litigate them in court. That means we brief them and we argue them at all levels of the federal court system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="084KZ2"&gt;Many of our lawyers come from other public interest organizations. I was at the ACLU for 14 years before I came to Columbia. Some of my other colleagues were at the ACLU, or at [PEN America], or at other organizations that focus on free speech and privacy issues. Again, especially in the context of new technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cd6sPU"&gt;We also have a research program and, through that program, we sponsor academic research and academic symposia around the same set of issues. Public education is something that we have spent less time focusing on over the last few years, but we’re going to spend more time focusing on that this year and in the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zX9SDf"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You mentioned the tangled relationship between social media and the First Amendment. If I had to make a prediction for 2022, it would be that this energy and drive to regulate social media in this country will come to a series of moments, maybe to a head, and we will have to contend with whether the First Amendment allows the government to pass speech regulations, to pass content moderation standards or laws preventing racism on platforms, all the things like that. There are two laws in Texas and Florida that the courts have put on hold due to First Amendment challenges. There are endless hearings and Congress loves to yell at tech executives. I don’t know if that’s going anywhere, but it keeps happening. There is a sort of dull roar about Section 230. All that seems like, in the next year or so,  it’s going to add up to, “What are the limits of the First Amendment?” That feels very real to me. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kEERHJ"&gt;It’s already happening to some extent, right? Because some of these laws are now being challenged in the lower courts. The Florida law and the Texas law have both been challenged. District court judges have already reached conclusions about those laws and those cases are now going up. I don’t know if those are the cases that are going to lead to the Supreme Court showdown; many things have to happen before that takes place, but if it’s not these laws, there’ll be others. I think Wisconsin also has a law in the works. Other states are considering various kinds of regulation of social media platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qfywb8"&gt;Congress is considering this as well – there are all sorts of ideas on the table. You know, what those lawsuits will look like in practice turns on the details of the laws that are actually passed. But there’s no question that over the next year or couple years, the courts are going to have to start grappling with those questions that you already alluded to. Those questions about what does the First Amendment actually mean in this context?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xQhr5G"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your piece in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New York Times&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; opinion section covered the arguments that social media platforms like Facebook and Twitter, through their various lobbying groups, are making in the courts. Your argument is that they are somehow co-opting the First Amendment in their lawsuits. Explain that to me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="ZxtxMG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9545330"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VwUKab"&gt;The op-ed piece was based on a brief that we filed in the Florida case. We found ourselves a little bit conflicted about these lawsuits because on the one hand, we agree with the companies that these laws are unconstitutional. I mean, these laws impose extensive transparency requirements on major platforms. They give users all kinds of rights with respect to content that’s taken down or accounts that are taken down. The Florida law restricts platforms from deplatforming or shadow banning – which is not very well defined in the law – political candidates or media organizations. The Texas law prohibits viewpoint discrimination. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vt2wQZ"&gt;So there really are very comprehensive regulations to the social media platform and they’re extremely burdensome. But more significantly, as it relates to the First Amendment, both of the laws are viewpoint discriminatory and they are viewpoint discriminatory in the sense that they were enacted in retaliation for the platforms’ editorial decisions. In the months preceding the enactment of these laws, some of the platforms took down President Trump’s accounts. They restricted access to reporting about Hunter Biden. They labeled vaccine misinformation as misinformation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WoWyAM"&gt;These laws were kind of payback for those decisions. And what we said in our brief is the fact that the laws were payback for those decisions is enough to doom them for constitutional purposes. That alone should be sufficient to justify the courts throwing these laws out. But the arguments that the platforms, the social media companies, are making actually go much further than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0ZxI7o"&gt;The platforms are not just saying that these laws are viewpoint discriminatory. They go on to make a number of arguments that, if you accept them, would preempt more than just the Florida and Texas laws, which have all kinds of problems beyond viewpoint discrimination. They would also preempt other laws that wouldn’t have those problems. So just to be a little more specific, the companies argue, for example, that the First Amendment entitles them to exactly the same protections that newspapers get under the First Amendment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3txVqp"&gt;They also argue that any law that burdens their editorial decision-making, no matter how minimal the burden, should be subject to the most stringent constitutional review and maybe even regarded as per se unconstitutional. And they argue that any law that targets larger platforms, or that draws a line between larger and smaller platforms, should be subject to the most serious constitutional scrutiny as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bGaJcY"&gt;And if you accept all of those arguments, yes, absolutely, the Florida and Texas laws will be struck down, as they should be. But it will also be almost impossible for legislatures, at the state or federal level, to pass much more modest laws. Laws that, for example, impose reasonable transparency requirements on the companies, or afford users reasonable due process protections. Or even restrict what kind of information they can collect and how they can use that information. In other words, privacy laws. So if you accept the social media company’s arguments. It’s not just the Texas and Florida laws that will be struck down, it’s all these future laws too. Laws that might be much more reasonable than the ones we’re looking at right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3InvgT"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you think the audience for your piece was regular people reading it? Was it the judges who read &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New York Times&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; opinion section? Was it the bar as a whole?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QbVoLh"&gt;I think part of why we wrote it was that even amongst the community that spends a lot of time thinking about the First Amendment and regulation of the platforms, there has been a kind of bifurcation in that community. People are gravitating towards these two poles that are represented in these cases by the platforms on one hand and by the state governments on the other. So you have the platforms arguing essentially a kind of “all” position; we have the same rights as newspapers and any law that would be unconstitutional with respect to newspapers must also be unconstitutional with respect to social media companies. That’s a very broad understanding of the platform’s own First Amendment rights. And on the other hand, you have these state governments which have staked out a kind of “none” position; the platforms have no First Amendment rights to speak of in this context and whatever state governments want to do, they should be allowed to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ekS9cc"&gt;And it seemed to me and to my colleagues of the Knight Institute that this kind of bifurcation, or polarization, of this particular debate is a real problem because the First Amendment doesn’t leave us with only these two possibilities, all or nothing. There’s a lot of space in between all or nothing. You could have a set of rules that restricted state governments from effectively using social media regulation as a means of distorting political debate, but still allow legislatures to impose reasonable privacy and transparency and due process protections. There is that kind of middle ground, and the First Amendment shouldn’t be understood to leave us with only these two extremely unappealing options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lndMkG"&gt;And so that message, I think, was in part for people in our own small community of lawyers and tech policy experts who are thinking about these issues every day but, in our view, have come to the wrong conclusion that there are only these two unappealing possibilities on the table. I don’t want to be too generous to our own writing, but it was also an effort to bring a degree of nuance to a conversation that has sometimes maybe lacked nuance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tUO3pC"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But let me push you on nuance specifically here. I was a lawyer for 20 minutes. I wasn’t any good at it. But my instinct is: of course the social media companies are arguing for a maximal interpretation of the First Amendment. That’s what their lawyers are paid to do. I just read the piece and it felt strange to me to say they were doing anything wrong. This is the argument because that’s what lawyers are meant to do.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BvjZTq"&gt;I guess that’s a fair point, although it’s notable that some of these companies, Facebook in particular, but not only Facebook, have been out there saying to Congress that they wanted regulation. “We want regulation.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YGNLBj"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Please regulate us.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vpAL1q"&gt;And at the same time, they’re going into these district courts around the country saying any regulation would be unconstitutional. So that seems like an important thing to note. And even if it’s not realistic to think that the companies are going to change their legal arguments, even if any reasonable person would expect financially motivated actors to make these kinds of arguments, it seems important to me to ensure that other people aren’t fooled when the platforms wrap themselves in the First Amendment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e4VDOS"&gt;We shouldn’t think that to support the First Amendment here necessarily means to support the platforms. The First Amendment might be something quite different from what the platforms are saying it is and might be something quite different from what the state governments are saying it is. There is this in-between space and we just want to make clear that being a champion of the First Amendment in this context doesn’t necessarily mean lining up behind the social media companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5ffp8P"&gt;So that’s a message not so much for the companies, but for others who are just trying to figure out what their views are on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yyOEs5"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I think that’s what I mean when I say it feels like things are going to come to a head in the next year or so. I would ordinarily assume that any First Amendment organization would similarly push for a maximal interpretation of the First Amendment in cases like this. And you’re saying, no, there’s a lot of nuance here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZTmmX3"&gt;First of all, I think that that phrase, “a maximalist understanding of the First Amendment,” is not a good way of understanding what’s going on here, because there are actually a lot of different free speech actors in the mix here. The platforms are asserting free speech rights. They say, “We are building an expressive community, we should get to decide what our expressive community looks like.” But the platform’s users are also asserting free speech rights. They’re saying, “This is the new public square and we have the right to participate in the new public square and we should be permitted to participate in that kind of conversation without interference on the basis of, for example, a viewpoint.” And then governments are also asserting a kind of free speech interest here when they say, “We need to protect the integrity of this public square. We need to make sure that this public square works for our democracy. We need to harness public discourse for democratic ends.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sgFPY5"&gt;And all of those are free speech arguments. And when you decide on what shape the First Amendment should take in this context, you have to take all of those interests into account, not just the company’s interests. So I don’t think it’s really a question of a maximalist understanding of the First Amendment versus a minimalist understanding of the First Amendment. It’s really a question of “What was the First Amendment really meant to protect?” What are the values that the First Amendment was meant to protect and what shape do we need to give the First Amendment to ensure that it serves those values?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="4krGfF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“In my view, the First Amendment was meant in large part to protect the process of self-government.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HMd96p"&gt;In my view, the First Amendment was meant in large part to protect the process of self-government. That means that it should accommodate regulations that are intended – and do actually – protect or strengthen the process of self-government, but it shouldn’t accommodate regulations that interfere with that process. So when we’re talking about regulations that are effectively state efforts to enlist the platforms in certain kinds of censorship, the First Amendment shouldn’t make room for those kinds of regulations. But it should make room for regulations that help all of us understand better what forces are shaping public discourse; for example, how the platforms are shaping public discourse through their editorial decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QYoCjf"&gt;That seems like something that the First Amendment should be not unsympathetic to, so long as the regulations are narrowly tailored and drafted in a way that doesn’t effectively give government actors the ability to rig the game. Now, whether any particular regulation should survive the kind of First Amendment review I just described, that’s going to be a hard question, and it’s not going to be a matter of just applying rules that we developed 50 years ago before anyone had even conceived of the internet to this extremely different context. It’s going to be going back to the values that animate the First Amendment and asking, again, what kinds of rules we need in place to give effect to those values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y0R11w"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The key line that really jumped out to me from your op-ed was, “The First Amendment should apply differently to social media companies than it does to newspapers because social media companies and newspapers exercise editorial judgment in different ways.” To me, this says there’s a test and if you’re doing X kind of editorial judgment, you get newspaper protection, and if you’re doing Y kind of editorial judgment, you get a lesser social media company protection. What’s the line?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h5Pohr"&gt;I actually regret that particular phrasing. What I meant to say, which is just a little bit different from what we did in fact say, was that it should matter how editorial discretion is exercised. It doesn’t matter whether it’s a platform exercising it or a newspaper exercising it, but it should matter how editorial discretion is exercised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SMgIdS"&gt;And here’s a very sort of concrete way of thinking about this. When my co-author Scott Wilkens and I submitted this op-ed to &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, we traded drafts with the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; three or four times. They wrote back to us and said, “Why are you using this word here? Why are you using this phrase here?” They had suggestions about the structure of the argument. They had suggestions about specific wording. They had questions about all of our claims. We went back and forth again several times, then they sent it to copy editors who also had comments on what we had written. Then they selected a title, and then they selected the placement of the op-ed on their website and they made a decision about whether to have it in the newspaper as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yxrq7r"&gt;And when they decided to put it in the newspaper, they decided where to put it in the newspaper, and they decided whether to attach a photograph to it. And all of those decisions were made by editors who were talking to one another about the kinds of things that we think about when we think about editorial judgment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="09rEOa"&gt;Platforms don’t do any of that. That doesn’t mean platforms aren’t engaged in editorial judgment as well. As we’ve been saying for the past 20 minutes: platforms do engage in editorial judgment, but they exercise it in a very different way. They exercise it through content moderation decisions, through community standards. They implement it both through human decision-makers and also through algorithmic ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wbWs3z"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can I just interrupt you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0TMCso"&gt;Yeah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I9BDUA"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This sounds like you’re saying there is a difference between a platform and a publisher, which are loaded phrases in the Section 230 debate, but you can see how this mirrors that kind of argument, right?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XMXUTV"&gt;No. I’m not sure it does. Let me just tell you what the argument is, and then you can decide whether it mirrors it or not. The argument is just that these two kinds of editorial decision-making look different, and, because they look different, it’s possible that any particular regulation that would burden the editorial judgment of &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; might not burden the editorial judgment of Twitter, or it might not burden it to the same extent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MpZjsj"&gt;That seems important to me because otherwise, if the question we’re going to ask every time Congress tries to regulate the platforms is, could they do this to &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;? We’re going to end up with no regulation at all — no due process regulation, no transparency regulation. Because, of course, Congress can’t say to &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, “Explain why you rejected this op-ed” or, “If you reject the op-ed, then you need to give the person who submitted it an opportunity to appeal the decision to the editor-in-chief.”It would be ridiculous for Congress to even propose something like that, but it’s not obvious at all to me that we should react the same way to those kinds of regulations when they’re proposed with respect to the platforms. I’m not the only one who thinks that; some of the platforms, too, have not just invited that kind of regulation, but have also already started to provide some of that transparency themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HjwD8J"&gt;If it were so offensive to the idea of editorial discretion that platforms should be required to provide that kind of transparency, it’s a little bit weird that they’re providing a degree of that kind of transparency already. So, the only argument we were trying to make is that these two kinds of entities exercise editorial discretion in different ways, and that might matter to the constitutionality of any particular regulation. It seems to me that should be noncontroversial, and that it has to be true. It cannot be the case that the First Amendment is indifferent to the nature of the editorial decision-making. It just wouldn’t make any sense. If that were the case, it wouldn’t make sense that the platforms are transparent in ways that newspapers never are. That seems like an important fact to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JC1eUL"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I’d push you on, though, is that your argument says there’s a set of actors that look like open access social media platforms and there’s a set of actors that look like &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The New York Times&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The Verge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;or&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Wired &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;magazine, and they’re different. What do you think are the differences?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BW8q3e"&gt;They’re doing different things. Yeah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BVNjq8"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the line? How would you define that, such that anybody could understand? We have a comment section, &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New York Times&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; has a comment section. That looks more like Facebook than not.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="WNpEDg"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“If &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; has a comment section, as it does, &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; looks a little bit more like a social media company.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Ofz3yI"&gt;Absolutely. Yes. That’s why I don’t think the line should be between newspapers and social media companies. The line should be drawn on the basis of the kind of editorial judgment that is being exercised in that particular context. If &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; has a comment section, as it does, &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; looks a little bit more like a social media company. In that particular context, what the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; is doing is something much more akin to what Facebook does in its main business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0qHcjZ"&gt;So I wouldn’t draw the line between newspapers and social media companies. I would draw it on the basis of the function. What function is the entity engaged in, in that particular context? Now, you might still ask the same question: how are you going to draw the lines based on function? I think the only way to answer that question is on a case-by-case basis. That’s what courts do. They draw those kinds of lines on the basis of case-by-case decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oMoExT"&gt;This is not a novel proposition, even on this question of which entities are exercising editorial judgment. There’s a long line of Supreme Court cases in which the court has given content to that phrase “editorial judgment,” through case-by-case decision making. There was a 1974 case, &lt;a href="http://oyez.org/cases/1973/73-797"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Miami Herald Publishing Company vs. Tornillo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, in which the court said that newspaper was exercising editorial judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eSLEKS"&gt;Then there was a case [12 years] later, [&lt;a href="https://www.oyez.org/cases/1985/84-1044"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pacific Gas &amp;amp; Electric Company v. Public Utilities Commission of California&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;], in which the Court said that a utility was exercising editorial judgment when it decided whether or not to include certain content in the envelopes that it sent to its subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vDKdzu"&gt;Then, a decade later, the Court said [in &lt;a href="https://www.oyez.org/cases/1994/94-749"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hurley v. Irish-American Gay, Lesbian Bisexual Group&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;] that a parade organizer was exercising editorial judgment in deciding who can be part of the parade or not. That’s case-by-case decision-making to figure out who is exercising editorial judgment, and you could have the same kind of case-by-case decision-making with respect to what kinds of burdens on editorial judgment are constitutionally permissible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A5JGph"&gt;The only argument I’m making here is that the kinds of burdens that are constitutionally permissible might turn on whether you’re regulating a parade, or a utility, or a newspaper engaged in traditional newspaper activities, or a social media company engaged in traditional social media activities. That seems to me that it’s got to be right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ee5Acs"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I feel you on that. I’m looking at the attempts at definitions, across the whole policy landscape. And those attempts at definitions keep crashing into the rocks, right?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J5T2P0"&gt;Yeah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lkJL0j"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Federal Trade Commission tries to sue Facebook for being a monopoly social media provider. They cannot even define the market that Facebook operates in, so their lawsuit failed. They failed on the first cut of defining the market for Facebook’s services. I’m looking at the Florida and Texas laws. Florida’s famously has an extremely corrupt definition, excluding people who own a theme park, so that Disney would not be hit by this law.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WcT2Px"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Even on the first cut — what is a social media company? — the government seems to be flailing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FM4BRs"&gt;That’s true, but you do not have to be a particularly sophisticated First Amendment expert to understand that the Disney exception was not going to fly, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VzZvN6"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yeah.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q627V9"&gt;To some extent, the bad definitions are a reflection of bad motivations, but there are more serious efforts, especially at the federal level. There is a draft bill that Sens. Coons, Portman, and Klobuchar issued last week that deals almost entirely with transparency issues, and it would require the platforms to share certain kinds of data with researchers. It would provide that kind of safe harbor for journalists and researchers who study the platforms. In my view, it’s very, very carefully done. I’m not sure that it couldn’t be improved. I’m sure that there are tweaks that could be made that would make it stronger, both as a matter of effectiveness and as a matter of standing up to a First Amendment challenge. To me that seems like a very serious effort at drafting regulation that would strengthen democratic values online, and shouldn’t be understood as an affront to the First Amendment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TF3xO1"&gt;It may be that the first wave of these laws, like the Florida and Texas laws, just don’t go anywhere, for good reasons, but I don’t think we should take that to mean that no regulation is possible here, or no regulation is likely to survive First Amendment scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QCooBi"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There’s another view in the tech industry that I actually hear quite a bit. It’s surprising to me, especially because, as you say, the platform’s lawyers are in court arguing for these very expansive First Amendment interpretations. However, the other view is, “Boy, the First Amendment is annoying. I wish the United States would be more like Germany, and just write a speech code that says Nazis are illegal, and here’s some speech that’s illegal, and write the content moderation standards for us. Because us trying to do it is an endless pain point. And I, Mark Zuckerberg, am tired of it. I’m going to rename my company to Meta, and do metaverse stuff instead of thinking about speech regulation at scale, which is an impossible problem.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z5sBEI"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s a more common view than I ever expected. I think that’s a horrible answer, but I hear it a lot. Do you think there’s a way for the United States to actually do something like that for this set of companies, if you can define them?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0f6JXu"&gt;Do something like that, meaning impose that kind of speech code?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4PW8Wp"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c8iLMg"&gt;No. I don’t see the First Amendment as an obstacle to good ideas in this space, but it is an obstacle to some bad ideas. I would put that one on my list of bad ideas. Anybody who actually finds this proposal appealing should just think about how that power would’ve been used had the last administration had it. If President Trump had the power to define, for example, vaccine misinformation, how would President Trump have defined that phrase? What would the speech code have looked like for the platforms?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BXp5eC"&gt;I suspect that the people who think that the imposition of a speech code would solve our problems here maybe haven’t thought very deeply about what that speech code would actually look like, and who would get to write it, and who would get to enforce it. I think that, on this particular point, we’re very lucky to have the First Amendment because it protects us from exactly that so-called solution to the problem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OFB5Hg"&gt;Obviously the companies disagree with me on this point, but I don’t think the First Amendment is an obstacle to the kinds of regulations that actually make sense, that would actually do something to address real problems. I keep going back to transparency, privacy, and due process, but there are others as well, like interoperability, for example. If Congress wanted to do something on interoperability that gave developers the right to build on top of the digital infrastructure that the big technology companies have created, I don’t think the First Amendment would be an obstacle to that, and that might actually do a lot to address issues relating to monopoly power. Similarly, in privacy law, creating privacy protections that limited what the companies can collect and how they can use that information would have a direct impact on privacy, but also on the quality of our speech environment because it’s all that data that feeds micro-targeting or nano-targeting of messages that often contain misinformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bnd48C"&gt;So, when I think through the kinds of non-viewpoint discriminatory proposals that we have now mentioned several times — Congress could actually improve our speech environment in very significant ways without generating serious First Amendment issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uOZTz0"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I want to end on a big idea. You started by saying these are the new public squares. The users of these platforms have an interest too. I think most people in America are more often touched by YouTube’s content moderation policies than any state or federal law. People are more aware of YouTube copyright strikes than maybe even the speed limit around them, right? The platforms and their rules are in your face all the time as you use the internet. Supreme Court Justice Clarence Thomas wrote &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/orders/courtorders/040521zor_3204.pdf?utm_campaign=04_18_2021&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=tpfp_newsletter"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;in a concurrence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; that we should just call social media companies common carriers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ov0BWM"&gt;Yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CMinqI"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We should use this other language from telecom law and just leave the First Amendment entirely and start regulating these companies as utilities, like the phone company. We’re also talking in the context of a Supreme Court that seems poised to flip 50 years of &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roe v. Wade&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; precedent. This court seems more willing to leave some precedent behind. A lot of the First Amendment precedent that we’re talking about is really only 70 years old. The notion of strict scrutiny is 70 years old. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5805ka"&gt;Yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8tbPzk"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So it just seems like there’s also room for another method here of thinking about how to regulate these platforms that almost has nothing to do with the First Amendment — escapes it entirely — but might lead to other significant kinds of consequences. Do you see that as a danger? Do you see that as an opportunity? How do you think about that?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nl3m40"&gt;It doesn’t seem obvious to me that this would avoid First Amendment issues. I think it would just generate its own set of First Amendment challenges because the platforms would argue that they are not, in fact, common carriers. They have never held themselves out to the entire public in the way that common carriers are usually thought to do. To the contrary, the platforms all have community standards or something akin to community standards, and they all have content moderation policies, and that makes them look very different from something like AT&amp;amp;T, which really is open to all comers. Now, there’s a certain kind of historical circularity to that argument, but the fact remains that these platforms do, in fact, exercise a great deal of editorial discretion. In fact, that’s what a lot of people are complaining about: that they’re exercising editorial discretion. But, the fact that they’re exercising editorial discretion makes them look different from railways and the telecoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1BEs7k"&gt;I’m not sure how far that argument goes as a matter of legal doctrine or common sense, but you’re right that Justice Thomas expressed some enthusiasm for it in that concurrence, in the Trump Twitter case, and appeals court judges have also expressed some enthusiasm for it. Florida and Texas are both, to some extent, relying on the common carrier argument. Eugene Volokh — who is a legal scholar who’s sometimes associated with libertarianism — has this argument that, to the extent the social media platforms are just hosting, they can be characterized as common carriers. It’s not obvious to me that that distinction is actually a workable one. Can you actually draw the line between hosting and everything else that the platforms do? That seems complicated to me, but maybe conceptually there’s some value in distinguishing these two functions. I don’t know, but I don’t think that just asserting that the platforms are common carriers is going to get us out of the First Amendment world. To the contrary, it’s just going to raise a whole other set of First Amendment questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OuUr53"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As somebody who has covered net neutrality for 10 years, I have to say, just the phrase “common carrier” lights my brain on fire. Where do you think this goes next? What should people be looking for over the course of the next year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JHMKO7"&gt;There are going to be these two appeals court arguments and decisions over the next few months. The Florida case is first. The 11th Circuit is going to hear this case early next year, and then the Fifth Circuit will hear the Texas case, if not in the spring, then I think early in the summer. It’s entirely conceivable that one of those cases goes up to the Supreme Court, but even if they don’t, I think those decisions will end up shaping the legislative debate both at the state and federal level over the next year or two, because those courts are going to start to sketch out what the First Amendment means in this particular context, and legislatures will then have to take into account the limits those courts have put in place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8mi248"&gt;That’s why we filed the brief we did in the Florida case. We really want to make sure that the courts understand the implications of accepting the arguments that the companies are making here, and that if you accept those arguments, you’re not just ruling out the Florida and Texas laws. You’re ruling out any other conceivable legislation that legislatures might come up with in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YnXufe"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Great. Well, Jameel, this has been really illuminating. Thank you for coming on &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decoder&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="TOIjA3"&gt;Thank you. Happy to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="zY10oR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Decoder with Nilay Patel","description":"A podcast from The Verge about big ideas and other problems.","label":"Subscribe now!","url":"https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/decoder-with-nilay-patel/id1011668648?i=1000496212371"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22838473/social-media-first-amendment-regulation-section-230-decoder-podcast"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22838473/social-media-first-amendment-regulation-section-230-decoder-podcast</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nilay Patel</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T09:58:59-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T09:58:59-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s latest AirPods are currently cheaper than they were on Black Friday</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-II7Ukqd8GJx6lHJo0VIACbTo5I=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70281083/akrales_190327_3315_0019.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple’s second-gen AirPods are just $89.99 right now at Amazon.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EQuJMI"&gt;Apple’s AirPods are always a popular gift, but they can be expensive, regardless of which model you opt for. Thankfully, you can currently nab the entry-level model for less than $100, making them a great present for friends and family if you don’t mind waiting until &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; the holidays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WcMZA1"&gt;Right now, Amazon is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-AirPods-Charging-Latest-Model/dp/B07PXGQC1Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;selling Apple’s second-gen AirPods&lt;/a&gt; with delayed shipping for $89.99, matching their lowest price to date. It’s also less than what we saw them for on Black Friday and Cyber Monday, when they were selling for around $110. The last-gen earbuds may be older and lack the wireless charging case found on the more expensive configuration, but they still offer great wireless performance, reliable battery life, and excellent ease of use, making them a terrific pick for Apple users shopping on a budget. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/29/18286012/apple-airpods-2-new-2nd-gen-review-price-specs-features"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our full review.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="e8OiQT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the shipping deadlines to get your holiday gifts there on time","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22833986/ups-usps-fedex-amazon-walmart-best-buy-target-shipping-deadlines-2021"},{"title":"Which AirPods model should you buy?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/19/22733797/airpods-2-3-pro-max-which-to-buy"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="oQz2aL"&gt;Of course, if you prefer the newer third-gen buds, which offer IPX4 water resistance and MagSafe charging compatibility, they’ve also plunged to their lowest price to date. Normally $179, Apple’s third-gen AirPods are &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B09JQL3NWT?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently on sale at Amazon for $139.99&lt;/a&gt;, which is the price we saw them going for on Black Friday. Just keep in mind that they may not ship until after Christmas, meaning they’d likely make for a belated gift. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22744686/apple-airpods-third-gen-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our full review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ND6NaP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="mEO1Uv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10887582"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XxOP0O"&gt;Speaking of all-time lows, if you’re on the hunt for a great, lightweight laptop that’s under $1,000, Amazon is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Microsoft-Surface-Laptop-Touch-Screen-Ryzen/dp/B08YWX4W7G?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently selling Microsoft’s Surface Laptop 4&lt;/a&gt; at its lowest price ever. Regularly $999.99, right now you can pick up the 13.5-inch configuration for $877.79, a $122 discount. To get this deal, you need to select the model that comes with a 256GB SSD, an AMD Ryzen 5 5600X&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;6-core CPU, and 8GB of RAM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HRSXAE"&gt;Note this is the smaller, less powerful version of the 15-inch model that comes with the Ryzen 7 4980U chip we tested, which we praised for its excellent battery life and performance. Nonetheless, it’s still a good laptop with a mid-tier processor that’s fine for streaming shows, using social media, and carrying out other everyday tasks. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22392778/microsoft-surface-laptop-4-15-inch-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our full review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iQHmdq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10882775"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2LnLzf"&gt;Shifting away from laptops to e-readers, Amazon’s kid-friendly Kindle Paperwhite makes for a great holiday gift both children and parents will love. It’s a fun way to get a child into reading that’s ad-free and comes with parental controls, and right now it’s selling at its second-best price to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f7dvdL"&gt;Typically $159.99, Amazon is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08WPB8PW9/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;currently selling the new Kindle Paperwhite Kids&lt;/a&gt;, which comes with a bigger display and a USB-C port, for $119.99 in all colorways and designs. That’s just $5 more than the price we saw on Black Friday. The waterproof e-reader, released only a few months ago, also comes with a one-year subscription to Amazon Kids Plus, which provides access to thousands of kid-friendly books as well as hundreds of Audible audiobooks. Amazon is also throwing in a two-year warranty, so if it breaks, you can return it and the company will replace it for free. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22745670/amazon-kindle-paperwhite-2021-review-usb-c-signature-edition-display-e-reader-books"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our full 2021 Kindle Paperwhite review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="saCmT0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10765369"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="05Un3F"&gt;As we get closer to the holidays, several retailers are selling discounted gaming-related gift cards that can come in handy whether you’re looking for a present or you just want to save some money. Now through December 17th, Costco members can buy a &lt;a href="https://www.costco.com/nintendo-eshop-%2450-digital-card.product.100431276.html"&gt;$50 digital Nintendo eShop gift card for $39.99&lt;/a&gt; or a &lt;a href="https://www.costco.com/xbox-%24100-gift-card-digital-download.product.100524149.html"&gt;$100 digital Xbox gift card for $79.99&lt;/a&gt;, the latter of which can be applied toward both current and next-gen titles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="YbomSw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10926235"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="kt5FXu"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10506009"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rALVbI"&gt;If you’re on the hunt for budget-friendly gifts you can still get before the holidays, today’s discount on the new Roku Express 4K Plus may be worth a look. Typically $39.99, the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Roku-Express-Streaming-Wireless-Controls/dp/B0916TKFF2?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;streaming stick is going for $24 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, which is an all-time low and $5 less than the Black Friday price. In comparison to its predecessor, the Roku Premiere, the entry-level 4K streamer comes with a faster processor and increased internal storage. It also offers support for HDR10 Plus and AirPlay 2, while sporting features like dual-band Wi-Fi and the ability to attach a Micro-USB-to-ethernet adapter if you’d prefer a wired connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="hzamnT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10925733"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="pxIi1v"&gt;Some other great deals worth checking out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="0XNCWu"&gt;As a part of its holiday sale, B&amp;amp;H Photo is &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1668450-REG%2Fapple_mj2c3ll_a_homepod_mini_blue.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F2021%2F12%2F16%2F22837670%2Fapple-airpods-microsoft-surface-4-kindle-paperwhite-xbox-gift-card-roku-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;offering a rare discount on Apple’s HomePod Mini&lt;/a&gt;, selling the smart speaker in various colors for $94.99 instead of $99.99. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21561589/apple-homepod-mini-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read our full review.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="JrVo13"&gt;In the market for an affordable TV? Amazon is currently discounting its lineup of 4-Series Fire TVs, selling the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08P3QB66R?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;55-inch model for $379.99&lt;/a&gt; instead of $519.99. The retailer is also throwing in a third-gen Echo Dot when you use promo code &lt;strong&gt;FTVDOT21.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="GTl02h"&gt;Amazon Prime members can enjoy 10 percent off of all deals available in the &lt;a href="https://www.jdoqocy.com/click-8836598-13144945?sid=TheVergeDailyRoundUp121621&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.woot.com%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Woot!&lt;/a&gt; app today, December 16th. Prime subscribers can also &lt;a href="https://www.dpbolvw.net/click-8836598-13093667?sid=TheVergeDailyDeals121621&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fforums.woot.com%2Ft%2Fprime-exclusive-free-two-day-shipping-12-15-21-12-19-21%2F908420" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;take advantage of free two-day shipping&lt;/a&gt; on select items between now and December 19th.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="4cqHfd"&gt;You can get a free $10 Best Buy gift card when you buy a &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/cgdkAtL6TLr" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$100 digital Google Play gift card&lt;/a&gt; at Best Buy. And if you buy a &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/1221032/2092?subId1=TheVergeDailyDeals121621&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fapple-gift-card%25E2%2580%2594100%25E2%2580%2594email-delivery-%2F-%2FA-80893567" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$100 digital Apple gift card&lt;/a&gt; from Target, the retailer will throw in a digital $10 gift card to Target.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="rdAyxR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="WbRtLZ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fh7vPO"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/12/16/22837670/apple-airpods-microsoft-surface-4-kindle-paperwhite-xbox-gift-card-roku-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/12/16/22837670/apple-airpods-microsoft-surface-4-kindle-paperwhite-xbox-gift-card-roku-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T09:51:23-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T09:51:23-05:00</updated>
    <title>Final Fantasy XIV sales suspended to try to help server congestion</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Z5xV6fq-WYIdqGIkSzLEKcbpQGw=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70281053/FFXIV_PUB_DIGITAL_FANFESTIVAL_2021_32.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XIV’s latest expansion pack launched this month.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Square Enix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VKdVR9"&gt;Square Enix has temporarily halted sales of &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XIV&lt;/em&gt;’s Starter and Complete editions, in an attempt to ease the server congestion that’s been plaguing the game since the release of its &lt;em&gt;Endwalker &lt;/em&gt;expansion. Writing in a &lt;a href="https://na.finalfantasyxiv.com/lodestone/news/detail/e7388986bc24d5a1337e0beed057f7b5b78b9bb3"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, the game’s producer and director Naoki Yoshida said the company is halting deliveries of the physical version of the game, digital sales, and is also suspending registrations for the game’s free trial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FgAN1J"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Endwalker &lt;/em&gt;released in early access on December 3rd and got an official release days later on December 7th. But limited server capacity has meant that players have often found themselves &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822793/final-fantasy-14-endwalker-early-access-server-queues"&gt;having to wait hours&lt;/a&gt; just to log into the game and have been stuck in queues of upward of 4,000–8,000 other players. As recently as last night, the game’s servers appeared to collapse completely under the load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GG8TE3"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We'd like to share an update from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FFXIV?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#FFXIV&lt;/a&gt; Producer &amp;amp; Director Naoki Yoshida on the ongoing congestion, additional game time compensation, suspension of sales, error codes, and our upcoming plans. &lt;a href="https://t.co/3WcXX6eVkf"&gt;https://t.co/3WcXX6eVkf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— FINAL FANTASY XIV (@FF_XIV_EN) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FF_XIV_EN/status/1471345410245464067?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7yh7E2"&gt;Yoshida says the sales suspensions will be “phased in over the next few days” and apologizes to potential customers who are losing out, as well as the company’s retail partners. He adds that new ads for the game are also being stopped, but that “Expansion packs and Collector’s Edition digital upgrades will continue to be available for existing players so that they may upgrade as needed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="siDL3t"&gt;In more normal times, a company like Square Enix would try to fix these capacity issues by investing in new servers. But &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XIV&lt;/em&gt;’s explosion in popularity has coincided with a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22777216/global-chip-supply-chain-shortage-holidays-christmas-shopping"&gt;global chip shortage&lt;/a&gt; that’s gotten in the way of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/7/22822825/final-fantasy-xiv-14-endwalker-global-chip-shortage-server-queue"&gt;Square Enix buying new server hardware&lt;/a&gt;. Yoshida reports that the company is “starting to see some progress” as it builds out its server capacity and says it hopes to provide a roadmap by January 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y5bwdj"&gt;The suspension follows similar action taken in July this year following a similar increase in new players, &lt;a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-14-digital-sales-stopped"&gt;&lt;em&gt;IGN&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; at the time. But this wasn’t officially announced by Square Enix, and it’s unclear whether physical sales were also affected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LboAYc"&gt;As well as the server capacity issues, Yoshida’s post also offers more details on the frustrating “Error 2002” bug, which has cropped up for players even after they’ve waited hours in virtual queues. A patch to address this bug is scheduled for release on December 21st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rzdkyd"&gt;Although fixes are underway, Square Enix has its work cut out if it wants to solve its MMO’s problems before it risks seeing frustrated players drift away. As an apology, Yoshida says the company is giving all players who own the full game and have an active subscription an additional 14 days of free playtime. This comes in addition to the seven days granted &lt;a href="https://eu.finalfantasyxiv.com/lodestone/news/detail/100b4b0f4ab853c7089ab68239a8505e75541ab1"&gt;earlier this month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cG2tPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0ekW2d"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839415/final-fantasy-14-sales-suspended-servers-over-capacity-digital-physical"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839415/final-fantasy-14-sales-suspended-servers-over-capacity-digital-physical</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T09:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T09:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Final Fantasy VII Remake on PC just about gets the job done</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Jk05V7_6iS0LoZj_QavEOIRj_jA=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70280972/FF7R_Episode_INTERmission_PC_Yuffie___Small_JPEG.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="sCjiKV"&gt;There was a time when PC versions of Japanese games tended to be terrible, if they existed at all. But in recent years, Japanese publishers have put more effort into their ports. They’re not always the most full-featured conversions, but games like &lt;em&gt;Monster Hunter World&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XV&lt;/em&gt; are great examples of titles that run much better on PC than their console equivalents. The days of games like &lt;em&gt;Dark Souls&lt;/em&gt; locking PC users to low resolutions and frame rates are mostly over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vgAoaL"&gt;The long-anticipated PC version of &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade&lt;/em&gt;, which launches today, isn’t exactly an example of the latter. But it doesn’t feel well-tailored to the PC either. If you’ve been waiting to play this game because you don’t have a PS4 or a PS5, it’ll probably give you a reasonable version of the console experience. It just won’t go any further than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="nHLH9h"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10927176"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hPhYTb"&gt;First, the good news. Unlike some recent PlayStation-to-PC ports, &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/em&gt; feels well-optimized for the PC from a performance standpoint. I tested the game on my own PC that I built more than five years ago, which has an Intel Core i5-6600K processor, an Nvidia GTX 1080 GPU, and 16GB of RAM, and had no problem running it at 1440p and 60 frames per second on “high” settings even though it was installed to a spinning hard drive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CNy3n9"&gt;This isn’t necessarily surprising. &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake &lt;/em&gt;is often an amazingly beautiful game, but its linear, enclosed levels feel designed with 2013 console hardware in mind, so it would have been disappointing not to get better performance even out of an aging PC. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Aw8aq2cHBVRXOjM0fMf3CN_CR7U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23101028/FF7R_Intergrade_PC_Barret___Small_JPEG.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5go3iX"&gt;What &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; disappointing is that you won’t get much better performance out of a much better PC. This version of &lt;em&gt;Remake&lt;/em&gt; has very few graphical options, and you’re forced to pick between fixed frame rate caps — it can run at 30fps, 60fps, 90fps, or 120fps. I tried running it at 90fps to see how things would hold up and the image quality was much blurrier, so it looks like dynamic resolution scaling is being applied. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I5WWjK"&gt;Better PCs should be able to run the game at 120fps with higher resolution, then, but the actual assets aren’t going to look any better. Other than basic output resolution and some HDR settings, the only other options you have are low and high texture resolution, low and high shadow resolution, and the ability to limit the number of characters on-screen to between one and 10. There is also no ultrawide support at all; which, again, I’m not really surprised at given how frequently the game bounces between pre-rendered cutscenes and real-time action, but it’s unfortunate nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="dXahF0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Final Fantasy VII Remake’s directors wanted to show ‘a new side’ of Midgar with Yuffie chapter","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22565517/final-fantasy-7-remake-intermission-intergrade-yuffie-interview-ps5"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XE75TO"&gt;Texture resolution was a major flaw with the original PS4 release, though it was improved with the &lt;em&gt;Intergrade&lt;/em&gt; update for the PS5. You’ll still see the odd blurry texture here and there on PC, but it’s a much better situation than when I played for the first time on the PS4 Pro. Most importantly, I can confirm that Cloud’s bedroom door no longer looks like it came from an N64 game — though his sink is still conspicuously blocky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Ls3Hk"&gt;All of this adds up to a port that does the bare minimum to run well on PC hardware. It’s not a showcase for the platform in any way — it’s a showcase for how great a console game &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/em&gt; was. And, well, I have to admit that that’s been my takeaway from playing through the PC version this week. It could have been a more thoughtful port, sure, but this game is still incredibly good and runs better than it did on the PS4, which is something. It’s worth checking out if you haven’t played it on the PS4, but I wouldn’t recommend double-dipping if you have a PS5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9JfSOa"&gt;&lt;small&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade &lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;will be released today on the Epic Games Store.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22839361/final-fantasy-7-remake-pc-review-epic-game-store"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22839361/final-fantasy-7-remake-pc-review-epic-game-store</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Fortnite’s holiday event has a frozen banana and Tom Holland</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BkKrBfqKW_1hkqC3l64RagW5f8A=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70280840/19BR_WF_SpiderMan_MJ_Outfits.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Ax7gc8"&gt;It’s that time of the year — when you get free gifts in &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;. Developer Epic Games has detailed this year’s big holiday event, where players have two weeks’ worth of daily quests to complete in order to unlock free items. That includes things like a frozen version of Peely the banana — I’m not sure if the ice makes him &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22666922/apple-epic-peely-naked-banana-judgement"&gt;more or less naked than normal&lt;/a&gt; — and a new character called Krisabelle, who is basically a winter-themed version of an existing in-game witch. There are a total of 14 things to collect, and you have until January 6th at 9AM ET to get them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5akI3Y"&gt;Outside of all the free stuff, there will also be new items in the shop tonight tied to the release of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22834061/spider-man-no-way-home-review-tom-holland-marvel-multiverse"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: No Way Home&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. That includes the Tom Holland version of Spidey, along with MJ. (This is the second time this year a Zendaya character is in &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;, after &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Atheverge.com+dune+fortnite&amp;amp;rlz=1C5CHFA_enCA717CA718&amp;amp;oq=site%3Atheverge.com+dune+fortnite&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57j69i58.3873j0j4&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8"&gt;the &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt; update in October&lt;/a&gt;.) There will also be a handful of gameplay tweaks over the holidays, as Epic is bringing back items like the Sneaky Snowman and snowball launcher.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sJGuKg1Bkscl7UIwVXrBtyDYTs4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23099713/19BR_WF_PolarPeely_Krisabelle.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fGujKB"&gt;It’s a busy time for the battle royale. &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; just wrapped up its second chapter with a huge event that saw the previous island flip over, before it revealed a brand-new map a day later. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/5/22817392/fortnite-chapter-3-season-1-spider-man-new-island"&gt;The current season has introduced new features like web-slinging, sliding, and persistent camps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22838346/fortnite-holiday-event-2021-spider-man-tom-holland"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22838346/fortnite-holiday-event-2021-spider-man-tom-holland</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Nvidia’s $200-a-year RTX 3080 in the cloud is ditching the waitlist today</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gtbAGqCPdlEbfB-5bVRcobHF78g=/147x0:1167x680/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70280826/GeForce_NOW_Ecosystem_5168761692b8ce49157.58524673.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Nvidia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="t1at7h"&gt;Nvidia’s GeForce Now cloud gaming service got a huge upgrade this October with its RTX 3080 tier. “Nvidia just kicked Google’s butt,” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22750246/nvidia-geforce-now-rtx-3080-google-stadia-cloud-gaming"&gt;I declared at the time&lt;/a&gt;. My colleague Tom Warren &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/1466426066541682688"&gt;was wowed as well&lt;/a&gt;. But if you went to sign up, you might have found yourself facing a &lt;em&gt;preorder &lt;/em&gt;page — yes, preorders to effectively rent time on a server in the cloud. Today, that should no longer be a problem: &lt;a href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/2021/12/16/geforce-now-thursday-december-16/"&gt;Nvidia now says&lt;/a&gt; the RTX 3080 waitlist is gone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sIHKPT"&gt;To catch you up, Nvidia’s GeForce Now is a bring-your-own-games service that supports many (but definitely not all) of your existing Steam, Epic, and Ubisoft Connect / Uplay PC games, letting you play them over the internet from what’s effectively an Nvidia GPU-equipped gaming PC in the cloud. You can stream them to an aging Windows laptop, MacBook, Android phone, or even iPhones using a web browser workaround, as well as set-top boxes like Nvidia’s own Shield TV and Shield TV Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="uEmwFS"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Nvidia’s three tiers are not equal&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zaCv1X"&gt;If you’re interested, I’d highly recommend &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-us%2Fgeforce-now%2Fmemberships&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F16%2F22838807%2Fnvidia-geforce-now-rtx-3080-preorder-waitlist-gone" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;testing out the free tier of GeForce Now first&lt;/a&gt; to make sure you’re within range of Nvidia’s servers and that your home internet and Wi-Fi is competent. Still, you should know that Nvidia’s three tiers are &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; not created equal — not only is the new 3080 tier the only one that’s going to competently deliver 1440p and beyond gaming on new titles, the latency is greatly reduced. It’s just a better experience all around, and I’m starting to think Nvidia should give you a taste of that instead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cnaXIM"&gt;You should know that you’ll only get the best streaming quality — 4K — if you’ve got Nvidia’s own Shield TV set-top box or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/28/20935215/nvidia-shield-tv-2019-review-streaming-stick-dolby-vision-4k-price-specs-features"&gt;tube-shaped HDMI dongle&lt;/a&gt;, because Nvidia hasn’t expanded that offering to any other devices yet. Perhaps that’s why Nvidia’s offering $20 (or £20, or €25, or $30 CAD)&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;off both of those devices this week. (You can find that same price on the Shield TV tube fairly often, but it’s rare to get a sale on the Shield TV Pro.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MPlg89"&gt;For now, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22788555/nvidia-geforce-now-crysis-remastered-free-bundle"&gt;you’ll also get a free copy of &lt;em&gt;Crysis Remastered&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; when you sign up for a paid subscription. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S1Bgwg"&gt;I can’t wholeheartedly recommend GeForce Now yet because it doesn’t play quite enough of my Steam library and I &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; manage to get my hands on a new video card for my PC, but I could see others diving in who can’t find or afford them right now. If you do wind up diving in and loving or hating it, would you drop me a line next spring?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="np5lMI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Hands-on: Nvidia’s GeForce Now just leapfrogged Google Stadia","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22750246/nvidia-geforce-now-rtx-3080-google-stadia-cloud-gaming"},{"title":"Amazon Luna runs on Windows — and yet it’s hiring Linux gaming engineers","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22827185/amazon-luna-linux-windows-proton-cloud-gaming-jobs-hiring"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22838807/nvidia-geforce-now-rtx-3080-preorder-waitlist-gone"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22838807/nvidia-geforce-now-rtx-3080-preorder-waitlist-gone</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
