<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-12-16T09:30:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T09:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T09:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Final Fantasy VII Remake on PC just about gets the job done</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Jk05V7_6iS0LoZj_QavEOIRj_jA=/300x0:3540x2160/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70280972/FF7R_Episode_INTERmission_PC_Yuffie___Small_JPEG.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="sCjiKV"&gt;There was a time when PC versions of Japanese games tended to be terrible, if they existed at all. But in recent years, Japanese publishers have put more effort into their ports. They’re not always the most full-featured conversions, but games like &lt;em&gt;Monster Hunter World&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XV&lt;/em&gt; are great examples of titles that run much better on PC than their console equivalents. The days of games like &lt;em&gt;Dark Souls&lt;/em&gt; locking PC users to low resolutions and frame rates are mostly over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vgAoaL"&gt;The long-anticipated PC version of &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade&lt;/em&gt;, which launches today, isn’t exactly an example of the latter. But it doesn’t feel well-tailored to the PC either. If you’ve been waiting to play this game because you don’t have a PS4 or a PS5, it’ll probably give you a reasonable version of the console experience. It just won’t go any further than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="nHLH9h"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10927176"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hPhYTb"&gt;First, the good news. Unlike some recent PlayStation-to-PC ports, &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/em&gt; feels well-optimized for the PC from a performance standpoint. I tested the game on my own PC that I built more than five years ago, which has an Intel Core i5-6600K processor, an Nvidia GTX 1080 GPU, and 16GB of RAM, and had no problem running it at 1440p and 60 frames per second on “high” settings even though it was installed to a spinning hard drive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CNy3n9"&gt;This isn’t necessarily surprising. &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake &lt;/em&gt;is often an amazingly beautiful game, but its linear, enclosed levels feel designed with 2013 console hardware in mind, so it would have been disappointing not to get better performance even out of an aging PC. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Aw8aq2cHBVRXOjM0fMf3CN_CR7U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23101028/FF7R_Intergrade_PC_Barret___Small_JPEG.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="5go3iX"&gt;What &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; disappointing is that you won’t get much better performance out of a much better PC. This version of &lt;em&gt;Remake&lt;/em&gt; has very few graphical options, and you’re forced to pick between fixed frame rate caps — it can run at 30fps, 60fps, 90fps, or 120fps. I tried running it at 90fps to see how things would hold up and the image quality was much blurrier, so it looks like dynamic resolution scaling is being applied. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I5WWjK"&gt;Better PCs should be able to run the game at 120fps with higher resolution, then, but the actual assets aren’t going to look any better. Other than basic output resolution and some HDR settings, the only other options you have are low and high texture resolution, low and high shadow resolution, and the ability to limit the number of characters on-screen to between one and 10. There is also no ultrawide support at all; which, again, I’m not really surprised at given how frequently the game bounces between pre-rendered cutscenes and real-time action, but it’s unfortunate nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="dXahF0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Final Fantasy VII Remake’s directors wanted to show ‘a new side’ of Midgar with Yuffie chapter","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22565517/final-fantasy-7-remake-intermission-intergrade-yuffie-interview-ps5"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XE75TO"&gt;Texture resolution was a major flaw with the original PS4 release, though it was improved with the &lt;em&gt;Intergrade&lt;/em&gt; update for the PS5. You’ll still see the odd blurry texture here and there on PC, but it’s a much better situation than when I played for the first time on the PS4 Pro. Most importantly, I can confirm that Cloud’s bedroom door no longer looks like it came from an N64 game — though his sink is still conspicuously blocky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Ls3Hk"&gt;All of this adds up to a port that does the bare minimum to run well on PC hardware. It’s not a showcase for the platform in any way — it’s a showcase for how great a console game &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/em&gt; was. And, well, I have to admit that that’s been my takeaway from playing through the PC version this week. It could have been a more thoughtful port, sure, but this game is still incredibly good and runs better than it did on the PS4, which is still something. It’s worth checking out if you haven’t played it on the PS4, but I wouldn’t recommend double-dipping if you have a PS5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9JfSOa"&gt;&lt;small&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade &lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;will be released today on the Epic Games Store.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22839361/final-fantasy-7-remake-pc-review-epic-game-store"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22839361/final-fantasy-7-remake-pc-review-epic-game-store</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Fortnite’s holiday event has a frozen banana and Tom Holland</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BkKrBfqKW_1hkqC3l64RagW5f8A=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70280840/19BR_WF_SpiderMan_MJ_Outfits.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Ax7gc8"&gt;It’s that time of the year — when you get free gifts in &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;. Developer Epic Games has detailed this year’s big holiday event, where players have two weeks’ worth of daily quests to complete in order to unlock free items. That includes things like a frozen version of Peely the banana — I’m not sure if the ice makes him &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/10/22666922/apple-epic-peely-naked-banana-judgement"&gt;more or less naked than normal&lt;/a&gt; — and a new character called Krisabelle, who is basically a winter-themed version of an existing in-game witch. There are a total of 14 things to collect, and you have until January 6th at 9AM ET to get them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5akI3Y"&gt;Outside of all the free stuff, there will also be new items in the shop tonight tied to the release of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/14/22834061/spider-man-no-way-home-review-tom-holland-marvel-multiverse"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: No Way Home&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. That includes the Tom Holland version of Spidey, along with MJ. (This is the second time this year a Zendaya character is in &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;, after &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Atheverge.com+dune+fortnite&amp;amp;rlz=1C5CHFA_enCA717CA718&amp;amp;oq=site%3Atheverge.com+dune+fortnite&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57j69i58.3873j0j4&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8"&gt;the &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt; update in October&lt;/a&gt;.) There will also be a handful of gameplay tweaks over the holidays, as Epic is bringing back items like the Sneaky Snowman and snowball launcher.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sJGuKg1Bkscl7UIwVXrBtyDYTs4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23099713/19BR_WF_PolarPeely_Krisabelle.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fGujKB"&gt;It’s a busy time for the battle royale. &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; just wrapped up its second chapter with a huge event that saw the previous island flip over, before it revealed a brand-new map a day later. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/5/22817392/fortnite-chapter-3-season-1-spider-man-new-island"&gt;The current season has introduced new features like web-slinging, sliding, and persistent camps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22838346/fortnite-holiday-event-2021-spider-man-tom-holland"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22838346/fortnite-holiday-event-2021-spider-man-tom-holland</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Nvidia’s $200-a-year RTX 3080 in the cloud is ditching the waitlist today</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gtbAGqCPdlEbfB-5bVRcobHF78g=/147x0:1167x680/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70280826/GeForce_NOW_Ecosystem_5168761692b8ce49157.58524673.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Nvidia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="t1at7h"&gt;Nvidia’s GeForce Now cloud gaming service got a huge upgrade this October with its RTX 3080 tier. “Nvidia just kicked Google’s butt,” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22750246/nvidia-geforce-now-rtx-3080-google-stadia-cloud-gaming"&gt;I declared at the time&lt;/a&gt;. My colleague Tom Warren &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/1466426066541682688"&gt;was wowed as well&lt;/a&gt;. But if you went to sign up, you might have found yourself facing a &lt;em&gt;preorder &lt;/em&gt;page — yes, preorders to effectively rent time on a server in the cloud. Today, that should no longer be a problem: &lt;a href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/2021/12/16/geforce-now-thursday-december-16/"&gt;Nvidia now says&lt;/a&gt; the RTX 3080 waitlist is gone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sIHKPT"&gt;To catch you up, Nvidia’s GeForce Now is a bring-your-own-games service that supports many (but definitely not all) of your existing Steam, Epic, and Ubisoft Connect / Uplay PC games, letting you play them over the internet from what’s effectively an Nvidia GPU-equipped gaming PC in the cloud. You can stream them to an aging Windows laptop, MacBook, Android phone, or even iPhones using a web browser workaround, as well as set-top boxes like Nvidia’s own Shield TV and Shield TV Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="uEmwFS"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Nvidia’s three tiers are not equal&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zaCv1X"&gt;If you’re interested, I’d highly recommend &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-us%2Fgeforce-now%2Fmemberships&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F12%2F16%2F22838807%2Fnvidia-geforce-now-rtx-3080-preorder-waitlist-gone" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;testing out the free tier of GeForce Now first&lt;/a&gt; to make sure you’re within range of Nvidia’s servers and that your home internet and Wi-Fi is competent. Still, you should know that Nvidia’s three tiers are &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; not created equal — not only is the new 3080 tier the only one that’s going to competently deliver 1440p and beyond gaming on new titles, the latency is greatly reduced. It’s just a better experience all around, and I’m starting to think Nvidia should give you a taste of that instead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cnaXIM"&gt;You should know that you’ll only get the best streaming quality — 4K — if you’ve got Nvidia’s own Shield TV set-top box or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/28/20935215/nvidia-shield-tv-2019-review-streaming-stick-dolby-vision-4k-price-specs-features"&gt;tube-shaped HDMI dongle&lt;/a&gt;, because Nvidia hasn’t expanded that offering to any other devices yet. Perhaps that’s why Nvidia’s offering $20 (or £20, or €25, or $30 CAD)&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;off both of those devices this week. (You can find that same price on the Shield TV tube fairly often, but it’s rare to get a sale on the Shield TV Pro.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MPlg89"&gt;For now, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22788555/nvidia-geforce-now-crysis-remastered-free-bundle"&gt;you’ll also get a free copy of &lt;em&gt;Crysis Remastered&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; when you sign up for a paid subscription. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S1Bgwg"&gt;I can’t wholeheartedly recommend GeForce Now yet because it doesn’t play quite enough of my Steam library and I &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; manage to get my hands on a new video card for my PC, but I could see others diving in who can’t find or afford them right now. If you do wind up diving in and loving or hating it, would you drop me a line next spring?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="np5lMI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Hands-on: Nvidia’s GeForce Now just leapfrogged Google Stadia","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22750246/nvidia-geforce-now-rtx-3080-google-stadia-cloud-gaming"},{"title":"Amazon Luna runs on Windows — and yet it’s hiring Linux gaming engineers","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/15/22827185/amazon-luna-linux-windows-proton-cloud-gaming-jobs-hiring"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22838807/nvidia-geforce-now-rtx-3080-preorder-waitlist-gone"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22838807/nvidia-geforce-now-rtx-3080-preorder-waitlist-gone</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Chrome OS tablets are getting fancier but not better</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;HP and Lenovo are aiming higher with their latest tablet Chromebooks&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="5h79hd"&gt;If you go looking for a new Chromebook, you’ll find a lot of traditional clamshell laptop designs and some convertible models with 360-degree hinges. You may also find a couple tablet-first options, with thinner, lighter designs and detachable keyboards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4zcIAx"&gt;These tablet models run Google’s Chrome OS software but mimic the hardware of Microsoft’s Surface Pro or Apple’s iPad. They often come with a keyboard and case that includes a built-in kickstand. Most support stylus input (using the USI standard, common across many modern Chromebooks); some even come with one in the box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5A0aNG"&gt;Like a lot of other Chromebooks, many Chrome OS tablets are inexpensive, such as last year’s excellent Lenovo Chromebook Duet. But this year, there are two Chrome OS tablets that aim a little higher, with nicer features, better specs, and correspondingly higher price tags. HP’s Chromebook x2 11 features a modern, all-metal design, high-res 3:2 screen, and $599 price tag (though it’s frequently on sale for significantly less than that). Lenovo’s Chromebook Duet 5 has a larger, OLED display, slightly better specs, and equally portable design and sells for $499. (One mustn’t forget the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/27/18113447/google-pixel-slate-review-tablet-chrome-os-android-chromebook-slapdash"&gt;ill-fated Pixel Slate&lt;/a&gt; that was so bad Google itself &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/20/18693399/google-abandoning-tablets-pixel-slate-failure"&gt;stopped making tablets entirely&lt;/a&gt;, but for the sake of this piece let’s forget about it.) These tablets aren’t trying to compete with Apple’s base iPad — they’re aiming for the iPad Air or iPad Pro shopper and maybe even someone who’s considering a Surface Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QUmIls"&gt;I’ve been testing both of them to determine if either of them are compelling alternatives to an iPad or Surface or if you should just stick with a traditional clamshell Chromebook instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XSsaFi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10925890"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="bpbmNO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10925895"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="CtThs0"&gt;The HP and Lenovo share a lot of design traits. They are thinner and lighter than the typical Chromebook, and both have magnetic detachable keyboards and back covers that double as kickstands. (Neither back cover provides much in the way of protection — I managed to crack the screen of the HP when it accidentally slid off my desk, while the keyboard cover on the Lenovo slides around a bit when it’s closed.) Both include two USB-C ports for charging and peripherals (on either side of the Lenovo, both on the left for the HP), and both lack 3.5mm headphone jacks. Even their case and keyboard accessories are both available in a shade of dark blue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ISWS3G"&gt;The HP has an 11-inch, 2160 x 1440 pixel 3:2 LCD touchscreen. The Lenovo has a lower-res but larger 13-inch, 1920 x 1080 OLED touchscreen in the more rectangular 16:9 aspect ratio. Neither have the fast-refresh rate screens of Apple or Samsung’s highest-end tablets, but they both compare well enough to other tablets in their price range. Though I much prefer the HP’s aspect ratio for tablet use, it’s hard to deny the appeal of the Lenovo’s screen, which, like most OLED panels, is punchier, brighter, and generally just nicer to look at, especially for watching video. The contrast levels of the Duet 5’s screen are much better, the colors are more appealing, and things like video and movie watching are just more enjoyable on the Lenovo over the HP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ODnA3d"&gt;The HP has two front-facing speakers (similar to Microsoft’s Surface Pro), while the Lenovo adopts iPad-style side-mounted speakers. Both are serviceable, but neither sound all that great compared to an iPad Air, with thin, sometimes distorted sound. I preferred to use headphones (wireless, of course, thanks to the lack of headphone jacks) with both, save for the occasional impromptu video call or short YouTube video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b-Patuzid594_c8eESR730buzS4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23086470/akrales_211207_4906_0019.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The highlight of the Lenovo is its OLED display&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JfU5wlcLzXvY0fGqPAcxjTmtQBo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23099259/hp_chromebook_x2_11_26.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The HP resembles Microsoft’s Surface line of detachables&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UmoBE1"&gt;Inside, the similarities continue. Both of these tablets have Qualcomm ARM processors — the Snapdragon 7c Gen 1 in the HP and the 7c Gen 2 in the Lenovo — paired with 8GB of RAM. Though the differences between the two generations of the 7c chip are quite minor, the Lenovo is noticeably snappier and more performant than the HP. I’m not sure if it’s down to the difference in resolution (the HP does have more pixels to push) or just general optimization, but the Lenovo stuttered and lagged far less than the HP in almost everything I used it for. Neither felt as smooth and fluid as a modern iPad, and traditional mid-range Chromebooks with Intel processors, like our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21296102/best-chromebooks"&gt;current fave&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22451261/acer-chromebook-spin-713-2021-review"&gt;Acer Chromebook Spin 713&lt;/a&gt;, will run laps around both of these tablets. Still, both tablets were able to handle my typical workload of multiple virtual desks, lots of browser tabs, chatting in Slack, watching YouTube videos, and taking Zoom calls without much issue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YyiZX4"&gt;Both the HP and Lenovo provide battery life that’s closer to what you might expect from an iPad than a traditional laptop. Even when used for work, which consisted of constantly browsing many websites, chatting in Slack, taking Zoom calls, watching YouTube videos, and more, both tablets were able to last beyond a standard day, reaching between 10 and 12 hours between charges. The Lenovo was able to edge out the HP by just a hair, but both have better than average battery life when used as laptops. One note, though: if you leave them unattended for a few days, they will likely have dead batteries when you pick them up again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="xgtbwK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best Chromebook for 2021","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21296102/best-chromebooks"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="COGLe8"&gt;Tablet time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="PqApcf"&gt;I am prefacing this section with the statement that Chrome OS is not a very good tablet operating system. Though it works quite well for desktop (or, more accurately, laptop) work, Chrome OS is nowhere near as refined or optimized for tablet use as iPadOS or even Android. Animations and interactions are awkward and stuttery, navigation can be confusing, and it’s very clear that the tablet mode was shoe-horned on to an interface that was designed to be navigated primarily with a mouse and keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gN0r_B3r8hA_rdOgXE3BUCBJ4Xw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23099250/hp_chromebook_x2_11_36.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The HP’s smaller size and 3:2 aspect ratio makes it easier to use as a tablet compared to the Lenovo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="FUXnA7"&gt;While you can install Android apps on both of these tablets, a lot of popular apps aren’t available (such as Microsoft’s entire Office suite) or don’t work particularly well (Slack, Kindle). Many apps are also poorly optimized for larger screens (a problem shared with Android-native tablets) with poor touch response and small tap targets. Then there are other strange app limitations: for example, &lt;a href="https://help.netflix.com/en/node/296?ba=SwiftypeResultClick&amp;amp;q=chromebook"&gt;Netflix only supports 480p streaming&lt;/a&gt; through its app on a Chromebook. These limitations and hiccups are more acceptable on a tablet that’s less than $300; they’re much less so when you’re spending half a grand or more. I’d much rather use an iPad for tablet-focused tasks over either of these devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d5ycHb"&gt;That said, the HP does work better than the Lenovo for hand-held tablet use. Its smaller size and more manageable aspect ratio are much easier to hold in portrait mode for reading, whether you’re perusing an article, email, or Kindle book. It feels more like an iPad than the Lenovo, likely because it’s shaped much more like one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JHDUxG"&gt;The HP also has a fingerprint scanner, which makes it much easier to just pick up and log in compared to the Lenovo, where you’re required to tap out a password or PIN code to unlock it. It’s baffling that biometric authentication is still an exception to the rule with Chrome OS devices, especially ones that cost as much as these do. (The Duet 5 does support linking an Android phone and logging in through that device’s biometrics, but I was unable to get it to work with my Samsung phone, and requiring a specific phone to have biometric login is ridiculous. Just build in it.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KdMhcezH7aGtoWSWtHlHF8EYp6M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23099256/hp_chromebook_x2_11_29.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The HP’s included USI stylus snaps on to the side of the tablet and charges while it’s there, iPad-style&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LFhuSI"&gt;Both tablets support USI styli, but only the HP comes with one in the box. The stylus conveniently snaps to the side of the tablet and charges there, much like an iPad Air and its Pencil. Though the stylus works fine for occasionally jotting down notes and doodling, it’s far from as fluid or precise as Apple’s. And if you’re hoping to use it with a variety of third-party apps, your options are limited (for example, it’s barely functional with Microsoft’s web-based version of OneNote).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="PG13yU"&gt;Laptop life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="iv2nDo"&gt;But when you want to use these tablets as laptops, with their attached keyboards and the Chrome OS desktop interface, the Lenovo pulls ahead easily. Thanks to its larger size, the keyboard is much more comfortable to type on than HP’s. On the other hand, neither design worked very well on my lap, but the HP’s keyboard was particularly frustrating there: it flexed very easily, causing errant trackpad clicks whenever I rested my palms on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gdZom1"&gt;Conversely, the Lenovo’s keyboard was a joy to type on, with excellent spacing, nice travel, and satisfying feedback. It’s the one I chose when it came time to type up this article, and I’d absolutely select it if I had to use a Chromebook for remote schooling. It still works best when it’s on a flat surface, like a desk or table, and while it’d be great to have backlighting (the HP keyboard also lacks a backlight), in general, I really like this keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Iqt2IARo8w8l78xibYl_ji7mX4k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23086474/akrales_211207_4906_0123.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Duet 5’s keyboard is shockingly nice to type on, so long as you’re using it on a hard surface.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="UUnNK0"&gt;The trackpads on both models can be classified as “fine.” They are large enough to use multi-finger gestures, and they generally have good tracking and palm rejection. But neither will blow you away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="09cri2"&gt;The Lenovo’s larger screen also makes working on it in laptop mode easier. Though its 16:9 aspect ratio is cramped vertically, it’s easier to compare two documents or web pages side by side compared to the HP’s overall smaller display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iwpu34"&gt;The Lenovo’s noticeably better performance also makes working on it in laptop mode much easier. I can load web pages faster, switch between apps and virtual desktops quicker, and generally go about my day with less interference than when I’m using the HP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0N_kAG6lJxf7xfgHH9Zf9Y6W0rY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23086477/akrales_211207_4906_0152.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Both tablets are thin and light enough to go just about anywhere&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VyZgj6"&gt;When it comes down to it, the Lenovo Chromebook Duet 5 is easily the tablet I’d choose between these two models. It’s got a nicer-looking screen, a lower price tag, a more comfortable keyboard, and better performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pFk4m4"&gt;In fact, I’d go as far as saying you shouldn’t buy the HP at all at its regular price of $600. If you see it heavily discounted — this fall, it’s dropped to as low as $350 — that’s a different conversation, but at its regular price, it’s a very poor value. The Duet 5, however, feels like it’s priced more accurately: $500 for a very portable device with an OLED screen that can be used for work or school and occasionally for entertainment seems like a decent enough deal to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="CHvipd"&gt;But before you jump on either of these devices, I’d strongly consider if a tablet is the right Chrome OS device to buy at all. For around the same price or even less, you can get a clamshell or 2-in-1 Chromebook that may be a little thicker and heavier but works a lot better and can even be used as a tablet in a pinch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div id="lYw0aO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10925926"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22838058/hp-chromebook-x2-11-lenovo-chromebook-duet-5-tablet-review-comparison-head-to-head"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22838058/hp-chromebook-x2-11-lenovo-chromebook-duet-5-tablet-review-comparison-head-to-head</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Seifert</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T08:30:28-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T08:30:28-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google still ran ads on climate denial, despite promising to stop </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Illustration Of Google Logo" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/A3ADbK5_m2pFlHRJo-AGOZg_jh4=/0x0:5300x3533/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70280782/1229221048.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Google closeup logo displayed on a phone screen. | Photo by Nicolas Economou/NurPhoto via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0Z5FjQ"&gt;Google has struggled to uphold its recent &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/11221321"&gt;pledge&lt;/a&gt; to stop running ads on content that promotes climate change denial, according to a new &lt;a href="https://www.counterhate.com/post/google-ads-still-serving-climate-change-deniers"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; from the nonprofit Center for Countering Digital Hate (CCDH). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T49mE6"&gt;The new research identified 50 articles that include lies about climate change and that still featured Google ads after the date that Google said they would be banned. Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/7/22715102/google-youtube-climate-change-deniers-ads-monetization"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; a new &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/11221321"&gt;policy&lt;/a&gt; in October that prohibits “ads for, and monetization of, content that contradicts well-established scientific consensus around the existence and causes of climate change.” The new policy was supposed to kick in for Google advertisers, publishers, and YouTube creators on &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/publisherpolicies/answer/10852414?hl=en-GB"&gt;November 9th&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="GI1IiH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“They have not followed through with real action”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WZVFkq"&gt;“In making their initial announcement, Google appears to recognise that they have played a part in making climate change denial a profitable business, and yet they have not followed through with real action,” Imran Ahmed, chief executive of the Center for Countering Digital Hate, said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q1sE21"&gt;In an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, Google communications and public affairs manager Michael Aciman said the company “reviewed the pages shared with us and have taken appropriate enforcement actions.” Google says it removed ads from a majority of the URLs because they violated the company’s climate change policy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5CzBKB"&gt;One &lt;em&gt;Breitbart&lt;/em&gt; article on CCDH’s list calls global warming a hoax. Another article by conservative website &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/08/22/us/western-journal-highlights.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Western Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; falsely claims “whether the climate is changing — and whether it is caused by man — are questions not answered definitively.”&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Scientists agree that human activity has already heated up the planet by &lt;a href="https://public.wmo.int/en/media/press-release/2020-was-one-of-three-warmest-years-record"&gt;more than a degree&lt;/a&gt; Celsius, which is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/9/22613531/climate-change-united-nations-report-extreme-weather-ipcc"&gt;driving more extreme weather&lt;/a&gt; and triggering other threats across the globe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BGtktD"&gt;The new report follows another &lt;a href="https://www.counterhate.com/_files/ugd/f4d9b9_2da34b078cbe43b6820297e3a3113f69.pdf"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; published in November by CCDH that traced nearly 70 percent of all interactions with climate denial content on Facebook back to just 10 “fringe” publishers. Many of those publishers carried Google ads, which CCDH estimates earned Google $1.7 million in revenue over six months this year. Five of those publishers, including &lt;em&gt;Breitbart&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Western Journal&lt;/em&gt;, showed up once again on the organization’s new tally of climate denial content that featured Google ads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r8OoDg"&gt;Facebook has also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22763795/facebook-climate-denial-worse-study"&gt;come under fire&lt;/a&gt; by activists for not stopping the spread of climate misinformation on its platform. But unlike Google, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/4/22763795/facebook-climate-denial-worse-study"&gt;Facebook maintained that the posts&lt;/a&gt; activists flagged as misleading were “posts these groups disagree with politically” and did not violate their policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EUxkve"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22838243/google-ads-climate-change-denial"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22838243/google-ads-climate-change-denial</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T07:35:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T07:35:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X consoles are available at Target (update: sold out)</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/npvAfNtlaJPFSveh-zpJlohFcIU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70280624/acastro_210511_1777_psRestock_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zg3za0"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 8:30AM ET, December 16th:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Target has sold out of consoles for now. This one went fast, but we hope you had some luck on your side.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4wg1Wx"&gt;Look, nobody is happy about the current state of new consoles and their availability. While the hunt for a good deal is something we’re all about, having to search just to find a normal, full-price product is a whole lot less fun. That’s why we are always doing our best to help you score a new console whenever the chance arises, and today is no different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CTEqZK"&gt;Target’s online listings for the PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X have just gone live, which means there is a narrow window to order one this morning. The &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fplaystation-5-console%2F-%2FA-81114595&amp;amp;subid1=vergeps5restock"&gt;PlayStation 5 is available in the standard $499.99&lt;/a&gt; flavor with a disc drive as well as the &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fplaystation-5-digital-edition-console%2F-%2FA-81114596&amp;amp;subid1=vergeps5restock"&gt;Digital Edition for $399.99&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fxbox-series-x-console%2F-%2FA-80790841&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Xbox Series X is also available for its usual $499.99&lt;/a&gt;. The listings show sold out to start, but the early bird (hopefully) gets the worm so be prepared to hit refresh. Target usually populates its stock of consoles for local store pickup within the hour of the pages going live, and the ones with the most persistence are usually the ones rewarded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AtWKoC"&gt;Be sure to log in to your Target account in advance, with all your account info — billing and shipping — sorted ahead of time. You might also want to consider trying both a desktop browser and Target’s mobile app at the same time. Target often bases their console sales around in-store pickup, so it helps to set your favorite store near you, though be prepared to widen your search to more stores if the availability dwindles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J6XL6g"&gt;If you’re out of luck on this one, be sure to stay tuned to Verge Deals for more info on future console restocks, and be sure to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/pages/newsletters"&gt;subscribe to our newsletter&lt;/a&gt; for your regularly scheduled tech deal savings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="DdeIXp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"PlayStation 5 review: a big, confident step into next gen","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21550146/sony-playstation-5-ps5-review"},{"title":"Xbox Series X review: a next-gen PC","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21548987/xbox-series-x-review"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;div id="JPNOJa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10905882"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="zdiZm3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10905886"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="Nl2GVr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10297750"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="NBcCd8"&gt;Accessories for your PlayStation 5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="2C0YOC"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10905916"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="kK2OJy"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10905919"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="SkU8dm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10905923"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="dubpaS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9734577"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="MkQix8"&gt;Accessories for your Xbox Series X&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="VNhNfb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10654449"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="Rp484O"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10420028"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="Jh3Bkr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10833343"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="V051Gj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10892449"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="x4OzjV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22820987/playstation-5-xbox-series-x-console-restock-target-stock-check-availability"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22820987/playstation-5-xbox-series-x-console-restock-target-stock-check-availability</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T06:58:03-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T06:58:03-05:00</updated>
    <title>Huawei’s P50 Pocket is a stylish clamshell foldable launching this month</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T6aRiNRkhbtH8SI2cHbl8CHI_Vk=/0x0:1620x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70280496/001RBNXygy1gxfadt3cfyj61hc0u07ee02.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The P50 Pocket appears to have a small external circular screen.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Harper’s Bazaar China&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="0qbOuv"&gt;Huawei is set to announce a new foldable phone later this month called the Huawei P50 Pocket, according to a post on the company’s &lt;a href="https://m.weibo.cn/detail/4714230723379666"&gt;official Weibo account&lt;/a&gt;. Unlike its previous Mate X foldables, which fold from a device the size of a tablet into a smartphone, the P50 Pocket has a clamshell design that folds out to the size of a smartphone. It’s a similar design to Samsung’s Z Flip devices, or the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/13/21135809/motorola-razr-review-foldable-flip-phone-verizon-price-camera-display-battery"&gt;Motorola Razr&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="seNxZo"&gt;A &lt;em&gt;Harper’s Bazaar China&lt;/em&gt; photoshoot of the P50 Pocket &lt;a href="https://m.weibo.cn/status/L6h3qlP5V"&gt;posted on Weibo&lt;/a&gt; makes it look like a stylish little foldable. It appears to have a similar dual-ring camera bump to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/29/22598135/huawei-p50-china-release-date-price-news-features-specs-cameras"&gt;Huawei P50&lt;/a&gt;, but its lower ring has been repurposed to work as a small external screen, which appears to be able to show notifications or work as a camera viewfinder.  &lt;a href="https://chinese.engadget.com/huawei-p50-pocket-harper-s-bazaar-teaser-062427696.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Engadget China &lt;/em&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt; that the phone has a side-mounted fingerprint sensor for security, and available colors include silver and gold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CHx8kttYuRFP1szeWEDe4IcW4o8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23100949/001RBNXygy1gxfat5sa7jj60u01400xc02.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Harper’s Bazaar China&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/h-wP6CpbfxKSh99T9kPa0fzo3QI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23100953/p50_pocket_3.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Harper’s Bazaar China&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Blj1lZbnmPp8RDE0ZmK9qtfqg3U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23100951/001RBNXygy1gxfadtvk2hj61400u0n0g02.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Harper’s Bazaar China&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zHDMhrpvEkBdgIl-peKwOf8iduE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23100952/001RBNXygy1gxfadvhl0cj61400u0q8202.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Harper’s Bazaar China&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TYT7cw"&gt;Huawei is of course no stranger to foldable devices, and has previously released the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/25/18239565/huawei-mate-x-foldable-phone-hands-on-design-mwc-2019"&gt;Mate X&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/24/21145519/huawei-mate-xs-foldable-phone-news-features-quad-layer-screen-hinge-kirin-990-5g"&gt;Mate XS&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22294983/huawei-mate-x2-fold-specs-price"&gt;Mate X2&lt;/a&gt;. But these use a folding form-factor that some have compared to a hotdog bun. In contrast, the new P50 Pocket looks to be using what’s been called a hamburger-style design. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oMxwvt"&gt;Huawei’s post only mentions a Chinese launch, and it’s unclear if or when the P50 Pocket could see a global release. We might be waiting a while, though. Huawei is yet to offer its latest flagship smartphone, the P50, outside of China following its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/29/22598135/huawei-p50-china-release-date-price-news-features-specs-cameras"&gt;launch in July&lt;/a&gt;, and the company is still subject to US sanctions that both &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/3/20993148/huawei-mate-30-no-american-components-manufacturers"&gt;limit its ability to source hardware components&lt;/a&gt; and mean it can’t &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/21/21147919/google-addresses-huawei-services-ban-android-trump-sideload-apps"&gt;preinstall Google’s apps and services&lt;/a&gt; on its phones.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839272/huawei-p50-pocket-china-launch-foldable"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839272/huawei-p50-pocket-china-launch-foldable</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T06:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T06:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Uber expands its same-day local delivery business to more cities</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ep1scKFm-K9vqjaKkuvb-dyZjWY=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70280394/acastro_180927_1777_uber_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tKAT16"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/4/20/21227828/uber-connect-direct-deliveries-medication-pet-supplies"&gt;Uber Connect&lt;/a&gt;, the ride-hail company’s same-day courier service, is expanding to more cities. It’s also getting a few new features to make sending and receiving items easier for customers and drivers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oxpvuo"&gt;Uber Connect is now available in 6,000 cities and towns in the US, including major markets like New York City, Philadelphia, Pittsburgh, Los Angeles, San Francisco, and San Diego. The service was initially launched in April 2020 as a means to diversify Uber’s business during the early months of the pandemic. Since then, the company has seen incredible growth in Uber Connect, registering a 200 percent increase in trips since the first week of January 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="OiF8QF"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Uber Connect is now available in 6,000 cities and towns in the US&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UjjBBt"&gt;In addition to expanding to more markets, Uber is also allowing the sender to include delivery instructions (e.g. Handle with care) to their driver and arrange “meet at door” pick-up and delivery. Originally, the package recipient needed to meet the courier at the curb. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R3NDRa"&gt;This isn’t the first time that Uber has experimented with same-day local deliveries. From 2014 to 2018, the company operated a business called &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/31/17184480/uber-uberrush-shut-down"&gt;Uber Rush&lt;/a&gt;. The company even opened an API to allow private businesses to use it as a delivery option, but never grew it beyond a handful of major cities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OmDjwO"&gt;During the pandemic, Uber’s core ride-hailing business tanked as a result of lockdown orders. In response, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/19/22583397/uber-grocery-delivery-expansion-cities-safeway-acme"&gt;the company quickly pivoted to food delivery&lt;/a&gt; and later to groceries, as it sought to find new revenue streams. Uber is still relying heavily on cash from its delivery products as it struggles to make up for a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/7/22371850/uber-lyft-driver-shortage-covid-bonus-stimulus"&gt;nationwide driver shortage&lt;/a&gt;. (Of course, delivery won’t work without drivers either.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fHFYw9"&gt;To help fuel its grocery delivery expansion, Uber has acquired a number of smaller startups in recent months, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/6/21312447/uber-postmates-acquisition-announced-food-delivery"&gt;Postmates&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/7/21315159/uber-grocery-delivery-launch-cornershop-latin-america-canada"&gt;Cornershop&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://investor.uber.com/news-events/news/press-release-details/2021/Uber-to-Acquire-Drizly/default.aspx"&gt;Drizly&lt;/a&gt;, as it seeks to expand its delivery options. Uber is also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/4/22419461/uber-gopuff-grocery-delivery-expansion"&gt;partnering with delivery startup Gopuff&lt;/a&gt;, which specializes in delivering “essential” or “instant need” items, like liquor, beauty and pet products, snacks, and over-the-counter medication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NCHQaa"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22838302/uber-connect-cities-same-day-delivery-expand"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22838302/uber-connect-cities-same-day-delivery-expand</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T06:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T06:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Ford launches new EV charging project to help commercial customers go electric </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zJz0SuTYRHjTSIxk8T7yX7k_yg0=/472x0:5566x3396/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70280422/FordPro_Depot_Charging.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ISXyAN"&gt;Ford is launching a new project to help its commercial customers switch to electric vehicles by selling them EV charging installation equipment and software management tools. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LX1gq6"&gt;The automaker says it expects to sell over 300,000 electric vehicles to businesses and government agencies over the next decade. To help ease the transition, Ford is launching a new project, called Ford Pro Charging, to offer the necessary software and hardware to aid in the charging of their electric vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yVRWaF"&gt;Ford’s commercial vehicles will come with the automaker’s telematics software, which makes it easier for fleet owners to keep tabs on the location, charging status, or the health of their vehicles. This software will help commercial fleet operators figure when, where, and how often they’ll need to charge their EVs, depending on the types of energy that is being expended. For example, a customer that is using an electric &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/24/22450563/ford-f150-lightning-pro-electric-pickup-truck-commercial-fleets"&gt;Ford F-150 Lighting Pro&lt;/a&gt; truck to tow materials may end up using more battery power than a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/12/21559954/ford-e-transit-electric-delivery-cargo-van-price-specs-range"&gt;Ford E-Transit van&lt;/a&gt; used for deliveries, and therefore may need to charge more frequently. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="vILjSL"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The automaker says it expects top sell over 300,000 electric vehicles to businesses and government agencies over the next decade&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cyWjiT"&gt;Ford’s fleet software will also help operators tackle some of the more unconventional issues that might crop up as they switch to electric vehicles. For instance, some workers take their fleet vehicles home at night, fill up the gas tank on their own, and get reimbursed by their employer. Ford has previously said it will help install home chargers for those workers, writing into the fleet software a way to let employers reimburse workers for the cost of at-home charging.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HAlB2Ogi1oCd9engRCeNgLmvZWg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23100243/FordPro_Home_Charging.jpeg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="bPA8sa"&gt;“Let’s say the customer fleet returns around 10PM planning to go back out starting at 5AM,” Muffi Ghadiali, head of Ford Pro Charging, said. “You have a limited window for charging and have to make charging decisions in a highly dynamic environment. Does every vehicle need to be fully charged? Can we balance charge power against the available charging window to take advantage of low overnight energy rates? Ford Pro Charging accounts for a multitude of variables and controls each charge station precisely to optimize energy costs and ensure vehicle uptime.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H4Xo3V"&gt;Ford Pro Charging customers will subscribe to the company’s software platform, meaning Ford will be able to count on subscription fees as recurring revenue. The amount that each customer pays is based on the number of vehicles or charge ports they have in operation, as well as a number of other variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SCCCZ3"&gt;Ford will also help install charging stations, whether at a customer’s home or at a depot for fleet vehicles. The company will install either AC or DC fast charging ports, depending on a customer’s needs. Ford said it is working with a number of different suppliers, though a spokesperson declined to provide any charging company names. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s46Qi3"&gt;Ford also declined to disclose the amount of money it plans on spending on this project. Previously the company said it would &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/4/22267195/ford-electric-autonomous-investment-29-billion"&gt;spend $29 billion on electric and autonomous vehicles&lt;/a&gt; through 2025. Ford expects to start shipping the F-150 Lightning Pro, its electric pickup truck geared toward commercial customers, and the E-Transit van in 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="trFWvV"&gt;The demand for commercial EVs is likely to be huge over the decade. Under the Biden administration, the federal government alone is likely to spend billions of dollars purchasing hundreds of thousands of electric vehicles in order to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/8/22824500/biden-executive-order-climate-change-carbon-emissions-electric-vehicles"&gt;fulfill the executive order to achieve carbon neutrality by 2050&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XUZyhn"&gt;EV charging has been a challenge for the entire auto industry, Ford included. In 2019, the automaker introduced its FordPass network, claiming that EV owners would have access to 12,000 public chargers. But the branding made it seem as if Ford were launching its own version of Tesla’s Supercharger network, when it was actually tapping existing stations from companies like Electrify America. Earlier this year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/29/22356539/ford-connected-charge-station-sales-halt-issue-mustang-mach-e"&gt;the company stopped selling its Level 2 home chargers&lt;/a&gt; for the Mustang Mach-E after discovering some weren’t working. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Msp8B1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22838465/ford-pro-charging-ev-f150-lightning-e-transit-commercial"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22838465/ford-pro-charging-ev-f150-lightning-e-transit-commercial</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-12-16T05:04:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-12-16T05:04:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>TikTok tests PC game streaming app that could let it take on Twitch</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The TikTok music note logo against a dark background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WDFW190i498zt3gQ6suyqNOCzD4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70280363/acastro_190723_1777_tiktok_0003.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="otLJyf"&gt;TikTok is testing a new piece of desktop streaming software called TikTok Live Studio that lets users broadcast live footage from games and other desktop applications, &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/12/15/tiktok-is-testing-a-desktop-streaming-software-called-tiktok-live-studio/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;. The software is currently being tested with a small number of users across some Western markets, TikTok says, but its &lt;a href="https://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:IcX8L3AB2AIJ:https://www.tiktok.com/studio/download+&amp;amp;cd=1&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ct=clnk&amp;amp;gl=uk"&gt;official page on TikTok’s site&lt;/a&gt; appears to have been taken down as of publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hEh4gD"&gt;If released, TikTok Live Studio could mark an interesting change for TikTok’s live streaming strategy. Rather than being focused on users streaming directly from mobile devices, it could expand TikTok Live’s focus to include game streaming, bringing it into competition with the likes of Twitch, YouTube Gaming, and Facebook Gaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ODSxFC"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;It's super basic in its current state. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Has both Landscape and Portrait Scenes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Sources include Game Capture, Mobile Capture, Video Capture, Program Capture, and some text/images. No browser sources, or alerts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Emojis are limited to the stock ones. &lt;a href="https://t.co/oOHwUbSdUF"&gt;pic.twitter.com/oOHwUbSdUF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Zach Bussey (@zachbussey) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/zachbussey/status/1471172519226916865?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 15, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ovdcdz"&gt;According to Zach Bussey, who shared screenshots of TikTok Live Studio &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/zachbussey/status/1471172519226916865"&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, the software is currently in a barebones state. It reportedly supports streaming in both landscape and portrait, and can draw footage from games, individual programs, mobile devices, and cameras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MbPV42"&gt;It’s previously been possible to live stream from a desktop device to TikTok using third-party &lt;a href="https://streamlabs.com/content-hub/post/streamlabs-announces-integration-with-tiktok"&gt;software like Streamlabs&lt;/a&gt;, but &lt;a href="https://streamlabs.com/content-hub/post/how-to-live-stream-on-tiktok-from-a-pc"&gt;a help page for the feature&lt;/a&gt; notes that access is limited and invite-only. There are also &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lAefS9XDPdQ"&gt;tutorials&lt;/a&gt; that use third-party services like Loola.tv as a workaround to connect TikTok with streaming programs like OBS. But even these aren’t perfect — a &lt;a href="https://support.loola.tv/en/articles/1755882-connecting-your-tiktok-account"&gt;Loola.tv help page&lt;/a&gt; notes that “TikTok streaming is currently disabled for most users” as of July this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L5M7O8"&gt;It’s not clear when TikTok might expand its test of Live Studio to more users. But if it becomes widely available, desktop streaming could bring a lot more variety to the platform’s catalog of live content.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839213/tiktok-live-studio-desktop-live-streaming-twitch"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/16/22839213/tiktok-live-studio-desktop-live-streaming-twitch</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
