<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-03-17T04:25:27-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-17T04:25:27-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-17T04:25:27-04:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung says it might skip the Galaxy Note this year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Samsung Galaxy Note 20" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WXUBlu67qThdoqzNvjiUniBOhqs=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68979722/dbohn_201004_4226_0002.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Dieter Bohn / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="A1PW2J"&gt;Samsung has warned that it might not be able to ship a Galaxy Note phone in 2021 after all, citing difficulties in launching two flagship phones in one year, in comments at its annual shareholders meeting &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-17/samsung-warns-of-serious-imbalance-in-the-chips-industry"&gt;reported on by Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y3IGzu"&gt;“[The] Note series is positioned as a high-end model in our business portfolio,” said mobile chief DJ Koh. “It could be a burden to unveil two flagship models in a year so it might be difficult to release [a] Note model in 2H. The timing of [the] Note model launch can be changed but we seek to release a Note model next year.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HcbvgQ"&gt;The comments came as Samsung sounded the alarm about a global semiconductor shortage, saying that its business will likely be affected next quarter. The potential delay or cancellation of a 2021 Galaxy Note is apparently separate, however; Koh says it’s more about streamlining the lineup, according to Bloomberg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="0euKFz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Samsung Galaxy Note 20 review: stylus tax","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21506471/samsung-galaxy-note-20-review-price-stylus"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="C0ofMo"&gt;The release of a Galaxy Note this year was already far from a sure thing. Samsung had indicated plans to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/15/22175769/samsung-stylus-galaxy-phones-s21-foldable"&gt;bring its key stylus feature to more phones&lt;/a&gt; in the Galaxy lineup, sparking speculation that the line may come to an end. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/16/22177972/galaxy-note-21-still-happening-yonhap"&gt;A Yonhap report&lt;/a&gt;, however, said that Samsung was still preparing to release a new Note phone in 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3kweW2"&gt;Samsung declined to comment to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; on the existence of this device at the time, reiterating its plans to “bring some of the most beloved features of the Galaxy Note to more device categories in 2021.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22335502/galaxy-note-2021-delay-canceled-samsung"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22335502/galaxy-note-2021-delay-canceled-samsung</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T21:39:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T21:39:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>The PS5 is getting DVR support in Japan this year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y0B4mZvfzrZuGjcFjI3AN9d2Qec=/0x0:2163x1442/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68978911/nasne.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HdP8Qn"&gt;Sony has announced that the PlayStation 5 will get DVR functionality in Japan by way of a new app that’ll work with its Nasne tuners. The app will be called Torne (pronounced &lt;em&gt;to-ru-ne&lt;/em&gt;) and should be available later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vsEWLF"&gt;Torne was originally a TV tuner add-on for the PS3 that was released in 2010 and allowed you to save broadcast shows to your console’s hard drive and transfer them to a PSP or PS Vita. It was followed by Nasne, which added its own storage and worked more like a NAS drive, with the recordings available through a mobile app. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DoRqKR"&gt;Sony stopped selling Nasne in 2019, but last year Japanese peripheral manufacturer Buffalo announced that it’d take over the product and release Buffalo-branded versions, with the first models set to ship this spring. The new Nasne still looks like a PS3, just with a Buffalo logo on it; Buffalo is doubling the internal storage to 2TB, however, and tripling external storage capability to 6TB. It’ll go on sale later this month for 29,800 yen (~$270).&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22335149/ps5-nasne-dvr-app-japan-release-buffalo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22335149/ps5-nasne-dvr-app-japan-release-buffalo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sam Byford</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T20:44:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T20:44:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple just gave Russia a spot on the iPhone to advertise its favorite apps to its citizens</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pM2WG3NS0H7dkbe0LJ91Bm-c8cQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68978734/acastro_180130_1777_0005.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="NkHvcU"&gt;Starting April 1st, users setting up a new iPhone in Russia will see a screen that allows them to automatically install apps that are officially sanctioned by the Russian government, in compliance with Russian law (&lt;a href="https://www.engadget.com/apple-iphone-ipad-mac-russia-apps-preinstall-144255015.html"&gt;via Engadget&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ptFlOo"&gt;The law in question &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/3/20977459/russian-law-pre-installed-domestic-software-tvs-smartphones-laptops"&gt;was passed back in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, and requires smartphones, tablets, laptops, desktops, and smart TVs sold in Russia to come pre-installed with specific apps made by Russian companies by April 1st, &lt;a href="https://www.vedomosti.ru/technology/articles/2021/03/15/861564-iphone-soft"&gt;according to Russian news site &lt;em&gt;Vedomosti&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. (The law was originally set to go into effect in July 2020, but was pushed back to April 2021). &lt;em&gt;Vedomosti&lt;/em&gt; also says that apps won’t be installed if users don’t want them. Apple confirmed to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that it will comply with the law by giving the users the option to install the apps when activating the phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XRBCqS"&gt;Which apps are specifically going to be offered to users remains unclear, though &lt;em&gt;Vedomosti&lt;/em&gt; cites a government services app, and apps from Russian companies including Yandex, Mail.ru, and Kaspersky Lab. The government seems to be aware that it might be problematic to favor specific apps, and is planning to expand its list over time: “The Ministry is not at all interested in seeing popular apps included in the mandatory pre-installation list take dominant positions. If alternatives emerge on the market, prove interesting to users and gain popularity quickly, they will be included in this selection and also offered for pre-installation,” a Russian official told &lt;em&gt;Vedomosti.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2DEOsL"&gt;Apple has historically kept tight control over the iPhone’s setup process, and that appears to now be changing, if only in one market. While Apple has previously made changes to stay on the side of local laws — it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/27/20985762/apple-maps-weather-apps-crimea-russia-territory"&gt;changed maps&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/31/17803638/apple-watch-pride-face-russia-block"&gt;blocked pride watch faces&lt;/a&gt; in Russia, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/18/17587304/apple-icloud-china-user-data-state-run-telecom-privacy-security"&gt;now stores iCloud data on state-run servers in China&lt;/a&gt; — this may be one of the more dramatic changes, as it affects a screen that every user will see when they set up their iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XOLofx"&gt;Apple has slowly been allowing users to change how iOS works out of the box, with the ability to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21301478/apple-ios-14-default-apps-browser-email-changes-features-report"&gt;change some default apps in iOS 14&lt;/a&gt;, but now it’s given a small amount of control over the setup process to the Russian government, too. As the company faces &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/16/21292651/apple-eu-antitrust-investigation-app-store-apple-pay"&gt;legal challenges from the EU&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/interface/2020/6/17/21292983/apple-spotify-antitrust-hey-email-congress-house-judiciary-tim-cook"&gt;US over antitrust&lt;/a&gt;, and over &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/3/13/18263453/spotify-apple-app-store-antitrust-complaint-ec-30-percent-cut-unfair"&gt;giving its competitors a level playing field&lt;/a&gt;, we may see Apple having to give over some more control to governments if it wants to sell its phones to their citizens — though it probably won’t be compelled to ask users if they want to install Spotify at setup. Probably.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334641/apple-follows-russian-default-apps-law-setup-screen-options-user"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334641/apple-follows-russian-default-apps-law-setup-screen-options-user</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T20:36:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T20:36:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Cricut promises unlimited lifetime uploads for existing crafting machines after user backlash</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ucVZNCoR9AXuDUHalhOpFmucaYk=/73x0:1113x693/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68978716/Screen_Shot_2021_03_16_at_3.22.55_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Cricut&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="z12izD"&gt;Cricut is changing its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22332212/cricut-crafting-machine-design-space-upload-limit"&gt;recently announced plan to require a subscription&lt;/a&gt; to get the full use of its crafting machines for precisely cutting paper and other materials. Following backlash from crafters and fans who rely on its machines, &lt;a href="https://inspiration.cricut.com/a-letter-to-the-cricut-community-from-ashish-arora-cricut-ceo/?fbclid=IwAR2nc73QTwCyEhdw0ihhsPdDrAMIlGlq0gMJk2SvuOeVefA6IFvQXts7a6M"&gt;Cricut CEO Ashish Arora apologized for the decision&lt;/a&gt;, and announced that the company will postpone the requirement for a subscription and give unlimited uploads to all users with a registered Cricut device purchased before December 31st, 2021 — for the lifetime of their machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uwzw2c"&gt;Without an upload limit, crafters will be able to use Cricut and its required Design Space app as usual. They can create designs in the app or third-party software like Procreate, and then format it to be cut out of materials like paper, fabric, vinyl, and even wood using a Cricut machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OebFvD"&gt;Prior to this change, Cricut was planning on requiring a $9.99 per month / $95.88 per year Cricut Access Standard plan or a Premium plan for $118.88 per year to keep unlimited uploads. Owners who didn’t pay would be limited to 20 uploads per month, which many creators, who often favor starting Cricut projects in other apps and uploading them into Design Space, were worried would make the device unusable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sO9Exy"&gt;Arora says that people who buy a resold Cricut machine can also get unlimited lifetime uploads, provided the new owner creates a Cricut account and connects their machine before the end of 2021. Arora says the company is also considering options for educational or maker space settings that might burn through 20 uploads quickly, but had no specifics to share other than a general promise that nothing will change before the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GBOZYU"&gt;While in an ideal world a machine that can cost up to $399 wouldn’t ever need a subscription, Cricut has at least listened to the concerns of its current customers and offered them what seems like a pretty good compromise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CJLwcJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PP5LUV"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334798/cricut-postpones-subscription-unlimited-uploads"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334798/cricut-postpones-subscription-unlimited-uploads</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T19:55:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T19:55:35-04:00</updated>
    <title>Elon Musk won’t sell his NFT song after all</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Billionaire Elon Musk Receives Axel Springer Award" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aTuSByLXDQ5PqH2RZaNL0TzF-oc=/0x0:3909x2606/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68978575/1229901655.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;div id="xYYRLM"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Actually, doesn’t feel quite right selling this. Will pass.&lt;/p&gt;— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1371969967176957956?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 16, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3iC9s0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/3/16/22335019/elon-musk-not-selling-techno-house-nft-song"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/tldr/2021/3/16/22335019/elon-musk-not-selling-techno-house-nft-song</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T17:53:59-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T17:53:59-04:00</updated>
    <title>Uber drivers in the UK will now get minimum wage and paid vacation after a big court win</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dLh3KDcRA0KISrLP3u6D7cMX2qU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68977920/acastro_180927_1777_uber_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1uiknL"&gt;Uber &lt;a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/0001543151/000155278121000124/e21143_ex99-1.htm"&gt;will classify&lt;/a&gt; around 70,000 drivers in the UK as workers and give them some benefits after losing an appeal at the Supreme Court level in February, following a years-long legal battle over their employment status. Drivers will still not be considered full-time employees, but they will receive a minimum wage, holiday time, and will be enrolled in a pension plan starting on March 17th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bPziZH"&gt;The decision in February was one of the biggest wins yet for drivers, and for gig workers writ large, in the UK. But that victory came just a few months after voters in California approved Prop 22, a ballot measure that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/4/21546037/prop-22-california-uber-lyft-ballot-measure-result"&gt;reversed a previous decision to classify drivers as employees&lt;/a&gt;. And despite repeated claims that classifying drivers as employees would make things more expensive for customers, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/19/22291580/prop-22-instacart-doordash-uber-lyft-postmates-grubhub-price-hike"&gt;all the major gig economy companies have since raised prices anyway&lt;/a&gt;. Uber, which helped bankroll the effort to pass Prop 22, is now looking &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/wx8y9x/uber-wants-to-export-prop-22-to-europe"&gt;at making similar moves in the European Union&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E64Tpm"&gt;The case Uber lost in February began all the way back in 2016 when two drivers argued that Uber had too much control over their actions to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; be considered their employer. Uber lost but continued to appeal all the way up to the UK Supreme Court, which affirmed the lower-court decisions in February. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yaXctd"&gt;Uber and companies like it have long argued that classifying drivers too rigidly would make it harder for them to work when they wanted, and that flexibility was just as, if not more, important than benefits and other protections afforded by more official employment status. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0mEFKZ"&gt;In an op-ed published Tuesday in the &lt;a href="https://www.standard.co.uk/comment/comment/uber-chief-executive-dara-khosrowhahi-drivers-rights-turning-page-b924529.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Evening Standard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Uber CEO Dara Khosrowshahi said it is “increasingly clear to us that flexibility alone is insufficient, and that it should not come at the expense of social protections.” But he added that he believes “outdated employment laws essentially force that trade-off.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nsFBT1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334771/uber-uk-drivers-workers-benefits-employees-decision"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334771/uber-uk-drivers-workers-benefits-employees-decision</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T17:43:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T17:43:55-04:00</updated>
    <title>Huawei has a plan to get a bigger cut of 5G, even with its phone sales limited</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cglpkfAQTGNKIcIEEPlMzMCaB7I=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68977880/acastro_190520_1777_huawei_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="o1pAUQ"&gt;Huawei has a plan to compete in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/22/22292074/5g-nationwide-verizon-att-tmobile-c-band"&gt;5G&lt;/a&gt; without being able to sell its 5G phones everywhere. Today, the technology company announced that &lt;a href="https://www.huawei.com/en/news/2021/3/huawei-releases-whitepaper-innovation-intellectual-property-2020"&gt;it intends to seek royalties&lt;/a&gt; from companies like Apple and Samsung in exchange for the use of its patents, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-16/huawei-to-start-demanding-5g-royalties-from-smartphone-giants"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Huawei believes it can strike licensing deals despite sanctions in the US, and it plans to use its earnings to invest even further into research and development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mVoDTZ"&gt;Huawei obtained patents on new technology during the development of the larger 5G standard — alongside companies like Qualcomm and Ericsson — that are needed for interoperability between different 5G networks, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/03/16/huawei-to-charge-royalties-to-smartphone-makers-using-its-5g-tech-.html"&gt;according to CNBC&lt;/a&gt;. “Huawei has been the largest technical contributor to 5G standards,” Huawei’s head of intellectual property rights, Jason Ding, said in a statement.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;The company intends to charge up to $2.50 per phone that uses its 5G patents. Huawei believes its patent business shouldn’t be impacted by ongoing sanctions, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;notes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u3TXKw"&gt;The company’s patent earnings are already large. Ding estimates Huawei will earn between $1.2 billion and $1.3 billion from patent licensing between 2019 and 2021. Huawei also plans to charge less than other manufacturers like Nokia and Ericsson for access to its 5G standard essential patents (SEPs), according to CNBC. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qZH7mJ"&gt;Huawei is still banned from doing business in the US by the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/15/18216988/white-house-huawei-china-equipment-ban-trump-executive-order"&gt;Department of Commerce&lt;/a&gt; over &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/11/21133631/huawei-china-spying-claims-us-officials-blacklist-5g"&gt;concerns of spying&lt;/a&gt;. The company’s networking technology is also still required to be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/4/21422939/huawei-zte-us-phone-networks-fcc-congress-reimbursement-cost"&gt;removed and replaced&lt;/a&gt; in the US and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/14/21322880/uk-bans-huawei-5g-network-infrastructure-trump-administration-pressure"&gt;UK&lt;/a&gt;. Aggressively pursuing patent royalties seems like a way to profit off the 5G business Huawei was already building. And with no indication that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22273729/huawei-ceo-ren-zhengfei-biden-trump-us-sanctions"&gt;the Biden administration will renegotiate&lt;/a&gt; with the company or &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274575/huawei-fcc-lawsuit-national-security-ban-broadband-rollout"&gt;reverse the ban&lt;/a&gt;, it might need it.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334247/huawei-5g-patents-royalties-apple-samsung"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334247/huawei-5g-patents-royalties-apple-samsung</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T17:16:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T17:16:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>Apple Maps now shows COVID-19 vaccination locations</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An illustration of several vaccine vials over a pink and purple background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QXIFQizdmwkGcOTXe2W3JNjotmI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68977675/acastro_210309_1777_vaccine_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="v3Tryz"&gt;Apple &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fnewsroom%2F2021%2F03%2Fapple-maps-now-displays-covid-19-vaccination-locations%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2021%2F3%2F16%2F22334609%2Fapple-maps-facebook-google-covid-19-vaccine-locations" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;announced today&lt;/a&gt; that Apple Maps has been updated with vaccine locations from VaccineFinder, a site run by Boston Children’s Hospital that provides information on vaccine eligibility and availability. People can search for nearby vaccination sites in Apple Maps or ask Siri, “Where can I get a COVID vaccination?” Over 20,000 locations are now listed, with more to be added in the coming weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Image of a phone showing Apple Maps with locations marked as COVID-19 vaccine sites." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uXmYci24ul9wSwpsQjnRm0WnxxU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22375689/apple_maps_vaccinefinder_vaccine_search_results_03162021.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vaccination sites in Apple Maps&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ACXEzW"&gt;Each vaccine site listing in Apple Maps includes the operating hours and contact information for the site, with a link to the provider’s website to find vaccine availability and make an appointment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BbwVJ4"&gt;With the new feature, Apple joins a number of other tech companies offering more ways for people to check their eligibility, locate vaccination sites, and get vaccine appointments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="VBOBY8"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How to score a COVID-19 vaccine appointment","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22279023/covid-19-vaccine-appointment-how-to"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="0iMqDU"&gt;Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/tech/news/2021/03/15/covid-vaccine-appointment-facebook-instagram-coronavirus-vaccination/4680803001/"&gt;announced yesterday&lt;/a&gt; that it will be adding VaccineFinder information to its COVID Information Center, showing people when and where they can get vaccinated and providing links to make appointments. The COVID Information Center will also be expanding to Instagram, and the company is working on expanding government and health authority WhatsApp chatbots to help people register for vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xO8sHB"&gt;Google is also offering more ways to find information about vaccination. The company &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/ai-machine-learning/googles-business-messages-helps-the-public-find-covid-19-vaccines"&gt;announced today&lt;/a&gt; that people can use Business Messages in Google Maps and Google search to contact local pharmacies owned by Albertsons Companies — including Safeway, Jewel-Osco, Vons, Albertsons, Acme, Shaw’s, and Tom Thumb — with questions about vaccine eligibility, availability, and appointment booking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NoqfW9"&gt;The US federal government is set to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22326335/biden-white-house-covid-19-vaccine-federal-website"&gt;launch its own vaccine-finding website&lt;/a&gt; by May 1st and has said that all adults in the US will be eligible for a vaccine at that time.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;So far, about 28 percent of adults in the US have received their first vaccine dose, &lt;a href="https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/#vaccinations"&gt;according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334609/apple-maps-facebook-google-covid-19-vaccine-locations"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334609/apple-maps-facebook-google-covid-19-vaccine-locations</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kait Sanchez</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T17:05:01-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T17:05:01-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft reiterates ‘VR for console is not a focus for us’ following localization bug</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5hWvKtjbkKgvU4bbiAuwpbs6H4Y=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68977570/acastro_180604_1777_xbox_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="s6ER77"&gt;Microsoft has once again reiterated that VR support for Xbox was not a focus for the company, following reports earlier today that hinted it was working on a VR headset compatible with the Xbox Series X / S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7VbMYr"&gt;The rumor first surfaced after &lt;a href="https://it.ign.com/xbox-series-x/179732/news/microsoft-al-lavoro-su-un-headset-vr-per-xbox-gli-indizi-arrivano-dalle-nuove-cuffie-wireless"&gt;&lt;em&gt;IGN Italy&lt;/em&gt; reported&lt;/a&gt; that some Italian Xbox users received messages, which translated to “[a]n update for the VR headset is available” and “[u]pdate VR headset,” when connecting the recently released Xbox Wireless Headset to their Xbox Series X or Series S consoles. My colleague, Cameron Faulkner, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22325883/microsoft-xbox-wireless-headset-gaming-series-x-s-pc-windows-10-review"&gt;reviewed the Xbox Wireless headset&lt;/a&gt; and did not encounter this pop-up message while using the headset on an Xbox Series X console in the US. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="AK4lU4"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“VR for console is not a focus for us at this time.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="E5n48S"&gt;A Microsoft representative told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that “the copy in this error message is inaccurate due to a localization bug,” while again reiterating that “VR for console is not a focus for us at this time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BO0ywN"&gt;Microsoft has yet to explore the VR space for its Xbox consoles. In 2018, the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/20/17485852/microsoft-xbox-one-no-vr-headset-support-windows-mixed-reality-e3-2018"&gt;pulled back&lt;/a&gt; on plans to support virtual reality headsets for Xbox in 2018, explaining that it wanted to focus “primarily on experiences you would play on your TV.” In late 2019, Xbox boss &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/28/20987089/xbox-phil-spencer-microsoft-vr-project-scarlet-half-life-alyx"&gt;Phil Spencer tweeted out&lt;/a&gt; that although he played “some great VR games” such as &lt;em&gt;Half-Life: Alyx,&lt;/em&gt; console VR was not Xbox’s focus ahead of the Xbox Series X / S release. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334533/microsoft-xbox-wireless-headset-vr-localization-bug"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334533/microsoft-xbox-wireless-headset-vr-localization-bug</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-03-16T16:59:08-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-16T16:59:08-04:00</updated>
    <title>Activision Blizzard lays off about 50 employees, citing COVID-19’s effects on its esports leagues</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-knS_tIIZ4zQfYoNHMqedkeR15M=/0x0:3840x2560/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68977519/The_Gauntlet_Final_Bracket_Day_3__62_.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo: Activision Blizzard&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YXDglQ"&gt;Activision Blizzard on Tuesday said it was laying off about 50 people across various divisions dealing predominantly with live events and esports as part of a restructuring. The company cites the COVID-19 pandemic’s effects on both the viability of live productions for its esports leagues and the changing viewership habits of its core audience over the past year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NNOwwL"&gt;“Players are increasingly choosing to connect with our games digitally and the e-sports team, much like traditional sports, entertainment, and broadcasting industries, has had to adapt its business due to the impact the pandemic has had on live events,” an Activision Blizzard spokesperson &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-16/blizzard-fires-50-people-amid-shift-away-from-live-events?srnd=technology-vp&amp;amp;sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FLEvwT"&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;, laid-off employees will receive three months’ severance, health benefits for the next 12 months, and $200 gift card to Activision Blizzard’s Battle.net PC platform. The layoffs also include some employees at Activision-owned mobile firm King, the maker of &lt;em&gt;Candy Crush&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KaXp0D"&gt;Activision Blizzard operates two massive esports leagues for two of its most popular franchises, Blizzard’s team shooter &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; and Activision’s &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty &lt;/em&gt;series. Both leagues had &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/6/21122974/overwatch-league-season-3-preview-youtube-hero-pool-china-travel"&gt;global, travel-oriented productions&lt;/a&gt; planned for 2020 prior to the pandemic, and both had to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/7/21505843/overwatch-league-owl-grand-finals-2020-schedule-youtube"&gt;shift pretty much every part of the operation&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/11/22276595/call-of-duty-league-cdl-2021-season-preview-johanna-faries-interview"&gt;online-only production and remote competition&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="tuZw9b"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It’s a reaction to the realities of how the leagues are playing”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6B7DZX"&gt;“We learned a lot last year in terms of how the leagues can be structured for online play, and we’ll look to carry forward the best practices from that,” Tony Petitti, Activision Blizzard’s president of sports and entertainment, &lt;a href="https://www.sportsbusinessjournal.com/SB-Blogs/Breaking-News/2021/03/Activision-layoffs.aspx"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Sports Business Journal&lt;/em&gt; in an interview&lt;/a&gt;. “In terms of timing, it’s a reaction to the realities of how the leagues are playing and what resources we need to allocate to best serve the league, owners, teams and fans.” Petitti says the company is nonetheless “really optimistic” that its esports business can grow with a new focus on online production. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0cA2Hy"&gt;While the company’s esports business may have suffered during the pandemic, Activision Blizzard’s core business is doing remarkably well. The company’s latest quarterly earnings report, &lt;a href="https://investor.activision.com/news-releases/news-release-details/activision-blizzard-announces-fourth-quarter-and-2020-financial#:~:text=For%20the%20year%20ended%20December,GAAP%20operating%20margin%20was%2034%25."&gt;released last month&lt;/a&gt;, indicated record revenues for 2020 that smashed Wall Street expectations, thanks in large part to the ongoing success of &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty &lt;/em&gt;and its &lt;em&gt;Warzone&lt;/em&gt; battle royale game. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y9ojIL"&gt;“In a year filled with adversity our extraordinary employees were determined to provide connection and joy to our 400 million players around the world,” Activision Blizzard CEO Bobby Kotick said at the time. “They accomplished this as well as generating record financial results for our shareholders. Under difficult circumstances, but with the same conviction and focus, they will continue to do so in 2021.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="93JlsF"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 16th, 5:41PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added information regarding the $200 Battle.net gift card as part of the laid off employees’ benefits. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334569/activision-blizzard-layoffs-esports-overwatch-call-of-duty-league-covid-pandemic"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334569/activision-blizzard-layoffs-esports-overwatch-call-of-duty-league-covid-pandemic</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
