<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-11-23T19:10:43-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-23T19:10:43-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-23T19:10:43-05:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter verified a fake account in the Norwegian government, but it’s not Twitter’s fault</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K4OkgI35ED6S8vmNZsu7ZPK9oJw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70185172/acastro_170726_1777_0012_v2.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="dilxhA"&gt;Twitter verified a fake account for Norway’s new Minister of Finance, but apparently, it’s not Twitter’s fault. As first reported by Norwegian tech site &lt;a href="https://nrkbeta.no/2021/11/23/smk-tabbe-verifiserte-falsk-finansminister-pa-twitter/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;NRKbeta&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the Prime Minister’s Office and Norway’s Security Authority (NSM) mistakenly passed along a fake account for verification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="d3K4fu"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Twitter has verified a fake account portraying the Norwegian Minister of Finance, Trygve Slagsvold Vedum.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Norwegian Ministry of Finance confirms the story to news agency NTB: &lt;a href="https://t.co/dcpINS9ZhS"&gt;https://t.co/dcpINS9ZhS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/U6MvNk93d0"&gt;pic.twitter.com/U6MvNk93d0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ståle Grut (@stalebg) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/stalebg/status/1462751042081370118?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 22, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iNwKcI"&gt;Norway’s Minister of Finance, Trygve Slagsvold Vedum, has never had a Twitter account. The report states that several fake accounts impersonating Vedum cropped up since he was elected into office this September, so much so that the Ministry of Finance &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Finansdep/status/1450045492520493056"&gt;sent out a tweet&lt;/a&gt; last month warning that the Minister of Finance doesn’t actually have an account. The translated tweet reads, “We want to inform that Minister of Finance Trygve Slagsvold Vedum does not have private Twitter. Accounts that appear in his name are therefore fake and will be reported.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2dGQKu"&gt;What was different about this most recent fake account, though, was that it was granted a blue checkmark by Twitter. According to &lt;em&gt;NRKbeta&lt;/em&gt;, Vedum’s fake account sent out tweets that oppose his political party’s policies, potentially ruffling some feathers in the political sphere. However, Twitter doesn’t appear to be responsible for the mistake — &lt;em&gt;NRKbeta&lt;/em&gt; found that the Prime Minister’s Office and the NSM were at fault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CaH9CA"&gt;“Unfortunately, there was an error in the reporting that caused a fake account to be verified,” Anne Kristin Hjuske, the head of communications at the Prime Minister’s Office told &lt;em&gt;NRKbeta&lt;/em&gt;. “The account has now been removed and we have made sure that no more fake accounts have been verified. Furthermore, we are currently reviewing our reporting routines to ensure that this does not happen again.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="6vsGja"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“It seems somebody at the Prime Minister’s Office was fooled by the account”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pLrdgC"&gt;The Prime Minister’s Office and NSM were responsible for verifying politicians’ social media accounts following the recent election. The fake account apparently tricked both organizations, got sent along to Twitter, and passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="baq32m"&gt;“Out of nowhere one of these fake accounts shows up verified,” Ståle Grut, the journalist behind the &lt;em&gt;NRKbeta&lt;/em&gt; article told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “It seems somebody at the Prime Minister's Office coordinating the verification was fooled by the account, and it ended up being sent to Twitter along with the other newly appointed ministers who are also now all verified.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IW0kID"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/14/22673213/twitter-verification-application-requests-open-how-to"&gt;Twitter recently revamped its verification process&lt;/a&gt; to specifically prevent the creation of fake accounts. It reopened its verification process this past May after nearly four years of overhauling the system, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/13/22623714/twitter-verification-program-pause-fake-accounts-review"&gt;later briefly put it on pause&lt;/a&gt; after mistakenly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/13/22575025/twitter-verified-fake-accounts-botnet-researcher"&gt;verifying several phony accounts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8f5eRh"&gt;But it seems that no matter how fancy Twitter makes its verification process, it still can’t protect against plain old human error. It remains unclear whether Twitter typically delegates its verification process to outside authorities. If it does, that’s especially concerning for accounts that belong to high-profile government officials, and this mishap is a case in point. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; reached out to Twitter with a request for comment but didn’t immediately hear back.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22799403/twitter-verified-fake-account-norwegian-government"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22799403/twitter-verified-fake-account-norwegian-government</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-23T18:57:43-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-23T18:57:43-05:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon Studios is reportedly trying to make a Mass Effect TV show</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eGJ6woIxJhzU3VFyDnlyCHUJvHE=/60x0:708x432/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70185126/MassEffect_LE_Key_Art_16x9_RGB_768x432.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: BioWare&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="NIQoaH"&gt;According to a report by &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2021/11/the-wheel-of-time-premiere-ratings-amazon-prime-video-mass-effect-lort-of-the-rings-jennifer-salke-qa-1234879517/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deadline&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Amazon isn’t relying on the just-launched&lt;em&gt; Wheel of Time&lt;/em&gt; series and its upcoming Lord of the Rings show to pull in sci-fi/fantasy viewers. The entertainment news outlet reports that Amazon is “nearing a deal to develop a series” based on the &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect&lt;/em&gt; games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="AefmO3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Amazon’s Wheel of Time tries a little too hard to be Game of Thrones","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/16/22785109/amazon-wheel-of-time-tv-show-review-rosamund-pike-game-of-thrones"},{"title":"Amazon’s Lord of the Rings series will premiere in September 2022 ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/2/22606267/lord-of-the-rings-amazon-series-release-date"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="WXCTFT"&gt;While Electronic Arts and BioWare have not announced a series, there have been more than a few hints. Earlier this year, the project director for EA’s remastered &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22256806/mass-effect-legendary-edition-pc-ps4-xbox-one-mac-walters-release-date"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mass Effect: Legendary Edition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; trilogy set &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/mass-effect-director-on-rise-of-video-game-tv-shows-2021-6"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;Business Insider&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that it’s “not a matter of if, but when” a movie or TV show project appears relating to the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PILS5D"&gt;There was also that &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CLrAjEuhtTe/"&gt;interesting Instagram post&lt;/a&gt; in February from Henry Cavill, who may want to add male Commander Shepard to his geeky resume along with Superman and Geralt from &lt;em&gt;The Witcher&lt;/em&gt;. The actor posted an easily-deblurred image hinting at a “secret project?,” and internet sleuths &lt;a href="https://www.thegamer.com/mass-effect-henry-cavill-tv-series-game/"&gt;figured out&lt;/a&gt; it was actually a printout of the Wikipedia entry for&lt;em&gt; Mass Effect 3&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DpGYdn"&gt;Any other details like how this could tie in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/7/21554092/bioware-new-mass-effect-game-announced-n7-day"&gt;with a new game in the series&lt;/a&gt;, are unclear, even if some people — &lt;a href="https://massfanon.fandom.com/wiki/Mass_Effect_(TV_series)#:~:text=Mass%20Effect%20is%20an%20American,Mass%20Effect%20video%20game%20series"&gt;like this very imaginative wiki editor&lt;/a&gt; — already have fan casting done in their head. W Well, there’s one safe guess I can make — it’s probably not going to be based on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/20/14961928/mass-effect-andromeda-review-xbox-ps4-pc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mass Effect: Andromeda&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22799583/mass-effect-bioware-tv-show-movie-amazon-studios-rumor"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22799583/mass-effect-bioware-tv-show-movie-amazon-studios-rumor</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-23T18:15:50-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-23T18:15:50-05:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung is building a new $17 billion advanced chip plant in Texas</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QBUCPU5l1Q0c3l15iyH4zLxXNW4=/0x0:694x463/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70181590/main_visual1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung already has a presence in Austin, Texas.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Samsung&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Ll0b4Z"&gt;Samsung officially announced a new advanced chip-making plant in Texas, that’s estimated to cost around $17 billion and could create 1,800 jobs, as reported previously by &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/samsung-to-choose-taylor-texas-for-17-billion-chipmaking-factory-11637627613"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The new plant will be located in the city of Taylor, roughly 30 miles away from Austin, where Samsung has an existing facility. The new site is roughly 1,200 acres in size, making it larger than Samsung’s Austin plant, the &lt;em&gt;WSJ &lt;/em&gt;notes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Samsung Austin Semiconductor — The new plant will be even larger than this" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZIP5iogAGXi6ogDCHmNwos0w9O4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23038809/Samsung_Austin_Semiconductor_Austin_Aerial.JPG"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Samsung Austin Semiconductor — The new plant will be even larger than this&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="deGfmN"&gt; Kinam Kim, the vice chairman and CEO of Samsung Electronics Device Solutions Division &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.samsung.com/us/sas/News/Detail/202111230901001_News_2021FabExpansion" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;says in a statement&lt;/a&gt; that “With greater manufacturing capacity, we will be able to better serve the needs of our customers and contribute to the stability of the global semiconductor supply chain.” He continued, “In addition to our partners in Texas, we are grateful to the Biden Administration for creating an environment that supports companies like Samsung as we work to expand leading-edge semiconductor manufacturing in the U.S. We also thank the administration and Congress for their bipartisan support to swiftly enact federal incentives for domestic chip production and innovation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vZCnLJ"&gt;Samsung plans to break ground on the location next year, and start producing chips in 2024. Eventually, Samsung is expected to begin using the new plant to produce processors, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/12/22226849/samsung-exynos-2100-chip-processor-galaxy-s21-international"&gt;for its own uses&lt;/a&gt; and for use in other companies’ products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="umagtU"&gt;The city of Taylor also offered Samsung incentives to locate its plant there, which reportedly amount to property tax breaks of over 90 percent for its first ten years, the &lt;em&gt;WSJ &lt;/em&gt;notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gIR3sT"&gt;Samsung is a giant in the memory chip manufacturing game, but it’ll likely use the Taylor plant to manufacture advanced chips for other companies based on their designs. Previous reports have indicated this new plant could produce chips &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/22/22243994/samsung-chipmaking-texas-plant-3nm-10-billion-report"&gt;as advanced as 3nm&lt;/a&gt;. Samsung has previously produced chips for companies like Qualcomm and Nvidia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8nT1t5"&gt;The expansion comes as the global semiconductor shortage &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22777216/global-chip-supply-chain-shortage-holidays-christmas-shopping"&gt;continues to cause major problems&lt;/a&gt; for everyone from console makers to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/5/22765709/bmw-chip-shortage-touchscreen-car-suv-manufacturing"&gt;car manufacturers&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a situation that’s unlikely to abate until at least 2023, according to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/21/22739192/intel-chip-shortage-q3-2021-earning-laptop-revenue"&gt;recent comments from Intel CEO&lt;/a&gt; Pat Gelsinger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SDt1nd"&gt;In response, the Biden administration is attempting to bolster US chip production, reducing the potential for supply chain disruption and reversing the country’s declining share of manufacturing in recent decades. The Senate recently approved $52 billion in subsidies for new chipmaking plants, though the CHIPS Act is yet to pass in the House of Representatives, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-11-23/samsung-is-said-to-pick-texas-site-for-advanced-u-s-chip-plant?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yUmx8s"&gt;The chip-making industry has production capacity increases planned, but many of the new plants won’t be online anytime soon. TSMC and Sony’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/9/22772167/tsmc-sony-semiconductor-fab-factory-japan-2024-7-billion"&gt;new $7 billion chip factory in Japan&lt;/a&gt; won’t see production start until the end of 2024, the same year as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/14/21259094/apple-tsmc-factory-chips-arizona-a-series"&gt;TSMC’s new $12 billion Arizona plant&lt;/a&gt;. TSMC has said it plans to invest over $100 billion in new chip factories over the next three years, while Intel plans to spend a similar amount over the next decade on investments in the US and Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22245325/samsung-building-chipmaking-fab-texas-taylor"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22245325/samsung-building-chipmaking-fab-texas-taylor</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-23T17:41:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-23T17:41:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s digital driver’s license has been delayed to next year</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0DRTLm7NE55KMdFk1uVaiSgpC6w=/0x259:1423x1208/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70184873/lcimg_f986f942_4ae9_4c26_ad87_37d148f9859d.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Apple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zueeoL"&gt;Apple’s digital driver’s license / ID feature won’t be coming until “early 2022,” according to an update to &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/ios/ios-15/"&gt;Apple’s iOS 15 page&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2021/11/23/apple-delays-ios-15-wallet-id-feature-early-2022/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt; noticed&lt;/a&gt;. The change comes after news broke that Apple was looking for strict control over how states roll out the feature, which was previously listed as coming late this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GrrzQa"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/7/22522864/apple-wallet-iphone-airport-ids-hotel-key-card-ios-15-wwdc"&gt;Originally announced at WWDC 2021&lt;/a&gt;, Apple says that the feature will let you use its Wallet app to store your digital identification for use at airport security checkpoints. Of course, the system is dependent on your state supporting it — the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/1/22652051/apple-iphone-drivers-license-state-id-arizona-georgia-ios-15"&gt;company announced&lt;/a&gt; that Arizona and Georgia would be the first to let citizens add their licenses to their phones (with Connecticut, Iowa, Kentucky, Maryland, Oklahoma, and Utah following later) but didn’t specify when exactly that would be happening.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fx8kOyrZGyq6vB6feS39yxgy7Zo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23038550/Screen_Shot_2021_11_23_at_13.36.54.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20211116015952/https://www.apple.com/ios/ios-15/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;WayBack Machine capture&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; from earlier this month shows that the “Coming early 2022” text was added recently.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="lsQrOt"&gt;Earlier this month, a report showed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/14/22781570/apple-making-states-pay-digital-id-service"&gt;how restrictive Apple’s contracts with the states&lt;/a&gt; chosen to lead the program are. &lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt; said, according to the contracts it viewed from Georgia, Arizona, Oklahoma, and Kentucky, that Apple has “sole discretion” concerning how the states marketed the program, how they reported on its success, and even the date that they launched the program and the devices they’re allowed to mark as compatible. States, and therefore taxpayers, are also responsible for funding the program, despite Apple choosing when it launches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cGkaJB"&gt;Apple does have conflicting info on its site about when digital IDs will be available — iOS 15’s &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/ios/ios-15/features/"&gt;“All New Features” page&lt;/a&gt; still says the feature is coming in “late 2021,” but it’s difficult to see that happening now. The holidays and the vacations that come with them are fast approaching, which traditionally makes projects difficult to complete, especially if other organizations (in this case, the state governments) are involved. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9LDdK0"&gt;The feature wasn’t alone in missing the official iOS 15 launch — the new version of the OS was released without a good chunk of the major features that Apple had announced on stage. Many of them &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22732647/apple-ios-15-1-download-release-available-now"&gt;have been added&lt;/a&gt; through updates or have &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/27/22749352/apple-app-privacy-report-ios-15-2-beta-feature"&gt;shown up in the beta&lt;/a&gt; for the upcoming iOS 15.2, though &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22765988/apple-macos-12-monterey-review-macbook-pro-air-imac-m1"&gt;Universal Control is still missing&lt;/a&gt; for those wanting to control their Macs and iPads with the same mouse and keyboard. Apple is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/18/22733044/macos-universal-control-later-this-fall-monterey-feature-delay"&gt;still promising&lt;/a&gt; it’ll launch “later this fall.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="moMYUc"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple’s unexciting 2021 Mac and iPhone software prove it should take a break from annual OS updates","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22771079/apple-macos-monteray-ios-15-mac-iphone-software-operating-system-updates-space-out-features"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22799338/apple-digital-driver-license-delay-2022-ios-15"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22799338/apple-digital-driver-license-delay-2022-ios-15</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-23T17:23:03-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-23T17:23:03-05:00</updated>
    <title>Chris Pratt can be Mario because they’ve apparently got that whole Italian thing figured out</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yuuN7gL5vr429MeDADYqyf6XAck=/0x0:2400x1600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70184768/Screen_Shot_2021_09_23_at_4.14.59_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Nintendo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vjcBj8"&gt;Chris Pratt’s voice as Mario is “phenomenal,” says one of the men who has the most to gain if that’s true. But Pratt likely won’t be putting on Mario’s familiar fake Italian accent for the majority of the film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qGzmgU"&gt;When asked to defend the casting of Chris Pratt (a white American man best known as the &lt;em&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy&lt;/em&gt;’s Star-Lord) as Mario (a denizen of the Mushroom Kingdom &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r4Eudb_Tqg8"&gt;previously voiced&lt;/a&gt; by a white American man of French descent attempting to sound like an Italian plumber from Brooklyn at the request of the character’s Japanese creators, just so we’re clear), producer and Illumination CEO Chris Meledandri &lt;a href="https://toofab.com/2021/11/22/mario-producer-chris-meledandri-defends-casting-non-italian-chris-pratt/"&gt;suggested to &lt;em&gt;TooFab&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that it’s OK because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="u4myl5"&gt;Meledandri himself is an Italian American.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LmXfz9"&gt;Charlie Day, the actor playing Luigi, “actually comes from Italian heritage,” so they’re covered there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="XGktO0"&gt;They’re not going to lean heavily into the “It’s-a-me, Mario!” fake accent in the movie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p id="sz0X15"&gt;“We cover it in the movie, so you’ll see we definitely nod to that, but that’s not the tenor of the performance throughout the film,” says Meledandri. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="K7MGUr"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;absolutely incredible defence of Chris Pratt Mario by an Illumination exec&lt;a href="https://t.co/HRX6Lll22L"&gt;https://t.co/HRX6Lll22L&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/eLlKmtIoCe"&gt;pic.twitter.com/eLlKmtIoCe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— James Whitbrook (@Jwhitbrook) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Jwhitbrook/status/1463152087307542545?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 23, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="c2yGhZ"&gt;I’m not quite sure how we got to this point, but I’m enjoying the show! I suppose we’ll just have to wait and see why Pratt got cast as Mario when the movie arrives in December 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hBdB7s"&gt;Oh, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/1/22758214/chris-pratt-garfield-movie-mario"&gt;he’s also playing Garfield&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22799382/chris-pratt-voice-super-mario-movie-nintendo-illumination-ceo"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22799382/chris-pratt-voice-super-mario-movie-nintendo-illumination-ceo</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-23T16:29:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-23T16:29:57-05:00</updated>
    <title>Funko’s new Star Trek NFTs show that resistance is futile</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ks3r8XEkT4UbwRK-ykvZA0f7e2I=/168x0:1590x948/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70184515/Screen_Shot_2021_11_23_at_2.54.42_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="zbYvqq"&gt;Funko Pop is teaming up with ViacomCBS for its latest “Digital Pop” NFT collectibles, with a new series of blockchain-based cards featuring classic Star Trek characters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qzRkVT"&gt;Funko’s “Digital Pop” NFTs aren’t a new thing: they’ve been around since July, &lt;a href="https://digital.funko.com/drop/12/star-trek-series-1"&gt;and the new Star Trek ones&lt;/a&gt; are just the latest incarnation. And as is the case with the other Digital Pop sets, certain specific rare NFTs cards will also include a free physical Funko Pop figure too, which is a potentially nice bonus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3ndWqV"&gt;But there’s something uniquely depressing about Star Trek NFTs specifically, given the utopian ideals of the Federation and the very intentionally post-scarcity world in which the franchise is set. Thanks to the ubiquity of advanced technology like replicators (gadgets that can instantly materialize any item out of thin air), &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;’s worlds (broadly) don’t revolve around money.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zoc77wGychSoyUJJKUPL26eEBus=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23038192/Screen_Shot_2021_11_23_at_3.05.22_PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="1GFM8I"&gt;NFTs, on the other hand, are intentionally limited digital items based on environmentally dubious cryptocurrencies that create a false dichotomy of ownership and scarcity for the purpose of attaching an artificially inflated value — or more or less the opposite of the future &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt; envisions. The entire concept feels more like the kind of straw man a classic &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt; episode would set up, with a moralizing speech about how “greed is bad... in space!” hamfistedly closing out the episode. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zcvxUr"&gt;Or, as my colleague Adi Robertson more put it, “Ah yes, &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt;, the series that famously explored the concept of ‘What if computer-created items were extremely scarce and induplicable?’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FbGmfL"&gt;The new series of 120 digital cards will include various characters &lt;em&gt;Star Trek: The Original Series, &lt;/em&gt;rendered in Funko’s inexplicably popular style, will go on sale on November 30th at 2PM ET. A total of 48,000 packs of cards will be sold, with 36,000 standard packs with five Digital Pop cards going for $9.99, while 12,000 premium packs with 15 cards will set you back $29.99. As with the other Digital Pop NFTs, you’ll have to buy them on the Droppp.io app, using the WAX Blockchain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yDRU2Y"&gt;Resistance is futile. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22798955/funko-digital-pop-star-trek-nfts-why"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22798955/funko-digital-pop-star-trek-nfts-why</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chaim Gartenberg</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-23T15:36:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-23T15:36:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple sues NSO Group for attacking iPhones with Pegasus spyware</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/l-EGsMPxGf0PtaoDncVOe6B8NEA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70183455/acastro_180604_1777_apple_wwdc_0004.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oJFqiU"&gt;Now Apple has followed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/29/20938676/whatsapp-nso-group-spyware-hack-encrypted-chat-lawsuit"&gt;WhatsApp and its parent company Meta&lt;/a&gt; (formerly known as Facebook) in &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2021/11/apple-sues-nso-group-to-curb-the-abuse-of-state-sponsored-spyware/"&gt;suing Pegasus spyware maker NSO Group&lt;/a&gt;. Along with promising new information about how NSO Group infected targeted iPhones via a zero-click exploit that researchers later dubbed ForcedEntry, Apple says it’s “seeking a permanent injunction to ban NSO Group from using any Apple software, services, or devices.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="ck7oLY"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Apple: NSO agreed to the iCloud Terms of Service&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rpQ3TQ"&gt;Senior VP of software engineering Craig Federighi &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761724/apple-craig-federighi-ios-sideloading-web-summit-2021-european-commission-digital-markets-act"&gt;didn’t mention sideloading this time&lt;/a&gt; but says in a statement, “State-sponsored actors like the NSO Group spend millions of dollars on sophisticated surveillance technologies without effective accountability. That needs to change...Apple devices are the most secure consumer hardware on the market — but private companies developing state-sponsored spyware have become even more dangerous.” Apple and WhatsApp aren’t alone in their push against NSO Group in court, as last year, tech companies &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22194930/microsoft-google-cisco-vmware-internet-association-amicus-brief-nso-group-spyware-whatsapp-facebook"&gt;including Microsoft and Google filed a brief supporting Facebook’s lawsuit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tYaPnj"&gt;Pegasus spyware is designed to let governments remotely access a phone’s microphones, cameras, and other data on both iPhones and Androids, according to Apple’s press release. It’s also designed to be able to infect phones without requiring any action from the user and without leaving a trace, according to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22589942/nso-group-pegasus-project-amnesty-investigation-journalists-activists-targeted"&gt;reports that came out earlier&lt;/a&gt; this year from a journalistic coalition called the Pegasus Project and Apple’s complaint. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Zuwfvv"&gt;Apple also cites reports that the spyware has been used against journalists, activists, and politicians, despite &lt;a href="https://www.calcalistech.com/ctech/articles/0,7340,L-3912882,00.html"&gt;NSO’s claims&lt;/a&gt; that its governmental clients are forbidden from using the spyware against those sorts of targets. It’s understandable why Apple, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/5/18169781/apple-google-privacy-troll-billboard"&gt;“what happens on your iPhone, stays on your iPhone” company&lt;/a&gt;, would be upset about its devices and services being used to carry out what it calls “human rights abuses.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="0UK4TH"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The lawsuit is a “stake in the ground” for Apple&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hmGje8"&gt;Apple’s senior director of commercial litigation Heather Grenier says in a statement to &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/11/23/technology/apple-nso-group-lawsuit.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; the lawsuit is meant to be a “stake in the ground, to send a clear signal” that the company won’t allow its users to suffer “this type of abuse.” Part of Apple’s argument &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/pdfs/Apple_v_NSO_Complaint_112321.pdf"&gt;laid out in the complaint&lt;/a&gt; (PDF) is that NSO violated Apple’s terms of service because the group created “more than one hundred” Apple IDs to help it send data to targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="8cZ79H"&gt;The Court has personal jurisdiction over Defendants because, on information and belief, they created more than one hundred Apple IDs to carry out their attacks and also agreed to Apple’s iCloud Terms and Conditions (“iCloud Terms”), including a mandatory and enforceable forum selection and exclusive jurisdiction clause that constitutes express consent to the jurisdiction of this Court&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="znIVpi"&gt;In Apple’s complaint, it breaks down how the attack worked — using the Apple IDs it created, NSO would send data to a target via iMessage (after determining that they were using an iPhone), which was maliciously crafted to turn off the iPhone’s logging. That would then let NSO secretly install the Pegasus spyware and control what was being collected on the phone. Apple says that the specific vulnerability that NSO was using was patched in iOS 14.8, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22672352/apple-spyware-gateway-iphone-software-update-nso-pegasus"&gt;you can read more about here&lt;/a&gt;. The summary is that NSO was sending files that exploited a bug in how iMessage rendered GIFs and PDFs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E62I1t"&gt;Apple says in its press release that, thanks to improvements it’s made to iOS 15 security, it “has not observed any evidence of successful remote attacks against devices running iOS 15 and later versions.” When the Pegasus Project was publishing its reports in July, Amnesty International said that the latest versions of iOS (at the time iOS 14.6) were susceptible to attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K40P9H"&gt;For more information about the reporting done on Pegasus, its capabilities, and its potential targets, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22589942/nso-group-pegasus-project-amnesty-investigation-journalists-activists-targeted"&gt;see our explainer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="nI8lDS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"NSO’s Pegasus spyware: here’s what we know","url":"https://www.theverge.com/22589942/nso-group-pegasus-project-amnesty-investigation-journalists-activists-targeted"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="jMtOKu"&gt;In addition to its lawsuit against NSO, Apple says it’ll be supporting “organizations pursuing cybersurveillance research and advocacy,” both financially and with technical resources. The company says it’ll distribute $10 million (plus any damages it wins from its lawsuit) to groups working on counter-surveillance and pledges in its press release to give free “technical, threat intelligence, and engineering assistance” to Citizen Lab, a group of researchers that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/9/13/22672352/apple-spyware-gateway-iphone-software-update-nso-pegasus"&gt;were involved with the Pegasus Project&lt;/a&gt; and that helped Apple discover and patch NSO’s exploits. Apple also says it’ll do the same for other organizations “where appropriate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7ozzFC"&gt;NSO was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/3/22761565/nso-group-pegasus-spyware-entity-list-us-government-human-rights"&gt;recently added to the US Entity List&lt;/a&gt;, which limits the ways American companies can sell or provide their technology to the company. According to &lt;a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2021/11/23/1040509/france-macron-nso-in-crisis-sanctions/"&gt;a report by the MIT Technology Review&lt;/a&gt;, the sanction has been seriously detrimental both to employee morale at NSO Group, and the company’s ability to do business. The report says the company has to request permission from the US government to purchase items like laptops running Windows and iPhones, and that the government has said its default decision would be to turn down those requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dQC9ov"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://embed.documentcloud.org/documents/21116782-apple_v_nso_complaint_112321/?embed=1&amp;amp;responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1" title="Apple_v_NSO_Complaint_112321 (Hosted by DocumentCloud)" width="700" height="905" style="border: 1px solid #aaa; width: 100%; height: 800px; height: calc(100vh - 100px);" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-forms allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="EJcX4O"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updated November 23rd, 3:36PM ET:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added context about sanctions against NSO, and the alleged misuse of Pegasus.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22798917/apple-nso-group-spyware-pegasus-cybersecurity-research"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22798917/apple-nso-group-spyware-pegasus-cybersecurity-research</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-23T15:35:43-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-23T15:35:43-05:00</updated>
    <title>PlayStation is facing a gender discrimination lawsuit</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Sony presents new games for playstation" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/11dSBahxyQ0nolg21h7PclAIHMU=/0x56:5592x3784/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70184178/1040895722.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Henning Kaiser/picture alliance via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="o0jXqW"&gt;PlayStation has been hit with a lawsuit that alleges gender discrimination and wrongful termination, as first reported by &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/playstation-lawsuit-alleges-gender-discrimination-6d3b5ef7-b34c-4e45-94e5-f6424983e8a7.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Axios&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. According to the details of &lt;a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/21116609-majosony?responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1"&gt;the lawsuit&lt;/a&gt;, former IT security analyst Emma Majo is seeking to establish a class action suit to represent other women who might’ve been affected by PlayStation’s alleged gender discrimination. The lawsuit claims that “Sony tolerates and cultivates a work environment that discriminates against female employees,” alleging that women were denied promotions and weren’t paid equally to male workers who held similar positions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lwyZyG"&gt; This comes less than a week after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787848/playstation-boss-jim-ryan-calls-out-activision-blizzard-staff-memo"&gt;PlayStation boss Jim Ryan sent out an email&lt;/a&gt; to employees condemning Activision Blizzard’s response to reports of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/16/22785457/activision-blizzard-bobby-kotick-ceo-wall-street-journal-wsj-report-allegations"&gt;CEO Bobby Kotick’s alleged abusive behavior and history of harassment&lt;/a&gt; during his 30 years at the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="q6ut3k"&gt;In the company-wide notice, Ryan stated that he was “disheartened and frankly stunned to read” that Activision Blizzard “has not done enough to address a deep-seated culture of discrimination and harassment.” He also said that PlayStation doesn’t think Blizzard’s “statements of response properly address the situation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4wjUMb"&gt;The lawsuit against Sony describes Majo’s experience as a female employee at Sony from 2015 to 2021, alleging she was continually denied an answer about how to get a promotion and claims that she was demoted because of her inquiries about it. Majo also claims that she heard managers “make gender-biased comments about female workers” that implied women are more “emotional” and “less professional” than male employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="YsDcog"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Majo claims that she was wrongfully terminated “because she is female”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="idXW3b"&gt;Majo submitted a signed statement to Sony that addressed the company’s supposed gender bias in 2021, the suit claims. She got fired “soon after,” allegedly due to the closure of a department that Majo says she didn’t belong to. Instead, Majo argues that she was wrongfully terminated “because she is female and because she spoke up about discrimination against females.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ag7NrF"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; reached out to Sony with a request for comment but didn’t immediately hear back.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22798969/playstation-gender-discrimination-lawsuit-blizzard-company-culture"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22798969/playstation-gender-discrimination-lawsuit-blizzard-company-culture</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-23T15:30:20-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-23T15:30:20-05:00</updated>
    <title>ConstitutionDAO will shut down after losing bid for Constitution</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IhrOMB9C9XNzcXDNn5Qtwh4Q-30=/0x0:1746x1164/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70184153/constdao.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;One of 13 remaining copies of the Official Edition of the Constitution. | Image: Sotheby’s&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rkbs0O"&gt;The organizers behind ConstitutionDAO have decided to shut the group down after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/17/22787993/constitutiondao-crypto-buy-us-constitution-copy-sothebys-ethereum"&gt;raising $47 million in cryptocurrency&lt;/a&gt; and then &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/18/22790452/constitutiondao-loses-auction-for-rare-us-constitution-copy-sothebys"&gt;failing to win an auction&lt;/a&gt; for a rare copy of the US Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h36IN2"&gt;Many members of ConstitutionDAO had expressed hope that the group could live on, albeit with some alternative goal given that there are currently no other famous copies of the Constitution at auction. Group leaders initially floated launching a new token for members who wanted to take part in the group’s continuation, called We The People tokens, but later backtracked, saying they should have given it more consideration. It was never made clear what, exactly, the group might focus on if it were to continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Z1pGbZ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The community has taken all actions that it was organized to accomplish.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1fvdGC"&gt;Now, five days after the auction, group organizers say they’re shutting down ConstitutionDAO for good. “The community has taken all actions that it was organized to accomplish,” Graham Novak, a ConstitutionDAO organizer, wrote in the group’s Discord. The Discord channel will remain operational for the next two weeks, then shift into a read-only mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TX0AQ9"&gt;“We have determined that building and maintaining an ongoing project is not something that we as a core team are able to support, given the technical and administrative requirements of doing it properly,” Novak wrote. He said there will be “no time limit” on claiming refunds for those who contributed Ether for the auction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8YSAXX"&gt;Organizers didn’t say how much money has been returned via refunds yet, but there’s been concern that contributors may get back much less than they put in. Gas fees — the transaction fee you have to pay to accomplish things on the Ethereum network — are fairly high, even for something as basic as sending money to another party. So someone who sent their money to ConstitutionDAO and now requests it back may find themselves with a lot less after paying for the round-trip journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eRrqMy"&gt;Novak calls ConstitutionDAO a “landmark event” that showed the power of “web3.” The group organized rapidly over the course of a week in an attempt to win an early printing of the US Constitution at an auction at Sotheby’s. The group &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/19/22791989/citadel-ceo-ken-griffin-won-constitutiondao-sothebys-auction"&gt;ultimately lost to Ken Griffin&lt;/a&gt;, a billionaire hedge fund CEO, who bought the document for $43 million. ConstitutionDAO organizers later said spending more would have left too little money to care for the document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DVasy1"&gt;“It is our sincere hope that this project will spark many others,” Novak writes.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22799192/constitutiondao-shutting-down-lost-auction-refunds"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/11/23/22799192/constitutiondao-shutting-down-lost-auction-refunds</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kastrenakes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-11-23T15:12:31-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-11-23T15:12:31-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Simplisafe Black Friday sale is here</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x1t_1y7RnJow-1Y4EppgJd0xA34=/8x0:851x562/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/70184082/Screenshot_2021_11_23_123108.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mb79Fz"&gt;The home security experts at &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/Verge/type/dlg/sid/VergeSimplisafeSale112321/https://simplisafe.com/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Simplisafe&lt;/a&gt; are offering big discounts on their home security systems during a Black Friday sale that runs until December 1st. This sale is marking down any new security system by up to 60 percent and will throw in a free indoor camera for your trouble. (If you’re still shopping around, make sure to pay a visit to our &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21583092/black-friday-guide-cyber-monday-tech-gadgets"&gt;Black Friday hub&lt;/a&gt; with ongoing coverage of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22759214/black-friday-early-deals-best-headphones-laptops-gaming-tvs-tech-sale"&gt;best early Black Friday deals&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JPaUwV"&gt;Our own smart home expert, Jennifer Pattison Tuohy, says that “Simplisafe is a good, easy-to-use smart security system that doesn’t rely solely on an app — you can manage the whole system from its keypad. It also has a decent selection of smart home devices to add on to your system, including an excellent door lock and new outdoor camera.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cuzh3Y"&gt;We largely consider Simplisafe products to be a solid value for anyone looking to step up their home security. However, Simplisafe products aren’t compatible with any products outside of their ecosystem and require ongoing subscriptions to continue monitoring. The standard plan costs $15 a month, but if you want to access your system through their mobile app, expect to pay $25 a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="stQAve"&gt;If you’re at a bit of a loss when it comes to home security, Simplisafe has a few pre-fab options for you to consider that we’ve listed below. Just note that the 60 percent discount requires you to sign up for a free month of interactive monitoring. This isn’t a huge deal, as you can cancel after your first month and still reap the benefits. Every system, whether you build your own or use a suggestion from Simplisafe, still gets a free indoor camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="mNGZZ9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10882965"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ijOpLp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10883000"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="lgdknm"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10882988"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="TVOo5C"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="S0pOgk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/11/23/22798813/simplisafe-home-security-black-friday-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/2021/11/23/22798813/simplisafe-home-security-black-friday-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alice Newcome-Beill</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
