<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-02-18T09:29:46-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T09:29:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T09:29:46-05:00</updated>
    <title>Fall Guys: Ultimate Knockout is coming to Xbox Series X / S and Xbox One</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="fall guys" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pDHogLEpHtKgkHlFZv-12f92osY=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68836072/ss_b2b6b170330b8af1f50d0e90efad984adafeb281.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="uDooaf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fall Guys: Ultimate Knockout&lt;/em&gt;, Mediatonic’s charming platformer battle royale title, is coming to Xbox Series X / S and Xbox One this summer, Microsoft announced in &lt;a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2021/02/18/fall-guys-ultimate-knockout-xbox-this-summer/"&gt;a blog post&lt;/a&gt; today. The news comes just one day after Mediatonic announced that the game was going to be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22288187/fall-guys-ultimate-knockout-nintendo-switch-mediatonic"&gt;ported to the Nintendo Switch&lt;/a&gt; sometime this summer as well. While no firm release date has been announced, both ports will likely launch within the same time frame. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LcfjtX"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fall Guys&lt;/em&gt; originally released in 2020 on PC via Steam and PS4, where it was a free title for users with an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/26/21402473/fall-guys-sony-ps-plus-most-downloaded-game-all-time"&gt;active PlayStation Plus subscription&lt;/a&gt;. The game mixes battle royale with the platformer genre, where players compete in elimination-type challenges. The title draws inspiration from competitive game shows like &lt;em&gt;Wipeout&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I57O8m"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fall Guys: Ultimate Knockout&lt;/em&gt; is currently available on PC and PS4 and is backward compatible on PS5. &lt;em&gt;Fall Guys&lt;/em&gt; also received a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/22/21397170/fall-guys-mobile-china-game-developer"&gt;mobile version&lt;/a&gt;, but it is only available in China. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="G6aHDE"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Fall Guys is coming to Nintendo Switch","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/17/22288187/fall-guys-ultimate-knockout-nintendo-switch-mediatonic"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289166/fall-guys-ultimate-knockout-xbox-series-x-s-one-announced"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289166/fall-guys-ultimate-knockout-xbox-series-x-s-one-announced</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T09:16:05-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T09:16:05-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Halo Bolt portable car jump-starter is more than a battery saver</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/c0EAdcMS0KLjJnMLUAPKId88jk4=/0x1:2040x1361/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68836020/khatton_210216_4411_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Kaitlin Hatton / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fRNeGs"&gt;Getting my license at age 16 was a breath of fresh air. It was me, my used 2007 Mazda6, and the open road. As anyone who knew me at the time will say, though, I was a misfortune magnet as a teenager and this extended to my car. There was even a running joke among my peers that I was on a first-name basis with the local tow truck drivers because &lt;a href="https://ohio.aaa.com/membership.html"&gt;AAA&lt;/a&gt; had to dispatch them on a regular basis — a dead battery being one of the more common mishaps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zIYf4c"&gt;Whether the battery died so often because I left a light on, the weather was frighteningly cold, or I waited too long to replace the battery, doesn’t really matter. However, my mom eventually saw fit to save me both time and money by gifting me the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Halo-Portable-Laptop-Charger-Starter/dp/B079FSPRXM/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Halo Bolt Portable Car Jump Starter&lt;/a&gt; so I would always have a way to give my little car a boost when I needed it most. Neither of us knew how often I would actually use it. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cDxG7dlPVPbGrxfPN31e3d_n0po=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22310675/khatton_210216_4411_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Kaitlin Hatton / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Halo Bolt can be attached to the battery using the short jumper cables.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="LnfbJ9"&gt;As my car aged and I put thousands of miles on it driving across Ohio and back to attend college, it needed more and more attention. On average, I would use my Halo Bolt charger at least once every few months, and it always worked. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fwYc4M"&gt;The device comes with its own set of short jumper cables which store easily in its carrier bag. The Bolt’s manufacturer says it can jump-start a standard car’s battery up to 217 times. (Luckily, I didn’t have to test it quite that often.) Additionally, the company claims that one of these chargers can jump a car, boat, lawn mower, or motorcycle. In between uses, simply plug it into a wall socket for a few hours before returning the charger to the car. It fits snugly under my driver’s seat and retains its charge for long periods of time without needing to be topped up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D0wRZB"&gt;The real value for me, however, comes from the ability to plug other electronic devices into it through its two 2.4A USB ports and three-prong AC outlet. Of my Mazda’s two power sockets, only one worked, and more often than not, I found myself in need of multiple outlets. Using the Halo Bolt’s two USB ports, I could quickly and easily charge my phone, my iPod Touch, and even the occasional laptop. When not actively jumping a car, it can charge multiple devices at once. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/I0TV5fruixOqehBqmy1QOMt9cu0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22310680/khatton_210216_4411_0008.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Kaitlin Hatton / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Bolt includes two USB ports and an AC outlet for portable charging.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="wOdj0G"&gt;Coincidentally, when I said goodbye to my first car, I seemed to have shed the bad luck that haunted me. I have yet to use my Halo Bolt to jump-start my newest vehicle, but I still find uses for the portable charger. It comes in handy when a storm has knocked out my apartment’s power supply. I’ve been able to keep my phone charged, which gives me peace of mind knowing I can contact loved ones or ask for help in case of an emergency. The product listing claims the Halo Bolt offers enough charge to allow for dozens of hours of talk time, depending on your phone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JSaNNZ"&gt;Finally, the Bolt has an LED floodlight, which I’ve used in tandem with a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01GCT9VIO?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;manual flashlight&lt;/a&gt; to see my way around my apartment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4e9EeY"&gt;The Halo Bolt weighs less than three pounds and comes in a variety of colors and patterns, including paisley, floral, graphite, chevron, camouflage, and more. The Halo Bolt 58830 model runs about $80, which is well worth the peace of mind that comes with having a power source to jump my car’s battery or to see me through a power outage.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9nwdf6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:10348983"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iG5zAm"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XJ7eqd"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SZ5hqX"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22288004/halo-bolt-car-battery-jump-start-charger-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22288004/halo-bolt-car-battery-jump-start-charger-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kaitlin Hatton</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The team behind indie adventure Minit returns with a side-scrolling racing game</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/x5xwkSzY9y1sCUXOIud6vVx3QrY=/0x0:1200x800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68835872/minit_funracer_x4_7.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Devolver Digital&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Qj2xHF"&gt;The indie gem &lt;em&gt;Minit&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/7/17207310/minit-indie-game-review-die-every-60-seconds-love-letter-classic-gaming"&gt;released back in 2018&lt;/a&gt;, felt like a breath of fresh air. The monochromatic adventure game took a seemingly absurd time constraint — killing the player every 60 seconds — and turned it into both a passionate love letter to top-down classics like &lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda &lt;/em&gt;and an ingenious and clever quest that threw constant surprises at the player. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xteSAm"&gt;Now, the core team behind &lt;em&gt;Minit — Nuclear Throne &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Disc Room &lt;/em&gt;developer Jan Willem Nijman, designer Kitty Calis, composer Jukio Kallio, and artist Dominik Johann&lt;em&gt; — &lt;/em&gt;are back with a new spinoff title, &lt;em&gt;Minit Fun Racer. &lt;/em&gt;The game takes the same core idea and applies it to a side-scrolling biking game reminiscent of arcade titles of decades past. All proceeds of the game, which is being published for free by indie label Devolver Digital, go to charity, including Doctors Without Borders and Special Effect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="631uEG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Minit Fun Racer &lt;/em&gt;releases today for $2.99 on both Steam and itch.io, with the latter store having a pay-what-you-want option for those who’d like to give more. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pnOMa1wQKt9duVxTPS5oVSAbJsM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22310133/minit_funracer_x4_4.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Devolver Digital&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Ro6mr5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Minit Fun Racer &lt;/em&gt;has less of a narrative than the game it’s based on and an even tighter time constraint of less than 10 seconds to begin with. You’re simply plopped down onto a highway full of obstacles and challenged to find your way to the end before the timer runs out and you start over from the beginning. But &lt;em&gt;Minit Fun Racer &lt;/em&gt;lives up to the original by hiding scores of secrets to find through experimentation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LFkz3i"&gt;The main engine of progress in the game is earning coins and using the currency to unlock new upgrades, which, in turn, help you progress further along the route. But there are Easter eggs and fun little side quest-style unlockables — like an air horn for waking up the sleeping cats by the side of the road or an impromptu helicopter chase if you bump two cop cars — that make the game worth exploring in full. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Nwtxi8"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“Our philosophy has always been if you have fun making something it really shines through in the final product.” &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qx6v5a"&gt;“We wanted to make a full game, not just something you would buy just for charity,” says Calis. “The bigger it gets, the more we can help, and in the end we want people to have a good time and to do good, too.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A1hFmt"&gt;In my first few play sessions last week with a preview build of the game, I died — a lot, as is expected. But after my first few upgrades, I felt like I was making steady progress and really enjoying the fast-paced, trial-and-error design. And the new music from Kallio, a longtime collaborator of Nijman’s who also co-wrote the catchy &lt;em&gt;Fall Guys &lt;/em&gt;soundtrack&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;is a fantastic addition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vL6pOo"&gt;“Our philosophy has always been if you have fun making something it really shines through in the final product,” Nijman says. Asked about other &lt;em&gt;Minit &lt;/em&gt;spinoffs or sequels in the future, Nijman and Calis say they aren’t yet ruling out future works — or as Nijman called it, a “Minit cinematic universe” — using the game’s pixel art style or its core time constraint. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VROxgK"&gt;“Never say never,” Calis says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dXVBVH"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287453/minit-fun-racer-charity-game-release-date-announce"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287453/minit-fun-racer-charity-game-release-date-announce</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Statt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Bravely Default is a classic RPG series designed for lapsed fans</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cwamv0YKNVNUA4_XsdTe2rLv-Yk=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68835901/Switch_BRAVELYDEFAULTII_screen_01.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="IgAb6j"&gt;When Masashi Takahashi, a producer at Square Enix, started working on &lt;em&gt;Bravely Default&lt;/em&gt;, he had a very specific audience in mind. Takahashi had grown up playing classic turn-based roleplaying games — he distinctly remembers watching his older brother play &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy III&lt;/em&gt; while he was still in kindergarten — and felt that many modern RPGs had become too complex, leaving older players behind. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4c6QHl"&gt;“They seem kind of impenetrable,” he says of modern games. “I thought if I could make a game that was able to make [older players] recall things they liked about games when they were younger, and create a game for that type of audience, that was one thing that spurred me forward.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cMP1Gh"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/2/6/5383040/bravely-default-nintendo-3ds-review"&gt;The first &lt;em&gt;Bravely Default&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; launched on the Nintendo 3DS in 2014, and it was an experience clearly inspired by earlier &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; games, starring a ragtag group of heroes traveling through a fantasy world powered by four magic crystals. Its defining feature was also the reason it had such a strange name: in battle, players could choose to be “brave” or “default,” in order to go all-in on an attack or stack chances for a more opportune time. It was followed by &lt;em&gt;Bravely Second: End Layer&lt;/em&gt; in 2016, also on the 3DS, and next week the series makes its debut on the Nintendo Switch with &lt;em&gt;Bravely Default II&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="Zv4yrB"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“They seem kind of impenetrable.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="xRV7Zn"&gt;The sequel takes place in a new fantasy realm and stars a new cast of heroes, but the formula is largely the same. The strange naming convention, Takahashi says, is inspired by other iconic Japanese RPG series. When a new, numbered &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Dragon Quest&lt;/em&gt; comes out, fans know it will be a brand-new adventure. Takahashi wanted the same kind of clean slate for the next &lt;em&gt;Bravely Default&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ikKw07"&gt;One difference eagle-eyed fans might notice, however, is that while the first two games in the franchise were developed by Square Enix and a partner studio called Silicon Studio, &lt;em&gt;Bravely Default II&lt;/em&gt; is being helmed by a relatively new company called Clay Tech Works. However, there isn’t much disconnect between the games, as Clay Tech was founded by some of the key staff from Silicon. “Although the public may be hearing of Clay Tech Works for the first time with this game, they are people we’ve worked with for a long time,” says Takahashi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Uqjzo8"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mlpR7bXopF0?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QsyBPq"&gt;Coincidentally, Shota Fukebaru, director at Clay Tech, &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; got his start in RPGs with &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy III&lt;/em&gt; at a young age. And both Fukebaru and Takahashi say that &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy V&lt;/em&gt; and its job system — which gave players the ability to customize their fighters by assigning specific roles, and became a key feature in the &lt;em&gt;Bravely&lt;/em&gt; series — were extremely influential on their careers. “I remember playing that game and thinking, ‘Wow, this is something I want to do someday,’” Fukebaru says. “That’s where that dream originated for me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;div id="KQyQFP"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:1255519"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OX8D5s"&gt;Development on the sequel faced some challenges. Like most studios around the world, the team of around 50 at Clay Tech had to adapt to working from home, finding ways to effectively communicate with each other over Zoom meetings. There was also the process of taking a series originally designed for a dual-screened device and adapting the interface to work on the Switch’s single display. Naturally, though, the change in hardware was mostly beneficial; Takahashi says the team was able to make more detailed characters and a soundtrack that wasn’t limited by the 3DS’s tiny speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3eXBN5"&gt;Takahashi also says that the team has been able to learn key lessons from each release and apply that to subsequent titles. The original &lt;em&gt;Bravely Default&lt;/em&gt; was criticized for having poorly defined characters, for instance, something the developers tried to remedy in the first sequel. And when &lt;em&gt;Bravely Second&lt;/em&gt; players complained that the story was a little too YA, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/12/17561880/octopath-traveler-review-nintendo-switch"&gt;a follow-up called &lt;em&gt;Octopath Traveler&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; focused exclusively on adult characters and themes. Finally, while &lt;em&gt;Octopath&lt;/em&gt; had an ambitious story featuring eight different characters — hence the strange title — this meant that there wasn’t a clearly defined protagonist, something the team is aiming to fix in &lt;em&gt;Bravely Default II&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bn0Bk3"&gt;The new game is also launching at a time when classic JRPGs are experiencing something of a renaissance. Outside of the &lt;em&gt;Bravely&lt;/em&gt; series, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/30/16951126/square-enix-tokyo-rpg-factory-lost-sphear-switch-ps4-pc"&gt;Square Enix studio Tokyo RPG Factory has been steadfastly focused on the genre&lt;/a&gt;, while indie creators have explored new ideas through games like &lt;em&gt;Undertale&lt;/em&gt;. When the creators of the classic series &lt;em&gt;Suikoden&lt;/em&gt; crowdfunded a spiritual successor last year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/7/27/21340344/eiyuden-chronicle-suikoden-spiritual-successor-kickstarter-funded"&gt;it was a resounding success&lt;/a&gt;. For Takahashi, who has been thinking about the genre since he was a five-year-old, it’s been rewarding to see so much renewed appetite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iChz7H"&gt;“This is something I’m really happy about,” he says. “Of course I really enjoy making these games — but I enjoy playing them as well.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287791/bravely-default-2-nintendo-switch-interview-square-enix"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22287791/bravely-default-2-nintendo-switch-interview-square-enix</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tracking down mystery boats on the high seas  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Tracking down mystery boats on the high seas  " src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/23Aewejvca1Uyln0lC_aP0k96_s=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68835882/Thumb_Textless.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Alex Parkin&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="M5SEST"&gt;Out on the high seas, more than 200 miles from shore, seafood companies can operate with almost no oversight. These are ungoverned, international waters where it’s easier for companies to get away with overfishing and abuses like modern-day slavery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zcP1vY"&gt;Scientists using new hacks for old technology are slowly changing that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZYjADs"&gt;Two decades ago, large vessels began carrying a little box that connects to what’s called the maritime Automatic Identification System (AIS). It sends out a radio signal with information about the ship, like an identifying number, and its size, course, and speed. That’s supposed to help ships avoid running into each other. It also helps authorities see where vessels are when they’re close to shore. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a5C4di"&gt;After the 9/11 attacks, AIS started getting more attention from the US government. It saw the tech as a way to keep an eye on potential threats to national security at sea. The US Coast Guard contracted the telecommunications company &lt;a href="https://www.orbcomm.com/PDF/datasheet/Satellite-AIS-Surveillance-Security.pdf"&gt;Orbcomm&lt;/a&gt; to launch satellites that could pick up on AIS signals from space. Meanwhile, the &lt;a href="http://www.esa.int/Enabling_Support/Space_Engineering_Technology/i_Atlantis_i_leaves_Columbus_with_a_radio_eye_on_Earth_s_sea_traffic"&gt;Norwegian government&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://artes.esa.int/sat-ais/overview"&gt;European Space Agency&lt;/a&gt; were developing similar technology. When the first AIS-enabled satellites were launched in 2008, that was a game-changer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xDMsUv"&gt;Now, satellites can pick up on a vessel’s AIS signals no matter where the ship is sailing. In &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/11/14/7219261/global-fishing-watch-map-tracks-illegal-fishing-across-the-globe"&gt;2014&lt;/a&gt;, environmental groups and Google partnered up to create a near real-time &lt;a href="https://globalfishingwatch.org/map/?locale=en"&gt;map&lt;/a&gt; that traces the movement of about 60,000 commercial fishing boats with AIS. The effort is called Global Fishing Watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="So8gB0"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; spoke with Jennifer Jacquet and Gabrielle Carmine, two scientists on a mission to find out who’s doing what out on the open ocean. Check out the video above to see how they used AIS and some old-school sleuthing to spot corporate actors on the high seas. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22289075/high-seas-overfishing-exploitation-tracking-ais-tech-scientists"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22289075/high-seas-overfishing-exploitation-tracking-ais-tech-scientists</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T08:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Razer Book 13 review: stop gaming, and get to work</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;Business on the lid, party in the keyboard&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="EcpNYl"&gt;For years, Razer has made some of the best gaming laptops on the market. They’re not uniquely famous for their high performance (Blades are powerful machines but not the fastest out there) or their prices (which are high). They’re famous for their high-quality build and their premium design. In short, Razer makes the best-looking gaming laptops on the market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t3lwJh"&gt;Razer has decided this year that this aesthetic shouldn’t be limited to gaming laptops. In its first notebook designed for productivity instead of gaming, Razer has combined its signature look and feel with a 60Hz 16:10 touchscreen and a lower-power processor with integrated graphics. The Razer Book aims to be a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21499199/razer-blade-15-advanced-edition-gaming-laptop-2020-review"&gt;Razer Blade&lt;/a&gt; on the outside and a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21546784/dell-xps-13-late-2020-review-design-specs-price-features"&gt;Dell XPS 13&lt;/a&gt; on the inside — and it mostly succeeds. Razer has made an excellent laptop with performance rivaling that of the top Windows clamshells on the market. That said, it’s pricey for what it offers, and it has a few drawbacks that mean it won’t be the right choice for everyone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Razer Book 13 keyboard seen from above. The keys display a green backlighting." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fe8-f1VUQmxBbLTr9bDvEZgu_z4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22290553/akrales_210203_4381_0116.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are 16.8 million colors in this keyboard, according to Razer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="s63e6v"&gt;On the outside, the Razer Book 13 borrows many of the Blade Stealth 13’s signature features. Razer’s three-headed snake adorns the lid. You may also recognize the customizable per-key RGB keyboard with speaker grilles on each side. (Unlike what you’ll see on some more &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21536996/msi-ge66-raider-dragonshield-edition-gaming-laptop-review-rtx-2070-super-300hz"&gt;garish gaming rigs&lt;/a&gt;, the lighting on these keys looks professional and adds to the sophisticated vibe.) The chassis is CNC-machined aluminum, with a smooth metallic finish. This is a fancy way of saying it’s quite nice; the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21570497/apple-macbook-pro-2020-m1-review"&gt;MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt; is made of the same material, as are many of the best Windows laptops including the XPS 13 and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22264792/hp-spectre-x360-14-laptop-stylus-oled-review-price-specs-features"&gt;HP’s Spectre x360 14&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="txtLcT"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:10347563"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QISdSb"&gt;But some subtle differences make clear that this laptop is for the office, not for gaming. It’s slightly lighter than the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21340554/razer-blade-stealth-13-review-keyboard-specs-price-features"&gt;Blade Stealth&lt;/a&gt;, at 0.6 inches thick and 3.09 pounds. The port selection is also better than that of the Stealth: there are two Thunderbolt 4 ports, one USB-A 3.2 Gen 1, one HDMI 2.0, one microSD slot, and one combo audio jack. This is also a big advantage the Razer Book has over the XPS 13 and MacBook Pro, both of which have comparably limited selections. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="320Zfr"&gt;The biggest change, though, is the 16:10 touch display. This makes the screen taller than the 16:9 panels you’ll find on the Blade (and on almost all dedicated gaming laptops). It lends you plenty of extra room for multitasking, with less scrolling and zooming necessary to see everything you need to. Aspect ratio aside, the 1920 x 1200 display on our review unit was quite bright, maxing out at 494 nits in my testing. It’s quite vibrant as well, with sharp and bright colors. While the panel has a glossy texture, it kicks back little to no glare in bright settings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The ports on the left edge of the Razer Book 13’s keyboard deck." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CQGnRfrYVKp-Zhr7MPVUVTDyx4Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22290557/akrales_210203_4381_0142.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;USB-C, USB-A, headphone jack on the left.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The ports on the right side of the keyboard deck of the Razer Book 13." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2zEtLPFL7yaY1oqVBA4CPecyuoE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22290558/akrales_210203_4381_0154.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;HDMI, USB-C, microSD on the right.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="UKABSF"&gt;Miscellaneous laptop stuff: the glass touchpad is roomy and quite smooth — definitely one of my recent favorites. The speakers sound great, with strong percussion, though I did hear some distortion at higher volumes. And I almost never get to say this, but the webcam isn’t that bad; it delivers a decent and fairly accurate picture, though there’s no privacy shutter or kill switch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="92for2"&gt;In a vacuum, I have very few complaints about the Razer Book’s chassis. I will point out that I find it slightly worse than the XPS 13 in a few (subjective) areas. Not only is it thicker and heavier than Dell’s flagship, but it just looks and feels clunkier, lacking the XPS’s sleek portability. And while Razer’s keyboard and touchpad are both fine, they’re not as exceptional as either on the XPS; Dell’s keyboard has more travel and a more satisfying click, and its touchpad is a bit more comfortable. Most frustratingly to me, Razer provides less storage for the price. You only get 256GB of storage in the base and midrange models and can only get 512GB in the top-end $1,999 configuration — 512GB XPS models come as low as &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dell.com%2Fen-us%2Fshop%2Fdell-laptops%2Fnew-xps-13-laptop%2Fspd%2Fxps-13-9310-laptop%2Fxn9310cto230h%3Fview%3Dconfigurations&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22287698%2Frazer-book-13-review-design-specs-price-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$1,399&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dell.com%2Fen-us%2Fshop%2Fdell-laptops%2Fnew-xps-13-laptop%2Fspd%2Fxps-13-9310-laptop%2Fxn9310cto230h%3Fview%3Dconfigurations%26configurationid%3D2c75050c-0f34-4b0a-9555-2e3dc8a34439&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F22287698%2Frazer-book-13-review-design-specs-price-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$1,599 XPS&lt;/a&gt; has 512GB of storage while the &lt;a href="http://razer.a9yw.net/c/482924/642901/10229?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.razer.com%2Fgaming-laptops%2FRazer-Book-13%2FRZ09-03571EM1-R3U1&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$1,599 Razer Book&lt;/a&gt; has just 256GB (their specs are identical otherwise). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M3drA6"&gt;There’s one area where the Razer Book solidly beats the XPS, and that’s performance. All Razer Book models are Evo-verified, meaning Intel vouches for them as top performers. And our test model includes a high-clocked (up to 28W) version of one of the chipmaker’s top ultrabook processors, Intel’s Core i7-1165G7. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Razer Book 13 seen perpendicular from the left side." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8EWthHs7TT66XAstkdKpge4M9RY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22290560/akrales_210203_4381_0181.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Evo is the 11th Gen version of Intel’s Project Athena program.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0a1GCk"&gt;This system flew through the demanding tasks we threw at it. It took nine minutes and 21 seconds to complete our Premiere Pro media test, which involves exporting a 5-minute, 33-second 4K video. That’s the fastest time I’ve ever gotten from a system with the quad-core 1165G7 (which powers many of the best ultraportables on the market). The XPS 13 took 10 minutes and 43 seconds to complete the same task; the more powerful &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21575308/dell-xps-13-2-in-1-2020-review-tiger-lake-specs-price-features"&gt;XPS 13 2-in-1&lt;/a&gt; took 10 minutes and five seconds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="orSIl5"&gt;Razer still hasn’t quite caught Apple’s M1 systems, though. The most recent MacBook Pro finished the test in seven minutes and 39 seconds. And of course, integrated graphics can’t hold a candle to a midrange GPU, even in a thin and light chassis. The Blade Stealth 13 with a GTX 1650 Ti knocked out the export in just five minutes and 50 seconds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Razer Book 13 open. The screen displays the Razer logo on a green and black background." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Yat_hMv_Hvxrn5o4CNrZbyNj60U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22290549/akrales_210203_4381_0015.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Razer Book’s processor is powered up to 28W, with turbo boost speeds up to 4.7 GHz.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="P6zDeY"&gt;In real-world performance, the Razer Book also shines. The laptop handled my fairly demanding load of Chrome tabs, Zoom calls, and other apps with no issue. It boots up from standby almost instantly and very quickly from the powered-off state as well. Of course, the XPS 13 is also quite good in these scenarios. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="girmav"&gt;While the Book 13 is decidedly not a gaming laptop, it is a Razer-branded product, so some might wonder how it games. The answer is it delivers some of the best integrated graphics performance I’ve seen from a Windows clamshell. It solidly beats the XPS 13 clamshell and is about on par with the more powerful 2-in-1. In practice, it’s most suitable for lighter gaming and heavier titles at lower settings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div id="uvptkf"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10347621"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="TQy403"&gt;&lt;q&gt;It delivers some of the best integrated graphics performance I’ve seen from a Windows clamshell&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="m7YpQr"&gt;The Razer Book averaged 142fps on &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt;’s maximum setting without dipping below 125; the XPS put up 111fps with a minimum of 100. Razer also wins on &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;, averaging 219fps to the Dell’s 205fps. Of course, since both machines have a 60Hz screen, you won’t observe a difference in the quality of these games — but these numbers should give you a sense of the Razer Book’s power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oMTffF"&gt;Graphic performance will make something of a difference on heavier titles. The Razer Book beat the XPS on the more demanding &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; at Ultra settings, averaging 65fps to the XPS’s 48fps. It also averaged 32fps on &lt;em&gt;Shadow of the Tomb Raider&lt;/em&gt; at its lowest settings, where the XPS averaged 22fps. That’s significant because it means you could feasibly play &lt;em&gt;Tomb Raider&lt;/em&gt; in 1080p on the Razer Book, which would be unpleasant to do on the XPS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Razer Book 13 seen from the back, open." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QU9hD99paF-tukNgurBLGeqkxjk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22290555/akrales_210203_4381_0130.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The color is called “mercury.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0FAgvv"&gt;That result also makes clear that — to reiterate — despite aesthetic similarity, this laptop is not a Blade. The Stealth 13 averaged 45fps on &lt;em&gt;Tomb Raider&lt;/em&gt;’s highest settings. If you want to game with this form factor, buy the Blade. You’ll also get &lt;a href="http://razer.a9yw.net/c/482924/642901/10229?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.razer.com%2Fgaming-laptops%2FRazer-Blade-Stealth-13%2FRZ09-03102E02-R3U1&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;way more storage&lt;/a&gt; for the price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;div id="glaHb9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:10347610"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="w79oyR"&gt;When it comes to cooling, the Razer Book has chops. It did a significantly better job of keeping its CPU cool than the XPS did in my testing. During the Adobe export, the 1165G7 stayed comfortably in the mid-60s to mid-70s (Celsius) with occasional spikes as high as the low 90s. It largely remained in the high 50s during the &lt;em&gt;Tomb Raider&lt;/em&gt; benchmark, with spikes up to the mid-70s. All in all, I didn’t see any throttling or slowdown, and the keyboard never got uncomfortably hot under load. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2DFpNp"&gt;But you’re making a trade-off for all this power: battery life. It’s not terrible, but it’s nothing to write home about. I got an average of six hours and 45 minutes while using the Book 13 for standard office work with occasional Zoom calls and streaming at 200 nits of brightness. (This was in the Battery Saver profile, which you can toggle in Razer’s Synapse software.) That means I can’t go a full day without charging, though your mileage will vary based on your tasks and settings. I’ve gotten over nine hours putting plenty of machines through that same workload, including the XPS 13. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iOQMdw"&gt;The Razer Book 13 has a lot of things going for it, especially for Razer fans. It’s certainly one of the best ultraportable laptops you can buy — but whether it’s &lt;em&gt;the &lt;/em&gt;best is a complicated question to answer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="f4GAOZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:10347607"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="wwm23S"&gt;In some areas (keyboard, touchpad, portability), the Razer Book is slightly worse than the XPS 13. In others (display quality and build quality) it’s about on par. And it brings a few nifty features (the port selection and the RGB keyboard) that Dell’s clamshell doesn’t have — but I doubt those are making or breaking the purchasing decision for most people. On net, I think Razer comes out slightly worse on the chassis front. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cXJkoh"&gt;But that’s not where the Razer Book makes its case. That category is performance. Compared to other Windows clamshells I’ve tested in the past year, the Razer Book is top of the class. It stands out in productivity and media work as well as gaming. On the other hand, you’re making some sacrifices for that power, in addition to the hefty price tag it carries. You can get a few hours more battery life from a number of laptops in the Razer Book’s class (including the XPS 13) and significantly more storage as well. For folks in the Book’s intended audience (users looking for a portable work or entertainment driver) those trade-offs are probably worth considering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="ntrRMj"&gt;Ultimately, the Razer Book 13 is an impressive new laptop from Razer with a lot to like, and I’m sure many customers will be happy with it. But those trade-offs mean I can’t quite call it the best product for most people.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22287698/razer-book-13-review-design-specs-price-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22287698/razer-book-13-review-design-specs-price-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T07:01:17-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T07:01:17-05:00</updated>
    <title>‘Spinning’ is trademarked, and Peloton isn’t happy about it</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7lPZORmtwdltbnE0aw261CfGn9w=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68835578/akrales_170407_1569_0200.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jx4gUe"&gt;Peloton is fighting to have the terms “spin” and “spinning” treated as generic terms, arguing that they’ve entered into common usage in spite of being trademarked since the late 90s, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-02-17/peloton-dominates-home-spinning-but-rival-won-t-let-it-say-so?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;. This week it &lt;a href="https://ttabvue.uspto.gov/ttabvue/v?pno=92076463&amp;amp;pty=CAN&amp;amp;eno=1"&gt;filed petitions&lt;/a&gt; with the US Patent and Trademark Office’s Trademark Trial and Appeal Board to try and cancel both trademarks owned by Mad Dogg Athletics, arguing that “spin class and spin bike are part of the fitness lexicon” and that they’re “generic terms to describe a type of exercise bike and associated in-studio class.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rixrua"&gt;Mad Dogg had earlier filed a lawsuit against Peloton, alleging that its products infringe upon its exercise bike patents. While the lawsuit doesn’t make claims on trademarks, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; characterizes Peloton’s attempt to cancel Mad Dogg’s trademarks as a “retaliatory effort.” Mad Dogg has challenged Peloton’s use of the term “spin” in the past, and last year asked it to remove a video from its YouTube channel that referenced the phrase. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eaUljR"&gt;There are numerous examples of product names that started out as trademarks, but which eventually entered common usage as product categories and lost their legal protections. &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; notes that “escalator” and “murphy bed” are two high profile examples of so-called “genericide.” But understandably, companies with trademarks are keen to hold on to the exclusive right to use and profit off them, and often go to great lengths to avoid terms like “&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/06/24/smarter-living/how-a-brand-name-becomes-generic.html"&gt;Band-Aid&lt;/a&gt;” or “&lt;a href="https://www.worldipreview.com/article/xerox-avoiding-a-genericide-headache"&gt;Xerox&lt;/a&gt;” from becoming generic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="1kUiM3"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Mad Dogg says the terms “should be treated with the care and respect” &lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jKFZJd"&gt;Mad Dogg Athletics devotes a &lt;a href="https://spinning.eu/legal-trademark/"&gt;page on its website&lt;/a&gt; to how the terms should be used. “These marks are brand names that serve to identify the unique fitness products and programs offered by Mad Dogg Athletics, Inc,” the company says, noting that they’re “important business assets” that should be treated with “care and respect.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CVS6OG"&gt;Mad Dogg’s website argues that consumers would be harmed alongside the company if the terms became generic. “Loss of a trademark,” it says, “denies consumers the opportunity to identify an original, quality product developed with years of experience for repeat satisfactory purchases.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7oJoyk"&gt;Peleton, unsurprisingly, disagrees. In its filing it says Mad Dogg “has spent years engaged in a bullying campaign of demand letters and litigation to force people and companies to stop using the very terms they have every right to use.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LJR3P9"&gt;“Enough is enough. It is time to put a stop to Mad Dogg’s tactic of profiting by threatening competitors, marketplaces and even journalists with enforcement of generic trademarks,” Peloton’s filing argues.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289005/peloton-spinning-spin-trademark-mad-dogg-dispute-appeal"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22289005/peloton-spinning-spin-trademark-mad-dogg-dispute-appeal</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T06:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T06:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook will add a new label to some climate change posts in the UK</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Facebook is expanding its “Climate Science Information Center.”" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/unYTqPdcUktUlOXmRvHK4V3FKog=/0x542:3250x2709/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68835446/FB_Mythbusters_mock.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Facebook is expanding its “Climate Science Information Center.” | Image: Facebook&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="q7LmGN"&gt;Facebook will start labeling posts about climate change with a banner that directs people to its information page on climate change. It’s the company’s latest effort to weed out lies and myths about the climate crisis, and it follows criticism from lawmakers and scientists concerned that the social media giant allowed false information to proliferate on its platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CHrY84"&gt;For now, the labels will only appear on Facebook posts in the UK. But the company plans to start rolling them out elsewhere “soon,” it said in an announcement on Thursday. Facebook debuted its “Climate Science Information Center” in the US, Germany, the UK, and France back in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/15/21437208/facebook-climate-change-misinformation-greenhouse-gas-pledge"&gt;September&lt;/a&gt;. Now, Facebook is also expanding that page to include new information debunking common myths about climate change. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1zIlUB"&gt;The company’s strategy for tackling climate misinformation is similar to what it’s done about COVID-19. Facebook started putting vetted information about the novel coronavirus at the top of its news feed &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/18/21185538/facebook-coronavirus-news-feed-information-center-covid-19"&gt;last March&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DCMxeP"&gt;Facebook came under a lot of pressure last year to do a better job at fact-checking posts about climate change and stop misleading content from spreading. The new labels seem to be one way to answer calls for Facebook to take more action, although it doesn’t address original concerns that legislators like Sen. Elizabeth Warren (D-MA) had about Facebook last year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="shFgy5"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“There should be no company too big, too powerful, and too opaque to be held accountable.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="8Xf6XZ"&gt;The whole saga started in August 2019 after Facebook reversed a decision by its fact-checkers to rate an op-ed as “false” for including inaccurate information and cherry-picked data on climate change. &lt;a href="https://www.eenews.net/stories/1063436369"&gt;&lt;em&gt;E&amp;amp;E News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; consequently reported that Facebook had created a sort of loophole that exempted opinion articles from fact checking. That’s been a part of its policy the entire time, spokespeople for Facebook have told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/14/climate/climate-facebook-fact-checking.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FdixOp"&gt;“The future of our planet is at stake, and there should be no company too big, too powerful, and too opaque to be held accountable for its role in the climate crisis. Facebook is no exception,” Warren and other senators said in a statement last year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Cm0sAz"&gt;Warren and others &lt;a href="https://www.warren.senate.gov/oversight/letters/warren-carper-whitehouse-schatz-call-on-mark-zuckerberg-and-facebook-to-stop-the-deliberate-spread-of-climate-disinformation-on-the-companys-social-media-platforms"&gt;demanded&lt;/a&gt; that Facebook answer questions about its fact-checking policies. In a letter from Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21368136/facebook-climate-change-fact-check-senators-warren"&gt;shared exclusively with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; last year&lt;/a&gt;, the company maintained that “clear opinion content” wasn’t typically subject to fact-checking on their platform. It also said that &lt;strong&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;speech from politicians” was not eligible to be fact-checked in an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z5OEJJ"&gt;Facebook hasn’t specified how it will decide which posts should carry the new “informational labels” launching in the UK today. “We’re continuing to learn from other informational labels that we’ve applied to COVID-19 posts and posts during the US election,” a Facebook spokesperson&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;said in an email. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zGwPuc"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mW9u1P"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22288439/facebook-label-climate-change-posts-misinformation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22288439/facebook-label-climate-change-posts-misinformation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T04:40:27-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T04:40:27-05:00</updated>
    <title>White House now says 100 companies hit by SolarWinds hack, but more may be impacted</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Fgkd16Gy_uEppfX1wBTYzXJEZ9w=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68835358/acastro_170621_1777_0006_v4.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="cC4u7v"&gt;The US government has released updated figures on the number of companies and federal agencies it believes were impacted by the recent SolarWinds hack. “As of today, 9 federal agencies and about 100 private sector companies were compromised,” Deputy National Security Advisor Anne Neuberger &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/02/17/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-and-deputy-national-security-advisor-for-cyber-and-emerging-technology-anne-neuberger-february-17-2021/"&gt;said in a briefing&lt;/a&gt;, though she declined to name specific organizations. Although the hack was “likely of Russian origin,” Neuberger said the hackers launched their attack from inside the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jgsB19"&gt;The latest figures revealed are lower than the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/2/22210667/solarwinds-hack-worse-government-microsoft-cybersecurity"&gt;250 federal agencies and businesses&lt;/a&gt; that were previously reported to have been infected, though Neuberger cautioned that the investigation is still in its “beginning stages” and that “additional compromises” may be found. In particular, the technology companies compromised gives hackers potential footholds for future attacks. Up to 18,000 SolarWinds customers are thought to have originally received the malicious code, though hackers did not attempt to gain additional access to all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="QQsF8Y"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“As of today, 9 federal agencies and about 100 private sector companies were compromised”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="v542Z4"&gt;The hack originally &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/17/22188060/microsoft-president-solarwinds-orion-hack-breach-brad-smith"&gt;came to light late last year&lt;/a&gt;, when it emerged that hackers had compromised SolarWinds’ monitoring and management software, which is used by multiple government agencies and Fortune 500 companies, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-02-17/solarwinds-hacks-perpetrated-from-inside-u-s-white-house-says?sref=ExbtjcSG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt; notes&lt;/a&gt;. Companies including Intel, Nvidia, Cisco, Belkin, and VMWare have all &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/21/22194183/intel-nvidia-cisco-government-infected-solarwinds-hack"&gt;reportedly seen computers on their networks infected&lt;/a&gt;, as well as the US Treasury, Commerce, State, Energy, and Homeland Security departments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T3x63G"&gt;The scale of the attack means that it may be many months before the government completes its investigation. As part of the process, Neuberger said the government is planning an executive action to fix the security problems identified, and that “discussions are underway” about how to respond to the perpetrator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vkzk2x"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uLXdaP"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22288961/solarwinds-hack-100-companies-9-federal-agencies"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22288961/solarwinds-hack-100-companies-9-federal-agencies</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Porter</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-02-18T03:30:44-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T03:30:44-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft’s next major Windows 10 update focuses on improving remote work</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VEXy_MjqsS_sYQZcb8mwU8m8MVA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/68835274/acastro_180504_1777_microsoft_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FMJvOO"&gt;The next major update to Windows 10, version 21H1, will be delivered in the first half of 2021 and focuses on improving remote work scenarios. Microsoft traditionally delivers two major Windows updates per year, with most of the bigger features dropping in the spring and a smaller update in the fall. While IT admins are used to this approach, Microsoft appears to be reversing this cadence for 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eIuFIh"&gt;“Windows 10, version 21H1 will have a scoped set of features improving security, remote access and quality,” &lt;a href="https://blogs.windows.com/windowsexperience/2021/02/17/introducing-the-next-feature-update-to-windows-10-version-21h1/"&gt;explains John Cable&lt;/a&gt;, Microsoft’s head of Windows Servicing and Delivery. “The features we are releasing in this update are focused on the core experiences that customers have told us they’re relying on most right now.” These improvements will include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="vpjo57"&gt;Windows Hello multicamera support to set the default as the external camera when both external and internal Windows Hello cameras are present.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nGUMwO"&gt;Windows Defender Application Guard performance improvements including optimizing document opening scenario times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ac1Wit"&gt;Windows Management Instrumentation (WMI) Group Policy Service (GPSVC) updating performance improvement to support remote work scenarios.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8sFLQA0rrBivkKRIdZ0z3N00jl4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22311903/brio_og_image_new.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Logitech&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Logitech’s Brio webcam will work better on devices with built-in Windows Hello cameras soon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="BXjIFA"&gt;The Windows camera changes mean you’ll soon be able to plug in an external Windows Hello camera and get the benefits of facial detection on a laptop that already has a Windows Hello camera built in. Currently, Windows doesn’t support this scenario well, and it means cameras like Logitech’s Brio do not work correctly with devices like Microsoft’s Surface range that also have Windows Hello cameras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="auuLLb"&gt;Microsoft’s other improvements for this 21H1 version are clearly designed for IT admins to improve support for remote working. This includes improving document opening times for Microsoft’s built-in anti-virus software, and performance improvements for the management and configuration side of Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l9LdL7"&gt;This 21H1 update will also install very quickly, much like a monthly cumulative updates to Windows. Microsoft has started testing this 21H1 update with beta testers today, and it’s planning to make it available to all Windows 10 users “later in the first half of this calendar year.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L5xHN2"&gt;Microsoft is also expected to deliver a larger Windows 10 update later in 2021. The company is planning a “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/4/22212817/microsoft-windows-10-visual-changes-update-sun-valley-2021"&gt;sweeping visual rejuvenation of Windows&lt;/a&gt;,” which is codenamed Sun Valley. Microsoft is planning to detail its next big changes to Windows at a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22261997/microsoft-news-events-gaming-cloud-windows"&gt;special event in the coming months&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22288937/microsoft-windows-10-next-version-21h1-update-remote-work-features"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/18/22288937/microsoft-windows-10-next-version-21h1-update-remote-work-features</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
