<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2020-11-25T10:57:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-11-25T10:57:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T10:57:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Hulu’s Animaniacs reboot can’t survive a BoJack Horseman world</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oydqkTyV74EdlMtOCWeSS5Xn9QE=/45x0:1395x900/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67981126/Screen_Shot_2020_11_25_at_10.30.50_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KSImBW"&gt;Watching the original &lt;em&gt;Animaniacs &lt;/em&gt;today is probably the closest you can get to scrolling through a TikTok feed from the mid-’90s. The madcap variety show was like &lt;em&gt;Looney Tunes&lt;/em&gt; by way of golden-age &lt;em&gt;Saturday Night Live&lt;/em&gt;, a pre-social media era meme factory that seemed more interested in parodying show business and celebrity than actually entertaining children. (The first episode is about a dang &lt;em&gt;psychiatrist to the stars&lt;/em&gt;!) Funny thing is, kids loved the antics of the Warner brothers and sister as they guffawed and rampaged their way across studio lots. Adults, on the other hand, were laughing at the jokes actually taking place &lt;em&gt;on&lt;/em&gt; said studio lots — jokes full of innuendo and references meant for avid consumers of celeb gossip, alongside deep-cut jokes about animation history. It was uncommonly clever, and bewildering in hindsight. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1e0fmy"&gt;The new &lt;em&gt;Animaniacs&lt;/em&gt;, rebooted and now streaming on Hulu, replicates the manic energy of the original but not really in the service of anything that feels as transgressive or groundbreaking. The premise is simple: after the show’s cancellation in 1998, the Warner siblings Yakko, Wakko, and Dot, have spent the intervening years roaming some forgotten land until cartoon Steven Spielberg — in a &lt;em&gt;Jurassic Park &lt;/em&gt;pastiche alongside cartoon Laura Dern, Sam Neill, and Jeff Goldblum — finds them. And then they’re brought back to the Warner Bros. studio lot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mvpot6"&gt;That &lt;em&gt;Jurassic Park &lt;/em&gt;mashup is a good teaser for what you can expect from said antics: &lt;em&gt;Looney Tunes&lt;/em&gt;-esque characters riffing on pop culture and current events. In one episode, the Warners recreate &lt;em&gt;The Odyssey&lt;/em&gt;, posing as Greek deities who help and hinder Odysseus on his journey, while also sprinkling in some pop culture satire (the story’s cyclops is Trump). There are a lot of jokes about reboots and the creative bankruptcy they signify, and the ways Hollywood has or has not changed since the ‘90s. When Dot meets a top female executive, she asks for advice, only to be told “I believe in pulling the ladder &lt;em&gt;up&lt;/em&gt; after I climb it!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a0OHLi"&gt;There are also segments featuring songs (both satirical and semi-educational), while stories featuring other characters are mostly limited to Pinky and the Brain. The wide roster of players that the original show had are largely absent in the reboot. Some of this is for good reason — Hello Nurse, a pinup throwback mainly there to drive the Warner brothers &lt;em&gt;wild&lt;/em&gt;, is an &lt;em&gt;astoundingly&lt;/em&gt; sexist character for a ‘90s kids cartoon — but otherwise don’t expect any segments solely dedicated to Slappy Squirrel or the mobster pigeons The Goodfeathers.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oqLQtG"&gt;Mostly, the new &lt;em&gt;Animaniacs &lt;/em&gt;seems to be attempting to succeed using the old formula. Trouble is, there have been other shows doing excellent showbiz satire in the &lt;em&gt;Animaniacs&lt;/em&gt;’ absence, like &lt;em&gt;BoJack Horseman&lt;/em&gt;, which managed to skewer Hollywood and the new media ecosystem that now covers it. &lt;em&gt;Rick and Morty&lt;/em&gt; is a genre-hopping adventure that lampoons genre tropes while &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; having plenty to say about the entertainment landscape. And &lt;em&gt;Family Guy&lt;/em&gt; has created a whole genre of television where the whole point is in self-aware asides to the audience. (It’s worth noting that the showrunner of the &lt;em&gt;Animaniacs &lt;/em&gt;reboot is a &lt;em&gt;Family Guy &lt;/em&gt;alum.) &lt;em&gt;Animaniacs&lt;/em&gt;, meanwhile, spends a whole Pinky and the Brain segment lambasting Seth Meyers and cute animal memes. It’s an odd segment that makes fun of a version of Seth Meyers with no basis in reality — Meyers being the late-night host most openly interested in giving airtime to unusual topics and more incisive political commentary. Applying the same joke to a more frivolous host, like Jimmy Fallon, would not be much funnier, but at least it would kind of make sense. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cULAoh"&gt;The problems with the show partially lie in the changes in the industry around it. The original &lt;em&gt;Animaniacs&lt;/em&gt; existed in an era where the monoculture reigned; the presumed audiences watched the same shows and movies, which kids picked up on. (&lt;a href="https://www.gq.com/story/george-clooney-icon-of-the-year-2020"&gt;A recent &lt;em&gt;GQ&lt;/em&gt; profile of George Clooney&lt;/a&gt; has the star stressing how different that industry was at a time when a TV show could have 40 million viewers watching.) Parodying celebrities was dependable fun at a time where no one had the easy access of perusing a celebrity’s Instagram account, and it was even funnier to see a “children’s” cartoon doing those parodies. Things are different now than they were when Yakko, Wakko, and Dot were first making a mess of the Warner lot. The reboot seems stuck just pointing that out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Juq1t6"&gt;&lt;em&gt;BoJack Horseman&lt;/em&gt;’s&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;comedy succeeded because it was specific. The show was made by people who knew &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; the kind of person who’d watch it, and it lampooned their tastes almost exclusively while &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; being a work of uncommon emotional honesty. It makes &lt;em&gt;Animaniacs&lt;/em&gt; feel like a relic from another time. It might as well be a dinosaur. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ubs1ME"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="93pNwZ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21719188/animaniacs-reboot-review-hulu-bojack-horseman"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21719188/animaniacs-reboot-review-hulu-bojack-horseman</id>
    <author>
      <name>Joshua Rivera</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-11-25T10:53:48-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T10:53:48-05:00</updated>
    <title>Satellite images show online shopping’s growing footprint </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Satellite imagery shows the explosive growth of warehouses surrounding the San Bernardino International Airport between 2005 and 2018" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZHJhSFW0yMT57ytr0AW-UW6x6Ag=/240x0:2640x1600/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67981102/ESRI_After.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: CCAEJ / ESRI&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ehRiRh"&gt;You might not see it each time you make a purchase, but online shopping takes up a lot of space in the real world. The number of warehouses built to keep e-commerce running smoothly is growing quickly, and they’re creeping closer to neighborhoods in order to meet consumers’ expectations for quick deliveries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="342fqI"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Online shopping has changed the landscape&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NJwWrB"&gt;These images taken by satellite show how dramatically online shopping has changed the landscape of one county in California. I grew up in this county, and I’ve seen that transformation happen in person. A lot of the stuff that Americans buy passes through here. The nearby ports of Los Angeles and Long Beach handle about &lt;a href="https://laedc.org/wtc/chooselacounty/infrastructure-goods-movement/#:~:text=The%20Port%20of%20Los%20Angeles,for%20the%20entire%20United%20States."&gt;40 percent&lt;/a&gt; of all goods Americans import. Once it gets off a ship, most of that stuff is quickly sent inland to “dry ports,” another term for warehouses and distribution centers that sort packages and send them off to their final destinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GZ059K"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="imageslider:9733853"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AOoEkt"&gt;The satellite imagery shows the explosive growth of warehouses surrounding the San Bernardino International Airport between 2005 and 2018. On &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/dir//ONT2+-+Amazon+Fulfillment+Center,+1910+E+Central+Ave,+San+Bernardino,+CA+92408/@34.0916921,-117.2500508,3312m/data=!3m1!1e3!4m16!1m6!3m5!1s0x80dca6c6754fcccb:0xa340105c0c7ea466!2sONT2+-+Amazon+Fulfillment+Center!8m2!3d34.0884704!4d-117.2459435!4m8!1m0!1m5!1m1!1s0x80dca6c6754fcccb:0xa340105c0c7ea466!2m2!1d-117.2459433!2d34.08847!3e2"&gt;Google Maps&lt;/a&gt;, you can see what businesses occupy some of those huge structures: Amazon, PepsiCo, Clorox, Kohl’s, and Mars Petcare (the parent company for well-known pet food brands like Pedigree and Iams). San Bernardino County and neighboring Riverside County together — a region called the Inland Empire — make up one of the biggest logistics and distribution hubs in the US. San Bernardino alone has enough warehouse space to fill more than 5,100 football fields, about 300 million square feet, according to a &lt;a href="https://scag.ca.gov/sites/main/files/file-attachments/industrial_warehousing_report_-_revised_2018.pdf?1605989650"&gt;2018 report&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="byoP2n"&gt;“When you press purchase on an Amazon or online, it doesn’t just magically appear at your door. There’s an entire infrastructure that moves those goods and the impact is really felt in different places, especially in the Inland Empire,” says Faraz Rizvi, a special projects coordinator at the local nonprofit Center for Community Action and Environmental Justice (CCAEJ). (CCAEJ’s webpage has an &lt;a href="https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/5d2ba8cbcd1d412897549b9d5d13e548"&gt;interactive map&lt;/a&gt; of the warehouses surrounding the airport.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="y0fdKa"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Warehouses are magnets for tailpipe pollution&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RCp5Vb"&gt;CCAEJ took these images with the help of geographic information system company Esri to show how this community is in some ways paying for the &lt;a href="https://grist.org/article/this-california-community-is-paying-for-your-holiday-shopping-with-their-air-quality/"&gt;environmental&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://grist.org/justice/san-bernardino-county-california-air-pollution-logistics-industry/"&gt;health costs&lt;/a&gt; of purchases people are making elsewhere. What you can’t see in the photos is the flurry of trucks, trains, and planes taking goods to and from these warehouses. The warehouses are magnets for tailpipe pollution. And San Bernardino County has consistently had the worst smog in the US, according to annual &lt;a href="https://www.stateoftheair.org/assets/SOTA-2020.pdf"&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; from the American Lung Association. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ibjbf3"&gt;More warehouses are on the way in the Inland Empire and will probably bring more truck traffic and pollution with them. (Some city leaders welcome the boom in warehouse jobs. Rizvi, on the other hand, worries that many of those jobs are seasonal or temporary and don’t necessarily come with a living wage.) The San Bernardino airport is &lt;a href="https://grist.org/justice/san-bernardino-residents-sue-to-block-controversial-airport-expansion/"&gt;expanding&lt;/a&gt; with the construction of a $200 million air cargo facility &lt;a href="https://www.sbsun.com/2020/05/08/amazon-is-landing-at-san-bernardino-airport-officials-say/"&gt;into which Amazon is moving&lt;/a&gt;. Globally, the warehousing industry is &lt;a href="https://www.mordorintelligence.com/industry-reports/warehousing-and-storage-services-market"&gt;expected to keep growing&lt;/a&gt; over the next several years.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="San Bernardino, Sept.07, 2007: An aerial view of San Bernardino International Airport which ha" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M1U944Hf2UqpaSaW2Nkz6lr-iQI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22121200/564026395.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Irfan Khan / Los Angeles Times via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;San Bernardino, Sept. 7th, 2007: An aerial view of San Bernardino International Airport which has attracted some major businesses, like Kohl’s, Pep Boys Auto, Mattel, and Stater Bros. to establish warehouses.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="OIP3sM"&gt;The pandemic &lt;a href="https://www.reutersevents.com/supplychain/supply-chain/bigger-boom-warehousing-way-part-1-current-demand-and-covid-19"&gt;isn’t slowing this trend&lt;/a&gt; down much. There’s more demand for warehouse space because people are &lt;a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/marketing-and-sales/our-insights/the-great-consumer-shift-ten-charts-that-show-how-us-shopping-behavior-is-changing"&gt;shopping online more&lt;/a&gt;. On top of that, some retailers are keeping &lt;a href="https://www.cbre.us/research-and-reports/US-MarketFlash-Post-Coronavirus-Industrial-Real-Estate"&gt;more inventory on hand&lt;/a&gt; because of disruptions to supply chains during the global crisis. And items that didn’t sell as much this year as they normally do — like summer clothes — are still sitting and taking up space. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YN8Yli"&gt;The place where I grew up is changing a lot because of e-commerce. And soon, your hometown could see changes, too. Amazon has reportedly looked into snatching up old brick-and-mortar department stores and &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/amazon-and-giant-mall-operator-look-at-turning-sears-j-c-penney-stores-into-fulfillment-centers-11596992863"&gt;revamping them into distribution centers&lt;/a&gt; to be closer to their customers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h4Z2A2"&gt;“You can see as you leave any city nowadays you have this whole strip of warehouses dedicated to online shopping fulfillment,” says Sharon Cullinane, a professor of sustainable logistics at the University of Gothenburg. “You have to have warehouses that are closer and closer to the centers of population so that they can do these half-hour deliveries — it’s a bit mad really.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HoEuEg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LZGWPk"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q7NRiK"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DhmlIH"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21611862/satellite-images-online-shopping-growing-footprint-warehouses"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21611862/satellite-images-online-shopping-growing-footprint-warehouses</id>
    <author>
      <name>Justine Calma</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-11-25T10:38:54-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T10:38:54-05:00</updated>
    <title>The best Black Friday tech deals at Amazon</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Google Pixel 5" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/g2_Kz1keuIkRc7163fVKqSU_EUw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67846759/akrales_201012_4137_0020.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Pixel 5 is $50 off at Amazon&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rzQIrV"&gt;Amazon is hosting a wide variety of tech deals for Black Friday and Cyber Monday. The company started its deal festivities early by knocking down prices for many of its own devices, including some of its newer products that hadn’t yet seen any discounts. The fourth-generation Echo smart speaker, the latest Eero 6 mesh Wi-Fi routers, and more are all discounted right now, in addition to several other Amazon devices, such as the company’s entire range of Fire TV streaming devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V7OYsE"&gt;Of course, that’s just the beginning. More deals will come later this week, and we’ll be including the best deals we find below. The latest deals to hit the wire will be at the top, while the others will be organized by category. If your search for gifts spans wider than what Amazon has in stock, check out our other coverage of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/black-friday"&gt;the best Black Friday deals happening elsewhere&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SWxkKJ"&gt;The latest deals&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jQbbOijOAeO6bhpFLhDwGc96ces=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19827389/bking_200322_3945_0022.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Brennan King / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dA7bdC"&gt;Both the 11-inch and 12.9-inch variations of the latest iPad Pro are cheaper than ever. The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08637NV8M/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;11-inch model with 128GB of storage&lt;/a&gt; is $729 (usually $799) and the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0862JF4KR?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;entry-level 12.9-inch model with 128GB of storage&lt;/a&gt; is $899 (usually $999).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3Ovbhy14PfmPVfO23bHYgZBG-IE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19868722/DSC00765.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Brydge Pro Plus keyboard has an integrated trackpad, so you don’t need to use the touchscreen (or, at least as much)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="cA2Ing"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0865JB97F/?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Brydge’s Pro Plus keyboard with a trackpad built-in for the 11-inch iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt; (2018 or 2020 versions) is $140, down from its usual $160 price. The 12.9-inch version is currently out of stock at Amazon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="18aWEh"&gt;If you don’t need a trackpad with your keyboard, the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B089H2P9T5/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Brydge Pro for 12.9-inch iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt; models costs $100, down from $170. The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B089H1RFGP/?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;11-inch version&lt;/a&gt; is the same price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="4yFMtD"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07HXH6NWN/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Brydge keyboard made for 10.5-inch iPads&lt;/a&gt;, including the seventh and eight generation iPad, the previous-generation iPad Air and iPad Pro models, is $70 off. You can snag one for $60.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iMKzBYoN3L6gzuK3TnLnOHOag9o=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21788164/dseifert_200819_4156_0001.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The Brydge Pro Plus 12.3-inch (left) and the Brydge Go Plus &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Jm8Uxb"&gt;If you have the Surface Pro 7 or any model going back to the Surface Pro 4, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08CWTKZQV/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Brydge’s Pro Plus 12.3-inch keyboard with a trackpad&lt;/a&gt; is $30 off its usual price, totaling $120.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wOlFwc"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08CWLKWK6/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Brydge Go Plus&lt;/a&gt;, made for the Surface Go, is $100 ($40 off)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Brydge" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P-EOHcL79LRDjbPa_kdzi20-3zc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21712488/W_Touch___W_Type.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Brydge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The W-Type keyboard next to the W-Touch wireless trackpad&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="W4BrrQ"&gt;For the first time, Brydge has discounted its &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08D6XQX14/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;W-Touch standalone trackpad&lt;/a&gt; for Windows 10. Normally $100, it’s down to $70.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="KTKnrb"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08D6XS52J?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;W-Type wireless, full-sized Bluetooth keyboard&lt;/a&gt; is discounted by $20, bringing the price down to $40.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="koAqPz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best Black Friday deals you can get right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/21569412/black-friday-best-early-deals-sales-tech-gadgets"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="Pam9x5"&gt;Smart speaker deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="Z69015"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9508352" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_portrait_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="kX6U64"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B084J4KNDS/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The smaller Echo Dot that has the same design as the more expensive Echo&lt;/a&gt; is just $29 (usually $50)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="tqFtlZ"&gt;If you want &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07XJ8C8F7/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the new spherical Echo Dot with a digital clock embedded in the fabric&lt;/a&gt;, that one costs $39. It’s normally $60. Stock seems to be running low for this model, as it’s currently set to restock on December 19th.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7KWZwX"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B084J4MJCK/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The new (and adorable) Kids Edition Echo Dot&lt;/a&gt; is $39. It normally costs $60.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="s0MMMy"&gt;The most capable Echo speaker, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07G9Y3ZMC/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the Echo Studio&lt;/a&gt;, is down to $160 (usually $200). It’s currently set to deliver in late December. The best option is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08F8P5G9Z/?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;this bundle&lt;/a&gt; that includes two Hue bulbs for free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DAJwTf"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07W95RBZM?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The Sonos Move Wi-Fi and Bluetooth-enabled smart speaker&lt;/a&gt; is $299 (usually $399). It’s currently set to come back in stock on December 8th, but you can still get this deal price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XptVQNN08ahmS1JtHwwzfvIX54k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19273864/dseifert_191009_3728_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the Facebook Portal 10-inch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="JFybR5"&gt;Smart display deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="pvInl9"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07XPLJ9TZ/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook’s Portal TV&lt;/a&gt; brings a camera to your TV for $129 (usually $149).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lygFUi"&gt;If you want to video chat with friends and family via Facebook, the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07HFWG8S4/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Portal Plus&lt;/a&gt; is $229 (usually $280). This model automatically pans and zooms to keep the focus on you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6uFsWv"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07XPDYRRJ/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The Facebook Portal 10-inch display&lt;/a&gt; is $129, dropping in price from $179.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="16NdfD"&gt;Lastly, the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07XKWKQYT/?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;smaller eight-inch version, called Facebook Portal Mini&lt;/a&gt;, is just $65 (usually $129).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="bfrAso"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07HZLHPKP/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The Amazon Echo Show 5&lt;/a&gt; smart display with a camera is down to $45 (usually $90). This matches the best price debuted during Prime Day 2020.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AD9yUz"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PF1Y28C/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The slightly larger Echo Show 8&lt;/a&gt; with a bigger screen and more powerful speakers is $65 (usually $130).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RUT6N-bKDk5u8gXKITBNO6U-cks=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19895600/vpavic_042009_3967_0060.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The OnePlus 8&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="R6U1UK"&gt;Phone deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="eVGzdK"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0872473BF?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;OnePlus 8 with 256GB of storage&lt;/a&gt; in the “Interstellar Glow” colorway is $600, which is $200 off its usual price. This phone will come back in stock in late January, so while you can still get the deal price, the delivery will take a while.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kO1M6Q"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08H8X23ZB/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Google’s Pixel 5&lt;/a&gt; is $50 off for the first time, bringing it down to $650 (usually $700).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="5FyBT9"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08FYTSXGQ/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The Samsung Galaxy S20 FE 5G&lt;/a&gt; is $549. This phone usually costs $699 and before this hadn’t dropped in price lower than $600.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="qmeGcd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9546311" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_portrait_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/X39_zzk4wIDd8_mBOpTTNmwAIqc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19327384/cwelch_191028_3746_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="qWj3qe"&gt;Headphones &amp;amp; headset deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="ilzStQ"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07F6VM1S3/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon’s Echo Buds wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt; are back down to $80, which matches their lowest price yet. This model is usually $130.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="c9noE3"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/deal/48a7bde1/ref=gbps_tit___48a7bde1?showVariations=true&amp;amp;smid=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Bose’s QC 35 II wireless, noise-canceling headphones&lt;/a&gt; are $200 (usually $350).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="cIlWRO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9549570"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="8Guz7G"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0863TXGM3/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sony WH-1000XM4 wireless, noise-canceling headphones&lt;/a&gt; are back down to $278, a $72 price cut. It’s a great discount on some of the best noise-canceling headphones you can currently buy. The black-colored model is currently running low on stock.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0ywUiD"&gt;If you’re okay with getting the previous generation model, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07G4MNFS1/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;the WH-1000XM3 are $230&lt;/a&gt; when you add them to your cart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="TCDXLB"&gt;For something far less expensive that has IPX5 water resistance, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07WHF6LLG?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Plantronics’ BackBeat Fit 6100 over-ear, wireless headphones&lt;/a&gt; are just $80 (usually $180, though they’re sometimes around $100).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="GxZnVV"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B083KVM9VW?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy Buds Plus wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt; are down to $110 (normally $150). This matches the best deal we’ve seen, and it applies to every color option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="hYaaWj"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07FFD3DG5?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Jabra’s Elite 65t wireless earbuds&lt;/a&gt; are down to $70 (usually around $100).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="i05qiU"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08141GQQG/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Logitech’s white-colored G733 wireless PC gaming headset&lt;/a&gt; that also works with PlayStation and Nintendo Switch consoles is $120 (normally $130).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="7vnPIf"&gt;TVs and home entertainment deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="VXQxSb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9603552"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="DlUp0w"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0829RMHCM?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;larger 65-inch model&lt;/a&gt; of the LG BX above is priced at $1,797, which is the lowest price we’ve seen yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qTfFHP"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07YP94PBJ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Nvidia’s Shield TV 4K streaming device&lt;/a&gt; is $130, down from $150&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="16QiLN"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07YNLBS7R/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The affordable Amazon Fire TV Stick Lite&lt;/a&gt; is down to $18 (usually $30).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RTqS9V"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07ZZVX1F2/r?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The standard Amazon Fire TV Stick&lt;/a&gt; with a more capable Alexa Remote is $28 (usually $40).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0XlwIm"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B079QHML21/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The Amazon Fire TV 4K Stick&lt;/a&gt; with Dolby Atmos and 4K HDR support is $30 (usually $50).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NO0c9f"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07KGVB6D6?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The high-end Amazon Fire TV Cube&lt;/a&gt; that supports 4K HDR, Dolby Atmos, and can handle  voice queries from across the room is $80 (usually $120).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9Wxlx4pELT-hNUP9Mt3cFN6JqQ4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/11605119/akrales_180626_2683_0030.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="6MZWID"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07D4734HR?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sonos’ Beam soundbar&lt;/a&gt; is $299 (usually $399). It includes a $10 Amazon gift card with purchase.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6VLZAD"&gt;If you want a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B087CCZH4Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sonos Sub wireless subwoofer&lt;/a&gt; to go with it, those are $599 (usually $699). It’s currently set to come back in stock in January, but you can still get this deal price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="RzNACi"&gt;Tablet deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="jQORh1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9538448" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_portrait_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="bLKr3J"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07KD7K4B1?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The Kids Edition Fire HD 10&lt;/a&gt; is $130 instead of $200. This version includes the tablet, a tough case, a year’s worth of the FreeTime Unlimited subscription, and a two-year replacement guarantee if it breaks.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qFQdT4sboZuoUVUYP8jocXxoIaY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16034170/dseifert_190414_3374_3952.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Ring Stick Up Cam&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="HSa1Nk"&gt;Smart home deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="kk46IM"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07Q6ZZFLS/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ring’s Stick Up Cam&lt;/a&gt; is $80 (usually $100). You can get an Echo Dot (third-generation) speaker with it &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07ZZY2F17/?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;for the same price&lt;/a&gt;, but the delivery time is longer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="NaNsvL"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0758L64L9/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;battery-operated Ring Spotlight Cam&lt;/a&gt; is $150 (usually $200).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="LNA6Ty"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0727XJQLD/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ring’s Floodlight Camera&lt;/a&gt;, which requires hard-wiring to operate, is $190 instead of $250. You can &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B089V19X29/?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;add an Echo Show 5 display to the order for free&lt;/a&gt;, but it won’t be in stock until December 1st.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="rPe8fl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9603639" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_portrait_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="k8YVtu"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0849J7W5X/?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ring Video Doorbell 3&lt;/a&gt; is $140 (usually $200). You can add an Echo Show 5 smart display to the order &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B085VHPH8P/?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;for just $10 more here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jl5ufs"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07WLP395R/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ring’s Video Doorbell 3 Plus&lt;/a&gt;, which offers four-second video previews of alerts, is $160 instead of $230. Likewise, you can add an Echo Show 5 to the order &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08CWFLDK8/?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;for $10 more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7UHbal"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B084YCCX7X?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ring’s 14-piece Alarm set (the latest generation)&lt;/a&gt; is $200, down from $330. You can opt to add an Echo Dot (third generation) &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B085RLNFR9?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;for no extra charge&lt;/a&gt;, but the current ship date is December 23rd at the earliest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="LOCuxJ"&gt;Mesh Wi-Fi router deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="uYbtEq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9599966"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="6PhEkQ"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B085VM9ZDD/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The new Eero 6 dual-band mesh Wi-Fi router&lt;/a&gt; is $103 (usually $130).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="69dry2"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B085VNCZHZ/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;If you want a three-pack of the tri-band Eero Pro 6 mesh Wi-Fi routers&lt;/a&gt;, it’ll cost $479 (usually $600).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="gW5u3u"&gt;For the more basic Eero mesh Wi-Fi routers that don’t support Wi-Fi 6, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07WMLPSRL/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a three-pack&lt;/a&gt; costs $183 at Amazon, down from $230.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NCqTP2XZ8-ZZiXTkyK7JrGchY0Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19276758/vpavic_191010_3722_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="sFtw50"&gt;Google’s Nest Wifi mesh routers are steeply discounted, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07YMKD6SM?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;starting with the single unit&lt;/a&gt; that’s $139 instead of $169.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rxFyWM"&gt;You’ll save even more &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07YMJ57MB?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;if you buy two Google Nest Wifi routers&lt;/a&gt;, priced together for $219 (usually $299).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3jl41O"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B086HJXKJJ?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;s&gt;Netgear’s two-pack of Orbi Wi-Fi 6 routers&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;s&gt; are $380 (usually $450; Amazon currently says these will ship in mid-January).&lt;/s&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="VLZhQ9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Find more Black Friday deals on mesh Wi-Fi routers here","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21591145/best-black-friday-mesh-router-deals-wifi-sale"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="eJfVyo"&gt;Smartwatches &amp;amp; fitness tracker deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="gGyKcG"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08DFGWDZR?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Fitbit’s Versa 3 smartwatch with built-in GPS&lt;/a&gt; is $30 off, down to $200.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="v9EBTo"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08DFGC8YG?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The Fitbit Inspire 2 fitness tracker&lt;/a&gt; is $69 (usually $100).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="xAwTpt"&gt;Gaming deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="ytmROV"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9591200" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_portrait_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="KPIW46"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07SH36GRX/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Watch Dogs: Legion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for PS4 and Xbox One is $30 (usually $60).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fGOZFF"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08B4SHYNQ/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;13 Sentinels: Aegis Rim&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for PS4 is $30 (usually $60).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="VuSoFj"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07SFZX5CH/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marvel’s Avengers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is $27 (usually $60).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wxJjNW"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B089F7Y472?th=1&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Star Wars: Squadrons&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is $20 (usually $40).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="y9QW4t"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PFT19MG/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sega Genesis Mini retro console&lt;/a&gt; is $50 (usually $80).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Splatoon 2" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E4ZZMNkqHezEY2r90LZQJQ1kjD4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/8867671/Switch_Splatoon_2_artwork_01.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: &lt;em&gt;Splatoon 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Splatoon 2&lt;em&gt; is discounted at Amazon.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="dGYtt4"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07BVY39ZX/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mario Tennis Aces&lt;/em&gt; (digital code)&lt;/a&gt; for Nintendo Switch is $40 (usually $60).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rPslCL"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B073J2Y9NR/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Splatoon 2&lt;/em&gt; (digital code)&lt;/a&gt; for Nintendo Switch is $39 (usually $60).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="zPCZi1"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07SMBJVS8/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Link’s Awakening&lt;/em&gt; (digital code)&lt;/a&gt; for Nintendo Switch is $40 (usually $60).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nbZWLz"&gt;If you need extra space for games on your Nintendo Switch, Samsung’s microSD cards are steeply discounted. A &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0887P21Z2?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;256GB card is just $25&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0887CHVFF?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;doubling that storage to 512GB costs $65&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7ENTrx"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0723CMH14/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Seagate’s 2TB USB 3.0 game drive for Xbox consoles&lt;/a&gt; is $70 (usually $80). It comes with a one-month trial to Xbox Game Pass.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ZeTmYX"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07M9VCHDG/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;The PlayStation-branded version of that same hard drive&lt;/a&gt; is also $70.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="OIrFic"&gt;PC tech&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rFz0vReiuhz21BtwJzuvHllZsuw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19584336/DSCF4877_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="bwkCj0"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B088HH6LW5/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung’s 49-inch Odyssey G9 curved gaming monitor&lt;/a&gt; is $1,190 at Amazon, which is the biggest drop from its usual $1,400 price that we’ve seen yet. This QHD resolution monitor supports G-Sync and FreeSync, and has a 240Hz refresh rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="HMUd4Y"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Verge Deals on Twitter","description":"Join our 36,000 followers, and keep up with our best daily tech deals with @vergedeals","label":"Follow us!","url":"http://bit.ly/2JzR5Ud"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21583112/amazon-deals-black-friday-tech-cyber-monday"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21583112/amazon-deals-black-friday-tech-cyber-monday</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-11-25T10:32:03-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T10:32:03-05:00</updated>
    <title>The best Black Friday deals on noise-canceling headphones</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wvhQHESYT7wUmXxcrFO4BQgz4TE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67930970/akrales_190716_3546_0312.5.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="WmMrK3"&gt;Noise-canceling headphones are an important piece of tech if you enjoy having zero distractions or outside noise while you jam to funky tunes or listen to podcasts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wC95lA"&gt;While not as convenient as popping earbuds into your ears, noise-canceling headphones do a better job of erasing sound distractions when stacked up against popular wireless earbuds like Apple’s AirPods Pro or Jabra’s 75t. But if you prefer earbuds over headphones, we have rounded up &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21611428/black-friday-earbuds-deals-wireless-cyber-monday"&gt;the best wireless earbud deals this Black Friday&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iVgfg2"&gt;We are picking out all of the best deals going on right now on several brands that offer noise-canceling headphones. If you want more deals for other tech categories, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/21569412/black-friday-best-early-deals-sales-tech-gadgets"&gt;check out our best Black Friday deals post&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="fteLe0"&gt;Sony headphones deals&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nGZZvomEBBi8FLYVhglm5nU3i9E=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21699853/IMG_0625-1.0.jpeg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sony’s WH-1000XM4 headphones.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="P7tphe"&gt;While these may look familiar compared to the incredible 1000XM3s, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21356313/sony-1000xm4-noise-canceling-headphones-review-price-specs-features"&gt;Sony’s WH-1000XM4&lt;/a&gt; headphones are some of the best on the market if you want a pair of over-the-ear headphones with noise-canceling capabilities. When stacked up against their predecessors, the 1000XM4s allow users the ability to pair two devices via Bluetooth simultaneously, much like the Bose Noise Cancelling Headphones 700s. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0tCs52"&gt;These headphones released in August, but they have been frequently discounted the last several months. And right now, you can get them for &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Frover.ebay.com%2Frover%2F1%2F711-53200-19255-0%2F1%3Fmpre%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fwww.ebay.com%252Fitm%252F114538095643%26campid%3D5338421468%26toolid%3D10001%26customid%3Dverge&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21585574%2Fblack-friday-headphones-deals-noise-canceling-cyber-monday#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$250 at eBay through a trusted third-party seller&lt;/a&gt;. If the deal is sold out, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-WH-1000XM4-Canceling-Headphones-phone-call/dp/B0863FR3S9?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724683617488500643" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; have the headphones marked down to $278. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dhOHDa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9523565"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="v9UbPz"&gt;If $278 is still too much for you, but you prefer Sony as your choice of headphones, you can buy the WH-1000XM3’s for $200 at Focus Camera. The price may say $348 on the product listing, but if you enter discount code &lt;strong&gt;THANKS&lt;/strong&gt;, it will knock off $148 off the price. The promotion is available for both the black and silver color models.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="kDiLfG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9563643"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TetIB9"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/20/18632441/sony-xb900n-headphones-noise-canceling-bass-price"&gt;Sony’s midrange noise-canceling headphones, the XB900N&lt;/a&gt;, at a discounted price. Normally, these headphones cost $248, but you can get them for $123 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07RM8WQ8G?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724683993194110376" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yzr73i"&gt;Although these headphones are not as effective at active noise cancellation as the WH-1000XM4s, the XB900N will get things a little quieter if you need peace and quiet but want to keep your budget under $200. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="jwFja1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9631953"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="a9Rxcr"&gt;Sony’s WH-CH710 have also seen a price cut this Black Friday. Normally, these headphones cost $200, but you can get them for just $88 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B085RQYX5Z?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724686850701604233" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. The WH-CH710s offer AI noise cancellation, which, according to Sony, means the product “constantly analyzes environmental ambient sound components, and automatically selects the most effective noise-canceling mode for users’ surroundings.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="46YEKN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9646609"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="TlVNAA"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best Black Friday deals you can get right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/21569412/black-friday-best-early-deals-sales-tech-gadgets"},{"title":"The best Black Friday deals on wireless earbuds","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21611428/black-friday-earbuds-deals-wireless-cyber-monday"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="LPCV7z"&gt;Bose headphone deals&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TK2IFKUrWHzgKpPDfFUQ6Qgae6U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/18314839/akrales_190716_3546_0110.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bose’s Noise Canceling 700 wireless headphones.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="kOClzM"&gt;If you need a reliable pair of noise-canceling headphones that you will primarily use for videoconferencing or phone calls, you can’t go wrong with the Noise Canceling Headphones 700 by Bose. These headphones also allow you to connect two devices simultaneously. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QORd7d"&gt;You can get &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/19/20700627/bose-noise-cancelling-headphones-700-redesigned-microphones-review"&gt;Bose’s excellent Noise Cancelling 700 Headphones&lt;/a&gt; for $299 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bose-Cancelling-Wireless-Bluetooth-Headphones/dp/B07X5F81JS?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724689194665262520" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https://www.bhphotovideo.com/c/product/1475153-REG/bose_794297_0100_headphones_700_noise_cancelling.html&amp;amp;xcust=___vg__e_21333453__r_theverge.com/authors__t_w__d_#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https://deals.dell.com/en-us/mpp/productdetail/6b3f&amp;amp;xcust=___vg__e_21333453__r_theverge.com/authors__t_w__d_#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Dell&lt;/a&gt;. Sadly, this deal is only available in “soapstone white” at all of these retailers. If you are not a fan of the white color option, you can get the Bose 700 headphones for $339 in other colors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="sqMrT5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9586877"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hv0HI6"&gt;Beats Solo Pro deals&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_uSUmgOqNB9BXbR_PSkcxTdRkyI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19316748/cwelch_191024_3759_0008.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Beats Solo Pro.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ZTdwhL"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/25/20931329/beats-solo-pro-review-noise-canceling-on-ear-wireless-headphones-features-price"&gt;Beats Solo Pro headphones&lt;/a&gt; are our best pick for on-ear noise-canceling headphones. They are the best choice for working out, thanks to great sweat resistance and strong clamping force, allowing the headphones to stay on your head while you move around. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IGbRcy"&gt;Right now, Best Buy has them for as low as $170 in &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724689742090135409" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;light blue&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724689727241469173" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;navy blue&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724689752964130781" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;red&lt;/a&gt; (more matte collection). Or you can buy them for &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724681399229938177" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$230 in black, gray, or white&lt;/a&gt;. B&amp;amp;H Photo also has the headphones on sale, starting at $200 if you buy them in &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1512391-REG%2Fbeats_by_dr_dre_mrja2ll_a_solo_pro_wireless_noise.html%2FDFF%2Fd10-v21-t1-x997146%2FSID%2F66960X1514734Xc5a53223b89ba2bc0321946299bdaba1#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;navy blue&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1512392-REG%2Fbeats_by_dr_dre_mrjc2ll_a_solo_pro_wireless_noise.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;red&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3pFQwv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9625639"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="TvCJlI"&gt;Other headphone deals&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XPnTKUxq3LOoYVfJ9es91huUefE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19167216/bfarsace_190903_3639_0007.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sennheiser Momentum Wireless (third-generation).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="X5hfVx"&gt;If you want a good pair of noise-canceling headphones and you have a higher budget to work with, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/5/20843395/sennheiser-momentum-wireless-3-review-release-date-news-specs-features-noise-cancelling-headphones"&gt;Sennheiser’s third-generation Momentum Wireless headphones&lt;/a&gt; are one of the best options. These headphones come with adequate noise cancellation along with bass-rich and detailed sound output. These headphones are also very good for extended use even if you wear glasses, so you do not need to worry about discomfort if you want to wear these while listening to long podcast episodes or while on a long train ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5aRBA9"&gt;Normally $400, you can get these headphones for $350 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sennheiser-Momentum-Cancelling-Headphones-Functionality/dp/B07VW98ZKG?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724685151178098131" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TLHMP6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9636852"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mqJ6ml"&gt;Speaking of headphones that offer amazing sound quality and noise cancellation, Shure’s Aonic 50 headphones are another alternative that come in an interesting build. These headphones use Bluetooth 5 Wireless technology, have a 20-hour battery life, and support advanced codecs like LDAC. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zzgzcK"&gt;Normally, the Aonic 50s would set you back $400, but you can get them for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Shure-Cancelling-Headphones-Studio-Quality-Technology/dp/B084S1CYKF?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$299 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724686048381502302" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$300 at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="YIXF2J"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9640163"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21585574/black-friday-headphones-deals-noise-canceling-cyber-monday"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21585574/black-friday-headphones-deals-noise-canceling-cyber-monday</id>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-11-25T10:12:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T10:12:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>The best Black Friday deals you can get right now</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NYR_JALnMblF26DFSzWtJdI3X-s=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67798744/akramer_201113_4290_0021.0.11.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;MacBook Pro (late-2020) | Photo by Alexander Kramer for The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="qSby2y"&gt;Most &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/black-friday"&gt;Black Friday&lt;/a&gt; deals will launch the day after Thanksgiving (November 26th) in the US as usual, but the pandemic has shaken things up in yet another way. The best deals will be happening online, with fewer in-person sales for the sake of safety. Better yet, some of those great deals are already available, so you can get started on your holiday gift (or personal) shopping. With this post, we’re rounding up the best early Black Friday deals from retailers like Amazon, Best Buy, Walmart, Target, Adorama, B&amp;amp;H Photo, Newegg, and anywhere else we find deals you should know about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Kq7sS1"&gt;Smart speaker and audio deals&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MRx7v2iKWDhr2lI1LUX0smT9vN4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19208402/dseifert_190915_3647_0001.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sono’s portable Move speaker.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="GbNCbs"&gt;If you are looking for a Dolby Atmos soundbar complete with rear surrounds and rotating speakers, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724766654076559156" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Vizio’s Elevate soundbar is $700 right now at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. The Vizio Elevate features 18 speakerstota  and comes with a wireless eight-inch subwoofer. Normally, this product would set you back $1,000 dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="E8dr2S"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9733903"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3TO80R"&gt;Sonos has slashed the prices on several of its speakers ahead of Black Friday. Three of its popular models are $100 off right now, a savings of up to 25 percent. You can buy the Sonos Move, the company’s first portable speaker, for just $299 right now at Sonos and Amazon or $300 at Best Buy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="APQVzv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9575913"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="tWOj2e"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07D4734HR?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sonos Beam is $299 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; (Usually $400). The deal is also available at &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8836598/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.sonos.com/en-us/shop/move.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sonos’ direct website&lt;/a&gt;. This is a great entry-level soundbar. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="sNyRnl"&gt;You can also buy &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B087CCZH4Q?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sonos Sub add-on speaker at a discounted price for $599 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; (usually $700). The deal is also available at &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8836598/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.sonos.com/en-us/shop/sub.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sonos’ direct website&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="jIQou8"&gt;If you’re looking for a compact and inexpensive smart speaker, both of the latest Amazon Echo and Echo Dot devices are on sale. The 4th Gen Echo Dot is down to $29, which is the lowest price we’ve seen since its launch this fall. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PJS3T7"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9607515"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rkA3Fv"&gt;The Echo Dot’s compact design might not be appealing to everyone, but if you are looking for an Echo Device but want something a bit bigger, you can grab the Amazon Echo’s fourth-generation speaker for $70 right now at a few retailers, including Amazon and Target. Like this year’s Echo Dot, the Amazon Echo has an updated design that makes it more spherical in shape. It also has much improved audio quality and the ability to connect Zigbee smart home devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="s8yyuQ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9508352"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="K1n5zT"&gt;Over at Adorama and Best Buy, you can buy a Google Nest Audio two-pack for $170 right now. A two-pack for this smart speaker would normally set you back $199.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="U1SnqO"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9503894"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="of9IqM"&gt;Headphone and earbud deals&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uPyp1tAFu7ySzKQN1zzQF9Y5QPI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19336099/cwelch_191031_3763_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="61vp5x"&gt;You can get &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/19/20700627/bose-noise-cancelling-headphones-700-redesigned-microphones-review"&gt;Bose’s excellent Noise Cancelling 700 Headphones&lt;/a&gt; for $299 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bose-Cancelling-Wireless-Bluetooth-Headphones/dp/B07Q4QK379?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724213175001080094" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1475153-REG%2Fbose_794297_0100_headphones_700_noise_cancelling.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdeals.dell.com%2Fen-us%2Fmpp%2Fproductdetail%2F6b3f#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Dell&lt;/a&gt;. The price is only available in “soapstone white,” unfortunately, at all these retailers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="IxWjk2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9586877"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OYOJJg"&gt;Apple’s &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8836598/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://electronics.woot.com/offers/apple-airpods-pro-18?utm_medium=affiliate&amp;amp;utm_campaign=CJ&amp;amp;cjevent=bf1dd84529dc11eb814400030a24060c&amp;amp;utm_source=Vox+Media" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;AirPods Pro wireless earbuds are $190 at Woot right now&lt;/a&gt;. This is the lowest we’ve seen yet on Apple’s flagship earbuds. Compared to the standard AirPods, the Pro model features better sound quality and noise cancellation, plus support for Apple’s new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/2/21498931/apple-spatial-audio-airpods-pro-surround-sound-quick-auto-switching"&gt;spatial audio feature&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ULP9BI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="G47XoL"&gt;Over at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Samsung-Wireless-Cancelling-Charging-Included/dp/B08J3Y4W5J/ref=as_li_ss_tl?th=1&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=vergegooddeals-20&amp;amp;linkId=4387f080251cd074ca147f7179f672d2&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1722751386730213452" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, you can buy the Samsung’s bean-shaped wireless earbuds the Galaxy Buds Live for just $140. Aside from an unorthodox design, my colleagues, Chris Welch and Becca Farsace, pointed out in &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/GwL-COqlauA"&gt;their&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21356260/samsung-galaxy-buds-live-review-wireless-earbuds-beans-design-specs-price"&gt;reviews&lt;/a&gt; that the Galaxy Buds Live also produce a powerful sound and come with a lengthy battery life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IhVQK2"&gt;Each retailer has four colors, but one color is exclusive to each site; if you want the Galaxy Buds Live in red, the sale is only available at Amazon. Over at Best Buy, you can buy them in blue for $140. Additionally, both retailers also have the earbuds on sale in black, bronze, and white.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="L89sjM"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9503020"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AhnjK1"&gt;Samsung’s Galaxy Buds Plus wireless earbuds are down to just $110 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B083KVM9VW/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724117005601449431" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. This is the best price we’ve seen for this model, which usually costs $150 outside of any discounts. Compared to the standard Galaxy Buds, this upgraded model that launched alongside the Galaxy S20 series of phones has improved sound quality, microphones, and battery life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j5zWQ0"&gt;If you are looking to buy two pairs of Galaxy Buds Plus, Best Buy has a few bundles, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724213386876980609" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;allowing you to buy sets for only $200&lt;/a&gt;. You can mix and match which color you want for both pairs and are available in blue, black, light blue, red, and white. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Wo6p68"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9581901" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_square_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ArxGby"&gt;Alongside the Plus wireless earbuds, Samsung’s Galaxy Buds are discounted at Amazon and Best Buy. Normally, these earbuds would cost $130, but you can get them for $79 at Amazon or $80 at Best Buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ttnzGj"&gt;Unfortunately, the color options are limited at both retailers, so you can only buy these earbuds in either black or silver. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="o58dM6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9586872"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="9A2EQ5"&gt;Laptop / tablet deals&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Q_SNbhcN5j7a3EiarLGQwvUdDzQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22038540/akramer_201113_4290_0009.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Alexander Kramer for The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;MacBook Pro (late-2020).&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="9wSrQ5"&gt;This month, Apple released new MacBook Pros powered by its own Apple silicon processors. If you are interested in buying the new MacBook Pro (late 2020) model with the new M1 chip, the base model, which comes with 8GB of RAM and 256GB of SSD storage for $1,249 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5LLDSG?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1604809-REG%2Fapple_myd82ll_a_13_3_macbook_pro_with.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;, knocking $50 off its normal retail price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yKA0iQ"&gt;If 256GB of storage is not enough for you can buy the same model but with 512GB of storage for $1,449 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-MacBook-13-inch-256GB-Storage/dp/B08N5LH3F7?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1604810-REG%2Fapple_myd92ll_a_13_3_macbook_pro_with.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="V4pCH7"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9733800"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Tf9DYs"&gt;If you are looking for an iPad in a smaller size, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-Mini-Wi-Fi-64GB/dp/B07PRD2NQ7?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon has the latest iPad mini with 64GB of storage on sale for $379&lt;/a&gt;. The 2019 iPad Mini features a 7.9-inch display and all the same specs as the iPad Air. Nevertheless, this is the best tablet for people that want an Apple device to watch movies, read books or play games, but want a something that is bigger than a phone but not as big as a laptop.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dlyLDy"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9515887"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LmyLtf"&gt;If you are looking to pick up an iPad Pro this Black Friday, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-11-inch-Wi-Fi-256GB/dp/B08637NV8M/ref=as_li_ss_tl?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=Apple+iPad+11+inch+Pro&amp;amp;qid=1606161912&amp;amp;sr=8-3&amp;amp;th=1&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=vergegooddeals-20&amp;amp;linkId=5f05426660dc58d28ae324183dffef5c&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724578293673083745" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; have Apple’s high-end iPad Pro for $729 and $730 respectively. This model includes an 11-inch display and a 128GB storage configuration. If 128GB is not enough storage space for you, both retailers are taking $100 off the 256GB configuration, bringing the price down to $800, which is what you would normally pay if you bought the entry-level 11-inch iPad Pro with the lowest storage configuration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="88eK3q"&gt;The iPad Pro’s 12-inch model with 128GB of storage is also on sale for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-12-9-inch-Wi-Fi-256GB/dp/B0863D15R6/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=vergegooddeals-20&amp;amp;linkId=076df3f320798fd15e55e2336fa98314&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$899 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724674102959813551" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$900 at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. Normally this model and storage configuration would set you back $1,000. If you need a bit more storage, the same 12-inch iPad Pro, but with 256GB of storage is also discounted, bringing the price down to &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-12-9-inch-Wi-Fi-256GB/dp/B0862HNWGK?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$999 at Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724674166117590966" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;$1,000 at Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GJf6F5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9515999"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="zbPVaT"&gt;Wearable and smart watch deals&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/big8WY8b6LcdHotTnUDvSFOpf2c=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21926117/dseifert_200930_4218_0002.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple Watch SE.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="SyzhPO"&gt;If you like Fitbit’s wearables and prefer to have a smartwatch by the company, you can get the Fitbit Sense smartwatch for $280 at &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Fitbit’s website&lt;/a&gt; or at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724580973739712242" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1590667-REG%2Ffitbit_fb512bkbk_sense_gps_smartwatch_carbon.html#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;. Normally this model costs $330 and allows you to track your stress levels and measure your blood oxygen levels. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="AAW1Mh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9603483"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DlkbsX"&gt;The Apple Watch SE was already the most affordable Watch that Apple made at $279, but it’s even cheaper at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-Apple-Watch-SE-40mm/dp/B08J5W9QWZ/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=vergegooddeals-20&amp;amp;linkId=991c5b97a31528a6a07f9a0fae1bdb29&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724578867741826427" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. You can score the 40mm GPS version for $259 or the larger 44mm Watch for $289 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-Apple-Watch-SE-44mm/dp/B08J5XTRZD/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=vergegooddeals-20&amp;amp;linkId=e39bfa3f763e4fa56204c59a62303c7a&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724578918898824263" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. Each size looks similar to the more expensive Series 6 but lacks the always-on display and a few other features. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Widfy"&gt;The Apple Watch SE aligns more with the Series 5 in terms of specs, but at $259, it’s a fantastic value. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21438413/apple-watch-series-6-se-5-3-comparison-smartwatch-models-versus"&gt;Here’s an in-depth post&lt;/a&gt; on how the SE differs from other recent Apple Watch models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="imKmLJ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9514947" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_portrait_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Ffa5rt"&gt;The Apple Watch Series 6 is also cheaper than usual at Amazon and Walmart. Normally $400 for the 40mm GPS model, it’s down to $330 — but there’s a catch. You must buy this model in either red at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08J5RBMRN?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-Watch-Series-6-GPS-40mm-PRODUCT-RED-Aluminum-Case-with-PRODUCT-RED-Sport-Band-Regular%2F478251261%3Fselected%3Dtrue&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="I6L1IF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9432291"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="BYR4vm"&gt;Smart home deals&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rxzqdk_gFIv-LKIK-EnEFxmFepE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19276760/vpavic_191010_3722_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google Nest Wifi.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="65HtKg"&gt;If you have a large home and want to make sure all of the rooms in it have internet and no dead zones, Amazon and Best Buy has discounted the Eero 6 mesh Wi-Fi router. You can get three units for just $479. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Jg0NxI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9599966"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="z8kPHL"&gt;Ahead of Black Friday, Google has discounted several of its products, including the Nest Wifi, and you can buy a two-pack for $219. The Nest Wifi system is easy to set up, and with two units, you can cover up to 4,400 square feet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="RtDGBK"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9603453"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="qwgnwv"&gt;If you need a mesh router system that will cover more square feet in your home, you can buy a three-pack Eero 6 mesh router for $223. The mesh routers also include a built-in Zigbee smart home hub, allowing you to connect and control select devices with Amazon’s voice assistant Alexa. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="dACyX2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9603441"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Av0Zih"&gt;If you prefer Netgear products, you can save 22 percent on a two-pack for the company’s Nighthawk mesh router system. It’s designed for homes that have up to 400Mbps of internet speeds. Netgear says its Nighthawk mesh router system provides up to 3,000 square feet in coverage and support for 25 or more devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wX8NXq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9603472"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="q2G2wV"&gt;At &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/All-new-Ring-Alarm-8-piece-kit/dp/B085RCLP9Z/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=vergegooddeals-20&amp;amp;linkId=8c21d9388b42892a758895a6df08cbd6&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724304542635172098" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, you can save $140 on an eight-piece Ring Alarm home security kit, and it comes with a free third-gen Amazon Echo Dot with purchase. Normally $290, this kit will only cost you $150. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="WM5ndj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9591273"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Kp4b3f"&gt;Circling back to Netgear, its $450 flagship mesh router system is also discounted. You can buy the Orbi RBK752 Wi-Fi 6 mesh router system for $280 at Best Buy right now. This is a great product if you need something that will have the bandwidth to stream multiple videos in 4K or 8K resolution in your house. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2cCTga"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9603482"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b88jpxQulhWOx3InDZAsODxGguo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/12794165/dseifert_180905_2925_9843.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Dan Seifert / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The SimpliSafe base next to the keypad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Cq5fql"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8836598/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://simplisafe.com/home-security-shop" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SimpliSafe’s home security systems are 50 percent off&lt;/a&gt; for Black Friday, starting at $114 for the most basic bundle. Each bundle includes a free SimpliCam (a $99 value).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ee3yV9"&gt;Other deals&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Samsung T7 USB-C SSD" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hlTovZEDQnfjSYa4cOU2ZuEFg-Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22052732/samsung_t7_ssd.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Samsung&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Samsung’s T7 USB-C SSD.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="B7FLKg"&gt;Samsung’s &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Samsung-Wireless-Charger-Trio-Compatible/dp/B08FBFJDQ1?ots=1&amp;amp;slotNum=6&amp;amp;imprToken=fabafd4a-5cca-0421-cb0&amp;amp;tag=theverge02-20&amp;amp;ascsubtag=%5B%5Dvg%5Be%5D21283333%5Br%5Dgoogle.com%5Bt%5Dw%5Bd%5DD" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Wireless Charger Trio&lt;/a&gt; is a charging pad that allows you to simultaneously provide power to three electronic devices — a smartwatch, earbuds, and phone, or a smartwatch and two phones. Amazon and Best Buy have the charging pad on sale for $20 off, bringing the price down to $79. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mq2s89"&gt;The Trio wireless charging pad can also charge iPhones (iPhone X or newer), but its right pad only supports charging for Samsung Galaxy smartwatches. Fortunately, you can charge your AirPods on the pad if you have a wireless charging case. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="fGsuLo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9529158"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="T6HkwD"&gt;Samsung’s fast T7 USB-C SSD with 1TB of storage normally costs $200, but you can buy this portable SSD for just $150 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0874XN4D8/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724300631221915412" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. It features optional password protection with AES 256-bit encryption and Samsung claims the T7 has up to 1,050MB/s transfer speeds. It’s compatible with a variety of operating systems, including Windows 10, macOS, and Android. Unfortunately, it will not work on iPad or iOS devices and it is not compatible as an external SSD for the PS5 and Xbox Series X/S. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GMnJXQ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9556309" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_square_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ILg7_gBLuk7L6nDS2JbrW45t_tk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19404056/Peak_Design_Everyday_Backpack_Zip_20L_MDNGHT_LFSTYL3.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Peak Design&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="4ShY7X"&gt;Peak Design has kicked off its “Super Massive Black Friday sale” &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.peakdesign.com%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F21569412%2Fblack-friday-best-early-deals-sales-tech-gadgets#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;with sizeable discounts on bags and tripods&lt;/a&gt;. It might be tough to imagine when you might next need a durable backpack that can fit a lot of gadgets within, but the company’s &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.peakdesign.com%2Fcollections%2Feveryday-bags%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F21569412%2Fblack-friday-best-early-deals-sales-tech-gadgets#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;“Everyday” lineup of bags is 20 percent off&lt;/a&gt;. Its &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.peakdesign.com%2Fcollections%2Ftravel-bags%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F21569412%2Fblack-friday-best-early-deals-sales-tech-gadgets#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;bigger “Travel” bags are also discounted&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0PrH58"&gt;If you’re into photography, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.peakdesign.com%2Fcollections%2Ftripods&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2Fgood-deals%2F21569412%2Fblack-friday-best-early-deals-sales-tech-gadgets#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Peak Design’s Travel Tripod and a few accessories&lt;/a&gt; that are compatible with it are cheaper than usual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="VDyIWJ"&gt;Gaming deals&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-0C6Bsc8ReKgT0rv3pfhFIiSt04=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/20079033/Watch_Dogs_Legion_StreetArtist_vignette_Light.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Watch Dogs: Legion.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Blx9fM"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Watch Dogs: Legion&lt;/em&gt;, the latest installment in Ubisoft’s hack-anything, open-world game, the PS4 and Xbox One versions are down to $30 at Amazon and Best Buy. If you are looking for the PC it &lt;a href="https://ubisoft.pxf.io/c/482924/864200/12050?u=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.ubi.com%2Fus%2Fwatch-dogs-legion-standard-edition%2F5cec2d5839798c0870c07698.html%3Flang%3Den_US&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;is down to $45 at Ubisoft’s official website&lt;/a&gt;. This title recently came out and this is still a good discount. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="621nK9"&gt;What makes this deal even better is that if you buy the Xbox One or PS4 version of the game, you get an upgrade to the Xbox Series X / S or PS5 copies for free. Even if you don’t have much interest in the game, it’s an affordable way to check out what &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/9/21556197/xbox-series-s-ray-tracing-watch-dogs-legion"&gt;impressive ray-tracing graphics&lt;/a&gt; look like on the new console hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="SZ4g2C"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9581295"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZvFCDQ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Last of Us Part II &lt;/em&gt;is one of the most popular PS4 games released this year. If you have yet to experience Naughty Dog’s latest title, you can pick it up for $30 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Last-Us-Part-II-PlayStation-4/dp/B07DJRFSDF/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=vergegooddeals-20&amp;amp;linkId=fc2d003cd4936f885db857399379224b&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724302857718714066" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=vergeevergreen&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fplaystation-4%2Fgames%2Fproducts%2Fthe-last-of-us-part-ii%2F11097389.html%3Fcondition%3DPre-Owned%26utm_source%3Drakutenls%26utm_medium%3Daffiliate%26utm_content%3DVox%2BMedia%26utm_campaign%3D10%26utm_kxconfid%3Dtebx5rmj3%26cid%3Dafl_10000087%26affID%3D77777%26sourceID%3DnOD_rLJHOac-aO7KyWbp_D6EPQtMi.er3Q" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GameStop&lt;/a&gt;. This is the lowest price the game has been marked down to date. If you recently purchased a PS5, you can also play this game via backwards compatibility. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="20AIbx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9591200"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3mRedx"&gt;Speaking of popular PS4 games that released this year, &lt;em&gt;Ghost of Tsushima&lt;/em&gt; is also on sale at its lowest price ever of $40 at Amazon and Best Buy. Even better? If you purchased a PS5, you can transfer your save data from your PS4 and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/6/21553494/sony-playstation-5-ps5-backward-compatibility-ps4-digital-foundry"&gt;experience the game in 60 frames per second&lt;/a&gt;, a feature exclusive to Sony’s next-gen console. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="XG8KV1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9591232"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5Oyb4M"&gt;If you’re having trouble narrowing down what games you want, why not get several? &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fc%2Fvideo-game-software%2F-%2FN-fhju6%3FNao%3D0&amp;amp;sharedid=verge"&gt;Target is hosting a “get three for the price of two”&lt;/a&gt; deal on video game purchases — even for newer titles like &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty Black Ops: Cold War&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Assassin’s Creed Valhalla&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Yakuza: Like a Dragon&lt;/em&gt;, to name a few. The list goes on, though one thing that isn’t eligible are first-party Sony games for the PS5, like the &lt;em&gt;Demon’s Souls &lt;/em&gt;remake, but you can pick up &lt;em&gt;Godfall, &lt;/em&gt;which is available on Sony’s next-gen console (and on PC.) Even &lt;em&gt;Cyberpunk 2077,&lt;/em&gt; a game coming out next month is eligible for this promotion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="0oBNwJ"&gt;PC upgrade and accessory deals&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XuFZME20BNo68OlTqyPAg_Qhe68=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16219641/akrales_190507_3407_0002.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Logitech’s G502 Lightspeed wireless gaming mouse&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ekCZCJ"&gt;If you want 2TB of fast storage for your PC, Samsung’s 2TB 970 Evo Plus NVMe SSD is $250 at Newegg and Amazon, beating the lowest price by about $40. Over the summer, the price was steady at $350. A PCIe 3.0 M.2 SSD like this will fit in only certain kinds of motherboards (so check before you buy). Alternatively, it can also make for a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/5/13/18518127/portable-ssd-external-thunderbolt-3-usb-c-samsung-x5-t5-specs-test-how-to"&gt;very fast USB-C drive&lt;/a&gt; if you get an M.2 enclosure for it. Either route you take, you’ll get a lot of speedy storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="SBMmrh"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9581101" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_square_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sp5U2o"&gt;If you are in the market for a new gaming mouse, the Logitech G502 lightspeed wireless gaming mouse is $100 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07L4BM851/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;amp;tag=vergegooddeals-20&amp;amp;linkId=6d40681213d2724c8f594037a42de79a&amp;amp;language=en_US" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724610993236129647" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD/rLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=vergeevergreen&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fpc%2Faccessories%2Fmice-and-mouse-pads%2Fproducts%2Fg502-lightspeed-wireless-gaming-mouse%2F194789.html%3Fgclid%3DCjwKCAiA2O39BRBjEiwApB2Ikj7V-m9Ll0yU2yEZIZ3ZMro_HXBepHnmSCHcSHuTCrOgHGrtECg9KhoCysUQAvD_BwE%26gclsrc%3Daw.ds" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GameStop&lt;/a&gt;. Normally this gaming mouse is $150. It features It features eleven programmable buttons, a 25600 DPI, and fully customizable RGB lighting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4e3ggr"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9550529"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Kjdq2f"&gt;Stay tuned for more deals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="cl8q2A"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="actionbox" data-anthem-component-data='{"title":"Verge Deals on Twitter","description":"Join our 36,000 followers, and keep up with our best daily tech deals with @vergedeals","label":"Follow us!","url":"http://bit.ly/2JzR5Ud"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/21569412/black-friday-best-early-deals-sales-tech-gadgets"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/21569412/black-friday-best-early-deals-sales-tech-gadgets</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
      <name>Taylor Lyles</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-11-25T10:02:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T10:02:30-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apparent ransomware attack closes Baltimore County public schools</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GmBozO7YlZKeZhPmpbGc_Xn4vW8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67980779/acastro_170621_1777_0006_v4.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="StfBhI"&gt;The Baltimore County Public School (BCPS) system has canceled classes after an apparent ransomware attack shut down internal networks. Described by officials as “a networking issue,” the outage is affecting the schools’ email and grading systems, among others. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hfGcK2"&gt;BCPS chief of staff Mychael Dickerson &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DMDForward/status/1331601353085513728"&gt;confirmed on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; that the outage is believed to be the result of a ransomware attack. “We were the victim of a ransomware cyber attack,” he said. “Our BCPS technology team is working to address the situation.” Dickerson could only tweet the message since &lt;a href="https://www.bcps.org/"&gt;the BCPS website&lt;/a&gt; is currently down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GxLeav"&gt;As a result of the outage, offices have been closed for the day and students have been given the day off. “We knew it wouldn’t be a quick fix,” Dickerson &lt;a href="https://www.baltimoresun.com/maryland/baltimore-county/cng-co-baltimore-county-schools-closed-network-issue-20201125-drhmnq5ilraplea2h4v7p4pn34-story.html"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The Baltimore Sun&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “We just don’t want people standing by thinking we’ll get back up.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jDy8hL"&gt;Ransomware attacks have become a common tactic for cybercriminals, often targeting underfunded infrastructure like hospitals, schools, and municipal governments. A separate ransomware attack paralyzed Baltimore’s City government in May of last year, shutting down online systems for paying water bills and other services. Major companies like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/9/21285758/honda-ransomware-virus-attack-production-halt-offices-workers"&gt;Honda&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/4/21353842/garmin-ransomware-attack-wearables-wastedlocker-evil-corp"&gt;Garmin&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/6/21356757/canon-ransomware-attack-usa"&gt;Canon&lt;/a&gt; have also been compromised by ransomware. In September, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/17/21443851/death-ransomware-attack-hospital-germany-cybersecurity"&gt;a ransomware attack on the Düsseldorf University Hospital&lt;/a&gt; was linked to the death of a female patient, the first death directly tied to a ransomware attack on medical facilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zyUhdh"&gt;Ransomware attacks work by encrypting data on compromised networks and locking out the network operators. Criminals then ask for a ransom payment (typically in bitcoin) to restore functionality. Because the ransom is often lower than the cost of recovery, many victims simply pay the requested amount, making it an unfortunately profitable scheme. In February, &lt;a href="https://blog.emsisoft.com/en/35583/report-the-cost-of-ransomware-in-2020-a-country-by-country-analysis/"&gt;a report by Emisoft&lt;/a&gt; estimated that US businesses paid more than $1.3 billion to resolve ransomware attacks in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QAG7nZ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;An earlier version of this article erroneously attributed the Emisoft report to ID Ransomware. The report merely drew on data from the ID Ransomware product, which is maintained by an Emisoft employee. We regret the error.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/25/21719056/baltimore-county-public-schools-cancel-class-bcps-ransomware-hack"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/25/21719056/baltimore-county-public-schools-cancel-class-bcps-ransomware-hack</id>
    <author>
      <name>Russell Brandom</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-11-25T10:00:04-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T10:00:04-05:00</updated>
    <title>These are the best Black Friday TV deals</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HbIYJbhaYuwZtj3CCImAKsl0nYc=/0x51:1560x1091/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67980741/Screen_Shot_2020_11_25_at_8.43.21_AM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="30Yud8"&gt;With a pair of next-gen video game consoles now on the market, it’s a very good time to be shopping for a new 4K TV that can best showcase their capabilities. Even if gaming isn’t your thing, Black Friday season always brings about excellent discounts on sets from many of the top brands like Samsung, LG, Vizio, Sony, TCL, and others. Whether you’re ready to spend over $1,000 or are looking for something more on the budget side, odds are you can find something to your liking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cAtFEz"&gt;Looking for more than just a TV? Check out our updating list of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/21569412/black-friday-best-early-deals-sales-tech-gadgets"&gt;the best Black Friday deals you can get right now.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="o5AZiQ"&gt;The best TV deals for Xbox Series X and PlayStation 5 owners&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="MHP8gq"&gt;The Xbox Series X and PS5 do much more than just play games in 4K. They support HDR, variable refresh rate (in the case of the X), and can output games at up to 120Hz. This makes games feel smoother and more responsive than ever before. Variable refresh can eliminate unsightly tearing and make any dips in frame rate unnoticeable, and this — along with 120Hz support — is also something you’ll find on the $300 Xbox Series S. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qMc5Vz"&gt;If you plan on getting one of the new consoles (or already have), finding a TV that can get the most from them could be tricky. Generally speaking, you’ll have to buy a very recent set, and you’ll want to ensure that it supports the newer HDMI 2.1 specification. But buying a TV released this year doesn’t have to mean breaking the bank. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CE2cWf"&gt;I’ve picked out the below TVs as the best options you can get for one of the next-gen gaming consoles in 2020. All of them should take advantage of everything the Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S, and PlayStation 5 can do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="P5UnlZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9733731"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="WscT1J"&gt;48-inch: $1,449 at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724766030161641896" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="CrC9TJ"&gt;65-inch: $1,899.99 at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724766059250185154" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; | $1,999.99 at &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1555067-REG%2Flg_oled65cxpua_cxpua_65_class_hdr.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21591567%2Fblack-friday-tv-deals-sale-cyber-monday#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="Qr8ekn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9733758"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="gOTJ4z"&gt;65-inch: $1,799 at &lt;a href="https://bestbuy.7tiv.net/c/482924/633495/10014?prodsku=6401923&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bestbuy.com%2Fsite%2Flg-65-class-bx-series-oled-4k-uhd-smart-webos-tv%2F6401923.p%3FskuId%3D6401923&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="dLiJkH"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9733767"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="5dpvuL"&gt;65-inch: $1,499.99 at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724766254883271209" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="O99z1H"&gt;Vizio’s Elevate Dolby Atmos soundbar, designed as a perfect companion for the OLED TV, is also &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724766285896033058" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;on sale at Best Buy for $700&lt;/a&gt; (normally $1,000). It has rotating speakers that point upward for Atmos content and then rotate forward for regular stereo audio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="Ubft3P"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9733779"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="TVRNxj"&gt;55-inch: $1,049.99 (normally $1,299.99) at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724766412231937570" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8836598/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.samsung.com/us/televisions-home-theater/tvs/qled-4k-tvs/55-class-q80t-qled-4k-uhd-hdr-smart-tv-2020-qn55q80tafxza/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1546571-REG%2Fsamsung_qn55q80tafxza_55_qled_q80_series.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21591567%2Fblack-friday-tv-deals-sale-cyber-monday#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ameOMr"&gt;Sony X900H&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="lBWPVd"&gt;As the maker of the PS5, you’d hope Sony’s TVs would be a good match for the console. The X900H fits that bill, though some of the OLED picks are a better overall package. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="yMu7t8"&gt;75-inch: $1,599.99 at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724766475965495345" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1545412-REG%2Fsony_xbr75x900h_x900h_75_class_hdr.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21591567%2Fblack-friday-tv-deals-sale-cyber-monday#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nDyzKP"&gt;65-inch: $999.99 at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724766501964102820" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; | $1,098 at &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1545417-REG%2Fsony_xbr65x900h_x900h_65_class_hdr.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21591567%2Fblack-friday-tv-deals-sale-cyber-monday#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="8RIV0k"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best Black Friday deals happening at Best Buy","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21583253/best-buy-black-friday-tech-deals-cyber-monday-tvs-games-phones"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h3 id="ZQHT45"&gt;TCL 6 Series Roku TV&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="JKrtPJ"&gt;TCL’s latest 6 Series TV has tremendous picture quality for the price and supports those next-gen gaming features including 4K at 120Hz and variable refresh rate. Plus, you get built-in Roku software, so you can find pretty much any streaming app you need right on the TV itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="IKTuZe"&gt;65-inch: $899.99 at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724766539321572183" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1584065-REG%2Ftcl_65r635_65_6_serie_4k_hdr.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21591567%2Fblack-friday-tv-deals-sale-cyber-monday#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="n96JSF"&gt;55-inch: $649.99 at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724766564895228249" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bhphotovideo.com%2Fc%2Fproduct%2F1584063-REG%2Ftcl_55r635_55_6_serie_4k_hdr.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21591567%2Fblack-friday-tv-deals-sale-cyber-monday#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tK3s30"&gt;Great 4K TVs for watching movies and TV&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="UcvLZF"&gt;If next-gen gaming isn’t in the cards for your new TV (or isn’t a priority), the options open up considerably. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="FqqizP"&gt;Sony A8H OLED 4K TV&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id="SrTxoY"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9733790"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li id="TOjabm"&gt;55-inch: $1,499 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-A8H-55-Inch-Compatibility/dp/B084KQFNBX?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724766755447061028" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="HzHArL"&gt;Samsung 70-inch Class 6 Series 4K TV&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="rC0gMz"&gt;This is one of those cases where if all you care about is a giant TV, it’s easy to score one for hundreds less than more premium models. &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724766794160975714" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;At just $529 from Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, Samsung’s 70-inch 6 Series TV gets you 4K resolution, HDR, and a slew of built-in streaming apps — all for under $600, let alone $1,000. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="UzE5Za"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"These are the best Black Friday streaming deals for Hulu, Spotify, Sling TV, and more","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21603508/black-friday-streaming-deals-tv-movies-subscription-cyber-monday"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h2 id="0eJZl6"&gt;Good 4K TVs on a budget&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="DZtTdb"&gt;Not everyone cares about having the absolute best, top-tier picture quality. Thankfully, TVs have gotten to the point where spending $500 or less can still get you a set with a very enjoyable 4K image. Some models still manage to include expanded HDR color in this price category, even if the difference won’t be as apparent as with more premium TVs that can get much brighter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="5DqUiO"&gt;TCL 4 Series 55-inch 4K TV&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="ISFq9p"&gt;$279.99 at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724767143876093364" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="CNhPQF"&gt;Vizio 50-inch MQ6 series 4K HDR TV&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="X2F2LJ"&gt;$298 at &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FVIZIO-50-Class-4K-UHD-LED-Quantum-Smart-TV-HDR-M6x-Series-M506x-H9%2F910109519&amp;amp;sharedid=verge" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="GiUeu9"&gt;Toshiba 50-inch Fire TV Edition 4K HDR&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="HMOiTt"&gt;$259.99 at &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724766981374235202" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="gbY6dQ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21591567/black-friday-tv-deals-sale-cyber-monday"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21591567/black-friday-tv-deals-sale-cyber-monday</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-11-25T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>A brief chat with xQc</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="xQC" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UsjOgWlBep5l4YRMW8x_RPP2Nq4=/0x0:1422x948/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67980671/xqc.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="DFNo4F"&gt;Last week, the streamer Félix “xQcOW” Lengyel was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/18/21573715/twitch-ban-xqc-felix-lengyel-cheating-twitch-rivals"&gt;temporarily banned from Twitch for cheating at a GlitchCon Twitch Rivals event&lt;/a&gt;. It was the third time this year he’s been suspended from Twitch, and his teammates Rabia “Nightblue3” Yazbek and Lucas “Mendo” Håkansson were banned alongside him. I got in touch with Lengyel to chat about what happened, and what he’s learned from the experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J58IHl"&gt;According to him, the stream sniping incident — when he and his teammates queued into a competitor’s lobby with the intent to derail their game — was a bit of banter that went too far, though Lengyel is careful to note that he’s not trying to justify what happened. “The atmosphere was really like funny, banter-y — we went to their Discord, they went to our Discord, you know, we’re talking shit, whatever,” he says. “And now that I’ve computed it, it’s like, holy, this is just... this is like so stupid.” After the event, Lengyel says he messaged the people involved to apologize. Even so, he says he didn’t think anything would happen on Twitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="pfVkjs"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“If I can be an example of wrongdoing, I can be an example of redemption.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PEb0wJ"&gt;Lengyel’s Twitch partner manager broke the news of his ban. He’s not mad, though; competitive rulings are competitive rulings, and through his career as an esports competitor he understands why these decisions are made. “I don’t want to do wrong stuff. I want to always be better. It’s why I’m rarely upset at competitive rulings and bans and whatnot,” he says. “And I think it’s sort of healthy, for people that have my platform to know for sure that I got punished for something, they know why it happened.” Lengyel’s interested, he says, in modeling growth. That said, he’s not without &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XQc#Controversies"&gt;controversy&lt;/a&gt;. Lengyel’s been temporarily banned from Twitch on multiple occasions for streaming explicit content, and he was previously suspended from esports teams for using disparaging language. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yqUpr2"&gt;“If I can be an example of wrongdoing, I can be an example of redemption,” he says. “And I think that matters, maybe even more.” He also says you shouldn’t stream snipe in games. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K1b0DB"&gt;Lengyel says he wants his audience to know that he’s trying to be better — to move forward. “Even though sometimes we take like, 10 steps back, as long as we create a pattern of gaining steps forward again, and getting through it again, I think that matters a lot.” (The overarching message, though, he says, is: “don’t fuck with competitive integrity.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6x4PUT"&gt;To that end, Lengyel is starting something he’s calling a streamer showcase: a show of some kind that features smaller Twitch creators. It’s an idea that grew out of his &lt;em&gt;Among Us&lt;/em&gt; games with smaller streamers earlier this summer, where he started a Discord server and invited people who replied to a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/xqc/status/1302924666387005442?lang=en"&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt;. “It’s been really crazy to see all these smaller streamers grow, like, out of the blue — and all of them getting partnered and getting sponsorships.” It’s an example, he says, of using his platform for good. He’s a little light on details. Personally, though, I think it’s interesting because to me it seems like he’s starting to grapple with the dynamics of online influence — with what it means to be famous on the internet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PohCs6"&gt;And Lengyel’s organizational partners are behind him as well. He’s part of Luminosity Gaming, a professional esports outfit. “Being partners is more than just celebrating the good times. Felix knows he made a mistake and we’re encouraged to see how seriously he is taking his return,” wrote Corey Mandell, executive vice president of Enthusiast Gaming, Luminosity Gaming’s parent company, in an emailed statement. “We remain committed to supporting his personal journey and help realize his ambitious plans.” Lengyel is set to return to Twitch on Wednesday. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/25/21693008/xqc-twitch-rivals-ban-streamer-showcase-felix-lengyel"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/25/21693008/xqc-twitch-rivals-ban-streamer-showcase-felix-lengyel</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bijan Stephen</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-11-25T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Samsung’s Odyssey G9 does the work of three monitors</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;And I am now thoroughly spoiled&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text" id="uiAqji"&gt;I have been a technology cheapskate most of my life. I’ve rarely bought a monitor brand-new; I’m pleased to say I pieced together &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/StarFire2258/status/1315735960139644929"&gt;my current&lt;/a&gt; three-screen articulating swing-arm setup primarily from Craigslist and hand-me-downs. But this fall, I had an opportunity to temporarily replace my three aging displays with the most ridiculous, most advanced gaming monitor ever made: the super-ultrawide, super-curved, ultra-high resolution 49-inch Samsung Odyssey G9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QaU80a"&gt;The Samsung Odyssey G9 is a monitor so big, so wide, so curved, it can fill a midsized desk and wrap around your entire field of view. It’s also simply a phenomenal screen: speedy (240Hz, 1ms, G-Sync, and FreeSync 2), high resolution (5120 x 1440-pixel), and bursting with brilliant color thanks to a QLED panel that tops out at an eye-searing 1,000 nits of brightness. I’m not kidding when I say I have to avert my eyes when I launch &lt;em&gt;Destiny 2&lt;/em&gt; in HDR, and I could swear I felt the flames the first few times my &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21496153/star-wars-squadrons-review-single-player-campaign-x-wing-tie-fighter-space-simulator-vr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Star Wars: Squadrons&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;’ TIE Bomber blasted an X-Wing into oblivion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3NT24N"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;...to this. &lt;a href="https://t.co/eehPZbxAYz"&gt;pic.twitter.com/eehPZbxAYz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Sean Hollister (@StarFire2258) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/StarFire2258/status/1330787569160785921?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 23, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aA6YCj"&gt;As they say &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ultrawidemasterrace/"&gt;on Reddit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;I have ascended —&lt;/em&gt; and the past few weeks have been a gaming and productivity experience like few I’ve had before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V1vnGj"&gt;But gradually, I’ve been coming back down to Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="VxIYwS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="scorecard:9719395"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="X5jBZx"&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="6KV2CD"&gt;The Odyssey G9 is a showstopper, and I don’t just mean that figuratively: last January, attendees of the world’s biggest technology show were &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/7/21055745/samsung-odyssey-g9-super-ultra-wide-gaming-monitor-ces-2020"&gt;dazzled by its unprecedented curvature and sci-fi inspired frame&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h3MuAv"&gt;When I put that same monitor on my humble IKEA sit-stand desk, the effect is otherworldly. Compared to my old hodgepodge of screens and rat’s nest of cabling, this G9 looks like a terminal aboard a &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt; spaceship... even if my physical keyboard and its long braided cable ruin the illusion a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4IBfBL"&gt;The sheer size of the Odyssey G9 and its broad-shouldered stand do limit your options. I’m lucky that my small-form-factor Ncase M1 can fit behind the screen, and there’s just enough clearance (a little over six inches) for my Audioengine A2+ speakers to fit underneath the monitor at the stand’s highest position. But if I had a bigger PC or bigger speakers, I might have also needed a bigger desk — or else had to use the included 100mm x 100mm VESA adapter to mount the nearly four-feet wide, one-foot deep, 31-pound screen to the wall. My current monitor arms can’t carry nearly that much weight, though you can buy some TV arms that do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xJnN9zHYkfl-KQc900rOKYC4OfE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22026740/shollister_201031_42850027.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I haven’t done a &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.theverge.com/work-from-home-remote-wfh" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;What’s on your desk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; yet, but now you know.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BTZhtO"&gt;As it is, I’m a fan of the way this monitor brings my whole desk together. Two DisplayPorts and an HDMI 2.0 port let me switch between three video sources easily, including a side-by-side mode which lets me display two at once, effectively giving my PC and game console (or a second computer) each their own 24.5-inch, 2560 x 1440 displays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UX55jg"&gt;There’s also a two-port USB-A 3.0 hub and a 3.5mm audio output, which worked perfectly with my keyboard’s USB and 3.5mm audio passthrough. As you can see from my photos, I can do a lot with only a single visible cable thanks to those ports. And while the narrow V-shaped stand might seem a little minimal for a monitor this hefty, it takes a decent shove to get it to tip forward even at its highest position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y1tkBzFGw-zW7vVTvIdSR7Em7Ms=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22067624/20201012_Sean_Hollister_Verge_1.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Underneath the rear cover, cable management at work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tF-7mIuLYWR0Y_FMDFytlQyVXq8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22026736/shollister_201031_42850043.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The five-way nub.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DwoAO52QH_uOGChttOgVh5BjaUM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22026734/shollister_201031_42850044.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cable management and OSD options.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HAKujH"&gt;You can adjust the monitor’s settings using a tiny five-way control nub underneath the power LED, and it’s remarkable how much you can tweak — including the ability to crop the entire panel to 4:3, 16:9, or 21:9 aspect ratios instead of stretching out the image. You can effectively have a 27-inch HDR panel for your game console or TV whenever you need. It’s just a shame that the monitor’s biggest benefits don’t necessarily translate to its side-by-side mode, where your 240Hz HDR screen &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ultrawidemasterrace/comments/huhuvu/samsung_odyssey_g9_why_on_pbp_the_refresh_rate_is/"&gt;generally&lt;/a&gt; becomes a pair of 60Hz SDR ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="YmYPjH"&gt;Productivity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="3xsg0V"&gt;My first big test for Samsung’s Odyssey G9 wasn’t a console or even PC gaming — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/13/21504585/apple-iphone-12-event-live-blog-news-announcements"&gt;last month&lt;/a&gt;, I co-hosted &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s industry-famous Apple event live blog, capturing every screenshot you saw. I normally run three monitors because I switch tasks like mad, and if there’s a better multitasking test than an Apple event, I haven’t met it yet.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a9AMfVkEquDEmR_5o8Fy7lmm54U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22026735/shollister_201031_42850042.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lots of room for productivity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mhGmxn"&gt;At first, I wasn’t sure this epic screen would work. Most apps and websites aren’t designed to display across the vast expanse of a single 32:9 monitor, so you &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to live in windows. I couldn’t simply toss one or two apps onto each monitor like I usually do. But while Samsung doesn’t ship the G9 with any good windowing software and Windows 10’s default Snap is woefully insufficient, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/6/20852451/microsoft-windows-10-powertoys-download-features"&gt;Microsoft’s free downloadable FancyZones windowing manager&lt;/a&gt; worked wonders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vbflgm"&gt;l built my own set of dedicated snappable spots for the Apple live stream; &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s live-blogging tool; Slack; a browser window to keep track of any Apple press releases that might pop during the show; and even a narrow strip of Windows Explorer so I could see which images I’d already captured and weed them out as necessary. The only other wrinkle was the additional Chrome extension I had to download to ensure YouTube could launch “full screen” in a browser window, instead of taking over my entire ultrawide monitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t2cWU2"&gt;In general, while I did occasionally miss my two vertically oriented monitors for scrolling long webpages, Google Docs, and Tweetdeck, I found the G9’s gigantic horizontal expanse of real estate nearly as effective for most tasks. Where I could only squeeze four narrow columns of Tweetdeck onto my old portrait-orientation screens, the G9 would comfortably fit five, plus a 30-tab web browser, a nice vertical strip of Evernote for note-taking, and our Slack newsroom alongside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JKcsjjxhieSaJXND5rtAlcw6pYI=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22026742/shollister_201031_42850021.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The curve is even more noticeable from this angle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="EdyQrs"&gt;I wouldn’t say it’s &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt; than having three screens for work, but it seems like a sufficient substitute — except maybe that toast notifications now pop up in the corner of my eye where they’re pretty easy to miss. Still, it’s nice not to have to match color, contrast, and brightness across three screens at a time, or adjust how my mouse crosses from one monitor to the next. Having a single, vast, unbroken expanse of real estate that’s always the same distance from my face (as I spin in my chair) is an absolute treat. And while the Odyssey G9’s unprecedented curve does tend to catch ambient light, the matte screen does a great job of diffusing any glare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BfjJoG"&gt;The ultrawide aspect ratio didn’t work as well for video as I hoped, though. While you might imagine 32:9 being great for movies, I had a hard time finding anything I could play in ultra high definition that wasn’t 16:9. Most streaming platforms won’t easily let you access their 4K and HDR content on a Windows machine to begin with — YouTube’s the primary exception, though Netflix works if you’ve got a recent Intel processor and use Microsoft Edge or the native app — and you’ll want 4K to take advantage of a screen this high-res and this close to your face. The 4K YouTube videos I played were definitely clearer than 1080p — I could really &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/OCnzH7IiHo0?t=194"&gt;peep these pixels&lt;/a&gt; in Dieter’s iPhone 12 video review. And while standard 16:9, 1080p content does display just fine full-screen with black borders on the sides, it feels like I’m wasting a lot of screen real estate that way. Plus, the blacks are a bit gray, not the deep inky black you’d get from an OLED screen — particularly with HDR on and Samsung’s iffy local dimming enabled. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Gn2AXA"&gt;Gaming&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="FUkeQG"&gt;The first thing you should know about gaming on the Odyssey G9 is that you’ll want a serious graphics card to go with it. Technically, 5120 x 1440 resolution isn’t &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; as many pixels as a 3840 x 2160 4K UHD screen... but remember we’re also talking about a monitor that goes up to 240Hz. To properly review the Odyssey G9, I borrowed an Nvidia GeForce RTX 3080 to get enough horsepower, since my GTX 1080 couldn’t even run games like &lt;em&gt;Death Stranding&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Destiny 2&lt;/em&gt; at 60fps smoothly at that resolution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fVoGsi"&gt;The second thing you should know about gaming on the Odyssey G9 is that it may not be quite as immersive as you’re imagining. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2Lj9FY"&gt;Don’t get me wrong: having an X-Wing cockpit wrapped all around you is an epic experience, and it feels like a true advantage to be able to use my peripheral vision in competitive shooters like &lt;em&gt;PUBG&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;CS:GO. &lt;/em&gt;But it wasn’t long until I noticed something weird going on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZPGruSowwurA01jalQLEeuj4bV8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22067625/32_9_star_wars_squadrons_hangar.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;That TIE Interceptor on the left is looking a little flat.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6ErXjZDycJs1Dp_X9Vlvmf2V5Og=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22067628/Screenshot__25_.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;No, the soldier on the left is not normally that short.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yqj5yp"&gt;Look carefully at these images: notice how the sides are warped? Imperial deck officers and Novigrad Temple Guards aren’t generally this pudgy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="ixdSFL"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Warping is the norm at 32:9&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="iWqITF"&gt;I tried game after game after game on the Odyssey G9, digging into my Steam, Epic, and Uplay libraries and tweaking a variety of settings, and this is simply the reality: every 3D game gets warped when you’re viewing it in a 32:9 aspect ratio, and there’s not much you can do about it. Changing your field of view in a game doesn’t get rid of the effect; it simply changes how much of the game world appears in the center of your screen (where things look normal) and at the edges (where they look stretched and zoomed). I actually pulled out a tape measure and checked: video game content that measures 4.75 inches at the center of the display can get stretched to a full 12 inches at the edges.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FovtAF"&gt;Now, this isn’t Samsung’s fault; &lt;a href="https://mail.google.com/mail/u/0/?shva=1"&gt;it’s just the way games are built&lt;/a&gt;. Most games have a single virtual camera that exists at a single point in space, and while Nvidia once proposed changing that (see link above), the company’s Simultaneous Multi-Projection doesn’t seem to have made it into any of the games I tested. And in games with pre-rendered cutscenes, like &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XV, &lt;/em&gt;you’ll be watching them at their original aspect ratio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6yNUy9"&gt;But before you write off 32:9 ultrawides right now, there are three things I’d like you to consider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="d5VJMe"&gt;You might get used to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="M0lOSV"&gt;It’s not that distracting in some games!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="zU1B9V"&gt;2D games aren’t affected at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="gK9TqI"&gt;Let me give you some examples. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qSpg1H9zWO-1DxxTYz55iv2L3W8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22067630/pubg_32_9.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;PlayerUnknown’s Battlegrounds&lt;em&gt; at 32:9.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hboJ08z2F8N4QZTMDtpX1qNrmKY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22067634/CS_go_32_9.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;CS:GO &lt;em&gt;at 32:9.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7v1xQ9"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CS:GO&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;PUBG&lt;/em&gt; are incredibly competitive, nail-biting games where focus is everything, where you always need to have your gun at the ready and be scanning for any sign of movement. I don’t have time to turn my head left and right to appreciate the scenery or think about whether it’s warped. The G9 simply gives me enhanced peripheral vision, and it helps — not hurts — that things which appear in the corner of my eye are zoomed in by default. I got used to treating it as my peripheral vision and nothing else. (The 240Hz also comes in pretty handy in games like &lt;em&gt;CS:GO&lt;/em&gt; where you can actually hit that frame rate.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/u7w2rpC32STAC3Ml2emfKMFO7Ys=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22067633/GenshinImpact_RKEDElbqFg.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Genshin Impact&lt;em&gt; cutscenes use the in-game engine and look great at 32:9.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_AqNrHSsnhW294k-sVbKOfmcS1A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22067632/bioshock_infinite_32_9.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;BioShock Infinite &lt;em&gt;at 32:9.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="FsXhDq"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Genshin Impact&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; Abzû&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;BioShock Infinite&lt;/em&gt; are games with gorgeous, colorful worlds whose proportions aren’t “normal” to begin with, and I love having them wrapped around me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b6Q52q_jY3Cms1hXxZ9SPhfDs10=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22067635/xcom_2_32_9.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;XCOM 2&lt;em&gt;’s more cinematic movements look pretty good in 32:9 as well.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="m53nyM"&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Destiny 2&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;XCOM 2&lt;/em&gt;, I found I could forgive the warping because of the enhanced field of view and the ability to easily zoom whenever you want. It’s nice to see more of the battlefield at once in &lt;em&gt;XCOM&lt;/em&gt; while planning out how my soldiers will move each turn, and it’s pretty cool to aim down the sights in &lt;em&gt;Destiny&lt;/em&gt; without the typical claustrophobia that comes with zooming in, since you’re still able to see what’s going on around you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5XIeHDfJj4YEtAkoUUzsHhURqNQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22067637/Worms_W.M.D_6ZejzXw2gF.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Worms W.M.D &lt;em&gt;in 32:9.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5hn-VRhn6SHYLYAeuQXCRbsM694=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22067638/disco_elysium_21_9.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Disco Elysium&lt;em&gt; supports 21:9, not 32:9, as you can see here.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="vhW4TV"&gt;2D / 2.5D games like &lt;em&gt;Worms W.M.D&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Disco Elysium&lt;/em&gt; do look fantastic on the G9 — when you can find ones that actually support an ultrawide screen. That’s not a given: I managed to launch &lt;em&gt;Soldat&lt;/em&gt; at 5120 x 1440 resolution, but it didn’t stretch across my monitor. Games with fixed widths like &lt;em&gt;Streets of Rage 4&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Hyper Light Drifter&lt;/em&gt; won’t either. Even &lt;em&gt;Disco Elysium&lt;/em&gt; only offers 21:9 support, not 32:9, unless you apply a hack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JaX9TxbDaxlNKGwjbURErYo6B5A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22067639/Borderlands3_DXlFm6diiE.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Borderlands 3 &lt;em&gt;looked pretty good at 32:9 when it wasn’t moving.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oWPjey"&gt;And for every one of the 3D games that worked, I also found a &lt;em&gt;Borderlands 3&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The Witness&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Goat of Duty&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The Witcher 3&lt;/em&gt; where the warped geometry really bugged me, either because I wanted to sit back and look at the beautiful vista or because the edges of my screen were moving faster than the center. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pMGOXl"&gt;That’s not easy to show you in still images, so here’s a video clip to show you what I mean:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div id="gOOjis"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dsmI_NVmEiE?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; clipboard-write; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="L4AYIU"&gt;In games like the hack-and-slash &lt;em&gt;Mordhau&lt;/em&gt; or the road-tripping &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XV&lt;/em&gt;, the distraction can also be when a piece of geometry that’s critical to the game constantly looks wrong. (Your &lt;em&gt;Mordhau&lt;/em&gt; sword or axe often extends into the warped area of the screen; the road itself in &lt;em&gt;FFXV&lt;/em&gt; looks curved instead of flat!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N2aKBp"&gt;Frankly, the most annoying game I played on the Odyssey G9 was figuring out which games would work in the first place. Here, I have to shout out &lt;em&gt;Rock Paper Shotgun&lt;/em&gt;’s Katharine Castle, &lt;a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2020/11/18/the-35-best-ultrawide-pc-games/"&gt;whose brilliant example-filled guide&lt;/a&gt; showcases nearly three dozen titles that do work, complete with GIFs so you can see for yourself. But if you’re willing to work at it (and understand the risks), a community at the &lt;a href="https://www.wsgf.org/"&gt;Widescreen Gaming Forum&lt;/a&gt; (WSGF) and &lt;a href="https://community.pcgamingwiki.com/files/category/23-wsgf/"&gt;PCGamingWiki&lt;/a&gt; can help you hack and patch many existing titles to work at 32:9, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/v1TAUBlQZQGN7qoPX_LDtjge8Ho=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22067641/death_stranding_32_9.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Death Stranding &lt;em&gt;tweaked to run at 32:9.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="orGcvN"&gt;For instance, I installed a trainer that let me run &lt;em&gt;Death Stranding&lt;/em&gt; at full-resolution 32:9, with an infinitely adjustable field of view, instead of the 21:9 that designer Hideo Kojima and company shipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hRpSzk-EK5H62YQjWOzLY37Qwto=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22067644/persona_4_golden.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Persona 4 Golden &lt;em&gt;at 32:9. I still need to un-stretch the UI.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LU41Yb"&gt;Using &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/widescreengamingforum/comments/h8izt5/persona_4_golden_pillarboxes_in_aspect_ratios/"&gt;a common tutorial&lt;/a&gt;, I hex-edited my &lt;em&gt;Persona 4 Golden&lt;/em&gt; .exe and remarkably wound up playing what was originally a 480p PlayStation 2 game — and later a 720p, 16:9 PlayStation Vita game — at a glorious 3840 x 1080 at 32:9. (I do still need to figure out how to un-stretch the UI.) And there’s an old, unmaintained program called &lt;a href="https://github.com/dlrudie/WidescreenFixer/releases/tag/Original"&gt;Widescreen Fixer&lt;/a&gt; that helped me revisit an old favorite:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="p-fullbleed-block"&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wPuzBE1VoTckteztLecAGym1ihU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22067643/MirrorsEdge_PQpIN3VMLk.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Mirror’s Edge &lt;em&gt;at 32:9.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yn9eXjvrXjDxYJ4gGMP3QYrWh2M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22067642/MirrorsEdge_TgcxYDob1j.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;More&lt;/em&gt; Mirror’s Edge.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="33Rugb"&gt;I wouldn’t say the community is robust enough that you could necessarily find a fix for any game in your library. But the WSGF &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fgoo.gl%2FmJbzkf&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21590961%2Fsamsung-odyssey-g9-review-ultrawide-monitor-price-specs#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;does now have a Discord&lt;/a&gt; you might want to check out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="fAk76B"&gt;The ultimate ultrawide, but the best monitor?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="5kDNR1"&gt;The Samsung Odyssey G9 costs $1,479.99 — a premium price for a premium monitor like nothing else on the market. You can find other 49-inch 32:9 panels for less, but none with this combination of resolution, brightness, curvature, and refresh rate. The closest you can come is last year’s $1,200 Samsung CRG9 which maintains the resolution and brightness but with half the refresh rate at 120Hz and a notably less pronounced 1800R curvature — which, I imagine, wouldn’t be as good at giving you convincing peripheral vision in games. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;div id="tVH16M"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="aside:9625148"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="cMBgUY"&gt;If you’re looking for the ultimate ultrawide, this is currently it. I’m just not convinced that I am, personally, even if I had that much money earmarked for a new screen. For $1,500 and the enormous amount of space the Odyssey G9 consumes, I could buy a 48-inch LG OLED TV instead. I’d get a screen just as gigantic for my multitasking, but taller, with 120Hz G-Sync and FreeSync support, incredibly deep blacks, HDMI 2.1 for variable refresh rate for the PS5 and Xbox Series X, and no need to troubleshoot aspect ratios for my videos and games. &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/x9n8Hz_RLqw"&gt;Linus Tech Tips has a video&lt;/a&gt; that dives deep into the pros and cons of that LG screen, and I came away fairly convinced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="LaCuDM"&gt;It wouldn’t be the same experience that the G9 offers, of course, and I might regret it if Nvidia and AMD ever dust off Simultaneous Multi-Projection for real. The TV might also cut off access to a large portion of my desk, and I might not be able to place my PC and speakers within easy reach without blocking a bit of the screen. But I’d have a more obviously future-proof setup; an equally, if not more gorgeous image; and a lot less ambient annoyance when I want to game. At the very least, here’s hoping Samsung adds HDMI 2.1 to this epic monitor next year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JWybHN"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photography and screenshots by Sean Hollister / The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21590961/samsung-odyssey-g9-review-ultrawide-monitor-price-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21590961/samsung-odyssey-g9-review-ultrawide-monitor-price-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Hollister</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-11-25T09:36:54-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T09:36:54-05:00</updated>
    <title>The best Black Friday deals on wireless earbuds</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Fl4nn1t-Hv3mPEA7oZ6ADHkyLFc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/67870514/cwelch_191031_3763_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The AirPods Pro are discounted at several retailers this season.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UhitJa"&gt;During &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/good-deals/21569412/black-friday-best-early-deals-sales-tech-gadgets"&gt;Black Friday and Cyber Monday&lt;/a&gt; this year, you can expect to find many of the best wireless earbuds on sale for their lowest prices yet. Apple’s AirPods Pro, Samsung’s Galaxy Buds Plus, and other popular models from Jabra, Sony, 1More, and more companies have never been more affordable. If you haven’t yet treated yourself to a set of truly wireless earbuds that connect via Bluetooth, prepare to never look back to using wired earbuds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MAI1eM"&gt;We have collected deals across multiple retailers below, and they’re all significantly lower than their usual asking price. As new deals become available or go out of stock, we’ll update this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="oQibUb"&gt;Apple AirPod deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="wgCXgH"&gt;Apple’s AirPods Pro, pictured above, are the star of Black Friday — and the best deal we’ve seen yet &lt;a href="http://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FApple-AirPods-Pro%2F520468661%3Firgwc%3D1%26sourceid%3Dimp_ywp0i3SwExyOT35wUx0Mo38vUkExdm3-WQ-N3A0%26veh%3Daff%26wmlspartner%3Dimp_482924%26clickid%3Dywp0i3SwExyOT35wUx0Mo38vUkExdm3-WQ-N3A0%26sharedid%3Dverge&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;will be launching online through Walmart&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday, November 25th, at 7PM ET / 4PM PT. Their asking price is $250, though they’ve regularly sold for around $200. Walmart’s deal sees the price plummet to $169, though we expect it to sell out extremely fast. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zd8vKE"&gt;If you’d rather not deal with the hysteria or if you don’t want to shop from Walmart, &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8836598/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://electronics.woot.com/offers/apple-airpods-pro-18?utm_medium=affiliate&amp;amp;utm_campaign=CJ&amp;amp;cjevent=bf1dd84529dc11eb814400030a24060c&amp;amp;utm_source=Vox+Media" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Woot has the AirPods Pro selling at $190&lt;/a&gt;. This was nearly the best before word got around about the Walmart deal. But once that inevitably sells out, you should be able to find stock available at Woot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3CAOpg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9513673" data-anthem-component-data='{"layout":"full_with_square_img"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QVXoTR"&gt;For a simpler, less expensive set of AirPods that lack the Pro’s active noise cancellation and snug fit, the standard model is down to $119 (normally $159) at Amazon, Best Buy, and other retailers. It includes a wired charging case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xJreM1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9502973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pTlrhv"&gt;If you want AirPods that include a case that charges wirelessly via a wireless charger, that model is $150 now (usually $199) at several retailers like Best Buy, Walmart, and Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="HRZzTq"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9507432"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Vf4Sih"&gt;Apple itself isn’t honoring the big discounts on AirPods this holiday, but it will give you a $25 gift card and the option for free engraving &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.apple.com%2Fmusic%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F21611428%2Fblack-friday-earbuds-deals-wireless-cyber-monday#donotlink" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;if you buy some through its online store&lt;/a&gt; between November 27th and November 30th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="2uJAIZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best Black Friday deals on Apple devices","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21583192/apple-deals-black-friday-tech-cyber-monday"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="pPjtU5"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="jsElvD"&gt;Samsung Galaxy Bud deals&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A photo of Samsung’s Galaxy Buds Live in someone’s ear." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bY3-AtgWgYwPxOs3OMRpHfd8MDg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/21699402/cwelch_200804_4129_0007.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Galaxy Buds Live are $140 at several retailers, but the best deal is at Best Buy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="lf48yH"&gt;At Best Buy, you can save on either the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724117005601449431" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung Galaxy Buds Plus&lt;/a&gt; ($110, usually $150) or the &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724676918321004525" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;bean-shaped Galaxy Buds Live&lt;/a&gt; ($140, usually $170). These prices aren’t anything &lt;em&gt;too &lt;/em&gt;special at this point, but these get a nod &lt;a href="https://shop-links.co/1724676948121680191" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;for including a $20 Best Buy gift card with either set of earphones&lt;/a&gt;. The only catch is that you need to buy your earbuds in the Best Buy-exclusive blue colorway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="wh14e2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9581901"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="8oyIZz"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="lRsLhO"&gt;Jabra deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="4xWXx9"&gt;Jabra is offering a great deal on its previous-generation Elite 65t wireless earbuds. Normally around $100 (though, they’re commonly available for less), you can pick up a set at Best Buy or Amazon for $70.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="hd8ah5"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9625428"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="sWSTjV"&gt;If you want features like noise cancellation, better sound quality, and a charging case that supports USB-C (unlike the Elite 65t’s Micro USB case), check out the Jabra Elite 75t, their successor. Normally $180, they’re down to $140.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cmro1D"&gt;Best Buy says it will discount the Elite 75t further by $10 on Thursday, November 26th, so your final cost then will be $130 before tax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="KFWm4o"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9625438"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="YzBzXa"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The best Black Friday laptop deals","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21591398/black-friday-laptop-deals-sale-cyber-monday"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="JDcp8N"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="KugMUD"&gt;Other earbud deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="phoZtF"&gt;1More’s ColorBuds are down to $80 from $100 at the company’s site and Amazon for Black Friday. For the money, these offer some colorful style and crisp sound quality. They deliver up to six hour of listening per charge, with up to 22 hours provided by the charging case. To get the $80 price at Amazon, you’ll need to clip the coupon on the product page to knock $20 off the cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bFcsGl"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9591243"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="E6ZcFW"&gt;The Sony WF-XB700 wireless earbuds usually cost $130, but they’re down to $68 at a few retailers, including Amazon, Best Buy, and more. These are a solid pick if you’re looking for a snug fit and better sound quality than you might expect for this price range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bzHUz4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9591267"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Iv45ou"&gt;Anker’s Soundcore Liberty Air 2 normally cost $100, but they’re $70 right now at Amazon and Best Buy. In our roundup of the best budget-friendly wireless earbuds, my colleague Chris Welch said these have better microphones for voice calls than any other model he tested in this price range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="q15sZo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9591175"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Pr9QWi"&gt;The OnePlus Buds wireless earbuds cost $59 through the OnePlus site and from Amazon and B&amp;amp;H Photo. They usually cost $79. The OnePlus Buds Z usually get our recommendation since they are just $50, but for this deal, the standard Buds have larger drivers and a slightly more fashionable carrying case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="PAcLCz"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9540296"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="r4nzHC"&gt;Amazon’s debut wireless earbuds, the Echo Buds, are back down to their lowest price at Amazon. Normally $130, you can snag a set for $80. For this price, they’re a good value since they feature Bose noise reduction technology and can &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/23/21593991/amazon-alexa-echo-buds-workouts-fitness-tracking-wireless-headphones"&gt;now track your workouts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="bS5miI"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:9625473"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;aside id="tMFYCi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/21611428/black-friday-earbuds-deals-wireless-cyber-monday"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/21611428/black-friday-earbuds-deals-wireless-cyber-monday</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Faulkner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
