<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  Front Pages</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2021-08-18T17:59:53-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/front-page/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-18T17:59:53-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-18T17:59:53-04:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft’s new Paint app redesign for Windows 11 includes a dark mode</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2T0M9LKgcUDV80vrOyvL70w8Oss=/200x0:2360x1440/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69744803/Xsgxcy2.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new Paint design in Windows 11.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="SKAG8c"&gt;Microsoft is redesigning its Paint app in Windows 11. The app will be updated with a new command bar that borrows most of the same options and tools as what exists in the ribbon interface for Paint on Windows 10. It’s the first major update to Paint in years, and it even includes a dark mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mbhxsL"&gt;Microsoft’s head of Windows and devices, Panos Panay, teased the new Paint redesign on Twitter today. The teaser video includes a brief look at improvements to the font picker, brushes, and a dark mode for Paint. The tools look a lot more usable now, with a quick picker that shows all the different brushes and their effects. Microsoft’s font tool for Paint also floats now, with options for size, alignment, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Hurlim"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Here’s another &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Windows?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Windows&lt;/a&gt; 11 first look. This is the beautifully redesigned Paint app, coming soon to Windows Insiders. Can’t wait to see your creations! &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Windows11?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Windows11&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WindowsInsiders?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#WindowsInsiders&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/jiKyfqQFUV"&gt;pic.twitter.com/jiKyfqQFUV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Panos Panay (@panos_panay) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/panos_panay/status/1428102755151847431?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;August 18, 2021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="tPGX7w"&gt;There doesn’t appear to be options for layers, but this is the first major update to Paint since it gained the ribbon interface. Microsoft had been planning to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/7/25/16024356/microsoft-paint-windows-store-app"&gt;remove Paint&lt;/a&gt; from Windows 10 at one point, before &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/23/18512247/microsoft-paint-windows-10-app-comments"&gt;reversing course and keeping it as part of Windows&lt;/a&gt;. Instead, Microsoft has started removing 3D Paint from installations of Windows 10, a program that was designed to modernize and even replace the traditional Paint app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b57he7"&gt;It’s not clear exactly when Windows Insiders will be able to test out this new Paint design, but Panay says it will be available to test “soon.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22631442/microsoft-windows-11-paint-redesign-update-app"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22631442/microsoft-windows-11-paint-redesign-update-app</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-18T17:51:43-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-18T17:51:43-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook’s delayed 2022 office return did not apply to these contractors</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The word facebook in white against a blue background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qMvIB01r7Mc7Dm08KGLzsyOVkZ4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69744783/acastro_180522_facebook_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GW5bQR"&gt;Facebook announced plans to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/12/22622282/facebook-office-return-delayed-2022-us"&gt;delay employees’ return to the office until 2022&lt;/a&gt; earlier in August, &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/08/18/facebook-makes-some-contractors-come-into-offices-amid-delta-variant-spread.html?&amp;amp;amp;qsearchterm=facebook"&gt;but &lt;em&gt;CNBC&lt;/em&gt; writes&lt;/a&gt; that some Facebook contractors employed by Accenture have been working in person since a week before. This might not be a surprise as &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/10/1/21497789/facebook-content-moderators-accenture-return-office-coronavirus"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; previously reported&lt;/a&gt; that some of Accenture’s contractors in Texas were instructed to return to office work as early as October 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1WvzyN"&gt;A Facebook spokesperson tells &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; that the 2022 return to office plan applies to a majority of all full-time and contingent office employees in the US, regardless of if they’re employed by Facebook or a contracting firm: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="9R12bn"&gt;“While the majority of full-time employees and contingent workers for Facebook continue working from home, some have returned to offices that have reopened at reduced capacities with strict health and safety standards in place. A person’s status as a full-time employee or a contingent worker does not factor into whether or not they can work from home due to the global pandemic.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="VY73o1"&gt;What seems to determine whether an employee is able to keep working remotely is their role and responsibilities. In the case of the workers &lt;em&gt;CNBC &lt;/em&gt;spoke to, that included contractors generating data for Facebook’s machine learning model. These contractors were given two weeks to prepare for their return to the office on August 1st and were only allowed to continue working remotely if they could get a doctor’s note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="VPUNuZ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Facebook says some jobs are more successful in person&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ViQS22"&gt;For contractors working in moderation, the main concern from Facebook and other platforms is that sensitive user content — including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/25/18229714/cognizant-facebook-content-moderator-interviews-trauma-working-conditions-arizona"&gt;frequently traumatic imagery&lt;/a&gt; — can only be viewed on secured company machines to avoid privacy issues. Working on machine learning might not as easily fit that same logic, especially since &lt;em&gt;CNBC &lt;/em&gt;reports the contractors it spoke to have been working remotely for over a year, but security issues may have also been a concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bLCs7i"&gt;When asked, Facebook was not able to share how many contractors are now working in-person. Both Facebook and Accenture claim they enforce strict COVID-19 protocols for employees in offices. Facebook mandates all employees to wear masks and in some cases &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22598818/facebook-vaccine-requirement-us-office-employees"&gt;requires office employees to get vaccinated&lt;/a&gt; “depend[ing] on local conditions and regulations.” Those are both helpful in keeping employees safe, but still leaves some risk of workers passing along an infection to a more vulnerable family member, like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22598818/facebook-vaccine-requirement-us-office-employees"&gt;children not yet allowed to get vaccinated&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="poE1Er"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SFOoJp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PsEh6z"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22631150/facebook-contractors-accenture-return-to-offices"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22631150/facebook-contractors-accenture-return-to-offices</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-18T17:20:15-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-18T17:20:15-04:00</updated>
    <title>Asus’ special edition Zephyrus G14 comes with its own DJ deck</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Asus ROG Zephyrus G14 Alan Walker Edition keyboard seen from above angled to the left." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r9K39qB4ndmZNzeimFKfeddqhow=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69741204/bfarsace_210817_4714_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can you spot the Alan Walker logo?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="r2faU2"&gt;If there’s one company I trust to do a good job with utterly ridiculous computer ideas, it’s Asus. Last fall, the company worked with cyberpunky fashion designer Acronym to make possibly the weirdest-looking gaming laptop I’ve ever seen (the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/18/21432977/asus-rog-zephyrus-g14-acronym-amd-ryzen-9-4900hs-nvidia-rtx-2060"&gt;ZPHYRS G14 ACRNM&lt;/a&gt;). This year, it’s partnered with popular DJ Alan Walker to create a less avant-garde, more musical version of the same device. This is the Zephyrus G14 Alan Walker Edition, a laptop for gamers, DJs, and (ideally) gamer DJs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gIVvhZ"&gt;The insides of this laptop are nothing ROG fans haven’t seen before. There’s only one configuration, selling for $1,999.99, which includes an AMD Ryzen 5900HS processor and a low-end GeForce RTX 3050 Ti graphics card, as well as a QHD 120Hz screen, 16GB of RAM, and 1TB of storage. So, just to be clear, this isn’t really a sensible purchase unless you’re an Alan Walker superfan, because &lt;a href="https://store.asus.com/us/item/202103AM300000011/A50184-ROG-Zephyrus-G14-AniMe-Matrix-Ultra-Slim-Gaming-Laptop%2C-14%E2%80%9D-120Hz-PANTONE-Validated-QHD-Display%2C-GeForce-RTX-3060%2C-AMD-Ryzen-9-5900HS%2C-32GB-DDR4%2C-1TB-SSD%2C-Wi-Fi-6%2C-Windows-10-Pro%2C-GA401QM-XS98Q-WH"&gt;that same price&lt;/a&gt; can get you a non-Walker G14 with a more powerful RTX 3060 GPU, as well as 32GB of RAM. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Asus ROG Zephyrus G14 Alan Walker Edition on a couch seen from the front, open. The screen displays Alan Walker hovering on a red and blue background, conjuring lights of each color with his hands. To its left is its box, with 11 DJ buttons and ROG X ALAN WALKER printed on the bottom." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/c3_PYRkWK0ugBoz-mngQOTxcW0Y=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22788137/bfarsace_210817_4714_0010.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yep, those buttons actually work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="dx3nzO"&gt;Still, it’s a pretty cool device. The lid is laced with a reflective belt commanding passersby to “JOIN THE REPUBLIC” and “JOIN THE WALKERS.” Alan Walker’s logo — resembling an A superimposed over a W — is printed in various places, including the A and W keys as well as on the nameplate. There’s a diagonal line print on the touchpad meant to resemble music equalizer patterns, and there are splashes of bright blue — Walker’s favorite color — across the keyboard as well. It’s not an obnoxious aesthetic, like these special editions sometimes have — it looks more like a standard G14 with some colorful tweaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mlXfGf"&gt;Walker says the design reflects the look he’d want his personal device to have. “They approached me and asked, what are your expectations for the laptop, what do you look for in a laptop if you were to pick one yourself?” he told &lt;em&gt;The Verge &lt;/em&gt;in an interview. “It was a lot of back and forth — like, a lot.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Asus ROG Zephyrus G14 Alan Walker Edition on a couch, facing away from the camera, half open." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2iW5dnLAmRyPm_0JkAphCBV-FWc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22788134/bfarsace_210817_4714_0003.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;JOIN THE REPUBLIC. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Asus ROG Zephyrus G14 Alan Walker Edition on a couch seen from the front, open. The screen displays Alan Walker hovering on a red and blue background, conjuring lights of each color with his hands." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pybxRhdumQhEIof99XaMe6oL09A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22788138/bfarsace_210817_4714_0012.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;JOIN THE WALKERS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OJjKIG"&gt;The other cool thing is that the packaging this G14 comes in becomes a DJ deck when connected to the laptop via USB-C. It’s not the most high-tech affair — if you lift up the paper floor, you’ll see a nest of wires taped to the bottom of the box. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h6FmJn"&gt;“That’s one of those crazy ideas where we ended up debating, would this be possible?” Walker said of the DJ box. “Asus is like ‘Yeah, cool, we can maybe think about something, figure something out,’ and then they came back with a box.” He added, “It’s so weird how it even works.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CUYwYy"&gt;I expected this to be complicated to set up for a non-DJ like myself, but it was a breeze. Plug the box into the G14, and a preloaded software called ROG Remix opens automatically. You can play a song within that program, and then tweak it by pressing various buttons on the box. There are buttons for things like speed, start / stop, and a few basic effects. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The left palm rest of the Asus ROG Zephyrus G14 Alan Walker Edition seen from above." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OSZEWOkdWXPjCDZDmClvmddk7hE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22788135/bfarsace_210817_4714_0004.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Same old chips, though.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The right side of the Asus ROG Zephyrus G14 Alan Walker Edition." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DacaWjLE2f5r-JK31Tiw0YSKMCY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22788136/bfarsace_210817_4714_0007.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Same old ports as well.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GUvJmF"&gt;This was — caveating, again, that I’m not a DJ — a lot of fun. The buttons all worked, and the effects sounded very cool to my untrained ears. It seems like something you could easily use at a party, especially since the G14’s speakers are fantastic. The music was crackling a bit at the beginning, but that seemed to sort itself out after a few tracks. Mostly, I’m impressed that this is all coming out of a plastic box. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ie7b9y"&gt;Walker agrees that his G14 is a better purchase for people like me than it would be for actual DJs. “It’s not necessarily the number-one gadget to get if you want to start with DJing, but it’s definitely a cool starting point,” says Walker. “I hope that people will use it to be creative and play around with music.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pljb8X"&gt;He does, however, expect that he’ll use the G14 on his next tour. “It’s got everything that I need, basically, to work and prepare for my shows,” Walker says. “I can easily foresee myself using it every day.” He says he might use it to plan his set lists prior to performances, and to work on the visuals as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h1hqpo"&gt;He might also use it for some gaming in his spare time. “Lately I’ve been playing &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt;,” he says. “Also some &lt;em&gt;Valorant&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lMlzZJ"&gt;The ROG Zephyrus G14 Alan Walker Edition is available for preorder now on &lt;a href="https://store.asus.com/us/item/202108AM130000001/A47070-ASUS-ROG-Zephyrus-G14-Alan-Walker-Special-Edition-Gaming-Laptop%2C-14%E2%80%9D-120Hz-PANTONE-Validated-WQHD-Display%2C-GeForce-RTX-3050-Ti%2C-AMD-Ryzen-9-5900HS%2C-16GB-DDR4%2C-1TB-SSD%2C-Wi-Fi-6%2C-GA401QEC-K2064T"&gt;Asus’s website &lt;/a&gt;for $1,999.99, and will be available soon at &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.ssense.com/en-us" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;SSENSE&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Asus ROG Zephyrus G14 Alan Walker Edition on a couch, seen from the front, angled to the right." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/O12jEu74BpMGMc1l5vW7K2giIpM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22788131/bfarsace_210817_4714_0001.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="iVyquW"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, 5:20PM ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Article updated to include purchase links.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VeHAH7"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/22629096/asus-rog-zephyrus-g14-alan-walker-edition-dj-deck-gaming-laptop"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/22629096/asus-rog-zephyrus-g14-alan-walker-edition-dj-deck-gaming-laptop</id>
    <author>
      <name>Monica Chin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-18T17:01:06-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-18T17:01:06-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Overwatch League’s 2021 regular season was full of drama amid an uncertain future</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gKdLCIUJfY5JcAnTz-UBgfcU7XM=/0x0:1920x1280/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69744418/owl1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Blizzard&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;With one more tournament and the playoffs to go, here’s an overview of the league’s fourth season&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="MsIbSm"&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League wrapped up its fourth regular season last weekend amid ongoing uncertainty of the league’s future. The pandemic knee-capped the league’s pivot to live, in-person events, and the employee discrimination lawsuit filed against its parent company Activision Blizzard has seen nearly all of the OWL’s sponsors revoke or pause advertising. Now reports are circulating that the league may take an extended break once the playoffs conclude in September in order to ensure the start of the new season coincides with the release of the long-in-development&lt;em&gt; Overwatch 2&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5UtIat"&gt;But before we can contemplate what’s to come for the &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League, let’s take a look at how this fourth regular season unfolded.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Overwatch" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_pFj58rrqZYdO5vb0YfLj52k8ww=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/2438706/Screen_Shot_2014-11-07_at_2.35.08_PM.0.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo: Blizzard&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="IrpVl4"&gt;The good&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="F48ZKz"&gt;In season four, teams participated in four alliteratively named tournaments (May Melee, June Joust, Summer Showdown, and Countdown Cup) consisting of three weeks of qualifying matches, a knockout round, and a final, double elimination bracket. The top two teams in each region competed in a final tournament in which the participants received cash prizes and league points that will be used to determine seeding during the playoffs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xR0azM"&gt;The tournaments were a welcome continuation from the previous year. Instead of regular season games existing as little more than filler for the higher stakes of the playoffs, the tournaments were a way to keep regular season play fresh and exciting. The introduction of league points created an additional level of competition complexity and produced some amusing shake-ups in the rankings. The Chengdu Hunters — the team in the Asia Division notorious for their unorthodox (and at times inconsistent) play style — rank higher than the defending champions San Francisco Shock despite having a slightly worse record. The Hunters have made appearances in two of the four tournaments earning them extra points, while San Francisco — the one-time gods of the league — never managed to escape the knockout rounds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ALKFTL"&gt;After dominating for two years straight, the Shock’s slight decline opened up opportunities for new teams to fill the space they left behind — namely the Dallas Fuel and my Shanghai Dragons. The Dragons had another amazing season earning two tournament wins, the top spot in the standings, and an automatic pass into the playoffs. Shanghai came so close to winning the 2020 season and this year they still look to be in top form. While there’s a chance for the Dragons to repeat their mistakes from 2020 (shout out to the Seoul Dynasty who stopped the Dragons from appearing in the Grand Finals last year) the only team their equal this year is the Dallas Fuel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rNihbJ"&gt;If the &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League were a scripted series, the Dallas Fuel would be the gifted kid who struggled a lot before finally coming into their own power. Some inspired roster additions and excellent coaching turned the Dallas Fuel from a team that, in three years, never obtained a positive win record to the easy favorite to win it all. For my money, the team’s main tank, Eui-Seok “Fearless” Lee, or their star damage player, Yeong-han “SP9RK1E” Kim, should be the top choices for league MVP. At the very least, Fearless should be a prime candidate for the Dennis Hawelka award (think OWL’s MWP or Most Wholesome Player) after &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/korean-overwatch-league-player-shares-his-experience-wi-1846655749"&gt;speaking out earlier this year&lt;/a&gt; about the discrimination he faced as a Korean living in America in the midsts of its pandemic-borne &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22359080/anti-asian-racism-attacks-surveillance-policing"&gt;anti-Asian hate wave&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9RftYz-O1l-eprXUGjwkrxpCSKg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22790656/owl23.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Blizzard&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Overwatch League teams in Asia were allowed to host homestands this year due to relaxed pandemic restrictions in Asia.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="WrNDwG"&gt;The bad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="jglRGf"&gt;Dallas and Shanghai are the two teams at the top of the standings. But if there is a top, there must also be a bottom. During the inaugural season, the 12 teams played 40 regular season games and, against all odds, the Shanghai Dragons lost all 40 of them. For three years, they were the only team to ever have a winless season. And though they’ve more than redeemed themselves with tournament wins, playoff runs, an MVP, and a very good chance to win this year — the ignominy of being the only team with a winless season stuck to them like gum at the bottom of a Balenciaga sneaker (a favorite among OWL’s hypebeast players). Now the gum has passed on to a new team, sticking to the bottom of their shoes or, rather, their wings. This year, the Los Angeles Valiant became the second team to have a winless season, losing all 16 of their regular season games. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T6fuP6"&gt;The Valiant were a good team. In three years, they accumulated a decent record, a tournament win, two Dennis Hawekla award winners, and the dedication of a lot of fans. However, the Valiant’s owners, Immortals Gaming Club, decided, with the league’s approval, that the team would relocate from the North American division to the Asian division — moving the team from Los Angeles to China. Management was unable to secure Chinese visas for the team’s North American and Korean players and therefore had to release &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/video-games/esports/2021/01/29/overwatch-valiant-china-league/"&gt;the entire roster and coaching staff&lt;/a&gt;, replacing them with all-new Chinese talent. Fortunately, most of the released players did find new teams, but fans considered the Valiant’s winless 2021 season “karma” for the management’s decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mOeqvb"&gt;The Valiant almost had company in the winless club. The London Spitfire and the Vancouver Titans ended their seasons at a single win apiece. It’s sad when former greats have crappy seasons. The London Spitfire won the inaugural season — an honor that should have gone to the New York Excelsior, the winningest team that year. And there was a time when the Vancouver Titans were the only team that could stand up to the league’s big, bad villains, the Shock. But roster changes and the stresses of the pandemic made it such that these teams barely managed to eke out a solitary win. If the script writers for 2022 are kind (if there even is a league in 2022), my fondest hope is for these teams to have the same kind of glow-up my Dragons had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sCAPxP"&gt;The ugly&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="Lkrpo8"&gt;The success of the &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League is ultimately tied to the success of its parent company Activision Blizzard King and this year, success for ABK was difficult to come by. In March, a month before opening day, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22334569/activision-blizzard-layoffs-esports-overwatch-call-of-duty-league-covid-pandemic"&gt;Activision Blizzard announced layoffs&lt;/a&gt; that affected its esports division that runs both the OWL and the &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt; League. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ANxKT6"&gt;In April, Seoul Dynasty damage player and one of the most beloved figures in the league, &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/chinese-overwatch-teams-threaten-boycott-of-korean-play-1846828529"&gt;came under fire&lt;/a&gt; for statements he made during a personal Twitch stream. Jong-ryeol “Saebyeolbe” Park expressed the frustration he felt as a Korean player trying to appeal to a Chinese audience. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TgU0uPzJ08EDxXbfcecKH-1dFPw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22790671/sbb.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Blizzard / Robert Paul&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jong-ryeol “Saebyeolbe” Park from his time on the New York Excelsior.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="zcml1U"&gt;“I can’t say Taiwan and [Hong Kong]. At all. They [China] don’t recognize them as countries. I got into so much trouble for saying their names,” Park said in an English translation of his Korean stream. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z8mPeN"&gt;“Make it make sense,” Park continued. “What are you talking about, ‘One China?’ So I objected to that and all the managers said, ‘If you want to earn Chinese money, you have to become a Chinese dog. So that’s what I’m doing right now. I can even say, ‘Thanks for subscribing’ in Chinese. Aren’t I good at Chinese?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xhLwK4"&gt;Park’s seeming denial of China’s “One China” policy that does not recognize Taiwan and Hong Kong as their own independent entities but as a member of the Chinese state, and the notion that Park was pandering to Chinese fans, drew the ire of the league’s Chinese fans and teams. Each of the four teams based in China — three of which are nearly entirely composed of Korean players — issued statements on Chinese social media condemning Park’s words while also saying they would boycott any scrimmages or matches should he appear. Park later apologized and the Chinese teams issued statements saying they would “resume normal activities.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XoHnep"&gt;The incident is yet another example of Blizzard running afoul of Chinese nationalist sensibilities. In 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/31/20940711/blizzard-hong-kong-controversy-gaming-protest-news-updates"&gt;Blizzard banned and later reinstated a &lt;em&gt;Hearthstone&lt;/em&gt; player&lt;/a&gt; after he expressed pro-Hong Kong views during a post-game interview. Though Park’s comments were made before the start of the season, he has not streamed nor has he appeared in a match since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gkmynv"&gt;In July, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/28/22597113/activision-blizzard-california-sexual-harassment-lawsuit-discrimination-employee-action"&gt;the state of California sued Activision Blizzard&lt;/a&gt; for sexual harassment and discrimination taking place at the &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; developer. Almost immediately after that announcement, league advertisers began to &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/video-games/2021/08/05/activision-blizzard-sponsors-overwatch/"&gt;withdraw or pause their sponsorships&lt;/a&gt;. In a broadcast that was dominated by commercials for IBM, T-Mobile, Cheez-Its, and Coca-Cola, only TeamSpeak remains. The league has never been candid about its finances. Team owners paid between $20 to $60 million dollars for a franchise slot and while individual teams can and have secured their own sponsorship deals, no one knows exactly how much revenue teams and the league generate. Homestands were supposed to provide regular income via ticket sales, but ever since the pandemic shut down live events, that avenue of income has been lost. Combine the loss of homestands with layoffs and the loss of key sponsors, and the league’s finances don’t look the healthiest.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wcPMK4hUzNAbkBW69HD1YHVHu7U=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22790641/ow2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Blizzard&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="cYlMvG"&gt;The future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="FQmAdP"&gt;Departing staff and a rocky development cycle on &lt;em&gt;Overwatch 2&lt;/em&gt; has cast uncertainty on OWL’s future. In April, Jeff Kaplan, &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt;’s creative director affectionately known to the league as “Papa Jeff,” &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/20/22394116/overwatch-director-jeff-kaplan-activision-blizzard-departure"&gt;left Blizzard&lt;/a&gt; with Aaron Keller taking over his role overseeing &lt;em&gt;Overwatch 2&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wW9rZ2"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://www.ggrecon.com/articles/report-overwatch-league-to-go-on-potential-year-long-hiatus-before-season-5-updated/"&gt;report from esports site &lt;em&gt;GGRecon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; also claimed that the League might implement an extended off-season. Jon Spector, &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League vice president, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Spex_J/status/1425489232911552518?s=20"&gt;refuted that claim&lt;/a&gt; saying in a tweet, “We have not set nor communicated dates about our 2022 season yet, but do not plan to take a ‘year-long hiatus’ in any scenario we are considering currently.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QtZI2S"&gt;This alleged prolonged off-season would purportedly push Opening Day 2022 from the first half of the year into the later half in order to fall near the release of &lt;em&gt;Overwatch 2&lt;/em&gt; — a game that still doesn’t have a release date three years after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/1/20943766/blizzard-overwatch-2-sequel-announcement-blizzcon-2019"&gt;its debut at Blizzcon 2019&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nx55Kb"&gt;Pinning the start of a season on the release of a new game is a little unorthodox in esports. The most popular esports on the planet — &lt;em&gt;Dota 2&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;CS:GO&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;PUBG&lt;/em&gt; — implement necessary changes via regular content and balance patches which don’t typically disrupt a season. The exceptions to this rule — &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt; and the various sports games like &lt;em&gt;FIFA&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Madden&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;NBA 2K&lt;/em&gt; — have yearly release cycles you could set your watch by, making season planning simple. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LQIx6l"&gt;We do know a little about how the new game will impact competitive play. The developers stated that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/20/22446374/overwatch-2-preview-five-player-multiplayer-new-maps-changes"&gt;team sizes will shrink from six to five and showcased the new competitive mode Push&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; team also teased new maps, new hero looks, and the anxiously awaited heroine, Sojourn — &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt;’s first Black female hero. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mkNPYzfMk5ui8yldyIsekFhhmh0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22790644/owl2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Blizzard&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id="KYT2Vz"&gt;Now what?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="VHYXym"&gt;The fourth season of the &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League isn’t yet over. This weekend concludes the last of the four tournaments, and I’m excited that neither the Dallas Fuel nor the Shanghai Dragons will participate. What I love about this year the most is its parity. The San Francisco Shock dominated seasons two and three. They won everything easily and made the seasons kinda boring. (Yes, Shanghai did, too. I’m biased, sue me.) This year, instead of the narrative being dominated by a scant handful of teams at the top, lots of different teams across both divisions had their chance to shine. Houston, Chengdu, Dallas, Atlanta, and the Los Angeles Gladiators all had moments of sheer brilliance combined with smaller but no less brilliant moments from weaker teams like Vancouver, Toronto, and London. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sW0jEA"&gt;For the first time in two years, I’m confident the playoffs won’t be attended by kings of the Bay. Instead, my hope springs eternal that the Dragons, &lt;em&gt;my &lt;/em&gt;Dragons, will finally play in a Grand Finals match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ymdJ8P"&gt;Every year a rivalry between two teams dominates the &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; League’s “storyline” and this year’s rivalry is between Shanghai and Dallas. They are the top teams in their respective divisions and met twice in tournament finals with each team claiming a victory over the other. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2tgOQO"&gt;I have a standing appointment with my local tattoo shop. If the Dragons win an OWL championship, &lt;a href="https://kotaku.com/i-am-two-shanghai-dragons-wins-away-from-my-first-tatto-1845317426"&gt;I’ll get their logo emblazoned on my arm&lt;/a&gt; (yes, I am serious). If this league is indeed scripted, a Dallas / Shanghai Grand Final is what we’ll get and it’s a final fans deserve. And if this is the end for OWL — please, just let my team win its last game. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22631026/overwatch-league-fourth-season-overview-blizzard"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22631026/overwatch-league-fourth-season-overview-blizzard</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ash Parrish</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-18T16:49:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-18T16:49:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>T-Mobile data breach exposed the personal info of more than 47 million people</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="T-Mobile network advertises seen on a Jumbotron in Times..." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SeY8vHs9AcZ2ShHiYHqB1aj5rMU=/0x30:4793x3225/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69741585/1229111902.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by John Lamparski/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YPCyBJ"&gt;T-Mobile has &lt;a href="https://www.t-mobile.com/news/network/additional-information-regarding-2021-cyberattack-investigation"&gt;released more information&lt;/a&gt; about its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/15/22626270/t-mobile-investigating-report-customer-data-breach'"&gt;most recent data breach&lt;/a&gt;, and while the company’s findings fall short of the reported 100 million records, the numbers are staggering. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="unYsU5"&gt;While saying its investigation is still ongoing, the company confirmed that records of over 40 million “former or prospective customers” who had previously applied for credit and 7.8 million postpaid customers (those who currently have a contract) were stolen. In its last earnings report (&lt;a href="https://s24.q4cdn.com/400059132/files/doc_financials/2021/q2/NG_TMUS-06_30_2021-EX-99.1.pdf"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;), T-Mobile said it had over 104 million customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FoGq9b"&gt;The data in the stolen files contained critical personal information included first and last names, dates of birth, Social Security numbers, and driver’s license / ID numbers — the kind of information you could use to set up an account in someone else’s name or hijack an existing one. It apparently did not include “phone numbers, account numbers, PINs or passwords.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="LMVzP9"&gt;&lt;q&gt;T-Mobile found out about the breach based on a forum post&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="96Jzp9"&gt;That isn’t the end of it, either, as over 850,000 prepaid T-Mobile customers were also victims of the breach, and for them, the exposed data includes “names, phone numbers, and account PINs.” Affected customers have already had their PINs reset and will receive a notification “right away.” There was also unspecified information accessed for inactive prepaid accounts. However, T-Mobile says, “No customer financial information, credit card information, debit or other payment information or SSN was in this inactive file.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="jZ2JEM"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T-Mobile: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1KlIcW"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Customers trust us with their private information and we safeguard it with the utmost concern. A recent cybersecurity incident put some of that data in harm’s way, and we apologize for that. We take this very seriously, and we strive for transparency in the status of our investigation and what we’re doing to help protect you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="AUHUn2"&gt;The notice includes boilerplate language saying that “We take our customers’ protection very seriously,” but it rings especially hollow from T-Mobile considering that this is at least the fourth data breach exposed in the last few years, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/3/22211839/t-mobile-customers-call-records-hacker-security"&gt;one in January&lt;/a&gt;. According to the company’s statement, its investigation began based on a report of someone claiming in an online forum that they had compromised T-Mobile’s servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jMaLXg"&gt;A Twitter account advertising stolen data for sale &lt;a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/08/t-mobile-investigating-claims-of-massive-data-breach/"&gt;claimed&lt;/a&gt; the attack affected all 100 million customers and included IMEI / IMSI data for 36 million customers that could uniquely identify specific devices or SIM cards, but T-Mobile’s announcement does not confirm that is the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oyYN5X"&gt;T-Mobile has &lt;a href="https://www.t-mobile.com/brand/data-breach-2021"&gt;added a page on its site&lt;/a&gt; where customers can go for information as well as shortcuts to change their PINs and passwords. It’s offering two years of free identity protection services from McAfee, recommends postpaid customers change their PIN, and mentions its Account Takeover Protection capabilities to prevent SIM-swapping attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="NCfIm1"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"T-Mobile says unauthorized access to its data occurred, not clear if customer info involved","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22627641/t-mobile-data-breach-unauthorized-access-servers-customer-info"},{"title":"T-Mobile investigating report of customer data breach that reportedly involves 100 million people ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/15/22626270/t-mobile-investigating-report-customer-data-breach"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="rGID8K"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update August 18th, 4:49PM ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Added link and information regarding T-Mobile’s dedicated site, and its apology statement.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630446/t-mobile-47-million-data-breach-ssn-pin-pii"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630446/t-mobile-47-million-data-breach-ssn-pin-pii</id>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Lawler</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-18T15:28:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-18T15:28:11-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook releases a report on the most-viewed content in News Feed</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/G4rwSZdNSMzXS4D_HulNyHbMvqc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69743712/acastro_180501_1777_facebook_dating_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6GkyEO"&gt;Facebook has &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/08/widely-viewed-content-report/"&gt;released a report&lt;/a&gt; to show what content was most widely viewed by Americans in the last quarter, and the list includes a post from President Biden, a video from 5-Minute Crafts, and arguments about whether you should put sugar on spaghetti. Facebook’s report comes as a response to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FacebooksTop10/status/1428031221875961858?s=20"&gt;frequent reports&lt;/a&gt; that some of the platform’s posts with the most interaction are from right-wing sources that critics say could have a radicalizing effect on users. Facebook says that the report shows what people actually see on the platform, as opposed to what content on Facebook gets the most interaction, and that it’ll be creating these reports on a quarterly basis in the future. However, the picture the report paints is, by Facebook’s own admission, an incomplete one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZGbDjj"&gt;&lt;a href="https://transparency.fb.com/data/widely-viewed-content-report/"&gt;Wednesday’s report&lt;/a&gt; covers the public News Feed content seen by Facebook’s US viewers between the beginning of April and the end of June. It contains sections including showing the top 20 domains, links, pages, and posts in terms of views. Facebook also &lt;a href="https://transparency.fb.com/data/widely-viewed-content-report/companion-guide/"&gt;released a companion guide&lt;/a&gt; that describes how it got and analyzed the data for the report.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cB-ZUonIVAFD-cV6LOjJyRUzmeQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22790432/Screen_Shot_2021_08_18_at_10.16.46_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Post: Gaur Gopal Das&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook says this post had 80.6 million viewers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="I7bTfl"&gt;According to the report, the most-viewed post is a letter scramble that invites users to pick out the first three words they see. The second most-viewed posts asks users over 30 to post a picture of themselves if they look young. Facebook has the full list of posts, along with links and screenshots, in its report, which &lt;a href="https://transparency.fb.com/data/widely-viewed-content-report/"&gt;you can view here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lLTAGK"&gt;Looking through Facebook’s lists, it’s all rather tame stuff. The most-viewed domains (which shows which websites’ links were the most viewed, as opposed to which specific links got the most eyes) include sites like YouTube, UNICEF, Spotify, and CBS News, while the most-viewed pages include a page called “Woof Woof” and “Kitchen Fun With My 3 Sons.” The seventh most-viewed link is &lt;a href="https://64.media.tumblr.com/2d32d91bcdfa6e17f18df90f1fada473/6094b00761d82f16-76/s400x600/f0383899ecb1484b10e3420a368d871d7dc68f91.gifv"&gt;an adorable GIF of kittens&lt;/a&gt;, and the third is &lt;a href="https://www.unicef.org/coronavirus/unicef-responding-covid-19-india"&gt;UNICEF’s response page for India’s COVID-19 crisis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="A0PXgQ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Facebook says it wants to give an “accurate representation” of the platform’s content&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uEQlHX"&gt;For some, this may seem surprising or suspect. We’ve &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/interface/2020/7/22/21332774/facebook-crowdtangle-kevin-roose-nyt-tweets-interactions-reach-engagement"&gt;heard before&lt;/a&gt; that Facebook’s own tools show that right-wing content from the likes of &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/07/19/1013793067/outrage-as-a-business-model-how-ben-shapiro-is-using-facebook-to-build-an-empire"&gt;Ben Shapiro&lt;/a&gt; and Sean Hannity is what captures the most interaction from the site’s users, and Facebook is reportedly well aware of that perception. In July, &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; ran a story that described how data published by journalists &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/07/14/technology/facebook-data.html"&gt;led to a battle within the company&lt;/a&gt; about whether it should be as open as possible with what its users engage with, or if limiting access to that data made Facebook look good. As the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; put it, it was a clash between transparency and image management. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YCEKyu"&gt;Facebook denied that characterization then, and it still does. “The narrative that has emerged is quite simply wrong,” Facebook’s VP of integrity, Guy Rosen, said on a call with reporters Wednesday. He added that the goal of releasing the data is to give an “accurate representation” of content on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kNy2Xq"&gt;While the report’s contents may be interesting, they’re not exactly representative of everything that Facebook users actually see. Facebook itself says in the report that the top posts were less than 0.1 percent of the content viewed by the site’s US users. According to the report, the percentage is similar for the top 20 links as well, though the domains made up for 1.9 percent of US news feed content views.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qeuiJEQGuBbkGick1W2azNf-ofU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/22790321/Screen_Shot_2021_08_18_at_9.30.12_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Graphic: Facebook&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Content that links out to other sites doesn’t make up a large portion of the views.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="N9qntC"&gt;Another caveat is that the views Facebook’s report show are the ones for public content — things shared in private groups or on private profiles aren’t included, as Facebook says that would be a violation of privacy. Groups specifically, though, are &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/interface/2019/7/9/20686955/facebook-groups-border-patrol-anti-vaxx-misogyny"&gt;seen as a large source of misinformation and bad behavior&lt;/a&gt; on Facebook, and the company has had to continuously navigate how to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/15/22436973/facebook-myanmar-military-coup-ban-arakan-army-resistance"&gt;enforce existing rules&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/7/21554349/facebook-groups-probation-violating-rules-misinformation-election"&gt;create new ones&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/17/21443742/facebook-health-groups-recommendations-new-admin-rules"&gt;manage them&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="AC6yhc"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The News Feed is personalized, so we’re only seeing a sliver of what Facebook’s users are scrolling past&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5fIJ9b"&gt;All this goes to say that, while &lt;a href="https://transparency.fb.com/data/widely-viewed-content-report/"&gt;the report from Facebook&lt;/a&gt; is interesting to look through, it’s important to keep in mind what it is and what it isn’t. Facebook has &lt;a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2020/11/what-do-people-actually-see-on-facebook-in-the-us/"&gt;been very clear&lt;/a&gt; that there’s a difference between what people see on Facebook and what they interact with, and this report really only touches on the former. There is an argument to be made, though, that what people interact with is what will actually affect them the most — you’re more likely to remember something you commented on than something you scrolled past. Plus, as noted before, the report only shows a tiny slice of News Feed views — with Facebook’s users getting a custom news feed, Facebook can only really summarize so much, which ends up leaving out a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630813/facebook-report-most-viewed-content-links-news-feed-transparancy"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630813/facebook-report-most-viewed-content-links-news-feed-transparancy</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Clark</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-18T15:07:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-18T15:07:32-04:00</updated>
    <title>Twitter is making it easier for other apps to point to Spaces</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Twitter bird logo in white against a dark background with outlined logos around it and red circles rippling out from it." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wgb5Ikdw8tLo_ppZXIxSWNgr0y8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69743550/acastro_180827_1777_0001.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HeaGVe"&gt;Twitter is updating &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/12/21364644/twitter-api-v2-new-access-tiers-developer-portal-support-developers"&gt;its API v2&lt;/a&gt; so that developers can look up its Spaces social audio rooms, &lt;a href="https://blog.twitter.com/developer/en_us/topics/tools/2021/shape-the-future-of-twitter-spaces"&gt;the company announced Wednesday&lt;/a&gt;, which could allow them to share information about Spaces more easily outside the Twitter app. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2YaQ1K"&gt;Twitter has been rapidly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/5/22611609/twitter-spaces-co-host-feature-moderate-manage-social-audio-rooms"&gt;improving&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/26/22455799/twitter-spaces-web-browser-clubhouse-social-audio-room"&gt;Spaces&lt;/a&gt;, but before now, you could only see them on Twitter’s own apps. But starting Wednesday, “all developers using the new Twitter API v2 will be able to look up live or scheduled Spaces using criteria like Spaces ID, user ID, or keyword,” Twitter says, which sounds like it means that a developer can use that information to point you to a Space from within their own app. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="5kbVUZ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;You can still only attend a Space on Twitter, though&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pXMY9p"&gt;This doesn’t appear to mean that developers will be able to let you listen to or attend Spaces inside their apps, however — it sounds like you’ll still only be able to attend a Space on Twitter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QBx9lX"&gt;Despite that limitation, the new features could be an enticing carrot for developers to adopt Twitter’s API v2, the company’s rebuilt API that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/12/21364644/twitter-api-v2-new-access-tiers-developer-portal-support-developers"&gt;launched in August&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/8/23/3263481/twitter-api-third-party-developers"&gt;For some time&lt;/a&gt;, the company opted to limit how developers could build upon Twitter and integrate it into their services and apps, but the ongoing updates to API v2 seem to signal that Twitter is continuing to welcome developers into the fold once again.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22631036/twitter-spaces-developers-api-v2"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22631036/twitter-spaces-developers-api-v2</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-18T15:02:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-18T15:02:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>Cryptocurrency supporters are in the middle of their first big fight in Congress</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/I32TNgGDYO53w3EKnQhm3F0G66Q=/0x2:2048x1367/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69743504/VRG_ILLO_1777_twitter_bitcoin.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Grayson Blackmon / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KjAtyn"&gt;Last week, the Senate approved &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/10/22618448/senate-bipartisan-infrastructure-package-schumer-broadband-cryptocurrency"&gt;a massive infrastructure package&lt;/a&gt; making serious investments in building out the US’s roads and bridges. It would be the largest domestic spending bill in almost a decade, and nearly every powerful lobbying shop circled Washington for months trying to shape its language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2Wu0XB"&gt;But one industry was surprisingly thrown into the fight last minute: cryptocurrency. When the Senate finally announced the bill text earlier this month, it included a provision that could impose devastating new tax requirements for wallet developers and miners. Suddenly, the cryptocurrency industry and its few lobbying shops faced one of its largest regulatory threats ever. They needed all of the digital foot soldiers they could get to help rally senators and fix the problematic language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="svY74v"&gt;So, they turned to their vast and vocal online community of investors and posters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lAXFW5"&gt;“We are at an advantage in grassroots organizing because we’re a structurally networked community,” Neeraj Agrawal, director of communications for Coin Center, told &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Everybody in cryptocurrency knows everybody else for the most part so information moves really fast across various social channels.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fknPJO"&gt;Advocacy groups and blockchain organizations were quickly able to direct their grassroots digital community’s energy toward the fight. Fight for the Future and the Electronic Frontier Foundation were able to prompt more than 40,000 calls to senators ahead of the bill’s final vote on the floor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8ucDbj"&gt;High-profile celebrities and influencers like Ashton Kutcher and Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey also came out in opposition of the bill, posting tweets prompting their followers to call on their senators to fix the language. These tweets inspired other community members to take part in the effort by making calls and posting their own tweets with information from Fight for the Future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="FjeuCo"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“The reason this even became a conversation in Washington was because of Twitter”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OdPiTv"&gt;“Senators who were probably not even paying very much attention to this section of the infrastructure bill suddenly saw their Twitter feeds swamped with messages from their own constituents,” said Rainey Reitman, EFF’s chief program officer. “It was so much they couldn’t ignore it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oNBLOI"&gt;“The reason this even became a conversation in Washington was because of Twitter,” Reitman continued.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ost6NT"&gt;Even crypto-focused YouTubers and TikTok accounts pivoted toward advocacy, informing their followers about the bill and how it could affect the industry. One TikTok user posted a video dancing behind text that said, “Dance if ur an 87 year old senator single-handedly ruining the economy over a $50 billion military dispute,” calling out Sen. Richard Shelby’s (R-AL) objection to an amendment to fix the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MFbLo9"&gt;It’s a surprising shift for an industry that has typically been an outsider in Washington, often directly opposed to well-established players like law enforcement and the banking industry. But as digital assets companies have been drawn into regulatory fights, they’ve had to engage with the process to defend themselves, whether against regulators calling for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/3/22608096/cryptocurrency-bitcoin-sec-gary-gensler-regulation"&gt;more authority&lt;/a&gt; over the industry or a growing concern over &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/6/24/22545675/ransomware-cryptocurrency-regulation-hacks"&gt;ransomware attacks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hbBxbr"&gt;The new push drew heavily on infrastructure from previous online organizing drives. The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/6/6/15745974/net-neutrality-day-of-action-tech-companies"&gt;2017 net neutrality fight&lt;/a&gt; was fought largely online with organizations like Fight for the Future and EFF using social media to prompt internet users to get involved in a policy battle that affected their favorite websites. Once the controversial language was added to the infrastructure bill, those same groups used the tactics they’d perfected in the net neutrality fight to push back.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YZrmM9"&gt;Reitman says the shift to digital organizing has also been a factor, as cryptocurrency fans “are using online platforms like Twitter and &lt;em&gt;Hacker News&lt;/em&gt; to educate themselves, educate other people, and then start speaking out about regulation.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0zBJ9h"&gt;Even with the heightened political pressure, it’s too early to say where Congress will land on the new cryptocurrency rules. Cryptography groups failed to stop the provisions in the Senate, and all hopes now rest on stripping the language from the House version of the bill. As of publication, it’s unclear if congresspeople will have &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/08/17/house-democrats-disagree-over-infrastructure-bill-vote-strategy.html"&gt;one last opportunity&lt;/a&gt; to amend the bill before it reaches its final vote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="48n9Hp"&gt;House Speaker Nancy Pelosi (D-CA) faces an uphill battle in passing the &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/congress/pelosi-faces-infrastructure-squeeze-between-moderates-progressives-n1276910"&gt;infrastructure package at all&lt;/a&gt;. Progressive members say they won’t vote for the Senate-passed $1 trillion package unless it’s tied to a broader $3.5 trillion social services bill. Some moderate Democrats pushed back, saying they wouldn’t vote to begin writing the larger bill unless the infrastructure package is approved first. If the two bills get tied together, it could make it harder for any lawmaker to bring an amendment to change the cryptocurrency language to the floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UiBrsV"&gt;Still, last week’s organizing efforts proved that the cryptocurrency community has grown into an impressive political force in Washington. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jfGz5Z"&gt;“It was really amazing to see how quickly they were able to turn that functionality on and get so many people involved,” Kristin Smith, executive director at the Blockchain Association said. “It’s definitely a turning point for the industry and I think one that will hopefully lead to better policy down the road.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aDqaBS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q2feKt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22631096/cryptocurrency-tax-bipartisan-infrastructure-bill-advocacy-jack-dorsey-ashton-kutcher"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22631096/cryptocurrency-tax-bipartisan-infrastructure-bill-advocacy-jack-dorsey-ashton-kutcher</id>
    <author>
      <name>Makena Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-18T14:47:22-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-18T14:47:22-04:00</updated>
    <title>Senators ask FTC to investigate Tesla’s ‘Full Self-Driving’ promises</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oFg7-OsKQJFW48cWR3dYFltJnWU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69743331/akrales_170414__1610_0497.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="BoKsid"&gt;Senators Ed Markey (D-MA) and Richard Blumenthal (D-CT) have asked new Federal Trade Commission Chair Lina Khan to investigate Tesla’s marketing of its advanced driver assistance system, Autopilot. The Senators are particularly concerned with how Tesla has been charging customers thousands of dollars for what it refers to as “Full Self-Driving capability,” despite the fact that buying that package does not make the company’s cars fully autonomous. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2muSsc"&gt;“Tesla’s marketing has repeatedly overstated the capabilities of its vehicles, and these statements increasingly pose a threat to motorists and other users of the road,” the senators &lt;a href="https://www.markey.senate.gov/news/press-releases/markey-and-blumenthal-call-for-ftc-investigation-into-teslas-misleading-advertising-of-driving-automation-systems"&gt;wrote in a letter published Wednesday&lt;/a&gt;. “Accordingly, we urge you to open an investigation into potentially deceptive and unfair practices in Tesla’s advertising and marketing of its driving automation systems and take appropriate enforcement action to ensure the safety of all drivers on the road.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MlISKh"&gt;The letter comes as the Biden administration has been steadily increasing the scrutiny of tech companies. Much of that focus to date has been through the lens of antitrust policy — especially at the FTC under Khan — but Tesla has drawn some heat as well. Earlier this week, the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration announced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/16/22626819/tesla-autopilot-crash-emergency-vehicle-probe-nhtsa"&gt;an investigation into Autopilot’s tendency to crash into parked emergency vehicles&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="p6WXus"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The request comes days after safety regulators announced a new probe into Autopilot&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="gScCGn"&gt;Tesla CEO Elon Musk has spent years claiming that his company’s cars were on the verge of being able to drive themselves without any human intervention, though that functionality has never arrived. In 2015, he said fully autonomous Teslas &lt;a href="https://fortune.com/2015/12/21/elon-musk-interview/"&gt;were just two years away&lt;/a&gt;. In 2016, Tesla announced that all its new cars &lt;a href="https://www.tesla.com/blog/all-tesla-cars-being-produced-now-have-full-self-driving-hardware"&gt;had the hardware required to accomplish this&lt;/a&gt;, and that the company just needed a little more time to dial in the software. That turned out to not be true, as Tesla &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/22/18511594/tesla-new-self-driving-chip-is-here-and-this-is-your-best-look-yet"&gt;has since created a new&lt;/a&gt; computer that these older cars would need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2aMiHF"&gt;At the same time, Tesla started offering customers a “Full Self-Driving” option when they bought their cars, essentially asking them to prepay for one day having a fully autonomous car. In exchange, these owners would get more advanced capabilities than what is offered in the standard Autopilot suite as Tesla developed them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H6TP9N"&gt;In late 2018, Tesla &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/20/18000884/tesla-full-self-driving-option-gone-musk-autopilot"&gt;pulled this option from its website&lt;/a&gt;, with Musk admitting that it caused “&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1053068635940388865"&gt;too much confusion&lt;/a&gt;.” But just a few months later, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/28/18245370/tesla-autopilot-full-self-driving-musk-2019"&gt;it was back&lt;/a&gt;, and Musk again promised that full autonomy would be &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/28/18245370/tesla-autopilot-full-self-driving-musk-2019"&gt;available by the end of 2019&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oEWzY9"&gt;Since then, Tesla has continued to charge money for the “Full Self-Driving” option — the price currently stands at $10,000 if you buy it when you buy one of the company’s cars, though Tesla also recently started selling “subscriptions” to the Full Self-Driving package if owners want it after purchase. The company is explicit on its website that the option &lt;a href="https://www.tesla.com/support/autopilot#usingautopilot"&gt;does not make its cars fully autonomous&lt;/a&gt;, though as of writing it still promises the functionality will be available by year’s end. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NYO5sR"&gt;Even then, Musk now says a “feature-complete” version of Tesla’s Full Self-Driving software &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sokane1/status/1354576531029430272"&gt;is defined as&lt;/a&gt; the car being able to drive someone from home to work “&lt;a href="https://electrek.co/2020/01/13/tesla-full-self-driving-feature-complete-soon-elon-musk/#:~:text=When%20Musk%20talks%20about%20a,features%20with%20city%20driving%20capability.&amp;amp;text=So%20feature%2Dcomplete%20means%20it's,it%20would%20still%20be%20supervised."&gt;most likely without interventions&lt;/a&gt;,” which does not describe a fully autonomous vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-right"&gt;&lt;aside id="iL91Gm"&gt;&lt;q&gt;Tesla once pulled the “Full Self-Driving” option from its website because of “confusion”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KFH7MJ"&gt;Tesla has been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/10/22570081/tesla-fsd-v9-beta-autopilot-update"&gt;beta testing&lt;/a&gt; this more “feature-complete” version of the Full Self-Driving software for months now, with a few thousand owners in the program running the software on roads across the country. Many of these owners have filmed their experiences with the software, which gets updated every few weeks or months. The results are a mixed bag; for every &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EtPGTOJ5Nks"&gt;intervention-free video&lt;/a&gt; of a Tesla gliding through a cityscape, there’s another where the car &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W3Ill_OYZTI"&gt;refuses to take a left turn&lt;/a&gt; or dives toward &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/tesla-fsd-full-self-driving-videos-flaws-glitches-2021-7"&gt;oncoming traffic&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WfSqFt"&gt;Musk’s many claims, as well as the beta, and a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tlThdr3O5Qo"&gt;video released in 2019&lt;/a&gt; showing an early version of the Full Self-Driving software navigating roads in the San Francisco Bay Area make up the bulk of what the Senators cite in their letter. They also say Tesla has been misleading in its advertising of Autopilot and Full Self-Driving — though the company doesn’t engage in traditional advertising. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uvHB8V"&gt;“We fear that Tesla’s Autopilot and FSD features are not as mature and reliable as the company pitches to the public,” the Senators wrote. “Tesla drivers listen to these claims and believe their vehicles are equipped to drive themselves – with potentially deadly consequences.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BlRMQC"&gt;Safety advocates and other regulators have long pushed for more scrutiny over the way Tesla treats its driver assistance technology. In early 2020, the National Transportation Board found that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/25/21153320/tesla-autopilot-walter-huang-death-ntsb-probable-cause"&gt;the design of Autopilot and overconfidence in its abilities&lt;/a&gt; were what led to a fatal crash in Mountain View, California. Musk has even admitted that drivers can get too complacent when &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/5/2/17313324/tesla-autopilot-safety-statistics-elon-musk-q1-earnings"&gt;using Tesla’s driver assistance features&lt;/a&gt;. But for years, he’s only allowed a passive form of driver monitoring when Autopilot is engaged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vFCC4E"&gt;Charging thousands of dollars for a feature that doesn’t wholly exist while also beta testing it in the real world, after spending years of moving the target for creating an autonomous car, is certainly still causing confusion like the kind that once made Musk step back from the Full Self-Driving option. In Wednesday’s letter, Markey and Blumenthal mistakenly say that the Full Self-Driving beta software is now available to “all Tesla owners” through a subscription. That promise, like many others Musk has made, has not yet been fulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630954/markey-blumenthal-ftc-lina-khan-tesla-full-self-driving-musk"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630954/markey-blumenthal-ftc-lina-khan-tesla-full-self-driving-musk</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean O'Kane</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2021-08-18T14:16:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-18T14:16:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Taliban may have seized biometric data that can ID US allies in Afghanistan</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="US And Afghan Forces Man Border Crossing With Pakistan" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/F8aXThOlPmJHK7D-QpHCvIkaNBU=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/69743101/122259189.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by John Moore/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="171QZO"&gt;The US military created a vast database of biometric data — one report suggests it had a goal of &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/01/14/956705029/first-platoon-examines-how-war-on-terror-birthed-pentagons-biometrics-id-system"&gt;25 million entries&lt;/a&gt; — as part of its effort to track terrorists in Afghanistan. Now that the US has &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/8/15/22626082/kabul-capital-fall-afghanistan-government-taliban-forces-explained"&gt;withdrawn from the country&lt;/a&gt;, reports from &lt;a href="https://theintercept.com/2021/08/17/afghanistan-taliban-military-biometrics/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/afghanistan-tech-conflict/afghans-scramble-to-delete-digital-history-evade-biometrics-idUSL8N2PO1FH"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; suggest the Taliban could potentially use it to target allies left behind. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hpiXoH"&gt;As &lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt; notes, the collection of biometric data &lt;a href="https://www.army.mil/article/32609/bats_helps_id_insurgents_hostages"&gt;was primarily billed as a military project&lt;/a&gt;, but Afghan civilians who worked for US embassies and the broader coalition government were reportedly also included in the database. The biometric information that could be on file for those people varies: the Handheld Interagency Identity Detection Equipment (HIIDE) used by the military collects everything from iris scans to fingerprints, along with identifying biographical information, according to the sources &lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt; spoke to. Those devices are now reportedly in the Taliban’s possession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7I3cIJ"&gt;There’s some conflicting information on whether the Taliban can actually access and take action with the information that’s been collected, however. “The Taliban doesn’t have the gear to use the data,” a former Army Special Operations official told &lt;em&gt;The Intercept&lt;/em&gt;. Accessing the biometric data that’s been collected might then fall to others, like Pakistan’s intelligence agency, Inter-Services Intelligence. According to &lt;em&gt;Reuters, &lt;/em&gt;local reports said the Taliban has used government biometric data in the last five years to “target members of the security forces, checking their fingerprints against a database,” which only clouds things further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0wyy8D"&gt;However urgent the immediate risk is, the possibility of widespread abuse of the collected data makes evading biometric scanning and securing civilians’ digital identities all the more important. Human rights organization Human Rights First has published guides on &lt;a href="https://www.humanrightsfirst.org/resource/evading-misuse-biometric-data"&gt;biometric recognition&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.humanrightsfirst.org/resource/steps-protect-your-online-identity-taliban-digital-history-and-evading-biometrics-abuses"&gt;protecting digital identities&lt;/a&gt; in English, Farsi, and Pashto that should be a good place to start. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="70aSS9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Afghan DJs hired and abandoned by the US military","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/11/19/20961811/taliban-afghanistan-radio-in-a-box-djs-news-war-us-army"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="FK5pmC"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qRd1yI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630686/biometric-data-afghanistan-taliban-hiide-civilians"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/18/22630686/biometric-data-afghanistan-taliban-hiide-civilians</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Carlos Campbell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
